[Music]
welcome to the can med coffee talk
podcast where we talked with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing who will
be part of the km ed 2020 conference in
Pasadena California this september 20th
through 22nd I am your host Ben emerald
I'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the can med conference
every year
head over to cam Med events dot-com to
learn more about this year's KM ed 2020
event and yes we are still planning to
hold the event this fall while closely
monitoring the Cova 19 situation having
said that we have modified our refund
policy for ticket holders and sponsors
to provide 100% refunds if the event is
rescheduled due to the pandemic all that
information is up on our website if you
are planning to join us at cam at 2020
and I really hope you are now is the
time to get your ticket the full
conference pass is just 420 dollars
through April 20th that's more than half
off the full price the full conference
pass gets you access to all the amazing
presentations from the top cannabis
science researchers access to coffee and
lunch stations as well as networking
events the exhibit hall and more head
over to Kim at events dot-com now to
learn more and get your ticket we have a
great episode for you today I was
thrilled to be able to talk with Ethan
Russo Ethan has been studying the
medicinal effects of cannabis and the
endocannabinoid system for as long as
anyone perhaps with the exception of
Professor Raphael McCollum who
coincidentally his Ethan's mentor he has
authored several peer-reviewed articles
and book chapters served as an advisor
for cannabis companies and publications
and spoken at all the top cannabis
conferences around the globe including
can med in fact I encourage anyone who's
interested to check out his chem ed 2018
presentation about the link between the
cannabinoid system cannabis and the gut
microbiome we get into that a little bit
in our conversation but we also cover
some of the cannabis medicine basics
like what is the endocannabinoid system
so for any listeners who
new to cannabis medicine this should
give you a good foundation having said
that there's still plenty of meat on the
bone if you're a more advanced listener
before I play you my conversation with
Ethan we are proud to have his company
credo science as this week's podcast
sponsor credo science LLC is an IP
development company dedicated to
solutions for better living based on
forward-looking research into the
cannabinoid system and related
therapeutic applications for cannabis
based medicines and wellness solutions
for more information go to credo
science com okay and without any further
ado please welcome dr. Ethan Russo
[Music]
good morning Ethan thank you so much for
joining us on the podcast thank you
first I want to say that we're so
excited to have you as a keynote
presenter this year I was watching your
can bed 2018 presentation in in
preparation for the call and that was
only 15 minutes which just was not
enough time so I'm really happy that
we've blocked off a full hour for you
this time because I know you have a lot
of great information to share yeah ah to
be a luxury that I'm happy to exploit
because the topic cannabis and
psychiatry is a really broad one and
it's been an under-recognized and
underutilized area absolutely and I'm
really excited to talked with you about
that
but I was hoping you'd indulge me and we
could kind of start with the basics
because I imagine there are some people
who are new to the podcast new to can
med who maybe are just starting their
cannabis journey and maybe don't have
sort of that foundational knowledge so
let's just let's start from the top and
I was wondering if you give us a brief
primer on what is the endocannabinoid
system sure
well the endocannabinoid system has been
known for about 30 years and then on
development during that time and it
basically is the major homeostatic
regulatory system of our physiology
let's break that down because it's a
mouthful
basically the endocannabinoid system is
what keeps the rest of how we function
and balance so if there is too much
activity in the system the
endocannabinoids system tends to bring
it down into the normal level and on the
other hand if there is an underactive
system it increases the game back into
the normal level now how this was
discovered was that about 1990 it was
found that there are receptors were THC
binds and not only that but that we have
endogenous cannabinoids cannabinoids
within that also bind to the
receptor on as it turns out this is what
regulates neurotransmitter release for
the various neurotransmitters in the
brain but it also regulates emotion
movement pain whether someone will have
a seizure or not whether they're likely
to vomit or not it regulates digestion
and almost every function of the body
Wow
so that's fascinating and I think a lot
of people are surprised to hear that so
I know the cannabis has been used for
medicine for a long time and it's only
now sort of gaining exposure again so in
addition to cannabis what other sorts of
activities or foods can kind of
stimulate the body's production of those
and endogenous cannabinoids well there
are actually a lot of things and it's a
complicated topic the one clear one at
this point is aerobic exercise that
seems to increase the gain of the
endocannabinoid system it's been shown
that that boosts levels of an and amide
which is natural chemical in the body
that is very akin in its function nor to
THC in terms of diet there's no one food
that I could tell people is going to
improve their under cannabinoid function
a lot of people have wondered about fish
oil and these kinds of things and that
can be very healthful but there isn't a
1:1 relationship between what you eat
and what your endocannabinoid function
is going to be if I were gonna suggest
the simplest thing that seems to provide
benefit it would be prebiotics and
probiotics probiotics are going to be
familiar to most people as the natural
bacteria that are is in yogurt and
various fermented foods and the
prebiotics are generally vegetative
matter that these bacteria likes that
promote their growth
why this is important is because these
bacteria reside in the gut on as it
turns out they are really key to not
only our nutrition but brain function on
various other aspects of our health and
it's a problem in modern life because
the modern American diet in particular
tends to be pro-inflammatory on and has
been associated with the vast increases
in a number of autoimmune diseases which
were quite rare in the 19th century when
people eat quite differently so when
people are cognizant of these
nutritional issues they really can help
themselves out in fighting chronic
disease at the same time that they're
increasing their endocannabinoid tone
now this would be I imagine and gross
over simplification but you can't
continue to have you know that standard
American diet and then just ingest
cannabinoids and expect to have an
improvement or Kenya well again it's
complicated this is very surprising but
it's been shown that THC actually favors
certain gut bacteria that are more
helpful and is the reason that chronic
cannabis users tend to be lean rather
than overweight as one might expect due
to the well known munchies effect so
it's true the THC stimulates hunger but
in fact it alters the gut bacteria in a
way that helps prevent obesity so
supplemental cannabinoids from cannabis
can improve the situation but you know
not everyone is going to resort to that
and there are again these nutritional
approaches with prebiotics and
probiotics that can provide hopefully on
the same measures of protection
and now does the delivery mechanism
matter when ingesting cannabinoids ah
well certainly in this instance oral use
is going to be better I don't advocate
smoking for medical use and vaporization
is better but there are still issues um
if someone needs has a condition for
which they need chronic administration
of a cannabis based product and almost
always oral administration or oral
mucosal with tinctures is going to be
preferred excellent I was wondering if
you could kind of explain sort of what
is the mechanism with how these
cannabinoids interact with the body you
had mentioned receptors before but sort
of walk us through when when you ingest
cannabis sort of what's the what's going
on in the body well first I have to
point out how complicated it is there
are at least 150 natural cannabinoids in
the plant and they're quite distinct in
their function so on the one hand THC
works directly on cannabinoid receptors
are the cb1 receptor which is
predominant in the brain and cb2 which
is a non psychoactive receptor that's
immunomodulatory also involved in pain
and reduction of inflammation so
different ones work differently a CBD
cannabidiol actually doesn't bind
directly very well at all to c b1 or c
b2 on c b1 it does alter the binding of
THC in a way that helps reduce THC
Associated side-effects but on CBD acts
on a whole bunch of other mechanisms in
the body primarily to reduce
inflammation but also like THC is
antiemetic it reduces nausea and
vomiting it's also associated with
anti-anxiety effects and antipsychotic
effects which are contrary to what
excesses of THC will do and then there
are a whole bunch of other activities
with CBD another one would be working
directly on another receptor called the
trip v1 receptor which is the same place
where capsaicin the active ingredient
chili peppers works but CBD isn't
caustic the way capsaicin is so yeah I
mean we could go on and on for an hour
just on that topic
sure and that brings up an interesting
point because there is sort of a debate
between health care professionals about
what's better the whole plant medicine
or these single compounds and it sounds
from what you were just describing that
getting a combination of different
compounds is what really drives the
medicinal effect well I'm a firm
believer in that there's been a movement
by some companies towards producing
cannabinoids either by bacteria yeasts
but they're never going to have the
range of activities that a whole
cannabis extract will with its
combination of ingredients there's a
term for this called the entourage
effect that refers to synergies between
different components and that can
consists of boosting a positive effect
or reducing a negative side effect so I
think it's extremely unlikely than any
single compound will have the breath of
activity or the safety profile of our
properly constituted cannabis based
medicine and with so many different
strains and cultivars out there how hard
is it to sort of knit zero in on one
combination of cannabinoids flavonoids
terpenoids that really gets that desired
effect well I'm afraid it's really a
function of where somebody lives on in
certain jurisdictions mainly in the west
coast there's a wide variety of
available chemo VARs or chemical
varieties and it may be possible with
good labeling and good knowledge at
point of sale for someone to seek out
the profile of cannabinoids and
terpenoids that's going to be optimal to
treat their condition
that situation does not obtain most
places however so right now it's very
difficult I'm still hindered by the
continued prohibition on cannabis
so we're severely limited in what
industry can do and also the ability to
do research on these kinds of topics I
get Oh imagine consistency is another
issue I had a conversation recently with
a cannabis safety testing lab and the
woman I was speaking with was talking
about how just within the plant itself
different buds from different areas of
the plant can have really different
chemical profiles so I got to imagine
that's another reason why you probably
are advocating more for at entry based
type delivery systems ah sure what you
pointed out is quite true there's going
to be a different cannabinoid profile
mainly greater amounts in the top buds
rather than ones lower down on the plant
that might not get as much sun exposure
the way around this is through pooling
in other words if we had a field of
cannabis so you'd collect all the
flowers and extract them and with
cloning vegetative propagation and
uniform growing conditions best done in
a greenhouse it is absolutely possible
to get extreme levels of consistency
over time on that's precisely how
sativex the cannabis space medicine
developed in england which is um has
regulatory approval in 30 countries
that's exactly how it was produced so it
has been done it's not a simple process
it's a long process it's an expensive
process but it absolutely has been done
and can be done again okay so so going
back to these
endogenous cannabinoids now is there
sort of like a one-to-one relationship
between you know what the body produces
and what the plant produces in terms of
the compound no unfortunately it's
always more complicated than one might
hope
as I've mentioned an and amide is quite
analogous to THC and they're both they
both are what are called weak partial
agonist at the cb1 receptor this is a
way of saying that they're not super
high potency they work through a great
deal of subtlety on this receptor that
is so widespread in the brain and body
to regulate neurotransmitter function
and all these other functions but there
is another main player let's say among
the endocannabinoids it's called - Iraq
or Donal glycerol - AG it's a little bit
different it works in different areas of
the brain it has a higher affinity for
the receptor so it's not a simple
relationship and they are all these
things are chemically distinct there are
at least subtle differences and how they
act in different places all right
interesting so I was wondering if you
could kind of share with us what
conditions have benefitted the most or I
should say what conditions have had the
most research to support cannabis as a
medicine oh sure well it's actually a
short list it's long been known the
benefits of THC in cannabis based
medicine and treating on nausea
associated with chemotherapy also in
aids wasting additionally sativex is
mentioned does approved in 30 countries
for spasticity or muscle tightness
associated with multiple sclerosis there
also has been a great deal of evidence
of certain cannabis preparations in
treating various types of chronic pain
especially neuropathic nerve based pain
beyond that we have a tremendous amount
of anecdotal evidence for a variety of
other conditions but it's not always
borne out in randomized clinical trials
now if we're talking about specifically
cannabidiol
it's an approved drug as epi dialogues
through the FDA for treatment of severe
epilepsy syndromes Lenox Gaston and
dravet syndrome and that's a relatively
recent event starting in 2018
additionally they've been to Phase two
clinical trials of pure cannabidiol in
high doses to treat schizophrenia and it
seemed to be as effective as
conventional drugs but with many fewer
side-effects all right and then on the
flip side what are some emerging
applications for cannabis therapeutics
well that's wide open um you know the
one of the exciting areas is treatment
of primary cancer in other words using
high doses of cannabinoids to treat
cancer directly much as chemotherapy
would do the advantage there is that
most chemotherapy agents are highly
toxic in and of themselves whereas the
cannabinoids are selective in their
ability to kill cancer but are not
damaging to normal cells so this is a
distinct difference and beyond that
there's the whole era psychiatry which
is heretofore been sort of a forbidden
territory but really needs further
investigation for the vast kinds of
improvements that properly constituted
cannabis based medicine could provide
yeah so let's get into that because I
know that is going to be the topic of
your presentation this year
oh sure well you know let's talk about
different conditions there was an one of
the most interesting areas is
post-traumatic stress on some years ago
there was an excellent study by matt
hill at all that looked at survivors of
the 9/11 tragedy on there were two
groups there were people that were in
the area and lower manhattan to the
events there that develop post-traumatic
stress and then people that were there
that did not and they looked at the
cerebrospinal fluid using spinal taps on
these people and showed clear
differences there was a deficit of
endocannabinoids in the people develop
pious PTSD as opposed to those who
didn't have post-traumatic stress and
this is a demonstration of deficient
endocannabinoid function in people with
post-traumatic stress
similarly on severe depression people
may be aware that when drugs fail on
there is still a technique called
electroconvulsive therapy or shock
therapy for people with severe
depression so what that does as a side
effect is produces some short-term
memory impairment at the same time that
there's a rapid improvement in mood now
a long time ago it occurred to me that
gee I wonder if the endocannabinoid
system is involved in this effect and a
couple of years ago in Germany in fact
after ECT treatments it was shown that
there were big increases in the
endocannabinoid levels as opposed to
before treatment so this is a certain
demonstration of the importance of
cannabinoids
in depression similarly anxiety is
definitely associated with
endocannabinoid deficiencies and as
already mentioned does in schizophrenia
although it's true
too much THC at a young age in a
predisposed individual could unmask
psychosis I caused a psychotic break in
fact though
cannabidiol is an effective treatment
for schizophrenia itself so those are
just a few examples those are some very
interesting examples I had never heard
that that factoid about the folks with
at 9/11 kind of having a very different
response with PTSD and it's being tied
back to endow cannabinoids that's
fascinating
oh sure you know and it supplements a
whole bunch of animal work which you
know sometimes is illuminating and
sometimes it's not but this has clearly
study done in humans very much on point
so now you know and I'm glad that you
brought up endocannabinoid deficiency
because when I was sort of gathering my
research for this conversation and
reading about the endocannabinoid system
I immediately went there and thought
that you know if this is something that
the body is producing there must be some
people who are deficient on it and sure
enough I googled it and whose name comes
up but Ethan Rousseau because you did
obviously a lot of a lot of research
into this going back many years so I'm
curious what causes this deficiency is
it because of diet is that behavior is
it genetic
there is a combination of all those
things yeah it is all of the above so
this is a theory I developed about 2000
was published first in 2001 more
extensively in 2004 then with a
follow-up paper in 2016 and the idea was
that we know that many neurologic
conditions especially are due to
neurotransmitter deficiencies so I
hypothesized well why won't there be
conditions in which there is a
deficiency of endocannabinoid function
and if so what would it look like and
certain things came to mind and these
would be conditions where there's a
hypersensitivity to life if you were
where there's pain where we don't
identify anything wrong with the tissue
there seems to be an overreaction and
you can't provide another explanation
and the three conditions that most
readily came to mind were migraine
irritable bowel syndrome and
fibromyalgia and what's interesting is
that these tend to occur in the same
individuals a person may have one two or
all three of these conditions at some
point in their life they're all what are
called diagnosis of exclusion meaning
that we don't have blood tests or
diagnostic tests for them but if he fit
a clinical pattern on and we've ruled
out everything else that's what you call
it they all have a hypersensitivity of
this census producing pain but in the
case of migraine also sensitivity of the
eyes to light and the ears to sound
these are painful stimuli whereas to
someone else is just the normal
background so there's a great deal of
overlap going back to what you asked how
does this happen well there are certain
genetic tendencies are not genetically
inherited the way eye color is however
they also could be acquired a lot of
people with irritable bowel syndrome
will develop the condition after they
have either had antibiotics or have had
some kind of infection like eating bad
clams and can go on and on and on with
fibromyalgia it often follows an injury
that fails to heal and develops in norm
or encompassing generalized pain
syndrome so there seems to be inciting
events and and certainly diet enters
into it again interestingly with
prebiotic and probiotic diet almost all
these conditions will improve on that
really depends on the degree to which
one adheres to that engages and other
lifestyle approaches that seem to
benefit the conditions now is there a
test one can get to see if they're
deficient and endocannabinoids not
currently but we're working on that I
mean a lovely thing would be if we had a
non-invasive scheme of the scan of the
brain that would show us the density of
the receptors and their current level of
activities or we could measure
endocannabinoid levels without doing a
lumbar puncture a spinal tap but right
now no and there could be genetic tests
that would identify these issues we're
working on one such situation now to see
right yeah and another thing that a lot
of people talk about with using cannabis
is that the effects can vary widely
between different individuals is that
does that have to do with deficiencies
or different levels of endocannabinoids
yeah exactly again we're invoking this
hypothetical endocannabinoid tone so how
an individual will respond to a given
dose of cannabis will depend on their
prior experience of whether they have
tolerance if they've been a regular user
and it would be a function of the
numbers of cb1 receptors in the brain
whether they're active or inactive the
levels of endocannabinoids in the brain
and also the activity of the enzymes
that make those substances and break
them down so pretty complicated concept
and again we have either direct or
indirect proof of a lot of these
concepts but right now it's not a simple
thing where someone can go out and get
tested to see what their levels are on
the future yeah we'd hope for
that it would be very useful yeah one of
the things you keep coming back to you
and it sticks out in my mind because I'm
a very active person I'm a runner you
keep talking about how activity can sort
of help modulate the endocannabinoid
system I was born if you talk a little
bit more about that oh sure well you
know this is a very topical issue right
now because for instance where I live
suddenly the gym is closed and the parks
are closed normally we take the dogs out
for a run every day and in addition to
the depression that people are having
because of kovat 19:00 they're going to
become chemically depressed without
their aerobic activity I hope you're not
experiencing that but everyone's going
to be at risk for this for shut-in for
long periods of time so I mean that
would be one example again this is a
situation where we have some human data
showing the relationship of aerobic
exercise to increased under cannabinoid
levels there was one such study in
fibromyalgia just recently years ago
when I was in neurology practice I made
the statement which I hold to today on
that in fibromyalgia I've never seen
anyone who improved without the addition
of a low-impact aerobic activity program
to their regimen and I think the reason
is improvement and endocannabinoid
levels that's fascinating
so we're coming up to the end here and I
did want to ask you you've been
researching cannabis medicine applying
cannabis medicine for so long now how
have attitudes among other health care
providers sort of changed over the years
well there's been improvement we're
getting better acceptance at this point
but the problem remains so we still have
vast prohibitions
active throughout a lot of the world
including this country and until er
unless those roadblocks to research and
wider availability of cannabis based
medicines occurs we're gonna have a
situation where there are a lot of
people out there that would benefit from
these types of treatments that just
don't have access at this time so no
matter how much things have changed or
improved there's vast potential for
improvement yet so we if we have any
patients out there that want to maybe
help educate their healthcare providers
are there some resources that are are
good to point them towards oh sure there
were a lot of good things online I might
point to the International Association
for cannabinoid medicines that's
cannabis - med org variety my papers are
available online now at ethan russo org
and yeah there's a lot of good
information available excellent i know
you just played your website there are
other ways people can get in touch with
you or hear more about what you're doing
well I hope that we'll be able to do the
can med conference and additionally
there are a large number of recordings
online if someone just goes to youtube
and inputs
Ethan Rees on cannabis they'll find
plenty of material excellent and I will
definitely put the links to your prior
Ken made appearances in the show notes
here and provide a link to your website
as well and yes we're very hopeful that
can med 2020 is going to go off without
a hitch this fall we're monitoring the
situation closely but as it stands right
now we're gonna be there and we're
excited to have you there as well Ethan
so thanks again for taking the time to
talk with us today
and if I don't see you before then we'll
see you in Pasadena this fall thank you
my pleasure
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Ethan Rousseau check out our keynote
announcement blog post to learn more
about him and all the important work he
has done to push cannabis medicine
research forward I've also included a
link to his can med 2018 presentation in
the show notes be sure to check out our
next episode where I will talk with
Martin Lee from project CBD Martin and
his wife Tiffany Devitt recently wrote
an article titled cannabis CBD and Cova
19 that explores what science says about
CBD as an antiviral agent you can check
out that article at project CBD org I
think you will find it a well researched
article that presents some interesting
data while not making any grandiose
claims that episode will drop April 29th
two weeks from this episode in the
meantime please go to Kim at events
dot-com / coffee talk and sign up for
email updates that will enter you into a
drawing to win two tickets to our kin
med 2020 VIP dinner and also keep you up
to date with all things can med 2020 if
social media is your thing you can find
us on Facebook Instagram Twitter and
LinkedIn just search for ken med events
and lastly if you're listening via
podcast app go ahead and hit subscribe
so you can get new episodes
automatically downloaded to your device
alright that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and be sure to come back for the
next episode of KM egg coffee fun
[Music]
you