[Music]
welcome to the can med coffee talk
podcast will be talked with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing who will
be part of the can med 2020 conference
in Pasadena California
this September 20th through 22nd we have
a great episode for you today as I had
the chance to talk with medicinal
genomics chief scientific officer Kevin
mckernon kevin is a legend in genomic
sequencing going back to his days
working on the human genome project he
has applied his experience and knowledge
to trying to better understand the
cannabis genome which as he mentions in
our conversation is one of the hardest
genomes to figure out so much so that
many of the top minds in genetic
sequencing have collaborated to try to
solve this cannabis genome problem and I
think you'll see from our conversation
that collaboration is something that
Kevin is very passionate about so it's
no surprise then that Kevin and the team
at medicinal genomics and at that time
core gene life sciences came up with the
idea for the can med conference to
provide a place where cannabis
researchers and clinicians could come
together share their data and learn from
one another and if you'd like to learn
from the leading minds and cannabis
science cultivation medicine and safety
testing you should definitely join us at
canva 20 2010 over to can med events
calm to learn all about the event and to
buy your full conference ticket at our
special 420 rate for just four hundred
and twenty dollars you'll get access to
two days of oral and poster
presentations are expanded exhibit hall
coffee and lunch stations networking
events and more that 420 dollar price is
more than half off the full price but
the offer is only available through
April 20th so get your tickets today now
I would be remiss to not mention the
kovat 19 pandemic first we all hope that
you and yours are safe and healthy
during this difficult time this global
health crisis has certainly changed life
at can med events and medicinal
and for me personally as I record this
from my home by the way I apologize in
advance if any ambient noise from my
children finds its way into the podcast
we understand you are likely dealing
with your own challenges and struggling
with the uncertainty of when we're all
going to get back to business as usual
and of course we understand how those
factors play into purchasing a ticket
for an event in order to put your mind
at ease we want to let you know that if
kovat 19 forces us to reschedule you
will be entitled to a 100% refund if the
new dates don't work for you for more
information about our co vid 19 refund
policy please check out our website at
Ken Med events com in addition medicinal
genomics and cabmen events would like to
do their part to support the community
and organizations in need so 10% of any
tickets sold before the April 20th
deadline will be donated to the CDC's
emergency response fund as of now can
med 2020 is still on for September 20th
through 22nd and we are working closely
with the Pasadena Convention Center to
make sure we can bring you this event
should anything change we will be sure
to let you know on our website and
through our email list another great
reason to sign up for email alerts again
we hope you stay safe and healthy before
I get to my conversation with Kevin we
do have a sponsor for today's podcast
PacBio sequencing technology matters and
PacBio gets cannabis sequencing right
with easy to use workflows long reads
and high accuracy PacBio provides the
tools to gain a complete view of genetic
diversity for more information go to Pak
b.com so without any further ado here's
my conversation with Kevin mckernon
chief scientific officer of medicinal
genomics
[Music]
hello Kevin thanks for joining us thanks
for having me Ben yeah I figured it
would be fitting to have you as our
first guest since you've been so heavily
heavily involved in kid med since its
inception so maybe we should start with
you kind of telling the story about how
can med came to be wow there's a long
story there and it um it actually drive
to think from a lot of the the the
parents that had children that are being
treated in this kind of split medical
care system we have we've got nine I
think this was presented a can med last
year that only nine percent of
physicians are educated on the ECS and
yet we've got a lot of people that in
the cannabis space have been forced to
practice medicine and circumstances
whether either uncertified or you know
don't don't have access to all the tools
in the medical care system so it creates
a really challenging environment for
parents who are obviously in oftentimes
having to use both systems both the the
current Western medicine while also
seeking you know caregivers and other
folks who are professionals and making
some of these oils so that up that kind
of a scientific apartheid system that
has occurred due to prohibition has
really created a need for physicians to
educate many people in the cannabis
field about the things we need to worry
about and treating a lot of these
complex diseases at the same time for
those physicians to learn from people in
the cannabis field that have been making
these products sort of under the table
for the last 80 years so we've always
found that you know the division of
labor makes people hyper specialized and
oftentimes the most productive
interactions are cross-disciplinary when
you get together minds of people who are
doing growing and people who are doing
at a local chemistry they're not always
speaking the same language of people
doing genomics or people that are that
are practicing medicine so getting them
all together to share notes is
extraordinarily important right now and
that's kind of the spirit II can med I
think you're absolutely right it it
seems like the the conference really
started with a real medical focus given
the fact that medicinal genomics is
still hard to coordinate courtesan at
that pole
but the conference has really grown to
include more of those other disciplines
like you had mentioned being cultivation
and laboratory testing so it's become a
very important event for the community
would you agree I would definitely agree
and and you know the initial conferences
were definitely more medically ridden
encourage everybody to go and look at
some of those those presentations you
guys have done great job keeping them
all online so you can kind of see the
history but it was really early in the
early days to demonstrate the medical
need and so that you'll see a lot of
patient examples and stories that are
brought out early on with some of the
physicians sharing their notes on how
those progressed and then as it's grown
there's been an interest in you know
more monies coming to the space more
tool providers or more comfortable
working in the space so now we're seeing
multinational companies come in that are
sponsoring the event to you know show
off mass spec equipment or the latest
genomic tools or even some of the
advances in the agricultural sector and
and all of these you're gonna play a
role because the cost of the medicine we
clearly want to come down prohibition
has clearly been elevating that price
for some time and it's only going to
come down if we can really drive yield
and efficiency in the process and that
requires a multidisciplinary approach
absolutely and so speaking of
presentations I wanted to talk a bit
about what I assume you're gonna be
presenting about at canva 2020 I mean if
we look back the last two years you know
2018 we use kind of introduced this this
project to create a new reference genome
and talked about how it was funded
through - and everything and then 2019
we got another update about sort of that
project and how it was progressing and I
know you have a lot of new and exciting
information to share about the research
you've dug to the cannabis genome so
it's wonder if you could talk a bit
about that yeah so a lot of things have
changed radically in the sequencing
space in the last few years it's really
coincided with cannabis becoming legal
which has been quite remarkable to see
there there are these new long read
sequencers I mean they've been out for a
while but they really the long read
sequencers have really been hampered by
their error rates they're not that
accurate but they can get you very long
reads
something we've never had before in the
sequencing space and to add to that just
this year we saw PacBio finally get the
single molecule sequencing to be more
accurate than Sanger data which has
really been the gold standard technique
that we use to initially sequence the
human genome you know plant genomes are
even harder than human genomes to
sequence they're more repetitive the
cannabis genome is upwards to 70% repeat
content that makes even these long read
tools trip up on them unless they have
the accuracy to separate all of the
repeats that are in the genome they're
closely related and similar sequences
and so you really need accuracy and long
reads to make that come together so
those came together those tools really
have only been available since this
December so we did present on Jamaican
line last year and those are done with
some of the more error-prone
tools that had very long reads and they
did they really push the genome forward
quite a bit in terms of its completeness
but some of the centromeres and the
telomeres and the repetitive regions
that have a lot of these cannabinoids
and face genes are still somewhat
Quagmire and these longer read more
accurate tools whatnot what they are
calling the hi-fi system at PacBio
has is begun to resolve those we're
starting to see full-length telomeres
and cannabinoid synthase gene clusters
all perfectly resolved with these newer
tools and that does change our
perspective on the genome and gives us a
better tool to compare it to all the
other cannabis genomes out there this
you know we all call it cannabis and
there's an active debate on how many
species there are but when you actually
start looking at the genomes across
multiple different varietals you realize
one genome project isn't gonna solve
this debate we're going to have be in a
world where we're looking at multiple
different references probably initially
a cannabinoid centric reference genome
set where we're going to have type 1
references type 2 references type 3
fours and fives so we understand the
genome from the perspective of the
various medical cannabinoids that
they're producing so you'll see so more
data on how we've used these long read
tools to really resolve and close the
chapter on genome completeness with
cannabis and you'll also see some tools
that are now being developed as a result
of that now that we have a confident
understanding of the order of all of
these chromosomes we've been building
chips with eurofins that can get us
90,000 sniffs out of the genome mostly
encoding regions that will be more
likely to be representative of
phenotypic changes or chemo typical
plant and these tools can now start to
get deployed at mass scale when you get
involved with DNA chips they're really
effective to run hundreds to thousands
some people run sixty thousand chip
studies and you can really begin to
tease apart the the markers that are
predictive of yield outcomes and I think
that's a really exciting change for the
cannabis field and so was it that there
was such advancement in sequencing
technology that you just really saw an
opportunity to improve upon the
references that were out there was that
really the well we the driver we
initially got involved in this because
there were only type one female
references being sequenced at the time
and we've realized we really need to
type two plants plants that made both
CBD and THC and and we want males
sequenced as well that y chromosome is
the largest chromosome and and it
probably has a lot of information in it
to understand hermaphroditism and other
types of characteristics of growing hemp
versus growing drug type cannabis plants
and so we wanted to get more
completeness there that the sequencing
benefits were kind of an accident and
and along the path of sequencing
Jamaican line the the companies that are
really heavily involved in this space
for doing too novo assembly began to
realize that cannabis is one of the
hardest genomes they've ever seen
you know they've recently announced
sequencing I think the redwood and
Sequoia and even those genomes are which
are bigger genomes in cannabis they're
not nearly as repetitive so they're
they're beginning to assemble into
better quality than the cannabis genome
so the cannabis genome has become a bit
of this trophy organism amongst the
people who make DNA assembly tools where
they all want to crack it because it
looks like it's one of the hardest ones
to manage so this is create a little bit
of an assemble thon this is where all
the people who build the DNA assembly
tools are now working on cannabis you
can see Sergey Koren has been playing
around with this with this new assembler
hang Lee at the brode who's another
famous person working in the DNA
algorithm spaces got his new assembler
that's been assembled with high ASM as a
name of his assembler Falcon has been
updated so all of the assemblers now
have refactored and retold and rewritten
themselves to manage this new data
content that's that's a testament in and
of itself and right now Jamaican lion is
the only cannabis plant that has these
HiFi reads run across it and put through
five different assemblers so it's um
it's a really exciting time to see some
of some of these changes because with
this accuracy means there are tools that
we can develop and are being developed
that can do DNA assembly faster than we
can map the Illumina reads and that is a
real change we've not had that in the
past so there's a so there's an
assembler called Peregrine we encourage
everyone to look at this is probably the
fastest thing we've seen yet we can
assemble genomes now like on home
computers which has never been the case
before so it's it's it's really we can't
take any credit for that in advance it
kind of happens there and impetus lis
but the timing is just perfect because
we can deploy these things on the
Cannabis genome and get the whole
community involved in trying to improve
the improve the reference so for people
who aren't maybe as familiar with the
intricacies of sequencing and assembling
what what does all this work really mean
for the industry and we're you know
cannabis breeding and cultivation can go
with this information well that and the
answer that will probably change over
time in somewhat regulatory driven and
the current regulations at the USDA have
placed a deep emphasis on washing for
residual THC content and there are
several sources theoretical sources of
residual THC content we can see genomes
now that have only CBD synthase genes in
them and they still make residual THC
and this is actually supported with a
lot of the cloning literature if you
clone CBD synthase into yeast and feed a
precursor you'll still get some some THC
made by that enzyme so there's a about a
23 to 25 to 1 ratio we tend to see of
CBD synthase leaking some THC synthase
now if your goal is to make CBD you
can't really get rid of that other than
to screen for plants that might have
variants and CBD synthase that alter
that ratio and there's some activity
with site-directed mutagenesis that
people are doing that may that may drive
that there's other cannabinoid synthase
genes in the genome that leaked THC as
well so none of these synthase genes are
really faithful they're promiscuous they
make a little bit of side product that
that is usually made by a specialized
enzyme so one thought is still a theory
but what what our data seems to be
pointing to is you know good number of
the plants out there have a deletion of
the cannabic Romijn synthase gene
cluster this is a cluster that can have
anywhere between three to eight
different cannabic roaming genes arrayed
in it and you can see this in some type
for plants type for plants have both THC
and CBD deleted I should say THC
synthase in the CBD synthase are both
deleted so they should have any capacity
to make THC a or CBD a but yet we still
see in these type four plants not just
CBG being made but also some residual
THC granted it's lower than what we see
in type three plants it's still making
some and we believe that's coming from
the residual can have a chromium genes
that may be present so understanding the
whole portfolio of cannabinoid synthase
genes is really the path to go if you
want to get breeding for seed lines that
can consistently make you lower amounts
of THC a it's almost it's very difficult
to do right now if you have a gene like
CBD sim face that is leaking if you grow
that above eight or nine percent CBD
synthase you'll start to see th see a
pop up in those in those plants at a
level that may make it insufficient for
USDA guidelines so the an average we're
seeing over forty different cannabinoids
and face genes to monitor so when we do
DNA sequencing or when we run these
chips that we've built we can begin to
profile these we alone have seen through
sequencing over two hundred and twenty
two variants inside CBD and THC
synthesis point mutations in the genes
that might be altering its function
those are all now embedded on the
urethane chips and we have tools coming
out shortly that will help breeders scan
for genetics that have the highest
likelihood of producing of the the best
ratios so I think that's what's going to
be helpful for guiding maybe the
the cannabinoids the major cannabinoids
then there's an interest in figuring out
what's making the minor cannabinoids
alright what might be making THC P or
CBD P these are the the the longer side
chain molecules that were discovered in
Italy that are 30 times more potent we
don't know what makes those we don't
think it's related to the synthase genes
we think it's related to the genes
upstream in the cannabinoid synthase
pathway and the genetics may help lead
the way in predicting that very recently
a Kanab of on was described discovering
heme 10 years ago but now they're
beginning to tease it apart and realize
that it is in fact plant derived and we
need to understand what are the other
synthase genes that might be responsible
there we're also getting some potential
now to predict terpene expression based
on the terpene synthase genes that we're
seeing and we're hopeful we'll be able
to get more focus on the can flavin gene
set as well by doing more sequencing the
canned Flavin's are showing a lot of
promise in I think I saw some work in
pancreatic cancer and prostate cancer so
these are flavonoids that are often not
tested for in the analytical chemistry
labs and can meds a great area to bring
some of those papers forward talk to the
analytical chemist to see if there are
standards and if there are ways to
detect them and get the extraction folks
involved to know what's the best way to
capture flavonoids they may not be
captured in oil extracts as efficiently
as other extracts and so that that type
of intersection with what the what the
medical field is seeing from a
cannabinoid standpoint so how to
analytically detect them properly in the
field and likewise how to potentially
grow for them and breathe for them or
all interdisciplinary tools that and
discussions we need to be having with
multiple different people and Ken meds
the right place for that so it really
seems like figuring out the the
cannabinoids the flavonoids and terpenes
is really the first step with with
genetics is that there's no I mean
that's one get that's one section of
yield I mean you're hinting at a really
important point here which is yield may
also be related to trichome genes or to
pathogen resistance for instance we
pathogens can severely limit a crop
upwards to 40 percent lower yield
if you have some of these pathogens and
understanding the pathogen resistance in
the plants is likely going to bring us
higher yield as well so the paper we
published back in January listed over 80
different pathogen resistance genes
these were mostly thamma team like
proteins and chitin aces and another low
sign known as mlo which has been studied
heavily in hops well if we can better
understand those genetics we can breed
for plants that are powdery mildew
resistance and and perhaps have less
Aspergillus that might be present in
them as well just by keeping an eye on
the portfolio of a pathogen resistance
genes they have some of the genes
involved in this pathogen response are
actually closely located next to the
cannabic roaming genes such that when
the plants are deleted in cannabic
Romijn they may pull out five other
genes for the ride in that deletion and
make those plants more susceptible to
pests that's a theory it's not been
proven yet we just happen to know those
genes are frequently deleted
concurrently which can have a CRO
meaning if people are selecting for
lines that don't have that to try and
meet the USDA we got to keep a close eye
on on the pathogen response to those
plans so they don't end up having hemp
plants that are compliant with the USDA
but are loaded with mold and mildew it's
important to know the hemp market is not
screening for mold and mildew the way
the medical market is and that's a bit
of an exposure point for us so whenever
you talk about genetics and kind of
genes and everything a lot of people
will start going to GMO or maybe even
CRISPR is there do you foresee a
potential that those types of
technologies will be used in cannabis
they already are
there's no stopping that I know a lot of
people find that to be controversial but
I think one thing you will learn from
looking at these cannabis genomes and
just comparing them is the plant is a
far better genomic engineer than we are
at the moment it is shuffling stuff
around at a really high rates I mean
we're seeing structural variations
between these genomes that may include
about 1/8 of the genetic content in the
plant that's a tremendous amount of
variation that can be occurring just
between any two given plants so
people are gonna make some modifications
some folks is gonna be very afraid of
that but they may not fully appreciate
the fact that this plan is doing that on
its own quite frequently and probably
more intelligently than we are at the
moment so I think there have been cases
of people like trying to delete tht sim
face with CRISPR and that's sure it's a
great plan but we already have naturally
deleted th decent faces in the
population and that doesn't give us zero
percent THC there may be some other
genes you need to delete as well maybe
another 39 can have nodes and face genes
that are leaking so you know the hemp
transformation protocols are really
early and I don't know that you can do
multiple site mutagenesis with CRISPR
and select forward and and it's early
for those types of studies I think what
you're more likely to see is rapid
breeding as finding the actual profiles
you want in the field and intelligently
breeding some of those characteristics
out of the plant and into the set of
cultivars you're working with and
getting you know CRISPR to transform
plants and get those to be stabili
represented and not to be mosaics
oftentimes when you do these genetic
modifications it's very difficult to get
them to transform every single cell in
the plant you have to start with a very
small amount of tissue and hope that you
get a hundred percent transaction
efficiency and then find a selectable
marker that brings that out to the rest
of the tissue type that's not that's
uneasy and and so that limits what you
can do in many respects right now with
the current CRISPR technologies but I do
think they're coming and I do think
they're gonna play a valuable role I
think some of the most exciting genetic
engineering stuff that we're seeing is
the capacity to bring some of these
genes into other hosts like yeast so
that you can really torture test them as
an individual gene in the different
organism to understand what it does so
the work that we saw presented last year
with Dmytryk s-- interesting enough they
were able to clone THC and CBD synthase
into a yeast and by feeding it different
precursors from hexanoic acid to octa
nona they were able to get the yeast to
make th TP that taught us a lot about
THC P that taught us that THC synthase
can in fact make it and so that's
probably not where to genetically look
for any of the mutations in the plant
that are making it but it also gave us a
model to know
that when you isolate this single gene
and feed it particular precursors you
get a desired outcome and that teaches
us a lot about the biochemistry in the
plan itself so oftentimes these tools of
shuttling genes around teach us a lot
about the complexity of the plant so
that we don't have to we don't have to
get to as much guesswork in the
engineering you want to do in the plant
so do you foresee a future where folks
are creating cannabinoids with yeast
instead of the plan I see some of that
yeah I think the the benefits of the
yeast derives cannabinoids are that
they'll be highly pure you can you can
make them and make only preferably only
one or two of them depending on how much
side product you get the thing about
yeast is you can control the conditions
you grow it in and perhaps coax those
enzymes to be less for me promiscuous in
that environment and then you can also
put different molecules on them if you
want to tag the cannabinoids so that you
can purify them that the casing paper
put a biotin on the tail and there are
ways to put biotin zhan molecules where
it's removable so they may be able to
they may be will you know edging into a
really highly purified form of one
particular cannabinoid which can be a
little bit difficult to iron out in the
plant that'll make for a great GMP grade
I don't yet know if it's gonna be
competitive economically with the plant
when you start with when you start
getting more efficient breeding going on
the plant may in fact be a very
productive way of making this but those
economic things are you know best seen
in the marketplace I think I don't think
it's gonna be necessarily an instant
replacement for all these other
compounds we want to make and part of
that is because you know you were
feeding yeast sugar in 99% of the sugar
the world's made by chloroplasts so it's
it's likely that this is a great tool to
simplify what's going on but it may not
be the most carbon efficient way to grow
other cannabinoids but we'll see that's
that's kind of an open field certainly
if we could get THC P expressed in the
plan up to 20% that would that might
make it more productive to make in
cannabis however I don't know that THC
or THC P is ever going to be grown
outdoors meaning it may remain
artificially elevated in price such that
yeast has an advantage I don't know if
people are doing this in yeast are going
to target CBD first CVD
something you can grow outdoors like why
is CBG and those economics are going to
probably plummet a lot faster than
indoor growing so I view the right now
the it has a very helpful tool for us
dissecting the biology and it may in
fact turn out to be a very productive a
very productive purification tool if you
will however we are consistently being
reminded by these whole plant extracts
being more productive than isolated
compounds that seems to be a theme
that's been in the cannabinoid space for
twenty or thirty years we don't always
know why we're doing the best we can to
profile those things but the complexity
of the expression of these of these
plant derived cocktails is it may just
be people need to get those plants
cloned and there's a great story of avid
echo which is an oral and that was
sequence and put on canopy D I think T
Kamala moans this this particular plant
but they went down the road of getting a
plant patent and in cloning that and
making sure that plant they could
stabili express the same extract from
and now they have that approved for
autism in in Israel and that's that's
that's a label that's really specific to
a plant that's dialed in and making a
particular whole plant extract and I so
I see that that model kind of emerging
is people find certain plants that work
for certain conditions it's going to be
faster to clone that and protect that
plant and make the the the extract that
way then to figure out the complicated
networks inside of yeast and try to make
yeast mimic the exact you know recipe
that the plants making for that
particular condition so I kind of see a
couple different things emerging but I
don't really have a good crystal ball
and which one's gonna be most affordable
well and it's interesting you said that
that was gonna be my follow-up question
is you know if if we were to move
towards you know having yeast create
these single compounds what does that
mean for the whole extract community
because I know that there's there's a
healthy debate between between the two
of you know whether or not the future of
cannabis medicine is the single
compounds or whether it's a combination
and I imagine that'll be a source of
debate and conversation that will
certainly be taking place that can
this year yet no indeed I think it's um
maybe people are starting to see that's
it's a bit of a false dichotomy to think
it's gonna be either-or they're likely
answers it's gonna be both and it's
gonna depend on certain niche conditions
in each of those those marketplaces
certainly the FDA route is more tuned
for single compounds but we have seen
the story before in cannabis every time
we isolate a single compound the
efficacy seems to go down and we don't
know why
so the it makes for cleaner science it
makes for cleaner studies it makes for a
more comfortable FDA process but for
those who are looking at this as you
know a wellness product or something
that is OTC and less FDA involvement we
may have the freedom to actually
fine-tune these extracts but I think
these whole plant extracts really do
need a lot more in a little whoo
chemistry done than what we're currently
doing on them we are monitoring maybe a
dozen cannabinoids and it doesn't her
penis but we really are not paying any
attention to the flavonoids you know and
a lot of the other compounds that that
could be in this plant that are playing
a role that is something that I think we
definitely need to up our game on if
we're gonna continue to push for this
whole plant extract approach absolutely
and one of the things that you've said
so much during this conversation is it's
early and we don't know yet and I got to
imagine that's got to be one of the
reasons why you decide to put the
Jamaican lion information and so much of
the information that you've put together
public so that you know you can almost
crowdsource this information and kind of
accelerate our understanding of the
plant
yeah it's I've been through the story
before the you know when we sequence the
human genome it is one of these
scenarios where it unleashes so much
information into into the world that no
single company can possibly comprehend
at all and so you're actually held back
by trying to hoard the data the more
eyeballs that look at it the more other
things are discovered and advances we
all we all build upon each other's
knowledge base here knowledge is
cumulative right so getting data public
is has been extraordinary helpful we've
already seen multiple people publish off
of the Jamaican lion reference before we
did
because they were at a stage in research
where we were the last piece of the
puzzle and their research had filled it
out and they're able to publish some
really meaningful results while we were
still trying to get the publications
ready for for peer review on entire
genome so it's really important the data
is out there public because this allows
it to float all boats and even if it's
your competitors boat it's going to help
you maybe hard to see at first but it
does happen so there's a few those
publications out there you can look at
there's a proteomic map I've been
wearing a lab that was that was
published there's some work from Keith
Allen on the terpene synthase genes and
Jamaican line that was published there
was a recent review article with Nolan
Cain's lab that was reviewing a lot of
the genomes that has looked at Jamaican
line I will caution folks so there are
three different main publications we
have done there's the earliest work we
put out instantly and October 1st and
2018 on this and that those are some of
the more I'd say though the earlier
draft genomes that we have this recent
publication in January of 2020 has some
updated sequencing on it that has I
think it improved the contiguity to
assembly about fivefold and it's better
annotated now we have the annotations of
all the genes because we did RNA
sequencing on there and if you want any
of the bleeding edge stuff that's going
on the assemble phone is all public
these are uh Nana tainted references but
they're the highest contiguity
references that I've ever been generated
you can see full-length telomeres on
these things which is really remarkable
we've never been able to see those
before and that's kind of where the
folks who want to play with the latest
and greatest are jumping on the the
assemble thon data excellent and I know
that you've touched on it throughout the
conversation but I was wondering if you
might be able to kind of summarize what
does all this work really mean for
healthcare providers or cannabis
patients why should they be excited
about all this work being done in
genomics well I think we're gonna get
it's gonna solve some of the
nomenclature issues many patients will
know that this strain particularly you
know works for me I don't know why it
seems to have the same THC level is the
next one but that one gives me a
headache or have some other adverse I
get sleepy some other adverse effect
happens so and then when they move state
to state they
necessarily rely on that same strain
name to get them the same response and
so once we start getting genetic
signatures across all of these things we
will begin to change the nomenclature
from being you know this is a sativa or
an indica and this one's going to give
you couch lock and this one's going to
be uplifting I mean that those those are
all associations on taxonomy that
doesn't exist and so we really need a
genetic taxonomy system so we know and
we can solve this sort of strain
specific whole extract market if you
will the other thing I think it's going
to do is it is going to enable people to
look at the genome and do different
things and think ok we have problems
with too many males and open fields and
the feminization process were afraid of
how do you solve that problem some
people might want to put markers in the
white chromosome so they can easily
detect males and remove them more easily
than doing perhaps genetic tests one
concept people have been throwing around
is putting a green fluorescent protein
on the Y so they can run drones over
fields and image them for the ones that
might be expressing in a certain
wavelength crazy idea but it would
probably work don't know if it's
economical but there's ideas like that
that weren't generated in our hands
they're just ideas that have emerged in
the community ever since there's now we
have a white chromosome when we know
what to target I think we're going to
see the same thing and modulating some
of the cannabinoids and modulating some
of the other compounds in the plant that
are lowly expressed many of the
cannabinoids and face genes we believe
have been bred into near extinction
because we had one biomarker we could
test for and that was THC people could
smoke cannabis and know that we were
breeding in the right direction but we
now know that the biochemistry involved
in the plant means the expression of one
cannabinoid is a bit of a zero-sum game
the precursors are all competitive and
so when you breed from one can have
annoyed you lose the other so
prohibition is probably bred many of
these rare cannabinoids into New York
station and we need to rescue them and
the genomics is going to lead to a map
on how to rescue those and I think
that's where I will see some of the most
exciting work that next year now that's
really interesting you touched on that
because I had kind of been wondering
that myself is that you know is there a
future where some of these minor
cannabinoid
to actually become major cannabinoids in
plants I think suck it up I think there
is and I think it's important while
we're doing that breeding we take a
holistic picture we look at all of these
other pathogen response genes to make
sure we're not sacrificing yield or
pathogen exposure to grab one of these
cannabinoids we're we're actively in the
space of monitoring the microbiome of
the plant we make a lot of the testing
kits out there that look for Aspergillus
a coli and Salmonella and powdery mildew
and a variety of these of these common
endophytes that are in the plant so we
think this is a really important space
we really need to understand the
microbiome of the plants in order to
make sure we can produce the right
amount of compound with the least amount
of patient exposure and you can't really
grow these plants like a boy in a bubble
it's not how they operate they really do
need symbiotic rate relationships with
other microbes they just have to be
microbes that aren't pathogens to humans
and so that process I think is going to
be more than just genomic driven it's
gonna be microbiome and genomic driven
and you need both tools to really I
think skin that cat all right Kevin
we're coming up to the end here it's
always fascinating talking to you about
these things if people want to learn
more what are the best ways to learn
more about what you've been talking
about today well there's a lot of the
Jamaican line data is an NCBI NCBI there
is a high friction to get data in there
so it's always probably three to six
months behind what you can find on our
website our website has the assemble
thought on it and a lot of the data
links to a lot of the data there so if
you can't find at NCBI make sure to
contact us or comb through a website we
can get you early access that data there
I'd also keep an eye on the Koji genome
browser that we have we have a couple
tutorials online teaching people how to
play around with that koji genome
browser this has now it has 47 whole
genome shotgun samples that are in there
so that's that's that's got hemp lines
that's got typed for lines it has
hermaphroditic wines it's got th cv
lines in it it has just a wide array of
different cannabis plants that are now
whole genome sequence in public for
everybody to use
and it also has a trio of Jamaican lion
samples it's got a male and a female and
an offspring enough Albin de novo
assembled so it's a really good resource
to take your sequencing data
made from any platform and spread it in
there so if you've sequence somewhere
else you can find ways to take that data
and align it against the Jamaican Lyon
references so that you can compare it to
all this RNA data and whole genome
shotgun data from other organisms so
that's becoming a really nicely and
heavily used tool so people can search
this stuff and then likewise other we've
got a lot of content on our on our
facebook page and on our web site
regarding one of the pathogen work that
we're doing we are having some great
success cloning enzymes out of the plant
that are we believe are responsible for
some of the resistance of these molds
and expressing them in other organisms
like e.coli so that we can make cannabis
proteins that we know fight off fungi so
we think that may turn into a really
interesting direction they're kind of a
green chemistry for pesticides that
don't have to don't generate small
molecules that are rich in extraction we
want to go enzymatic here so we can make
natural cannabis peptides that destroy
or attack fungi and do not enrich or
cause any risk in the extraction process
and contaminating oils so that's a whole
new kind of green chemistry field that
we're looking at excellent a lot of
things going on we love it any any
closing remarks about km and
specifically I think it's gonna be a
banner year I know there's a lot of
right now there's been a lot of
nervousness over the koban crisis that's
going on we are still planning can med
are we've been playing close attention
to that pandemic and in fact we've even
built ourselves our own little Kovac
test here for employees so we're not
taking it lightly but we do sense
there's optimism in the air and that
this will pass and that some of the
compounds that are coming to play here
are showing some promise and that the
the testing rates that we're seeing lead
to a little bit of optimism there is a
there's a high number of patients out
there that don't have this or or the
antibody tests are beginning to show I
have some immunity so we do we don't
think this is going to stall can med
or delay it we actually think that we're
gonna be around this corner by
summertime and that the conferences will
then cisu manned and we'll need them by
then because so many have since been
canceled so keep keep the data open for
can med we think it's still gonna go
live and we think it's gonna be a banner
year great way to close it out
thanks again Kevin all right yep take
care of em thank you
[Music]
well I hope you enjoyed my conversation
with Kevin I'm included some links in
the show notes to read more about the
work that he's doing and to view some of
the presentations that he's done at
prior kin met events you can find those
videos and the videos of all our
previous presenters at Ken Med events
com
and while you're there don't forget to
purchase your ticket at that special
four hundred and twenty dollar rate it's
only good through 4/20 so buy it today
and be sure to check out our next
episode where I sit down and talk with
dr. Ethan Russo dr. Russo is a
board-certified neurologist specializing
in child neurology his interest in
medicinal plants led him to incorporate
cannabis into his practice and his
research since then he has authored
several books and articles about the
endocannabinoid system and we are so
excited to have him as a keynote
presenter at km ed 2020 that episode
will drop April 15th but if you
subscribe to our feed it'll download
directly to your device
and please also go to Ken men events
calm to sign up for email updates so you
can be entered to win a pair of tickets
to our VIP dinner and please also follow
us on Facebook Instagram and Twitter
at can net events well until next time
bye bye for now
[Music]