[Music]
welcome to the can med coffee talk
podcast will be talked with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing who will
be part of the kam med 2020 conference
in Pasadena California this September
20th through 22nd on this episode we get
the chance to talk with our first
representative from the safety focus
area in yah Thea is the scientific
director at canna SAF labs one of the
largest cannabis testing labs in
California if you aren't familiar with
what exactly goes on at a cannabis
testing lab you're likely in the
majority as I mentioned in my
conversation with any the cannabis
testing labs are sort of like the unsung
heroes of the cannabis industry they
serve a very important role in ensuring
consumer and patient safety but they
rarely get recognized for it during our
conversation
Annie and I discussed the types of tests
labs perform in California what
challenges they face being in a
regulated market and how they balance
keeping customers happy with also
keeping consumers safe so by the end of
this episode you will hopefully have a
much better appreciation for cannabis
testing labs we also get into the
testing any has performed on the
ingredients in vaporizer cartridges in
the wake of last year's vaping crisis
we're excited to have any as a can met
presenter this year and we are also
fortunate to have him as a member of our
advisory board he along with the other
advisors review all the abstracts that
were submitted and select the very best
to be oral and poster presentations at
the event our first round of abstract
presenters along with the preliminary
schedule will be announced June 3rd
which is just one week from when this
podcast goes live be sure to sign up to
our email list so that announcement will
be delivered straight to your inbox if
you sign up on our podcast page Kinman
events dot-com / coffee talk
you will also be entered into a drawing
to win two tickets to our can mid 2020
the IP dinner while you're at Kinmen
events calm be sure to also bye
your tickets to Kim at 2020 early bird
pricing is available through August 1st
now I know what you're thinking what if
the event is postponed due to Cove in
nineteen first rest assured that we are
working closely with the Pasadena
Convention Center to make sure we can
provide a safe environment for our staff
and attendees as of this recording the
event is still on but just in case we
have updated our refund policy to
provide a 100% refund to any ticket
holders in the event that we do
reschedule and the new dates cause a
conflict check out on our website for
details before we get to my conversation
with any I want to thank this episode
sponsor can a safe labs can a safe is
proud to be the first fully ISO 17025
accredited cannabis testing lab in the
world it is a full-service testing lab
dedicated to relentlessly championing
the safe cannabis and hemp movement
learn more about canna safe at CSA
labs.com alright and without any further
ado please enjoy my conversation with
ania thea of canna safe labs
hey any thanks for joining me today
thank you for having me absolutely I'm
really excited to have a conversation
with you today because you come from the
testing side of the cannabis industry
and we deal a lot with the with the
testing labs here on the medicinal
genomics side and I hope you don't mind
me saying but I really feel like the
testing labs are sort of the unsung
heroes of the cannabis industry and I
was just telling ya a good bit and I was
just telling a colleague earlier that to
use a football analogy I feel like you
guys are like the offensive line of the
cannabis industry which unfortunately
means that if you're doing everything
right we don't hear about you guys a lot
but fortunately when when things go
wrong that's when we hear about the
testing labs which i think is really
unfortunate did you guys do a lot of
great where it can have a lot of great
contributions to the cannabis industry
but do you feel like my analogy is apt
it's absolutely spot-on you know it's
easy to pick at the negatives when
things do go wrong but forget all the
positive and here long hard work that we
put in to ensure consumer safety
absolutely and I first some context any
it is of course the scientific director
at canna save labs out there in
California and there's a lot of there's
a lot of cannabis labs out there in
California I think I was reading an
article that said there's there's about
33 licensed labs in California so it
seems like a pretty pretty competitive
market out there how do you guys guys
navigate that yes definitely
probably a lot more now you know Cantus
aid isn't a lab that just began
yesterday we've been the business for
quite some time now on the third was a
smaller lab being the first lab to be
ISO 17025 accredited in cannabis sort of
sets us apart and we simply took off
from there and continuing down that path
of you know being the go-to lab in the
space or being the industry tiny
so the name the branding itself is sort
of I guess you could say sets us apart
you know when you think of going to the
store you can think of Target Walgreens
although there are many other drugs or
she could go to but apart from that
we've upheld the scientific excellent in
the industry and we've been on the
forefront of every breaking news and and
and whatnot and new mekin development
you know that's allowed us essentially
be able to keep the market share
excellent then you mentioned you were
the first ISO certified lab in the
cannabis space
lettre yes back in of about 2011 yes we
were the ISO 17025
first item to notify created lab in
cannabis you know calling up the
creating body and saying hey we want to
get a credit for cannabis wasn't an easy
easy feed you know they just kind of
laughed like really and this illegal
stuff I mean given that I wasn't we
counted at the time but just being able
to eventually get that accreditation
kind of paved the way for even that
industry to realize hey there's another
sort of niche here that we could tackle
and and and kind of it helps legitimize
the whole industry yeah I was gonna ask
what that conversation was like being
the Pharaoh oh yeah you know from what
I've heard they pretty much laughed at
the call hi what you wanna steal credit
credit cannabis what did what do you
mean you know at that point it was
mostly potency and a couple of
contaminant assays and canapes in in
Murrieta California was owned by you
know well respected sciences and and he
wanted to help legitimizing business
industry from the beginning
eventually the creating body called us
back and decided to give it a shot after
some convincing that the lab is a
legitimate lab and not just you know
another cannabis storefront or something
so what's a typical day like a can a
safe labs oh well
you know you come in and hit the ground
running Janice's labs being you know the
number one market shareholder in the
space it's very busy
we have a variety of staff groups I mean
from our marketing to Account Executive
to the samplers with a fleet of car and
then of course the lab staff there's
admin staff we employ over 150 people in
this space so it's quite busy so you're
constantly going around making sure that
this machine is well-oiled machine is
running smoothly of course that's not
always the case
with any business but we put people in
strategic position to make sure that
everything's being communicate
effectively and of course our customers
come first so we have a huge customer
service team that we are constantly in
contact with to make sure they are
getting their needs met and I sort of
you know bouncing between all those
areas to make sure that you know
whatever wherever I meet it I'm there
excellent so how many samples do you
guys manage the process with you know
150 people working what I imagine is
probably around the clock yeah we're
pretty much working around the clock and
I mean up all of those 150 people
probably about half of them are actual
analytical lab staff and the rest are
cells and other ancillary positions but
you know it's we know without giving up
the exact number it's quite a bit we're
in the hundreds well anywhere from 100
to 200 samples a day yeah and then you
mentioned when you guys first started
that it was mostly potency and a few
contaminants but I know that the
regulations in California have gotten
quite more stringent since then so what
is sort of the battery of tests that an
average sample needs to go through oh
yeah so of course back in early 2000
yeah it was really no regulations up
until about two three years ago when the
real regs
with creation of the DCC and and
Lucretia but we're talking about potency
pesticides
terpenes if appropriate the contaminant
assay such as heavy metals microbial and
when we're talking about micro we're
talking about that a specialist species
a sugar toxin producing e.coli and
pathogenic Salmonella there's water
activity tests and also moisture on
flour residual solvents as well so a
typical flour would have to go through
essentially those complete battery of
cat and have to pass the stringent limit
to be able to be put on the market
excellent and what percentage give or
take do you think actually gets through
and gets to the Shelf how many samples
are you are failing well you know it's
funny cuz we've been doing some trending
data which we'll be putting out shortly
we've already put some out but looking
back at the canna save as it exists
today in LA when it was open back in the
beginning of June January of 2018 or so
and you know about a quarter of the
product I were coming through him or
were failing for a lot of exercise and
and whatnot so it was a learning period
for people who had to now come into the
light and and learn to deal with this
regulation they had to learn which
decides not to use and how to grow
without them so products were selling
about 1/4 to 1/3 but recently you know
not an exact figure but there's about 10
percent failure rate for you know the
various assays so the manufacturers have
really learned an upper game to be able
to grow cleanly without pesticides or
pathogenic organisms and also without
introducing things like heavy metals
which generally bait cars would fail for
mostly because of hardware well so
that's great so that things are trending
in the right direction the manufacturers
are getting better it's good to hear
yeah the manufacturers are definitely
getting better you know we've been
leading that effort in education making
sure that you know instead of just
failing somebody we're helping educate
the whole community will have educating
our clients how to better produce clean
products and avoid some of the pitfalls
we've seen yeah I'm glad you mentioned
education because if anyone follows can
a safe on social media you'll see that
you guys are very dedicated to to
educating the market on you know whether
it be testing or just the science behind
cannabis and its really great follow so
if you're not following canna sakes
definitely definitely do that because
you guys are putting on some great
content yes sir thank you very much for
that yeah we've been making sure that
our community we have a very big social
media presence element ensure that
community is well informed
after all the regulations do not work is
people are not following them or people
don't know what to look for making sure
you're educated about you know asking
about certificate of analysis and what
sort of contaminants should you be
looking for in your canvas products you
know especially for people with certain
conditions who should not be ingesting
certain contaminants so just making sure
that a well that you're well informed
consumer not just a consumer but the
manufacturers like I spoke on before I
think it's a very important aspect of
this community in that in order to let
you know in our for all boats to rise in
the tide and come into the light we have
to be well informed yeah I think that's
so right and and as far as educating in
the consumer you I mean we have to
remember that a lot of these consumers
aren't just consumers their patients and
like you alluded to there's certain
considerations they need to to take
whether they're immunocompromised or
have some other vulnerabilities that
they need to really be aware of what's
in their product and make sure that it's
tested and performing in the right way
yes indeed and you know there's
something I strongly believe in and that
all labs in this industry all kind of as
lab should be joining efforts to make
sure the consumer is protected to make
sure that
we are all on the up and it's very
important like you mentioned for
immunocompromised individuals who are
using this for cancer therapy or whatnot
you know you when you ingest cannabis
there's different routes of
administration so while some of this
contaminants may be higher level in
other food products I chances are you're
inhaling certain chemicals and you know
that not enough has been studied about
it to be able to speak on whether that
rat administration is more detrimental
or not but one thing we know for a fact
is if it's not going to register system
chances are it is more detrimental data
then not so it's important that people
are aware of that yeah especially when
so much of the the narrative that's out
there about cannabis is how its how safe
it is because when you're really looking
at you know THC or CBD and how there's
never really been an overdose of these
compounds you assume that
oh it's safe I don't need to worry about
it but like you said there are these
additional contaminants that could be
present that you really need to be aware
of and that's why labs like yours are so
important yes indeed absolutely and one
of the things that was recently in the
news
was the whole issue with with the vape
crisis or the veep situation and I know
that you and the folks at canna c4 doing
some research into that I was hoping
that you could share what you found yeah
you know when the vade crisis broke we
jumped on it because there was a big
consumer concern people were coming to
our say what do you suggest where can we
go what do we do so we jumped right on
it to continue to instill that consumer
confidence in the industry and make sure
that the whole industry is not taken
down by a few bad actors and you know we
went in to the quote-unquote black
market and purchased product and started
doing the testing ourselves before the
CDC was able to verify that it was
vitamin you have to say you know I
quickly jumped on instruments and
developed the assay to look for vitamin
yeah
it you know it was quite surprising
quickly finding out in our first set of
assays that first set of testing that
there were huge levels of vitamin E and
E acetate in this product over 50% in
some cases so people were just
unscrupulously cutting the product with
just you know
thickening agent or whatnot and not only
that but there were high levels of
several pesticide along with you know
not actually meeting labeled THC claimed
most of these products were labeled 80
to 90 percent THC but you only found
that they contain about 10 to 20% while
the majority of it was vitamin D acetate
and other cutting agent and contaminant
well yeah that's that's certainly scary
yeah and you know it was really
unfortunate after that first set of
acids we really decided to dig a little
deeper and go into what else
may we be able to find in these illicit
products and actually compare them to
legal product as well and we looked at
things like some other cutting agent or
you know what they set of temperatures
and flavors and even other contaminants
such as metals running more of a full
scan type of study onto what other what
you would refer to as a harmful or
potentially harmful contaminants such as
carbonyls so we did a lot of work on
that I don't know these indicate they're
out there yeah I did get a chance to
review it before we before we jumped on
the call here but I mean I guess it's it
shouldn't be a huge surprise that you
know the black market products not going
to be as safe as things that are going
through your lab but I mean especially
with the with the vape cartridges it
being sort of a a newer form of a newer
delivery system for the product it's
certainly introducing a lot more
variables a lot more dangerous
contaminants consumer you mean you're
completely right it shouldn't be a
surprise honestly I do not believe that
characters that were put in this product
out there had ill intent I think it was
lack of information lack of research
lack of I don't know a scientific study
because people will be thinking oh it's
vitamin E of course it is useful it's a
necessary nutrient and people uses all
the time topically ingesting it but
nobody thought about the fact that hey
what about inhaling this what could it
possibly do and you know these people
were finding good way to cut corners of
course they were putting humans Lyman
Allies at risk by using pesticide Laden
product you know but as far as the
vitamin E acetate I do not believe that
that was ill intent definitely the
pesticides and and and other
contaminants that were in there could be
seen as such yeah well another thing it
did was it really highlighted with
another thing what we probably all know
is that the black market is still out
there and still thriving and I don't
know what do we do to sort of try to
reduce that let's put you on the spot
yeah it's hard because it's more of
grayish so there's the black black
market quote-unquote and then there is
the auther market which are just let's
say the non-legal market these are
people who've been in the industry I've
been doing things right and haven't
acquired a license yet and have to
continue making a living right so
they're making great products and
putting it out there they just don't
have a PCC license or whatnot that are
probably in the process of getting that
license and of course there's those
folks that just want to do whatever they
can to make a quick buck in their
kitchen and cut with whatever they can
so I think you know definitely getting
people as a license as quickly as
possible
for those that are trying to get license
is key for the state to make sure that
that's done as efficiently as possible
and then really going after the bad
actors that are you know not in the
process of trying to get a license or
not interested in there that are just
cooking whatever in the kitchen you know
those bad actors have to be removed from
the scene
so it is tough to tackle that and sort
of see who to go after but I believe
that if the state does their best to get
people who are applying for license as
quickly as possible so that they can
come into the light and make sure that
you know they're branded well the
products are tested a company with a co
way it would really help the whole
industry but I think it's you know like
I'm saying I think it's more than just a
simple black markets more of gray areas
difference change in there yeah now it
is getting a license in California
particularly difficult I don't believe
it's difficult but I think there may be
some lack of efficiency in the process
in terms of how quickly people are able
to get license and even education on
what you need to do to get a license a
lot of people we found are still not
educated on the licensing process which
that's the unit to take how you know
what what municipalities are accepting
licenses or there is a lot of lack of
education out there for people being
able to acquire licensed licenses
quickly and efficiently so I think that
has to be tackled first excellent well
while we're kind of on the on the topic
of you know the regulated market you
you're your business being a testing lab
is definitely dependent on on different
regulations and we mentioned before that
California recently came out with with
regulations with the BCC a few years ago
where before there weren't many so what
are your feelings on sort of what you're
required to test is it is it enough
would you do you think it's overly
scrupulous kind of what are your
thoughts well you know I thoroughly
believe that regulations make the world
go around you know people may may whine
at speed limits but you know they're
there for a reason and it makes us all
safer now interestingly I joined
cannabis in
directly in a highly regulated market so
I joined Canada's back in about 20 2013
2014 in Nevada when they just introduced
a set of regulations that pretty much
all states are followed on afterwards
you know federal regulations
encompassing pretty much what California
has so I don't know any worse than that
you know so for me I thoroughly believe
in the current regulations there are for
certain things that California did a
little differently that I don't
necessarily enjoy for instance the
packaging so California says you have to
test product in its final packaging okay
that's great to keep people in line
however what they don't realize is we're
looking at things like babe cards so you
have to acquire up about 0.35 percent of
a certain amount of bait card based on
batches you know that's just an estimate
but generally hundreds of cards based on
whatever batch the manufacturers
produced so for anything if I go to pick
up a sample and the manufacturers
produce you know thousands of vape cards
I may have to pick up hundreds of the
card and I have to come into the lab and
open all of those you know these are
fused together they're metal pieces that
you have to crack open they're all in
their packaging and they're cardboard
boxes they all contain lithium batteries
or nickel bars or whatever and it's just
a whole amount of whole lot of waste
that happens so now you have to worry
about recycling the batteries from the
date cards recycling the metals throwing
away the cardboard boxes you know if
we're caring about the environment here
this is not really the way to go about
it so we produce a ton of waste in the
lab just because we're sampling final
product packaging I think that's one
piece of legislation eyes I wish could
be redone in a way that you know you
have to track and trace it and use it
well so that we can sample if you're
making vape cards you have a gallons of
oil the lab can go and sample that
finished
that point and do the testing and then
the manufacturer can still afterwards
but having them fill and then having the
labs and all this effort and introducing
all this waste you know it it's unlike
California so I'm surprised at that
piece of legislation Wow and that's
that's going to be a huge risk for the
manufacturer as well I mean to basically
go through the entire production process
of packaging everything that with the
reality that it can potentially fail and
you just have to scrap all of that
that's gotta be currently it happened
quite a bit where they've gone through a
testing and actually fell then you know
now they're having to sort of recollect
their products from those bodies you
know Tara boxes open up trade cars and
recollect the product and maybe try to
remediate it but that's why we try to
educate our clients in in R&amp;D testing
hey get it tested immediately so that
you know what you're getting into
did your hard work says that because
what has happened is you can sample that
finished product and explain and then
you stick it into some bad hardware and
metals are leaching into your final
product now so now you found out that a
after I packaged ten thousand eight cars
they're now all failing for lead because
you put it into untested cart so again
part of education is working with our
clients on making sure every piece of in
process material is tested so they can
get to a final clean product without you
know any surprises yeah that makes sense
and I suppose that's sort of a sort of a
vote for protesting that final product
like you said that you know once you
introduce it into packaging or you put
the oil into the vape car you could be
introducing some new contaminants so
yeah I make sense it would be important
for the manufacturer to kind of be
testing multiple times throughout the
entire process so they can kind of
really zero in on where the potential
failure point could be it is important
that you know some manufactures may say
well why would I spend all this money
you know doing all those in process
thing well you think about what kind of
money will you be wasting to remediate
or the kind of losses you'll be taking
if you do sell solely it's in
everybody's that interest to make sure
that you type in proxy material
excellent and so you mentioned that you
you got into the cannabis space in 2013
what we what were you doing before
cannabis what was your pre cannabis life
like pre cannabis life I was working at
a few pharmaceutical companies including
Berg and Abbott Labs and life
technologist and right before cannabis I
was actually in nutraceutical at a
vitamin manufacturing company in Las
Vegas Nevada and you know it was
enjoyable I guess I've always been in
this trend of I don't know what you want
to call it wellness so it was a next
natural jump you know yeah you know I
love to take vitamins to stay healthy
but I also recognize the benefits of
cannabis so I've always been in that
sort of industry and and the QC testing
part of those industries so jumping from
nutraceutical testing QC testing for
consumer safety to Q success in cannabis
consumer safety was right up my will if
you want to take them ya know it seems
like a logical wheel out sure gonna yeah
right up my wheelhouse right and so it's
interesting so how does the the safety
testing and QC differ in an adulterous
oota calor vitamin scenario as opposed
to cannabis like do they have
third-party testing labs that need to
test the product before it hits the
shelves in that space as well you know
it's funny because can a nutraceutical
or vitamin stage sort of a similar
problem that I think some cannabis is
now facing in that they had or let's
just say before before there were rules
in cannabis nutriceuticals were sort of
free-for-all before they became
regulated by FDA and other
and people could you know make vitamin C
in their living room have a label
printer and stick it on and sell it but
luckily the company I was working in Las
Vegas had an in-house testing lab which
is where I was working on but they also
send that part of a third-party testing
so they were doing potency and other
contaminants testing both in incoming
raw material and finished product
so it works similarly testing for the
efficacy the potency microbials and
heavy metals not necessarily pesticides
unfortunately but it can sort of
interesting to see how cannabis is
involved pads what you know industries
like nutriceuticals which i've been
around for quite some time where they're
at now the only difference is the FDA
does audit nutraceutical companies but
they do not in Canada right obviously
because cannabis isn't isn't federally
legal yet exactly but how do you see the
kind of testing landscape changing if it
one that that finally does happen you
know I believe it will be the same set
of rules
maybe different action limits for
different analytes but it'll become
federally regulated by the FDA you'll
now have the FDA coming in to audit your
processes not just you know whether
you're following your own SOPs but
making sure everything from top to
bottom you know your consumer complaints
and whatnot that you your marketing
practices I mean they audit everything
so I see it being a little more
stringent in that sense but as far as
what assays are actually being done they
will most likely remain the same or
similar but now do you feel like there's
anything that labs should be testing for
that they're just not testing for now
whether it be because it's not mandated
or the customer doesn't doesn't on it
mm-hmm you know
it depends which side you're looking at
because we know that cannabis contains
so many other nutrients phytonutrients
vitamins and and antioxidants it would
be nice to start to quantify those
things on the other end of maybe
contaminant assays I think it's well
covered as far as a contaminant assays
what perhaps expanding the pesticide
scope to be more open-ended you know
there are hundreds I think over 800
pesticides out there and you look at
California old testing 60 of them
granted there are no rules for
applications of any pesticides on on
cannabis and listen California but I
would like to see that expanded because
as III guess if I were a grower you're
telling me hey there is reggie's residue
limits for this 66
well there's hundreds more other
pesticide I think with maybe similar
functionality out there that I could use
that the labs would not be looking for
so in the end of the day in an effort to
ensure consumer safety it would be
better to expand that scope yeah it sort
of reminds me of that that documentary
or is it Icarus with when they're
they're testing for
performance-enhancing drugs that you
know as soon as you identify one you
come up with an assay and you start
testing for it then you know the
cheaters are just gonna get a choose
something else to pull the test so I'm
sure it's a cat-and-mouse game very
similar to the ethical of course and I
understand some people may not agree
with that statement my statement I was
expanding the scope but you have to
think about it is we're all about
wellness and consumer safety it should
not be a problem to expand that scope
the only people who would be really
worried about this are you know maybe
people who are doing someone's cooking
with things sure absolutely and you also
mentioned maybe expanding the difference
and ab annoyed Zoar terpenes that the
labs are reporting on are there any are
there any in particular that
that piqued your interest that you think
you know could be the next the next big
compound that these cultivators or
manufacturers are going to try to be
developing products around you know I
you know I know there was a recent
discovery of DHCP and or so but you know
it's such a residual levels of it it's
hard to say because they're a lot more
cannabinoids available in the plant but
there's such minut levels
it's almost inconsequential testing for
them until their efficacy is proven at a
certain level I may be more testing
around other side of nutrient so you
know vitamin K for example or certain
and camphor all some of those
antioxidants some anthocyanins which are
definitely available especially in some
of your more colorful varieties and
cultivars those would be useful and
finding ways that we can preserve those
or different routes of extracting those
whether it be fresh flower or whatnot
but there's definitely a lot of
nutrients that are being missed by just
sticking to a certain either extraction
are certain mode of use as an inhaling
right definitely another thing that
plant has a lot more benefit to offer as
a fresh plant
absolutely and you know to bring it all
back to can med that's why you know
that's why we're so happy with with the
model that we have here because we're
bringing together people from all
different sides of the of the industry
where we have sort of the research
scientists who are trying to discover
these lesser cannabinoids or our
compounds to see what sort of medical
efficacy they could have bringing that
information to the physicians or the
healthcare professionals who are
treating the patients but also bringing
it to the cultivators who may want to
try to develop some new novel strains
that are going to be producing these
compounds and then folks like yourself
who are
have to be developing the methods to
either test for those or if you're more
on the extraction manufacturer side how
do we extract those those compounds out
of the plant so we like to think that
we're bringing in all the people
necessary so that we can get the most
out of this plant so we can you can
benefit the patients Oh certainly
certainly and and you know last year 10
that I was really impressed with what
was happening with would I forget who
the main owner company is but I believe
roughly I'm a Coulomb is a partner in
that with her new discovery of sort of a
methylated cannabinoid that was found to
be highly more efficient or or useful or
by available I shall say then I took an
Abba know it by itself so I see things
like that happening simply adding a
methyl group an ethyl group to the
cannabinoid allows it to penetrate the
cell better or have more bioavailability
so those are really exciting Forks that
make this industry exciting for me and
you know make me glad to be in this
every day and see how people are
introducing this novel ideas that are
only gonna set us further apart as a
legitimate industry and medicine
absolutely it's certain it's certainly
exciting thing to be part of when you
realize that we're only really
scratching the surface of what this
plant can do not even yet I mean to even
look beyond you know pharmaceutical or
ingesting it but when you think about
hemp and all the possibilities that has
for you know producing textiles or or
different things like that so it's just
it's a really exciting thing to be a
part of and we're excited to have you
any be a part of can med this year I
know you're serving on the advisory
board and we're really excited to have
you out there Pasadena the September yet
here I'm definitely looking forward to
it you know it's one of my favorite
conferences there's a great variety of
talks based around medicine it's just a
high level
conference very few of conferences like
that so I always enjoy being at
candidates on the control to it
excellent well thanks again any for
taking the time and we'll see you out
there all right
thank you for having me on
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
any afiyah check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and please also
check out the canna safe website next
week we welcome our keynote presenter in
the cultivation focus area
Seth Crawford of Oregon CBD Seth and his
team at oregon CBD have applied
large-scale breeding techniques combined
with the latest genetic sequencing
technology to create some truly amazing
THC free varieties for the hemp market
if you've ever been curious about how
cannabis and hemp breeders create a new
strain you don't want to miss this
episode that episode will drop June 10th
two weeks from this one in the meantime
please go to Cadman events dot-com slash
coffee talk and sign up for email
updates that will enter you into a
drawing to win two tickets to our kin
med 2020 VIP dinner and keep you up to
date with all things can med 2020 if
social media is your thing you can find
us on Facebook Instagram Twitter and
LinkedIn just search for kin med events
and lastly if you are listening on a
podcast app go ahead and hit the
subscribe button so that new episodes
automatically download to your device
and if you want to leave us a 5-star
review that'd be great too
alright that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and be sure to come back for the
next episode of kid