[Music]
ah
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben amert i'm the
marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on the canned med
conference
every year head over to
cannemedevents.com now to learn all
about
our canmed 2021 event that will take
place
october 12th through 14th at the
pasadena convention center
in pasadena california and be sure to
get your tickets today at our special
early bird rate
while you're at cam at events.com be
sure to sign up for email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry-leading event
the best place to do that is on our
podcast page
which you can find in the main menu
under the media tab
you can also go there directly by going
to canmedevents.com
coffeetalk there's a sign up form on
that page
and if you complete it you'll be entered
into a drawing to win two
canmed2021 vip dinner tickets
on that page you can also listen to all
the coffee talk podcast episodes
in our archive including conversations
with keynote presenters
dr bonnie goldstein dr ethan russo
and seth crawford speaking of keynote
presenters my guest today is our canmed
keynote presenter in the safety focus
area
grace bandong grace is a scientific
strategy leader for eurofins
where she has spent over 25 years in the
food and supplement industry
specializing in contaminants analysis
and risk assessment
she has recently started applying that
expertise to the hemp industry
helping to establish contaminant testing
standards for the industry as a member
of many different trade associations
and groups including the aoac
the u.s hemp authority and the hia's
sampling and analytical task force
on this episode i speak with grace about
her experience in the food testing
industry
the need for better standards for
cannabis and hemp testing
what makes cannabis and hemp such a
difficult plant to test
how a risk assessment strategy can help
ensure safe products
and why safety and contaminant testing
should be done throughout cultivation
and production of cannabis products
before we get into my conversation with
grace i want to thank this
episode's sponsor eurofins eurofins is a
world leader in food
environment pharmaceutical product and
agroscience testing services
with 48 000 staff and 900 labs across
50 countries eurofriends offers clients
over 200
000 unique analytical methods learn more
at eurofins.com and finally this episode
and every episode of the canmed coffee
talk podcast
is fueled by the hemp and coffee
exchange
hemp coffee is a healthy delicious
natural product
rich in trace minerals and nutrients
providing sustained
energy without the crash of regular
coffee
for more information check out
hempcoffeeexchange.com
and use the promo code drinkhemp to get
10 percent off your purchase
okay without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation
with kmed 2021 keynote presenter grace
[Music]
bandong
good morning grace thanks for joining us
good morning ben
it's a pleasure
great to have you um here on the podcast
and also
as our keynote presenter at canmed2021
in the safety focus area
and um i have to admit that the safety
focus area is always a little
challenging for us to select speakers
for
because as you know we like to attract
folks from many different facets of the
cannabis and hemp world the researchers
physicians
nurses cultivators lab managers
and typically the safety and lab testing
topics are a little
a little too technical for some people
who aren't in that field
but i think the topic that you have laid
out is really applicable to everyone
because it's all about implementing best
practices to ensure product safety which
we can all agree is is very important so
i was hoping you
we could start today with you providing
an overview of your presentation
um yes i'd be happy to so what
we did um it's it's great that you
mentioned that
um you know your your audience is
usually in the safety side
um in the in the health area
nurses and doctors and then we come the
lab managers
because i i took this risk assessment
approach actually
from the um from the emergency response
system
or or from codex
where they um where you assess
if there's something that's happening
for example a disease or an exposure
is it likely to cause illness
or harm and so i use that
into um into looking at contaminants for
food safety
so what we what we did was because a
long time ago
i had somebody come to me and and ask um
i have 2400 ingredients could you please
tell me what i need to test as far as
contaminants and what i need to consider
on this 2400 ingredients
and i looked at them and i'm like um
i really have no idea and that's
probably going to take a long long time
and a ton of money for you to test
so then i on my research i discovered on
this process of
of defining risk and and then we ended
up being able to come up with a
process where you look at your
ingredients the materials you work with
and then you determine
which materials are high risk medium
risk or low risk and then you categorize
your ingredients
and then if since most people only have
a limited amount of money
to put to testing even though
safety is number one and quality
is to protect the consumers um
it will it helps them it helps them to
um focus their dollars
on the riskiest ingredients and and and
cover more
and do more for uh ensuring safety for
the consumers
wow 2 400 ingredients what was the
what was the product if you don't mind
me asking
the product was actually candy wow
their products were candy a whole series
of candy
and um and a bunch of chocolate and
and gum and it's something that's near
and dear to a lot of us
and especially me i love chocolate
so um i had to do a really you know
it was important to get that and that's
very common
in the food industry actually um they
have
a lot of ingredients that go into
um one little product
to before it goes into the shelf there's
a lot
of processes that that happens and
there's a lot of safety checks that need
to happen
before it makes it to the consumer
yeah that's interesting because you look
at the back of the label and
you certainly don't see 2 400
ingredients listed there
so is it just that there's other
ingredients involved in
sort of the processes that go into the
final product that don't have to be
reported on that label oh no the 2400
ingredients is that that entire
company's um
ingredients they have different products
no no no we
we don't want 2400 ingredients in a
chocolate bar
i was going to say i thought it was a
fairly straightforward thing there
yeah that makes it that makes a lot more
sense forgive me for that
no that's all right so as you said your
camera presentation is a lot about risk
assessment when it comes to contaminants
and in cannabis and in hemp products
so when it comes to those those products
in cannabis and hemp products
which do you feel have kind of the
greatest risk in terms of
contaminants um what do you mean
the products or the contaminants itself
uh
let's start with the contaminants so i
know that there's you know microbial
contamination heavy metals pesticides
residual solvents
um where do how do you kind of rank them
are they all
i mean i guess they're all pretty bad
well they're all pretty bad and but and
they're important but they're important
in different stages of the of the life
of what we call from from seed to
shelf so as we all know
um in the hemp world that hemp
is a phyto remediator which means
it absorbs things from the whatever is
in the soil
so from the well first of all you have
to start with good quality seeds
and um and there's not much of concerns
for contaminants there
once you get into the ground you start
the exposure
to contaminants and that's where the
risk is how likely is it to be there
and how likely is that is there to be
going to be multiple contaminants
present in
in in the sample or in that material
that you have
so in the beginning pesticides and heavy
metals are really important
because as you plant it as soon as
you're growing it that's really what you
expose
your hemp for even though the farmers
don't unnecessarily apply to
the apply pesticides
as they're growing except in really
emergency needs and
when there's an infestation or something
like that
the crops that were there before
some pesticides could have been used for
it and then
there are there's also the pesticides
that have
lingered in the soil from ddt for
example from 20 years ago
it just doesn't want to go away so it's
still there even at low levels
and then the heavy metals which are just
part of
the soil you know lead cadmium and
arsenic and sometimes
sometimes and then as you grow them
you use water you know to irrigate and
and you have to think about the
irrigation system what kind of
contaminants you're introducing and
those usually are
also pesticides and some synthetic
compounds that you introduce
as you um as you grow that so in that
early stage
um it's your focus is pesticides and
then
heavy metals and then you harvest it and
as you harvest it
then you get into the then you introduce
some of the micro
because of storage and um when there
when there's moisture and um
so the pesticides still you inherit the
pesticide
and then as you store them there are
still some air there are still areas
that
use pesticides or insecticide for
cleaning
in the material area where you store
them so you could expose it to them
and then micro uh microorganisms
start growing and then you can start
having problems um
if the storing is not proper
and there's moisture and then you take
that from the
from the material that you have and then
you get into processing it
and let's go to the extraction part as
you extract it
that's when you start introducing the
risk for residual solvents because
that's what you use
um to extract them and all that and
and the process and then as you clean it
up um if there's a high possibility
that residual solvents could still
remain
and sometimes mistakes happen in in the
extraction process
and it's not the right solvent or
something
it's things like that those are of
course extreme situations
and then as you go take your extracts
and you go into the
production of other products where you
incorporate your
extracts or your oils
you introduce other ingredients and as
you buy ingredients
and some of it like for example you
combine your extracts with frankincense
or um some exotic scents and
essential oils um you introduce a lot of
then you could go back to increasing the
risk for contaminants again
and the reason for the higher risk of
contaminants is if you're
importing ingredients from outside of
the united states
or you're you're taking ingredients
outside of the
intended market um geographical market
of your product
the laws and regulations
are different in other parts of the
world
to to ourselves for example in
in the food industry in the eu um
carbaryl is not allowed is has
no longer has a tolerance for grapes
or it's very low i think it's the loq of
the method
in the united states scarborough is
allowed at 10 parts per million
so you could be making a product that
you're getting from grapes here in the
u.s
and be perfectly comfortable that you're
then you find carburetor you'll be
perfectly comfortable here in the u.s
um because you're well under what's
allowed the 10 parts per million send it
over to
you and your product will be out of
compliance
because carburetor is not allowed there
and that happens
a lot back and forth for example for
apple juice concentrate
the methyl weight or methylate is
allowed in
brazil if we import here
into the united states the method weight
the tolerance for dimethylate in
apples have been has been revoked so it
now becomes non-compliant
even though it was compliant from where
it came from
but it enters here we use it it is not
compliant
so the regulations um
enter into that a whole lot
and it has to be taken that's part of
the risk
and so that's basically at the end and
then
and then when you when you bottle your
uh
so that's basically how you look at the
distribution of the contaminants
for for hemp anyway and so
you have to determine what you're doing
with it
where it's coming from and what's going
and all the other things that
when you have final product that's a
derived product
um what went into the product and where
all those things came from
absolutely so it seems that you know the
best practice really is to be doing
uh ongoing testing throughout the entire
um
life of the plant the life of the
product i mean i know that
so much of i mean on the medicinal
genomic side we work with labs and
provide them with microbial testing
technologies and you know that's really
at the
at the end stage of all of this so it's
the final product that gets tested
before it can finally go to sale
and i think that a lot of manufacturers
or
cultivators sort of think that that's
where sort of this the testing begins
but it sounds like um there should have
been a lot of testing going on before
then
yes because if you if you think about it
if you're making a product you know in
in in
we used to have i don't a long time ago
uh we used to have this saying um
in the food industry a lot a lot of my
years were spent with the food industry
that if you're testing the final product
by the time it's in the can
it's too late to correct anything
because
if you test your final product and you
find contamination
you already have thousands if not
millions of cans sitting out there
what are you going to do with those now
but if you create a practice where
you're tracking it from
especially because hemp is such as
although it's been in existence for a
while
um a lot of this best practices is new
there's not a lot of background data so
you don't know
really the predictability
um of having contact is is still not as
well said as is it as it is in some you
know
food matrices that in the food world
that we've been doing
like apples oranges you know the risk
and all the stuff
generally no the contaminant risk yes
so that was the long answer the short
answer to your question is yes
it is a good it is really good practice
to keep an eye on your
product from seed to shelf
and correct me if i'm wrong but that's
that's a difference between
at least on the cannabis side and food
testing where
i know in the us that
we have third party labs that sort of
test the the final product to
give it the stamp of approval before it
goes on the shelf but again correct me
if i'm wrong that's not really how
food testing works right it's more sort
of on the manufacturer
or the producer to do their own testing
am i do i have that right
um not quite because
okay glad i added we'd have to close
we'd have to close down our labs if that
was true that we're good
our food that's right so um
there are testing that um is
in the um in the manufacturing plants
that are necessary for them to do
um in in place um like their quality
requirements and they're usually fast
um fast tests but um
food companies you actually use um
third-party labs
um a lot because it is very expensive to
maintain your own lab
and they have um it's not only
the food testing laboratories uh the
food
testing are you they usually utilize in
the food industry third parties
i um define it for uh
for two things the things that should be
in food
and the things that should not be in
food and
they can't which means like your
nutritional label
your your approximates your fat
calories your vitamins that's the what
should be in food and then
my world which is which are the things
that are should not be in food
and those are the pesticide contaminants
heavy metals any other contaminants that
you
could think about and testing
it's it's the go-to is usually a third
party lab
because it is very like i said in the
beginning it's
very expensive to maintain your own um
lab in-house
and it does require a lot of equipment
expensive equipment
and highly trained people to be able to
produce the kind of quality
that we use the term defensible in court
you know when when you have you you have
to consider
safety and compliance and in the
contaminant side
they use this often because not a whole
lot of food companies
nowadays it used to be more
have their own testing labs
they've gone to the third party route
and and and people because sometimes
people think
that it's not really required to test
for you know pesticides
you take a risk you don't have to
there's no law that asks you to test for
pesticides or heavy metals
but that's actually not 100 true because
the law in the food industry says that
you cannot introduce adulterated food
into the system but then pesticides
and heavy metals are um are defined
by law as adulterants
so indirectly yeah you have to because
you cannot have adulterants in your food
so you have to test for that and um
third-party labs
are the way to go for a lot of companies
it is a lot
less it is makes
a lot more sense economically to use a
third-party lab
i see so maybe that's where my
misunderstanding
lied are laid
was with um but there is no kind of
strict law that says you must send it to
this lab and have them sign off on it
but it's sort of just a more broad
general
law that says you know you can't
introduce anything that's contaminated
and then yes um the way that they they
meet that mandate is to send it to a lab
like yours
so that yeah so that's the difference
they they they don't um
they they suggest methods and all stuff
but they don't dictate you to go to a
certain lab
like they have they should have these
registrations like
ta registrations and all that good stuff
got it uh and so to continue in sort of
this vein of comparing
cannabis and hemp to more traditional
food testing
how is cannabis and hemp testing kind of
different
than food testing just in terms of like
the matrix itself is it a more difficult
uh matrix to work with when you're
looking for things like this
uh it it uh more difficult would be like
an understatement
it's really complex um the
the plant material is very complex it
has a lot of
you know you have all those can have um
i'm i'm gonna speak about
um for contaminants because that's i
know that very well um it took us a long
time
like for example when you in food just
take an apple
apple is mostly 90 water
some sugar in there a little bit of
minerals
and it's nice and clean when you
when you inject it into a for example
when you do that your extraction
um you inject it into the mat uh
into a gc you get a nice long baseline
and if there's some pesticides the peak
comes up
because that's the method it's very easy
to
hemp on the other hand is like um
there's so many things you have to it's
it's like
um a field of grass that's what it looks
like
or it's like a field of where you're
going through a field of grass
whereas when you're doing apple you're
like walking on
paper that's the difference interesting
so it's very uh the matrix itself is
very complex and there
are um compounds that are
that are present in there that could
mimic they're very
similar to sometimes the pesticides
themselves
so you have difficulty in separating
them and
um whereas in in many of the food that's
established already
you could easily do a screen for 300 to
500 pesticide compounds
that is not the case for him it's it's
quite challenging
and especially if you have to meet um
iso standards then it becomes really
expensive
when you have to validate for testing in
him
yeah and in talking with other
other folks in the lab testing space one
of the things that they always come back
with
as being one of the major challenges in
in doing what they're doing
has has to do with standardization um
and i think the kind of the first thing
is kind of is in line with what you were
talking about was just having
good standards to work off of um
in terms of all the different
cannabinoids and things so how does
that sort of lack of standard make
things even
more difficult for you um it
it challenges it's challenging for
everybody because that is the
the basis of your ability to quantify
um your results so if you're
if lab a uses a standard
they're assuming that they're all the
same but for example um
cannabinoid a i'm just gonna do it in
general terms
a cannabinoid a um and lab a standard
is 99 pure
in that for cannabinoid a whereas lab b
um is when you finally look at it
the cannabinoid that cannabinoid a for
the reference standard for lab
b is 95 pure
then you have a four percent difference
in in
results and it will be consistent the
difference will be consistent
so unless and hopefully
unlike other materials
nist as reference standards and you all
know that this is
when when you you know you can you can
calibrate
to that material because everybody
agrees that that material
has this kind of concentration we
don't have many of that around
for the cannabis and hemp world yet
in the testing um pesticides is
different but in the cannabinoids
because pesticides the reference
standards are very well established
let's see and to sort of
continue that line on standards i know
that you're involved with
a couple different groups who are sort
of trying to
establish some standards sort of in
different areas
and i i guess let's start with um with
the us hemp authority
what are you looking at from a lab
safety perspective
in terms of i know that well let me
backtrack
um the us hemp authority is working on
kind of certifying
companies who are distributing hemp
products
so and i know you're involved with that
so what are you looking at from a lab
safety perspective when you're
looking to certify companies well
actually what they're looking to certify
is the
the the good practices from from
beginning to end
in different areas of the from from the
growing to the production
and so um basically because there's
not only the actual reference standards
but there's a lack of standards
itself on on how what you do when you
have this plant
you know how do you harvest it how do
you test it and what testing should be
done
and that's the the the goal i think uh
for me the usm authority the
certification program
is to standardize this and um and to
give
um those that are involved in the hemp
industry
a a good solid ground to look at
as far as what is what how do you
um work with within the the industry
you test the product and so that you can
ensure
a um high quality and quote-unquote safe
product for consumers out there and um
just a little plot the guidance three
the usm authority has just come out
actually with the guidance three and
it's out for public comment and it'd be
great if everybody could look at that in
in the amp world and um
comment on the guidance that um
because it was revised um especially
with the
um ifr that just you know after the ifr
came out
yeah that's great and i'd be happy to
put a link in the show description too
so
people can easily find that
and submit their comments so
how does sort of the certification or
the standards that the us hemp authority
is creating how would that differ from
what we hope eventually the fda will
come up with in terms of
of safety standards it's actually very
aligned
to um there there's there's
um everything that we did we hope uh
we purposely made sure that it's aligned
with
um the usda and and
all the uh and a lot of auditing
groups there so that um everybody has
the same standard to work
from so they're they're aligned and
sometimes the requirement of the
certification
is a little more robust in some area
and in other areas the uh
the usda is more robust although
if you have the hemp certification you
will
be meeting the the goal the goal is that
you're meeting the
usda requirements
right so you're sort of that's sort of
you're meeting it
and more right yes yes right
excellent and one of the other groups
that you're that you're working with and
it sort of
ties into some of these uh usda
requirements that came out with with the
farm bill is i know that one of the
groups that you're working with
is the hia's sampling an analytical task
force
for sort of coming up with standards
around sampling
and i know that that's that's needed
because
and correct me if i'm wrong here but
when those
standards originally came out for the
farm bill um there was
quite a difference between um the
sampling standards that they set out
there as compared to sort sort of like
some of the international standards that
have been
in place elsewhere outside of the u.s
so um i didn't know if you wanted to
kind of briefly comment on
um how the what the disconnect is
between those two
sets of standards and um maybe give a
glimpse into
what you guys are working on well
it's it's um it's always the same
problem with sampling
because it's statistics and it's very
difficult for people to come to an
agreement
on what uh really is the best approach
to sampling
and there are many many things to
consider like even just the idea of
sampling
um what part of the plants do you sample
um
to define that and how much percent
comes from
the top from the middle the bottom and
so that
uh that is um up for discussion because
there are always
many um many
points of view and um in the end what uh
and and it's like you know many ways to
skin a cat
and most of them are statistically valid
depending on how you
you look at them and so that's the aim i
think that's the aim of the
of the hia's sampling task force
is to come up with a not only
a relevant and a solid
a fit for purpose sampling plan but it's
also
not um not burden
and it's not it's not going to be a
burden for the
um the growers or the people in the hemp
industry
so you want to get that balance of the
fit for purpose
and the practica and the practical
aspect of the sampling so you you want
to marry them together so that we all
are happy
we can all do it and you know it's it
because if you make this
the sampling part is part is very is key
um because if your sampling is messed up
then it doesn't matter what you do
afterwards the testing becomes
irrelevant
if the sampling is messed up the
interpretation is
is is gonna be different so it's
important that
um everybody um that the
sampling portion is not so difficult
that people get discouraged and don't
follow the proper way of sampling anyway
so you want to marry that
practical and fit for purpose
well yeah it sounds sounds challenging
for sure
and i know that when i had spoke with um
i believe it was brianna cassidy who is
another lab manager who's going to be
presenting at canmed
um she she said that the difference in
potency
in one cannabis plant you know from one
blood
one bud to another can be vast it could
be as much as
50 difference plus or minus
which sort of blew my mind a bit so i
imagine that
that's something you need to keep in
mind when you're thinking about sampling
to try to get a true representation of
what
this plant really is yes we're dealing
with
we're dealing with an organic material
you know so it's it's it's very
difficult it's not uniform
the weather the amount of sunlight
two days ago or thing or where you cut
it so so many factors
um affect the uniform distribution
it's you know if you because if you
if you think about it it's like the
distribution of the cannabinoids
if you had like a whole basket of
blueberries
and you sometimes apply pesticides on
the surface or it's it gets mold
on the surface um
if you don't mix it properly and if you
don't um
quarter it portion it you could end up
just getting the top and a whole
bin a whole a whole load of of your
contaminant
but if you mix it then you distribute it
evenly and you
you you have a better representation of
the entire sample itself
and that's and that's really one of the
key things to consider
um when you're creating or
writing a standard for sampling and and
the plant material
is the hemp is a very
um challenging it's it's yes it's a
challenge
and every and hopefully we can all come
to an agreement on
because if everybody's doing it the same
way then
you know the um you have
um confidence that you'll all be getting
the same results
great and and finally i that's
kind of working down your resume here um
your involvement with aoac
as well and the casp task force uh i
wonder if you could tell us a bit about
what you guys are working on there
um the the the aoac casp
program is actually working on a lot of
different things
they have um they have
a group that's involved with the
mycotoxins and they have the group with
the cannabinoids
and the group that i'm involved in
is in the training and education so
there's a lot going on
and i think casp has uh they were the
one that
established the method for testing for
uh for
the potent uh the cannabinoid um the
concentration
the cannabinoid the thc concentration
and they so they're they're the group is
aiming to
um standardize the analytical testing
portion
and there is also part for sampling but
and they're trying to put that together
so hopefully the hia the aoac the usda
and everybody
could be aligned in their approach to
sampling
right i mean i guess that's one of the
challenges of multiple groups trying to
set standards is that
there needs to be some standardization
amongst amongst them as well
so just in closing here grace i don't
know if there's any closing thoughts you
want to have
or if you want to give folks either
your social media if you're on it or any
ways to get in touch with you
for any additional questions
prior to the event this is your
opportunity now um
well uh just uh the one thing that i
kind of always like to tell people is um
uh don't forget your contaminants
especially your chemical contaminants
because they
they they are important and you need to
to be cognizant that they
they are present and then you could
potentially expose your
consumers to contaminants and if
if you're not paying attention to them
and
um to contact me i'm on linkedin and
um i'm old school i'm kind of old school
so my email is on linkedin
and that's pretty much my social media
presence
that's nothing there's nothing wrong
with that you're probably healthier for
it
so um and so if
they connected me in linkedin i would be
able to get to it
all right excellent well thank you again
grace for taking the time and we look
forward to seeing you out in pasadena
as a pleasure thank you
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
grace bandong
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and please also check out our sponsors
eurofins
and the hemp coffee exchange our next
episode will drop september 30th
in the meantime please go to
camennements.comcoffeetalk
to sign up for email updates that will
enter you into a drawing to win
two tickets to our canmed 2021 vip
dinner
and keep you up to date with all things
canmed2021
you can also follow us on social media
we're on facebook
instagram twitter and linkedin just
search
for kim and events and lastly if you're
listening via a podcast app
go ahead and hit that subscribe button
so new episodes automatically download
to your device
and please leave us a five star review
as well
alright that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy
and be sure to come back for the next
episode of the camed coffee talk podcast
[Music]
you