[Music]
welcome to the can med coffee talk
podcast where we talked with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing who will
be part of the km ed 2020 conference in
Pasadena California this september 20th
through 22nd I am your host Ben Amer alt
I'm the marketing manager of medicinal
genomics and a proud member of the can
med 2020 team head over to Ken med
events dot-com to check out our phase 1
schedule which includes presentation
topics from 20 of our invited speakers
and abstract presenters we will continue
to add to this lineup throughout the
summer so be sure to sign up for email
alerts so you don't miss any
announcements if you sign up on our
podcast page cam at events comm slash
coffee talk
you will also be entered into a drawing
to win two tickets to our cam med 2020
VIP dinner on this episode we talk with
Brianna Cassidy who is the chief
scientific officer at CDX
analytics Brianna and the team at CVX
performed safety testing on all types of
cannabis samples including potency
pesticides heavy metals residual
solvents and microbial contamination as
you will hear from our conversation
brianna takes a creative and analytical
approach to solving problems that come
with testing cannabis products at cam at
2020 Brianna will share her process for
evaluating new analytical methods and
technologies for her lap as you can
imagine there are a number of vendors
looking to install their systems and
cannabis testing labs so it helps to
have a thorough and objective process to
choose the best option our team knows
firsthand that Brianna is thorough when
evaluating new technologies she and the
team at CVX provided data that was a
major part of the medicinal genomics
manufacturer validation document Brianna
and I also discussed the issue of
consistency when it comes to potency
testing I was surprised to learn that
cannabis flowers from the same batch are
often 50% more or less potent
than what's reported on the package she
also explained how water content can
make a big difference in potency results
we are excited to have Breanna as part
of canva 2020 and we are excited to see
you there as well go to cam at events
calm now to see our ticket pricing
options and get your ticket today we are
currently offering early bird pricing
through August 1st we are also offering
a 100% refund to ticket holders should
can med 2020 need to be postponed due to
kovat 19 rest assured that we are
working closely with the Pasadena
Convention Center to make sure that we
can provide a safe environment for our
staff and attendees and as of this
recording the event is still on but just
in case we have updated our refund
policy so please check out our website
for details I also want to thank this
episode sponsor the cannabis scientist
the cannabis scientists is a publication
with an important mission to promote
good science in our growing field
register for free on their website the
cannabis scientist comm and get
unlimited access to expert commentary on
testing extraction medical research and
regulation and finally we want to thank
our friends at the hemp in coffee
exchange for fueling the can med coffee
talk podcast the hemp and coffee
exchange is a grassroots Tampa based
Coffee Roasting Company creating
progressively sustainable consumables
combining two of the most genetically
diverse plants on the planet hemp and
coffee
check out hemp coffee exchange calm and
use the promo code drink hemp all one
word to get 10% off your purchase that
promo code again is drink hemp okay
without any further ado please enjoy my
conversation with Briana Cassidy of CDX
analytics
[Music]
hey Brianna how are we doing today doing
pretty well van yourself I'm doing well
thank you so much for joining us on the
podcast and as I always like the same
when I talk to people from the lab
testing profession I love getting a
chance to talk to you because we at
medicinal genomics we work with you guys
very closely and I know what you do on
the microbial side obviously because of
what we do at medicinal genomics but I
really like to talk to you about all the
other things that you test for at the
testing lab so tell me a little bit
about CDX your position there and what a
what a typical day is like sure first
off I'd like to say I'm honored to be a
part of the can med conference I'm very
excited to be presenting there so I'm
looking forward to that and my title is
the chief science officer at CDX
analytics and we test for a myriad of
different things in cannabis and
cannabis infused products of course the
cannabinoids the active ingredients
terpenes also possibly active
ingredients and then some contaminants
so we're looking at heavy metals
pesticides microbials mycotoxins and
then we have some disruptive technology
in the lab too in regard to our dry
weight measurement and accounting for
water content in samples Oh tell me a
bit more about that I had a feeling you
might ask you have good instincts yeah
it's it's important to talk about water
content because the reported
concentrations are supposed to be
indicative of how much what it is we're
seeing is in the dry weight of the
sample being tested and cannabis can be
around 80 percent water so if you don't
accurately account for that 80 percent
and subtract it out
the result from your very precise
analytical instrumentation could be
completely moot the suggested way to do
this by the American Herbal
pharmacopoeia is by loss on drying and
that's essentially taking the sample and
putting it in an oven for a certain
amount of time so that has some
implications that loss on drawing method
number one water desorption is a very
slow process and as you reach completion
it becomes slower and slower so if
you're to put a really wet sample in
alongside a very dry sample after the
same exposure to temperature and time
those two samples will still have
different water contents so the more wet
sample will still be wet and if you
don't account for all the water in a
sample you are going to artificially
deflate all of your analytical results
if you over account for water content by
possibly let's say baking off terpenes
and other volatile parts of your sample
assuming they're water but they're not
then you can artificially inflate your
analytical results so what we've done is
we've incorporated a technique other
than loss on drying we're using gas
phase Karl Fischer titration and what
this does is using a sub sample of what
we're testing we can figure out how much
reaction we get with the water content
in that sample using a chemical test and
simply subtract the water content out
using the molecular weight at the end so
this allows for an extremely precise and
accurate result for all of our testing
that we do on flour okay
so so if I follow that if I follow that
and I'm not sure that I did but that's
okay
so what you're doing is actually just
measuring the water content and then
kind of subtracting that out or applying
some kind of algorithm to separate that
out rather than trying to
make it to be 80% or whatever percent is
the recommended dry weight is that do I
have that right exactly so instead of
baking out the water content we test for
it chemically and then subtract it from
the result excellent excellent
now when you get so a consumer going
into dispensary and buying some flour
what is sort of the average water
content there does it vary between the
different buds or the different strains
or is it sort relatively consistent we
see cured bud coming in at around four
to ten percent water content by weight
okay that's a that's a decent range yeah
you know when you're talking about the
testing limits in Massachusetts where
we're quantifying down to parts per
billion levels that range has a huge
impact on the final result and now is
that specifically for potency or can
that apply to you know heavy metals and
other contaminants as well yeah it's a
good question
every single result that is reported for
a flower or plant based sample is
impacted by water content okay okay so
this all really seems to jive with the
article that I was reading that you and
Cindy Orser had authored that was all
about cannabis uncertainty and so and
how you know if you're taking a big
batch of cannabis and selecting
different sub samples of that to do your
testing the the difference in those
different sub simples can be pretty vast
and I imagine that this water content is
just another variable that goes into
that fair to say yeah yeah so that
article was a blast to write with Cindy
I think it's you know medicinal genomics
is great about this too is the
collaboration to talk about these
variables like
measurement uncertainty water content
you know why is it that people are
getting different results for what they
think is the same batch so those
discussions are really important to have
and yeah you're right that article does
encompass a lot of different discussions
on what can impact your test results and
so in addition to water content what are
some of the other things that can be
leading to this uncertainty problem is
it something that's just sort of a
necessary evil of testing something like
like cannabis flour or is it something
that there's not enough standards
between the labs combination of the two
or more yeah I mean you covered a good
bit of them but it is true to say that
any measurement that is taken whether
you're measuring a string with a ruler
or you're measuring the mana grams of
pesticide and one gram of flour both of
those situations are going to have a
plus or minus around the result so the
article that Cindy and I wrote goes into
some other variables that could be
adding to this plus or minus we already
talked about water content and you
briefly brought up testing different
buds from the same plant and how the
plant itself being inconsistent
throughout in terms of cannabinoid
concentration and possibly contaminants
does contribute to the plus or minus of
your result and the most efficient way
to mitigate that is to have homogeneous
batches of product meaning that they're
well mixed and that they are the same
throughout so that when a sample a
subsample of that batch is taken to a
laboratory the results for that
subsample actually represent the batch
itself now that's gonna be pretty hard
to do with cannabis flower though
because you don't want to you know take
a huge
a huge batch and grind it all up because
then you're gonna you know lose your bag
appeal lose those nice beautiful buds
that people are so interested in so how
do you how do you overcome that it's
difficult and you know instead of
overcoming it in an industry where that
isn't something that is altogether
possible you instead have to accurately
account for it and what I mean by that
is you know if one bud has a different
result than another bud then
understanding that when you look at the
label of your product of your cannabis
buds when you pull a bud from that
container to consume that that bud could
be plus or minus 50% or more of what is
on the label and it's you know that can
be alarming but at the same time knowing
that and understanding it is is just as
important as solving it Wow 50% that's
that's significant at Lee's especially I
didn't mean to cut you off but there is
a peer-reviewed publication in forensic
science International where they show
the test results of different plants
that are within the same clone and how
much the cannabinoid results vary from
bud to bud so that's that's an
interesting to look at interesting one
to look at if you're if you want to get
into it even further yeah and you know
I'm just thinking with with can med
being so focused on using cannabis as a
medicine that's going to be something
that if you are using flower to treat
your condition that's something you
really need to take take seriously so
you know what are your thoughts I mean I
know you're not a physician you're not
going to be giving out any medical
advice but in terms of patients who are
treating with cannabis flower what are
sort of sort of some things that they
need to keep in mind
you know it's first of all I appreciate
you recognizing that I'm not a medical
doctor philosophy is a completely
different deal I look more towards the
products that are available that are a
little bit more homogeneous meaning you
know liquids and it's you know they all
have their own inhomogeneity variables
related to them and until someone does a
test comparing the homogeneity of
cannabis infused products to
concentrates or extracts to flowers it's
it's kind of hard to to navigate that
question but theoretically I would
assume that liquid or cannabis infused
product based options are more
homogeneous than buds themselves right
but then then comes the whole problem of
you know consistency from batch to batch
or locked a lot which I can imagine can
vary as well just because of whether it
be sourcing the the material or changing
in production or things like that yeah
that's true and you know in with with
pharmaceuticals that's that's where I
come from as a pharmaceutical industry
the USP has very strict testing
requirements that have to be met in
order for a sample to be even considered
representative of the batch and those
tests into taking you know 30-plus units
and testing them individually and they
have to be within the same result in
order to actually move forward with with
that batch so I I do see the cannabis
industry eventually getting to the point
where they require homogeneity testing I
have seen clients that are
starting to undertake homogeneity
testing as just a precaution for their
business because what that does is it
gives them a snapshot of how consistent
their product is and it ensures their
clients the consumers of this product
that they can expect that the label
represents what they are consuming and
that it's consistent as well so it's
actually a big advantage to the
marketing of a product to go ahead and
undertake this homogeneity testing and
to shoot to create a more consistent
product yeah and I imagine that's where
we hope this is all going or is that the
the companies and the manufacturers will
do all this testing not because they
have to but because they want to or
because the customer demands it or
expects it so it's good to see that at
least some are already taking that step
and eventually everyone will get there
so you mentioned you came from
pharmaceutical testing and I'm curious
when you say that you know in the
cannabis space that the the difference
in concentrations can be up to you know
50% where is it that the pharmaceuticals
what percentage or what difference are
they really aiming for in terms of
consistency so with with cannabis I
think the 50% is gonna be a relatively
normal happening I think that the
concentration can be a plus or minus
more than 50%
just to clarify in pharmaceuticals
they're looking for they measure
consistency by a metric called relative
standard deviation and so there are USP
guidelines on it's called content
uniformity is the title of the document
where they give different different
relative percent differences based on
the product type and how potent it is
okay okay that makes sense I did want to
go back to you mentioned when we were
kind of talking about alternatives to
using maybe cannabis flour for treating
a condition that there are stiffer --nt
cannabis infused products out there
and I'm curious because you see all
different types of cannabis infused
products out there I'm wondering what
are the sort of the normal ones that
come through your lab or maybe some of
the not so normal ones that may have
come through your lab we see a myriad of
different matrices and we're not
generally surprised anymore we've seen
anything from infused drinks that market
is growing and we see a lot of infused
chocolate products a lot of infused
gummy products and more recently vaginal
and anal suppositories I mean it's the
list of products that we see in the lab
just is unending ya know it seems like
seems like every week every month
they're coming up with a new a new thing
to infuse cannabis into what is the most
challenging of the matrices that you've
had to deal with I would say be infused
drinks um
infused palmerston yeah you know infused
products in general require more astute
testing because they include ingredients
that could possibly interfere with the
test they could interfere with the test
by covering up the signal of the analyte
that we're looking for or we can't see
the cannabinoid or we can't see the
metal they could in few they could
interfere with the test in a way that
those ingredients hold on to the
Constituent that we're looking for and
keep it from being in the solution that
we're looking to test and to mitigate
that CDX has launched a
formulation test and what that is is we
actually go in and we work through the
sample in several different methods to
ensure that those things that that those
possibilities are mitigated so you know
cannabis infused products in general
where we're talking about literally an
infinite list of possible interferences
have to be taken seriously in testing
and you know in any instance where
anybody says that they have a one method
solves all process they just simply
haven't looked into it in-depth enough
to to find that there are variables in
these different cannabis infused
products that do impact their tests so
you basically put any new cannabis type
product through sort of a battery of
tests to sort of really break down
what's in there and what could
potentially be throwing off your results
right this is this is something that we
have been working with a few of our
clients in doing and this is actually
part of what I plan on presenting at kin
med so it's it's gonna be a
demonstration of how you know different
methods can give different results on
the same exact products and
understanding how to take that knowledge
and mitigate in order to report an
accurate and precise result what an
excellent segue so the yeah the title of
your talk here is navigating cannabis
method options through implementation of
novel validation design and statistical
comparison and you did just give a
little bit of a preview with about what
that talk is going to be about but it
it's wonder if you give us a little bit
more absolutely so we we have a lot of
different testing options as as
third-party testers in the cannabis
industry a lot of instrument vendors
have prepackaged methods and
instrumentation that can be used to
measure
the cannabinoid concentration or the
heavy-metal concentration or as you very
well know the microbial concentrations
and the talk is going to be about how to
choose the method that is most
appropriate for what it is that you're
doing in a quantitative and statistical
way because you know accurate science is
all about absolving subjectivity as much
as possible and looking at the data and
the relative standard deviations and the
robustness that's what's going to give
you the answer to which platform you
should choose to do your testing
excellent excellent
so what are some of the the different
methods or ocean say methods but what
are some of the different types of
testing that you are going to be sort of
highlighting in your talk is it more on
the the potency side heavy metals
microbials a little bit of everything we
find different avenues everyday that
we're in the lab so what I plan on doing
is choosing the ones that best
illustrate the need for a quantitative
decision making and right now it's
looking like that discussion will be
based on microbial testing there was a
little bit of a preview to this given by
Yvonne
she's already presented this last fall
with the the groom reefer and so you
know I might build on that a little bit
with the in lab testing we did its EDX
and the validation that we have for
inter laboratories but I have a lot of
different options in terms of what other
test methods I include could be a little
bit on the water content quantification
we talked about earlier comparing that
to the loss on drying method in terms of
precision and accuracy and robustness I
could talk about cannabis infused
products and different extraction
methods for cannabinoid testing and how
those impacts
the results it just goes on and on it's
such an exciting new industry you know
scientists have only had you know 2025
years to work with this matrix and it's
really fun to be a part of you know
battening down the hatches and coming up
with methods that consistently trump
what was currently in use days weeks
months or years before we're gonna have
to block off a whole afternoon for you I
don't know about that man you laptop to
AJ no but um it's I'm glad that you
brought up Grim Reaper in the talk that
Yvonne had given at kin med 2019 because
you did contribute a lot of great data
that was used in that we want to thank
you very much for that and if folks are
interested they can check out that talk
and all that came a 20-19 talks at kim
at events comm nice little plug in there
for that
so you mentioned what you did before you
got into the cannabis space a little bit
briefly but I was wondering a bit more
what did you do before you got into
cannabis and and why did you decide to
make the switch sure it's been a long
journey but just very quickly you know I
I have a chemistry bachelor's with two
art minors art history and studio art
after that I got my PhD in analytical
chemistry and during that time I worked
on a lot of forensic applications blood
detection blood stain age development
using different light based techniques
combined with statistical data analysis
to correctly classify unknowns a lot of
really fun stuff I also did
environmental sampling and testing and
from there I moved on to the
pharmaceutical industry where I worked
to identify the impacts different
formulation
have on active pharmaceutical
ingredients so essentially what I did
was keep track of what fillers in drugs
do to the drugs themselves and how they
impact the expiration date of the drug
so that work it turned out to be
incredibly relevant especially to
cannabis infused products and I'm really
excited to apply that but in getting
into the cannabis industry it was
something you know like I said it's so
new people really haven't had time to
mail down the testing methods and there
aren't they there weren't that many in
peer-reviewed publications and still art
on cannabis testing so that was very
lucrative to me I thought it would be
neat to be a part of something where
creativity paired with chemical
knowledge could be used to really give
back and have a high impact to society
so that's what I did
you know I worked at CDX analytics for
nearly a year with state of the art
brand new instrumentation designing
methods and I'm very grateful that the
president and CEO of CDX has a PhD
himself because I don't know any other
businessman that would give me that long
to come up with these methods but you
know the creativity I had from my art
background really did come in handy and
I was given the time to look into the
variables that impact test results that
really has given us an insight into the
industry today yeah I think that's
that's one of the things that we all
really love about the cannabis industry
is that it's such such a frontier you're
such you know fertile ground for us to
apply creativity and kind of innovative
solutions to really push this thing
forward so that's really interesting I
had no idea you had an art background
what what what specifically you painter
sculptor well like I said one of the
minors is in art history so looking back
you know all the different time periods
and what drove art and what what the
artists were thinking at the times that
they were creating the pieces that they
created but my studio art was centered
first on drawing and then on oil
painting excellent yeah we're gonna have
to Commission you to paint a mural for
us in the office well my husband is it's
funny I recently came home with
something that I did and he told me that
we couldn't have any more naked women in
the house so apparently I'm not supposed
to be doing the live modeling and in the
studios for a while but I still do keep
up with it and I do really enjoy it okay
thanks
well yeah I'd have to check with HR to
make sure we could bring that into the
into the mural but not hold my breath I
saw the picture of Kevin mckernon
superimposed over the Grim Reaper's face
and I think that's I think that'll be
just fine that's some pretty pretty
heightened artistic ability right there
there you go yeah so so wrapping up here
I know you said you were really excited
to have to be coming to Canada and we're
super excited to have you if I remember
correctly this will be your first time
out there correct yes
I've been chomping at the bit you know
can Matt is one of the most
scientifically revered conferences that
I've heard of to me can med and the
Emeralds are top-notch so it's it's an
honor to be a part of the conference
I've heard nothing but great things
about it and I look forward to the
scientific discussions and the
collaborations that come about because
of it excellent I think you're gonna fit
right in there's there's plenty of
people out there who kind of share your
enthusiasm for cannabis science and I
think you'll be a great addition to the
event and we're looking forward to
having you out there
thanks again Briana for taking the time
to talk with us today and if I don't see
you before then we'll see you out there
in Pasadena
thanks so much Ben I'm looking forward
to it myself
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Brianna Cassidy check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and please also
check out the CB x analytics website our
next episode will drop July 8th but in
the meantime please go to Kinmen events
comm to view the phase 1 schedule to see
our growing list of sponsors and
exhibitors and sign up for email alerts
if social media is your thing
please also follow us on Facebook
Instagram Twitter and LinkedIn just
search for can met events and lastly if
you are listening on a podcast app go
ahead and hit the subscribe button so
that the new episodes automatically
download to your device and please also
leave us a 5-star review alright that's
it from us stay safe stay healthy and be
sure to come back for the next episode
of the Ken Ned coffee talk podcast
[Music]