[Music]
welcome to the can med coffee talk
podcast for each episode we talked with
the leading minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I am your host Ben emerald I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the can med conference every year
head over to Ken med events dot-com to
learn more about this year's kin med
2020 event scheduled for September 20th
through 22nd in Pasadena California and
if social media is your thing you could
find us on Instagram Facebook Twitter
and LinkedIn just search can net events
if you listened to the last episode with
dr. Ethan Russo then you know he will be
joining us at cam med 2020 as a keynote
presenter in the science focus area and
if you've not listened to it go back and
check it out Ethan has such a wealth of
knowledge you're sure to get something
out of it no matter what your level of
cannabis expertise we do have three more
keynote presenters to unveil in each of
their respective focus areas medicine
cultivation and safety testing the next
keynote presenter will be my guest on
the next episode of the podcast may 13th
you don't want to miss that one or any
episode of the KMA coffee talk podcast
so be sure to subscribe on your app of
choice speaking of announcements we have
extended the deadline for our special
420 dollar full conference ticket price
to May 20th we understand there's a lot
of uncertainty in the world right now
and that purchasing a ticket for an
event in September might not be high on
your priority list hopefully this
extension will help head over to Kim and
events calm now to get your ticket and
learn more about this year's event yes
you heard that right can mid 2020 is
still on for Pasadena California this
September 20th through 22nd we are
monitoring the Cova 19 situation and
working with the Convention Center to
ensure the safety of all of our
attendees we have also modified our
refund policies so that if we do end up
postponing the event due to kovat 19 we
will provide a 100% refund to ticket
holders if the new dates cause a
conflict you can view our full refund
policy and any kovat 19 updates on our
website Kemet events comm we have a
great episode for you today I had a
conversation with Martin Haley the
co-founder and director of project CBD
in addition to creating content for the
project CBD website and speaking at
conferences around the globe Martin has
authored several books including smoke
signals a social history of marijuana
medical recreational and scientific it's
a great read we actually have a copy in
our office Martin and I discussed the
topic everyone is talking about covin 19
Martin has reviewed the scientific
literature to find out whether CBD can
calm the cytokine storm that the kovat
virus can set off whether CBD has
antiviral properties and if cannabis is
an immune booster suppressant or both as
you can imagine where the virus as new
and novel as kovat 19 and a federal ban
on cannabis the research is far from
conclusive but i think you will see
there is some potential in some areas
that merit future research who knows
maybe you will see some compelling data
at a future can med event before I get
to my conversation we are proud to have
project CBD as our sponsor this week
project CBD is an educational news
service reporting on cannabidiol other
components of the cannabis plant and
herbal medicine synergies learn more at
project CBD org okay and without any
further ado here is my conversation with
Martin Lee
[Music]
good afternoon Martens thanks for
joining us
my pleasure yeah I just want to thank
you again for for taking the time to
join us during what I imagine must be a
hectic time for you and your family I
know you were personally affected by the
cove in nineteen pandemic so first how
are you and your wife doing well I'm not
showing any symptoms but my wife did
what was infected and she's now just out
of quarantine so she had a relatively
mild case of the Koba 19 virus and you
know as you know it's not always mild it
can be sometimes fatal but there's a
spectrum of symptoms and you know we're
obviously interested in how cannabis in
general and see meeting that particular
might affect that entire spectrum yeah
absolutely that's one of the main
reasons I wanted to to talk to you today
I did see the article that you published
on project CBD about just this sort of
the the interaction between Koba 19 CBD
and cannabinoids and I must admit I've
seen a lot of articles out there sort of
trying to tackle this issue and I'll be
honest a lot of them I've sort of tuned
out because they make a lot of old
claims but I was I was very happy to see
that yours was very well reasoned and
well researched so first kind of what
prompted you to want to write this
article well I should say initially you
know what one when you consider the
therapeutic promise and potential of CVD
in particular in cannabis you know
there's an awful lot there and one does
not need to exaggerate an overstate and
I do think there's a lot of exaggeration
and assumption and overstatements
happening with respect to you know
cannabis and CBD and the hand emic that
we're experiencing Mallon obviously we
felt it was important to address this
issue because it's the burning issue of
the day and there is a lot of confusion
a lot of people do use cannabis for
therapeutic purposes or otherwise an
obvious question is how will that usage
impact the virus over the course of the
virus their exposure
and you know our symptoms if for one Gus
come down with it so you know it's an
important issue because of what's
happening today and so in reading
through the article it seems like one of
the primary things that you tackled was
looking at whether cannabis or CBD
specifically can kind of calm this
cytokine storm I hope I'm pronouncing
that correctly first can you explain
what exactly that is and why it's
dangerous well you know the most severe
reaction to the köppen 19 virus involves
what scientists refer to as a cytokine
storm syndrome in The Lancet the eminent
British Journal they drew attention to
the fact that the evidence indicates
that people dying of this disease are
experiencing what they refer to as a
cytokine storm and and in essence it's
not the virus that's killing people
because if that were the case then
anyone exposed would die what is
resulting in mortality is is how the
body reacts to the bias and in extreme
cases there is an intense immune
overreaction in the lungs and that's
what can actually kill someone or sick
and one to a very significant degree so
ultimately it involves a respiratory
distress which is the leading cause of
death with the Cova 90 cases so
basically it's an intense autoimmune
reaction to the virus and that's what
the cytokine storm syndrome is and
because it's so in autoimmune or immune
overreaction it raises the question well
what can what can be done to treat this
and so you need something that's going
to suppress the immune system and
cannabis could do that cannabis and CBD
in particular but also THC notoriously
have immunosuppressant effects and
that's the reason why cannabis can be
very effective for people with
autoimmune diseases of which there are
many different kinds autoimmune disease
when when the body over reacts to when
the immune system over reacts to I'd say
a misperceive threat in autoimmune
condition can result and cannabis could
be very effective for that so it raises
the question well if the Koba 19 virus
in the most extreme form of the disease
is an intense immune response might
cannabis or might CBD and particular be
helpful in that regard that the problem
is we really don't know this hasn't been
any test in this regard but
theoretically you can posit that the
autoimmune or the anti-inflammatory
aspect of CBD of M THC potentially if it
could be harnessed might be a treatment
down the road for something like this
but the evidence at this point is
fragmentary and sketchy but it is
compelling that there really ought to be
research in this area unfortunately we
don't have that research to date so with
cytokines specifically so how do
cannabinoids sort of interact with them
or even endocannabinoids
how does that all kind of work together
well these cytokines they're really a
group of proteins that regulate
inflammatory responses that disease is
an infection and they're secreted by
immune cells the cytokines
cytokine could be either
pro-inflammatory or anti-inflammatory
typically it's a pro-inflammatory
messenger an example would be the tumor
necrosis factor-alpha that that's a
cytokine that's produced in excess in
cases of rheumatoid arthritis which is
another very painful autoimmune disease
it flicks more than a million people in
the United States that's condition so
what what cannabis could do is it can
suppress the inflammation
in various different ways there one of
the cannabinoid receptors as you may
know that there's two cb1 and cb2 the
cb2 receptor
is present in immune cells and when that
is activated by THC or in other ways
that will confer in Ottawa I would say
an anti inflammatory response
so CBD doesn't directly activate the cb2
receptor but it seems to do so
indirectly or it has many effects that
are parallel or similar to activation of
the secretory sector both CBD and THC
are very potent anti-inflammatory so
when you have a pro-inflammatory
expression of the cytokines this is
something that could be helpful and
there of course there are other things
like corticosteroids and so in this is
how steroids operate as
anti-inflammatories they've their
appropriate perhaps for acute
inflammatory flare-ups but unfortunately
in cases of the cytokine storm that is
not always the case with corticosteroids
because they could be harmful in their
own right to the lungs and in the lungs
is that you know the focus of the
disease so I think scientists are
looking for other options other than
corticosteroids to treat a cytokine
storm syndrome and again it might be
down the road that CBD or other
cannabinoids could be developed in this
way but we're not there yet
yeah is another example of they're just
not being enough research it seems at
this point yes exactly and you can
credit that to federal prohibition that
has really been a major obstacle to
research and we seem bitter fruit of
that but hopefully that will shift in
the future yeah hopefully some
researchers will kind of take up that
mantle and and start doing that research
we'd love to see that presented it can
med one of these years another thing he
got into in don't go ahead please I was
going to add if I could you really there
is a compelling is a compelling scenario
to justify this kind of research because
the CBD at pure CBD single molecule CVD
something like EMA dialects for example
which is
prescribed for epileptics CBD is now
being tested and showing some degree of
success for what's what's called
graft-versus-host host disease which is
also an extreme autoimmune reaction it
happens when someone receives an organ
transplant and rejects the organ that
often can be fatal
that rejection it's called a
graft-versus-host disease it's usually
fatal in 80% of the cases and there's
really no treatment for it but CBD
because it is a very potent
anti-inflammatory is now being looked at
there's a clinical trial in Israel
that's ongoing as a treatment for
graft-versus-host disease and there is a
parallel there because both Graham
versus host disease and and the cytokine
storm associated with extreme reactions
to the Cova virus they are both
autoimmune reactions but it's important
to keep in mind that with the Cova 19:00
virus it's a virus induced phenomenon
whereas with the graft-versus-host
disease it is not virally induced but
there is some you know some reason to be
hopeful that if that CBD could be
harnessed its therapeutic potential for
in both of these situations well I think
that's a good a good segue because
another thing that the article got into
was sort of looking at whether CBD can
actually be used as an anti viral agent
so what does the research say about that
well there's there's some hints of that
there's not a lot of research that shows
this but a little bit you know there
there's there was one study that showed
or sillies suggested that CBD had ant
direct antiviral effect against hippest
hepatitis C virus but this was only a
one preclinical study and there's really
nothing else that's see that shows that
CBD has this direct antiviral properties
what it does show though in certain
situations
you know virally induced diseases can
have can be expressed in terms of
inflammation and the CBD can temper the
inflammation of the viral induced
disease without necessarily directly
affecting the virus itself so that's a
possibility and there are several
studies that suggest that
so as for direct viral antiviral
activity there's not a lot out there but
in terms of reducing the inflammation
associated with a viral induced disease
that's quite possible and what about
just kind of having an optimized
endocannabinoids system does that sort
of help an individual be able to fight
off a viral infection well it's a little
tricky you know at project CBD we've
gotten a lot of emails people asking
questions and sometimes complaining that
we haven't put out stern warnings
against people taking cannabis during
this period the suggestion being because
CBD is immunosuppressive typically it's
not might not be a good idea to be
consuming to CBD you th see you cannabis
at the present time because it might
make one more susceptible to the virus
there's no indication that that's
actually the case but there are some
concerns and I think when we talk about
the endocannabinoid system and the
immune system and and it's a little
tricky because it's not like a one-way
street it's not that simply in the
cannabinoid system will have a
suppressive effect against u-neck immune
activity it could again when there is a
overreaction of the immune system and
cannabinoids a systems job is you might
say it is to temper that almost like a
dimmer switch to turn down overactive
immune activity but in a normal
situation that doesn't seem to be the
case that that's happening it's in a
situation where one one is not dealing
with in a autoimmune disease it doesn't
seem
that cannabis or cannabinoids such as
CBD and THC has a negative effect on the
immune system if anything it might be
the opposite case it might help the end
of cannabinoid system for the tone to do
its job as a Tana fire and and rather
than just suppressing immune activity
it seems that evidence suggests now that
the cannabinoids have an you know
modulating effect which could entail
suppressing immune activity when that's
important to do but otherwise just sort
of maintaining things and keeping things
at a healthy level so you can look at it
this way when when one has a fever to
fight it and that's necessary to fight
an infection the endocannabinoid system
doesn't turn down the fever doesn't turn
down the anti inflammatory response
until it's okay to do so it it's more
like it steps out of the way and it gets
out of the way so that the immune system
can do its thing and fight off the
infection but in a healthy situation
it's just simply there helping to
modulate helping to boost
endocannabinoids own so that the
endocannabinoids system does its job
well then that seems to be the case so
it can really go either way and when you
always talk about immunomodulation
again it could be suppressive or could
be allowing the immune system to act as
it needs to there is there was one study
of the AIDS of the HIV virus that
suggested that cannabis consumption can
actually boost immune activity in that
regard which would be helpful when when
dealing with AIDS or HIV infection so
that underscores how with cannabinoids
if they can go in two directions that
the endocannabinoid system is sort of
operates in a bi-directional way it can
calm an overexcited nervous system or it
can boost a situation with this less
energy than needed because the
endocannabinoid system will modulate
both glutamate which is an excitatory
neurotransmitter so again will as a
dimmer switch using that analogy will
kind of toned down
excitation but if if one's imbalance is
in the other direction and one is too
sluggish if maybe the gaba is more
prominent which is a depressive
neurotransmitter the endocannabinoids
system can slow down gaba meaning can
speed things up overall in the system so
it underscores how it operates in a
bi-directional capacity and a CBD and
THC since they're operating through the
endocannabinoid system whether directly
or indirectly we'll also have a
bi-directional effect and that will
apply to the immune system as well so it
can really it can move things in either
direction and hopefully it will do so
you know when it's necessary in the
healthy way so coming back to the
question should be to one be consuming
cannabis at this time you know I'm not a
doctor I couldn't really say I don't
know that it would be harmful if one is
not affected with the disease but one
should keep in mind that it is
immunosuppressive and I think that's
reflected actually now in the sales of
cannabis products and CBD products well
CBD products of which has been a they've
been driving the sort of a natural
supplement market it's been the biggest
seller for the last couple of years
since the virus the pandemic has erupted
of anything it seems that the sales are
slowing down of CBD products and people
are turning to other supplements that
are known specifically to boost immune
function whereas CBD as sort of a Depot
up mode we tend to be you know
immunosuppressive in most situations but
not always so it's a really it's tricky
and it's tricky because the virus itself
and how the disease expresses you know
it's different at different phases so
what might be helpful at one phase of
the disease might be harmful at another
phase if you need to boost immune
response
you know maybe cannabis and CBD and THC
wouldn't be the best things if you need
to suppress immune response well that
could be ideal but when you're talking
about it the phase of the disease that's
most critical the cytokine storm
syndrome
you know you're talking about an intense
immune response an intense inflammatory
response where in these situations an
anti-inflammatory compound like CBD or
THC a cannabis in general might
conceivably be helpful but but it's
really tricky because in these
situations we're dealing with a cytokine
storm I imagine that if if the
cannabinoid could actually be effective
in this situation who probably need a
pretty high dose and high doses of
cannabinoids tend to have the opposite
effect of lower doses or low doses are
immunosuppressive may be very very high
doses would be just the opposite which
is what you wouldn't be in a cytokine
storm syndrome situation but then again
you know cannabinoids which have been
often been described as biphasic meaning
you know low doses have a certain
response high doses have an opposite
effect it might be that when you're
dealing with something like a cytokine
storm syndrome you can get entering a
sort of a triphasic realm where a really
high dose of a cannabinoid such as CBD
could could not simply have an opposite
effect of a low dose but would be almost
amplifying what a low dose would do it
so it's very complicated and we really
don't know and one shouldn't be cavalier
about these things and make you know
statements as if one one could be
certain about what what would happen but
one should emphasize that we don't know
at least in terms of exposure you know
short of dealing with the cytokine storm
that that it would be harmful either so
I think you know one has to be careful
about these thing and has to use their
own judgment ultimately at this point
yeah I agree and I think it's
interesting at least to look at the
mechanisms look at what's actually going
on with these conditions and then sort
of look to see what what CBD or the
different cannabinoids what effect they
have on the system and just sort of try
to draw some parallels and say like you
like you've been saying this whole time
and you say in your article there's
potential here but we just don't know
and I think there's a lot of value in
that at Lee
to sort of explore whether or not it's a
possibility and then of course we could
take the next step and actually do the
research but I got to imagine that there
must be tough to do that in a situation
like a cytokine storm because it's you
know a very dangerous situation that is
probably being treated with a number of
different drugs to really sort of
isolate what's doing what must be very
difficult well I think obviously you
have to go through step by step process
and preclinical research involving
animal models would be necessary here
but all right you know there is some
there's enough information out there
that's can make a compelling case that
this should be explored that the one
should explore this direction and it's
so much criminal that hasn't happened up
until this point because it's not like
sauna kind storms is something that we
only learn about recently it's been
implicated in a century ago in the
Spanish flu pandemic it's thought that
the deaths resulted in or in that
pandemic 50 million people died
worldwide earth this is 1918 1920 during
that period it's it's lost my train of
thought there a little bit it decided
scientists have known about cytokines
and cytokine storm syndrome for some
time when no one was really
investigating whether cannabinoids could
be a treatment in this regard sure and
this can happen with the the normal
annual flu as well right yeah but
usually that doesn't result in a
cytokine storm that kind of extreme
overreaction like you know things you're
obviously dangerous and they could be
fatal and what's kind of an interesting
analogy here is that the when one looks
at what when one compares the the
expression of lung disease in people who
have died because of if they been poor
products for cannabis oil products or
CBD oil products the unlicensed products
typically what the symptom ology shows
what's referred to as ground-glass
opacities in the lungs it looks like the
lungs like they're filled with ground
glass and similarly that shows up in
cytokine storms that symptom ology is
described as ground glass acid passages
in the lungs
so the immuno both the vaping disease
and in the cope in nineteen are lung
diseases died from respiratory failure
so that's is something worth looking out
there as well so I wouldn't suggest
vaping unlicensed products now to deal
during this period that that in general
one should avoid those but when we
talking about immune over reactions and
people dying from the immune system
rejecting what's going on in the lungs
there is a similarity between the baby
don't miss we saw past summer and what
we're seeing today with the cytokine
storms yeah and I meant to meant to ask
you about that obviously there's a
number of different ways that you can
consume cannabis and sort of in the
current state of you know there being
the potential for a covert infection
would someone who regularly smokes
cannabis or vapes are they at any higher
risk of kind of having a negative
response should they actually contract
kovat like are they kind of setting
themselves up for for a bad time it's a
better term it's a very good question
and it's something that's been discussed
a little bit in Canada stresses it but
the problem here is for so long the
authorities had been crying wolf about
cannabis and and making claims of harm
that that are either exaggerated or
fabricated so at this point now then
we'll get hearing warnings from doctors
and officials Oh smoking marijuana
smoking cannabis could harm the lungs of
making more susceptible to copa90 more
exacerbated if one is exposed you know
it's the cry phenomenon that we've heard
people people ignore it
there's been relaxing creative work just
so much about cannabis that's
been said and that's unfortunate because
frankly at this point anything that that
weakens the lungs that irritates the
lungs and that would include tobacco
smoking or just air pollution which is a
more serious problem than air pollution
that that's a risk factor and people
should recognize that so yes obviously
better than VAP if you're using a good
product than to smoke it's less
irritating or obviously better to
consume cannabis in other ways you can
ingest edibles or drink beverages and so
forth it's probably wise to do that in
general lung health you know could be
supplemented by jogging a little bit
each day just doing things to stay
healthy I mean cannabis in general
should be or it's best used as part of a
healthy lifestyle and that that's
underscored that message should be
underscored and in the current moment
given what we're doing yeah and one of
the things that we're sort of trying to
consider trying to look into is what
about cannabis itself being infected
with kovat 19 you know us at medicinal
genomics we do a lot of work in
microbial safety testing so looking for
different molds different bacteria that
might be infecting cannabis and you know
bat guano is sometimes used as a plant
fertilizer and could that potentially be
infecting the plant in some way probably
unlikely but I guess it's something
worth considering yeah you know it's
very in the nd stuff yeah it's very
interesting that you should bring that
up of that back one I really never
thought of it I know that back on I was
considered an excellent supplement for
fertilizing plants and so forth
generally well I think it is quite safe
organic not chemical and so forth but
it's worth an worth researching I think
medicinal genomics is probably
well-positioned to do that i through a
genomic research I think one could
identify a virus in a plant
and so they can kind of find mold and
other things so that would be really
great
one could look into that and but you
know we're also dealing with what was at
least initially as somewhat of a
localized phenomenon thought to be
originating in China so one couldn't one
shouldn't assume and that if indeed
there was a transfer from bats to humans
that might have sparked this crisis that
that would also be the case that guano
essence that's used as a supplement for
cannabis cultivation because we're
talking about different areas of the
world but definitely worth considering
and looking into it's an it's an
intriguing notion absolutely and one of
the other things that you had gotten
into sort of in the later parts of your
article was sort of just the the current
situation that we're in with the the
cannabis industry and how but certain
restrictions might be actually putting
folks in the industry at higher risk and
one of the things that you pointed out
was that banking restrictions mean that
dispensaries have to deal in cash which
exposes them more to the virus than if
you were say using a debit card or
something like that I thought that was a
very interesting thing to point out I
don't know if you want to expand it
that's not just yeah I mean it's not
just the cannabis workers so people in
the industry which is well it's tax
collectors because people have
businesses pay their taxes in in cash
and literally wheelbarrows of cash are
brought over to the appropriate places
you know every quarter where you have to
pay their quarterly attacks and that's
just the absurd situation we're in
because cannabis is caught between
betwixt in between you know legal being
legal on a state level certainly at
least in the state like California or
Massachusetts for that matter in many
other states but the federal law is
federal law and banking privileges are
not extended to cannabis businesses
hopefully that will change perhaps in
the near future but it's just another
way that prohibition federal prohibition
is is dangerous and contributes to the
the problems that we're having today
it's not just simply that federal
prohibition is blocked
we don't really know to what extent CBD
or cannabis can have an antiviral effect
which would be really nice to know now
we don't know that because a federal
prohibition and we also are consigned to
dealing with cash in terms of the
cannabis economy because of federal
prohibition so it's and you know we also
have to consider the fact that many
people in jail or jail are in jail
because of drug crimes they're in prison
because of cannabis violations I think
over 40,000 cannabis British prisoners
in the United States and there's
probably no place worse to be now and in
prison because it's close quarters and
prisons are hot the hot beds for the
kovat 19 virus and prisoners are dying
prison workers are being infected and
it's another aspect of how the drug war
on cannabis prohibition has contributed
negatively to the situation we're now in
Wow
yeah well at least I guess one silver
lining is that at least in my state in
Massachusetts and yours in California
and others at least cannabis is being
considered essential so hopefully that's
a step in the right direction we can
start maybe correcting some of these
wrongs I know we're coming up on either
I'm sorry go ahead
you should sooner or later we hope right
no absolutely so I know we're coming up
on on the on the time here so I wanted
to give you a chance to tell the folks
where they can learn more about you or
some of the work that you're doing with
project CBD it's project CBD org we have
a website that's dynamic and a good
source of information now we've been in
this game for now ten years we were
involved in actually introducing CBD
into the medical marijuana world at
California back in 2010 and it spread
from there I think the website is a
really good source of information a good
educational resource for interested in
regularly interested in all aspects of
cannabis and cannabinoids particularly
the therapeutic and scientific
dimensions and as you pointed out you
know we try to stick on
focus on the important stories and
certainly Kovac 19 today's is preeminent
in that regard absolutely am and as I
said at the top of the interview were
very happy to have you at km ed 2020 for
this year your presentation at cam at 19
last year was one of the most popular
most well attended so I encourage
listeners to check out that video I'll
put a link to it in the in the show
notes so again excited to have you and
hope to see you out there and Pasadena
this fall so thanks again Franklin
important oh well thank you and I hope
we can all join together in Pasadena and
be there actually in the flesh rather
than virtual that would be wonderful
yeah that is the plan so let's hope that
happens so thanks again
thank you
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Martin Lee check out the links in the
show notes to learn more about the
topics we discussed and please also
check out project CBD I hope you will
join us for our next episode where I
talk with our kin med 2020 medicine
keynote presenter bonnie goldstein
bonnie is the founder and medical
director of canna centers and she has
treated thousands of patients with
cannabis medicine she has lectured both
nationally and internationally about her
clinical experience and also helps to
educate healthcare professionals on how
cannabinoids can be incorporated into a
patient's treatment that episode will
drop may 13 2014 2 a drawing to win two
tickets to our kin med 2020 VIP dinner
and keep you up to date on all things
game at 2012 if social media is your
thing you can find us on Facebook
Instagram Twitter and LinkedIn just
searching for can med events and lastly
if you're listening via podcast app go
ahead and hit the subscribe button so
that new episodes automatically download
to your device and if you also want to
leave us a five-star review we'd really
appreciate that
alright that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and be sure to come back for the
next episode of can med cough
you