[Music]
welcome to the can med coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing who will
be part of the km ed 2020 conference in
Pasadena California September 20th
through 22nd I am your host Ben Amer alt
I am the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the cam med conference
every year head over to Kim at events
dot-com to learn more about this year's
kam ed 2020 event and purchase your
ticket at our earlybird rate on this
episode we talk with Kim at 2020
presenter Eloise Thiessen of radical
health Aloise is a board certified adult
geriatric nurse practitioner with over
20 years experience in nursing she
started her own cannabis practice about
six years ago and since then has treated
more than 6,000 patients with cannabis
there are very few health care
professionals nationally with the same
level of expertise and experience as
Eloise she's also the president of the
American cannabis Nurses Association and
will serve as the president through 2022
Eloise made her first kmn appearance at
our 2019 event in a presentation sharing
her experience using cannabis to treat
geriatric patients we talked about some
of the unique challenges that come with
working with seniors including the
stigma older patients have towards
cannabis how the end of cannabinoid
system changes as we age and navigating
drug interactions we are excited to have
Eloise as a presenter it came at 20:20
this year but that will not be her only
contribution to the event
Eloise will also be an instructor at a
full-day medical practicum along with
dr. Bonnie goldstein dr. Dustin Sulak
and dr. Kevin Spellman this is a great
opportunity for healthcare professionals
to learn about the latest research into
cannabinoid therapies and also tap into
the deep
experience the instructors have to offer
when you consider that most medical
schools don't teach the endocannabinoid
system courses like this are really the
only way healthcare providers can learn
how to properly administer cannabinoid
therapies attendees will walk away with
practical information about the
different types of extractions and
products that are on the market and
optimal dosing due to federal guidelines
CME credits for physicians are not
available for the practicum however the
course is approved by the California
Board of Registered Nursing 49.5 contact
hours learn more at can men events calm
/ practicum the practicum kicks off this
year's can med 2020 event on September
20th and will be followed by two full
days of oral and poster presentations
about the latest research into cannabis
science medicine cultivation and safety
testing go to km and events calm now to
see the latest collection of presenters
and purchase your ticket to the event we
are currently offering early bird
pricing through August 1st we are also
offering a 100% refund to ticket holders
should cam at 2020 need to be postponed
due to Cova 19 rest assured that we are
closely monitoring the situation in
California and working with the Pasadena
Convention Center to make sure we can
provide a safe environment for our staff
our attendees and our presenters and as
of this recording the event is still on
but just in case we have updated that
refund policy check out our website for
details before we get to my conversation
with Eloise I'd like to thank this
episode sponsor radical Health radical
health helps patients healthcare
professionals and retailers navigate the
complexities of cannabis medicine
through patient care clinical education
community education and industry
training learn more at radical health
care comm and finally this episode of
the cam med coffee talk podcast is
fueled by the hemp and coffee exchange
hemp coffee is a healthy
just natural product rich in trace
minerals and nutrients providing
sustained energy without the crash of
regular coffee for more information
check out hemp coffee exchange.com
and use the promo code drink hemp all
one word to get 10% off your next
purchase okay
without any further ado please enjoy my
conversation with Eloise Thiessen of
radical health
[Music]
good morning Eloise thanks for joining
us my pleasure thanks for having me
absolutely we're very excited to have
you as part of K and med 2020 and I know
you're gonna be quite busy out there
because you're wearing a lot of hats for
us this year which we definitely
appreciate you're a member of the
advisory board which is excellent you're
helping us weed through all the
abstracts and select the best speakers
you're going to be an oral presenter
again which we're very excited about and
they're also a big part of our medical
practicum which is going to be a great
addition to this year's event and I know
that you're you come from a nursing
background which i think is going to be
a really nice addition to to this year's
practicum or it's CMU event so we're
going to get to speak a bit more about
what that practicum is going to cover
and yeah yeah it's going to be a
jam-packed day I know we're planning on
doing about nine and a half hours worth
of content for those who attend and I'm
really excited that we're gonna be
covering you know Pediatrics to
geriatrics you know looking at chronic
pain looking at a panel for dosing kind
of talking about how we as clinicians
approach patients differently you know
so I think we're gonna have some really
exciting content that they won't find
during the regular can med present
presentation so we really did try to
make sure when we were looking at
abstracts that we had good diversity
among topics and stuff that people would
get excited about and if I'm not
mistaken that medical practicum will be
some continuing education nursing
credits will be available for that is
that true yeah so they had a hard time
getting continuing education credits for
physicians and pharmacists but I'm a
continuing education provider in
California so I'm able to offer nursing
continuing education credits for nurses
nurse practice nurse practitioners that
come in so I'm really excited about that
nine and a half hours worth of
continuing education credits towards
their license yeah that's great
and in advance of this call I did watch
your
can med 2019 presentation again which is
excellent I encourage everyone to go and
check that out on cam at events comm
I'll drop a link in the show description
and one thing that you mentioned is that
we need to get more nurses educated
about cannabis and more involved so I
know that you're president of the
American cannabis Nurses Association so
I was wonder if you could speak a bit
about what you all do there absolutely
so we're a national nursing organization
we're celebrating our 10th year this
year hard to believe um it was started
back in 2010 by Marilyn mathri and a few
others and we're now at about thirteen
hundred and fifty members we have a few
in Canada and Australia so we do have
some global presence as well and our
mission really is to improve nursing
excellence through education advocacy
research policy development so we've
been working really hard to you know get
more eyes on us because we really do
feel like nurses are going to help lead
the change you know we outnumber
physicians five to one we really are the
the boots on the ground the work force
in the medical community I think people
have seen that with kovat you know how
nurses have really been on the front
lines caring for these patients so I
think the more that we can get nurses
educated and the more that we can the
more patients we can reach yeah one of
the things that stood out to me from
your presentation is you had mentioned
you were talking with dispensary owners
and they had said that it's not uncommon
for them to spend a half hour to an hour
with new patients mostly seniors who are
trying to kind of navigate their their
cannabis journey and try to figure out
what's good for them and I have to
imagine from a clinician perspective
that's got to be a little concerning
that these patients are kind of going to
the dispensary for this medical
education and as knowledgeable as they
certain as they are in most dispensaries
they're not clinicians no and I mean in
California it's very clear that you're
not to give any medical advice
however it's sort of this you know
it's this I don't know if I want to say
catch-22 but it's it's awkward because
most clinicians don't want to be
referred to as the pot doc or the pot
nurse so they're not necessarily
interested in getting into this field
they're still concerned the fact that
it's a Schedule one drug so often you
know the the dispensary staff are the
first ones to meet the patients and
they're there for them and I'm you know
as a clinician I'm grateful that they
have someone to work with I would like
to see an increase in scope you know
some standardization around scope of
practice some you know mandatory
training so that we can have you know at
least some consistency in you know how
we approach patients you know when
should they be referring them to a
clinician you know because it's there's
such a high turnover rate and the
dispensaries here in California that you
get a lot of myths and misconceptions
get repeated you know as a clinician
I've had my patients go to the
dispensary to pick up their cannabis and
then the dispensary staff will
contradict what I say so it can be
really confusing to the patient you know
they're already scared and overwhelmed
and intimidated and so if they go into
an environment that that they're you
know clinicians advice is being
contraindicated it really puts them in
an awkward position you know if well
what am I supposed to do and because
they can be really you know we can be
very passionate about cannabis we can be
very convincing sometimes from both ends
you know the dispensary staff in the
clinician so I just worry about seniors
who you know have a high risk of drug to
drug interactions or a high risk for
Falls potentially getting information
that could lead to an adverse event and
then they never use it again right and
one of the things that you had mentioned
there was kind of referring to a
clinician and is that is that something
that's sort of common for maybe
dispensaries to be referring patients to
you or is that not how you're you're
seeing most your patients no I well I
have a few companies that I've worked
with here locally in the Bay Area that
that know I'm here and will refer
you know some of the more complex
patients or customers that come to them
most of my referrals now are coming from
some of the larger health systems like
UC Davis Stanford UCSF those physicians
and clinicians refer there are very
complex patients to me who you know want
to use cannabis as a treatment for
things like chronic pain anxiety
depression sleep so that's exciting to
me that we're seeing that shift where
it's I know my patients are going to use
it I don't know anything about it my
policy that my hospital policy doesn't
allow me to really engage with the
patient in this area but here is a
trusted clinician yeah that's fantastic
and that's a really good sign that the
doctors are are opening up to to the
idea of using cannabis medicine and I
know with the population you're working
with
there is certainly a stigma associated
with with using cannabis so how
difficult is that to sort of navigate
when you when you're taking on new
patients you know it's it still catches
me off guard sometimes you know because
it's just to see how deep the stigma
goes you know we will see patients come
in who are still arms crossed you know
against that you know their body
language is very you know shut off you
know like I can't believe I'm here
talking to you about this and they're
almost a little bit like angry or
irritated that they've quote-unquote
resorted to this drug and often by the
end of the consultation through
education they start to kind of open up
and see it a little bit differently and
you know building that trusting
relationship with them and giving them
the space to be uncomfortable and to be
hesitant and and to explore those with
them really helps them I think become
more open and there are times when I've
met with people who are so still so
hesitant resistant that I will be very
honest with them and say this isn't
going to work with you unless you keep
an open mind you know so sometimes
they're bringing and they're putting up
such a big roadblocks that they're not
going to be successful so it's it's
fascinating
I still have one lady I've been treating
for over five years who hasn't told her
adult children that she's using it
because she spent her whole life telling
them to stay away from it so this guilt
and shame that she has around it and I'm
like they know you're doing better so
what do you tell them you know what's
your success what do you what are you
sharing with them and she said oh I just
tell them you know I'm just doing
alternative things I wonder if they can
read between the lines I was like you
know kids are a lot smarter than you
think they are even if they're adults
right and another thing I was curious
about with you know working with older
patients is when I spoke with dr. Bonnie
Goldstein a few episodes ago I was
surprised to learn that children sort of
tolerate the effects of THC better than
adults
she needs to actually kind of increase
the dose for children I was wondering is
that the same or similar with seniors do
they sort of have a difference in
sensitivity to cannabis well it's yes
it's the opposite though they tend to
you know as we age our metabolism slows
down our ability to process medications
decreases by about 30% so often they
need less and I've had some times where
I can I had one gentleman who was
responding to 0.33 milligrams of CBD we
had given it to him daily and he was
still having adverse effects from it so
we did it every three days and that was
his dose that he tolerated so you see
that they are more likely to have side
effects and that low dosages are often
enough and sometimes they don't even
need it daily because you know they're
building it's building up and
accumulating and they don't eliminate it
as quickly as kids will yeah I suppose
that's a good thing in terms of cost
savings yes yes especially with taxes
making it so expensive it does help
absolutely another thing I wanted to go
back to you said you know a lot of your
first consultations with folks sometimes
there's a lot about education I'm
curious what are so
the resources or the tools you use for
education that seem to to resonate with
with your patients yeah I've learned
over the years to have a lot of backup
materials you know because I am
fortunate enough to have you know 30 to
45 minutes with each new patient to
really sit with them and and understand
their health history and and help you
know talk about their goals and then
educate them on the plant but you know
it's it's such a steep learning curve
that they tend to forget a lot of that
information so I do a lot of
reinforcement with materials and
handouts that I provide them but I think
that the conversation I love having with
them is talking about that euphoria that
they're so scared of because it's you
know the the one thing that they'll come
in you know often and say don't you dare
recommend or you know they usually say
prescribe you know don't you dare
prescribe THC for me Eloise I do not
want to get high and you know I'll
usually smile really big and say well
tell me more what's that mean what does
it mean to get high so we have this
great conversation about euphoria and
how you know it can help them be more
relaxed and maybe more communicative
with their spouse and improve their mood
you know and help them then just feel
better and and that you know when you
present it to them that way they're like
well that doesn't sound so bad you know
giving them that permission to feel good
because you know we're encouraged to
find recreation in so many areas of our
life but if that recreation is cannabis
we're ashamed for it right it's
considered a bad thing so giving them
that permission and educating them on it
usually really it's it's it improves
their quality of life greatly it's
really fun to watch
right and so typically what sort of are
the the ratios that you're using to
treat the different conditions that that
you're presented with well I always like
to say it depends yeah I you know I do
find gender I do find differences among
males and females and that's part of
what I'll be presenting at kin
with a dementia population you know and
I I'm I like to start out with one
cannabinoid at a time again because the
older adult tends to be more sensitive
and they're more likely to have drugs or
drug interactions or even side effects
from cannabis if I can isolate you know
one cannabinoid at a time I have a
better sense of you know if they're
having a reaction you know it's clearly
its THC or it's clearly CBD there are
cases where I will be a little bit more
aggressive and start out I do like a one
to one for pain of CBD and THC but a lot
of times it's sort of one cannabinoid
building on the other and and I don't go
to ratios too often because I like to
individualize it so much for them
interesting so one of the things I had
prepared to ask was are you on the side
of whole plant or isolated compounds and
it seems from that answer that you're
more in the camp of the isolated
compounds well I don't know that I pick
isolated compounds I pick whole plant
THC products or whole plant CBD products
or older or full-spectrum CBG or
full-spectrum CBD a so they're always
being minor other cannabinoids in there
but the majority of it would be you know
a CBD dominant regimen that I start out
with and then they have some you know
small amounts of THC but I'm not you
know I rarely use isolates but I'm not
opposed to them because there are some
some cases where it seems appropriate
but it's the minority okay so are some
terpenes getting involved there too yeah
I mean I wish that we did a better job
of providing a CoA to to consumers and
patients and clinicians so that we could
identify these cannabinoid terpene
profiles and then you know use that to
be able to repeat it you know identify
what what this profile is that's working
so well so that it can be repeatable
instead of going in and telling them Oh
we'll go back and get a g.push or blue
dream or you know some of these came of
our names that really aren't a good
indication of what's in you know what's
in the the product and may may be
misleading and not repeatable absolutely
and I actually just recently spoke with
Cindy Orser who is a she's on the lab
test lab testing side and she was really
talking about the importance of testing
for terpenes and how that's sort of a
blind spot for a lot of patients or a
lot of consumers that are just going
there and seeing the THC CBD and then
kind of making assumptions on a product
based on that and they could really have
a very different experience based on the
terpene profile absolutely absolutely
and sometimes at this really interesting
case just last week where this woman had
an incredibly complex medical history I
mean I was a little intimidated by it
and I was looking at her allergy list
and she was allergic to black pepper and
I said well tell me what your allergy is
to black pepper and she said oh I get
like an itchy throat and I said do you
have a hard time breathing you know want
to see the severity of it and she said
no and I said okay well this product
that I'm about to recommend to you has
beta carotene in it which you know is
thought to no we know comes from black
pepper and so I want to you know make
sure we're monitoring you for potential
side effects or an allergic reaction and
so she started out at a low dose and was
tolerating it quite well checked in with
her on day five and she was doing well
and then she increased her dose that
night and woke up with hives all over
her body so I have to assume that she
was having an allergic reaction to the
increased dose because of the beta
carotene Wow how about that so so are
there any any terpenes that you tend to
favor in when you're kind of
recommending products for your patients
definitely beta Karratha lean I like
that terpene if I
find Alan Ahlul and Mersin I'll
definitely use those as well you know
but again it can be hard to identify you
know I like to use companies that I know
are sort of vertically integrated and
are using the same kemo VAR so you know
once once I've identified those products
and the the terpene cannabinoid profile
I like to use them because I'm like okay
well likely get some consistency here
but you know a lot of products today are
distillates and it's kind of hard to
really geek out on terpenes right and
another thing that came up when I was
talking to Cindy was that a lot of these
producers manufacturers are now actually
putting in terpenes into their blends
and into vape cartridges and things like
that and her concern was that they might
actually be overdoing it and putting too
many terpenes in there and what are sort
of the downstream effects of that so
yeah that was really interesting too
I'll have to listen to that as that's
definitely my concern as well as you
know when we're you know do we know what
levels of terpenes should be in these
products I mean what are we basing it
off of and you know now recently I've
seen some of these hemp companies
testing their products for minerals
phosphorus magnesium potassium and you
know we don't have any standards around
these levels and I've seen you know you
know these levels are high of phosphorus
and potassium and magnesium and I'm like
well how does that affect the end-user
especially some of my patients who may
have a history of cardiac disease or
kidney disease where they can't have
these high levels of potassium or
magnesium you know is it is it impact
maybe it's not I don't know but I'm
curious about it you know just as I am
with terpenes yeah I was pretty sure I
should say when I spoke with her she had
mentioned that she had tested some
products and the terpene levels were as
high as like 20% we're yeah we're
naturally occurring in the plan like it
rarely gets higher than 5 so that's
right
quite the increase so I told her that it
might be a good potential can med topic
so anyone out there is listening is
curious please do that research we'd
love to have you I want to go back to
the whole idea of the stigma but not
less on the patient side here maybe more
on the provider side and I guess the
first question is you know how many
other geriatric providers are out there
kind of treating patients with cannabis
is that number growing I know that the
number of seniors who are using cannabis
is growing but are the number of
clinicians they can turn to is that
growing as well you know it's hard for
me to assess that I would say no at
least not at the rate that I would like
it to be you know it's just so many of
them are coming to their clinicians now
and asking about it and their clinicians
are like yeah that's fine if you want to
use it and then it kind of ends there so
there's there's no real opportunities
for these seniors to get more
information about it I think we're
seeing and I probably have a skewed view
of it but I do see more nurses getting
into into it around education and
advocacy but you know not I'm not seeing
Jarett ition you know Garriott
geriatricians and get into it you know
and again with my work with that
Alzheimer dementia patients I get a lot
of referrals because they don't they
don't want to or their Hospital policy
as they can't write so it could be a
situation where a patient comes to their
doctor says that are interested in it
but they don't feel comfortable and kind
of refer to to someone like yourself
mm-hmm now how does that vary from state
to state I know that you know nurse
practitioners and some states can
administer medications and kind of do a
full practice where in other states it's
more limited mm-hmm how do you navigate
that well not you specifically but how
is that a difficulty for some patients
well nurse practitioners have been
trying to get full practice authority
forever you know in California requires
a collaborator collaborative
relationships I have a physician
who is my medical director so in some
states they can have full practice
Authority where they they don't need to
work with a physician and you know
there's it's it's tough because you know
we're educated to assess and diagnose
and interpret lab results and x-rays and
in some states say yes we can do that
without a physician in some states say
that we can't and it it's it really
makes no sense to me
obviously and you just see more and more
research coming out about how there's
practitioners have better outcomes
because and I talked about this at
Canada last year you know we spend more
time with our patients were less likely
to prescribe opioids we're less likely
to have patients become go back to the
emergency room or be readmitted after
they leave the hospital because of our
level of care so you know in California
I would say you know because we have to
have this collaborative relationship
what has happened as many of these
physicians hire what they call as
mid-level practitioners or providers and
they can charge a physician rate for us
to see a patient and then pay us an
hourly rate so it really does to you
know work to their benefit financially
to have nurse practitioners under a
physician and not be able to practice
autonomously so I'll just leave that at
that
no but I'm familiar with nurse
practitioners and it seems like they're
really kind of filling the void in in
primary care because now there are a lot
of there are fewer physicians who are
going into primary care or family
practice because reimbursement rates and
things like that so yes I think you all
are filling a valuable need and you're
right tend to take more of a kind of
holistic approach whole body approach
instead of sort of specialized yeah
therapeutics though
yeah and it's it's hysterical to me
because that's like you know physicians
come out of school and they don't want
to get into primary care like you said
because the reimbursement rates but yet
they're blocking us from having full
practice authority
so it's just you know okay you can't
have it both ways so to anyone who's
listening now and you know maybe has an
older relative who they think might be
might benefit from cannabis medicine
what's their first step like what what
could they do to help out their loved
one well you know if it's a serious
medical if they have a serious you know
medical history I would certainly look
in the area to see if there are any you
know knowledgeable cannabis clinicians
knowledgeable CBD clinicians who can
help you know do a thorough health
history and determine you know risk
versus benefit of using the cannabis and
I you know my the thing I always tell
people is if you're going to work with
the cannabis clinician make sure they're
telling you you know how much to take
how often to take it they're reviewing
potential side effects that you may have
from the cannabis therapy potential drug
to drug interactions and that they're
there monitoring them so that they can
adjust things as they go because you
know often people come to cannabis and
lately CBD and they just think that it's
a one and done I'm going to take this
and it's gonna be good to go and you
know because they're friends or other
people they know are having success
already so it really is you know
sometimes it can take months for us to
get them the right treatment plan
especially if they're suffering from
age-related and chronic illness you know
it's not a silver bullet it's not gonna
just work overnight right and so I guess
where do you start with sure and you
said that can kind of be this this long
process so where do you start
yeah with me particularly um
I mean someone will book an appointment
with me and I have them fill out a very
thorough health history and then we have
the appointment you know discussing the
goals and sometimes I'll identify other
things that I think cannabis could be
helpful with and then you know what I do
is provide them with the treatment plan
here's you know here's the cannabinoid
profile I want you to obtain here's how
I want you to take it
and I go very low and slow obviously
because 90% of the people that come to
me are cannabis naive I mean they they
haven't even touched it ever so I try to
empower them in terms of you know giving
them a treatment plan that says take
this dose wait three days and if your
side that you know your symptoms are
still there then you increase it to this
dose so it's very I spell it out for
them as much as I can you know so that
they really can feel confident in the
way that they're approaching it you know
that they have again building that trust
and giving them an opportunity to see
how it affects them and take note of it
and take a journal and write it down and
start empowering them to be more
involved in their health care and
outcomes not not everybody has access to
somebody like me and so that's the
challenge challenge right especially if
you're in a state that's illegal so you
know it's that there's you know
obviously the American cannabis Nurses
Association there's society Society of
cannabis clinicians these are nonprofit
organizations that are helping to
educate and train more clinicians out
there and to try to reach you know as
many people as we can and do you have a
preferred route of administration or
something that seems to work better than
others or is it sort of patient
dependent yeah I mean I I certainly have
found you know certain conditions will
respond to certain you know to different
routes better somebody who has severe
chronic pain inhalation tends to be the
most effective it works quickly it's the
most predictable it gives them the most
control over their experience and so
there sometimes can be a lot of
education around that because they may
come to me and say you know I'm not
gonna smoke it and it's very
counterintuitive to think that inhaling
anything is going to benefit their
health but you know giving them some
education around that often if they
won't consider it at first they may come
back to it if there's you know just look
like I'm like how successful do you want
to be you know are we just going to
dance around
a little better do you want to go
straight to what I think is going to
help you right away and sometimes less
I'd rather dance around it a little bit
you know older people definitely come to
me and they want to cream you know
they're like I want a cream or a bomb or
a salve so like a topical and then a
tincture is often probably the second
thing that I'll recommend because it's
you know easy for them to kind of
titrate and it feels more medicinal to
them they tend to overeat edibles right
because they taste good and they don't
really understand the delayed onset and
you know even if I do educate them and
say just take one I can't tell you how
many times I've gotten a call like well
that was really strong okay well how
many did you take how I eat the whole
thing okay thank you I tell say no and
you you try to tell them not to and it's
just like I said people forget so
they're not going to over consume a
tincture because they generally don't
taste not great right and and I know
your presentation this year is gonna be
talking about treating patients with
Alzheimer's and dementia I was wondering
if you could speak a little bit more to
that yeah it's an area that I really
have enjoyed being a part of and I'm
fortunate in my area I've had some
assisted living communities and boarding
care facilities that have been early
adopters and willing to dispense you
know cannabis to their residents because
you know we don't have any fda-approved
pharmaceuticals for their behavior as
they go into these severe agitation and
aggressive behaviors so often they're
giving these off-label medications that
just have horrible side effects and
black box warnings meaning you know the
risk of death is higher in this
population so it's very you know
stressful for the family it's stressful
for the staff at these communities that
are caring for them and you know we have
been trying cannabis we started this
about five years ago and it's just grown
you know
and now I mean sometimes when the
residents before they even come into the
facility the families like call Eloise
get on this regimen because they see
such great success in terms of managing
you know they're more redirect about
they're calmer sometimes they're kind of
you know laughing again you know all
those benefits of that euphoria and that
we can see in this population is just
it's life changing when it works well I
know that prior to your presentation it
came a 20-19 which you can see at cam in
events calm nice little plug there
you mentioned the story of Lucy at the
beginning of the presentation which was
really interesting and you had said that
you actually after getting her onto
cannabis actually managed to get her
dementia diagnosis removed is that
correct
her daughter did all that hard work yep
and how they had it removed how cool is
that
that sounds pretty remarkable I would
say you know there are an exam that
family is an example of family that just
was so supportive right when when Lucy
got her her mind back and lost all that
way and you know there was no dementia
anymore and the daughter was just a
fierce advocate for her mom and had
Kaiser remove it from her diagnosis list
of diagnoses it's very uncommon well
it's amazing it's really powerful mm-hmm
all right before I let you go with us -
excellent yeah all right before I let
you go I wanted to give you an
opportunity to plug your company plug
your social media anything any way that
people can learn more about you or get
in touch with you
sure okay thank you you can definitely
visit our website at
www.carandtruckremotes.com
no platform that we have for healthcare
professionals I'm on LinkedIn at eloise
Leeson and at twitter our handle is at
radical healthcare and I think Instagram
too I don't manage all of that so I'm
not the best at it kept plugging that if
you're interested in learning more about
the American cannabis Nurses Association
it's cannabis nurse org is excuse me
cannabis nurses it's plural org is our
website and we're gonna have our
conference which I believe will be
sharing some some tables I think
medicinal genomics will have a table at
our conference in December of 2020 in
Albuquerque New Mexico absolutely and I
will put all those links into the show
description so listeners you don't have
to feverishly write all that stuff down
I'll put that in the description for you
so thanks again Eloise for joining me
and we're really excited to have you as
part of KM at 2020 and we will see you
out in Pasadena
I can't wait thanks for having me Ben it
was a pleasure
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Eloise Deason check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and please also
check out the radical health website our
next episode will drop July 22nd in the
meantime please go to cam met events
comm slash coffee talk and sign up for
email updates that will enter you into a
drawing to win two tickets to our can
med 2020 VIP dinner and keep you up to
date on all things can med 2020 if
social media is your thing you can also
find us on Facebook Instagram Twitter
and LinkedIn just search for can Med
events and lastly if you are listening
on a podcast app go ahead and hit the
subscribe button so that new episodes
automatically download to your device
and if you'd like to leave us a five
star review that'd be nice too alright
that is it from us stay safe stay
healthy and be sure to come back for the
next episode of can med coffee Talk
[Music]