[Music]
Our Guest today is Dr Dustin sulac
Dustin is a traditional osteopathic
physician an expert in Integrative
Medicine his clinical practice in main
focuses on treating refractory
conditions in adults and children Dr
sulac is an internationally renowned
expert in medical cannabis the author of
the handbook of cannabis for clinicians
principles and practices and co-founder
of healer a medical cannabis education
resource and Products Company he serves
on the board Board of Directors for the
Society of cannabis clinicians and is a
passionate educator and leader in the
medical cannabis field Dustin is also a
true canmed veteran having participated
in every canmed event dating back to our
first conference at Harvard Medical
School he returns to canmed 24 this year
as one of the medical practicum
instructors and an oral presenter
presenting the Art and Science of
combining cannabinoids for treatment
success during our conversation we
discuss what attendees can expect from
the camed medical practicum the
expansion of available cannabinoids and
how Dustin evaluates new options which
cannabinoid Dustin would choose if he
could only use one to treat patients the
difference between acidic and neutral
forms of
cannabinoids the process for combining
cannabinoids and challenging old
assumptions about the benefits of
combining CBD and
THC before we get to my conversation
with Dr sulac I wanted to thank this
episode sponsor healer healer is a
trusted physician developed medical
cannabis brand founded to address the
challenges of helping patients and
healthcare providers get the best
results with safe reliable dosing
products and education on how to best
use them healer's distinctive product
formulations and educational material
are based on the work of leading
cannabis clinician Dr Dustin
sulac visit healer.com to learn
more okay and without any further Ado
please enjoy my conversation with Dr
Dustin
[Music]
sulac good afternoon d Dustin thanks so
much for joining us on the podcast yet
again my pleasure Ben glad to be here
yeah we are thrilled to have you back
not only on the podcast but to have you
back for camed 24 you know I was
re-watching your camed 23 presentation
just this morning and you mentioned how
the event last year felt like a family
working towards a common Mission which
was so great to hear we certainly feel
that way and we appreciate you being
part of that family and playing such an
important role in the event since the
very
beginning well thank you I'm glad that
you reminded me of that because it it
really did have that feeling was like a
huge family on vacation together uh
learning together there was just so much
passion and uh collaboration and
interest it was it beautiful environment
excellent and of and of course you're
returning again as one of the
instructors for the medical practicum
which will be taking place on Monday May
13th which is a full day workshop up
it's a bit of a crash course in canabo
medicine uh with you and Dr Bonnie
Goldstein Eloise th and new this year Dr
Ethan rouso which is which is quite the
lineup so I want to give you an
opportunity to kind of talk about the
value of the practicum for folks who
might be interested in in attending sure
yeah we we received so much Fe good
feedback on the practicum last year and
it's always a mixed crowd you know we've
had some people in the audience that you
know could potentially be up on stage
helping teach you know experts with a
lot of experience in cannabis medicine
and um you know all the way to
clinicians that have never recommended
cannabis to a patient before that just
kind of like took the leap to come to
canmed to this event and and everything
in between and it's uh really nice to
get a mixed crowd like that uh you know
so much uh relating and learning I think
the the conversations that were going on
in between the lectures were just
fabulous really exciting and the
feedback we got was great so the
practicum is uh Soup To Nuts kind of uh
you're a medical provider and you want
to know about cannabis and how to get
great results treating your patients
with cannabis know what the uh what the
risks are the contraindications how to
have a a conversation about it with your
patient but also know how to think about
it like the uh physiology the
pharmacology and um and we we are able
to pack that all into one day remarkably
there's always uh you know a lot of um
but it's it's just very con place and I
think that uh year after year we've been
able to refine it and get the curriculum
to a point of what's most relevant to
Medical providers and it's a yeah it's a
great day it's amazing that we get that
much information across uh also uh
accepted and based on the feedback
retained in just one day yeah no and
it's a great sort of um prerequisite for
for the rest of the the conference too
gives you people a nice Foundation to be
uh for the the rest of the presentations
absolutely we we actually had quite a
few people that were not clinicians that
came in and were also just thrilled that
they had made the choice to do that uh
to to attend the the medical practicum
uh you know even just some patients and
they're like well this was so much over
my head but it really uh you know like
validated what I'm what I was thinking
about you know there there's people in
the Cannabis industry that are working
on other aspects of the industry not
like the provider patient aspect of it
and so I think for them to you know get
a a glimpse into what's in our world
what's important to us what we're
thinking and talking about it it really
validates and and kind of you know
solidifies their experience as part of
this industry of course yes and so
you're also going to be giving an oral
presentation at C 24 we've got you
working hard um it's about the Art and
Science of combining cannaboids for
treatment success and before we get into
sort of the benefits of com combining
cannabinoids I want to ask you about
just the sheer number of cannabinoids
that are available now and how has that
sort of changed since you first started
working in cannabis
medicine yeah it's um like we've known
for since I started that this plant was
a treasure chest of different medicinal
compounds but what we really had was THC
you know I started in 2009 in Maine and
it was um you know like sending letters
to people on the west coast asking if we
could get some of these CBD they weren't
really even CBD dominant back then it
was like more like type two chemo type 2
varieties mixed TC CBD there were a
handful of them available we really need
these in Maine we've heard this great
stuff about CBD yeah you know and then
2013 we finally had access to CBD and um
thought that was great and thought we
knew what we were talking about when it
came to uh combining THC and CBD there
was this kind of you know somewhat
limited black and white idea of what the
combination does together uh that has
persisted uh you know through now but
over the last you know five years or so
we've been working with uh
therapeutically relevant amounts of
thca cbda and CBG these are you know the
the more prominent newcomers uh CBN is
in there as well um you know there's
there's some isomers and synthetics
which are worth talking about even I'm
not sure they're that valuable
clinically some of them probably have
some value um but then there's the real
mystery which is the combination of them
you know we can we can isolate them out
and uh do uh pre-clinical rodent
experiments and try to understand their
pharmacology but where the rubber meets
the road in the clinic you know
understanding
how how to make selections for what to
treat patients with and then how to
interpret the response to those choices
how to
kind of Orient around dosing and what
are some of the general strategies when
it comes to combining canavs this is
it's a whole new area of um medicine
that cannabis is kind of leaning us into
like maybe it's not new that there's
this idea of poly pharmacology or
network pharmacology using multiple
agents with different mechanisms of
action to get better results than
relying on a single agent that's not new
but um it's just amazing how cannabis
kind of Mand that we learn that and take
that approach and it's it's doing so
more and more all the
time and how is this you know kind of
expansion of available compounds and and
different combinations how's it made
finding the right medicine more
difficult for you and for patients and
consumers well it's yeah so there
there's more options certainly can be
more overwhelming if you don't have kind
of a methodical way of sorting through
it which is what I'm hoping to conin Bay
in my presentation um and and I think
cannabis was already overwhelming to
people even when they just had you know
few options so now they you know for
example if they look at uh our medicinal
products at healer you know we've got
all these different products right we
try to make a chart for how they can
sort through it but it is it is it does
get overwhelming for people on the other
side of it though what I think we're
seeing as a benefit is that patients who
may not have responded to cannabis say
we were just using THC and we really did
our best to get THC to work for them and
it didn't work you know instead of
saying okay I guess you know you're one
of these very few people that just
doesn't respond well to cannabis and we
better try something non- cannabis next
um now we have more things to try and
and things that um from all that we know
these other options have a similar
safety profile and have uh a similar uh
capacity to help with this broad range
of conditions so it's it's not like we
discovered a new canabo that's perfect
for just this one diagnosis here we go
again with another compound that could
work in all these different you know
diagnoses all these different fields of
medicine it just adds to to the
complexity and until we you know I think
until we get like supercomputers working
on this problem where you know human
beings are going to be the best uh the
best one to uh kind of determine where
are we going to start what are we going
to try next what do we what's it going
to take for us to decide this really
isn't the right fit for you before we
move on these are the basic questions
that I'm hoping to help clinicians
answer excellent and now you mentioned
healer.com and and I'm glad you did
because I kind of wanted to ask you what
is your process for for adding new
products that like new cannaboids into
your
portfolio yeah um we had a big pipeline
you know the wish list is Big um um we
have prototypes and so you know things
that I find uh interesting based on
pre-clinical literature based on what
people are telling me we usually make
prototype and share it around with the
staff and with myself and some of our
colleagues and see what people think you
know a good example of this is our I
think it's our newest product still it's
a a combination of cbda and cbga so cbga
like who knows anything about cbga you
look in the peer review literature
there's so little on it um you know a
few a few more hits just this past year
but it's is it is it similar to CVG
which we also don't know that much about
but we know more is it different than
CVG you know a lot of unknowns there but
there was this um you know preclinical
study that gained a lot of headlines
about how it could inhibit the SARS Cove
2 virus in its infectious potential in
mice and in cells and so we thought well
you know we've seen such impressive
results with the acidic cannaboids the
thca and the cbda it kind of makes sense
for us to explore cbga next let's see
what it does we started playing around
with it and we found that in combination
with cbda it seemed to be doing
something special um you know we weren't
testing it against SS you know like
against covid uh we were just taking it
and see how we felt and people were
reporting very similar things that this
combination made them feel alert awake
focused like in the zone resilient to
stress you know I didn't expect that I
still don't exactly know what's the
mechanism of action um but enough of us
felt like well this is a prototype worth
bringing to Market that you know that's
what we did and we still have so much to
learn from it you know I mean even even
CBG I knew it had a lot of potential
what do we know about it in humans right
now other than the anecdotes almost
nothing right there's one survey study
and the people in that study weren't you
know the data is um just not very clear
like it's a good starting point but we
don't know exactly how much most of them
were taking or what what other you know
can avonoids they were taking it for uh
and and so because of that we have
currently have an ongoing uh another
survey of CBG users to try to to try to
clarify that but what it it seems like
you get you get something that's a hit
in a small number of people you allow
other kind of cannabis uh enthusiasts to
to start using it and before too long
we've got some signals that are worth
following then we do the observational
research we kind of confirm what we
think we're seeing and then you know
maybe that leads to more more clinical
trials or more animal research it's you
know it's so backwards with cannabis
that we start with humans and then we go
to to the after that right but but I
love it I love it so that that's kind of
our process and then also the the idea
that we just don't want to have too many
products like it it does get confusing
and overwhelming and there can be kind
of a downside where if people are you
know just looking at it and not sure
what to take or there's no good
algorithm for helping them make a
selection then they might make the wrong
selection and kind of rule out cannabis
say oh I tried it it this doesn't work
for me I'm not going to try anymore so
there there's a there's pros and cons of
everything in life yeah no and I kind of
you know from a personal standpoint my
mom has been dealing with some some back
pain
um and she's done physical therapy and
some things doesn't really seem to be
working and I was like well have you
tried cannabis and she was like well
what do I get and that's where I was
like well I don't know I mean is it THC
thca CBD cbda um a combination uh it it
can be a bit
overwhelming and that's where you know
that that's where I'm I'm hoping to
train clinicians to do that but it
sounds like you know so say we take
someone like your mom with back pain
maybe it's not a very complex case right
you know maybe I would get her in the
office and ask her a bunch of questions
and in the end she's just a lady with uh
you know some like intermittent back
pain there was no big injury I'm not
worried about any kind of like you know
spinal stenosis or anything like that
she just got to SAR back and she did her
fpt and her exercise is not working what
can I use for pain you know I'm going to
have a very few number of questions that
I'm going to need to know where to get
her started this is not going to be
rocket science my you know Ju Just to
use this as an example for our audience
today you know one question is going to
be is the back pain disturbing your
sleep or is your sleep Disturbed for
some other reason and if it is to me
that is the lwh hanging fruit if you can
get somebody sleeping better it's very
likely their next day is going to be
better it's very likely their their
healing system is going to take over and
fix the underlying cause of the problem
and in my mind T in my experience THC is
still the winner when it comes to
improving sleep in just about anyone but
certainly in anyone whose sleep is
disturbed by either pain or anxiety
especially trauma related anxiety I'll
start with THC you know maybe your mom's
never tried cannabis before so I'm
talking to her I have no clue if she's
going to be a 2 milligram person or a 20
milligram person and because of that I'm
going to start her at two and very
gradually work up see see if she's a
responder when it comes to sleep and
then if she is we'll say okay let's
watch for a month or two see if your
daytime symptoms resolve if they don't
come on back and let's let's talk about
step two how do we treat you during the
day uh so that's just kind of my
clinical approach which I think doesn't
have to be exclusively clinical I do
think through education we can bring
that to the consumer and they can kind
of skip the clinician and uh and and get
good results with with the right
information that's my hope yeah no and
it really seems like it's a process of
you know trying something for a period
of time really checking in with yourself
seeing how that's working and then
adjusting accordingly yep but uh how do
you you know shooting from the hip and
trying the right thing because there's
different personalities too right maybe
your mom's someone that loves doing
things methodically or maybe she's
someone that like if it's not going to
show her something some improvement
within four days she's done you know
yeah and U you know that's kind of the
art in medicine is like figuring out
which patient is which and how
aggressive we need to be at at the
beginning but I will say you know all
these new canono inss are great they do
not replace THC not not one of them THC
is still such a powerful agent you know
if I could only choose one to work with
that would certainly still be it
interesting so yeah that's that's good
and that's a good segue because one of
the things I was gonna sort of ask about
is you know after we're talking about
the the variety of cannaboids sort of
narrowing things down a bit um and am I
correct in assuming that well you've
already confirmed that you know THC
being kind of one of the most well
studied widely available um would you
also put CBD and potentially CBG in sort
of that category of sort of the um maybe
most effective cannabinoids or most
well-known canabo at least right
now welln for sure but I think if I you
know what I said about THC before if I
could only have one what would it be you
know I think if if the if the offering
was for me to only have two you know if
it was THC and the second best what
would that be at this point I think I
would choose cbda over CBD it it seems
to me in most people to do just about
everything that CBD does but to do so
more powerfully and at a lower dose um
it's not perfect it you know what I just
said does not apply to everyone there's
some people that try both and then go
back to CBD but the vast majority uh
will try both and say wow the cbda
actually worked a lot better I'm going
to stick with cbda and we know that um
at healer we offered cbda samples to our
CBD customers and most of them switched
over I will I will confess not confess
but disclose I am a cbda user of healer
so um I'm a Believer you like it too and
and then CBG you know I'm still figuring
it out it's certainly seems powerful
like it it sells well people get it and
then they want to get it again they
think that it's helping them I've seen
some remarkable results clinically you
know not not with everyone that tries it
I'd say a lot of people it's it's more
similar to a CBD is response we're like
yeah I tried the CBG it's helping me I
like it it's not like oh my God you
changed my life I feel like myself again
I've returned to work from being
disabled like those are the stories that
we hear about with THC you know I I
don't get that much of that with CBG
except once in a while I do I do hear
something that's that's pretty profound
interesting and now so you mentioned CBD
versus
cbda um in that
scenario um do they have similar kind of
therapeutic or you know similar effects
um because I know that in some cases the
neutral versus the acid they actually
have opposite
effects right so many of the targets of
CBD and CB da are the same they're
they're very similar and and so yeah if
you look at THC versus thca and compare
their pharmacology in the body very
different and when people take them they
feel very different um CBD versus cbda
is much more similar and so probably you
know one of the targets that's going to
be most important for for people that
are using this is the um the activity of
the serotonin receptor so they both can
kind of reduce anxiety and improve mood
via that serotonin pathway there's
there's been a number of animal studies
looking at the two um sometimes not in
the same study but two different studies
that have used the same model to
evaluate cbda versus CBD and you'll see
that they they can do the same thing
they both can reduce seizures they both
can decrease inflammatory pain they both
can uh decrease nausea and vomiting you
know there's there's a lot of overlap
there uh mechanistically it's usually
the same targets the the way in which
they're achieving these outcomes is the
same but the dosing is often vastly
different with cbda requiring a much
lower dose suggesting it has uh well
what we know from the animal studies is
that it has both better bioavailability
so take a dose more of it's getting into
the body and then it also has more
potency once once it's in the body you
know if you look at brain levels or
blood levels of these compounds that are
necessary to achieve their result you
need much less of it so more gets in and
you need much less maybe one of the
downsides is that CBD seems to last
longer in the body cbda you'll excrete
more quickly you might therefore have to
take it more often but um but a lot of
overlap there yeah and then kind of one
of the Nuggets that I picked up watching
your presentation from last year was you
showed some graphs showing that
cbda um is actually better absorbed when
it's part of a full plan
extract but that is that that I mean
there's there's findings in rodents you
know we haven't proven that for humans
yet but based on what we're seeing when
people say you know we get we taking
these low Doses and they're working
really well and then there is a human
study that showed cbda absorption
through the gut was extremely high it
didn't test it like it did in the rodent
study on its own versus in the in the
context of a whole plan extract but all
the information we have is pointing to
to what you said that essentially if if
there's a little bit of THC or
CBG present with the cbda you might
absorb it or at least a rodent might
absorb like 15 times more of it with
just a little bit of THC or or CBG and
no one none of us would have planned
that but I think a lot of us would have
said there is a pretty good chance that
for one reason or another taking this
thing in the context of the whole plant
is going to beat taking the isolated
compound you know and that that's just a
lesson we've learned again and again
again there's going to be exceptions to
that lesson you know in certain
situations but typically that is the
case and once in a while we know why
that's the case this is one of those
scenarios where we we think we know why
that's the case right and that speaks to
the topic at hand here right this
combining cannaboids for Success yes so
um you know in the presentation we go
through the what we know about the
pharmacokinetics so this is how do drugs
or compounds interact with each other as
they're getting absorbed as they're
getting metabolized and as they're
getting excreted and we have quite a bit
of information about these various
canabo and what some different
combinations will do
pharmacokinetically uh when when they're
in each other's presence so that's kind
of one chunk of what I'm presenting and
then another aspect of it would be the
phod dnamic interactions so these are
not about absorption and Metabolism but
about how they actually act their their
mechanism of action their pharmacology
and that when these two are present you
might see one thing compared to when
they're they're um you know on their
own and then um you know strategy so
there's the pharmacokinetics the
pharmacodynamics and then strategies uh
for both clinicians and patients about
how are we going to sort through this
like what's step one what's step two how
do we combine things so that that's the
um main content in our presentation my
presentation excellent no
and kind of the the process I'm very
interested in like is it better to I'm
sure it's always dependent on the person
and the condition but you know is it
better to start with a combination and
then you know maybe zero in on um maybe
a single compound or is it better to
start with one and then start adding
things in sort of how does that
work yeah it it depends on some factors
but I am very comfortable starting with
combinations and more simple cases like
if like if you just told me what you
told me about your mom and I started
saying Ben you know like tell me does it
radiate down her leg I don't know you
know does it disturb her sleep I don't
know you know like I couldn't get any
more information out of what would I do
yes I'd started with a combination I
probably recommend our formula that's
like equal parts THC CBD cbda and c and
um thca you know it's it's got like we
call the balance formula so it's only
one quarter THC um it's you know not too
strong easy for people to titrate in
small increments it's literally made
from 19 different varieties you know
it's a huge shotgun approach uh would I
take that shotgun approach as my first
line with someone absolutely I've done
it plenty of times it works well no
problem with that if it's a more
sensitive case maybe it's someone who's
already tried cannabis and hasn't really
succeeded or has a history of being
Ultra sensitive to cannabis or it's a
high stakes case where it's like we got
to get results fast or this person's
going south or their fames you know this
person's going to have to be
institutionalized or whatever you know
if there's some urgency there I might
not just start with the shotgun approach
I might take a really kind of
accelerated and targeted approach but a
lot of times I do what I what we talked
about before like I'll treat the Sleep
problem with THC and then look come back
and say like yeah I guess I got a few
little remaining things but bulk of what
I came to you for is is fixed or I'll
start with a balance formula kind of a
shotgun approach and they'll say you
know what that works really well and I
might say well you know is there some
room for fine-tuning it are you having
any other symptoms and maybe we do a
little fine-tuning but a lot of times
that's that's not even needed so yes you
know short answer to your question is
sometimes combination is a Fine Place to
Start and that's good enough for a lot
of people
excellent and now you hinted at
something earlier and I know I I read it
in your abstract too and I wanted to
make sure I asked you about it was that
there's some new research challenging
some old assumptions about the effects
of combining THC and CBD hoping you
might elaborate a little bit on that
sure yeah the the kind of old adage of
CBD is going to mitigate the side
effects of THC while augmenting the
benefits of THC there is definitely some
truth there uh we've seen you know the
product satx designed by Ethan Russo you
know which combined the THC and the CBD
in roughly equal p uh proportions and
that's been very successful it's helped
a lot of people um so so while there is
some truth to that statement there's a
lot of nuance and there are many
situations uh that I've seen and that we
are now seeing in human clinical
research where that is just not the case
adding CBD to THC does not mitigate this
the side effects it can actually enhance
the side effects and it may dampen the
benefits in certain cases so um you know
like one example would be um a study of
people with fibromyalgia who have
vaporized either THC dominant or
combined THC CBD cannabis they rate how
it affects their pain you know it's
blinded they rate how it affects their
pain and they have their blood levels
measured to see you know H how much THC
and CBD in the blood are needed to
achieve these reductions in pain well it
it turned out based on the results of
that study that the presence of CBD in
the flour and in the blood actually
limited thc's ability to treat the pain
you know we know mechanistically that
THC stimulates the CB1 receptor and CBD
turns down the activity of the CB1
receptor a little bit it's kind of
arrogant to think like the only way in
which it's going to turn down that
activity has to do with negative side
effects but turning down that activity
is never going to bother the positive
effects no like it you know physiology
doesn't work like that mean maybe
sometimes it does but um there is
evidence so I I I think that's a big
like you know people love grabbing on to
things in cannabis and running with them
I'm guilty of this also you know we all
think like oh Mir scene means it's
sedating no miring means a lot of things
you know if it's present you know or or
like you know probably even worse than
that is the whole CBN story that people
are going for right now like um cbn's
valuable it's naturally occurring it's
very similar to THC I'm not putting it
down you know what I might put down is
like dirty CBN that's been manufactured
in a way that might not be safe but CBN
itself you know there's a couple studies
from like the early 80s that you know
showed some people got sedated and maybe
some rodents got ated when taking it you
know they get sedated with thc2 but all
of a sudden that little bit of
information turned into wow CBN is the
best for sleep right it's like it's
totally not I mean for some people it is
some people are have really more
paradoxical reactions to CBN than they
do to THC and it and it wakes them
up it's less potent than THC so you're G
need a little more of it but in the end
it's very similar so yeah try to keep it
real like I'm I'm um you know also a
victim of that kind of thinking
sometimes you know like I I take what I
think I know and run with it and maybe I
don't question it enough um but as a
kind of a leader and educator in this
industry I really periodically like to
look at all of those assumptions and
challenge them and uh um you know the
The Challenge on that CBD THC
combination there there's a lot of data
to suggested is not that simple and
sometimes it might do the opposite of
what we hope yeah no I mean I think
we're all sort of guilty of that
especially in this industry where we're
learning and you know to keep saying
well it depends uh is a little
exhausting so when we can kind of grab
onto something as a bit of an absolute
um we do um but again it it
depends
absolutely all right Dustin I do want to
be mindful of your time but before I let
you go I want to give you the
opportunity to share any additional
resources related to some of the topics
we disc discussed or that your
presentation that you're going to be
giving um and then of course any other
information about you or healer uh links
that I can put in the show description
please let me know okay yeah so the the
topics that we discussed this is um this
is like me pulling together a bunch of
threads that I typically cover every
month uh you know individually on on the
Healer webinars so what I do with these
free webinars every month is I go over
usually five or six different research
studies that have come out recently that
I think are interesting or clinically
relevant and so that keeps me on top of
the literature and it also keeps my
audience up to date with what's new and
and then I you know what I've done with
this presentation is kind of zoom out
and say like over the last two or three
years what have I learned about
combining canabo how's that affected my
clinical practice and can I synthesize
this for an audience in a concise way uh
but for people that are are excited to
be kind of like the first to know and on
the front lines please check out
healer.com you'll find a tab there for
webinars uh the webinars are free anyone
can join them and they happen every
month not going to happen in March
though because I'm having a baby so I'm
taking one month off um uh but we have a
lot of other resources on healer.com
dosage programs you know if um if if it
weren't you been someone that knows a
lot about cannabis but if it were
someone else asking me about their mom
I'd say you know just send her to
healer.com tell her to to go through the
program called new to canab is you know
how to get started and um and I think by
the end of that she'll have a lot more
confidence a lot more understanding of
the basics without needing to become an
expert and what else the other thing I
would just like to say is I I would love
people listening to this to find this
conversation interesting to come to
canmed it's it's just a beautiful
experience and I want to be there with
you on the beach in the in the lecture
hall um you know I'd like as as many of
the right people uh who are truly
interested interested and inspired in
this field to to show up so please
consider it'll be worth every penny it's
it's such a beautiful event it is um and
again we're so happy to have you be a
part of it this year and for all the
years and all the support over the years
we we so much appreciate it all right
Dustin thanks again for doing it um
congratulations on uh on the incoming
baby and uh we'll see you down in
Florida in May great thank you Ben see
you
soon
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Dr Dustin sulac check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and thanks again
to this episode sponsor healer.com our
next episode drops March 20th that's 2
weeks from
today in the meantime go to to canmed
events.com to check out all the details
related to canmed 24 speakers poster
presenters networking events panels
workshops meals and more all the
information is
there while you're at camet events.com
sign up for email alerts so you don't
miss any announcements before the event
if you are planning to join us in
Florida this may register for your
ticket package now space is limited and
tickets are going fast I also invite you
to follow us on social media we we are
on LinkedIn Instagram X and Facebook
just search for cam at events and lastly
please rate review And subscribe so you
don't miss an
episode all right that's it from us stay
safe stay healthy and be sure to join us
for the next C Coffee
[Music]
Talk