so for many of you have heard me speak
before seeing some of the things I've
done you'll see this is a bit of a
contrast to it but if you remember what
we're trying to do all this time is to
solve the question of is there a way to
accurately and consistently dose
cannabinoids across disease sets over
time with that being the question that
we're trying to solve we're doing it by
the clinical experience that we're
having working with excuse me working
with patients let's go back working with
patients through aunt Zelda's the
preclinical research is going on with
competency university and other
researchers like DeeDee and others and
then also through Zelda therapeutics
which is the hat that I'm wearing here
today where we're actually funding the
clinical trials and the preclinical work
that's going on to prove out some of
these theories so that we can answer
this dose in question and create
solutions for patients so this is a
collaboration that went on between Spain
California and Australia so let's go
here so there's been a lot of work done
in the past showing the anti-tumor
effect of cannabinoids in most cases the
ones that have been studied have been
using pure compounds of CBD and THC so
and there's fantastic evidence of that
but when you get into the human trials
and human looking at the the anecdotal
and the experience that we're having
working with patients this is not
necessarily the case so what we've done
is we've hypothesized that whole plant
extracts are in fact more effective
anti-tumor tools than pure compounds and
why do we believe this we believe it
because the as as our previous speaker
and excuse my typo there
because as our previous speaker has said
there are hundreds of compounds that we
don't know even what they are yet now
apparently we do have ways that we can
test and I look forward to collaborating
more on those things with you moving
forward because it's all about solving
this conundrum so because there's other
cannabinoids in there and there's other
cannabinoids within the plant itself
that contain anti-tumor properties such
as the THC a CBD a and etc etc there's
also other non
cannabinoid compounds within it that
activate the receptors such as
beta-carotene that has been shown to
activate the cb2 receptors and also have
effects on the tumor response as well so
because there's so many things that have
not been studied how can we reduce it
down to a pure compound and say this is
it because if it doesn't work on one
does that mean that there's no other
solution well there's last time I looked
on seed finder there were over 10,000
different cultivars out there probably
you know boils down to quite a few less
but depending on where within the
greenhouse it's being grown what part of
the hill that's being grown what time of
day you pick all these different factors
that it greatly influences what the
actual compound is going to contain
within the medicine itself there's also
evidence already and things like Marinol
that is a pure compound or it's a
synthetic in this case but it does not
work nearly as well as a full plan so
why would we think that it would work in
other areas as well so the aim of this
was to is to I'm looking at breast
cancer in this case and we're and we're
going to be concentrating on the subtype
of her2 positive in particular however
one in eight women in the and we're will
be affected impacted by breast cancer in
their lifetime and as you get older this
risk factors go up considerably as you
can see and we are an aging population
so this is a considered problem moving
forward an estimate of the cost for this
well moving forward are at the moment
we're spending in excess of fifteen
billion dollars a year treating breast
cancers and as we move to 22 and 2010 so
that's already outdated and as we're now
closer to 2020 we're looking at an
excess of twenty two billion dollars a
year to extend the life and what a great
percentage of that spent in the final
year of life for a lot of these patients
so we wouldn't we need to do something
about this so we there's been you know
right now the her2 positive er positive
PR positive and then of course the
triple negative or the three mode major
subtypes without getting into all the
genetics and the anomalies of each of
those in their cases so we have the
targeted therapies for ER and PR
positives of tamoxifen which many people
choose to take
part of their therapies in the
her2-positive RTK targeted which is
lapatinib is pretty well the standard of
care in both cases it's with or without
chemotherapy and/or radiation depending
on what your doctor has recommended for
you or your oncologist triple-negative
there are no targeted so chemotherapy is
really the only option for these so if
we're gonna look first of all so what we
did is I'm going through the methodology
right now is we started out with two two
compounds the first one was a pure THC
compound that was sourced from THC farm
it's very typical used in a lot of
different research projects and then the
second was and I still have no idea how
our extract got to Spain but aunt
Zelda's extract from California we
selected one that was not extraordinary
we did not pick the one that was like
ooh this is gonna have phenomenal
numbers we picked a an average that we
may use as a starting point with a
cancer patient and we only remember in
this study we're only really concerning
ourselves with the THC so I'm not
showing you the whole profile in the
terpenes etc this actually happened to
be one called purple Arkell the names
don't even get me started but it was
about about 55 percent THC within this
and what's important is that we used the
same concentration dose in both in vivo
and in vitro so the differences in will
only be responsible based upon the pure
compounds versus the full plant extract
all these numbers the first labs for
aunt Zelda's were done by Sonoma lab
works which has been verified multiple
times in other labs for the accuracy of
their numbers and in this case they were
all both of these compounds were double
checked through canna Foundation in
Spain so the what we did is we started
out of course and I say we absolutely
have no if that's a that's a not a real
we because I didn't do it this was all
done in the in
Christina Sanchez Manuel Guzman's lab in
Spain but what they did is they started
out with the cancer cells in petri dish
which is pretty typical and they were
incubated with THC or the vehicle which
in this case was sesame oil or the THC
extract for 24 hours and then they were
subjected to the MTT of you know putting
the yellow and what what lights up
what's still alive will be blue using
they're able to identify which cells are
still alive and the viability the
intensity of the blue tells them the
viability and how many cells are alive
and this was the first results we had on
the her2 positive that we showed pretty
clearly that the full plant extract at
the 50% mark which is really what's the
most significant here we had far greater
cell death with the full plant extract
than with the pure compounds and then
these are two different variety her2
positive breast cancers with the bt 474
and the HCC in one 1954 to move forward
on that we then went ahead and tested on
the triple negative because even though
it was not initially the focus of this
we know that we have to check all of
them and there are no other alternatives
at the moment for targeted therapies for
this particular type so it's imperative
that we find something to help this this
group of sufferers so at this point we
also can show once again that the THC
extract is more potent than the THC pure
compound in decreasing triple negative
breast cancer cells so then it was time
to move on to the mouse models and I'm
not going to even pretend to understand
exactly all the things but I'll just
explain the way it was explained to me
what was going on in the process is that
these breast cancer cells in this case
it was the bt 474 were injected
subcutaneously into the mice that had
been that were immune deficient they'd
been nude mice as the is the term calls
it in this case
and they were when the when the tumors
actually they were checked on a daily
basis and when the tumors achieved the
200 cubic millimeters then they were
then ready to be treated they were
divided randomly into seven there were
seven in each group put into these four
different the vehicle once again the THC
pure compound our extract and then also
with the lapatinib which as we mentioned
before is the RTK for targeted therapy
for this type of cancer and what we
found was that if you can look it's very
it's very very clear here excuse me I
went back a slide let me go back up it's
very clear that the full plant extract
was far more effective in killing cancer
cells than the pure which was really
much more statistically the same as the
vehicle in this case and then when we
moved on to then comparing it to the
lapatinib once again the lapatinib and
the THC rich extract performed almost
IED statistically identically in killing
the cancer cells which is very very
promising to now see what we're going to
do and run and see together
synergistically to see how they work and
killing those cells if we can get even a
greater said the similar to what the
same lab discovered years ago
comparing TMZ with THC and finding that
each one works very well on its own but
it was a 50% increase in apoptosis when
they were combined so what are what are
our next steps on this so next we will
be comparing the THC versus the THC rich
of course obviously in the ER positive
and the PR positive breast cancer cell
lines we're then going to do the same
exact set of experimentations with CBD
pure and CBD extracts there's a huge
amount of of noise around CBD and CBD
Pyrrhic compounds with people there's a
lot of salesmen and marketing going on
around this and the evidence just is not
showing that using these pure compounds
is giving anywhere near the medical
benefits that we can achieve
of using full plant in any of these if I
and a lot of its for the reasons that we
just don't know what we don't know yet
so we're then going to go ahead and
compare the different combinations of
the major cannabinoids and then
including with that also looking at some
of the other compounds that within the
plant seeing where we can add those in
we'll be doing a combination of
cannabinoids with standard therapies to
see where we find the best numbers we
had a lot of work to do and then
validating of course all the results
from the in vitro into the via in vivo
and I just was very quick presentation I
just want to thank obviously this the
hard heavy lifting in this study was
done by Christina Sanchez and her in her
team in particular Sandra who was a you
know doing all the gavage and doing the
the autopsies and doing all the testing
on it which were very very pleased with
and then of course our team at Aunt
Zelda's that has worked very hard over
the years and creating these wonderful
compounds to help treat cancers and I
beat the time thank you yeah so if
anybody has if anybody has any questions
I'm more than happy to see if I can fake
my way through it so the pure THC
extract how was that extracted that is
an ethanol extraction we have found from
our experience working with patients
where we've actually done an experiment
in the past where we took the same plant
had it extracted was with the same same
crop of plant we had it extracted with
co2 we had it extracted with ethanol we
compared that very same results on
patients and patients did better on the
ethanol extract using the same than they
did on co2 sorry that wasn't ethanol
extraction comparing though the THC farm
that was an extract that you were
comparing that was a pure compound and
where how was that extracted that was a
isolate and I have no idea the answer of
that interesting short path distillation
there you go interest that's what it was
thank you
my wife has Stage four breast cancer
metastasized to five tumors in liver I
turned to you last year and it worked
she has no evidence of any cancer in her
body and this is this comes from the
head of the breast oncology department
at University of Colorado who is
aggressively ignorant and aggressively
opposed to cannabis having said that my
question to you and follow-up to
yesterday is what now what talk to me
about a maintenance dose yeah
maintenance dose is a very interesting
conundrum also and I will do love that
word because it seems so appropriate in
this in this environment that we're in
right now what we've been doing with
patients as a general rule and like I
said general rules are broken they're
the medium there's people on this side
on this side that we do different things
with but for the average patient what we
do especially when they respond as well
as for example your wife has without
getting into specifics because it's a
little slightly different than this but
to say what we usually do is after we
have two full cycles of anyd which
usually is between six months and a year
we'll start a titration down to about
between 10 12 % is statistically where
it's working out on a graph of what the
highest therapeutic dose was and we
leave them at that maintenance dose
indefinitely and now when we have
patients with with quite a few cancers
what we're doing is when we see that
there's id-1 gene involved and I I have
told already that I'm I have a you know
a little bit of a girl crush our next
speaker because of his work with the ID
one and we've taken that forward and
said okay we're in a human laboratory in
California because of the lack of
regulation we've been able to do
phenomenal amount of work with patients
with their consent of course but when
their ID one gene we're able to and a
lot of breast cancers have we're able to
flip that and have very high levels of
relatively high levels of CBD in
comparison to THC
anybody else still time for few more
questions
which we all know is very time-consuming
and exhausting and toxic and there and
its cost can you comment on the cost of
this type of regime versus what we're
typically seeing in medicine right the
first of all the one I actually gave a
presentation a couple of years ago where
I took some of the standard I took some
of the standard dosing protocols that
are out there on the internet and in
mouse models and other things and I
extrapolated them forward and showed on
a chart what that would mean for human
consumption and it was ridiculous you
cannot take from mice what you would
give to a human having said that though
what we have found over our years of
experience and working with the plant
and working with patients is that we've
been able to get a pretty good idea of
what the ratios of the major
cannabinoids what the terpene profile to
the best of our ability to understand it
we test for about 33 terpenes right now
I believe is the latest number and we're
able to look at that and create the the
regimen for the patients however it's
it's a lot of it is based upon the
individual comorbidities other
treatments going on with the patient
it's you can't really just say what it
would be but I can tell you that a
patient a woman probably age 45 with
breast cancer let's say she has her to+
or breast cancer she can expect to spend
in below $500 a month during her peak
treatment maybe even a lot less than
that
I have one patient for example one
breast cancer patient right now that
came to us at Stage four she was really
circling the drain so to speak and she
is able to successfully on a hundred
milligrams of CBD and 30 milligrams of
THC along with the other profile of the
plant she's able to have had extreme
reduction in her tumor activity and is
now living a pretty
pretty healthy life so I would say at
that if you look at the cost somewhere
around seven cents a milligram nine
cents a milligram then you can just run
the numbers yourself and figure it out
yes but to your point it's a very
inexpensive way to save your life and
it's a much more comfortable way to do
it the only problem is insurance doesn't
cover it and these are populations that
are usually off of work because they're
sick and they're the most at risk even
when treating the children that might be
on these higher doses a lot of times the
you know nowadays to try to live in
California on one income is almost
unheard of the mother or the father
somebody has to taste stop working to
address the child's needs so right at
the point when they're financially most
at risk is when they then have to take
on treatments that are not covered by
insurance so it's a real problem yes
Thank You Maura for the work you're
doing on the front lines helping
patients and now on the back lines with
the research I really appreciate it
there's a concept that's been spreading
through the medical cannabis world that
THC is a bad thing for estrogen
sensitive breast cancer and I've looked
through the literature to find try to
find any evidence of this and haven't
been able to seems like your research
also disputes that I wonder if you could
comment on this kind of thought process
and how it's been spreading and and what
you're seeing clinically yeah I would
say that first of all thank you I am
another fan of yours as you know and we
have found that that oh there's a lot of
rumors out there and usually when we can
come back to is there either
you know promulgated from the
pharmaceutical industry or from the
naysayers or whomever is trying to keep
people away from using cannabis --is is
an option but what we have found is that
you can keep the THC levels pretty low
in the triple a in the in the breast
cancers and do a lot more with the CBD
and get the same effect but we have not
found that are any of our cancer
patients have had increased tumor
activity as a result of using THC i00
yeah I've had patients where it hasn't
worked but I haven't and that's probably
because we don't know enough about what
the content of that actual medicine
but I've never had a patient where it's
grown as a result of using the medicine
have you seen any examples of people
developing resistance meaning you know
recurrences while they're maintaining
themselves on maintenance doses yeah I
think what happens is people get become
where they don't no longer having the
therapeutic effects depending on what
the effects are that they're going for
because when you are using the cannabis
therapeutically and you get to a
therapeutic dose you do not have to feel
disassociative you do not have to have
the psychotropic effects necessarily etc
you're able to do an awful lot with
without because you titrate up to the
point where it you no longer able to
adjust to that dose and then you know to
back off a little bit because you've
exceeded your therapeutic dose and as a
person improves their health improve the
dose can go down because otherwise that
same dose will start making them feel
more psychotropic effect that they may
or may not be interested in but what
happens is over time you become where
you're acclimated to it and one of the
things that we do about it is we try to
keep our medicines very similar in their
profile for treating different disease
that's but we'll change them up so that
the people are constantly being as
having different medicines that they're
getting in addition to that after about
every six months we tell we suggest that
they titrate down they go off to town to
nothing they spend about 48 to 72 hours
off of any cannabis whatsoever and then
start back up again and find this
they're able to once again increase and
and have their tolerance be much lower
and start having results again from the
medicine
thank you
[Applause]
you