thank you very much for having stayed
that long it's definitely the better
choice you would be just stuck in
traffic so now you're stuck with me and
we are enjoying process chemistry so we
talked so much about the plant genetics
the chemo profiles of the cannabis and
then the cancer effects anti-cancer
effects and other medical effects but
I'm the Loney chemist Wow one of the few
chemists up here and I just wanted to
point out it's not as easy to just say
if OD Kosh works that's the one that
treats your indication and to make this
point that there is a little bit more to
the whole production pipeline than just
like strain and then you're good with
the medical outcome I just want to show
what all happens during these steps for
that I bastardized one of the discs
anomic present a graphical
representations because up here I
devised this kind of visualization and
here in the middle the middle circle
shows us which cannabinoids are present
so the blue ones are THC the red ones
are CBD so this shows the ratio and the
diameter of that circle is how much
there is the total concentration and the
same counts for the terpenes just pon
different point of view out and it's not
important to really remember which
cannabinoids which color and which
doping is which color it's just
important to just understand the basics
like ratio and the diameter is your
concentration I will also not
concentrate on cultivation or
formulation because they are not my
fields of expertise and we talked about
that enough over the last few days so we
do see different strains different
cultivars offer different chemical
profiles on the cannabinoid side not so
much because there as it was pointed out
in a recent paper
is actually not much difference thanks
to being able to test for THC all
cultivars in California and our high THC
if there was the greatest idea we are
not really sure but there is still a
large variation in the terpene profiles
and as you can see you have different
dominant terpenes here's the yellow
that's limonene then that's that's
Mersin and here the orange one is better
clarify lean but you also see them in
different concentrations so and that
there is a difference and terbium
profiles we saw on the talk yesterday
about this this omics and there's also a
very nice paper that talks about the
chemical chemo vas by Fischer dick but
again my focus is on what happens
between you grow it and then you
actually give it to your patient and I
just wanted to point out it might be
obvious but some people might forget
about this too is the way you draw your
plant actually he controls how much
terpenes there is so you don't have much
effect on the cannabinoids itself but if
you do the fast dry like hey I dry and
in four days and then I go on you lose
most of your terpenes and you have to
control the conditions in your drying
room to really control what is left on
the plant in the terpene on the terpene
side and we can take that further
depending on which atmosphere you store
the cannabinoid or the cannabis itself
you again you affect the concentrations
the amounts of terpenes the
concentrations of cannabinoids and even
the ratio of terpenes so if you look at
this here this is blue yellow grey green
which is the same here but if you change
the gaseous now we have instead the gray
we have a blue in here and I really
can't remember which happens they were
but the point is we are changing the
terpene profile so that is good and bad
for one if you wanted something to be
stable don't change your gases but if
you want to be more an artisan approach
- to really modulate the flavor or the
terpene profile you can do this you can
also use all these aspects to compensate
for any variance that might come out
from the grow maybe your lights were off
for a day or you had a hail day more
properly then it's all dead but if it
rained for example too much so and this
is just in the drying and curing aspect
of the cannabis plant then my main field
of research has been on the extraction
side so if we just pick one of the of
the cured strains and we take them along
protip if you want to extract on cue
it's just a waste of time but for the
extraction part it even makes a
difference how you mill different
milling methods will give you different
extracts if you keep everything else the
same and I want to point out the food
blender here because you can't just say
oh I'm millet and then we are good
compared to whole flan because at 2
millimeters we get this basic best yield
out and if you do a food blender which
gives you a very imprecise very particle
size it will be all over the place and
if you care about efficiencies that's
definitely not the way to go and then in
the extraction itself and here I just
show that for supercritical co2
extraction you can really modulate what
you extract I can pick out just the
terpenes I can pick out just the neutral
cannabinoids the THC here or I can
extract a THC acid so the acid form and
have that one relatively purified or
enriched so you can't even go like oh
you took sour cush and extracted it with
co2 you still don't know what you
actually go out and you can't go from
one vendor to the next they properly
don't use the same methods so you can
play with that but it's a as an extract
I myself I can now still use that to
play and modulate so what does the
doctor want what does the patient need
what variants did I get out of the Grove
what do I need to buffer and the same I
can actually do with CBD versus THC
extraction
they do have different solubilities in
co2 so I can now play with that ratio we
know from all these key move our studies
that this cannabis cultivars mostly
extract exclusive tier Express mostly
THC mostly CVD or one-to-one mixture in
the middle but if you want a three to
one from a cultivar you can do that if
you play with your extraction conditions
and for the hemp people if you need to
suppress your THC amount there is a
method there's a way doing that in the
extract and not having to deal with it
afterwards so okay now we're done right
unfortunately not because normally you
post process or most people will post
process the material and the general
thing that is done is decarboxylation
and i've seen it in person
far too often you go in an extraction
room and they have like these two liter
five liter beakers on a hot plate and
it's just bubbling away and so ask them
so how long does that go and they're
like yeah two three hours
not really that precise so we did some
research on like process analytics to
actually track that in real time how it
carboxylates but one of the big
takeaways was if you do decarboxylation
on the air you have oxygen you have heat
there's a lot of stuff that's going on
and in my case here when you do it under
air yeah you get your THC decarboxylated
but you also get delta ath see there's a
cbn and then there is a plethora of
stuff that you don't know like they are
currently known analytical methods that
can tell you what it is
well i'd made the people high it looks
clear so we're good but so far we don't
even know so i would recommend doing
that in under an inert atmosphere so
here x amplified by co2 there's an
oxygen presence so you don't get all
these wild and side reactions and
talking about side reactions that is
still possible
new distillation apparatus if you're
good in distilling you kill these few
percentage of THC a and maybe some other
minor cannabinoids and get rid of all
the flavor and you have like really nice
clear pure THC which we just saw on the
talk before isn't maybe not the thing
you should use anyway but if you don't
really know how to extract and you just
think Lee is king you get all these
other things that are currently still I
unidentified but at least they make you
high so so it's just boggles my mind as
a chemist like they don't know what
they're doing and like most people don't
seem to really care but we really need
to to think about this processing step
also on a very specific and organized
method and I said where I'm not talking
about formulation I just want to do one
case study we have a patient so most all
of this research was done at outcault in
San Diego it's a fully vertically
integrated dispensary so we do see
patients and we had a patient in his mid
30s and he had about eight seizures a
day and the mother was at the end of her
hope everything else then classical
medications didn't work so she comes to
us and wasn't sure that she really wants
to do it is tea cannabis it's weird and
at some point she's like okay we try it
so she takes a bus this CBD THC tincture
with a 1 to 3 ratio 40 milligrams per
milliliter no terpenes because I do
remove them mainly for flavor aspects
out of my extract first and then MCT
also medium chain triglycerides from
coconut oil distillate and the patient
basically went seizure free for weeks
like a so then the mother comes back and
by Stan ice next bottle when it's empty
and it's the same bottle the three to
one oil and the she sees us we start
immediately and like she's freaking out
they in the dispensary freaking out
and this was
earlier this year so I had seen
professor Dini Mary's talk last year at
Harvard and I was like yes I was waiting
for this case because we changed
Kim OVA because we ran out of diamond OG
so we use lemonade haze but we
formulated it exactly to the same
concentrations and the patient ceases
again so we scrap together all the
leftover diamond OG give that to the
patient and the patient is seizure free
again so now I'm sitting there and it's
like that's awesome
and I have until Christmas because then
we are out so I look at this and okay so
CBD THC is exactly the same my
formulation scientists actually can do
his job and waste the materials
correctly we look at the acid forms of
the cannabinoids and they are kind of
the same we even look down our list of
tested molecules they're cbn present CVG
present THC V present and you can't
really say there is a difference and and
then it's CVG and CBC we do see a
present or absence but thanks to the
talks we saw before and that might still
not be the right answer but that's where
my analytics end i right now I have no
access to further analytics and I'm
definitely not going to fractionate my
oils and going to try that on the one
patient if it works or doesn't I'm not
going to do that like 20 different oils
let's see what works but it just we are
we are here at this conference and we
are already happy and yes cannabis works
it's great but it might not be as easy
we we should consider all the steps in
between and there might be hard and I
might be boring like I'm a chemist like
that kills the party normally but but
now when I tell them what I do I own
this party
but I like do you bring samples so we we
shouldn't get ahead of ourselves like
yeah cancer cures everything
cannabis cures everything what cancer
does you're dead and don't care but so
cannabis cures everything like don't
don't let's not do it that easy we still
have to you have a long way ahead of
ourselves and I was talking to a
formulation scientist recently and she's
like yeah we are born in the 1930s with
the progress that's currently there like
we have a few decades to catch up to the
other industries so I have to thank
everyone I worked with so I worked or
work at outcall for now the dispensary
in San Diego that does all the work and
gives me all the material on these
optimization studies where you saw the
few disks that's about ten kilos or
twenty pounds of weed per disc just to
get the data points so that's a lot of
stuff but it makes it money back
afterwards and so then the other
companies we worked with is Nate for the
controls in the drawing room
Henkel Minh was for the gases and the
curing fridge is the milling study apex
is all the extraction work PerkinElmer
was the work we did for process
analytics and we did make it to the end
what I want to point out is I'm getting
kind of frustrated with like these
things we currently do and don't do yet
and can't do so therefore I wanted to
mention that earlier you don't actually
have to take pictures of it because I'll
upload everything on SlideShare and
otherwise if you have any questions or
want to do any collaborations please
find me there there are votes next month
I can't I'm German I'm heading to Canada
and I do some work there so please find
me there thank you
we have time for a couple questions if
you like I just clarify with those two
preparations were you fortifying with
isolated compounds to reach those equals
three-to-one levels we fortified with
CBD isolate yes we only grow THC strains
so we used isolated CBD and are you
aware if the patient has had a chance to
try CBG or CB GA I have no access to
that purified so I can't offer that
great thank you
any more questions thank you very much
round of applause dr. mark raucous
brilliant