[Music]
I'm Rob big Leone I'm co-founder of
horizon formulas em cash and I'm gonna
talk about cryptocurrencies and
blockchain technology in general at Ken
Med conference and there's a few really
important themes that I want to go over
one is on the payment side and how
applicable equipt of currency payments
are to the medical marijuana industry
for a variety of reasons one being that
regulations and access to banking
services do vary quite significantly
across different states on different
parts of the world so having a kind of a
unifying payment system why
cryptocurrencies I think it's very
useful for the industry and the second
big aspect is blockchain technology
lends itself very well to as an
entrepreneurial platform a framework
upon which businesses can now start
leveraging the technology and making
services
you know easier for their users so I'm
going to talk about these two general
strands and one big unifying element to
all of this stuff is the commonality of
philosophy I think between the the
Bitcoin world and the original movement
where we are resigned and horizon and
where the medical marijuana industry is
is it there's a kind of a fundamental
belief and the right to privacy and
personal choice so these are really big
themes that I think linked the
industries together so I'm really happy
to talk to the conference
[Music]
you