[Music]
but could it be something that you know
Growers sort of um I mean it' be an
extra Revenue stream for them that they
could be providing that um that waste
material to to your company or whoever
whoever is going to develop this um turn
that into that's the dream yeah the
dream is to get extra revenue for
Growers get a safe
biopesticide uh for
producers and uh you know expand this
because you know if you have something
that is uh naturally broken down by what
whatever is in the environment on the
plant in the soil and that type of thing
that's these natural products are broken
down easily more easily than synthetics
uh and then you so you have something
that's environmentally friendly you have
something that Growers get an extra
Revenue stream from um and that you know
and it works so if you have all of those
three things you've got the kind of the
pillars of developing a a a
biopesticide great and so where are we
at in terms of sort of evaluating
whether it works or actually getting to
Market so kind of where are you at there
well I'm I'm hoping that the interest
from cmed will bring people around that
that want to invest in it to be honest
with you uh we would love to see this go
into a uh a company and uh develop this
technology so that it could be available
to
everyone yeah and so what is sort of
the how how do you get something like
this approved um what are the sort of
agencies that dictate that it's a it's
EPA and the uh there are are there are
rules for biopesticides for uh
developing those that are less stringent
than um those for synthetics because
most of the those things are natural uh
so we would go through the EPA uh we
would we would then you know we would
tell them everything that's in ours uh
and how it is used and how it's
formulated and then we would uh show
them the efficacy because they approve
it unless it's going to it's going to
work uh and uh they will do that but
they have approved other essential oils
like garlic oil uh rosemary oil those
types of things are already approved as
biopesticides and some of the same uh
Turing are in those as well
[Music]
a