[Music]
and one of the things that my lab has
been working on um we do have some uh
some funding from the USDA as part of a
a larger multi-state project and uh
we've been looking at uh at what is the
called the critical weed-free period in
hemp and and all crops have this uh sort
of
theoretical concept where you know if
you can control the weeds during so many
weeks initially as the crop gets
established then you can maintain uh you
know reasonable yields by the end of the
season so there's this critical period
when uh plants are are more sensitive to
competition and you have to to Really
take care of the weeds during that
period of time well we were looking at
this and uh there were students in my
lab that were weeding hand weeding our
hemp plots uh at different intervals
throughout the season so some of the
plots were not weeded at all you know we
planted the hemp and and walked away
basically and then uh there was a there
was a treatment that was only weeded for
a week and then two weeks and three
weeks and so on and there was one
treatment that was weeded for the entire
season um so we were all a little
surprised when we did a preliminary
analysis of the data and we found that
statistically there was no difference
whether or not we we didn't weed the
plants at all or whether we weeded for
87 days which was the entire season wow
so exactly
that's that's what we thought as well um
we could see a little bit of evidence
for um heavy grass competition so we
could see that the plots where had where
there was a lot of grass uh competing
around um those were our 14-day weed
weed treatments but but we could see a a
hit in the overall biomass uh with some
of the competition but it was just
amazing that statistically there was no
difference so so we're now in our second
year of that study and we'll be um doing
a more um detailed data analysis and
we'll be looking at all the different
yield components because that was just a
rough look at overall biomass of uh
fiber and Dual Purpose crops so um so
yeah it's it seems like um it's one of
those crops where if it gets a head
start it's it's fairly competitive
interesting yeah so timing is everything
yeah it is it is no but so just want to
make sure I heard that correctly so the
amount that you weeded whether you did
none at all or you weeded throughout the
whole thing it did it didn't have an
effect on the overall yield at the end
it didn't on the overall biomass that
was produced not looking at quality of
fiber or amount of seed yield so just
overall plant biomass now there may be
differences for each of those components
right because plants will uh in that's
it's an investment strategy right so um
they may have been investing in growth
and inst structure and putting less into
seed production for example so uh now
that we have two years of data I I hope
that we're able to sort of tease apart
any any of those differences but um and
and now we do have of course we have a a
pre-emergence herbicide that's labeled
as well so if uh if Farmers want to grow
hemp now there's there's more um more
tools available uh to give the hemp a
head
[Music]
start