okay so I'm paranoid of the voice of God
so I'm gonna be dashing through this
presentation so this is if you haven't
quite captured the power of
cryptocurrency hopefully this project
will sum it up a lot of people think
it's used for nefarious uses but
actually they're now funding scientific
purposes scientific projects their
funding charities all over the world and
- decided back in the in the spring time
to fund this project and what is this
project about well John gave a great
description what you can do with the
current genomes you can do a lot however
if you look around other plant genomes
that have much larger a much smaller
economic impact in cannabis their
genomes are much better shape than ours
the cannabis genome right now is in is
in horrible shape compared to these
things and it does create some artifacts
Philippe showed some artifacts where you
try and replicate markers and the
primers fall in snips and it doesn't
reproduce and we've seen this with a lot
of the vendors supplying sequencing
services as well that the things just
don't fully reproduce lab to lab we got
to changed that and the best way to
change that is to actually sequence the
genome to a quality of at least what the
human genome project had back in 2001
and the metric back then was to get to
about 500 KB and 50 what that means is
the average length of the sequence
contig in the assembly was about 500,000
letters this is not perfect this is we
want chromosomes that are hundreds of
millions of bases long that are
completely contiguous and completely
phased but this is the best we could do
back then nowadays I think you'll find
the hurdle rate for a good genome people
will say is if you're in the mega base
Club they want this n 50 number to be
north of a million bases and I'm gonna
show you how we pulled this off on the
Cannabis genome so there are several
reasons to do this that Jon touched on I
won't go very long we want
marker-assisted selection we want
accelerated breeding we want reliable
snip chips which I don't think you can
get off the existing references and we
we want to do this on as many genomes as
possible not just any one sort of
victory' genome we want a pan genome we
want type 1 genomes type two genomes
type 3 genomes type 4 type 5 you name it
hemp lines we really want 12 really
powerfully done genomes to make sense of
what's going on now some some
terminology here you're probably you
to hearing about context this is what a
normal assembly turns into a couple
hundred thousand of these and we really
want to get it into chromosomes like
this and there's a technologies from
phaz genomics impact bio that help do
this that we'll touch on but this is
really important for you to understand
where those chromosomes came from like
if they're in certain organelles or if
they're in certain microbes that often
contaminate genome assemblies so we
started off sequencing a jamaican lion
strain and this was a strain that I
selected mainly because it had some
impact on my father he was using type 2
strains but there was also some
controversy over IP and we figured let's
see if we can shed some light on that
and I also like teasing mark Lewis once
in a while and trolling him a little bit
so I decided that let's sleep on
something that that he may have bred I
think this is actually dates back to
2007 and there's some awards that won
and it is a type 2 plant and it looks as
if it is beta care off the lean dominant
a little bit immersing in there as well
these might vary based on conditions
this is all grown in a hydro to get rid
of microbes or at least to limit the
microbes but you can see the the the
reports down here in terms of the DH
it's about a 2 to 1 CBD to THC line so
how do we do this well - as Chuck just
described it consists of these master
node owners that are all over the world
that vote on how to spend their Treasury
and you submit them proposals and they
decide will this help us improve our
network and they're interested in
solving the banking problem in cannabis
industry and they saw this conference
and they saw this genome and said let's
do it
let's build the best reference in the
world and then we can maybe even build a
seed to sale tracking system that is
forensic in quality so they voted on
this in in June third and this is what's
crazy about the process is you submit
the the grant application we should
probably spend it a week before the
deadline and and by a week later we had
- in our bank ready to spend and were
able to kick the project off so this is
the summer time June third we started
you PCR screening for type two plants
this is little color metric ass that we
have that can tell you whether it's type
1 2 or 3 we all then went into Illumina
sequencing to screen for hetero zygosity
just pick a plant that had the less of
that because that would be better to
sequenced as a first genome and then we
got to go back to these old-school - the
tools of actually doing pulsed field gel
electrophoresis to get high molecular
weight DNA this is
really critical if you get DNA as long
as possible because the read lengths we
have now in these single molecule
sequencers can actually get out to fifty
to a hundred thousand bases and so we
chose to do this on the Pacific
Biosciences platform because it had the
highest accuracy there are some other
nanopores up there that have longer
reads for the accuracy right now when we
played around with that last year at cam
and we couldn't get those assemblies to
gel so we turn back to pack bio and look
for higher accuracy reads and fed at DNA
that could actually get us these 32,000
base pair reads and we assembled this by
August third and put it public at about
a 650 KB and 50 so we beat the Human
Genome Project draft I should say in a
matter of a couple months 60 days from
getting funded to putting it public and
this isn't the end of the story we then
decided to team up with faze genomics to
turn this thing into a perfection genome
and what these folks do is they use
something called chromatin capture which
basically cross links the proteins that
are attached to the DNA and it tends to
mostly do that to inter chromosomally so
you don't get chromosome to chromosome
cross links as much as you get
neighboring DNA cross links and so what
you can get from this technology are
pieces of DNA sequence that are millions
of bases apart but are on the same
chromosome and then you can order up all
your chromosomes into pretty pictures so
we did 600 million high c reads like
this on Illumina to to get the high C
data together threw it into an assembly
and we ended up with a 5.4 mega base and
50 genome still not perfect but but you
know we're up above the mega base Club
but we realized you know what we really
want to get this into like the 50
megabase range so that we have full
chromosomes that are touching and we can
phase the genome so we went back and did
more PacBio sequencing on their latest
chemistry it's a version 6 chemistry
that does 42,000 base pair reads and I
think it can do longer this is probably
limited on the type in the quality of
DNA we gave them and it gave the
laboratory that was doing this you
really need to get that DNA as long as
you can so that you can maximize that
the throughput on these on these systems
so this one into another assembly a
falcon assembly and this raw assembly
unscaled it without any of the high C
data trying to glue the context together
came out at three times this one mega
base Club all right we're at 3.7 mega
bases of just the PacBio date alone and
that
fantastic to give you some perspective
on where that is in it slider so is she
where other historical assemblies were
and then of course we quickly uploaded
this into a preprint server because our
funding cycle is ending by the end of
October and we really wanted to have the
chapter closed on starting a funding to
end of funding we're gonna have a pre
printout that represents all this data
so what are these platforms Sara gave a
great talk in the other hallway and what
Pacific Biosciences is these are single
molecule sequencers so that trace you
see if there is actually a single
molecule going through a zero mode
waveguide with a polymerase that's
putting in fluorescently labelled
nucleotides and you are watching a movie
of a polymerase replicating DNA at a
single molecule levels absolutely
mind-blowing Star Trek stuff and they
can do millions of these wells at a time
which is which is which is fascinating
and then the other one is this this high
C approach that phase genomics was doing
and what this does is it really gives
you three-dimensional structures of the
genome because their genomes not these
perfect beautiful linear chromosomes
it's actually a big Gordian knot and
when you cross link that you end up
cross-linking certain DNA into certain
compartments of cells like the
mitochondrial DNA ends up in one place
and the chloroplast ends up in another
and then all of them might the the
microbial contamination end up
cross-linked in their own buckets
because they have they have nucleuses
and other cell walls that are kind of
constraining them so this helps
partition cells into the buckets that
the DNA actually exists in inside the
cell so you can do much more complete
and thorough assembly so this is one of
the first ones that we did and the most
I think the most remarkable thing about
this technique is that you don't need
high molecular weight do you need to do
this you take the tissue and you just
cross-linked it with formaldehyde and
then you chop the DNA up but once it's
cross-linked this huge loops of mega
bases apart get cut and you like ate
them and you're effectively reading the
ends of these large loops of DNA and you
end up building these maps and so what
the map that you have here is a contact
map it's one of the earliest ones that
we have so it typically you want to say
really bright line in the middle we're
not completely getting that yet with
cannabis because of the the repeat
content in it but it is bucketing now
into ten nice chromosomes which is what
we want to see we want to see chromosome
1 through chromosome through all the way
through the x and y chromosomes as well
and we want to see two of them all right
because the cannabis is diploid
most of the time and that's the neck
Faye's that we have to do no pun
intended is we have to then take this
diploid genome and split it into the two
maternal paternal chromosomes for every
one of them and then organize them
okay so just put the brakes on here and
look at what types assembly as we
traditionally have so back in 2001
John's group and our group played around
with assembling these some of these
genomes with Illumina data and they
ended up in hundreds of thousands of
pieces and the average contact size was
like around 3,000 bases okay
that's that's very small contig size
when you consider the human genome
declared victory on a draft at 500,000
bases and then many other people started
chipping and steep hill put out a really
nice assembly that then bumped this
number up likewise Philo's put one in
there and I think that the N 50 number
got up to 159 KB that was the longest
can most contiguous assembly and it was
on kin atomic which was a type 3 strain
so we weren't getting much information
out of the THC genetics from that strain
but it was still giving us great insight
into maybe the CBD genetics so then we
jumped on to Jamaican Lian and started
pumping these numbers up into the 648
region in the 665 region with just the
pack bio assembly alone and then when
they terminate when we top this off with
version six chemistry these numbers all
jump to 3.7 mega base and 50 results so
it's really we're really talking about
thousands of fold improvement over
contiguity from where we started in 2011
to what we have what we have today so
very fast response working with with
cryptocurrency folks say they they move
very quickly and it really helps to get
the public the data out there publicly
we did play around with trying to figure
out some aspects of this genome with the
existing assemblies we had we published
a preprint that we never really
converted into a paper because it just
opened up this onion of confusion once
we did this we we did we did PCR
amplification of THC synthase with two
different primer sets and some primer
sets that were described in the
literature from a group name from the
Onofre paper we're sitting right inside
the gene so when they amplified this
they were the primers were sitting on
the start and stop codon and they're a
little bit blind to the variation in the
start and the stop codons and that's
going to mean something in a minute
but you'll see when we amplify with
those Onofre primers we amplify a lot of
copies and we don't know where they
the genome we just amplify them in
sequence them and we know that they're
unique copies because they have high
confidence polymorphisms between them
but we don't know the order of them in
the genome and I don't know where they
go in the genome and we don't
necessarily know if they're fully active
in the genome we just saw there's a lot
of those copies we then backed those
primers out to amplify with more unique
regions in the genome and we started
getting much fewer genes that were
coming through and the ones that were
coming through seem to all be
full-length there weren't any stop
codons in them and they looked as if
they were really good
th-these in face context now when you
get a good genome reference this is what
happens is they all show up in a tandem
array so interestingly enough THC
synthase has replicated itself almost
like it's kind of skidded across the
genome and so here's one region and one
contact that has five different copies
of THC synthase but they're all mutated
substantially in fact I don't even know
if we want to call some of these th T's
in face because they're mutated probably
they're probably only 85% identity and
then likewise you can look at another
con take that is the one that contains
can have a chromium synthase now we know
that this thing actually is for tandem
copies about 30 or 40 KB apart and you
probably can't see this but there are
some mutations in the three prime end
and the 5 prime end that changed the
amino acid structure such that primers
probably missed this in the past because
they would haven't placed on those
sequences theirs happens to be two more
copies of this and another content in
the genome that's now been linked by the
hi-c data so there's actually six copies
of this thing and they're all slightly
diverged and we don't know if they fold
at the same rate or if they maybe fold
some of the other rare cannabinoids that
these need to be cloned and expressed
and a lot of the work that John's done
on this gene needs to be repeated with
maybe some of these and that some of
these variants this is how many we're
finding that have at least 80% identity
there's 30 different DNA sequences and
this is a cladogram of them and the
scaffolds that they're sitting on on the
genome so we can see there's a lot of
cannabinoid diversity cannabinoid
synthase diversity and then if you if
you kind of Whittle those down and say
well which one is a really full-length
and possibly functional because some of
these are so mutated maybe they're just
they're just pseudogenes and we get down
to it about 18 of these different THC
synthase jeans that look like they're
they possibly could be in actually
encode for something that's a
full-length don't know what they do we
need to be teaming up with people that
can probably clone these express them
and get more information on
now in terms of assay development as
Philippe was touching on this is what we
were dealing with before is that this is
a mapping to the references that were
made back in 2011 and if you're not
careful when you map to these genomes
these blue reads are paired reads that
means they're Illumina reads we have a
forward and reverse read and they both
map to the genome the thing highlights
it blue red and green are ones where we
can only map one of the reads to the
genome and not the other and so
something's wrong and those ones you
should always kind of discount us with
and I should trust them but even with
these blue ones you can see paired reads
there are four snips in here that
probably don't really exist and what
this is when you map these same reads to
Jamaican lie and you see that those
reads then map to those other genes that
we just found that are tandem and so it
cleans up a lot of your mapping it
cleans up a lot of your polymorphism
discovery and now we have a reference
where we can actually maybe go ahead and
make a snip chip out of this and not be
confusing all the signals that that we
might get out of the chip so phase
genomics then stepped into this to try
and phase the genome which is using this
hi-c stuff to peel apart the maternal
and paternal haplotypes so that we can
have a perfectly phased genome and when
they run this through a bus going now
I'm starting out of busco but this is a
cost analysis it looks at how many
pieces of the genome you have it's it's
up in the 800 range there and you can
see the end 50 numbers are getting
closer to 5.4 mega bases the more
complete genomes a little bit more 80
rich I don't have time to go into this
we are publishing this on - and what
that means is we're using an incentive
I'd review system to speed it up we
select 3 3 reviewers we end up putting
out a cryptocurrency bounty for doing
the review and everything every
communication they do ends up getting
hashed onto the blockchain so it's
completely censorship resistant and
transparent so the phasing stuff is
tough right this is what typical genomes
should look like as it should have two
different copies of this of this genome
and then what typically happens is
genomes get collapsed if they're not if
they're really homozygous like humans
they get collapsed into one copy they
can't discern the material from the
paternal because there's only a snip
every hundred bases mean or every
thousand bases we wanted we wanted to
tease those apart and you do this with a
program called purge applet eggs which
looks for coverage differences among the
contexts rips the ones that are high out
of the
sure and then you can begin to zip these
things into even better maps and we have
here and if you add in bigger data from
PacBio these things turn into this mess
now this is actually not a mess it looks
like a mess for you but actually we're
seeing here is the numbers that popped
out of this 475 mega base in 50 contexts
this means we have perfect chromosomes
that are all sorted now there might be a
couple gaps in between the scaffolding
from high C which we can fill with a
couple other programs that they're
recommending like Polar Star and another
tool that helps to connect those things
called PB jelly and we're in that
process right now to just now polish
these things and fill the gaps but I
think it's safe to say that we now have
a genome that is better than most of the
other agricultural crops out there and
this is just more statistics I won't
bore you with but what the future is
going to hold is we have a cross of this
going on so we can get a tree oh it's
with its brother and what we're gonna do
in the future is a lot more methylation
sequence a lot more RNA sequencing and
we're gonna do some more trio work and
maybe build some some really powerful
snip chips so I want to thank all these
people involved there's a lot of
volunteers that jumped into this project
and made this work and I should leave
some time for a question or two thanks
please come up to the mics and ask any
questions hey Kevin thanks a lot for for
the talk I do have a question you
mentioned the the repeats on on the THC
and cannabinoid synthase and I think you
probably saw a lot on Turpin synthesis
can you comment a little bit on
oh thank you for bringing it up so we've
done a little bit of looking into the
terpene synthase genes as well to be
honest luca and and keep a Lynette steep
hill have been digging it a little bit
more we've got a kind of a little
community here that I know that you're
involved with that they're staring down
that they're remapping all of John's RNA
sequencing data onto the new assemblies
and the terpene synthase cluster is even
bigger there's many more of those to
work through
I this I'm kind of new to this does this
mean anything of value can be sold or
distributed to anybody or everybody are
you referring to the blockchain side of
this or or the Cannabis sequencing is
out of this if I have a photograph of
Jimi Hendrix does that mean it can be
somehow quantified into some massive
distribution or so there are there are
things going on on the theorem network
where people will get art and hash it
onto aetherium and you can get certain
number of digital copies that are
verifiable so that that art is
effectively scarce digitally if you will
and there's some unique attributes the
music industry that that plays a role in
but I think I'm getting a getting the
god light coming up on me over here so I
think with this we're going to turn this
over into a more Q&amp;A with the panel to
talk about medicinal cannabis and I
would like to invite all of our
panelists up for this this event