community it's an indispensable
component of any successful business
cannabis included networking
collaboration in strategic partnerships
and the evolution of our industry this
conference has demonstrated the dynamic
reality of shifting social attitudes and
greater acceptance of the medical
efficacy of cannabis by the scientific
and medical communities the need to work
together though is greater than ever
hyper-competitive attitudes only serve
the needs of a selective view in
actuality we operate in the nage of
unprecedented information sharing to
that end can med is notably created a
space to share cannabis information in a
very meaningful way we all appreciate
this opportunity today and that mission
that are honored to be speaking here in
our work community literally starts from
the ground up
nature crafts complex ecosystems that we
growers nurture this Raisa soma
ecosystem forms the base community that
supports everything else that we do as
an industry this panel was formed to
discuss the intricacies inherent in the
simple concept of community gentlemen
it's great to have you here today thank
you very much great to be here we all
have impacted our collective cannabis
community in very different ways so to
have an opportunity to assemble you all
in one place is really really special
again thank you for being here each of
us represents a thread in the communal
fabric that is cannabis can man has
helped reinforced the importance of
establishing a dynamic cannabis
community and I welcome regimen
David Big Mike and Jason to discuss that
very subject today so you start off you
guys well you know when we first started
we're in the black market
okay and the community was very limited
to who we could talk to and who do we
could speak to in fact we kind of had a
closed-off mindset when it came to that
kind of thing because we didn't know if
they were the man or we're gonna be
going to jail well now it's a whole
different world out there and we must
work together the more that I
collaborate the more that I meet people
and I talk to them this is how things
get done in today
society now look you gonna have to go be
like your secret secret trade stuff out
but there's this community now that's
out there that's open and willing to
discuss things and we should embrace
that we want to get things done we want
to move this industry faster it's gonna
be collaboration personally I like to
talk to everyone and anyone that I can
that can help out and that I can help
them in sharing information that you
might come in from the cultivation
coming from the cultivation side you
know in the black market days nobody
wanted to share any of their secrets you
wanted to keep you know your special
sauce in there as we're expanding and
starting larger scale cultivation
centers and then what will be acres and
acres of cannabis cultivation we're all
gonna deal with the same problem same
powdery mildew botrytis for sehri and
things like that these problems are not
necessarily in the secret sauce these
are problems that all of us have to deal
with and that all of us should work
together on and figure out safe and
effective treatments for these problems
as well as you know just building a team
in a community throughout this cannabis
industry David so I guess I'm here to
represent academia and so for me
academia needs to work and and Hanan
with the industry so that's one thing
for sure and then the other thing is
that right now so I'm from Canada so of
course things that are a little bit
different but a lot of companies are
paying like our developing research
project with academia to do things but
they want to keep everything secret so a
lot of money is wasted because like the
same research is done by a lot of
different groups separately so if we
would work more together like networking
and like a collaborative competition or
computational collaboration I'm not sure
how to call it but anyway it would be
way better for the industry move faster
because no money would be wasted on
replicating the same experiments over
and over in different groups thank you
graduate I think for me it's been a
little different as a scientist you know
we publish that's how we do things right
and the publish or perish thing is a
very real thing even in the cannabis
industry because we have investors who
are like well you know why are we paying
you all this R&amp;D money if if nobody
knows what we're doing right so but I do
understand that we've had a huge
evolution of what community means
because when I came into the industry
and I tried to start to talk to some of
the underground breeders said hey what
about sequencing let's study your
genetics that was not a very popular
thing right so but it's come a long way
right and and I think now you know just
recently me and my team published a
paper on the chirping you know new genes
in cannabis and I think you know if we
had not been a community minded like
organization that would have been held
behind and patented right so I think it
is really important for for academia
industry for the industry to understand
that we get further along in our common
goal because we do have a common goal
right and that common goal is keeping
the industry to ourselves and not having
big AG or whatever come and take it from
us I think as long as we keep that in
mind
community kind of falls into place so
totally and I think for me the fear was
when I got started that my community
would ultimately end up being jailed if
I were to be caught or we work too
closely together it collaborated so to
say that we've come a long way there's
an understatement I also feel that if we
don't collaborate if you if you're one
of those people who want to hold on to
all your secrets you're gonna get left
behind and your secrets are gonna leave
with you too thanks guys how do you see
the relationship between microbial and
fungal communities as they relate to
overall plant health what is investment
in a healthy and vital roses crisis
normal community translate you know our
life period
listen microbes are so important there
would be no trees no grass no prairies
if it wasn't for beneficial microbes and
when you talk about fungal
I don't know who did the study but they
did a study where they used radioactive
isotopes and they wanted to check out
the soil web in these trees and so they
fed the one tree and to their amazement
none of the isotopes were in that tree
they were in a tree four hundred yards
away and then there is another tree a
hundred yards away another 140 class
they're sending and they're
communicating with each other and
they're putting in the vital nutrients
and what they're looking for for
survival and they're helping each other
out in that forest it's extremely
important nothing lives without microbes
plants no community I really do think
the cannabis industry is going to be
driving the study of this now that we
have the funding and the the desire to
see this I think cannabis right now is
in its infancy what we're really doing
right now is just trying to out-compete
the bad we're putting our back Phyllis's
that our bacillus is in there GLIAC
ladies um
Pseudomonas is in there to out-compete
but we're really not sure which one of
these is the most effective right now
and I think it's going to require a lot
of bomb a lot of research and a lot of
science behind it that you know the
growers see see the cause and effect and
we see the benefits of these but we
don't know exactly which is doing the
most there and which is specific
cannabis and which is just specific to
out competing other detrimental
detrimental of biologicals interesting
so you know it's interesting because
there is a whole set of terpene genes
that are only expressed in the roots
right so clearly there is communication
between the plant and the soil so that
communication is there for a reason the
the terpenes that get expressed in the
roots are likely and they're mostly
monoterpenes so they are able to be
volatilized and spread easily in the
soil right so that means that there's
some sort of conditioning or attraction
repellent reno repellent kind of thing
going on where the plant is
communicating to the soil what it needs
and in response the soil is providing it
with the nutrients and also the
beneficial microbes that are helping
that's that life cycle you know progress
right so the
is communication that does it's a living
mat right from the soil up to the planet
it's one big living organism so I think
to make the link with the first question
again it's it's one place where I mean
we need to see the results from all the
different groups that are working in
that aspect so there was Daniel and ryx
that we're showing is results my group
is doing similar thing about playing
with the microbiome of cannabis curry
there's a lot of improvements that can
be done in that area for sure I think
there's a lot of research we still need
to do to understand the relationships
between the microbes the fungi in the
overall plant health but one thing that
we can all agree on is they're linked
there's definitely a strong relationship
with a healthy community their mandatory
testing boy that's been a hot button
issue in the last couple years hasn't it
how do you guys interact with the
regulatory bodies that govern how you
operate your business and you ever run
into trouble and how do you feel about
mandatory testing well I love mandatory
testing third parties that that cannot
be bought or corrupted we need to go
through another kind of cycle of testing
where we have labs that are just they're
there to help the community make sure
that safe products are going out and
they can't be bought so yeah I would
agree with that as well mandatory
testing we need it we need safe products
out there what we do need is is
standards you know lots of labs have
different standards lots of labs have
different techniques we need mandated
standards so that we get consistent
results through any lab that you use on
I know in Colorado there's a game to be
played especially when it comes to
potency testing some labs will give you
better results than others and we also
know that you can take the same sample
and test it in three different methods
and get three different on three
different results with it so really
standardizing standardizing the way that
these third-party labs test and then you
know making sure that there is some
governing bodies that make sure that
these companies are not bought out or
that you're not paying extra to get you
know that a couple percent your THC
potencies so for me in Canada I guess
it's a little bit different but
like for me I I think that there could
be exception to mandatory testing for
people like me doing research like I'm
not selling any product I mean I so to
me it like sometime it does not make
sense that I'm required to do like to
have my my product tested even though I
just wanted to you know weight them and
have an idea of it did I get an
improvement using that experiment so I I
understand that like for companies it's
it's something that should stay like
that but for research I I think there
should be some like exceptions that's my
point
I don't know if I should speak on this
coming from a lab previously I recuse
myself from this one so but you know if
we're gonna treat it like a medicine if
we're gonna call it a medicine it should
be treated like a medicine and so that's
a lot to say on that one so 20% I've
been operating in Arizona for the last
decade and we got mandatory testing like
last week and up until this point the
onus of responsibility has been up to
dispensary owners and cultivators to
maintain standards of purity and as a
result patients and suffered Aspergillus
powdery mildew black toxic mold they've
all made it out onto the into the
patient scene and as a result people
have gotten sick so people have died
right so this is this is no [ __ ]
right people have died from
aspergillosis and other things like that
right so you know it's not the cannabis
that's killing them but it's bad
cannabis that when put into the wrong
body creates a bad situation right so
and and for that reason alone again if
it's if we're gonna use it as medicine
that should be treated like medicine
well I think you're right you have
individuals that are so profit focused
that they'll sacrifice the well-being of
their patients to bring a product to
market and that's why third-party
testing and so mandatory thank you very
much let's chat about the value of
networking how do you feel about
collaboration versus competition about
co-branding global distribution change
and research between nations and
global partners that have similar
cannabis legislation to our own or
enhanced legislation like Canadians I
think in today's cannabis world
collaboration is a must there there's so
much competition out there and we need
to get together in groups of the
smartest people and collaborate who know
what they're doing and make superior
products for the patients that are out
there collaboration is extremely
important in today's day and age
especially coming out of a black market
where we didn't collaborate with people
[Applause]
once again from the cultivation side as
we get more and more into this and we
progress further along we're starting to
find that you need to really specialize
in areas you know your breeder needs to
be a specialist
even your propagators and your your your
Fino hunters need to be specialists on
this and well a lot of the early
emerging markets were required to be
vertically integrated now as some of
those requirements are going away
there's no way around joining forces
with other teams and with other
companies that may have a specialty that
you don't possess otherwise you know
years will be wasted in research that
someone else has already done just by
not sharing it so I'm lucky enough to be
from a province where the government
actually created an office that is
responsible to build that cannabis
industry in the province so they're
trying to link the industry with the
academia and and third-party testing
agency and the health authorities so and
they're traveling to word trying to lure
companies to New Brunswick so it's very
nice to see that but we're almost the
only province that has that and I hope
at some point the other will will follow
our steps and that you will have the
same here in the u.s. once it's
legalized but the other point I'm I'm
gonna raise here is that I would also
like to see more collaboration between
Canada and the US because since it's
legal on our side of the country or off
the border there's a lot of things we
can do that you cannot do now so you
know by playing together then maybe you
can act come
there's more and get ready quicker for
when it's gonna be legal here I think
the ultimate collaboration will be when
we can actually start to ship stuff
across borders and it's what one big
global economy and I think that's what
ultimately we have to go for and the
only way you do that is to get back to
standards and a oneness right you you
need to have some governing body that
steps in and says this is the way we
have to do it so that the labs are
performing the same way and so that
everybody has the same target and then
we don't have 87 different freaking like
you know regulations because they test
for 22 pesticides but they test for 104
pesticides right so you know human human
safety is not a commodity and and all
humans suffer from the same things more
or less right so I don't understand why
there are different regulations in the
first place it seems to me when you have
different regulations you're saying that
some people are more or less susceptible
to certain things and other people which
is a crock of [ __ ] right so can I say
that we're not on TV right so you know
so I think that's what we really need to
strive for in the industry and and I
think it has to come from in the
industry right if we wait for the USDA
or the European Union or whoever to do
it and they're gonna come down with
regulations that we don't like and I
think if we drive it from the inside and
come up with stuff that that is sane and
reasonable and promotes good products
for the patients I think we'll have a
standard that they would adopt right and
I think that's ultimately what we should
be in for so I'd love to see sanity and
reason from our government period let's
move on ours is a global community with
unprecedented access to technology our
online communities and forums have
become more prevalent what relationship
do you feel our industry will have with
tech and online communities I find them
to be a good place to start
you know you hit the message boards when
you find a problem that you
you haven't encountered before or
something that you're looking at you'll
hit the message board see you know see
some of the smaller scale growers what
they've run into things that they've
tried stuff like this um but I think as
we mature as an industry we need to
start moving towards purity papers you
know real research with solid controls
and actual things done other than just
you know my 4/20 guy up there on it
saying this is absolutely tobacco mosaic
virus or something something similar to
that so I really think it's a good place
to start but as we move forward we
really need to start going into a more
scientific field more peer-reviewed more
real data
I think the boards are great especially
for first-time growers and people coming
into our industry think of the
information that they're looking for and
then obviously as you graduate there
should be March the board that go all
the way up into the scientific community
where we can talk to each other in the
language where we understand it doesn't
sound like a foreign language when we're
speaking with someone that's needed as
well I've got a lot of project ideas by
looking at those forums so it's always a
nice place to look but as you said so
like I think we should move toward more
like peer-reviewed articles and like
more curated source especially like I
have a plant pathology background so I'm
interested like in cannabis diseases and
this is one of the worst example like
you will see a lot of pictures and then
people oh this is that thing and this is
that thing and often it's not that at
all like I seen many people saying this
is rust I'm sure nobody has ever seen
rust on cannabis so there's a lot of
misinformation so I think that's why we
need to move toward like more curated
platforms and stuff like that no I agree
hundred percent although I will say that
when I first started growing and I had
brown spots and I didn't know what they
were I I went to the board
gene-editing and genetic intellectual
property will become hot topics in
popular culture in our scientific
community and indeed here at can MIT
what does genetic modification in
cannabis actually mean and how do you
feel about this technology oh I'm sorry
so go genetic modification so let's look
let's start with the definition right so
cuz a lot of things that we talk about
in the cannabis industry are not GMO
right so if when you have a knockout
that's used CRISPR or something like
that that's GMO right and but
technically it's not even GMO because
traditionally GMO was you introduced DNA
from a from another organism into that
recep recipient organism right that was
technically why European Union went nuts
and genetic modification was banned and
bla bla bla right so so when you use
CRISPR to knock a gene out is that
really genetic modification or is that
just accelerated breeding because we use
marker-assisted breeding to do the same
thing and that's not genetic
modification because we use traditional
breeding techniques we just accelerated
right so having said that have at it i I
mean I completely agree so there's a lot
of stuff that is not considered genetic
modification and that people can grow
organic and one example is that crops
have been like irradiated to produce
mutation like the red grapefruit is an
example so CRISPR to me is just the same
thing but instead of you know having
thousands of unknown mutation you have
one mutation exactly where you want so
if you want to consider gene editing as
a GMO then all those array-like
gamma-irradiated crop need to be
considered GMO as well what people
aren't aware of a lot of the vegetables
and fruits that you're eating today have
been gene edited in it and then you can
use both a conventional path or gene
editing I think the two go hand-in-hand
but the future in cannabis you're going
to see a lot of gene editing it's going
to
we're looking at it now we're doing it
now I I think that it's important it's
not considered GMO and you can get to
the results in some cases a lot quicker
so I personally like it I agree with all
the panelists here I think there's no
way around at least gene editing in our
field on I mean let's be honest we have
read nothing for resistance to pathogens
diseases anything that we've bred
strictly for smell flavor taste potency
excuse me we've really bred for nothing
but one see smell taste looks like that
nothing that that affects resistance to
anything and we're really behind we're
gonna need to really step up as an
industry to make sure that it's done
safely and it's done carefully and with
with some purpose as we move forward but
there's just no way around using it to
kind of get back in line with the big
egg all right what does it say about
gene editing boy I lost my place I have
I have also something more to say so in
so in California here you have someone
you have a couple actually so pamela
ronald inner husband role role and Adam
Chuck so one is a like a big advocate of
gene editing technique the other one is
an organic grower and to me that's the
perfect example of what the future
should be like organic growers should
embrace gene editing technology because
it's just the future
gene Eric will also allow for more
competitively priced products in the
marketplace if you got a bio synthesize
a cannabinoid it's going to be a hell of
a lot cheaper to gene added a plant and
grow it in the field and so gene editing
is going to offer certain hard-to-get
cannabinoids at more affordable prices
that means our products
we'll be more affordable for the patient
to buy as well ironically as the science
is the molecular biologist here I'm not
a big fan of gene editing and so go
figure but I but at the same time you
know traditional breeding accelerated
with molecular diagnostics is another
form of gene editing that just doesn't
use the CRISPR technology right it's
it's intelligent breeding done with data
that you say you're driving to a product
right that also can be done in an
accelerated fashion and to be honest
gene editing to model is a great thing
right so so if I'm trying to build a
strain gene editing helps me determine
whether or not that feasibility study
works but then you go back or I go back
and then breed it traditionally using
molecular markers so do you think the
farm bill and legalize tent is going to
change how we approach cannabis IP hell
yeah here it goes you know why because
if you look they make you put it says
hemp derived phyto cannabinoids I love
that that means we can grow any kind of
cannabinoid unman to produce any kind of
cannabinoid except THC that plan is wide
open for research there's a lot we can
do with them do you think we're gonna
see more research into isolating we're
gonna see a lot of research in in
regards to have the future isolate
different can I have analyzed for
textile use for production of CBD your
ear to see all kinds of different things
coming out of them absolutely I'd
actually say that you're gonna see hemp
that's being bred from multiple passes
right so right now we talk about hemp
for CBD or we talk about hemp for fire
excuse me passes at at you know multiple
bites of the Apple right so you know we
we talk about CBD hemp or fiber hemp or
you know have
but for protein right 4c right but
theoretically if you if you are gene
editing or you are breeding
intelligently you actually can build a
hemp that you you extract the CBD first
and then you send it on for fiber
processing etc there's no reason why
that can't be done it's just we haven't
had a reason to build it yet so yeah
that's that's what has been done for
flax for example where you used to have
like flax for for linen and flax for
seed and then they built that like full
usage or double purpose flax so will be
the same for hemp hemp will be used
completely so then it's reduced waste as
well communities I can really only speak
to the local community just with the
with the laws and regulations but you
know I think it's it's improved the
community quite a bit in Colorado we've
seen quite a bit of money pushed into
our schools quite a bit of money pushed
into our roads um quite a bit of money
just pushed into our economy in general
as well as just taking away what is a
lot of us have lived with is the fear of
what is a great product you know it is a
safe product what is something that is
wonderful to use um so I think the work
we're doing here is really starting to
improve and then change and change the
minds of most of the world on what
cannabis can do for for everyone very
locally so like my my lab is located for
like eight minutes drive from licensed
producer so every time they have a
problem they will just call me and then
it's very easy for me to try to help
them so that's the very local way to
help the the industry but from a more
global perspective I'm trying like with
my group to put some resources that will
help the order the industry from like
internationally like one example is that
I'm trying to build that
pest and disease survey for now of
course it's a little bit more restricted
to Canada because of shipping problems
but this is something that at some point
some people in the US will add their
information and by building that global
database it will just help anybody in
the industry no matter where they are in
the world
do you see a need for a global pest and
disease database for sure because I mean
like if you think of Dutch elm disease
chestnut blight those were all disease
that were not present on in the US and
we're introduced from elsewhere now we
have a chance to know those disease
before they arrive here so we need to
know what is present here what is
present elsewhere and put in place like
all the detection assay that medicinal
genomics will develop for us and so you
know you'll be able to know when
something is new and make sure that is
destroy him immediately as a cultivator
it's more vital than ever we did all of
that yeah lately I've been enjoying
going to different countries around the
world and there was a few more that want
to see me and talk to me about getting
their programs together and we have a
lot in this state we have a lot of
experience a lot of people have a lot of
experience you should share that with
the world because you'd be surprised how
many countries and ministers in those
countries have no idea at all about what
to do they're excited they want to be
part of it but they they just don't
understand it so our community should be
going out to the world and teaching and
instructing so the science that we've
done is open publish so that's available
to everybody I hope I hope they take
advantage of it because you know a we
worked hard on it for you guys but you
know we shared it because there is a
need for the community to kind of pick
this up pick itself up out of the dark
ages by science and get ahead of the
curve right so one of my big things when
I came into the industry was hey
if you don't do it they'll come and do
it for you right so which is the truth
and so I that but on the more local side
you know it's been a real pleasure to be
able to educate and again it's about
education people about genetics and the
power of marker assisted breeding and
how that stuff actually can bring the
cannabis industry a whole generation
faster right so you know I think the
most important thing that we do is is
the education part both on the local and
the global side right so and I would any
of you who have not had that opportunity
people are so thankful around the world
I was in Zimbabwe recently talking to
the Minister of Agriculture there and
they they love when people come and
teach them right so if any of you have a
heavy desire to teach this is the
industry to do it in because people are
hungry for we know so what advice would
you give the young person who is
interested in cannabis today with that
in mind look if you're a young person
you want to get into this industry go to
go to a lot of shows talk to a lot of
people go into labs get tourists talk to
people who are in the trenches
understand this industry as much as you
can but more importantly than that pick
the area in which you want to go into
because there's so many different
aspects in this industry first find
where you want to go what you want to do
and then study the hell out of it both
academically and in the trenches I think
I mean it's like don't work alone and
[Laughter]
perhaps be open especially on the
cultivation side we like to call it the
e grow but no know that there are a
million different ways to grow cannabis
and none of them could be
wrong but you know to be open to new
experiences and new ways of doing things
so we've talked a little bit about the
cultural social and economic impact that
we've had on our communities I want to
talk about social equity programs that
have become more and more commonplace
with new states they're being enacted in
several different states to help level
the playing field for those individuals
who've been disproportionately affected
or disadvantaged by cannabis prohibition
what are your thoughts on programs like
this that give licensing preference or
discounts to people with prior cannabis
convictions I think by and large the
program's being put forth are all shams
honestly I don't think any of them are
actually doing people of color much good
anywhere how about people with rare
cannabis convictions look I've been
approached several different ways I've
had people come to me hey I'm gonna get
this opportunity in this social equity
program do you want to buy your license
for from me and then the other one is
will you partner with me oh that's
that's not a bad idea you shouldn't sell
your license you get that license find a
person get a great lawyer and make a
deal that you can you can live with or
as my answer was before start studying
your ass off and figuring out what this
industry is and learn by the path of
hard knocks and become a business person
and you'll do extremely well it is a
hell of an opportunity for you to get
one of those licenses do not squander it
take that opportunity and run with it
and go as far as you can and if you want
to know more about it you can listen to
business outlaws I teach business there
all the time I talk about cannabis stuff
too alright with that in mind I'm going
to ask my final question which I've
asked her in every AMA I ever hosted
where do you envision the cannabis
industry in five years from today
well I guess I mean we discuss about
like having a unified set of you know
testing approaches we talked about
networks communities so I hope that we
will have some global partnership that
will emerge from from all those
conferences that that we that we have
and yeah I mean public databases and
what I would really like to see would be
like an international germ plasm
repository but I guess I'm dreaming
about this one so no I so an
international germ plasm repository
would be outstanding right so we have
them for every other important economic
crop hemp arguably is one of the most
important economic crops and it's never
been put in there to any appreciable
degree I believe there are some hemp
strains in the volcanic Institute in
Israel but I'm not sure that would be a
good representative sample of all the
hemp in the world so it's something that
we need genetic diversity is a thing
it's being lost we know that from
science because we've seen papers where
they've seen the hide that drive for
high THC has completely eliminated some
minor cannabinoids and hide TAC strains
right so so we are already doing damage
to the plant and losing some of those
minor cannabinoids on that side and but
the reality is is in three to five years
now at least from the regulatory side
we're not going to be in any different
spot than we are we're gonna have the
same conversation three to five years
from now about the USDA coming in and
regulating things for us so well five
years from now I see we have banks that
accept cannabis companies I see the USSR
opened up I see a lot more hemp being
growing around the world and I see a lot
of countries look at South Korea now has
in in their creams and their stuff that
they put on are allowing for CBD
Oklahoma opened up I thought
be the last date actually that are Utah
and and they're available so you just
you just never know I see that the world
is gonna open up it's going to be a
totally different marketplace I believe
the United States will be able to import
and export there won't be a problem with
280e and will be able to bank I see us
growing a lot of a lot more especially
cannabinoids as we discover what these
do and what we're looking for I also see
the industry possibly following what the
the the beer industry has done where it
goes through a band flows of micro
breweries and then just major huge
breweries um with the cost of regulation
with the inability to take the tax
breaks and stuff that are available
right now I really see only the big guys
surviving for the next five years and a
lot of the mom and pops dropping out but
as we move forward even past five years
and we start kind of correcting some of
the regulation issues that we have I you
know I'll see some some of the more
micro grows come back into the into the
field right after alcohol prohibition it
took 30 years for everything to get
straight now and we have the internet
and better communication so I'm gonna
guess that I'm going to say 15 to 20
years this thing should be pretty well
running the way it should be whatever
way that's gonna be hopefully so yeah
well guys and everybody here before I
open up a QA session I'm sure everybody
has some questions I want to take a
moment to recognize all of you here
every one of you here is a trailblazer
who has impacted our community in some
way shape or form and we all owe you a
debt of gratitude thank you so much for
being here and for the impact that
you've had on all of us thank you
[Applause]
and also we're hiring scientists if
you're interested send into science at
advanced hemp dot-com science at
advanced hemp comm we're looking for the
brightest smartest people out there
alright yeah gotta get it so as we
depart today I have a message for all of
you I heard every individual who's
assembled here today to take a moment to
reflect on your own community and the
impact that you're gonna have on it how
does your work your research and your
dedication change your community what
would be your legacy with that in mind
let's all work together question is the
following thanks guys you talked about
four needs for deeper collaboration so
what I would love to hear an example you
can share where you had collaborated
with the stakeholders and where you
would want that how would you want that
to be improved going forward I'm sorry I
missed the beginning of that question
the question is having spoken about the
need of more collaboration I'd like to
hear an example of what would that mean
like if you had collaborated already but
you know you would like to have a better
collaboration what would that mean give
an example thank you
so my example would be he where he just
sat down Kevin's back there so Kevin and
my team thanks to the outstanding
sequencing work that Kevin did on
Jamaican Lion my team was able to find a
57 terpene genes we just published that
paper last weekend plus one again so you
know steep hill has its own genetic
program medicinal Charles had his own
genetic program but yet we were able to
come together and do some great work
together so
everybody's read that paper by the way
and and don't be afraid to ask go up to
somebody introduce yourself
and shake their hand and go hey I like
to talk to you about X or Y or whatever
just don't just just go up to be amazed
how many people especially here I talked
to are just willing to open up and talk
hi there thank you guys
wonderful presentation I'm curious what
what exciting trends do you guys see and
how are those trends sort of guiding
your whether it's your work in terms of
strain development just what trends do
you see in the market that you think are
going to become you know whether it's
the next CVD to use you know that is an
example of something that's come in
recent years which is legs in a bowl I
think that's exactly it at least for the
trend for me that I'm most excited about
is finding what the different
cannabinoids do what the different
terpenes do and what the entourage
effect does between these you know you
can you know take the synthetic
synthetic THC and it doesn't do anything
the same as the THC grown from a plant
and I really do think that's from the
entourage effect the different
cannabinoids and different turkeys even
the different files that are in there so
just a bunch more research into these
isolating these products and really
seeing what makes me tick and then what
makes them tick together
I think that's there's a lot of research
that needs to be done on the interaction
between the terpenes and the
cannabinoids and you guys are doing some
of that research presently thank you for
that thank you okay in regards to the
all the information that we have to
collaborate on passing throughout the
world
technology is a great way to build
platforms to get that information
expedited from point A to point B and
keep track of it
what kind of platforms and technology do
you guys suggest be built in order for
this industry to accelerate at the speed
we want it to
from a programming system standpoint we
need platforms that are very strong that
patients can go to you know tilray has a
very strong platform we need grower
platforms for people who can who want to
grow at home I mean there's a lot of
these countries are allowing six plants
per household so we need these very
strong platforms without a bunch of I
call it hippie magic you know it's it's
just real science real stuff this is how
stuff's done this isn't behind this guy
this isn't theory this is this is what
if you do this you'll get this if you do
it you know follow the instructions and
do you guys think that there's
opportunity for AI and machine learning
and additional technologies used in in
the tech industry to make some of these
decisions predict analysis I think AI
will be a future you know people popping
up explaining the things that you need
to do and looking at that with spectral
now assistive actually could be in your
garden and a person could pop up and go
hey you've got spider mites or hey
you've got powdery mildew and here's
what you need to do at this this is
early stage because we've caught it
absolutely the two could come together
and you'll see stuff like that the
future for sure
technology to identify problems in your
plant pest control deficiencies
integrated into platforms or the
diagnostic for the purposes of diagnosis
of different issues there are already
like different number of companies that
are developing that for many crops so I
mean cannabis is just a different crops
so like SS like a biotic and abiotic
stress like the water status of your
plant and even like for cannabis that
you could probably find a way to assess
when the trichomes are already you at
the perfect stage for harvesting better
than the human high human I can do thank
you thank you could could the panel
speak to the over these next five years
the
of genetics and intellectual property in
the determination of the value centers
in this industry the winners and the
losers how important a role will
intellectual property patenting all of
that play
reg Mike look patents are always
valuable the money guys like to see
patents you're gonna see a lot of
strains going forward being patented and
different techniques and things because
people want to protect their investments
that's just how business system yeah
yeah intellectual property is is a part
of the fabric of business right so you
you really cannot run a successful
business these days without intellectual
property the cannabis industry is full
of potential intellectual property right
so from plants trains to I'm a patent
agent so the the number of applications
that I see coming out in the cannabis
industry is is enormous from things like
hot gas extraction right what a thought
right so but the there is so much
innovation in this industry right now it
would be I would be surprised if we did
not see the cannabis industry taking a
large segment of issue patents in the
next ten years thank you on I love the
word co-op petition said cooperation and
competition combined and my question is
both the commented questions initial it
to you Reggie and this is creating
community through economic cooperation
and as a breeder got really big into hip
breeding where in southern Aragon I'm
with a company that's really dedicated
to breeding hemp and I create what I
laughingly call three ways four ways I
have a breeder as good feminized pollen
have a homie over here there's got a
greenhouse full of ladies let's put that
too
let's share that strain three ways and
my question that's what I call it the
three way specifically is if you could
speak to that kind of whatever you want
to categorize it as the intellectual
property the cross-licensing how to do
that I love to do that because I've just
taken four breeders and we've created
cooperation economically so we have to
play together otherwise what we see in
certainly in Oregon is the potential for
all those readers to get swallowed up by
a big company but if we're working
together to start with that to me is a
way to create co-op petitions I welcome
any other thoughts on that no that's
actually a brilliant way to do it and
probably a real smart way to do it so
now you've got it
so so but here's where the science comes
in to support that right so you your
scenario you had a guy with a green
house flow ladies and somebody with
really good male pollen right so from
that cross you will obviously find
several fee knows unless it was a true a
true breeding male and a populate some
true breeding females in which case
you're gonna get one offspring right but
either way you're gonna come out with
some phenotypes from that cross that are
desirable science the science part of
this is you fingerprint them you get you
identify that unique genetic signature
and then you can then use that unique
genetic signature as the basis of a
licensing program and then because it's
like a unique genetic signature we're
talking about FBI level unique right
because every cross will produce a bunch
of offspring that have their own
genetics right so now anybody not in the
four of you growing that obviously got
it through something gotten gains and
there's a you know either somebody let
it go or somebody stole it but now you
have the ability to protect this right
so you follow a plant patent on it it's
not very expensive it's the plant as
shown and described
you print it you got the genetics and
now you have the basis for a very
credible legal foundation to build this
business on it's a brilliant idea more
people should be doing it hi I'm dr.
Xion Walker and I really want to
appreciate you guys for coming out and
sharing everything and I think it's
pretty awesome so I decided one day that
I couldn't go back into my office and
continue to do what I was doing because
I needed to be more in the community
educating and this came after a patient
came into my office and told me hey you
know I feel so much better and I got
this vape so I carry this I've been
having this thing for over a year and I
will show it to anybody who wants to see
it I looked at it from across the room
and a person said oh it's really cool or
not I said oh my god they've really got
an event they've gotten a camouflage
cartridge the thing has so many toxins
in it until it looks like camouflage
it's brown and spotted all over so while
we sit here and we talk about all the
education that we need and the things
that we need to share among ourselves as
community of professionals we still have
a professional or moral or obligation to
talk to everybody we see about
everything that we know because they
don't know and somebody's gonna kill
themselves or you know die and it'll be
attributed to cannabis canvas will have
nothing to do with it and all of the
work that's being done here will go back
under the rug again it'll get
criminalized again and we'll still yeah
forgot we haven't gotten already yep so
I just wanted to remind us it's that we
still have an obligation to the
community to make sure that we educate
so I've decided to you know Chuck all of
that sitting around listen to people's
problems all day but and get out in the
community
educate people so that they will know so
that's kind of my lane dr. Walker
[Applause]
I guess I'm the last one here so I have
a question because I I'm finding the
community aspect of this whole event
very intriguing especially this talk so
thank you for contributing to it but how
do I say it I'm on the East Coast and I
think the innovation and collaboration
is is wonderful and it's gonna just
advance and accelerate us as you are
saying but the way it translates to me
not being as immersed in the industry as
you all are is is the products that we
get say out on the East Coast are by far
I'm sorry if I offend anyone but a far
it inferior to then what you get out
here on the west coast and so well my
question is is the collaboration effort
in any community whether it's with
cannabis or other things there's always
the ringleader you know in certain areas
of expertise and then that translates
into innovation and community and then
the byproduct is these this you know the
great product so what do you think is
the essential thing for you know in a
place that has the products excuse me
California has products that you can get
that you know help people that are
really in need like the patients on the
East Coast there's not as much because
they haven't caught up so what I'm
worried about is as a patient lying to
get certain products I want that
collaboration to really accelerate as
much as possible in specific areas and
in California there there's a plethora
of you that just are out here and
there's think tanks and all that and I'm
not saying there aren't places all over
the place that have them but maybe not
as concentrated so what do you feel is
the best way for to encourage the
collaboration of say what's going on in
California with places that are further
behind and therefore the patients end up
suffering if that makes sense it's
actually not a a collaboration thing it
has more to do with regulations and and
attitudes right so if we had no borders
for cannabis to cross state lines you'd
have the same products on the East Coast
the issue is is that states like New
York think that it's only CBD and it's
only oil right and and then you have to
look at the way the licenses are given
out because now you have the good ole
boy network where you have the ten
richest cronies who are friends with the
governor
again the licenses and they may not know
what the hell they're doing right so it
has more to do with that then it has to
do with collaboration because the
products are there the only thing
keeping you from getting them is
distribution in like say Boston or in
Massachusetts they're recreationally
legal but now it's like we're trying to
catch up and they don't have a lot
there's just a lot of stuff they don't
have so you're still isolated and
quarantined in Massachusetts from
California from all of us here on the
west coast so I think until we do away
with the interstate commerce clause that
prevents us from shipping cannabis
domestically you're gonna still run into
that problem that's the real issue I
think the other part that is actually so
as you get regulations opening up and in
Massachusetts where they just did
legalize it so now you're gonna see a
lot of the California companies set up
shop in Massachusetts it will take them
a little while to get up and running but
they will use the same SOPs they're
using in their California shops okay I
hope you hurry up and get here because
get to the east coast yeah thank you
thank you very much
[Applause]