[Music]
you do use AI environment informaticians
to help screen our molecules and give uh
um us information for where we think
this might be most applic one um one of
the things that we know that our
ingredients do very well is they target
the inflammatory related properties and
we know that chronic inflammation
um systematic chronic inflammation is
related to a wide variety of diseases
usually everything starts as that slow
burning continuous inflammation goes
undetected then it can turn into cancer
into neurod degenerative problems into
cardiovascular problems so on and so
forth so where we start is we look at
okay um what areas of disease or what
other indications are related to a
inflammation um even if inflammation is
the primary um driver of that disease do
our molecules hit other targets that are
related to that disease for example in
our cancer program fora we found out our
molecules also hit Tre be so that we
were able to go down that pathway but
then really what I try to do is I
thought try to find a key opinion leader
someone who's used to doing the academic
or pre-clinical or Discovery work
required to be able to validate the
ideas the hypothesises that we have so
in Canada we are very forunate to have a
wide variety of um
universities um with a lot of
investigators with the government
programs that can fund um student
research so that professors with the
oversight can lead a PhD or a master
student or even sometimes undergrad
student students to do a series of
experiments for us proof of concept
experiments for us that will give us the
information we need to deductively
reason and say yes this is what we want
want to do or this is where we think we
have the highest chance of success or we
can turn this around in a reasonable
time because from this batch of
experiments and work previously done we
can FastTrack this into the clinic which
we're trying to do with our first asset
our lead asset for M neuron disease
[Music]
ALS
a