afternoon thanks for being here so I'm
here from Dmytryk today to tell you
about how we are unlocking access to
rare cannabinoids using scalable bio
synthesis so our mission at Demetrios is
to make nature's rarest ingredients
accessible sustainable and affordable
for happier healthier lives we focus on
natural products because they have huge
impacts and huge challenges and so I've
got three of my favorite plants on this
slide on the Left we have
Artemisia annua and that's the plant
also known as sweet wormwood from which
the anti-malarial drug artemisinin is
derived so artemisinin is the drug
that's recommended by the World Health
Organization for treatment of malaria in
the developing world so it's a very
important drug and we need a lot of it
and it's also a drug that has suffered
from huge price volatility so swings of
as much as 10 fold and pricing and that
occurs because of boom-bust cycles in
agriculture because of bad weather
because of stockpiling and speculation
so a few years ago a second source of
the drug came online it's a semi
synthetic form so basically what happens
is that scientists engineered some yeast
with the genes to make a precursor of
artemisinin and then that precursor can
be converted by human chemists into
Artemis and with a couple of more
chemical steps and so what that's done
really is put a ceiling on price swings
for the drug and it's leveled out price
and considerably and made the situation
more manageable so the second example
that I wanted to bring up is taxes Bravo
folio or the Pacific yew tree and that
is our source or was our source of the
drug tax salt which is an important
cancer drug the Pacific yew is also an
endangered species and so you can
imagine that that was not going to cut
it for supplying a cancer drug and so
again a semi-synthetic actually several
semi-synthetic methods of producing tax
all have been developed and that is
led to the ability to supply this drug
to the world essentially and of course
the last example I'm going to talk about
is cannabis and so you know with the
approval of epidemics recently that's a
botanical extract from the plant so a
highly pure preparation of CBD and of
course the excitement about you know how
many other cannabinoids that are even
rarer I would propose that there could
be a scaling challenge ahead of us for
many of these compounds and I would also
propose that again the solution could be
production via fermentation maybe with
some semi synthesis so today's market
for natural ingredients across the board
is putting considerable pressure on
traditional harvesting methods consumers
are demanding effective and rare natural
products and these are global consumers
now brands are requiring a stable supply
of high quality and high purity
ingredients to meet that demand on the
pharmaceutical side botanical drugs are
extremely difficult to manufacture in
scale there's very few of them actually
that have been approved by the FDA and
so we think across the board that
agriculture is going to struggle to meet
the growing demand for these types of
very rare natural products I think
everyone here would also agree that
cannabinoids offer a range of untapped
opportunities and this is a chart from
actual Capitol forecasting legal
cannabis sales in the United States
through the year 2030 as well as the
number of consumers and so they're
making the assumption that by 2027
canada's cannabis will be legal
federally in the US and of course no one
knows that when or if it will be legal
but i think that you know taken together
looking at kind of loosening regulatory
structures in the US and abroad in the
last few years there's reason to be
optimistic that we could really have 60
million consumers of cannabinoids in the
US by the year 2030 and so if that's if
that's the case you know the question
occurs to me is which cannabinoids will
they be and where will we be getting in
front so our understanding of cannabis
is growing beyond THC and CBD as we've
heard in several talks before today
there's more than 100 different
cannabinoids
then at least identified or structurally
characterized and we just know very
little about them on the whole and I
would say one of the reasons we know so
little about the majority of these is
that the majority of cannabinoids are
virtually inaccessible in the plant due
to their scarcity so this isn't the case
for the common cannabinoid it's like THC
or CBD which make up you know anywhere
from let's say ten to thirty percent of
the dry weight of the flower but it
really drops off quickly after that so
you start talking about the Varens like
THC V or C v DV or C V G which is the
precursor to these other cannabinoids
and those are more like 1% of the dry
weight from the flower of the plant so
that's putting you closer to $100 per
gram cost to isolate and purify these
and from there you get into the rare
cannabinoids which are 0.01% to 1% of
the flower dry weight that's 100 to
$10,000 per gram and that group includes
CBC by the way finally getting to these
very rare cannabinoids these are
probably structures you haven't seen
before those are less than 0.01 percent
of the flower dry weight and that means
that they would cost if anyone was doing
it greater than ten thousand dollars per
gram to produce so it was really this
challenge that motivated our founder Jay
Keasling
to establish the matrix in 2017 so the
little background on Jay he's a busy guy
he's a professor of chemical engineering
and bioengineering at UC Berkeley he's
also the associate lab director for
Biosciences at Lawrence Berkeley
National Labs and he's the CEO of the
joint bioenergy Institute he's generally
regarded as an authority in metabolic
engineering and he's founded multiple
companies so down there you can see ls9
Y gose and then amorous which is
actually the company that developed that
artemisinin technology I was talking
about earlier out of an invention that
came out of his lab and it was really a
breakthrough discovery that Jay made
with his his lab that provided the
meatrix with a real head start in this
microbial production field I'm at this
point
we've raised over 60 million dollars in
funding and seed in series a based on
the strength of Jay's reputation the
team that he's been able to put together
and the progress we've made in the last
two years our major investors are
tuatara Capital and her eyes
ventures so I'm gonna start talking a
little bit about what the plant does to
make cannabinoids because everything we
do is inspired by the plant and so it's
a very interesting pathway in plant an
interesting means hard when it comes to
metabolic engineering so okay so
starting over here is a metabolic
pathway that kind of shows how the plant
pushes chemicals to make the final
cannabinoids down here and so at the top
you have hexanoic acid coming in and
through a series of conversion steps and
incorporation of other cellular
metabolites you get down to this
molecule livet aaalac acid a littlie
Cassatt can be joined together with the
second molecule called geranyl
diphosphate or GPP to make c vga and
that of course is kind of the mother can
have annoyed the one which all the
others are made off of and the enzyme
that does that is called an aromatic
kernel transferase and i'm going to talk
about that a little more later so keep
that one in mind once you have CBG a
that can be converted into Delta 9 THC a
or CBD a through the action of these
cannabinoid synthesis so THCA synthase
or CBD a synthase there are other
synthesis as well we heard about some of
them today many probably uncharacterized
and then finally the a of here of course
means acid and they can be
decarboxylated by heat for example into
THC or CBD and so what makes this
pathway unusual and more challenging for
us is that it occurs in two phases in
the plan so in the first phase GPP and a
limit aaalac acid are made inside the
cell and joined together to make that
CBG a molecule that's where it gets
interesting so the CBG a and the
synthesis then secreted into an
extracellular kind of lumina a chamber
called the trichome and so that last
reaction to make THC or CBD a is
occurring outside of the cell so I have
a weird observation now it's occurred to
us that about a thousand cannabinoid
producing yeast cells could fit into a
single trichome and so if instead of
doing that we were to fill up a large
fermentation vessel with those yeast
cells we'd essentially have a gigantic
trichome and that's kind of the point of
all this is that fermentation and de
beatrix has the advantages of a
specialist so if you think about a plant
the plant is an amazing organism and it
does a lot of stuff
it grows roots it grows leaves it does
photosynthesis it makes thousands of
compounds and in the cannabis plant in a
very small part of the total biomass it
also produces these trichome structures
and makes the cannabinoids that we're
interested in so that means that it's
actually inefficient for some of these
rare or natural products because it's
doing so many other things so it
requires a lot of resources we have
limited control even with some very
heroic breeding over the final products
it makes and in the end you have a lot
of waste and the process overall isn't
very agile and so by contrast
fermentation is really a specialist so
it takes a streamlined and highly
efficient approach requiring fewer
resources complete control and creating
little waste and working quickly so I
want to get into this in a little more
detail basically as a specialist we take
nature's unpredictability out of the
equation so the process that I'm
describing it is consistent in pure it's
resource light and reliable it scales
easily and quickly as the market does
and it yields ingredients in weeks
instead of months so if we were to
follow the production of some purified
cannabinoids through via agriculture or
fermentation that comparison would look
like this so if you wanted to make a lot
of purified cannabinoid via agriculture
you'd start by growing a lot of wet
plant say a hundred thousand kilograms
and that's going to be probably three to
four months of minimum to get your
plants grown you then dry down the
plants now you're at 30,000 kilos you
trim away to get just the flower now
you're down to ten thousand kilos and
then you do some pretty intense
purifications to separate these
cannabinoids from all the other products
in the plant from the waxes the other
chemicals the tissue and in the end if
you had a high THC strain you might have
two thousand kilos of THC if you add a
strain that specialized in making CBD
maybe you're at 1,200 kilos of CBD if
you're going after one of the rarer ones
like the Varon CBD v you'd have only 250
kilos and if you're going after one of
these really rare compounds I was
talking about earlier I'll call it C V
DX you'd have as little as one kilogram
and this is this is really a best-case
scenario well it's gonna be variable
depending on weather geography and of
course the natural abundance of the comp
so if you were to take the fermentation
route you would inoculate a large
fermentation tank with the cannabinoid
producing yeast they would fill up the
tank by growing over the course of one
to two weeks and then that would be it
the fermentation to be done and so at
that point you would do a purification
process which is would be much more
straightforward than purifying from
plant tissue because now you're just
separating from these cells and from the
media and the tank and you would end up
with 2,000 kilograms of either THC or
CBD or CBD V or the CBD X rare compound
and that's because the fermentation
process is not dependent on the natural
abundance of the compound in the plant
we choose the strain that we we grow and
it makes the product that it's
engineered to make it's also reliable
this is not happening outdoors in a
field it's independent of whether
geography and as I mentioned the
abundance of the compound so I'm gonna
get into a little more detail here I'll
try not to get too hardcore because it's
the afternoon but the Demetrios process
to produce alcohol and common
cannabinoids THC a and CBD a for
managing your yeast looks something like
this so we start by engineering a yeast
cell over here and so this is sacrum I
see Survey's yeah it's baker's yeast it
was it's what brings us beer wine bread
pretty well known organism we then
basically need to bring in all the parts
to make cannabinoids and so I like to
think of it like an assembly line where
each gene we bring in each piece of
genetic engineering we do is a unit
operation in this assembly line and so
we source those unit operations from you
know whatever organism has the best
version basically and so some of the
genes and our yeasts come from cannabis
but some of them come from other
organisms so in the end we have to
engineer yeast cell and we're gonna feed
it sugar and we're gonna feed it
hexanoic acid and so the yeast cell
takes the sugar and converts it into
geranyl diphosphate that's a GPP
molecule and another molecule called
malonyl-coa in combination with the
hexanoic acid we feed in the cells can
make that a liver taluk acid molecule I
talked about and then finally make the c
vga
kyoool from here at the strain has a CVD
a synthase we make CBD a if it has a THC
a synthase instead we're gonna make THC
a so these are common cannabinoids but
they're obviously valuable products that
do important things so they go into
api's which are pharmaceutical
precursors they go into consumer
products anything from skin creams to
nutriceuticals and of course there's the
recreational market with THC so I think
where it really it's really interesting
though for this this conference is when
we replace this hexanoic acid with
different carboxylic acids and start to
get access to rare and new to nature
cannabinoids and so for example if we
were to take that same setup and feed
butyric acid instead of hexanoic acid
now we'd be making Varun's so we'd make
cv g'v a which is the variant form of
CBG and we make CBD VA which is the
variant form of CBD
we can go so that's that's basically a
carboxylic acid with a shorter chain we
can also go to a longer chain like octa
Noack acid and so in that case we'd be
making these compounds that have C 7
tails both the the c vga and the CBD a
version and by the way if I had a THC a
synthase here we'd be making the THC a
versions of these compounds the last
thing we could do is we could go to the
Sigma catalog and we could we could
select 30 carboxylic acids that look
roughly like hexanoic acid but obviously
are pretty diverse there and then just
test them in our strands and we've done
this and we see that the majority of
them end up getting incorporated into
the final molecules there's little blue
stubs there represent any of these
functionalities and so now these are not
natural compounds anymore we're calling
them new to nature cannabinoid so
because these are very interesting for
for new drug development you can imagine
given the number of carboxylic acids
that are available that you could make
quite a few compounds this way so I want
to zoom back and just kind of summarize
the advantages of the system basically
we have an agile platform for the
economical production of rare
cannabinoids rare and novel cannabinoids
and so we have two dials that we can
turn on this platform the first is the
strain the yeast strain so for example
we could choose a strain that makes CBD
here so we fill up the fermenter with
those East cells and then we choose the
feed of the carboxylic acid so if it was
standard movie feeding hexanoic
and in that case we're gonna make CVD a
which is the the natural natural form
it's chemically identical and
indistinguishable from what the plant
makes however if we were to switch to a
THC strain over here and then instead
feed a rare carboxylic acid so that
butyric acid example I was telling you
about now we'd be making the Varon form
at the same efficiency that we make the
natural molecule or the more common
molecule so getting to where we could do
this there were some challenges along
the way I'm going to go through the kind
of big three challenges we faced and at
a very high level how we've solved them
and so the first challenge was really D
bottlenecking CVG a production in yeast
and so CB GA remember is what you get
when you can fine
combine that Olivia taluk acid and GPP
molecule with an enzyme called an
aromatic parental transferase to give
you CVG a so when we first started out
using the enzymes described in the
literature we were not making a lot of
CB GA so what we did was put in the
enzyme that the Keesling lab had
identified called CSP t4 and immediately
saw massive improvement in production so
greater than 10,000 fold improvement in
production of CB GA and this is pretty
important because no C VGA I know no
downstream cannabinoids so I wanted to
spend a little more time on that enzyme
and so the original characterized enzyme
was called CSP t1 this was discovered by
Jonathan pages group and it's a it's a
relative of CSP t4 but but actually
fairly different only about 65 percent
identical and CSP t1 I would say cruelly
makes well for the microbial engineer I
can't speak to the plan but for the
microbial engineer it's a cruel enzyme
because it makes just enough see BGA in
yeast that you might think hey this is
the red enzyme it's just we've got to
adapt it to the east so we got to tweak
it to get it into the yeast cell but I
guess no amount of tweaking has really
worked well there because groups had
moved on and found another alternative
and pH B so that's a that's another
error
a kernel transferase from streptomyces
bacteria and that one makes will the
wild-type version of the enzyme the
natural version the enzyme makes mostly
the wrong product but if you do some
clever mutagenesis on it which has been
done you can make a modest amount of C
BGA lastly we get to CSP t4 and that's
the enzyme that the Keesling lab
developed and when you put that into
yeast you can just make I would just say
massive amounts of C BGA so it's pretty
clear to me at least from the microbial
work that this is the enzyme that is
meant to do that step and to use an
engine analogy here CSP t1 is maybe a
compact car engine and PHP could be a
truck engine CSP t4 is more like a jet
engine so we found ourselves in early
2018 in the position of having strains
that made a lot of CVG a and that's
where we ran into our second problem and
so that was that the cannabinoid
synthase enzymes just don't work well in
yeast and so remember we're making CVG a
we got past that hurdle and now we want
to convert that into CBD a here with one
of the cannabinoid synthesis in this
case we're trying to use CBD a synthase
and so it really it basically totally
failed at first like barely detectable
production micrograms berg yeah nothing
so at that point we took kind of a
two-pronged approach
so we re-engineered the synthase enzyme
itself to try to make it more amenable
to yeast and then we also attack from
the other end and we engineered the
yeast cells to make them support the
function of this enzyme better and so
that actually was quite a few steps so
you can see this was the synthase
optimization early on and then there
were a series of engineering features
that we stacked to get to the point
where we were essentially converting all
of the CBG AR strains was making so the
third challenge is scale up in
manufacturing so basically 2019 has been
all about getting those strains into
fermentation vessels so basically tanks
that mimic what they would be in at
full-scale production and manufacturing
making sure that we have processes and
processes and strains in place that are
stable and that's in process and that
sounds less interesting and maybe less
hard than the first two challenges but
for folks that have been in the
industrial sin bio
area they know that this is actually
quite challenging and the good news is
that we have several folks on our team
who have experience with that I think
there's over nearly ten molecules that
have been scaled to multi-ton amounts
and production and that experience is in
our team and so you know we take this
challenge seriously but we're also
confident we can do it so in total I've
really told you about how we do bottle
necked microbial cannabinoid production
in yeast and so what that means is we
have a platform where we can produce the
common cannabinoids and then we can also
produce rare and new denature
cannabinoids so we're using our funding
right now to go further faster and
there's kind of three parts to that the
first is the team and at this point
we're up to nearly 35 people and it's a
it's a team of experts in R&amp;D in
manufacturing commercialization and in
regulatory of course we've also invested
in building a best-in-class lab and so
I'd characterize it as a lab that's you
know efficiently focused on production
of strains to make high-value natural
products and so there are a lot of
automation computing tools that are a
part of that lab that make make the work
go faster and so you know essentially
our scientists spend a lot less time
pipetting and they kind of do higher
value activities the last piece that I
think is pretty important too is that
we're developing industry-leading
intellectual property around this
microbial production so we've invested
in IP licenses for example the license
of the work from the Keesling lab and
then over the last couple years we've
also developed our own suite of
intellectual property that is propelling
our technology forward and enabling
commercialization so with that I wanted
to return to our mission statement which
is to make nature's rarest ingredients
accessible sustainable and affordable
for happier healthier lives and really
everything that I've been talking about
in the last 20 minutes has been about
the first part the accessibility part
the ability to scale these compounds and
what's great about being at this
conference is getting a chance to see
the second part which is finding out
what these compounds are good for and
how they can really impact human health
for meaningful
and so with that thanks for your
attention and happy to take some
questions oh that is absolutely
fascinating work I love seeing the the
adjustments on the panel transferases
I'm trying to get a gauge of the
relative efficiencies next to cannabis
and obviously you're using sugar and and
99 percent of the sugar in the world is
made by the Calvin cycle and
photosynthesis and so why rip out the
middleman there and are you getting
close to the efficiencies and the carbon
audits that that make this type of
activity economically feasible yeah I
think yeah I don't want to knock the
plant I hope it didn't come off like
that
I think it's mostly that the cannabis
plant has a number of responsibilities
so I can't get into specific numbers on
where we're at right now but I would say
the cannabis plant is doing all sorts of
things if its sole job was to convert
the sunlight into cannabinoids it would
it would kick our ass but it is doing
all sorts of things as a plant needs to
and so I think that really what we do is
we take a single slice of all the
metabolism that plant is doing put it
into yeast feed them sugar just run them
at full speed and and get the process
done in one to two weeks and so I think
that's where the competitiveness comes
in could you comment on the regulatory
structure which licenses you need and
then which labeling would go on the
products using those ingredients I think
so regulatory is something we understand
is is definitely very important and a
major challenge in this area I am not
qualified to tell you the answer to that
yet but it's definitely something we've
made central to our early development
effort we're not waiting until we have
the product to do it is it a DEA license
because it's not a plant
yeah so we're DEA license everything we
do is within federal law and it'll
always be that way but I think I mean
that that situation is kind of changing
rapidly and still defined right now so
we err on the side
caution there Thanks sure thanks for the
great talk you mentioned that you're in
the scale-up phase with you know scaling
up the amount of a product that you're
making I've seen in literature in the
past that there's issues with
cytotoxicity with some of the
cannabinoids that are produced at least
the terminal cannabinoids is that
something you've addressed yet in
scalability or have seen one way or the
other
yeah so it's it's interesting in
metabolic engineering I've heard this
for a number of products and there are
some cases where the products were truly
toxic and in other cases it just has to
do with miss balancing the metabolic
pathway and so I can't get into detail
but I'd say we think it's the latter
we're not we're not overly concerned
about the toxicity of these compounds to
east excellent thank you yeah all right
great thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
I think we have one more question early
what's the healed of the product we are
making yeah I can't I can't tell you
that right now I'm sorry yeah yeah just
curious when can you give us any sense
of when this technology might come
online and be a competitive threat to
the traditional art of growing marijuana
and cannabinoids yes I think first this
is going to be a massive ecosystem and I
don't think that what I described here
today is ever going to be a threat to
you know large number of people that
want to interact directly with the plant
that's a different experience I think
that we could be a threat to rare
cannabinoids pretty quickly and I but I
don't I don't view it as a threat you
would more as a bonus because there just
isn't a good way to scale those right
now
but yeah I don't know exactly I'm more
on the science side I don't know exactly
how much I'm allowed to say about our
scale-up timeline but it's it's what
we're working on right now essentially
so so we just one of the questions terms
of relatively quickly for rare
cannabinoids are we talking 12 months we
talking five years seven years type of
thing is there any type of time frame
less than definitely less than five
years yeah okay
do you know or is it known what it is
about cannabinoids that are toxic to
uced yes so I actually don't think
they're that toxic to yeast and so I
have seen those reports I think that I
think that that's a hard question to
answer I mean you can I guess you could
add the misogynist lead to a yeast
culture and maybe see toxicity but you
know they're not very soluble compounds
so there's questions there I think that
producing cannabinoids can be toxic
perhaps even if the final yeah yeah
[Applause]
yeah I I gotta just fall back on kind of
a variation on my last answer which is
that you need to get everything lined up
right going back to that assembly line
analogy I think of the I Love Lucy part
where she's on the the conveyor belt
with the chocolates and they're
basically coming in too fast and
starting to spill over so a metabolic
engineering when you end up in that
situation that's spillover instead of
being chocolate is usually toxic so it's
it's that kind of thing where you just
basically need to get things balanced
correctly so if somebody had 30
cannabinoids and they wanted to go into
the FDA with a plan and we wanted to
start a master drug Wow
how saying could you do that I think it
depends on on which cannabinoids there
were I think that our technology is
particularly amenable to certain kinds
of variants I think that you know we
should have access to in principle the
full range of cannabinoids from the
plant but I'd say I basically would need
to see the compounds to give an estimate
for some it could be very quick
all right thank you
[Applause]