good afternoon everybody thank you jeff
i understand i can kick off shortly
my name is toby astle i work for perkin
elmer i'm the global market manager for
cannabis and hemp
it's my job to listen to our clients to
understand the challenges they're facing
in testing cannabis and hemp
and hopefully deliver technologies and
the support to get better data quality
we're not a testing lab we're a
technology
provider
just by a quick show of hands in the
room
who is currently testing their own
cannabis or outsourcing their cannabis
to a third-party lab anybody in the room
all right so we're gonna we're gonna do
some science uh 101 probably in this
talk which is great
i'll probably keep this to be a little
shorter than 30 minutes but my goal here
is to show you some of the technologies
available to testing labs or quality
control labs to help get better data
quality in more time efficient manners
and ultimately what you heard jeff just
speak about is
understand where we can standardize some
of the testing
there's a lot of activities out there
but they're not always public
so we've all gathered in la um
coming from various continents and parts
of the country
as we know cannabis and hemp is an
exciting space for us to all be in there
are now global markets available for
both obviously some of them very
different to others but what we've seen
is our international team really embrace
this and share knowledge to deliver
answers faster than before
as a chemist
cannabis is one of the most challenging
matrices to test there's no plant that
is the same as its neighbor so that
presents challenges in the lab and now
we have seen a huge
[Music]
amount of a variety of products derived
from cannabis oil and hemp oil which in
itself can pose testing challenges once
it gets to the lab so our goal is to
understand what these
product types look like and how they
behave differently as they are tested
and provide guidance so that we can
generate better data so people can make
the right decisions particularly when it
comes to administrative medicine
what i'm going to talk to you today is
very much focused on the laboratory
environment but i think this
can be
looked at in other areas of the vertical
but what we'll look at today is
optimizing the core foundations in a lab
to generate good data and in my eyes
that looks like the three we see here
that's the choice of the soft goods the
reagents are consumables not all
suppliers are created equal
the instrumentation
some of these assays or state compliance
requirements are incredibly
demanding you need sensitive equipment
and instrumentation and lastly
cannabis labs are reaching a maturity
where we're seeing thousands of samples
being tested a month and that's
generating huge huge amounts of data and
ultimately as jeff just mentioned that
data needs to be made available if
needed
so managing that data in a timely and
qualified manner is important
and what i'll also say is particularly
as we come out of the pandemic
we've seen a lot of challenges around
the staffing or the personnel in labs
and there's been a lot of delays
ultimately getting samples processed or
data
produced because the staffing hasn't
been available
so what i like to add at the end is how
we've
adopted automation to take some of the
burden off the staff
and generate quality data in a timely
manner
as i mentioned cannabis is a complex
matrix and it's full of fats chlorophyll
terpenes cannabinoids and contaminants
like heavy metals and pesticides
so as a scientist it's it's key to
really understand what's going to maybe
catch you up in the lab or work with a
partner that's already encountered and
developed methodologies to overcome them
but we know testing is essential and
depending on what market you're focused
on or what you're looking into we know
it's key and core to generating a safe
product for the consumer both in the
medicinal and in the recreational market
and it's not hard to look at some of the
press releases or the media or the data
available to show that bad samples are
out there and it's the responsibility of
the industry to accept that testing is
essential and empower the labs to
be able to do that effectively and it's
an exciting time for us to understand
how these regulatory requirements differ
and support each of them in the various
states and countries
what i will focus on for the next few
minutes is the pesticide and mycotoxin
testing requirements in cannabis and
hemp and depending on where you're
coming from or what you're testing this
is a patchwork of requirements and as
you can see for pesticides and cannabis
in all the markets across the us they
have different regulatory requirements
so
[Music]
you may think you have it easier in a
state that has a lower number of total
analytes however the detection
requirements of those could be quite a
lot lower than say california so really
a lot of time has to be spent on these
methods and as a new lab that's not
ideal you want to be generating coas so
we've taken that responsibility on and
developed these methodologies fit for
purpose for these various state markets
and we'll focus on california because it
does still to this day have one of the
most comprehensive lists in the industry
but before we get to the instrumentation
i just want to take a step back and we
have a number of discussions in the
field where ultimately the data isn't
what the lab or the client expected
and what this means is there needs to be
a robust quality control or compliance
framework in that lab to understand
where potentially an error was
introduced
and this isn't for any not this isn't
just for cannabis labs this is for all
labs in general and what we can see is
that a huge amount of time
is associated with preparing the sample
for the analysis
and this is where we see a lot of
cumbersome steps typically done by
inexperienced personnel and a small slip
at the beginning can have a significant
impact on the final data result
so what we've done is looked at this
workflow taken one of the most
challenging assays to date which is
pesticide analysis and try to improve
the lab's chances of success by bringing
technology to their lab
and if we look at the incumbent or the
legacy scenario for sample preparation
what we see as
the norm is
labs having to utilize a large
number of suppliers to meet their soft
goods needs they need to
source reagents consumables labware for
multiple vendors and then they also have
to spend considerable time on the bench
preparing mixing diluting transcribing
recording inventory and this for a busy
lab can take up a significant amount of
time
so we saw this paradigm and wanted to
change it and what we were able to do
is put all those steps into one kit take
a lot of the heavy lifting and the wet
chemistry that's typically done
in that sample preparation procedure and
do that at the factory so that now we
can supply an iso so it's a certified
reference material regarding kit to
cannabis labs so they have more
confidence
in the calibration and the quality
control standards they're going to use
for the final determination and
we've seen
a lot of interest in making lives easier
and starting with the reagents which are
instrument agnostic has been it's been a
great step forward for us and i'm happy
to talk about this offline at the booth
after my talk
but what i'll say is we've tried to
aggregate all the pesticide and
microtoxin
requirements in this one kit for the u.s
and currently we have 77 pesticides and
five microtoxins down to one parts per
billion all the way up to 250 parts per
billion so
if you look at your state requirements
and see that it includes uh all or some
of these pesticides you know you can use
this kit out of the box with really no
prep time to improve your data quality
and improve your lab efficiencies
we also have included
internal standards and for those that
maybe aren't as familiar because of the
challenging matrix cannabis is we often
use a number of analytical techniques to
improve the data quality or understand
where we'll see suppression effects from
the matrix and one of those that we
suggest and recommend is the use of
internal standards which are similar
molecules but they are isotopely labeled
so they're a little bit heavier in their
mass so you can identify them more
specifically in the assay and account
for any fluctuations in that test
and again this is ready to use out of
the box
and i'm excited to see the feedback from
various labs that have struggled in the
past in getting their reagent prep
correct
no
no lab is equal however we've summarized
the time savings from a kit like this
and you see
up to 90 plus minutes of time savings so
in a busy lab environment running 500
samples a week
this ends up
helping them out a lot and getting
through to more important steps like
data review or coa confirmation
and together with our instrumentation
we're excited to provide the complete
workflow i'm not going to get into the
instrument per se but
we have established these verified
methods that work side by side with the
reagents and the hardware to meet the
testing needs in cannabis and hemp
and uh
we're very confident in the method and i
want to be able to demonstrate that
where possible we participate in the
emerald proficiency test yearly and last
year received our 2021 badge for this
assay
in particular
so what i was mentioning earlier is that
we're seeing
a maturity and the volumes across the us
and in canada
get to be quite sizable for labs trying
to handle thousands of samples per month
having cannabis being deemed essential
during the pandemic has only increased
the number of samples that have needed
to be tested
so it's an exciting time to be a
scientist in the space as every day new
samples new product types are being
manufactured and sold and they have to
be tested appropriately
but we saw this as being a challenge
because as i mentioned uh during the
pandemic in particular labs were
struggling to find the right personnel
or the right amount of personnel and
they were really looking to leverage
anything to get them ahead of the sample
preparation uh challenges they were
seeing
perk and elm is a big company we do a
lot of work in the diagnostics clinical
side of the world and we're able to
leverage a very mature automation
platform and develop something specific
for cannabis labs so i've been working
with labs in the team for the last year
and a half and i'm very excited to be
able to provide a fully autonomous
workflow to cannabis labs now so before
they may have had two three four people
preparing samples preparing reagents
that can be now replaced by a machine an
instrument
and i'll share some slides on what it
does shortly but we know that if we can
take some of the human influence or
human error out of the workflow the data
quality is likely going to go up
and it's going to be far more consistent
the instrument doesn't get hung over it
doesn't get tied it does the same thing
every day day in and day out
and this development we believe is going
to be important for the sustainability
of cannabis and hemp testing
but we wanted to make sure we weren't
just
tackling the hard goods so we have the
instrumentation now we have the
automation but that data is essential
in
maintaining the credibility of that
result and also communicating that data
to the client or the lab manager so we
looked at this holistically and realized
we needed to develop software to
communicate digitally between each
platform in the workflow and that starts
with weighing the sample on the balance
you'll talk to a number of labs where
they'll tell you that oh yeah we wrote
down the wrong way that has a massive
cascade into the quality of the data at
the end so to now take the data off that
balance
automatically at with the right value
offers a lot more security in that lab
workflow
and just to summarize what the platform
does
if you've been around a cannabis testing
lab for pesticide and microtoxins you
will have seen samples be homogenized
extracted
centrifuged vortexed filtered diluted
all very manual steps up until now but
they can now be accommodated on this
platform and the idea is you put your
flower sample in at the beginning press
go and you come back and take your small
lcms file off at the end and run the
quantitation after that and our
turnaround time is about 48 samples in
two hours so
we're very um
happy uh as we're seeing that being a
lot faster than what it typically takes
labs to prepare that amount manually
and just a quick snapshot on the data
this is just showing the reproducibility
of of the automation uh it's far more
consistent than a human
which which gives us the confidence to
meet some of the stringent state
regulatory requirements that are in
place for cannabis and hemp testing
and again we know that every state has a
different testing requirement so it was
important for us to make sure you're
running the technology on the right
application to meet the right
requirements this is just a summary of
the various states and some of the
differences in their action limits some
are higher some are lower but
collectively we can support all these as
needed in your market
and this is just an eye chart but this
gives you the data for the california
list
showing that we can successfully use an
automation platform to meet the dcc's
requirements in a busy lab
and i focused on pesticide and
microtoxins but we appreciate that
a busy cannabis and hemp lab is going to
have a number of workflows or testing
assays that could also be automated
we have had a lot of success looking at
the molecular qpcr prep using a similar
platform as they just mentioned
we can work with the kit providers like
medicinal genomics
and the qpcr instrumentation providers
to integrate that automation into the
software as well
for myself on the platform i just showed
we are automating the pesticide and
microtoxin and now the potency prep
shortly this summer so giving labs a lot
more
options into improving their throughput
and their workflows uh with technology
and lastly i just want to touch on
software um those that went to grad
school or those have been around labs
recognized lab notebooks being stacked
to the ceilings and we know that in a
compliance environment that's not ideal
or really
um allowed so we took a lot of the work
we've done in the farmer and the food in
the nutraceutical space and looked at
the frameworks for iso gmp
compliant environments that are now
being required in certain cannabis
markets iso being the more predominant
one in the us gmp being very common now
in canada but we were able to use that
framework and apply it to the state
specifics of cannabis and hemp
to deliver a software that now manages
and controls access to that data
this is a software as a service from
perkinalmer so this is a cloud-based
software that really starts at the
beginning where you can take your order
entry look at your inventory your
samples you need to process that day and
then follow that data completely through
the workflow to the final certificate of
analysis
and
we've looked at the entire regulatory
requirements
which is typically four or five
chemistry assays
one microbial assay and then foreign
matter moisture
and included those workflows in the
software so
you may or may not have instrument
already if you do have instrumentation
already you can work with the prokaryo
software to improve the data transfer
across your lab
the certificate of analysis and the
reports have been developed to be
configurable however we started with our
best attempt at looking at that specific
state requirement looking at the font
size the colors that have to be used so
that you are
going to be in a good position to submit
your data for the state
for it to be approved
and lastly
we're very excited about the science
in cannabis and hemp and helping labs
across the globe get or
produce better quality data so that the
right decisions could be made for these
markets
and what that looks like from our team
is having a dedicated cannabis team that
starts at the very beginning on the
installation of any instrument
we perform a specific cannabis
suitability test so we know that the
matrix you're trying to test ultimately
is the one that
is being validated by us
and then we train with a dedicated
cannabis application team and uh let you
obviously go through the validation
process yourself um but then you're in a
position to to run client samples and
generate coas
and people like myself and the extended
team are always available
to
listen understand challenges or
opportunities where we can always work
together in the field
if you'd like to learn more please stop
by the booth or check us out on social
media
we are global we have a very strong
presence in the u.s i'd love to
introduce you to the local parking
number representative
and for those that like virtual reality
we have a new
vr demo lab it's very
cool because you get to pick up the
cannabis
walk through the lab touch the
technologies learn about it and interact
with myself and the team
and i'm happy to schedule that after
this meeting
by reaching out to me on my email
and in summary we're excited to have
this portfolio to support cannabis and
hemp science we strongly believe in
automation whether it be hard technology
or software
to improve the data quality so that
regular regulators
medicinal discussions can be supported
with the right data set and
really no matter where you are if you're
in a legal market we're there to help
you can reach me on the email uh shown
here i'm happy to take one or two
questions as i know we're tight for time
and i'll be available at the booth after
this for about the next hour thank you
for your time