[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed conference
okay we are back to our normal podcast
format this episode but i hope you
enjoyed the conversations we recorded
live at
canmed2022 and the canmed coffee talk
lounge
it was great to have some face-to-face
interactions with folks and i look
forward to doing it again real soon
speaking of doing it again we are
working hard behind the scenes to get
all of our ducks in a row so that we can
announce details around canmed23
while i'm not allowed to give too much
away i will say that next year's event
is going to be unlike any other event we
have done so far you aren't going to
want to miss it and i can't wait to
share the details
of course you can tune into the podcast
for updates but you can also sign up for
email alerts at cammanevents.com
and follow us on social media to make
sure you are among the first to receive
the announcement
this episode features a conversation
with tj martin who is the vp of r d at
abstracts a company that specializes in
research development and production of
botanically derived and cannabis
inspired terpenes
tj and his team recently published a
paper that identified a new class of
aromatic cannabis compounds called
volatile sulfur compounds or vscs which
are responsible for that signature
skunky gassy smell that is so prominent
in certain cannabis cultivars
this was a major breakthrough for their
team because as tj mentions in the
conversation a common criticism of
botanical terpenes is that they can't
recreate the signature gas smell of an
og or a gelato
it was a critique that inspired tj and
his team to investigate what they were
missing and lo and behold they found
vscs
during our conversation we discussed
abstract's process for recreating flavor
profiles for classic cannabis strains
how tj and the team used
multi-dimensional gas chromatography to
separate compounds by molecular size and
polarity revealing additional compounds
how even though vsc concentrations are
orders of magnitude lower than terpenes
their effect on our taste and smell is
much higher
the similarities in structure between
cannabis vscs and vscs found in garlic
and what medicinal implications that
discovery may have
and finally although vscs are needed to
create that skunky gassy aroma is
actually a combination of vses and other
terpenes that makes that signature smell
before we get to my conversation with tj
i want to thank this episode's sponsor
advanced nutrients
founded in 1999 advanced nutrients was
the first to develop a complete nutrient
system that unlocks the true genetic
potential of the cannabis plant
since its inception the brand has
introduced more than 50 innovations to
the cultivation community and continues
to revolutionize the space through
proprietary scientific discoveries
learn more at advancednutrients.com
all right and without any further ado
please enjoy my conversation with tj
martin
[Music]
good afternoon tj thanks for joining us
on the podcast
thanks for having me ben really stoked
being part of the podcast
yeah me too because today we're talking
all about that stinky skunky smell
that's so potent in certain strains of
cannabis
and you know for a long time that that
skunk smell or that gas was one of the
few things cannabis users could use to
judge the quality of cannabis of course
today we know that good cannabis can
smell like just about anything from
fruit to herbs
and so tj i was hoping you could start
and tell us a bit about what interested
you about researching the causes of that
skunk smell in cannabis
so yeah um what really interested us
over here at abstracts i mean
we're a company here who not only are we
so we're a company that focuses on
cannabis flavors and aromas specif not
only just botanically drive but also
cannabis derived so we have one business
that's abstracts tech so we do all of
our non-cannabis infused flavors so
these are
directly replicating the exact flavor in
a realm of cannabis but without using
any actual cannabis in it so if you're a
brand who wants to be like coca-cola and
have your product in every single state
and country in the world but have it
taste exactly the same like you want
so you own jack hair or gelato or runts
or cushman's right and you want it to
taste the exact same in every state well
you can't extract it and ship it to
every state that'd be illegal
but
we can create it in a botanical format
using our research to directly replicate
that exact smell and aroma and then now
since it has no cannabis in it we can
ship it to every state and country in
the world so as a brand now you can
start building that
brand recognition and that
that flavor profile that people know and
love in every single state without any
concerns of variability or legality
and we also have our cannabis touching
business which are licensed extraction
facility and research facility in long
beach where we research
and understand what it what makes each
cannabis strain different unique
why does jack hair have its own unique
scent that's wildly different from
gelato which is also wildly different
from like og kush i mean yeah some of
these two of those have really heavy
gassy skunky scents to them right
but gelato and og kush are wildly
different not only from when you smoke
them consume them but also to just how
they taste gelato's known to have a
really complex layered flavor profile
it's a very citrus earthy musk
as well as a ton of gas in it right
whereas og is very woody piney with it
maybe some citrus notes depending on
which og you like
and a lot of gas on it as well
and so that facility not only do we
create
cannabis flavoring extract products we
also research and understand
what makes those things tick right why
they're all unique and different
great so maybe a good place to well
first of all i'm glad that you are
you're an expert on the aromas of
cannabis because i've been i'm curious
so i think
i was wondering can you explain the
different types of compounds that
contribute to the aromas of cannabis
because i think you know most people we
like to think most people are at least
familiar with terpenes
and that's what a lot of us associate
with the aromas but
are all you know the sense associated
with cannabis necessarily terpenes are
there different classes of those
compounds
so i mean cannabis produces a wide
variety of flavor compounds you'll see
everything from terpenes sesquiterpenes
terpenoids right as well as other flavor
compounds
these may be
esters ketones aldehydes alcohols
volatile sulfur compounds like the canna
sulfur compounds we discovered in our
paper
it's a whole wide variety of
different flavoring
isolates and found in cannabis and even
if you break down terpenes into things
like terpenoids
you can start seeing
other of these like alcohols within
terpenes so like a terpene alcohol like
menthol
or linoleum these are known for mincian
more lavendary floral scents as well as
aldehydes like citronellal
or ketones like camphor
these are just typical flavor isolate
these are
just different ways of how the chemicals
orient in space like they have oxygen in
them which then gives them more either
potentially pungent or different flavor
notes and your volatile sulfur compounds
always have sulfur on them and those
typically tend to be by far the most
pungent right i mean you can smell you
know when you're driving by a weed grow
by the skunky smell not by
you know the minty smell right
yeah so you know in reading through your
paper
you determined that the
the compounds that create the skunky
smell are these volatile sulfur
compounds like you mentioned so
how did you determine that it was this
new family of volatile sulfur compounds
that were creating the smell and not
more of the well-known like isoprene
derived compounds
well we didn't know going into it right
we just we went into the project knowing
uh
cannabis gas is something that as an
industry we don't know definitively what
it is we know skunky gassy smells
obviously exist we can smell it in the
plant
but at the time there was really no
terpene products out there that directly
recreated this there was no products
really on the market that did and so
into the project was well we know
there's some strains that have less gas
than others or no gas like a jack herrer
and there's some that have a ton of it
like gelato and og kush and so we just
started procuring a lot of
fresh really high-end genetics
because of our extraction facilities
licensed we have the ability to procure
from anybody within the california
marketplace
and just sort of pulling in lots of
different samples and analyzing them and
looking for trends to see
if we if this strain smells gas in
another what are the differences here
where is this trend going
um that's we'll see in the paper we've
kind of oriented these from
highest gas to something from like
something like boccio gelato which
anybody's consumed bachelor gelato from
scherbinski is extremely gassy right
by far some of the most pungent weed you
can find on the market
um all the way down to something that
doesn't really have any skunky smell to
it's really good but doesn't have skunky
notes to it like jackhair that's not
really what it's known for
and then everything else in between
so yeah so tell me a bit more about how
you went about designing the experiment
to identify these compounds like what
was novel about your approach and why
hadn't anyone kind of found these
compounds before so your typical testing
labs and a lot of cannabis companies are
going to have something like a
one-dimensional
gas chromatograph with a mass
spectrometer on it that is i don't know
how familiar you are with it but gc
basically separates based on
molecular size in a 1d system and a mass
spec allows you to see
what those compounds are right but it's
very limiting it's good for what it does
it's high throughput it's affordable
but it does have its limitations because
you're only going to see anywhere from
20 something to maybe cap out at 80 to
100 depending on how deep you go into
your method development right whereas we
have is a custom built out
multi-dimensional gas chromatograph
which allows us to only separate based
on molecular size but also polarity so
some of these volatile sulfur compounds
these oxygenate species that may come
out at the same time as a terpene are
now able to separate out in the second
dimension and we get way better chemical
characterization
and we also have a mass spectrometer on
there and also a sulfur
chemiluminescence detector which allows
us to see all those specific sulfur
compounds only on the detector so kind
of helps guide our research
really fancy expensive equipment right
it's very specialized it does take a
specific science team to actually run
it's not as easy as a 1d by any sense
and you do not get it it's not as high
throughput
but what you lose on your throughput you
gain on the characterization abilities
interesting interesting so
adding that second dimension
enabled you to get you know more
resolution to see you know kind of maybe
similar weighted compounds that are
different in other ways
correct the end will be similar weighted
but because they have say oxygen in them
or sulfur now they're going to separate
out from those compounds that don't have
any oxygen or sulfur in them
right now
so in that one dimensional readout it
would just look like all the same thing
correct on a 1d system if you're running
a typical 1d system you're going to see
obviously all your peaks right well
within one of those peaks say like five
minutes there could be one compound
there could be 20 compounds there right
they'll come out they all loot out the
same time you have no way of separating
it into the second dimension because
you're a 1d system
whereas ours we pull it into that second
dimension so now it's like having you
get a second layer of separation
right
so i'm curious so what
what other terpenes kind of come up at a
similar time point as these uh vscs like
were we kind of
maybe
misappropriating some of the the gas
smell to a different terpene just
because it has a similar weight
i mean i have to look in the data
specifically to see exactly what's
coming at the same time but
i mean
these vscs are in very minor
concentrations so even on a typical 1d
like you're talking these vscs are
low part per million typically in part
per billion range
whereas terpenes are in the percent
level
right you're if you're talking about the
relative weight to one another
um like mercine
a lot of strains like an og is going to
be like it's aroma fraction 60 to 70
percent may be emerging
whereas that volatile sulfur compound is
just
i mean your sub
sub percent you're way down there so on
a typical system even if you were
looking for it you're just not going to
see because there's a there's such a low
concentration unless you have that extra
layer separation or if you have
the right detector to look for it
yeah but in this case a little goes a
long way right because you know even if
it is you know orders of magnitude lower
than those other terpenes like
that's usually what breaks through
that's the most pungent smell that you
get oh yeah this is where i mean just
because it has a lower weight doesn't
mean it's impact on your sensories or
that much lower right
every isolate has a different pungency
to it and sulfur compounds as we're all
aware
with um like skunk spray itself from
like an actual the animal skunk itself
very pungent right super super pungent
you can smell skunk from miles away at
that point right
same thing with cannabis these things
aren't in high concentrations but their
organoleptic impact how it impacts your
um how you taste and smell very very
high
um
now are they even lower
yeah now are they more volatile than
your typical terpenes too like do they
you know sort of burn out fast
um some of them yeah like
like
parental mercaptan one of the main files
we detected in um in cannabis super
volatile
really really volatile i mean
it's definitely more volatile like
beta-carotelline and the sesquiterpenes
right those aren't i mean those are
volatile but they're not as volatile
and
i haven't really done
extensive studies to quantify it but
it's definitely i'd say more volatile on
things like miracin as well
interesting so i know that as part of
your research too you were you're
looking at how these levels of these
vscs change throughout the plant's life
cycles hoping you could talk a bit about
that
yeah so in the paper we kind of we also
did a greenhouse experiment where we
grew out cannabis plant monitored the
vsc
evolution through from when it was first
growing it weak everything from week one
all the way through cure
when it was finished curing and what we
see is around week seeks weeks six and
seven
is when the plant starts producing
these volatile sulfur compounds these
cancer sulfur compounds
and i mean we were growing out i believe
it was gelato specifically in the paper
we obviously different cultivars are
going to be different right
this is cannabis has so many different
cultivars and so many different strains
that it's just this wide variety of
potential here but typically when we saw
on gelatos right around week six sevens
when it starts and then
definitely right when secure is finished
that's when it's at its height that's
when there's just so much concentration
those via season exp makes sense right
super fresh wheat as you mentioned
when you're looking for quality
um specifically like on like an og or a
gelato
the fresher it is the more gassy it is
and you know that it tastes better has a
big has a more perceived euphoric impact
just a better overall product at that
point and makes sense it's fresh
yeah and i know that you you looked also
at the storage conditions for some of
these uh flowers that you got a hold of
too um so what is sort of the optimal
storage conditions to preserve these
vscs
so i mean we haven't we're still looking
into storage conditions right i don't
have a ton of data on that but
i mean if you look at it from if you're
comparing like a mason jar to like a
sandwich baggie two very common typical
ways people may store cannabis at home
sandwich baggies
not exactly conducive to keeping things
away from air right
it's going to off gas a lot it's going
to leave the baggie because they're not
fully sealed whereas them like a mason
jar or any kind of type of canning jar
it's gonna have a nice tight seal on it
which explains why you're able to
preserve your cannabis longer right
absolutely and what about extracts do
the vscs sort of go through the extract
process
yeah in our paper we looked at some
extracts um
because we have an extraction facility
right so we did some experiments with
our hydrocarbon extractors and we saw
that these these can of sulfur compounds
do go from the flour into the extracts
and that makes sense right if you're
somebody who loves waxes whether it be
rosins or even hydrocarbon extracts
they're still gassy they still have that
gassy skunky note to them so you can
smell it there so you know it's there
absolutely absolutely and now you know
one part that kind of stuck out to me in
the paper too and you have a nice
visualization of this was the similarity
between these um cannabis vses and the
vsts that are also found in garlic
i was wondering if you could speak a bit
about that and i'll definitely include a
a screenshot or a picture of
that visualization that you had because
it's really it's really interesting to
see just how similar these compounds are
it's just that cannabis has an extra i'm
sorry i'm not a chemist um so it has a
few extra lines on there and i'm sure
you can explain um what that is
yeah so i mean when we're that was
actually we didn't this is not something
we anticipated at all right we were just
we really just want to see what makes
cannabis tick where is this gassy skunky
smell come from and as we're going
through the data it was just
really strange that
if you look as like as a trend from the
garlic bottle sulfur compounds and same
thing the cannabis ones
you have very similar structural motifs
going through them all as far as like
how the sulfur is oriented in space
um cannabis has that same thing but
instead of being an allele it's a
mercaptan group so you have the extra
two methyl compounds on the very end so
you have two more carbons to it but the
actual sulfur aspect of it on the end
rather be the terminal
vial or sulfur bonded to it to a methyl
group or being a disorder being a
disulfide or just a sulfide in the
middle
it followed that same trend as what you
see in garlic and so these compounds
actually in garlic
like allele files what's being
investigated for its anti-cancerous
benefits
and some of the other files mentioned
are being have been
potentially attributed to the
cardiovascular beneficial properties of
garlic as well so that begs the question
of like does cannabis have similar
benefits does it have other medical
benefits from these can of sulfur
compounds
in
that we've detected um and are they
similar is it more pronounced is it
something different
does this change how cannabis impacts
you right does this potentially explain
why
can't
fresher cannabis has a bigger impact on
the body than say
six months a year old weed i mean any
but any avid consumer will know that
i can tell you from at least from
anecdotal evidence they prefer prefer
fresher wheat that makes sense right we
don't we don't go to the store and buy
eight-month-old oregano you buy you want
fresh oregano for your products the same
thing applies here but the begs question
how does this impact the actual
experience of the product and what
medical benefits are there
it's a question we don't know the answer
to yet but love to find out
yeah we'd love to find out too and if
there's any listeners who are looking
for something to investigate to maybe
potentially bring to a future can med
this would be a great topic to to take
on and this really ties back to what you
were saying before too right where you
at your business you're looking to
recreate a lot of the aromas that are
associated with these signature strains
but using compounds that aren't cannabis
derived so is this a good example of
where you could use some
otherwise derived compounds to recreate
a cannabis smell
yeah so i mean with our research over
abstracts labs where we have our
cannabis license and our
instrumentation for analyzing we have
our multi-dimensional gc
we're able to see everything that's in
the plant right that's at least that's
volatile which attributes the majority
of its flavor and aroma and we can take
that data and then recreate it using
the same iso it's like prenatal more
captain isn't only found
um in cannabis it can be found in other
things like when you look at
say skunky beers like a corona like a
light struck beer
that has pronomer captain in it
and so
these compounds can be found some of
them in other botanical species so we
can
you can extract these isolate them out
and then use them in the same ratios
and have the same compounds to directly
recreate that exact same scent because
pronomer captain if it's isolated from
cannabis or isolated from
i might say hops or some other botanical
species once you isolate it down into
high enough
high enough concentration it's going to
smell and taste the same and just about
matching those direct ratios
yeah and i know as part of your paper
you
you were trying to reverse engineer some
of the aromas of the cultivars that you
were studying um talk a bit about that
and you know i thought it was
interesting that there seems to be an
entourage effect when it comes to aromas
as well
yeah i mean with that we obviously have
the data to know everything that's in
there and so we wanted to recreate it
isolate by isolate and see
when does it start smelling skunky and
gassy right it's one thing for to see
trends in the data it's a whole other
thing to actually experience it and
confirm this is what it is
so we take the major terpenes things
like myrsine limonene carrot flame
terpenolane pinenes right
start adding those in the right ratios
that we're seeing in
say boccia gelato and just kind of going
down the list and adding in other
terpenes or flavor compounds for
identifying and
noticing when does it become that skunky
gassy aroma and it's not just pronoun or
captain by itself yes pranamar captain
as well as some of their canon sulfur
compounds are a huge driver for it but
you also need those terpenes there you
don't have those terpenes and terpenoids
it's not going to smell like cannabis
it's not going to smell like that
signature gassy scent it's just going to
smell
very sulfurous
um
maybe potentially a little bit caddy or
skunky but it's not like the cannabis
gas like you would notice in an og or a
gelato that makes
so it's what the cannabis community
loves so much right and so really what
we were doing just utilizing that data
and just slowly going down and seeing
just trying to identify one by one what
what's needed and we did this with just
terpenes we did with just the vscs as
well as we then adding the vscs to the
terpenes to see
what is that scent that we're looking
for
yeah and you mentioned that you know it
it is
such a signature aroma and one that the
the community loves so much
and you know it has to be part of the
reason why
you know the what is the original skunk
always seems to be to come up on social
media
and
it's just interesting how that skunk
smell has become just so synonymous with
cannabis
that's super polarizing right the
cannabis community loves it people who
don't consume cannabis a lot of times
hate it yeah absolutely hate it
they're just really put off by it and
maybe that's why
they may prefer strains if they're new
consumers in the market they're looking
for something a little bit fruitier more
like jack hair
but regardless i mean
mine does research
kind of elucidate
potential health benefits to look into
obviously calls out exactly where these
scents come from
but provides guidance for people who are
trying to odor mitigation or
controlling the odor and they're on
their growth so that way
you're not upsetting the general
community around you right
yeah can't lose inside that i mean yeah
our community really enjoys this scent
but a lot of the population doesn't
unfortunately right it is a very pungent
scent that does permeate everywhere it's
at i mean
drive through downtown l.a there's a lot
of cannabis grows and you'll smell just
driving on the freeways crazy
yeah and like you said earlier i mean
that is the scent that people associate
with cannabis you know if you
if you smell a more fruity
um strain out there in the wild you're
not immediately going to think cannabis
but when you when you smell that gas
like there's no mistaking like
what that is
exactly and i'm curious too like with
your business i mean your business is in
recreating aroma so was there a lot of
demand for creating this scent in
particular
i mean that's always been a critique of
botanical terpenes right not going to
shy away from that i mean it's one of
the critiques on social media is that
botanical terpenes may capture some
aromas of cannabis do really well with
like hazes and
jack carrera type strains
but when it came to ogs it was
significantly lacking that it missed
that signature
gassy skunky aroma
and scientifically i mean i was just
interested in why what is that that's
why we kind of pursued this project
and being able to actually recreate in
that flavor and fragrance format
allows brands now to
like i said take their product across
state markets
across state lines country lines and
have that exact flavor and aroma now
because we can directly recreate it
using these compounds
don't get me wrong it's a lot of work
it's very expensive ton of work a lot of
time to recreate that exact profile but
once you do i mean it's really rewarding
you can there are some people who we've
created products i mean
one of the stories i like to show people
or tell people about is when we first
started making these discoveries
when we were reverse engineering and
recreating these products we started
formulating some vape pens in our lab um
we also did some with cbd
started handing them out people and they
started smoking through and tasting them
compared to just regular botanical
blends and
when they would smoke the ones that had
all the compounds in there from all the
reverse engineering work
some folks back oh this is a really nice
light resin pen like well it's not a
live resin pen that's actually botanical
terpene we've just been able to identify
and
really pull in all the different flavor
isolates that previously had been
undiscovered in cannabis
and so when you're able to
really recreate it and make the product
taste like live resin i mean just as the
scientists are just so cool you know
what i mean being able to finally figure
those things out
yeah that's quite the vote of confidence
to be uh or the seal of approval to get
that um
to get that that's great um
yeah and before we started talking you
were you were talking about how it's
great at your facility or it's great
that management of your team
has this publish first sort of mentality
because you know a lot of other folks
who who would have made this discovery
especially in your field may have held
back that information and not made it
public so speak a bit about why you
thought it was important to share this
information
yeah i mean i'm very blessed here at
abstracts we have an ownership team that
really believes in educating the
cannabis community and
sharing this information that's so
important to the community and that
science team as well that really really
buys into that as well
and so we made these discoveries i mean
if you're in a typical privatized
industry it's very common that most of
your work
doesn't get published maybe you get a
patent here and there when it's it's
possible but the rest gets filed away in
the basement and never to see the light
of day whereas the approach here with
abstracts our ownership is hey we have a
community
um that really wants to see this
information we think it really benefits
the community
as well as this is a plant that
historically hasn't been researched very
much
this could be due to you know it's
pretty difficult to research in
university setting you have to go
through a lot of red tape
you have don't really have access to all
the different cultivars that are on the
market like we do
and so when we found these cool
discoveries that we thought man the
community will really love to see this
you have to publish it right you can't
discover the gas and not tell the
community about it it would just be i
mean such a travesty the industry to not
show this information to the whole world
and educate the whole community
and it was great i mean the community
really loved it
everybody fully bought bought into it
was looking at reading the paper really
appreciated all the support
and
hopefully it just encourages more folks
to publish as well because as a
community there's not a lot of science
out there
and the universities can't touch it i
mean yeah they can research cannabis but
they can't research cannabis that's
grown by like a scherbinski's or cookies
or jack hair
any of the major brands that you're
seeing in all these states like
these are not strains that the
universities can research but we can as
a privatized community and when we have
actual license facilities
yeah you're absolutely right and you
know i think that we at medicinal
genomics kind of share that same
philosophy and that's always been our
approach is to is to publish and get the
information out there to benefit the
community and it's part of the reason
why we put together canmed right is to
bring together these other people who or
other companies who are
sort of taking up the mantle for for
getting research going on this
on this plant because like you said
there are universities that are coming
on but they're you know they're studying
hemp
which is you know very valuable and a
lot of it's going to apply also to
cannabis but you're right in terms of
really looking at these well-known
cultivars that are are purely cannabis
and are not going to be mistaken for
hemp
it's really up to the private companies
to
uh to do the work
exactly i mean like i mentioned the
beginning of this
big fan of medicinal genomics for a
while here love
love all the work you guys are doing
i think it's great to educate and
support the cannabis community
it only helps better serve our community
by having people who are more educated
on their products
helps them make buying decisions when
they're looking for things that may
how's this going to impact them what
flavors are they looking for it's no
longer just
i'd love to get two point words longer
just strained names right and marketing
strain names but actually how do these
things smell and taste how do these
things impact you because there's
so many cultivars out there they're so
wildly different
there's just i mean there's a ton of
work to be done but that's what makes it
so much fun
yeah yeah we need to get beyond just
straight thc values too right
oh for sure i mean it was just thc
values why would jack hair
impact you differently than an og kush
or then a gelato or a run right
i mean anybody who's an avid consumer
can tell you the difference and how it
impacts them especially when it's fresh
right
yeah absolutely all right so winding
down here tj before i let you go i want
to give you a chance to plug any social
media or websites or other resources
that you think that the listeners would
be interested in learning more about
yeah you can follow our social media at
abstracts tech on instagram so we post a
lot of
our new product launches where our
research goes any educational pieces or
collaborative work we do as well as our
website abstractstech.com it's abstracts
with an x by the way not a ct
and on abstracts tech dot com you can
buy
all of our different terpene products
whether they be typical flavor blends
because we do create traditional flavors
as well as
our cannabis inspired products
also on there to republish all of our
white papers and our different pyramid
publications as well so we have some
really interesting ones on there your
community may enjoy like we did do a
white paper looking at what is the
difference between
flour hydrocarbon extracts and rosin
extracts of the exact same exact same
cult of our same lot
but applied different extraction
processes and we looked at the different
flavor and terpene isolates found in
each and how those changed to try and
the way we can
i mean because we all know they do have
different flavor profiles and why is
that
so we went ahead and looked at it so
definitely something to check out we do
publish that on our website
excellent yeah we will definitely be
checking that out
all right thanks again tj for joining us
on the podcast keep up the good work and
um hope to see you out at a future can
med event up at the uh up at the podium
presenting some of this great work
thanks ben looking forward to seeing you
guys as well thanks man
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
tj martin check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor advanced nutrients
our next episode will drop june 22nd
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime i hope you will continue
to engage with us on social media just
search for canmedevents.com
across all those platforms
continue to contribute to our kmed
community facebook group and also
remember to sign up for email alerts at
cam at events.com
we will be sharing details about our
cammed 23 event across all our platforms
very soon so stay tuned
we are also hard at work adding video
recordings of all of our canmed 2022
oral presentations and panel discussions
to the canmed video archive and we will
be making an announcement about that
soon as well
one last thing please rate review and
subscribe on your favorite podcast app
doing so really helps the podcast reach
more listeners
okay that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and please join us on the next
canmed coffee talk
[Music]
you