we have got one over here on the left
hi i'm kirsten i'm here again everybody
uh
i would like you guys to give us just
your overview
not so much about aea 2ag
or the phytocannabinoids but about
upregulation
of cb1 cb2 and possibly even
trpv-1 so if there's a
method or an analysis of those receptors
or maybe people just don't upregulate
there might be
something that you guys have to say
about that thank you
well i i just briefly touched on a study
from a couple months ago that was using
pet scans
to look at cb1 receptor densities and
people that had tolerance to
thc-based cannabis and they found that
after two days of
abstinence those receptors came back to
normal level
so we know that cb1 agonists can down
regulate the cb1 receptors and we know
that taking a break from those
agonists can upregulate it there's
probably other ways to upregulate it as
well which are
covered in dr mcpartlin's paper that
ethan
just mentioned right i'd add something
else i think that
heretofore there's been too much
concentration on thc
if he asked me what drug would
upregulate the system over time it would
be cannabidiol
and when used chronically it does seem
to increase the gain of the system and
help with uh so many aspects of this
beyond that and again from john's paper
uh you have aerobic activity
seems to upregulate the system
there's good evidence that the runner's
high is a an endocannabinoid mechanism
rather than related to endogenous
opioids and then
finally the prebiotic probiotics
may figure into this in a big way they
seem to produce some
many of the same benefits on illnesses
that cannabidiol for example thank you
very much
i was wondering if i use cannabis
topically for pain and i was wondering
if you have ever
administered it or had somebody use it
for skin cancer
for what skin cancer
yeah there have been many many
attestations on
the web of curing or eliminating
skin lesions including cancers with
cannabinoids this really
uh what's amusing to me is that this
isn't new
this has been reported for hundreds of
years in other cultures it's just that
we forget history and because they
didn't have double blind controlled
studies then
nobody pays any attention to them
currently
but yeah you know it's clear that
many of the phytocannabinoids not just
thc and cbd
have this ability to kill cancer cells
in high concentrations while being
preservative for normal cells
so a great deal more work in a palatable
form in other words the double-blind
controlled studies
need to be done so that the rest of the
medical community will accept these
results
hi jeff block university of miami a
question
probably for dr sulak the two
abstinence considering perhaps a longer
time for chronic
down regulated patients any chair and
can you share with us how you rate the
two days and
if in fact you may miss a full healthy
retrieval of a naive system to work from
sure i i don't think that any program is
going to be
the optimal program for everyone but
based on the work i was doing about five
years ago when i was asking people to
take different lengths of abstinent
breaks
it seemed to me that most people did
really well with two days
in the six day program that i developed
the three days after the two days of
abstinence involved very low doses
of thc so it's almost abstinent but
we're just very gradually
reintroducing it and i'm i'm not sure
that that's the best method it's just
the best one that i've found
and it seems to work for most people any
comments on starting off with a
full compliment all of the knight of
study after four weeks of abstinence
i'm sorry could you repeat the question
any benefit to starting off with a
full complement of receptors all i would
after a longer abstinence break i'm not
sure i
think some patients they might need
longer than two days but i doubt
many would need a full month
hi this is guillermo moreno from the
university of california irvine
i was i first described the peripheral
restricted fine cubed or european 937 uh
which has to be improved to
be effective in a model of migraine and
also be an effective uh
painkiller and that got me interested on
the the possibility of activating
peripheral cv1 receptors
as opposed at both central and
peripheral
the research on thc a that dr zulek has
presented got me thinking after an
interaction with a patient with breast
cancer
if you believe that the presence of the
carboxylic acid
in thca might prevent it for accessing
the uh
the brain that would be one of my
hypotheses and then the fact that it is
effective
is something that we were discussing uh
with dr gosling too
will it be possible in a case of
epilepsy
that a peripheral cb1 agonist will help
with the seizure but not with the uh
with the central
spike if that makes sense you know able
to control the
the motor uh component of the seizure
without controlling the central
if you think something like that will be
possible thanks
those are some interesting ideas i you
know i think that um from my experience
pretty clearly uh thca
does penetrate uh the central nervous
system
um you know based on on some of those
studies that i presented
and i think that the peripheral activity
of thc
uh as a anti-spasmodic wouldn't be
potent enough to really i mean it might
reduce the
intensity but i doubt that it would
reduce the observable effects of the
seizure
altogether i'd like also to add to that
i'm not sure why
you just want to stop the motor activity
of the seizures because if the brain
activity is still going on that
can still continue to cause damage
right we were we were questioning
whether or not we were seeing just
non-convulsive seizures when we give
thca was it calming down the
manifest the motor manifestation but
possibly if we hook somebody up to an
eeg we'd still be seeing some
uh seizure activity and brain waves
and that would be an interesting
question to look at uh and that's one of
the things i do with all my cbd patients
that i have an epilepsy i monitor their
eg's very closely and very frequently
no in florida where i was practicing
unfortunately we weren't allowed to use
thca so i didn't have any experience
with that
i'm not sure if dr guytanis is still
here but he has
looked at eegs of some of the thca
patients
i mean for it's mixed i've had some
patients where there's no
change in spike weight discharges in
terms of frequency
but uh and others where i've seen a
pretty dramatic proven spike rate
frequency
with the seizure question though the so
the question of like a non-convulsive
uh status without a pulse of seizure uh
we did have one of our
patients who was getting thc report
seizures
we actually had hooked up on eg at that
time and it was truly aborted seizure
there wasn't
an electric seizure with absence of
propulsions and that's what we see that
clinically because
the patients who've used thc to afford
seizures are alert after so it's pretty
that's the most
dramatic part is when they get uh
we're valued during the seizure usually
these rectal dies again
patients out of it for like five or six
hours
if they get thc to avoid a seizure
they're alert within you know 10 or 20
minutes
back to themselves pretty close to it a
little giggly but
you know it's really good so that's how
you know the seizures ended
i think there's no doubt that it's true
hi i'm pat fry i'm a private
practitioner
my question is regarding patients um
who are using cannabis for its
anti-tumor or anti-prolific activity
is it a lifelong commitment to cannabis
therapy
um or is is there any i know there's no
protocol for anything but
um what is the approach for patients who
are able to get go into remission and
then
the second part of my question is
regarding
pregnant and lactating women what your
i'd like to hear the panel's thoughts on
cannabis use
in that patient population well i i can
answer the question on the anti-tumor
it's it's a very good question because
it's something that patients come in and
ask is how long am i going to have to
take this it's expensive
sometimes the high doses of thc disrupts
your functional ability and so we don't
know
there's no clinical trials we we don't
know if somebody uh
there's anecdotal reports of people
taking high-dose cannabis oil for three
months
they report that their seizure sorry
cancer free
and then they go about their business
and it's
they're not taking high dose anymore but
one presumes that they might be taking
some
low-dose cannabis for other symptoms and
it's possible that that might be keeping
them
at a level of cancer freedom
many of my patients who have very
advanced cancers who get good results
are terrified to go off cannabis oil and
so many of them
will reduce the dose once they have
some success usually after six months
sometimes a year if they achieve
cancer free or in remission
and the reality is nobody really knows
how long to stay on it it would be very
interesting to start looking at these
patients
to see if is it can you stop right after
or is it five years like they talk about
in the
in the conventional treatment it's hard
to know
i have a few colleagues that have
treated patients with cancer including
on medical marijuana for a year or more
so and they've been taken off of it and
the cancers have recurred
okay we'll go with fred vogelstein over
there or sorry hans
you're just not gonna let that go are
you hey it's fred vogelstein at wired
for dr goldstein or any of you guys um
assuming that patients are taking say 25
to 1 cbd oil
at what dosages do you
ca what dosages can you administer
before you start to see thc effects
on some of the kids so for example like
at 25 to at 25 to 1 for example
a 250 milligrams a day would be 10
milligrams of thc
would that do patients tend to
see any kind of thc effects or do the
cbd effects tend to cancel those out how
does that work what's been your
experience
well i can talk to my experience and
then i'll let the other panelists talk
to theirs
i do find that children and there's
one report in the literature that says
that children may have
immature cannabinoid receptors so they
may not respond
i do find children tolerate thc much
better than adults
many of them do um i have not found
and you know people ask me how do you
know a child's
uh not high right and you know many
parents can tell
we had a problem in um or i should say
seven patients contact me not this uh
past summer the summer before right
around the same time
there was a product that was parents
were sharing information on the internet
about a particular 25 to 1
ratio cbd made from ac dc and the
company had shipped out just a new batch
to a handful of my patients
and on a friday i got a call from a mom
who said okay this batch is different my
kids acting weird
and i wasn't sure what to make of it and
then the next day i got two phone calls
we just got a new batch
people who did not know each other um my
kids on the floor giggling
and one parent says my kids hasn't
gotten out of the refrigerator
i mean there's a clear cut and then i
four out of the seven k
uh parents that reported this to me um
actually took the oil themselves and
reported that they were um that had
major psychoactivity
and so um it was clear-cut that these
people were able to recognize
psychoactivity i do not
hear that from my families that are
using the 25 to 1 even with very high
doses to 300
sometimes 450 milligrams that being said
i do find that many patients who are
able to be verbal about their
experience find that if you start at a
high dose
they have some difficulty so we start at
a lower dose and we titrate up i do that
anyway
but for some families who came to me
without
me starting them they started earlier
prior to my advice they said oh we're
told to start at 300 milligrams a day
and you know the kids
kind of wiped out from it so there may
be some tolerance issue there that you
know you start low and you're able to
build it up over time
yeah i'd echo that you always want to
start low
on use the dose that's effective um
with these high cbd low thc
i like my rule of thumb currently is to
try not to exceed
a total of 15 milligrams of thc a day
after titrating upwards
and generally well particularly for
adults it's very unlikely someone's
going to get into trouble with that
approach
but even with these broad ratios
thc tends to overwhelm the effects of
everything else if given the chance and
so
uh titration from a slow start is is
really necessary
i have a question uh have any of you
noticed a circadian rhythm
to endocannabinoid activity either with
respect to time of day of dosing
or increased pathology and shift workers
or
people with different sleep disturbances
well i couldn't relate to that but yeah
there's a lot of evidence to show there
is a circadian rhythm
to levels and um yeah that literature
exists
has has there been any experience in
time of day of dosing
is more effective well the thing to keep
in mind is
these don't last 24 hours um generally
speaking depending on the preparation
and the motive administration most
people are going to need to administer a
cannabinoid drug
two or three times a day if they're
inhaling it probably is a lot more
but for chronic illnesses there should
be an an emphasis
on some kind of either oral mucosal or
gi
administration and do you see more
pathology with deficiencies and shift
workers or anybody
who's i couldn't say for sure it's
worth studying all right thank you get a
grant
this one's for uh dr selleck here you'll
have to excuse me the past few days have
been a little bit of a whirlwind and the
slides have gotten a little blurry
already
there was one slide that you had up
where you were talking about the
up and down regulation of cannabinoid
receptors in a 48 hour cessation
from thc would then up regulate
uh the cannabinoid receptors again but
then in the same slide there was one
showing that thc
actually causes the up regulation of of
cb1
is that dose dependent as well did you
notice or was that or
how does how does that work quite so i
think it's pretty well established that
enough thc or any cb1 agonist will down
regulate the receptors they're
internalized
and there's just a little bit of
evidence that a low dose or a single
dose of thc can upregulate
the expression of the receptors and also
the affinity of the receptors
thank you yes this question is for dr
goldstein
would you please comment on your
experience with adhd
sorry with what um
your experience with adhd and
any ratios that that you use on your
patients
uh well i always start with it's
personalized so different people respond
can have the same diagnosis and respond
differently
to different ratios i have
patients using 27 to 1 25 to one all the
way down
to one to one i do find that my adult
patients
with add or adhd when i very first
started practicing it was mostly people
who were smoking or vaporizing
thc and they found very good results um
and many of them there's two kinds of
patients that i see some that get
enhancement of activity that like we're
looking for if somebody gets
ritalin or adderall but without the side
effects and then i have another
like subset of population who do find
good results with the stimulant
medications
but they find that some of the side
effects are intolerable including you
know loss of appetite and poor
sleep so they're using cannabis in the
evening to counter out
the effects of a medication that
actually does work functionally for them
but at nighttime it they are feeling the
side effects
in my pediatric population i am starting
to see a lot of patients coming in
because parents are very concerned about
putting their children on these
medications
i always start with pediatric patients
with a high ratio cbd to low thc
sometimes there's other comorbid
comorbidity epilepsy
autism sometimes exists ocd sometimes
that i'm seeing and i just find that i
start with i always start at the
high cbd low thc so like 27 to 1 25 to 1
sometimes 21 depends on what the parents
can find and get
and then i slowly will depending on
results checking in frequently every
couple of weeks
maybe titrate in a little thc to see
what the effects are i have a little boy
right now that i'm taking care of that
came to see me with epilepsy he's he
at the time was four he's been my
patient now for two years
and he was having terrible rage uh with
kepra it was
impossible they couldn't go anywhere or
do anything the family came in tears to
me
we started him on cbd oil and he
responded beautifully
but what's interesting is that his
adhd and autism kind of
persisted no rage anymore but he was
really kind of a very
difficult child he couldn't be in a
preschool he couldn't uh
wasn't really learning and had no focus
and we started very low dose thc added
in
as a separate for more treatment of that
and it turns out he's on a one-to-one
ratio he takes
50 milligrams of cbd three times a day
for seizures
and he takes 50 milligrams in the
morning of thc which
is a very large dose
and is actually in
a classroom that's considered mild and
his focus he's learning to read and
write and
as the mom says i feel bad giving him
this but he's not high
you know he's going off to school and
i'm getting good reports and
nobody knows he's on thc because she's
worried about being reported
but meanwhile the child is having major
success
and so it really does depend on
individual but again
starting low and tip toeing up on dosing
and just really going by how the patient
responds is really the way to go with
cannabis
and i just wanted to add it's not a
direct answer to the question but
because this conference has focused a
lot
on cbd and especially in the treatment
of children
i have found clinically that thc is a
very safe and effective medicine
for children with self-injurious
behavior violent behavior chronic pain
with seizures with many different
conditions thc seems to have
a better side effect profile in children
than it does
with adults and it for for some of these
really sick kids it's something that
should not be ignored it might even be
a first line treatment option because of
better efficacy faster at lower doses
better cost effectiveness than cbd so i
think we've got time for one more
30-second question
to the whole panel two questions one
about uh the use
the efficacy and bioavailability from
nanoparticle
uh cannabis full spectrum not just cbd
and the second question is
what other kind of uh chemical can be
used
uh to expedite bioavailability
outside of nanotechnology i'll just
address the second part
um as we heard alluded to this morning
uh cannabinoids get invest with a lipid
carrier
so you'll see a lot of preparations in
sesame oil or coconut oil or
ghee is a really good one
additionally absorption is aided by
taking with food
as opposed to a lot of other medicines
particularly herbal agents
but that would be the advice there
all right if we can thank the the
panelists here this has been very
enlightening and
conducting discussion
you