[Music]
our knowledge of the effect of cannabis
and the use of cannabis is expanding all
the time we're learning how cannabis
works were learning about the mechanism
of cannabis work and we are learning how
it affects different states of well
disease one type of disease another type
of disease and we have to learn that and
we have to expand our knowledge all the
time and I'm glad to learn that the
meeting of can met this year is going to
do exactly that it's going to tell us
about the new things that we have
learned over the last few years on
cannabis use in medicine and just to
give you a few examples we published
that
cannabidiol is effective in several
neurological diseases in particular
epilepsy many many years ago we
published actually a clinical paper on
epilepsy but the the use of cannabis or
Canobie diode in epilepsy was not taken
over for 30 years we should not allow
this to happen again we should try to
move from basic science to clinical
science as fast as possible and this I
hope will be happening over the next few
years and I hope that by having meetings
like can MIT will make possible this
faster advance and I can just mention a
few diseases that I believe can be
helped with cannabis but at the moment
they're not being used to any to any
extent because clinical trials missing
for example diabetes type 1 which is an
autoimmune disease namely the body
attacks
the cells that produce insulin and the
body doesn't have enough insulin as sick
well we found in animals that
cannabidiol is very effective but it has
not been tried yet in humans I believe
that it will be helpful it may be a
pretty good cure I hope but we don't
have the data
another example is schizophrenia about
1% the world population has
schizophrenia and it has been shown in
clinical trials in this case that it
definitely is hopeful cannabidiol at
very high doses it's helpful and yet it
is not being used I have no idea why but
if we show in many preclinical and
clinical trials that it's useful
ultimately it will be used and there are
many many other examples and I believe
that one of the ways to expand our
knowledge to put pressure when needed
so that cannabis or specific Anna Beadon
cannot be no it's like cannabidiol or
THC and by having these meetings we can
help and I believe that can met 2:18
will be one of the major most important
meetings in this area this year
[Music]
you