[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed conference
all right i have some great news to
report at the top here
the recordings of all the canmed 2022
presentations and panel discussions have
been added to the canmed archive
head over to
canmedevents.com to check out more than
20 hours of new content yes we did the
math
while you're at canmedevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts as i said
last episode we're working hard behind
the scenes getting ready to announce
details around our canmed 23 event
the higher-ups won't let me give away
too many details but trust me this is an
event you won't want to miss
and if you're signed up for email alerts
you will be among the first to receive
word
my guest this week is heather grab
heather is a senior lecturer at cornell
university's school of integrated plant
science where she delivers best
practices for the cultivation and
processing of hemp to professionals in
cornell's hemp science mps program
she works with plant breeders
pathologists biochemists
extension professionals regulatory
officials and industry partners in new
york state and across the globe to
translate the latest science and
industry insights into a curriculum that
covers hemp from soil to sale
so it should come as no surprise that
our conversation covered a wide range of
topics related to hemp cultivation
those topics include
how heather got involved in studying
hemp
an overview of the cornell university
hemp research program
heather's research into integrated pest
management in hemp
in particular finding out which pests
are most harmful to outdoor hemp plants
we also talk about the wide variety of
hemp varieties that cornell grows in
their field trials and how they prevent
male fiber crops from pollinating the
cannabinoid rich plants
we discuss what is preventing hemp from
displacing other legacy crops how
pollinators specifically bees interact
with hemp plants how frost and other
stresses affect cannabinoid levels and
much more
but before i get to my conversation with
heather i want to thank this episode's
sponsor
conception nurseries
conception nurseries the world's largest
micropropagation lab brings proven
agricultural technology to cannabis with
tissue culture technology
to date cannabis cultivators have been
dependent on mother plants to produce
clones resulting in inconsistent
harvests
with diluted and uncontrollable traits
tissue culture technology which is
widely used in industrial agriculture to
address the exact problems cannabis
cultivators face today allows conception
to quickly mass produce identical
disease-free plantlets with customized
and consistent characteristics
for more information visit
conceptionnurseries.com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with heather grab
[Music]
good afternoon heather thanks for
joining us on the podcast
thanks so much for having me ben
all right well i'm excited to talk with
you today about hemp science and
specifically about the work you're
involved with at cornell university
which is one of the leading academic
institutions in the u.s here
studying the plan
so first
i was hoping you could tell the audience
a bit about yourself and how you got
involved with hemp research and how you
ended up at cornell
sure happy to give a brief intro to
myself and then to talk a little bit
more about our program here
at cornell
my academic background is actually in
entomology so the study of insects i did
a lot of work with small farms in the
region for my phd focused on crop
protection and developing integrated
pest management solutions that would
also be beneficial for crops that rely
on other insects for services
including pest control and biological
control which greenhouse growers can
rely on to help suppress their pest
populations but pollinators as well i
did a lot of work with wild pollinator
populations and that is actually
interestingly what got me
interested academically in hemp and
cannabis research so when we first
started producing
industrial hemp here in new york state
our team leader dr larry smart
was fielding a lot of calls from our
grower collaborators in that very first
year or two
asking why they were seeing so many bees
in their fiber and grain hemp crops
so
as somebody who is an entomologist with
a strong interest in bees uh he sent me
an email and i was like great i would
love to get out there to hemp fields i
had
a student who was working with me that
summer nate flicker on his
senior thesis project and he made that
sort of what his focus was for the rest
of the year and we went out and surveyed
the pollinator communities on industrial
hemp to see what the bees were doing
out there and after sort of getting that
experience in the field with hemp there
was an opportunity for me to join our
hemp team here full-time to teach and
mentor students
in our professional master's degree
program
that has
a whole ability for students to focus on
a hemp and cannabis tract within that
degree program and so i left for that
opportunity which is
how i joined our broader hemp team here
at cornell it's truly a privilege to be
part of this community
at cornell that includes academics like
myself who focus on teaching
communicating doing research
as well as extension educators who are
sort of this interface with the grower
community in the state to help solve
problems that they have and to build the
industry
so that's a little bit of the overview
of myself and the
broad research and education program
that we have here at cornell
excellent um and i do want to get into
some more detail about the work that
you've done with the pollinators in hemp
but before we do that i do want to talk
a bit about the program at cornell so
i was wondering if you could give a
little more detail in terms of you know
what does the program cover and kind of
what makes it unique from other programs
that are going on
i'm glad you asked that ben we have a
broad array of different
educational opportunities in hemp and
cannabis we recognize that there's a ton
of interest
in this space and we want to help
support and build the industry by
providing knowledge and helping
companies and individuals to answer
questions that they might have whether
they're interested in starting a new
business in the hemp space or if they
just want to know more about the plant
as a consumer we have a huge range of
options so of course there's sort of the
traditional student option for
undergraduates where they are already
going to be participating in the college
of ag and life sciences as an
undergraduate student they can take many
of the courses that we have developed
but we also uh began offering a few
years ago
this specialized track that focuses on
hemp and cannabis in our professional
master's degree program so we developed
a suite of five different courses there
we're considering many new ones all the
time
but we have a broad industry overview
course called cannabis biology society
industry
that draws from all over the university
law school students business school
students hospitality students of course
ag sciences and biology students take
that class
i teach a course on production systems
also in the fall semester that covers
everything from cultivar selection
and site selection all the way through
all of those cultivation practices that
students need to know about propagation
how you treat plants in the field
whether you're going to make decisions
about pruning and trellising your plants
harvest timing choices
planting density which is critical for
industrial hemp cultivation practices
we have courses in the spring semester
that focus on the processing
of industrial hemp
we also have classes that focus on
breeding and genetics of hemp
and also of course on the pharmacology
of the plant so how the compounds within
the plant interact with our own unique
biology and that of other organisms so
including things like veterinary
applications of some of these hemp
derived molecules so huge suite of
different classes and one thing that i'm
really excited about is that we are now
beginning to offer some of these classes
in an online format so the two options
that i talked about before those are
degree granting programs so either a
traditional bachelor's degree where you
might take a series of courses and
concentrate
in hemp
for your
undergraduate studies
or our professional master's degree
program where you're focusing on these
classes and then building your own
independent project
often with our industry partners to
solve a problem
but we're also beginning to offer these
classes online in a partnership with e
cornell so we already have dr larry
smart's hemp breeding and genetics class
that's launched on there my hemp
production system and my hemp processing
courses will be the next to go up we're
working really closely with our industry
partners to hear what they think are the
most critical skills and areas where we
can provide education so those might be
things like
analytical lab skills which is
incredibly important for this industry
or integrated pest management so we
might develop future classes that focus
specifically on those topics in
particular
yeah and it's it's interesting you
mentioned integrated pest management and
i it stuck out to me too when you were
kind of talking about your background as
well because
that's something that we're seeing at
least on our side with medicinal
genomics pop up more because
obviously we're involved in the
microbial testing of sort of the end
product and you know one of the things
that's coming online is irradiation
which we're finding has all sorts of
different issues and one of the
alternatives to remediating your product
that's that's contaminated is sort of
preventing that on the front end which
as i understand it ipm can really help
with so
um
how much work have you done with with
ipm on hemp and what are some of the
some of the things you've learned
um i have actually a grant right now
with my colleague marion zuffal from new
york state ipm so we actually have this
broad ipm program that's supported by
the state and housed at cornell
university to establish what's called a
crop profile for him so this is the
foundational material that ipm
practitioners would be able to look at
to understand crop schedules
cultivars that are used what kind of
production practices are cultivators
using in the system
and really importantly at this early
stage of development in the industrial
hemp and in the outdoor production to
also see what pests are going to be most
critical i think we have a relatively
good idea of what pests are most
causing issues in greenhouse and indoor
production
but as we cultivate more hemp outdoors
especially grain and fiber hemp learning
what those issues will be and trying to
be
aware of the broad array of different
issues that can occur across the full
life stage of hemp so things that attack
those early germinating seeds out in the
field like pythium for example or head
blights that can cause
the buildup of mycotoxins in grain
production and where what regions of the
country are those likely to happen or
even issues like pests of
birds for example and maybe eating grain
that surprisingly is a very large issue
here
in many of the research farms that we
work on there's farms that we just don't
plant on because the bird pressure is so
high that we lose a substantial portion
of our grain crop to birds every year so
just
understanding what the landscape is
so that's a project that we have funded
that will hopefully complete over the
next year with the help of some of our
professional masters students who might
take on a portion of that as their
capstone project that they complete in
the course of their degree
excellent well when you when you finish
that project i look forward to having
you back on to talk about that
um i know one of the other things that
you guys do and i saw that you just
posted about this it was either this
week or last week is you have a field
day
where you sort of present
all the field trials and things that you
guys have been working on throughout the
year tell us a bit about that and what
do you have planned for 2022
sure so
um my colleague dr daniela vergara is
taking the lead on organizing our field
day this year this is sort of
one of the main feature days where we
highlight the research and
the work that we're doing
as a hemp team here at cornell so i
think one of the things that makes
our entire team unique is that we have
so many different experts from across a
broad range of disciplines who are all
leveraging their unique insights skills
and connections with their industry
partners to help us
build solutions that are
really right at the point where growers
need them and having the opportunity for
growers to come out and actually see
what we're doing in the field
is so critical so daniela and her
colleagues in cornell cooperative
extension have been doing a great job of
putting together a schedule of speakers
for that event that will include
pathologists who will talk about the
kinds of diseases and issues that we're
seeing in the field across multiple
different market classes whether that's
grain fiber or
high cannabinoid hemp
we will have of course marion and myself
there talking about insect issues
we will have our breeders there
graduate students are frequently also
presenting some of the projects that
they are working on so i think a
personal highlight for me is always
seeing our cult of our trials out there
in the field
there's nowhere else i think you can go
where you can see as many different
cultivars of hemp being grown in one
place so we have a huge array of
different cultivars that we include in
our high cannabinoid outdoor trials but
also grain
and fiber cultivars so i think this year
whether
as long as the weather cooperates with
us we will have some demonstrations on
harvesting fiber hemp we'll talk about
some important processes that are
enacted by beneficial microbes in the
process of reading fiber hemp out there
so you really get to see that full
experience you're welcome to touch the
plants to get out there to smell them to
see what we're seeing in the field
on this field day so it's a great it's a
really great experience for those who
can make it to our agritech campus in
geneva new york
awesome now in the pro is the primary
audience for that event like growers
like maybe folks who are looking to get
into the industry and are trying to
learn as much as possible
um i certainly encourage growers to come
out of course we try to think about
things that are most relevant for
growers however
it's a great place also for processors
to be so they can understand what some
of the issues are that growers are
seeing on the field so for example if
you're a fiber hemp processor it's
beneficial for you to be there so that
you can understand and help to guide the
partners that you're working with on the
production side
things like cults of our choice or
harvest timing or post-harvest issues
that they might encounter same is true
for the high cannabinoid market as well
so it's great for them to get out there
see what those plants look like in the
field in our cult of our trials what
kind of practices you mentioned before
some issues with microbial contamination
what what are the things that we can do
in terms of biological controls that may
be really helpful in preventing issues
like botrytis or powdery mildew that can
occur either in the greenhouse or in the
field and how might some of the
applications of those crop protection
materials influence downstream
processing
last year we had great attendance
by folks who are on the analytical side
as well we usually also bring in
regulators who can help us to understand
the current regulatory landscape which
is always sort of in flux it seems
there's always new changes that are
happening at you know the usda level or
the state level within our program so
making sure that we're really actively
communicating
all of the
different reports that growers need to
be processing and thinking about all the
licenses that they need to acquire to be
successful
excellent and now you mentioned this
this huge array of different cultivars
and some being grown for cannabinoids
some being grown for fiber what is sort
of the mix there in terms of the focus
of the research there at your program
though is it primarily focused on on the
cannabinoids or is it fiber because i
know at least
when you look at a lot of the folks who
are are growing it commercially
it tends to be a lot of cannabinoids
yeah and i would say that's very true in
new york state our production has very
much been dominated by
high cannabinoid hemp in terms of
overall market value acreage most of the
markers you would look at
of course cannabinoid hemp has been
dominant and that has been a feature of
our program but we also have a lot of
research on the ground to help support
the development of the industrial hemp
industry so i would say we have a fairly
even distribution but of course there's
you know i mentioned before we have this
broad range of expertise within our
program so dr neil matson who leads our
controlled environment agriculture
program so focuses mostly on greenhouse
and indoor cultivation strategies of
course his lab has been focused almost
entirely on high cannabinoid hemp
production there was a little bit of
baby leaf hemp that went on
in indoor cultivation so some interest
in these like specialty niche markets
but i would say we're very much
interested in
exploring and supporting all aspects of
the hemp industry
excellent
and so
you know we we mentioned that a lot of
the commercial uh environment is really
focused on cannabinoids and so i have to
ask this for any time i talk to anyone
who's focused specifically on help is
you know why do you think hemp really
hasn't lived up to this this promise of
it being a super crop that's gonna
replace all these other legacy crops
it's an excellent question um of course
we we do hear a lot of hype um and it
seems like things change
all the time what it is that we're
excited about with the crop whether it's
carbon sequestration or replacing
other crops that might have a higher
level of environmental impact through
pesticide use or through use of limited
water resources in some regions and i
think
hemp is beginning to make inroads in
many of these areas but making sure that
all of those pieces of the supply chain
can come together in a coordinated
fashion
is a major
barrier to the development of the
industry and that's part of where
extension services and where
academia can help to come in and to
support some of the creation of
knowledge so for example
you know speaking with our industry
partners who work in
food applications they're really excited
about using hemp proteins as an
alternative to animal based proteins or
even to other plant-based options so for
example
almonds and cashews which are frequently
used in these plant-based alternatives
don't necessarily have the greatest
profile in terms of either
sustainability or their social equity
impact so having hemp as an alternative
is great however
we have to build the knowledge for how
to process and how to handle those
ingredients so that you know of course
we don't want uh to drink a hemp milk or
have a hemp ice cream that tastes
exactly like you're eating hemp hearts
we want it to taste like the chocolate
flavor or the coffee profile that is
supposed to be there and for other
proteins we have a lot of knowledge
about how to incorporate those into food
products so we have food scientists here
who are working really closely with our
plant breeders to help to develop
cultivars that can meet those specific
needs for the industry same is true when
it comes to industrial fiber
applications i think a big issue in
grain which i'm sure you know other
podcast interviewees have probably
mentioned is the ability to use grain
in animal feed so
the opportunity for that crop or some of
the byproducts that come from grain to
be able to be incorporated for poultry
or for other uses is very important so
right now growers who are not able to
market their crop into the human food
market for whatever reason
don't have any other option for where to
offload that crop in order to perhaps
recover some of the investment that they
have so if you're a soybean grower
and you had planned to have some of your
product used for soybean oil for human
consumption but for whatever reason
you're not able to make it into that
market space of course you have the
options to offload that product in a
number of other markets that we don't
have developed yet for hemp the good
news is there's many different academic
institutions and industry groups that
are working to develop those
different supply sources right now so i
think we will see him develop as a crop
but slow and steady will win the race
and having this integrated
across the board knowledge base whether
it's developing the right cultivars for
the right end uses or the right climates
having food scientists who are really
familiar with the attributes and the
qualities of these products all the way
through the supply chain that's going to
be really important
yeah well i guess that makes a lot of
sense that you know
the cannabinoid sort of supply chain or
processing chain like that's that's
pretty well established um but in order
to sort of
unseat some of these other
other crops that have had you know
decades of refinement in you know
optimization it's definitely gonna take
some time in order to get there that
makes sense
um and then i i mean from what limited
knowledge i have as i understand it just
you know the actual processing equipment
and the availability of that is somewhat
of a barrier as well and
um you know in getting ready for this
podcast i did see that colorado they
just had a proposal up there to use five
million dollars of their cannabis tax
collection funds to buy processing
equipment for that reason too to sort of
help support uh hemp growers in that
state but unfortunately that got quashed
so how much of a barrier is sort of just
processing equipment or processing
facilities
processing facilities are a
a big challenge in terms of developing
the industry so
there's a bit of a chicken and egg
issue that we have in developing
especially the fiber
side of the industrial hemp market so
for grain there's a whole lot of
infrastructure out there that's fairly
easy to adapt to handle oil seed crops
like hemp grain of course there's some
you know unique issues with
incorporating those into food products
that i mentioned before but with fiber
hemp it's really about these very large
capital investments in
facilities so five million dollars is
really a drop in the bucket when we
think about what it costs to
establish even one of these processing
facilities we are fortunate in that
there are many companies who have
already been gaining experience
with fiber hemp processing mostly in
europe so a lot of equipment that was
traditionally used to process flax
in northern europe can be fairly easily
adapted to handle
fiber hemp as well there's
of course france has been cultivating
fibre hemp and germany on a large scale
for a while now but some of the
companies
um
cretes or la roche those companies that
are producing this equipment so
building those individual pieces of
equipment is a challenge right now due
to supply chain issues but even if it
wasn't
a single piece of equipment from one of
those companies can run anywhere up to
three million dollars depending on the
size and the type of processing
equipment that we want to import so
that's a substantial
investment
and then at the same time those
processors that are coming into that
middle space in the market
also need to be coordinating with the
manufacturers who are going to take that
processed material and convert that into
a final product whether that's a textile
that goes on to
use in clothing or automobiles or
furniture other sources or an insulation
product or a hemp cream block something
like that and they also need to
coordinate with the producers who are on
the cultivation side helping them to
choose the right genetics and to make
sure that there will be someone there if
they plant their crop that in a couple
months that there will actually be
someone in place to purchase and utilize
that crop that they have invested in so
that is sort of the challenge of
building up this entire industry where
do we start um the having that sort of
middle processing component in place is
very important but it's also
a fine line to walk for those who are
investing in that space because they
have to manage both sides of the market
but of course they're also in a very
unique place to have the opportunity to
help to set the standards and to build
that supply chain so
wow
so
and now you mentioned different
applications whether it be for um you
know a textile or hemp crete or anything
like that so is the actual processing of
the material different for those
different applications
absolutely yes
so even in in the textile space there is
processing equipment and even in the
field harvesting methods that you would
use if you want to produce a long
textile fiber so i have an example here
you can't see it but it's you know a
very long fiber so the reading practices
that you use how you harvest it you want
to of course keep all of the individual
stems parallel for that so they're not
all mixed together how they would be for
example for hay so keeping everything
parallel from the point of harvest all
the way through processing is very
important the kind of equipment that you
use
whether you're going to do switching and
hackling there's all these fun terms
that come into play in the fiber hemp
processing world
the choices that you're making there are
different than if you want to produce
what we might call cottonized hemps so
that is really short fiber hemp that
could then be used for spinning so if
you're thinking about developing a 100
hemp t-shirt
you're going to go for a cottonized hemp
product and the manufacturing line
so from the field processing line it's
going to look very different it's
similar so i think a lot of your
audience is really familiar with all the
different choices you can make in
processing high cannabinoid hemp if you
want to make a hash product you're going
to make a ton of different choices
you're going to select different
cultivars based on their trichome
architecture and development you're
going to take those plants potentially
freeze them right after harvest rather
than dry and cure them so all of those
things are very different depending on
the final product and it's exactly the
same for fiber hemp processing as well
excellent all right all right um so
let's talk about bees
because i don't know we're running out
of time here and i don't want to make
sure that we talk about that so um tell
us a bit about the research that you did
looking into how um hemp can support
some of the pollinator population
sure
so um nate and i when we took on this
project um we were able to connect with
a lot of growers who had formal
collaborations with our university
during the early days of our hemp
production program here in new york
state all of our growers were
essentially collaborating in some shape
or form
with our land-grant universities to help
understand what the challenges would be
so
we were welcomed to come and visit many
of the farms across the state to see
what their challenges were in the field
but also to see what opportunities have
presented and in this case we found a
huge array of different bee species that
were visiting industrial hemp fields
and the reason that they were there was
to collect pollen from male plants so
unlike cannabinoid hemp production where
you want a completely female field so
every plant would be female in grain and
fiber hemp production we have mixed
stands of both female and male plants or
in some cases we even have monicious
plants which means that they're actually
selected to produce both male and female
flowers on the same plant which is
uncommon for hemp generally but we do
see that happening so they're out there
collecting pollen hemp and cannabis
generally produces no nectar for the
bees so they're really just there to
collect that pollen and they use that
pollen if they've collected it bring it
back to their nests and then feed their
developing offspring on that most people
are of course really familiar with
honeybees and after we published this
paper we got a lot of buzz
around maybe the ability to produce um
high cannabinoid honeys for example
however
you know while the bees seem to very
much focus their foraging attention on
hemp even when other floral resources
are available to them in terms of the
overall scheme of what they're bringing
back to their hives at least in a
diverse region like we have here in new
york state it's pretty small and
the pollen which does have cannabinoids
in it still at such a low level that you
would really need to eat a substantial
portion of honey in order to get even a
small dose i think i calculated out a 25
milligram dose
of cannabinoids would take you about a
thousand pounds of honey or more
to just at the natural level so that's
not to say there are other folks out
there who are experimenting with
different methods of introducing
cannabinoids to hives or
sort of focusing more of the foraging
effort of a colony on
hemp and cannabis
but i would say if you're
getting hemp honey advertised to you
it's almost certainly not something
that's a
naturally created process and
spontaneous it's
most likely cannabinoids that have been
added to a honey product after the bees
were involved so i'm still very much
interested in beneficial insects
including bees that might be supported i
have many of the bee species that we
found so outside of the european
honeybee of course we have
bumblebees which are native here we had
a wide array of other small native bees
that we're using hemp many of which are
very important pollinators of other
crops so
pollinators of tomatoes apples
strawberries blueberries squash pumpkins
all of these other really high value
crops which
you know may be lacking floral resources
on the farm at the period when those
crops aren't blooming and hemp can help
to fill that gap when there's no other
flowers around it can support some of
those bees of course we also need to be
aware that it's not providing nectar
so thinking not only about the resources
that it provides but also if we're going
to make crop protection choices we need
to account for the fact that there could
be beneficial insects like pollinators
there and to think about that for even
these crops that are not pollinator
dependent but maybe supporting a lot of
beneficial insects as well
yeah so so what's the difference between
pollen and i mean obviously there is a
difference between pollen and nectar but
in terms of the bees
how do they use each oh thank you so
much for asking i feel like i'm such a
bug nerd that i
don't always think about what people who
aren't as focused on bees and the floral
resources and rewards that they provide
are doing so nectar is usually sort of
that sugary
secretion that often comes from the base
of petals for example so hemp does not
provide that many other crops buckwheat
for example is a crop that provides
great resources
goldenrod which we have abundantly here
in the northeast is an excellent floral
resource that provides a ton of nectar
but pollen is really the key protein
source for bees so i mentioned before
that bees are collecting all of that
pollen and in the process of collecting
they're pollinating our crops but that's
really secondary in their objective it's
really not necessarily an objective of
theirs at all but they are actually
collecting that pollen and bringing it
back to their nests in order to feed
their developing offspring so the almost
entire life cycle of a bee is spent
underground in most cases eighty percent
of bees nest in the ground or in their
nest and they consume pollen as larvae
and then develop into a bee so most of
the time they're in this larval stage
underground and it's only maybe a few
weeks out of the year for most bee
species that we see them
in their characteristic b
form so really important protein source
for them these are actually sort of
carnivores but focused on this
high protein resource that's provided by
plants so
interesting and you mentioned that it
seems like the bees actually prefer hemp
to other you know flowers that may be in
the area yeah we haven't done a big
formal study of that but i was really
shocked to have observed
these that had many other floral
resources available to them
seemingly focusing heavily
on the hemp crop so in one of our large
fiber trials last year
there was a ton of bees visiting that
planting all day long
a large field of buckwheat planted right
next to it as i mentioned that's a crop
that provides a great source of nectar
very few bees on that crop um fields of
clover cover crop nearby
also a high protein source of pollen
very few bees they were really excited
about foraging on the hemp potentially
because the pollen is so much more
easily accessible on hemp plants because
they're releasing it onto the wind so
um i'm really interested to look though
to see if there are potential benefits
of
having access to
this unique floral resource either
because of its nutritional composition
high protein relative to other sources
perhaps
or if there are any effects of these
cannabinoid or terpene molecules that
may be present in the hemp pollen that
could have beneficial effects for the
bees so bees don't have endocannabinoid
systems like we do actually no insects
have the active cb1 cb2 receptors that
typically is you know that's how we
sense the effects of cannabinoids in our
own body insects lack those but that
doesn't mean that they're not having
other effects beneficial or otherwise on
those insects there's been some
speculation about
potential
effects of cannabinoids in
mitigating some of the diseases that
we're really worried about and
pollinator populations right now so
it would be
great to have the opportunity to work
with a student on a project like that
excellent excellent and now when you
mentioned
that um you know when hemp is being
grown for fiber or for um
well for fiber that you know the concern
about having males isn't as high
obviously because you know it's not
going to produce seeds in your flour so
now i'm thinking back to your your field
day
at cornell where you said that you're
growing both for fiber and for
cannabinoids so how do you manage how do
you manage that and make sure that some
of the male pollen or do you not grow
males
so we absolutely have male plants in our
green and fiber trials so for our
cultivars that are not monica so
producing both male and female on the
same plant for grain production we need
those uh male plants there to pollinate
our female plants and to produce grain
in fiber actually male plants have some
benefit some positive attributes
relative to female plants especially for
textile production they tend to have
finer fiber structures on them so
we really do want to have a lot of males
in our production for those plants so
what we do is we spend a lot of time
coordinating among our entire research
team so we have you know we have this
issue in many different flavors so
pollen transfer certainly won and we are
lucky at cornell to have a really large
system of research farms spread across
the region so we have facilities on long
island we have facilities at our
agro-tech campus in geneva farms here in
our ithaca region and then other
research farms that are spread out
across the state that can help us to
achieve some separation so of course
though at our agritech campus which is
part of our research hub for cannabis
and hemp um we have a lot of programs
going on there
interested in fiber grain and
cannabinoid production and so we try to
space our plants around if you go to our
page that talks about all of the
research work that we do there we
actually did a study a few years back
looking at how far pollen is likely to
move and where that risk of pollination
is and so we do a good job of
coordinating the placement of our
different trials so that our fiber cult
of our trial is not pollinating our high
cannabinoid trials we also work with
industry partners who are developing new
cultivars so an example of this is the
triploid genetics that are being
produced uh so we are really involved in
researching those cultivars and sort of
giving them a really good pollen heavy
challenge and that was part of our field
day last year those who came to the
field day could actually see
these triploid cultivars grown in an in
an area right next to a large fiber
production field where there was an
incredibly high pressure of pollen and
to see how well they perform in that
environment
wow that's that's really cool
all right i've already kept you over the
time that i promised but i before i let
you go i did want to just ask you you
mentioned that you work a lot with your
students on on capstone projects um so i
want to give you an opportunity to to
talk about some of the ones that have
really stood out or i know that you
mentioned that one of them just recently
published so let's talk a bit about that
sure yeah i would say that's
one of the great privileges that i have
in my role on the hemp team here at
cornell is mentoring our
hemp professional degree students in
their capstone projects so throughout
the course of the fall and spring
semester and usually also into the
summer our students are working
intensively on whatever area is really
of interest to them so i mentioned
before we have this really broad
curriculum because we want students
especially who are in
our professional master's program to
really understand all components of the
industry because we believe that's
critical for helping to build a
workforce and to build a well-integrated
strong industry but we recognize also
that students come with a desire to
focus in particular areas whether that's
understanding lighting issues and what
the most effective lighting practices
are or
maybe processing and analytical
challenges and so
each student sort of has the option to
work with
industry partners and most critically
with really strong mentorship from our
faculty to help to design a project that
they can tackle which ideally addresses
a challenge
within the industry and so um the one
that was just actually published today
uh congrats to andre gallis who led this
project uh was based on an observation
that andre had with some cultivators who
were working in vermont so back in
it was probably the fall of
that he was in dialogue with some
growers in the northeast that had
experienced that fall a really hard
frost
just prior to harvesting their crop and
in some cases they lost their crop in
other cases they were able to recover
some of that harvest but they really
were interested in understanding what
impact that would have
on their plants or what happened so as
the climate becomes more variable these
frosts become less predictable how what
would happen if that had happened
earlier in you know the early flowering
stage so andre set out to design this
experiment to help answer that question
exactly he grew out plants starting at
different dates so that he would have an
array of three different ages he did
some acclimation experiments where he
allowed some of those to sort of come to
this gradual cool temperature
and then some of those plants as well as
some that had not been acclimated
were exposed
to different amounts of freezing
so some got one
freezing for a few hours and some had
consecutive multiple freezing stresses
on them he measured a whole bunch of
plant stress responses as well as
looking at the final biomass that was
produced by those plants in terms of the
flower biomass which is most important
for our growers and we also looked at
how that might impact cannabinoid
profiles so some other work that has
also been published out of our hemp team
program here led by jacob toth
fantastic experiment looking at how
stress influences cannabinoid profiles
that was a big concern in the industry
especially when we think about that
0.3
limit there's been debate about bringing
that up to 1
and what he found is that stress is not
a big factor in driving plants above
that compliance threshold of three
percent so he tested plants with
herbicides he did damage he did many
different things to stress these plants
out and really
underscore the fact that it's based on
the plant's genetics that drive that
change so with cannabinoids we also
expected that to be the case with this
cold stress as well so what is the
impact of cold stress on the changes in
cannabinoid profile generally not much
we see that of course there are
differences among cultivars but one
thing we are concerned about in terms of
frost especially very late in harvest is
the potential to actually lose trichomes
through physical
impact on the plant so of course we're
thinking about
making an ice water hash for example we
know we get those trichomes really cold
they become very fragile
so that's something that we were also
looking for in that publication and i'll
make sure to pass that on to you so you
can include a link to that in your show
notes
yeah i will absolutely do that and
no that's interesting that stress
doesn't seem to have um you know a big
impact on cannabinoids but i'm curious
what about terpenes um because as i
understand it you know terpenes can sort
of be used to ward off pests or be sort
of a response to stress so did you find
anything there we did not look at
terpenes in either jacob or andre's
study however we are very excited to
begin incorporating studies looking at
terpenes in a lot of our research going
forward so
we have a an hplc in our teaching lab we
also have now a new mini gc
from lucidity systems which is a cem
corporation so that allows us to
evaluate plants that we grow out and use
in our courses for both the cannabinoid
profile and their terpene profiles i'm
really excited to work with students on
developing methods that are tailored to
those machines our
big testing lab on campus of our
research analytical facility has a
really excellent new gc system from
agilent which is sort of sole purpose i
mean you can use it from anything but we
will be using it solely for looking at
terpene profiles in our research program
here for
hemp so very excited to start looking at
that more to see how stress may impact
uh terpene profiles or just regular
cultivation practices could be
influencing them or genetics there's a
whole bunch of different angles that
we're excited to work on
excellent okay
so
thanks again for staying late um but
before i let you go i do want to give
you an opportunity to plug any websites
social media anything that people can do
to get in touch with you or just follow
what you're working on
sure yeah so folks can find me
on the um cal school of integrative
plant sciences website
i am on linkedin also it's a great place
to connect with me i would encourage
folks to attend our field day in august
in geneva if they can make it if not uh
there may potentially be some recordings
that could be made of that
and there's always handouts from our
field days that are posted on our hemp
team research and extension page if you
just google
uh cornell hemp you will
almost certainly find that as the very
top response on your page and you will
find all of our faculty who are involved
with different areas of research and all
of the many many reports that we have
been producing so it's a great place if
you're an industry member who's looking
to partner with cornell to get in touch
with faculty who have expertise in
different areas i will also put out a
plug for any industry members who are
excited about
working with our professional
masters students on capstone projects
all of the students who have worked with
me in our professional master's program
focused on hemp have done capstone
projects in collaboration with industry
partners it's been a great success so
far and we're always looking for new
ideas
all right excellent
all right heather thanks again for
joining us and sharing all the great
work that you're doing over there in
cornell and um
hope to see you soon maybe i'll make it
out there for field day we would love to
see you ben and anybody in the audience
you can make it out
all right thanks again
thank you
[Music]
bye hope you enjoyed my conversation
with heather grab
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode's sponsor conception
nurseries
our next episode will drop july 6th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do go over to
canmanevents.com and check out our
canmed 2022 video recordings
please also be sure to follow us on
social media we're on facebook twitter
linkedin and instagram just search for
cam at events
also we welcome you to contribute to our
canmed community facebook group
it's a great way to interact with other
members of the canmed community
including past speakers and fellow
attendees
one last thing please rate review and
subscribe on your favorite podcast app
doing so really helps the podcast reach
more listeners particularly the reviews
each time we get new reviews we see a
bump in our rankings which really helps
us out so we appreciate that
okay that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and please join us on the next
cam ed coffee talk
[Music]
you