good afternoon
my name is Hunter land I am vice
president of research and development
for BRC for those of you who don't know
BRC we're a schedule one research
facility and Manufacturing producer of
cannabinoids
I've been in research about 20 years 12
has been focused on cannabinoids and so
I picked up a couple disclosures along
the way
so today I've come to talk to you a
little bit about cannabinoids aging and
potential effects on neurological
diseases
start the start of this
it began with conversations with the FDA
around
the CBD laws and how to effectively
determine a safe dose of CBD the FDA was
very interested in you know acutely
we're not seeing anything toxic but what
happens when you take this for long
periods of time potentially you know
decades and there's a it's very
difficult to do that type of work in
mammalian models rodents take years and
it's quite costly so one of the models
that is used for that is the C elegans
model we looked at CBD in this model
which I'll tell you about those results
can Abigail on that model as well and
then that brought us to well if we're
seeing this in healthy wild type what
happens in diseased models which brought
us to the town model
so why see aliens
um they do have the best characterized
genetics of any animal that we know a
lot of the metabolic signaling pathways
are conserved with humans they have
short life spans three to four weeks so
this is high throughput you can look at
a bunch of different compounds very
quickly cost effectively it's easy to
track life Movement we can do this with
AI and machine learning and as far as
toxicity and safety goes it's as
predictable as many mammalian models
it's kind of like the canary in the coal
mine approach just with nematodes this
models accepted the EPA likes this model
if we don't know exactly what's in let's
say contaminated water we don't know
what to test for we can determine if
it's toxic just by utilizing the C
Elegance model if they die quicker
probably don't want to spend much time
in the water you certainly don't want to
drink it same kind of application here
and it's also been used by NASA in the
International Space Station to kind of
determine what are the effects at
atmosphere for long periods of time
so the first study we looked at CBD but
you don't see on this slide is the um
the initial study where we tried to
determine uh what the therapeutic range
was and that's done through thermal
tolerance and what we saw was the three
doses or the dose ranges were 10 40 and
100 micromolar or we weren't seeing
toxicity and actually potential some
some potential reduction in stress so
those are the the doses that we use for
this this particular lifespan model and
we did ultimately see increased lifespan
in in all three doses with the 40 micro
molar being the best in the extension of
approximately 18 in life span so
positive they didn't live forever but
it's roughly consistent with what you
would see with things like Resveratrol
or metformin again not compared in this
specific study but looks positive and
non-toxic
we also looked at movement which is a
which is an indicator of health and good
health and we again saw Improvement in
health Spain characteristics this
activity and um it was primarily in the
40 micro molar range and you can see if
you look at day 12 to day 15 the green
being the 40 micromolar you see that's
almost consistent with with what you see
in the normal healthy nematodes without
CBD at day 12 so again this is a sales
against mono but it would be great if
you know 80 year old humans acted more
like 60 year old humans so exciting but
again take it you know in the confines
of this model definitely positive and
potentially good in the wellness sector
so he moved on to Canada which has been
an interest of mine as well as many
others here for some time and we
actually found in the thermal
intolerance test that it was much more
well tolerated than CBD so if you notice
the dose range we have here 7.5 75 and
375 micro molar higher than what we
tested at CBD and that's because the
initial
toxicity wasn't seen with canaba Gerald
and again we see the the middle dose the
75 micromolar extending mean lifespan by
about 19 so again looks positive doesn't
look toxic uh good news we of course
shared this with FDA I'm not sure they
cared much but we did share
we also looked at Health span a bit more
variable in this particular model but
again the middle dose at day 15 we see
increased locomotor activity so again
another positive
cannaba Gerald seems to extend lifespan
at least in nematodes and health span
characteristics
so that brought us to well that's great
for the wellness category and for people
that may want to you know utilize this
as a supplement but what about in
diseases you know what what disease
model and C elegans has been accepted
and we landed on the Tau model of C
Elegance
um so so many for those of you that
aren't familiar with Tau I imagine a
list of you are but it is characterized
by these intercellular Aggregates of
this Tau protein and what that does is
it disrupts signaling it also affects
mitochondrial motility there's many
ramifications and we see this not just
in Alzheimer's dementia but also
traumatic brain injury epilepsy stroke
even cancer and some other specific
diseases even in instance of concussion
the the movement between the gray matter
and the white matter can stretch the
neurons resulting in increased Tau
expression so it is a problem we don't
know how much it causes the disease or
it's a symptom but it's definitely in
this model these nematodes don't live
nearly as long as their counterparts
okay so we use the style strain as BR
5270 and they have drastic reductions in
survival compared to Wild type the
design was we had a vehicle control so
just the
br5270 the towel C elegans
and then we had positive control of the
40 micro Mueller CBD so keep in mind
there's not really a great positive
control for Tau if we had that we would
probably treat a lot more diseases but
we didn't know that it was effective in
Wild type at life extension and Health
Plan Health span improvements so we've
stuck with this kind of optimal dose
that we found in the previous study
um as the exploratory test articles we
looked at we've been in partnership with
canerta so thank you kenarta for
providing the canned flavins because
those are difficult to produce and we
don't have them and also from informing
on study design as far as dosing and
concentrations are concerned as it
relates to canned flavins so the goal
here was to look at initially to look at
can flavins specifically at compared to
CBD so those were matched 40 20 and five
so 40 being the exact dose of CBD and
then 20 and 5 as as reduced doses or
exposures of canned flattens
then we looked at a Botanical drug
substance which contained at those
concentrations so 80 micromolar that is
CBD so that does not include the CBG
component and the THC component and the
other minor cannabinoids that are in
this Botanical drug substance so we can
essentially do a direct comparison at
the 40 micro Mueller group of CBD
isolate versus CBD BDS plus the other
constituents and then at 20 would be
roughly half the CBD exposed as the
control group and then lastly we
combined them all so we said what
happens when you combine CBD CBG Delta 9
THC the miners and camoflavins versus
the isolate so really trying to figure
out is there some rational polypharmacy
is there this Entourage effect or is it
more of a non-trage effect which you can
see in some models and with some
compounds
and this was completed in triplicate
so first we looked at the cam flavins
and you can see the separation so if you
look at the the brown and the orange
that's clearly separating from the
control the the green and then once more
from the purple so you see this nice
Trend again they're not living forever
but they don't live very long so
when you move into the t-test you can
see the control CBD at day 16 that's at
Lower Blue Bar you see that's about four
percent survival so pretty pretty poor
outcome if you're a br2 br 5270 C
elegans and you don't get anything CBD
about double a nice Trend but not as
good as what we see can five and so on
so again we've got 40 micromolar cam
Flavin looking Superior to CBD alone and
20 micromolar cam 11 again Superior to
CBD alone
we moved on to look at the same group
but with the Botanical drug substance so
this is CBD CBD and Delta 9 THC versus
CBD versus control
you see this nice Trend and kind of this
early bump in survival at day eight so
looking very positive
and as you move into survival and again
back to the t-test you see 22 percent
survival and 19 at 80 and 40 micro
molars so again about double
a little bit more than double in the 80
micro molar but almost double at a match
CBD dose and still once again even
better at the 20 micro molar so again
positive positive both at day 12 and day
16.
so finally we looked at the canned
Flavin plus the Botanical drug substance
we again see elevation early on day
eight a little bit better than what we
saw with CBD BDS on its own and
certainly better than CBD and that Trend
continues throughout the study
as we move into this overall not seeing
at day 16 not seeing significantly
better survival than we saw with just
the Botanical drug substance although we
do see some improvements kind of midlife
so if you look at that day 12 56 versus
39 pretty much across all dose groups
very positive and again even the 20
micromolar dose at 14 survival is better
than 10 and certainly better than four
so about three to four fold higher
survival levels
the last thing that we looked at was
activity levels it was
um quite difficult to examine activity
levels because
these nematodes were so
entangled with Tau so to speak so we
didn't really see very much the only
thing that we we saw in terms of
positive was that day eight with the
camflaven so we saw a little bit
increase the statistical increase in
motility at day eight we didn't see it
with CBD we didn't see it with any of
the Botanical drug substance but on a
positive note we didn't see the sedation
or we didn't see lack of activity which
you know the cliche would be that maybe
stoned CL against don't move around as
much but we didn't see that so we didn't
see toxicity we didn't see decreased
activity in only a slight increase with
Cam Flav in that day
and unfortunately
there's kind of a rule of thumb that
I've I've come up with working in with
cannabinoids even if your schedule one
DEA facility and you're working with a
partner that has a schedule one license
and it should be really easy to send 25
grams of THC to them it still takes
three months for the DEA to add a
protocol
and for you to be able to ship the the
product there so what I've shared today
is preliminary data we are looking to
see specifically
um if there have been changes in the the
amount of Tau in the the C elegans and
um we have plans to to do further
research with this data set just that
information is not available yet so
thank you
tutor that was really interesting I'm
sure one of the questions that come up
these concentrations seem high can you
provide a little translation for us
about whether these are achievable
levels say in a mammal uh or what the
comparative dosing might be so a great
question Ethan so these are the
concentrations are actually delivering
living environments so they're consuming
essentially the bacterium the E coli
that is exposed to this so they're
consuming CBD so the actual
intracellular levels are not this high
it's much more consistent with what we
would get so about the 80 micromolar
would be consistent with exposure in the
epidiolex trial at 20 makes per kick so
as you go down you have about half that
at 40 and again further reduced at 20.
um it's not exact but that is the best
way that we've been able to kind of come
up with the
correct physiologically relevant
concentration so again not quite like
oncology studies where you're looking
these super high exposures that is it
does tend to mimic more whole organism
real life kind of situation
thank you
okay
all right thank you very much
thank you