so everyone I'm excited to be here AEM
Gardner those lights are
bright um first of all may is ALS
awareness month so I want I'm very
excited to be able to be here to present
on what we're doing in regards to ALS
research I want to challenge all of you
if you know the ice bucket challenge go
home do the ice bucket challenge
challenge your peers to do that and we
are um continuing along with the ALS
Association to raise money for ALS
research it's very well needed now today
I'm going to try something a little bit
different a little bit new so I'm going
to start by asking a question have any
of you guys watched the movie
Oppenheimer alimer learned the story of
the atomic bomb right I thought it was a
very very good movie a powerful and
compelling sto Story one of the things
that blew me away no pun intended but
blew me away the Striking power of
nature when combined with modern
science and just as that film aimed to
bring to light a pivotal moment in
history today I aim to draw a similar
parallel but in the realm of Medical
Science to benefit human health by the
end my aim is to aim is to convince you
that complex human disease are best
solved with the complex but beautifully
beautifully designed power of nature not
as n not nature as a Destroyer but
nature as a Giver of Life and today I'm
excited to share with you the story of
how I think we get
there good
perfect so to start to quickly recap our
mission at Kera is to develop
Therapeutics that Target inflammation
and address unmet needs in neurology and
we're using the Synergy of Cutting Edge
science and proprietary natural
ingredients to do just
that over the last 3 years we've been
exploring Uncharted plant molecules and
doing a lot of work to validate them
pre-clinically this our team is Young
talented gritty and driven there's such
a joy for me to work with each and every
day and we have a science Advisory Board
experienced and proven in Botanical
Pharmaceuticals our goal is to Target
inflammation the root cause of all
disease because 50% of human mortality
is attributed to systematic chronic
inflammation now most drugs on the
market and the ones that still fail in
development still have pretty bad safety
concerns and Botanicals though generally
regarded as safe have efficacy
standardization and patentability issues
but as the prevalence of disease
continues to rise we at kerta see an
opportunity to challenge the traditional
drug development and treatment
Paradigm now can Flavin A and B are two
of our star molecules that help us do
just that these two are penol flavonoids
unique to Cannabis sativa
they have a flavone backbone consisting
of two fennel rings and a heterocyclic
ring they're highly lipophilic and that
allows them to easily accumulate in
cells and potentially membrane Brown
enzymes and receptors and they're
traditionally found extremely scarce and
rare in the plant and under
0.014% of the plant's
biomass well we've developed production
technology um patented Tech that allows
us to be able to produce the as extracts
alongside purified molecules that we've
been able to use to gain deeper
understanding of their mechanisms how
they work against inflammatory and
neurodegenerative targets today I'm
going to start by laying the groundwork
of how these molecules might be
beneficial in areas of neurod
degenerative
disease canlen is a dual inhibitor of
proinflammatory enzymes it has 30 times
the potency of Asa the active ingredient
in Aspirin but it doesn't have Cox one
activity as it works through five alone
so a higher safety profile is expected
with repeated and chronic use now though
this initial Discovery was made in vitro
in the mid 1980s no one's produced
enough of this molecule to be able to
validate the original assays with
botanically derived ingredients as we
have here or they haven't moved things
forward in Vivo not in a human or in a
mouse until
now what we were able to do was do an
LPS induced acute respiratory distress
model that was able to show that can
flaven a was able to reduce cyto kind
storm markers and amarate the pulmonary
function in a statistically significant
way we have other data not shown on the
slide but it shows that we were able to
decrease no activity which is a measure
of inflammation and a reduction in the
cyto known as
cxcl1 notably while
dexamethasone I think we can see it here
in this one is what I'm talking about
dexamethasone was failed to improve the
respiratory dysfunction improved by LPS
our can 5 and a successfully restored
the respiratory function in these
mice so then we contined to look at how
these molecules could help and what we
used here was C elegans in a model due
to their genetic and behavioral
suitability for simulating human
neurological conditions in these studies
compounds were tested at a concentration
of 20 micromolar with Endeavor own
serving as the positive control over 10
experiments three that I'm going to show
you today our can Flavin exhibited
significant activity especially in
models related to ALS and frontal
temporal dementia this suggested to us a
valuable direction for future Research
into their potential
benefits and this is what brought us to
ALS otherwise known as lugar's disease
for any of you not familiar ALS is a
rare dehab motor neuron disease with
rapid progression and average mortality
coming just 2 years after
diagnosis there's currently no cure and
or treatments to manage symptoms as the
disease is very complex with a
multifactoral nature of neuron
degeneration there's a need for new
treatments to meet the unmet needs of
patients as every 90 minutes someone in
the US is newly diagnosed with ALS and
every 90 minutes someone with ALS passes
away from the
disease it's hard to understate just how
much of a challenge this disease is and
how much of a challenge it's been to
modern science as it's completely
heterogeneous means meaning it manifests
differently in each patient and it's
governed by a unique combination of
genetic environmental and biological
factors and there's so many different
things going wrong in the motor neurons
once they start to degenerate
the disease also exists on a spectrum
with other diseases like FTD and
Parkinson's so symptoms are often
misdiagnosed leading to a challenge when
it comes to
treatment traditional drug therapies are
often designed to Target a singular
pathway and these continue to fall short
in effectively treating the multifaceted
disease now one would think with our new
technology and our new ways of making
medicines today over a 150e history of
this dis disease we would have some
traction towards the solution but nope
life expectancy back then was 2 years
post diagnosis and it's still the same
today and the options that we have on
the market today are no good as patients
are left with the options of taking
multiple drugs multiple pills various
solutions to help them manage a dehab
quality of
life even in today's news we still
continue to see failure after failure
after failure in clinical trials most
recently with Amex voluntar voluntarily
withdrawing their medicine due to a
failure after phase three clinical
trials even though both the analyst and
the company thought that this could be a
blockbuster drug but once again patients
were let down um and disappointed after
promising phe 2 Data because it didn't
work and this is just top of the news
over the last 12 months a lot of
failures from a lot of far tical
companies now this has led to Industry
experts calling for change in how we
approached ALS diseases it's not just
one disease you have to treat treat the
illness in multiple different ways and
someone in the room here with us had a
similar calling he had been talking
about it for many of
years this was Dr Ethan Russo our senior
medical adviser and CEO of kedto science
where part of his business is
formulating novel Botanicals that could
be developed
pharmaceutically a few years ago Ethan
began to tell me a story of a patient
that he had first treated when he came
to practice diagnosed with this terminal
disease and this patient refused to be
treated with the traditional
Pharmaceuticals his choice of therapy
was Cannabis and as Ethan will tell you
over 10 years of seeing this patient he
never got
weaker he also told me of his personal
mission to do something here for this
patient population as he too felt the
pain of watching a loved one pass away
from the
disease so as Ethan and I started to
talk this is where things started to
change for me as Ethan let me know about
a patent and formulation he had been
working on throughout his career that he
knew would be able to serve this patient
population so the first thing that I
needed to catch up on was learning the
full potential of the cannabis plant one
of Nature's greatest medicinal plants
with respect to ALS it's important to to
note that there's much anodal evidence
reported of the plant's utility as
patients suffering from both ALS and
other neurodegenerative diseases have
used it in various forms since Antiquity
to manage their
symptoms the second thing I had to learn
was all the advantages of of the
Botanical drug these are multi-target
therapies that are made up of well Toler
tolerated ingredients that we as humans
co-evolved within nature they can be
delivered in a uniform product and as as
many of you know there are Streamlight
advantages in developing Botanical drugs
with Regulators around the world
recognizing the long history of
traditional use that we have for these
medicines and lastly patients they
generally prefer natural naturally
derived medicines anyways versus the
synthetically derived ones they all lean
towards the laws of
nature now for me as a law school
graduate I love that I get to lean on
the historical evidence of proof of can
ab's utility in human health like in
2700 BCE Emperor shenan wrote that
protracted taking may make one fat may
make you will make you strong but you'll
never go see
now in the 1200 CE writings from the
anak Anaconda shared that in combination
with celibacy those who used cannabis as
part of a rigorous regime could leave
live 300 years free from any disease and
signs of old age maybe worth it maybe
not I don't
know and in the 9th century alindi
famously wrote hashish eases the muscles
of the limbs and What
flows now more recently the bioactive
molecules from the plant have been
pharmaceutically developed and
standardized to treat neurological
diseases like multiple sorosis and D
syndrome with commercial
success and researchers have long
investigated how the key constituents
from the plant may be us useful for
helping patients suffering from
ALS one of these studies was a
randomized control clinical trials of
nials trade named
satx 60 patients in the study 29 took
nials all of them looking to treat their
spasticity and here Not only was the
drug tolerable but patients showed
statistically significant Improvement
when compared to Placebo at two of their
endpoints the Modified Ashworth Scale
for spasticity and on the pain numeric
rating
scale but the trial wasn't powered
strong enough to show statistical
significance on all the other
secondaries including the ALS functional
rating scale
revised though some of these findings
were St were statistically significant
and some were not what's key here is
that satx was not optimized for the ALS
patient this is exactly what we have the
ability to do with CNR 4
or1 this is our botanically derived
cocktail mixture specifically designed
to harness the powers of nature
standardized in a way that will meet the
requirements of regulators like the FDA
and just like a nuclear bomb doesn't
rely on a singular
reaction but a series of simultaneous
reactions that amplify each other to
produce a massive synergistic effect
similarly 401 isn't just us throwing
together a bunch of ingredients in a pot
or an extract and hoping that one works
it's a calculated strategy where each
component plays a specific role
enhancing the overall drugs
effect the beauty of this approach lies
in its Synergy each ingredient in the
cocktail is selected not only for
individual effects but how it interacts
with each other this is crucial because
in ALS where multiple cell cellular and
multiple pathways are impaired what we
have the ability to to do is to provide
benefit by targeting multiple Pathways
simultaneously leading to a therapy that
will create a Cascade of beneficial
effects mitigating the disease from
several angles with with each and every
dose now I know all this sounds nice but
some may ask where's the proof what are
the other ingredients how do we know
this approach will work well now I'm
going to take you through a little bit
about what the last few months have
looked like for us and where we intend
to go from
here so several toxic agents such as BPA
bmaa pet pesticides and heavy metals are
known to trigger symptoms similar to Als
bmaa in particular is produced by a
symbiotic cob bacteria and has been
linked to ALS Parkinson's and
dementia this compound has been found in
the food supply chain in Guam and
detected in the brains of individuals as
well as American Alzheimer patients and
bmaa is suspective of causing neuron
damage by promoting excessive glutamate
ex
cytotoxicity which which has propelled
it which has propelled its study um as a
significant environmental factor in ALS
research across various preclinical
models now zebra fish are increasingly
recognized as a preferred model for
preclinical drug research particularly
in the study of neurodegenerative
diseases so we've partnered with crem
cabs a CR with specializing in zeber
fish studies to conduct an assay
involving neurotoxicity induced by
bmaa In This study first we had to
establish the toxicity parameters for
bmaa using zebrafish larve and then we
validated the study using Endeavor own a
therapeutic drug for ALS known to
restore motor function ensuring the
relevance and the reliability of our
findings in the context of ALS
research our objective in this overall
project is to develop a Botanical drug
this is going to be a product composed
of plant extract effect that meet our
targeted ingredient ratios but as we
finalized the chemistry manufacturing
controls for this investigational
product that will put into human
clinical trials we used botanically
derived isolates at optimal ratios to
ensure that in these initial tests we
were able to assess the overall Target
activity of our formulation just for
these
studies with these materials we then had
to make sure that they actually worked
in the medium so what we did determined
was that a uh an addition of 10 molar of
py cyclodextrin solution was safe and
non-toxic as a carrier for dissolving
the ALS formulation into the test
medium our toxicity assays conducted um
6 days post treatment confirmed that all
the products that we were that we were
using were safe up to final
concentration of two micromolar and they
all stayed in the
medium after we were able to do all this
it was time for our
experiment our findings were able to
show us that our CNR 401 and some of our
other products were able to demonstrate
a statistically significant effect in
this model indicating the promising
therapeutic effect that we have for
potentially treating
ALS treatment with our 401 in the
zebrafish lar larva led us led to
statistically significant Improvement in
the bmaa induced phenotype compared to
the positive control and Deon and these
experiments were conducted in 48 wall
plates with 6 to9 experiments performed
per
condition after we knew we had our hit
then we wanted to test the uh efficacy
of our formulation across various
doses so we did a couple more
experiments um these assets were
performed in 48 wall plates with seven
replicates involving more than 60 larvae
for each
formulation the results showed a dose
dependent response for both CNR 401a and
402a are mixed and pure formulations
respectively so next what we're doing is
we're progressing our formulations and
development research research
initiatives our current efforts are
Guided by the Botanical drug development
standards which need us to refine our
extraction Sops enhance our product
fingerprinting and and ask us to adhere
to rigorous QA QC procedures
in terms of our drug delivery we're
focusing on optimizing our
investigational product formats our
pharmakinetics studies are particularly
concentrated on enhancing the bloodb
brain barrier penetration using things
like solid lipid Nano par particles and
in addition we're also embarking on a
study of our investigational product in
a k9 degenerative myopathy study at the
University of Montreal this is a
naturally occurring animal model that
mimics ALS and has various similarities
because these dogs also carry the sod
one sod one mutant
Gene we're also working to better
understand the multi-target modes of
actions of our formulation and how what
that has on ALS progression one of the
things that we're looking at is
investigating the potential role of can
Flavin on mod modulating calcium levels
in the bra in the brain and addressing
impaired glutamate uptake by asites this
is a Hallmark of neurodegenerative
diseases like ALS so we're very
interested in what we're going to find
there we're also doing some biomarker
Discovery um including RNA sequencing
from our previous experiments to gain
insight into Gene regulation and
biomarker Analysis and we're looking
we're using
bioinformatics bioinformatic screens
from people on our team to enrich
patient data profiles and predict
outcomes by integrating existing data uh
respirator like answer ALS
and other information so that we can
identify biological Pathways for
intervention one of the targets that
we're really interested in is the bitter
taste receptors and we're going to talk
more on this at our later presentations
later in the
year we're also preparing and raising
money to go into a pivotal P Phase 2
trial right now we're putting our team
and our infrastructure together
targeting a first patient dose sometime
in the first nine months of 2025
so we have and we and we have a strong
understanding of the road map in front
of us with a potential accelerated
approval obtainable and orphan drug
designation Pro protecting our
commercial advantages as we continue to
grow and develop out this
asset our patents are filed globally and
give exclusivity to our methods our
compositions and our products over the
next 20 plus years and Beyond C CNR 401
we also have multiple other assets
Assets in development that follow
closely behind and Beyond this we have
numerous molecules in Discovery some of
that them that have been characterized
some of them that are yet too that as we
learn more and more about and learn more
and more about their therapeutic
potential we're extremely excited about
what we can bring to the
world so just as Oppenheimer and his
team orchestrated reactions to change
the course of history today we're aiming
to coordinate a therapy that can
fundamentally change the trajectory of
those living with ALS its treatment and
its
care this isn't just an addition to our
Arsenal against ALS it's a really
transformational solution that will
resonate across the spectrum of neurod
degenerative diseases bringing New Hope
where there were previously very little
so as we dive deeper into our work and
we roll up our sleeves and get ready for
the real work to begin I invite any of
you who that may be able to help in any
way possible to join our team our story
which is a tale of groundbreaking
science complex challenges and the
profound impact of natural Innovation
this is the moment we seek to emulate in
our journey towards a breakthrough ALS
treatment and a world without complex
degenerative terminal
illnesses thank you for our for
listening to our presentation a special
shout out to our conera research team
all of our service providers our
partners and the government of Canada
for providing in funds that we were able
to use to do this work thank
[Applause]
[Music]
you and I have a couple of minutes so if
we have any
questions I'm here any
questions or you can find me oh
question two Bonnie I just thank you
very interesting presentation oh thank
you so much very interesting um it's
probably proprietary Terry but any
chance to give us a hint as to what um
cannabinoids or non-cannabinoid
compounds you're focused
on as as Ethan spoke about yesterday we
have a variety of different ingredients
in our mixture that we know that do
various things that help with the ALS
pathophysiology if you're at Ethan's
presentation yesterday you got A Sneak
Peek or you can bother Ethan later to
find out about his Trade
Secrets hiim thank you that was a great
presentation I'm curious about the
results of the zebra fish model and the
I forget what drug it was that was the
standard you were comparing against
which obviously did not translate to
humans and I'm curious about you know
your thoughts on the translational
potential there and the results of your
compound versus that drug well actually
Endeavor own is a solution right now
that's used for ALS treat ALS patients
it's approved as an IV formulation but
it only minimally extends lifespan about
2 to 5 months right so we know it works
at restoring motor functions but what it
doesn't do is um over a series of time
is stop the disease progression and help
the patients what we know is that with
cannaboids our ingredients and our
mixtures will be safe for chronic use
and there's a variety of different
information on the various cannabinoids
tpin and flavonoids that we have in our
mixture that should allow this to be um
beneficial for the patients at
mitigating their symptoms but also
provide the neuroprotective patient the
neuroprotective potential sorry so that
as they use it each and every day
they're able to stay alive longer have a
better quality of life and um it just
changed their overall experience of what
it means living with ALS or other motor
neuron diseases thank you great answer
uh hey there uh just wanted to say uh my
grandfather passed away of ALS and I
just wanted to thank you for the
critical work you're doing to helping
sick people anybody in here if you can
help this guy you should learn
everything about what they're doing we
appreciate them thank
you thank
you
okay anyone else if not you can find me
on lunch I'm happy to chat thank you all
h
[Music]