thank you very much
by thanking the organizers for this
opportunity to talk to you today the
research that I'll talk about has been
jointly funded by a company in British
Columbia Agreement botanicals as well as
the Natural Sciences and Engineering
Research Council of Canada which is
enteric federal granting body as well as
SFU Simon Fraser University those of you
that need to contact me after the talk
or through email
punjah at SFU dot CA so what I'd like to
do is talk about some diseases of
cannabis diseases that have been
previously unreported and review some of
the moles that can get onto cannabis
product and assess some potential
disease control methods any licensed
producer any grower is going to
experience some form of disease or mold
and it's important that we understand
what they are and what we could do to
manage them this work was done in Canada
but all of the results I think are
applicable to any state or region that
grows cannabis so what am I going to
talk about I'll start with the root rot
and crown rot diseases those of you that
are familiar with these Latin names
Fusarium and Pythium and then I'll move
on and talk about botrytis which is a
major disease as well as a Penicillium
disease and then a few of the molds that
can get on to cannabis product and then
finally I'm going to end with a
discussion on powdery mildew which is a
major disease around the world we
conducted sampling in indoor and
greenhouse facilities very limited field
production of cannabis in Canada it's
mostly hemp and so my work is limited to
a greenhouse and indoors so in Canada
probably the most largely expanded
industry in cannabis is in greenhouse
we've got growers that previously grew
tomato peppers cucumbers that are
switching over to cannabis production
you can see the highly intensive
production system here in this slide
there is also indoor production mostly
hydroponic this is an old production
system few years back where individual
plants are in these buckets provided
with hydroponic solution now they use
rock wall blocks which are on raised
benches and also provided by hydroponic
nutrient solutions so when we first
started this work we started looking at
root system
see on your left is a disease or a root
rot that causes the Browning of the
roots and when we isolated from that on
your top right is this pretty pink
fungus which is fuse area and on the
bottom is Pythium species that we
isolated from these plants we conducted
pathogenicity studies and what that
means is that we made sure that the
organisms we isolated are able to cause
symptoms here on your left are is the
disease or the symptomology caused by
fees areum and on the right is the
inoculation with Pythium and you'll see
stunting and reduced root growth as a
result of these organisms but otherwise
other unless you had a comparison you
wouldn't actually know that these plants
were were diseased and that makes it
quite difficult for for diagnosis here
again is results from inoculation
experiments on your left are plants on
your extreme left is a plant that was
not inoculated with fizz areum on the
right is a plant with fizz erm you see
the stunting the yellowing and on your
right is the internal discoloration of
the pith that's due to infection by by
fees areum this is not a wilt fees areum
this is a root in a crown rot fees areum
hence we see the discoloration only in
the in the pith and not in the vascular
tissue in some cases you encounter fees
areum and Pythium together and when you
do that you can see that the the results
were lethal those plants collapse
whether they're in the greenhouse or
under field conditions the photograph on
the right was taken in Northern
California those plants completely
collapsed within two or three days under
extreme heat the roots are completely
gone so one of the concerns with fuzzy
arm of course is that the inoculum of
the spores can spread from infected
areas up onto the foliage or onto the
flowers and more importantly the
inoculum can move sideways onto other a
Jason plants particularly if you're
growing in a hydroponic system is very
easy for spores to move around in fact
we saw that when we looked at
propagation systems where these cuttings
that were being rooted were actually
damped off by infection by Fusarium
moved through the hydroponic nutrient
solution and on your right you see
colonies of fizz areum that came out
from the hydroponic solution so these
organisms are moving through the systems
in greenhouses or indoor production
facilities we've also seen cases where
propagated
rooted cuttings that are being sold on
the marketplace actually contained
Fusarium infection you wouldn't know
this from the dark green leaves but you
see the stunted growth in some cases
yellowing and in extreme cases the
plants actually are dead and we're
seeing a lot of movement of these types
of plant materials from one area to
another and that's going to cause some
major problems with fees areum in the
future the other thing we wanted to look
at was the growing substrate a lot of
the hydroponic growers use Coco fiber or
coconut husk derived substrates and we
wanted to see whether or not these
substrates contain organisms or
microorganisms that potentially had the
ability to spread potentially spread
either into the air or onto the flowers
and we were actually surprised this is
cocoa product that hasn't been
autoclaved and sterilized and there's a
lot of organisms in there particularly
organisms such as Aspergillus
aspergillus niger various types of
Penicillium species and other types of
organisms this came as a bit of a
surprise to us that hydroponically
manipulated substrates such as this can
actually have microbes in them here's
another slide those of you familiar with
moles you know this is aspergillus niger
this is a specialist Arius and again
this is material that comes from
overseas that probably hasn't been
sterilized and actually contains a fair
amount of these pretty awful organisms
that have the potential to spread
through the plant or onto the flowers so
airborne contamination can be a problem
a spores that are in the air may land on
the flowers they may land on the roots
and and after that colonize those
particular tissues and potentially
result in contamination of product so
what we did is we we devised a
system where we could sample air and
it's a very simple straightforward
system we take a petri dish with agar
put it out in the greenhouse or in the
growing environment leave it there for
60 minutes and bring it back and what
you see in this particular slide are
colonies of klaris Boreum colonies of
Penicillium there are in the air and we
can monitor and quantify the numbers of
these microbes in the air and what you
see here this is weeks of flower you see
the blue bars clara ciborium levels
start to go up as the plant grows we see
Penicillium levels start to go up and
what this is saying to us is that as you
accumulate plant materials and plant
matter these moles start to propagate an
increase in the environment this is a
fairly horrific horrific in the sense
when you look at this you realize it's
completely covered in mold this was a
plate that was exposed to the trim room
and the trim room is where mechanized
pruning or cutting of buds occurs and
what we're seeing is a release of spores
from the pine material getting up into
the air and then landing back down on
the petri dishes or potentially on
product and these are organisms such as
Aspergillus here as well as various
Penicillium and claryce Boreum species
and this is something that needs to be
looked at I think in the future we're
confined spaces that are being used to
trim product can actually accumulate
very high levels of mold so we did some
scanning electron micro microscopy and
what you see here are the stigmatic
hairs that are found on buds of cannabis
flowers and you notice the the spores
these are spores of Penicillium that are
actually stuck to the surface of the
stigmatic hairs which is one way for the
spores that get into the air to land
back on plants and start to colonize
those here's a close-up I think it's an
awesome photograph because it actually
shows you these Penicillium spores stuck
to the stigmatic here these are about 3
microns in diameter so what that means
is that this magnification that you're
seeing here is about a hundred thousand
times so they look large but they're
actually Thai
spores that get onto product and so what
we found is there actually is a
Penicillium but rot these are the
Penicillium spores here they are again
and we actually were able to identify
Penicillium species on petri dishes that
came from these various production sites
these penicillin species are diverse
some of these actually have been
reported by medicinal genomics two years
ago in a study that they conducted they
were the first to actually report
Penicillium species on cannabis and
we're seeing of a diversity of species
Penicillium citroen um here and various
other species on product and some of
these are mycotoxin producers boat
riders bird rod is another disease i'm
not going to say too much about this but
it certainly as seen here a devastating
disease that gets on certain strains and
can cause a high degree of devastation
I'm going to finish my talk just to
spend a few minutes and talk about
Prouty mildew that's a major major
disease on cannabis caused by this
fungus Golovin oh my sis chicory serum
and as most of you know those of you
that grow cannabis will know it causes a
white powdery appearance on the leaves
on the buds on flowers and it makes
product unsaleable we've looked at this
organism again in the scanning electron
micrograph and like I hate to use the
word pretty and amazing for mold but
this is really quite quite a stunning
photograph that shows you the mildew
spores actually being produced on the
surface of the leaf a cannabis leaf
which causes the white appearance that
we attribute to mildew and actually in
some cases this mildew has a real
preference for trichomes and what you
see here is the mycelium actually
coiling itself around a try come on a
cannabis bud and here it is again
because cannabis trichomes are sticky
they actually attract spores and so
we're actually seeing spores to talk to
cannabis flowers because of the resin
that is extruded that causes these
spores to stick to the surface
okay so what are we going to do about
party mildew our objective here was to
screen six biocontrol
reduced risk chemical products we ended
up looking at these products shown here
regalia max Rhapsody which is a
bacterial product mil stop potassium
bicarbonate Zero tall which is hydrogen
peroxide actinovate
and neem oil as six of these treatments
to see what effect they would have on
powdery mildew we've set up a very very
good system for reproducing powdery
mildew disease we used a strain called
Copenhagen cush which is highly highly
sensitive to mildew they were grown in
these humid chambers for for two weeks
and allowed to develop hardly mildew
infection and then we assessed disease
development and then we started the
applications of the products that i
mentioned to you they were sprayed on a
weekly basis for four weeks and then we
assessed disease here's what you see
with some of the more effective products
powdery mildew disease spreads rapidly
as you see here within four weeks or
five weeks it's reached as high as 40 to
50 percent disease various products had
different levels of control with
products here that are regular and
Rhapsody providing pretty pretty good
control of this particular disease
here's a representative illustration of
the effectiveness of these products
control act innovate Rhapsody zero tall
Mills top and regalia now none of these
obviously are completely effective
against disease but remember this is a
highly susceptible variety or strain and
so in combination with genetic
resistance I think some of these
products might be effective the other
thing that this slide illustrates is
that we're ready for genetic screening
of cannabis cultivars with strains we
have a method now that will allow us to
look at whether there are any forms of
resistance present in cannabis using
this sort of a system because it's
sensitive enough that we can see
differences that may be attributed to
genetic differences so just to summarize
these results the
the two products that are registered in
Canada mil stop in xerath all are
reasonably effective in controlling
powdery mildew regalia which is which is
registered in various states in the US
is not registered in Canada but it is a
very good product Nieman Rhapsody were
not the greatest they're not registered
at this point in Canada and actinovate
interesting enough which was not a great
product in his studies has now been 2d
registered in Canada for various for
various reasons so I think what I've
tried to do here is illustrate some of
the important diseases that are
affecting cannabis productions in Canada
and elsewhere I try to show you some of
the ways in which these diseases spread
the importance of mold in the
environment that could potentially land
on product whether it's in the
greenhouse in an indoor facility or in a
trim room and I've tried to show you
that some of the major molds are things
like Penicillium and cladosporium that
can cause issues later on in packaged
product and we've looked at some ways to
manage these various diseases I've
Illustrated some of the products that
we've assessed there are others that
we'll be interested in looking at to see
whether or not things like powdery
mildew and fizz areum and Pythium root
rot can actually be controlled so I
think the the need for research on this
topic is obviously critical we're happy
to collaborate with with people on
looking at various types of disease
control methods and I think particularly
for screening for genetic resistance
we're also looking at a molecular method
to see if we can identify some of these
pathogens this is just a straightforward
PCR and it shows you the various disease
organisms that are identified with this
test phase areum Pythium botrytis the
four species of Penicillium that I
talked about Alternaria which is a
disease that's just starting to come on
board we haven't seen very much of it
and this is plant DNA this one right
here this very unique banding pattern is
partly mildew we can see powdery mildew
very consistently using this PCR test
which uses the I TS region three minutes
so I think early detection of disease is
very very important because growers can
then manage the the possible outcomes
and I'll leave it at that Canada is now
one week into
legalized cannabis production and this
research again was funded by agreement
articles and answer and I thank Darren
and Cameron for the help in this and
this research thank you very much
[Applause]
time for questions yes sure thank you
great lecture and incredible images you
mentioned them one of the species of bud
rot can be mycotoxin producing any of
the powdery mildew no the good news
about party mildew is it's not a micro
toxin producing organism so the
Penicillium are probably the most
notorious Aspergillus as well as
Alternaria there's one report of Kardos
Boreum producing a micro toxin but the
big ones are the Penicillium and the
Aspergillus the ones that are in the air
that could potentially land on product
thank you
you