thank you for having me what a great
conference so far
it is my honor to present to you a
little bit of what i've learned over the
last six years in maine
practicing cannabinoid medicine on the
front lines
so uh just an overview of the next 20
minutes an introduction to my work
and then some of what i've discovered
about cannabinoid dosing nuances
including
the nonlinear dose response
sensitization and tolerance
bidirectional effects and then i want to
talk a little bit about acidic
cannabinoids
which i've been seeing some great
results with in my practice
and then i'll end with three pediatric
seizure cases
and kind of the theme of today so
integrate is the name of my clinic we
started in manchester maine now we have
three practices
two in maine one here in burlington
massachusetts i work with about 16 other
medical providers
and together we take care of at least
eighteen thousand patients actually i
think it's closer to twenty thousand
patients now
these are all real patients with real
medical conditions we're not in the
business
of providing certifications for uh
personal adult use even though i don't
think prohibition is a very good public
health
policy in addition to medical cannabis
we practice
good medicine integrative family
medicine osteopathy which is one of my
loves and specialties functional
medicine mind body medicine
and more you can see the age demographic
of our practice so it's mostly adult
patients
in maine we have uh distinct qualifying
conditions for which we can certify a
patient to use cannabis
and so here's the basic demographic
about 72 percent chronic pain
13 ptsd and there's certainly an overlap
of people that have comorbid ptsd with
chronic pain
and then the rest is pretty much a big
mix of many other conditions but as a
clinician it's a
incredible honor to be in a practice
where i see such a variety of pathology
and i get to apply all my skills
and what i can learn from the primary
research and from my clinical experience
to help different patients with
different conditions
so i'll back up for a second about two
or three years ago with some of the
documentaries
on cnn parents started coming to me
requesting that i treat their children
with cannabinoids for various neurologic
conditions
and at the time i was basically faced
with and a lot of the clinicians in the
room could probably appreciate this
a mom holding up a bottle of tincture
and saying how many drops of this should
i be giving
to my child which is uh puts a clinician
like myself in a very uncomfortable
position what's in that bottle how
potent is it
and so forth so we did our best to start
tested labs and i believe that we're the
only medical practice in the world
that does cannabinoid medicine and has
in-house analytics
of the medicine that patients are using
this allows us to
discover new things about what's working
and what's not working
and also to really fine-tune the dosing
and
understand what's what's happening there
so we're making new discoveries
all the time and some of our best
discoveries come from
uh people's mistakes in the words of
someone i admire a lot bob ross the tv
painter with the afro he said there's no
mistakes
there's just happy little accidents and
the worst thing that we can do is
learn a whole lot from them and
fortunately in cannabinoid medicine
that's the truth these substances are so
safe and non-toxic that even gross
errors are
typically safe and we we can learn a
whole lot from them
so it's really wonderful to be
experimenting clinically
with something with this type of safety
profile and just to show you
you know morphologically some of these
medicines can look exactly the same but
have
vastly different therapeutic effects so
here we have a flower that's mostly thc
dominant
here we have another one that's about
half and half thc in cbd
and here we have another one that's
almost all cbd and no thc
so for the people that in this room that
aren't actually handling the plants
please know you can't tell by looking at
it or smelling it what effect it's going
to have on someone we really need
the analytics to look at the medicine
and understand what it is
so also solving some of the biggest
problems we had practicing
cannabinoid medicine i came out with
healer.com which is a patient education
website
unlike other types of medicine with
cannabis i can't tell a patient
here take 10 milligrams three times a
day i might be able to say that as a
starting dose
but really cannabinoid medicine is
highly individualized and a lot of it
needs
dose titration and feedback with a
provider and most
clinicians don't have the time to do
that with their patients and don't have
the experience that i had
that allowed me to do it so on
healer.com we have programs to take
someone who's never
used cannabis before who doesn't even
know what it is and walk them through it
kind of hold their hand and introduce
them to it
we have programs to take existing users
who are maybe using it recreationally
and want to start using it
to promote health using it medically
switching from inhalation to tincture
non-psychoactive strategies and other
programs that can help patients
it's free so i invite you to check out
healer.com and share it with
your family friends and patients so
maine has a wonderful
medical cannabis program one of the best
in the country we have 13 indications
we'd like to see more but all the major
indications are on there
mds do's and mps are allowed to certify
we have eight dispensaries and over 2
caregivers home grow is allowed which i
like people can grow outdoors in the
summer and potentially produce
enough medicine to last them the whole
year donations are allowed so if a
patient or a caregiver has surplus
they can give it away freely without an
exchange of
value which is quite nice for the
altruistic
type of feeling that we get with
cannabis in the cannabis community out
of state
reciprocity so we have a lot of patients
from massachusetts coming to maine to
access our program
i'm getting mainstream referrals from
the medical community all the time we
have
four pediatric neurologists in the state
they are all sending me their toughest
cases
and we have a collaborative grassroots
activism environment and i just want to
thank
people like catherine lewis from medical
marijuana caregivers of maine
and glenn peterson both in the front row
these are fellow mainers we work
together
to create this good program and that
type of collaboration is essential
so dosing by the milligram i have found
in my practice that for the most part
the effective oral dosing range
goes from .05 milligrams per kilogram
per day
all the way up to 30 milligrams per
kilogram per day
so this would be like someone my body
size taking
three milligrams of cannabinoids a day
and doing well versus taking
you know 1700 or maybe even two thousand
i will say it doesn't make a lot of
sense to dose adults by body weight
these compounds do go to the nervous
system and
i think our nervous systems all have
pretty similar weights
but in in pediatrics we certainly need
dosing per kilogram
this is such a broad dosing range we
really don't see this with other
medications
but we're still in a very safe range as
some of you know researchers have tried
to kill animals
with high doses of thc and they simply
haven't been able
to do it including at you know 300 times
the dose that i'm seeing in my practice
at the high end let's see we've got a
little pointer here
so what i've also observed is this
biphasic or non-linear dose response
curve
where if someone starts at a low dose of
cannabinoids whether it's thc or cbd
and this isn't every case but a lot of
cases follow this trend
as they titrate up they'll get increased
efficacy up to a certain point
and beyond that point they'll start to
lose efficacy
everyone seems to have somewhat of an
optimal dose and i can't tell an
individual what their optimal dose
will be they'll have to find that out
for themselves so instead of
recommending a dosage i recommend a
methodology for how to find
your optimal dosage and that seems to
work well the vast majority of our
existing cannabis users come here
and what we do for them is actually
reduce their dose so that they can
increase efficacy not only that they're
saving money and reducing side effects
this is well known in the animal
research so this is a study
on a lot of locomotor activity in rats
giving thc and you can see from the
baseline a very low dose of thc
0.2 milligrams per kilogram actually
decreased their activity level
then as the dose increased activity
level went up then as the dose
increased again activity level went down
again so this is
kind of a triphasic dose response curve
what's interesting is that at these
higher doses
five milligrams per kilogram they
weren't actually seeing the same
efficacy at these ultra low doses
but they were seeing the emergence of a
side effect in this case
catalepsy which is remaining still in an
unusual position
so i see this with my patients we can
get efficacy at higher doses
but often at lower doses we get better
efficacy with less side effects and i
i believe that not many people in this
field are dosing as low
as i am this is also well established in
human data here's a trial
using nubiximals a one-to-one ratio of
cbd to thc
in patients with poorly controlled pain
already treated with opioids and here
you can see from baseline
the dose the group that was getting 20
milligrams did much better than the
group that was getting 52
or 83 milligrams less can be more with
cannabis it usually is
the entourage effect can also change the
dose response curve this was a study
from 2015 in rats looking at pain and
inflammation
and it showed that a full plant extract
of cbd
performed better than the individualized
cbd molecule
and with the full plant extract here on
the right we didn't see
this biphasic dose it just kept getting
better and better as the dose went
up so the whole plant entourage i think
can really change the dose response
curve
and if we have the whole plant entourage
again i believe that we can get better
results
at a lower dose so for the patients that
are on too high of a dose i developed a
six day protocol
that gets them to lower their dose it
includes two days of cannabis
abstinence three days of very careful
titration and on the
on the sixth day they go to the dose
that gets them the same benefit they had
uh previously and usually they've
reduced their dose by about 50 percent
doesn't work for everyone
but it it works for most people so
they're using less less side effects
saving money
uh feeling more functional there is
supporting evidence
to this concept of sensitization to
cannabinoids
and most of you probably have your own
supporting evidence i think most people
for the first time when they try using
thc based cannabis whether it's in high
school or college or whenever
they don't feel anything the first time
and it's the second or third time
that they feel it maybe there's a
sensitization process going on or maybe
they're just becoming
more aware of what those psychoactive
effects are like and how to describe
them
either way i think thank john mcpartlin
for these three references here
and this first one that just came out
this year so 48 hours of abstinence is
enough
to return cannabinoid receptor levels to
their baseline after they've been down
regulated
due to thc tolerance but there's also
evidence that thc can actually up
regulate the endocannabinoid system
at certain doses another
experience that i've had with thc
especially in cannabis naive patients
is this widening of the therapeutic
window over time so with any medicine
we have the effective dose and we have
the dose that's going to cause
intolerable side effects that's the
therapeutic window
with thc first of all cannabis naive
patients are much more likely to have
side effects
whereas regular users have much fewer
but over time thc can widen its
therapeutic window
people tend to build tolerance to the
effects of thc
at different rates and usually people
will build tolerance to the adverse
effects faster
than they build tolerance to the
beneficial effects so we can use this
understanding in our plan with patients
to help them get better efficacy
with less side effects there's also
bi-directional effects in cannabinoid
medicine and we see this
all over the place cannabis as martin
lee described it as a dialectical
substance or dialectical medicine so
first of all the same
medicine can have opposite responses in
different
individuals so you give it to someone
that's anxious it might make them less
anxious
but you give it to someone that's
relaxed it might make them more anxious
that's an old study
with thc from 71 but we see this all
over the place i give 9 out of 10 people
one strain
that gives them energy and the 10th
person it sedates them and it's all over
the place
in cannabinoid medicine it happens
within the same individual the same
medicine the same dose
give it to someone in a relaxing
environment and they'll get even more
relaxed give it to someone in a
stressful environment
and they'll get more anxious also the
different doses of the same medicine in
the same individual
can cause completely opposite effects
and with cannabis
overdose especially orally we tend to
see the symptoms that cannabis would
tend to treat
so if at a low dose it might reduce
anxiety reduce
pain reduce nausea at a high dose it'll
cause them to get anxious experience
pain and start vomiting
so one of the discoveries that i made a
couple years ago came from a mom
who came back with her seizure child and
said
this cbd is really working well to
reduce seizures
we had just started the lab up and i
said well let's find out what's in that
cbd and how much of the cbd they're
actually getting
so we ran the test and we found that
there was no cbd in the bottle there was
also no
thc in the bottle and there was quite a
small amount of
thca and this was a very surprising
finding to me so
probably 99 of the research on
cannabinoids as they act on animal
physiology
has been done on the neutral compounds
that have been decarboxylated this
uh oops sorry about that this carboxylic
acid group
decarboxylates uh when exposed to heat
and so any all the smoking all the
heating and so forth changes the
acidic cannabinoids to neutral there's a
little bit of evidence
about the therapeutic effects of thc and
it's actually summarized beautifully in
a paper
on a poster that's downstairs thank you
to the author of that poster
but for one there's really no
psychoactivity especially at these doses
which are relatively high doses tested
in
animals we also know that thca
suppresses tumor necrosis factor
alpha which is a an inflammatory
mediator that's part of the process of
many different conditions
it's uh both thca and cbd are cox
inhibitors so they have these
anti-inflammatory properties
and interestingly cbda is kind of a
cox-2 selective
inhibitor but we don't know
too much more of that so a couple
interesting studies from 2013 came out
looking at thca to reduce
nausea and vomiting behavior in rats
that were treated with lithium chloride
and what they found was that these tiny
doses .05
milligrams per kilogram of body weight
of thca
reduce the the gagging episodes
significantly
whereas 10 times that dose of thca
didn't improve efficacy
and the same dose of thc did nothing
actually it was 10 times this dose of
thc
that did something so the researchers
found wow one tenth of the dose of thc
thca can actually suppress this nausea
and vomiting
and the next study they did actually
switched over to microgram dosing so
this .05 this is 50 micrograms per
kilogram
they repeated the study using even lower
dosages of
cbda and found that one microgram per
kilogram
of cbda could reduce seizures this is
tiny tiny
dosing of the raw cannabinoids now thank
you to ethan russo for providing me this
uh
photocopy of the scan of the paper from
19 where where were we 79
showing that relatively high doses of
thca
had an anti-convulsion effect in mice
200 and
400 milligrams per kilogram so what
i'm seeing clinically i'm going to
present to you now
uh regarding ultra low doses of thca so
this was a five-year-old boy
who failed six anti-convulsants a
ketogenic diet
and a frontal lobectomy he had both
autism and seizures
they came to me from out of state they
had illegally tried
cbd thc and thca all without
efficacy in this dosing range two to
five milligrams
per kilogram per day and that's similar
to what you've heard some of the other
presenters
uh describe today so i thought you know
i've seen some responses to ultra low
doses of cannabinoids let's try that
here let's decrease thca
to i was shooting for .05 milligrams per
kilogram per day
but instead of taking the 0.3 milligrams
of thca three times a day
the parents made a happy little accident
and gave it just once a day
and so this is 15 micrograms
of a milligram micrograms per kilogram
per day
and the seizures totally resolved so
we're talking about a third of a
milligram once a day of thca
seizures resolved they doubled the dose
and the seizures recurred
they cut the dose down again and the
seizures resolved again
hard to believe but what i've found is
that that
previous dose response curve that i
described
is here and ultra high doses by the way
can be very effective
in different conditions but i believe
that there's a dose response
section a curve way down here in the
microgram dosing range
that's actually effective not for
everyone but for many patients
and most of us clinicians are probably
starting here
some of us clinicians are probably
starting here or here
and we're missing this whole low part of
the dose response curve
so there's also evidence that thc can
have effects at these microgram doses
this was mice
thc given two hours before myocardial
infarction
improved fractional shortening troponin
leakage infarct size
and inflammation in that area so
cannabinoids and tiny doses
can do things physiologically that are
quite powerful
here's another case the 13 year old girl
with dravet syndrome
failed about 20 drugs vagal nerve
stimulator ketogenic diet
she had tried cbd and had some initial
improvement in cognition but anything
above this very low dose would increase
her seizures
they found that thca at 80 milligrams
per day
was the best treatment and overall had
about 90 percent
seizure reduction and i want to thank dr
gaitanas
for connecting me with this patient who
made a profound influence
on my career and my life and he cared
for her for almost her whole life
thc also this these this family were
pioneers in using thc as a rescue to
abort
generalized seizures uh rubbing 10 to 20
milligrams of thc into the gums or using
it
rectally would abort the seizure within
less than a minute
sometimes just seconds really powerful
and of course there's all the
neuroprotective
aspects of thc on board for the seizure
recovery
now interestingly while she was using
thca
they switched strains and found that the
subsequent strain was not as effective
as the previous strain
so we said well get your hands on both
we want to test this
so they tested both and what we what we
found was that the strain that worked
had very high levels of linalool
linoleul is a terpene that's found in
lavender it's known to have sedating
properties and also in a couple studies
anti-convulsant properties and animals
so you can start to see how the
entourage makes sense
when working with these terpene
compounds and cannabinoids
uh this strain worked well the other
strain worked somewhat
but this this worked the best and just a
little tribute to cindy mae who died
a few weeks ago of sudden unexpected
death and epilepsy and we continue to
learn
from all that she taught us she was an
incredible patient and i'm
just so honored to be part of her path
so the last case that i'll present a
five-year-old with epilepsy having two
to thirty clusters of partial seizures
uh every day plus a ton of clonic
seizure each night
failed a few drugs and so we started thc
at this new low dose you know that was
about .05 milligrams per kilogram so
this is one milligram of thc
twice daily had an immediate effect four
days seizure free
right after starting that it's so
surprising that one milligram can have
this powerful effect
we went up to two milligrams twice a day
all the seizures resolved except for
that nighttime seizure
which was now averaging every other
night instead of every night
and uh currently this family's tapering
valproic acid they've went from
625 down to 125 milligrams daily
we increased thca a little bit to
control seizures
and he's doing well they're very happy
with on the lower dose
that his hair is growing back so that
this family is
very enthusiastic so some of my take
home messages
there is a extraordinarily wide and safe
effective dosing range for cannabinoids
and i encourage
clinicians and also the people that are
designing experimental trials to explore
the edges of this wide effective dosing
range because there's some really
interesting
results we have these multiphasic dose
response curves
we see bi-directional effects in
cannabinoid medicine it might be a pain
to control for those
in clinical trials but i think we have
to understand how this medicine works
very promising results with acidic
cannabinoids i encourage people to try
them
and of course the improved efficacy with
the synergy of the final constituents
thank you very much
you