i'd like compounds
interesting things
summarized by bacharin punos
to researchers at nih in washington they
have published that modulated
endocannabinoid activity may have
therapeutic potential in almost all
diseases affecting humans i doubt
whether we can say this about any other
uh system
and that's the reason that
many many groups
look at the activity of endocannabinoids
all of the plant cannabinoids from
various
aspects now we have worked on three
different
phases types of cannabinoid research one
of them is on the plant cannabinoid
second one is the endocannabinoid
anatomite and 2hg and more recently over
the last few years
in additional anandamite-like compounds
when we started work
on the plant cannabinoids
essentially only two compounds have been
isolated it cannot be
diol and uh
thc cannot be known had also been seen
but i'm not sure that cannabinol is a
natural product anyway
cannabidiol as you can see here and thc
are very closely related
they have essentially the same structure
except the thc has
three rings cannabidiol as only touring
and they're completely completely
different in their activity while thc as
we well know causes uh
the effects that everybody associates
with cannabis cannabidiol essentially is
a compound that
is being used today
for a long list of medical
reasons
surprisingly the plant actually doesn't
synthesize either thc or cbd
it synthesizes their precursors their
assets we the plant synthesizes
cannabidiolic acid it synthesizes
tetrahydrocannabinolic acids as a matter
of fact there are two acids
there are two thc acid you can see here
and this depends on the uh position of
the carboxyl group here is the carboxyl
group
here in a carboxyl group here
and these compounds
uh are not stable they slowly
convert into
cannabidiol from cannabidiolic acid othc
from thc acid
and
these compounds have not been
investigated very thoroughly because
they are not stable and scientists don't
like to work with unstable product
because we don't know whether
the effect seen or due to
the compound itself or to a degradation
product
in the body we were able recently to
stabilize
uh
cbd acid by making a metal ester and
this is
putting a metal group on the acid and
this and we have been able to
look at the activity of this uh
acid derivative
and together with the canadian group we
found that it reduces depression
in
two animal models it lowers spain with
another canadian group so this
particular compound which is present in
quite large amounts in
in
in cannabis in the plant
is of considerable interest and i assume
that it will be used
uh for one of these
the effects that we we see whether it's
depression or whether it's pain
most of the work that has been published
actually is of course not on the asked
but on cannabidiol itself i will
not go into details there are
hundreds of papers on cbd action
basically it works on information and
epilepsy and diabetes type one
on graph versus crohn's disease a few
works
on epilepsy we
did in collaboration with the group in
south america some
initially work on
mice and rats and we saw that it is
pretty
active in
models of epilepsy in
these animal models
and then we went into a
clinical study
we had 15 epileptic patients that were
not being helped by the existing drugs
at that time they received two to three
hundred milligrams per day of
cannabidiol for quite a long time four
and a half months
and
my colleagues in south america founded
patients
out of eight
remained completely free of seizures
three patients had partial improvement
and only one patient had no improvement
with the placebo patients of course we
saw
essentially no no change
this was published
as you can see the date here
about 40 years ago but nothing happened
for nearly 30 years we could have helped
a lot of epileptic patients over these
uh 30 years but about
10 or 12 years ago
additional groups
got interested and a major clinical
trial was done
by a british
company
the trial was done in the us and they
found that
it is indeed
very active
in
certain epilepsy states so and
now
cbd has been approved as a drug for
certain
epileptic conditions
i also mentioned graft versus hose
disease well this is uh
actually a disease caused by
by medicine there are certain diseases
where
bone marrow transplant is needed
and it is
very helpful in certain cancer diseases
but
it may cause
problems
the bone marrow transplant can attack
the body the body can attack
the bone marrow and the patient is sick
at times very sick
a colleague of mine
dr yeshua at one of the hospitals she
administered cbd
to
as you can see here 46 patients that had
a bone marrow transplant and he followed
them for several months and he saw
very very substantial
improvement
and they had essentially
no
graft versus hose disease so i suppose
that
cannabidiol will become a drug not only
for
cbd and for epilepsy but also for
uh graft versus hose disease as a matter
of fact probably of uh quite a few other
diseases as well
what about thc again i will not i
will not go into detail but basically
what dhc does it lowers pain
it is used and approved actually uh for
nausea and vomiting
it helps with sleep and many of
those patients that take
thc
actually take it in order to improve
sleep or to make sleep possible
it at low doses it is an anti-anxiety
compound but
as we all know at high doses we can see
completely different effects and it also
increases appetite
so for nearly
20 years since we
reported the structures of these
compounds structures which were not
known previously
for
20 or 25 years there was a lot of
pharmacological work on these two
compounds and we learned from them a lot
about
the effects of cannabinoids and
hundreds
of papers were published on them one
thing that we did not know
for many years was the mechanism of
action of thc
how does thc act
uh a group in the u.s
in the 80s found
that
there is a specific cannabinoid receptor
in the brain and this specific
cannabinoid receptor in the brain is
found in
a
brain
areas that are really typical for the
effect that we see this is found in the
basal ganglia
that has
a lot to do with movement control
it has
it has been found in the cerebellum in
the hippocampus in the cerebral cortex
and as a matter of fact the res this
particular receptor
cb1 is one of the major receptors that
we see
uh in the brain in our body not only in
the brain
um
well we assume that
if
there is a receptor
it is not there because a plant produces
thc
uh just we assume that
our body produces compounds
which uh activate
this receptor
by
for some peculiar reason a plant
compound binds to the same receptor
so we worked
for quite a few years actually
and we found
in
uh more than
20 years ago 25 years ago we found a new
compound which we call the nanobite that
has a structure which is completely
different from that of dhc yet
this compound binds
to the receptor today known as the cb1
receptor to the same extent
as tetrahydrocannabinol
a few years later we found the second
compound which is closely related to
anandamide and it also binds to the
receptor these two compounds have been
investigated
thoroughly by many many groups and these
two compounds as i mentioned previously
are involved in a large number of
biological systems
they are part of today we know of the
endocannabinoid
system
which is
which consists of two receptors a second
receptor was found a few years later
than the previous one there are two
receptors that the two major compounds
anandamite and 2ag that i showed you the
structures previously there are a few
other compounds found in
lower amounts which have not been
investigated thoroughly but it seems
that these two compounds which we
discovered in the 1990s anandamite and
2ag they are the main
compounds involved in the
endocannabinoid system of course the
enzymes that synthesize
endocannabinoids and the enzymes because
the hydrolysis of the endocannabinoids
so these
the compounds and the enzyme
today are known as the endocannabinoid
system because
thc and cannabidar are closely involved
now what are the
effects
that we
see
that are due to the cannabinoid system
we know today and there are lots of
publications and i possibly can have a
few more slides
uh i'm just giving a few of uh the
effect that we know this
this system is involved in anxiety and
appetite and all these uh
that you can see
this slide
uh mood movement neuro protection pain
stress etc etc
i'll just give a few examples neural
protection
in collaboration with a
colleague of mine
professor shahami
we
try to see what happens in the brain
after
damage not a major damage by but a small
amount smaller damage
and
we saw that uh
after the
such a damage the mouse
the brain of the mouse
produces
two ag
in very large amount you can see here
the red bull
which
you can compare with the control
huge amounts of 2ag
are synthesized by the brain
does the brain produce 2ag because
it has been damaged and
doesn't know what it does or is
the production of 2ag
actually a response a protective
response perhaps about the brain
so we synthesized large amounts of uag
and
gave it to mice
that had undergone brain damage and
compared them to myself and not
undergoing that damage and we saw that
2ag when administered to
the mount to the mice
lowers the damage seen
here you can look at the brains
of mice that have received luigi
compared to control animals and we can
see that
the
damage
in the controls is
uh 50
higher than those that can
that received to a g
so chances are that at some point i hope
some company will develop 2ag as a
compound against brain damage
i don't believe that we have any
drugs
in this area at the moment
i mentioned that there are two receptors
one of them the cb1
when
uh thc or nandamite bind to
the cb1 receptor they
uh
lead to those effects that we are
we know the
associated with
with cannabis
cb2 by contrast doesn't do all these
things the cb2 receptor seems to be a
protective one a compound
receptor that when stimulated actually
is
leads to protection and the protection
being can be in various areas
there are papers on a protection of
brain pro of
heart problems
atherosclerosis stroke liver fibrosis
etc etc
and i'm under the impression that
several of the major companies
are working on specific cb2 receptor
compounds
as
for specific
diseases and it is we and many others
have published compounds which act
on the cb2 receptor alone and here are
two examples from my lab
and one of them
is the hua2 hebrew university hu308
which you can see
binds
very well to the cb2 receptor but does
not bind
to the cb1 receptor or the second
compound which is a different one which
is hu910
binds to the cb2 receptor extremely well
and rather poorly to the cb1 receptor
i mentioned brain injury
and
in brain injury we see quite a lot of
different types of damage
one type is
has to do with glutamate cytokines
reactive oxygen intermediates and this
can
lead to cell death
another type of damage is vessel
constriction
and we
tested 2ag to see whether it has to do
with vasoconstriction and i mentioned
2ag because we saw
some one of the previous slides that 2ag
is helpful in brain damage and yes
indeed
it helps with vasoconstriction uh
it lowers the vasoconstriction
in the brain
however and we were surprised really
however
the total extract
of the brain was much better than 2eg
alone
so we assumed maybe
we have
another compound much more active
compound than 2ag which which works on
the
vasoconstriction by the dilation
and
a student of mine in it is phd on this
topic
looked for compounds or a compound that
is better than 2hg
in
vasodilation
and after quite a few years
of work
we were able to identify a compound
compound the structure that we isolated
and elucidated the structure it is uh
our hidonia serine it is very close to
anatomite
they both compounds
are derivatives of arachidonic acid this
here is the arachidonic acid
both are
bind to
in this case ethanol amine and in this
case exactly the same but
with a carboxyl group
here essentially the same compound is an
endomite but
arasa hidonovial serine
does not bind to the receptors
and is much more potent than endomite
in the vasoconstriction
uh and you can see that the three
compounds
the anatomized the two ag and rs are
achieved in serine ras very closely
related but
they have
uh different activities
i mentioned head trauma so we looked at
a few
additional compounds present in
in the brain that may act on brain
trauma and we have and we found that rs
as i mentioned the rs previously
is
pretty good in lowering brain trauma it
is as active as 2ag
surprisingly two very closely related
compounds also present in the brain
are essentially
inactive
this particular compound rise
the wheel
the serine the dimension
possesses vasoactive and neuroprotective
properties resembling those of the
cannabinoids but as i mentioned again
it does not bind to the cannabinoid
receptors i'm not sure how these things
work together
as i believe the neural protection with
the cannabinoids with the nandomite has
to do with the cb1 and cb2 but ras does
not so here we may have two different
mechanisms leading to the same type of
effects
let me go to another
um
field
which cannabinoids are involved
[Music]
it has been published
and
there are several papers on this that in
greece greek peasants
seem to have less osteoporosis
than
presence in other places
in in the north in norway in
germany in sweden
and we wanted to know why this happens
and we
found
that
the bone has contains a compound
it is also present in the brain all in
serine which promotes osteoclast
apoptosis and increases bone formation
let me explain
the bones we have
do not stay the way they are for
throughout our life
they are broken down all the time by a
south coast osteoclast and there are at
the same time
being rebuilt
by osteoblasts
[Music]
certain diseases osteoporosis for
example the osteoclasts
work
overtime if you wish and
the osteoblast cannot
promote enough
bone formation
if only serine was found to
lower the effect of osteoplast it causes
apoptosis and in this way
there is less breaking down of the bone
and more a bone formation
and
you can see here again this is
anandamide and here is the only in
serine
which acts on bones and which causes
lowering of the
effects of the osteoclast
and it seems to be pretty good in
osteoporosis
so another colleague of mine
the late professor bob
looked at
the activity of
oleosyrin
he caused
osteoporosis and osteoporosis like
disease
by
causing ovaryectomy in female mice
and indeed if one causes ovary ectomy uh
and looks at the mice after about 40
days we see
that the bones are
the
bone content goes down
but if we start giving
only serine at this point
we can see now
that the bones not
do not continue breaking down does the
matter of fact
recover
now most of the drugs that we have of
osteoporosis nowadays
usually just stop the disease or they
stop to a certain extent the disease
very few of the drugs if any at all
cause
the formation of the bone again
there are quite a few diseases known
that have that are closely related to
osteoporosis there is a disease
called prada willis syndrome
which causes bone abnormalities
they are
closely related to osteoporosis of
course the plant and wheelie symptoms
has a lot of other effects but i'm
speaking of the bones alone
and um
it it was found
that uh
in
prader-willi syndrome we have the body
produces
lower amounts of olive theory
so
when
my colleague
jose tom
who is a specialist in this area started
administering only syrian two
animals that have the plan of willie
syndrome
they most definitely
caused
enhancement upon formation and
improvement of the
bone disease
now all these compounds i mentioned all
these anandamite like compounds i
mentioned
are
not very stable
they're all of them are amis that can be
attacked by amidases and therefore i
doubt whether they can be used as drugs
on their own so we
prepared
a few derivatives that wouldn't go into
the chemistry one of them is the a2671
in which the mite bond is kind of
protected
and the enzyme
does not attack it as easily as in
the compounds i
mentioned only serine for example and
indeed 678
exhibits high efficacy inversing
reversing the osteoporosis and it is
active in the prada willie syndrome
let me move to another field
one of the major problems we have
in medicine today is that many of the
microbes we have
uh have
antibiotic resistance
and if
we don't
we we cannot overcome this major problem
we
should probably be back
as if we were in the 1930s with microbes
that we cannot
attack by antibiotics
we try to see
whether our body
has a way
to work against
this
microbial resistance
and after quite a lot of work which was
done
in the lab professor turnbull in
collaboration
we found that
methicillin an antibiotic
which
against which certain staphylococci
streptococci
they have become resistant
we can
enhance the activity of the
antibiotic
if we give the antibiotic together with
anandamide or aras the same compound
then mentioned previously our
arachidonial serine
and
we found that
rs
really can overcome
the microbial resistance of these
particular
microbes
we are looking at many additional
microbes at the moment we're looking at
additional compounds but this may be a
very promising field
or promising
way of overcoming microbial resistance
and here again is
an undermined 2eg and rs which i
mentioned uh previously
what is the mechanism how does uh rs do
that
well
when microbes
are attacked by
an antibiotic one of the
ways they can
resist is by
producing a biofilm millions of
microbes get together they form a
biofilm which is not
attacked by
by the antibiotics the ris
prevents the biofilm formation
by altering the surface of the cell
without actually killing them by the
bacteria
and let me end
with a completely different field
the field of nicotine addiction
uh quite a few people that smoke
cigarettes or other types of tobacco
become addicted
to
nicotine
and this addiction
causes them to smoke although they know
that
smoking is not good for them
and
we wanted to see whether our body has a
way of
preventing lowering this
type of
this addiction
we found a paper in the literature
that a person who was involved in a
traffic accident and was addicted to
nicotine after the traffic accident
which he had a
brain trauma he was not addicted anymore
so we thought maybe
just maybe the brain is producing a
compound that blocks the addiction
and so we
looked
forward
and we found a compound which again
is very closely related to an endomite
it is a fatty acid it is a fatty
fantastic bound
to
uh
uh this part here to this forming amide
and
a colleague of uh of ours in the
uk in canada went ahead looking whether
this compound indeed you know those
models of
addiction is active as a matter of fact
and i want to stress this again i
mentioned several times that i work with
colleagues all my work is done in
collaboration with
friends and colleagues in this case in
the field of addiction we are a group of
four
labs in addition to my own lab a lab in
the u.s a lab in canada and lab in italy
and we work together
and
the lab in
italy actually found a compound
from from a brain and the group in
canada worked on the addiction process
dr parker a canadian
looked at the conditional place
preference in an animal model of
addiction a conditional phrase
preference
is a relatively simple
way of measuring addiction
mice or rats are given
the option to
uh go to
food with or or go to food with
nicotine at the beginning they go 50 to
one part of two to the nicotine
uh containing food
and fifty percent
the food it did not does not contain
nicotine well after uh
some
day so
probably some weeks
they are addicted to the nicotine and
almost all of them go to
the nicotine
with food and that's called conditional
place preference
and
linda parker in canada found that if we
give the compound we discovered in the
brain
the mice do not get addicted and
they
they found that
the condition placed preference works
absolutely
in this case
we thought that it might work also with
opiates well we were kind of
disappointed to see that uh only that
olympic glycine does not work with
opiates
but
again surprisingly it was both the
nicotine and opiate withdrawal responses
we know that
animals
of course human
humans that are addicted they can
undergo withdrawal responses which
sometimes are very very uh
unpleasant
and we found that
only glycine eliminates both nicotine
and opiate withdrawal responses which is
kind of strange because only glycine
does not work on
opiate addiction
but it turned out that
withdrawal and the addiction there are
two different
types of
response and today we know that olive
glycine works on nicotine addiction does
not work in opioid addiction but it
works on nicotine and opiate we do all
symptoms
and here is
what linda parker wrote morphine
withdrawal reactions were accompanied by
suppressed endogenous levels of
polyglycine
in
different parts of the brain
well only glycine as uh is again an
amide and as i mentioned before
mites can be easily attacked by
amidazes
so we decided to
again
try to
suppress this
enzyme reaction by
having a metal group not far from the mi
and so we
they
synthesize the compound this is polyel
glycine and this is an oreo glycine with
a metal group so it becomes alanine
only only ill alanine and this compound
turned out to be more active
for a longer period and then early
inflation itself
so
we found that only
alanine is not only
most stable but it's also more potent
anti-withdrawal molecule than only
glycine and i
am under the impression that
this compound may or should become a
drug
well as i mentioned before on the basis
of what i've been telling you we assume
that the exogenous administration olive
of oil glycine or all in alanine may be
beneficial for the prevention of
nicotine addiction and nicotine and
opiate withdrawal
well let me summarize
what i've been um
talking about the can of
endocannabinoids are involved in a large
number of physiological processes
and thc
which is a plant cannabinoid just mimics
their actions
cbd derivatives may lead to wide
spectrum of novel drugs
endocannabinoid-like compounds may lead
to better understanding of biological
processes as well as novel drugs and cb2
specific avenues may lead to a wide
spectrum of normal drug maybe part of a
general protective system and i want to
thank to thank my collaboration
collaborators in israel these are
fellows in my lab
uh there are many other
labs that are professors in jerusalem
that i collaborate i mentioned my work
with professor obama professor shohami
and
some in other
academic
institutes in israel and i work with a
lot of
collaborators abroad
from the from
the uk aberdeen
roger petrie you can see the names of
many of these and i thank them and i
thank you
[Applause]
you