um so I'm going to be talking about a
bit of a uh tragedy and a controversy
today and I need to First figure out how
to work this remote there we go um so we
went down this Rabbit Hole uh it's very
interesting Rabbit Hole it may be
playing a role in a fatality we had in
the state of Massachusetts um so
whenever something as complicated and
tragic as that happens I think it's very
important for us to just get all of our
conflicts on the table uh many people in
this audience know that medicinal
genomics and canmet are are same
organization um don't know why that's
jumping ahead on me let see if I can go
back one
um mainly for the folks on camera here
if this is recorded that's not always
known that the canmed team is part of
the medical jics team and they do a
wonderful job running our marketing and
making this event happen every year but
this event is managed uh on a on a break
even basis and that we try to even every
year we sometimes fail and when we fail
the medal genomics marketing uh budget
picks up the rest but we have a lot of
sponsors as a result of this um and
we've done this seven years now so we've
been sponsored by many many parties in
the industry but I want to assure you
that this presentation none of these
sponsors actually played a role in what
I'm going to present but I am going to
be presenting you some uh some
quantitative PCR data and we do make
quantitative PCR kits that um we're
using to try to shed a little bit more
light on this question
okay so so what are endotoxins and why
do we care um well we think this is
still a very you know hypo hypothetical
level here we think these may have
played a role in this person's asthmatic
attack um so we put out a pre-print
describing this I'll give you a bit of a
background on what endotoxins are but
this is an area that we effectively have
not looked at and I've been looking at
cannabis safety testing since 2011 no
one's really brought this up we were
looking at mot toxins which makes sense
we're not looking at all the mot toxins
that we probably should be looking at I
think zumir Puna and others have pointed
out there's a lot of fusarium and
penicilium on the species which make mot
toxins and uh those aren't being looked
at um but endotoxin is something that
has gone overlooked largely and it's
quite ubiquitous it is a it's only found
on gram negative bacteria and uh this is
really a molecule a lipopolysaccharide
that embeds inside of a cell membrane
and has an inner cord an outer cord and
an O antigen and many of you may be
familiar with serotyping particular
bacteria a lot of that stereotyping is
based on antibodies that that bind to
the difference in the length of these o
antigens okay however these are highly
inflammatory molecules you cannot have
these in any injectable product in fact
they can give you anaphylaxis and have
you drop like on the spot after a
vaccine for example if they're in a uh a
vaccine at too high of a level so
injectable products are highly
scrutinized to be below one endot
endotoxin unit per uh you know
particular dose or weight um there is
also a standard we'll touch on a little
bit later for air born endotoxin how
much of that is tolerable and a lot of
that is based in the fact that these
molecules are known um to induce asthma
so there have been some studies of um
how much gram negative bacteria is
actually on cannabis uh there's a great
study from bright green here and he's
coming up with the estimate around 40%
of the bacteria on cannabis are gram
negative and potentially endotoxin
producing uh so this is the first that
we saw this is has shocked us a little
bit so we asked our biomatics team can
you go and dig into our database and see
if this holds up uh so at medicinal
genomics we most of our clients now who
do sequence genomes have been switching
from doing exome capture sequencing to
just doing whole genome sequencing
because it's cheaper and when you do
whole genome sequencing you get the
whole microbiome with it so it's a two
for one uh and we've now done this in
close to a thousand samples and we have
microbiomes from flower from root from
Leaf from stem and a whole bunch that
are unknown because some people just
send us in DNA and we don't always know
the source
um but with this data we can dig into
the data and sort of ask a lot of these
regulatory questions like what is the
prevalence of certain microbes on
cannabis um and when you do some
sequencing like this here's here's an
example of some DNA from Roots that's
zir pja sent in and in this case we got
about 11% of the reads are microbiome
reads and 89% are cannabis uh usually
with roots around 10 to 20% of the reads
come back as a microbiome when you get
to the stems it's more like 10% when you
get to the flowers it's more like 5%
when you get to leaves it's more like 1%
there's very little microbiome on on the
leaves maybe powdery Milo samples would
be a little bit different um we haven't
sequenced many of those but um
nevertheless you can get a good profile
of what is uh what what is on these
plants um by just doing whole genome
sequencing and looking what comes
through now when you do this and you go
through this these 959 whole genomes you
can see that the predominant species in
on cannabis across all jurisdictions is
camonis uh which is in fact gram
negative uh billus is next in line which
is gram positive now Gram Gram positives
are very interesting particularly pillus
because many people use those as
biocontrol agents that can push
asparagus out of the plant and can uh
even in some cases um push the gram um
the gram negatives out of the plant so
um for those who are making these types
of biocontrol Agents I'm hoping this
presentation will encourage you to get
rid of the gram negatives and use the
gram positives because um this would
lower potentially the endotoxin numbers
that are out there but you can see by
the numbers on the right hand side here
that yes there are a large number of
these in this case perhaps 60% of the of
the samples have camonis in them uh so
there are gram negative bacteria uh
quite frequently found even in the
sequencing data that uh that we find
here um now the reasons why these in
fact May differ a little bit uh is
because we're doing whole genome
sequencing and other studies may have
looked at what can culture out of these
things and so we will get different
results we will see sequence everything
but not everything will cultured at the
same rate so we don't expect them to be
exactly the same okay so here's the um
the fatality that occurred um there was
a 27-year-old employee Laura McMurray
who was in a trimming facility in
Massachusetts she had an asmatic attack
on the job and and and sadly suffered
fatal consequences um she was a cannabis
user so everyone was confused by this
like she clearly has been around the
plant before was not suffering uh so
what changed what made this fatal event
occur now the a lot of pitchforks came
out in the industry about the employer
and not having masks and all this stuff
but uh when I've kind of tried to
neutrally look at this I encourage
everyone to put the pitchforks down we
need to solve this uh and and to get
objective about this and sober about
this I think we should put all the
finger pointing away uh the the employer
instantly put a new HVAC uh before any
regulation came in place or any
regulator showed up and uh if if you dig
into PPE OSHA and Nash standards that
was the right call uh when you do not
know what the hazard is you can't mask
your way out of this uh and a lot of
people were accusing employer of not
having enough masks but the masks
frankly don't work for for for a hazard
that you don't know what it is um so the
CDC did play pay visit um they came in
and tested for all types of Airborne
hazards but we took note that they
looked at endotoxins um and that's not
something the Cannabis industry usually
looks for so that was very intriguing to
us and OA got involved as well um so why
is h factor right play here well if you
Megan Manel has a great book on uh on
all the mask Madness that happened
during the pandemic and how these masks
really weren't fit for purpose she's a
nios and an OSHA expert that does PPE
but I think the real takeaway from this
is they have a they have a logic tree
there of a hierarchy of controls and
when you're not certain what the actual
environmental hazard is you cannot PP
your way out of it you start with
elimination the top of this tree you try
to get rid of or clean the air you don't
try to put porous masks on people's face
that aren't sealed because you don't
know what's going to get through those
masks so um HVAC is the right way to go
HVAC was not easy to do at this time
this occurred during the pandemic and no
one could get agac during the pandemic
because it was backlogged for um for
many
hospitals okay so there is now an mmwr
at the CDC on this fatal occupational
hazard in cannabis grows um CDC has
helicoptered in and and written up this
report um now an important aspect of
this report is that they now when they
went into this grow after the HVAC was
put in and measured it there the
endotoxin levels were safe they were
below the decost limits but that was
probably because they put in new HVAC
they did not get to sample this during
the event so we don't know what was
happening while the patient uh was
suffering but they did note that when
they have looked at this in other grows
40% of the employees are exposed to
endotoxin levels that exceed these D
cost limits all right so this is a a
hazard in a trimming environment that I
don't think anyone in the industry was
really paying attention to we're were
paying attention to patients and not
really thinking about okay what about
people in trimming environments that are
getting large amounts of this uh of this
dust um why we care in this case is
there's lots of literature from the
tobacco industry showing these endotoxin
exposures are in a risk for asthmatics
uh she had asthma so this is something
that uh could have triggered her asmatic
uh reaction to this um and it seems to
make a lot more sense than perhaps total
yeast and mold or other things because
we know in Massachusetts those grows
were regulated to at least produce
cannabis that was below particular yeast
and mold threshold so uh it would make a
little bit more sense to look at the
things that we're not testing for when
we're trying to assess um what's going
on here um the decost limits come out of
um come out of the Netherlands they're
90 endotoxin units per cubic meter of
air a cubic meter of air is a big space
you have to think of that as being about
a million MLS or maybe a million grams
um and I'm going to show you some data
of endotoxin levels on cannabis that are
thousands of times higher than this
which is a little bit shocking at the
moment um these can also be a concern
for people who do are not asthmatics
which is paper on the left sadly I think
might be getting cut off a little bit on
my picture here um is uh we'll show you
what types of clinical implications
these endotoxins can have from an
inhalation
standpoint now this is not the first
time this has been seen um James couch
has been looking at these types of
Occupational exposures in other cannabis
cultivation and processing facilities
and it has endotoxins have been brought
up in both of these papers um there's a
nios review there and another um review
of a hemp processing facility in
Minnesota where they we detecting very
high levels of of endotoxins so um this
is beginning to build a little momentum
so we decided uh we would go purchase a
$6,000 fluorometer from Thermo and uh
and and run their endotoxin test on some
cannabis samples um this is using a l
assay this is a an assay that uses an
enzyme that's harvested out of horseshoe
crab blood and it clots whenever there's
endotoxin and it measures that clotting
reaction with fluoresence um now there's
a standard curve that you have to run
with this and you will notice if you
take a gram of sample of cannabis put it
in 10 MLS of water and then put just
five microliters of that into this
machine you will be off curve high on
standard if you put a half a micr in
you'll be off curve high in the standard
you have to get all the way down to like
50 Nan to 5 Nan to actually be in range
on this machine which is telling us that
this cannabis samples are in the
thousands to hundreds of thousands of
endotoxin units per gram um which is
remarkably High uh so high that I really
want to encourage the industry to
actually double check this technology
maybe with mass spec or something else
because if you go through the endotoxin
literature uh these lassay are very
temperamental based on the Matrix that
they're are implied in and you do have
to run this in Matrix so you have to
dilute your sample and do lots of
standard um curves and dilutions to make
sure that the Matrix isn't inhibiting
your your actual endotoxin reaction so
we just started very simply we went and
grabbed a hemp sample a pre-roll in in
cal um in in Massachusetts they are not
required to do microbial testing as you
can see and you go to the dispensary
pre-rolls and you can see that they are
required to do microbial testing when
you put this on three imp plates you get
night and day differences however these
samples had equivalent endotoxin un
uh we also ran um you know Tac uh qpcr
and and um you can see very similar
effects so for those not familiar with
3m lots of blue dots means lots of live
colonies uh if you look at the
dispensary sample those colonies have
all been Zapped uh probably probably
radiated but we don't know in
Massachusetts there is no requirement to
label any type of
remediation um so we said all right
that's interesting uh we have to expand
this let's do 12 more samples we went
and grabbed um a bunch of non-
dispensary samples labeled as ND they
are on the right in this bar chart and
then a bunch of dispensary samples which
are on the left the blue bars that
you're looking at there are the
endotoxin units detected off the
platform uh you can see that they're
ring you know they're ranging between
maybe 5,000 and 100,000 and as you get
more to The non-d Dispensary samples the
endotoxin levels get a little higher
they push up to over 100,000 it's it's a
log scale we're dealing with there now
the orange and gray lines are something
that we're doing to try to get a
surrogate detection system for this with
qpcr we run quantitative PCR with 16s um
uh PCR primers those are total aerobic
count PCR primers they measure all
bacteria we measure it two different
ways we measure it with a in the
presence of a nuclease in the presence
without a nucleas and this gives us a
live dead estimate so the nucleas runs
around and choose up DNA that's outside
of a cell and any DNA that's inside of a
cell is protected from the nucleus so we
can get an estimate of total DNA that's
present in the sample and then DNA that
is protected by a cell membrane with
this type of Liv dead and you can see in
some cases there are in fact the live
dead offset is quite significant and in
the case of the two samples on the left
we have lots of uh 16s qpcr signal and
then once we apply a nuclease all that
stuff disappears and we get samples that
look a lot more like the plating results
but there are samples where the nucleus
doesn't get rid of all of this um in
fact Jenny Glaros gave a great
presentation last year on this topic uh
with uh decontamination tools uh using
radiation and uh the radiation does seem
drop the signal uh or the cfu counts
almost to the floor whereas qpcr
sometimes is still there in some samples
you can still detect it with qpcr even
though it's clearly been killed from a
viability standpoint uh nevertheless
there is some correlation here between
the live dead PCR signal and the
endotoxin levels but it's not great it's
like0 43 so we can't really use this as
a replacement for measuring endotoxins
yet so we we aim to try to improve that
we picked up a paper from biso that made
it was a qpcr assay trying to discern
gram positive from gramam negative uh D
if if you recall the PCR system we were
using before looked at all bacteria and
maybe that's confusing the signal we
should just look at bacteria that's gram
negative and correlate that with the
endotoxin number so we modified this
thing to work with our particular dieses
and moved on and started measuring how
specific it was so if you put in a gram
negative sample into this assay uh
you'll see the gram the gram positive
signals come out in Blue on fam and the
gram negatives come out in sci five and
we get about a 15 CT offet set between
that on something that's known gam
negative if you put in billus which is
gr positive you get the opposite
reaction that occurs you get more blue
signal than purple signal and it's about
a 15 CT offset that's about a 32,000
fold discrimination between gram
positive and gram negative with qpcr
that's all we need that should be good
enough to to sort this out so we started
running these Solutions and endotoxins
to get a better estimation of whether
qpcr can guide this process or not um
you can see many of these l assays in
there are bright green to your eye you
can almost tell which ones are going to
be off chart High just by looking at
them and the standard curve is way out
there and back um and again this is the
uh you know 5 microliters all the way
down to 5 nanoliters of um serial
dilution going into these things and
there's still you can still see very
Vivid color changes that are you know
almost breaking the standard curve there
and back um so here's just a couple
examples where we've done this on uh
sample here's sample 8 and Sample five
you can see there's clearly a lot more
Gram Gram negative DNA in purple there
there on Sample 8 coming out at a CT
around 15 and then you can see that the
gram um the gram positive signal is just
behind it and Sample five is shifted
almost entirely over so that there's
much lower amounts of uh of gram
negative versus gram positive and when
we look at the endotoxin levels for
these over on the right um there's a
hundredfold difference in endotoxins
between sample 5 and Sample 8 and that's
pretty close to what we're seeing in
qpcr we're getting about a 58 to 174
fold offset between Grand posi gr
negative um results there so there's the
correlation here is getting closer to 6
now uh where the qpcr can predict the
endotoxin loads to some degree uh it's
not 0.9 which is where we want to try
and push this to but um it may be maybe
it's a tool that can help flag samples
that might need a further scrutiny for
this test now this endotoxin test since
we're running uh you know four different
serial dilutions uh it's about $10 a
well so it ends up being like a $40 test
even though the instruments very cheap
the reagents are a little bit expensive
and temperamental um you have to use
them kind of the day you open them
otherwise they get contaminated with
Airborne endotoxins so um but
nevertheless you can see the endotoxins
on the on the scale there there are many
samples cracking the 100,000 eus per ml
uh we're getting we're talking about you
know four orders of magnitude over the
decost limit here um now this needs to
be checked with mass back and it
probably needs to be looked at through
aerosols like what happens with aerosols
uh like when you burn this stuff um you
we do know that it's autoclave uh
tolerant so you can't get rid of it with
autoclaves we don't know how much of
it's going to end up in the smoke and
that's really I think what needs to be
um scrutinized next um you can also run
these assays with and without this Grim
reefer tool this nuclease that destroys
the dead DNA and the correlations get a
little bit better uh you can see on top
are the same samples this is sample
seven and Sample eight and when you add
in this nucleus the all the CT curves
kind of shift to the right um and we can
see we begin to quantitate how much more
gram negative DNA is actually around in
the sample uh here's just a chart of um
five different samples um that came
through I think these were PT samples AO
CPT samples that we were taking a look
at uh and you can see these large
offsets on the top one there's gr means
Grim reefer and no Grim reefer is the no
grr and you can see that the CT scores
when uh you don't use that nucleus are
lower for those not familiar with PCR
lower CT scores mean more uh and it's a
log two scale so when you see like a 10
CT offset that uh you're look you're
looking at um about a thousandfold u
difference there it's about 3.3 CTS for
every scale of 10 okay uh so there's a
you can see a big shift here between
live dead so we can we can detect which
samples uh are in fact we believe are
potentially been put through some type
of remediation process by looking at the
change in these signals not all the
samples show the signature uh which is a
sign that some samples in this in this
um set of of uh of um PT standards were
decontaminated or remediated and some
were
not okay so just to summarize a little
bit here the nucleas treatments we think
are can be very helpful to discriminate
between live dead um there are high
amounts of gram negative DNA and these
are correlating with a correlation about
I think it was 62 on that last slide uh
between um you know PCR signal and
endotoxin load uh We've also run um
tac tac Q PCR this we've run our CA form
PCR we've run a variety of other
orthogonal pcrs I didn't have time to
show here that confirm this this DNA is
in fact there um it's soften living but
the challenge that we have is um the
plating is blind to these risks of
people using remediation U so we really
need to think through this because if we
if we're not labeling for radiation
asmatics are going to be concerned
because there's a Temptation for Growers
to grow dirty and just blast things when
they're done and anyone who knows
manufacturing you want to fix that at
the sort of of the problem and grow
clean and not have to do that uh so um
the right now we're very blind to this
in the field is that when people
remediate this remediation there's no
reason to believe this is removing the
endotoxin I think I think we've got hard
evidence it's not removing the endotoxin
so it's just masking a potential risk uh
from uh from the patients uh by being
able to run this through a a viability
assay if you will um there's a pre-print
here that you can get more information
on um and uh there are other confounded
ERS we have to think about now I I get a
lot of people throw um the accusation at
me that I'm just druming up fear porn to
do more testing uh we don't make any
money on this L test it's not something
we sell or make um and and they're right
in the fact that this is an infrequent
case in fact it's very hard for you to
get um you know to be pitchforking the
employer here because we've never seen
this before no one's looking for
endotoxin uh and uh you know it's it's
something that is it's a complete
tragedy but we don't really understand
why it occurred at the same time there's
a lot of cannabis use out there and we
don't have people dropping from from
deaths from asthma everywhere at least
if they are they're they're not reported
or they're not happening in the
workplace maybe there is endotoxin
loaded material hitting asmatics outside
of the workplace and we would never have
it really recorded as a hazardous risk
so we do have to put this into context
there are other confounders that
occurred during this death this was
during the pandemic and there is a
Litany of Publications out there showing
that the spike protein both from the
virus and from the vaccine exacerbate
LPS and du cyto storms Google this
you'll find tons of papers on this in
fact the cyto storms in uh covid are an
artifact uh and often manifest
themselves in what appears to be sepsis
which is um a condition of a you know
ayine storm so we don't know the status
here of this patient we don't know if
they're vaccinated we don't know if they
were sick or recently recovered or had
long covid um these are all unknowns but
this is perhaps one of these other
confounders that might be making this
lightning strike event more apparent
these days um and and something to to
consider that uh these are this is
probably not being considered in general
throughout um uh you know measuring this
type of uh
epidemiology so um I do want to point
out though there are papers showing um
vaccination uh can actually drive
asmatic reactions like this and we were
in a state that mandated vaccines for
people over a uh over 100 employees so
they were larger than that and maybe
that maybe that's playing a role
um so the conclusions here the the
endotoxin levels are from this from this
La assay I want to be very specific here
because this does need to be confirmed
with alternative methods right now but
from this laay they are exceeding the
decost limits by orders of magnitude on
cannabis it's on every sample we've
measured so far um remediation hides
this risk we have no labeling of this
type of remediation and we probably need
it for asthmatics if we want to avoid
future fatalities like this um going
forward and um there are environmental
confound now in the environment that are
playing or interfacing with LPS so um
this is something that wasn't present in
2000 and no one probably could have
anticipated um and there is a strong
amount of um literature out there
suggesting maybe the mass specs we have
in the Cannabis Testing Labs can run
these types of assays because uh this
would be a great way to confirm what's
going on with thermos assay is to see if
these Mass specs come up with similar
quantitation um so anyone out there who
wants to collaborate on that with mass
spec equipments this would be something
that you could probably hopefully run on
existing equipment that's already in the
Cannabis Testing uh pipeline um and uh I
think we do need to look at this in
aerosols we are just measuring what
homogenizes off of a gram we don't we do
not know what happens when we burn this
and pull it through uh as as a smoked
flower that's something that is uh you
know we're making some leaps here as to
what we're finding on the flower and if
any of that's going to make it into the
patient um after pyrolytic so U and with
that I will I will leave it with
questions I apologize when over this
clock didn't really start on time and so
I could be
late oh one more slide yes I've got to
say thank you for all the people who
worked on
[Laughter]
this um any yes
please my question is what was your
negative control on this if you uh when
you were looking at your samples on the
LA assay oh great great question so the
thermo kit comes with endotoxin-free
water and that is an important point
because many Ro systems don't perfectly
clean it out uh so you have to get very
specific water from um uh uh from uh
from Thermo uh and run that through the
assay but you didn't have a bacterial
free cannabis sample D no I can't find
one that's why I was going to ask if I
could have some yeah yes um but we did
run we did run tobacco I didn't put that
in there but the tobacco's loaded with
it too and it was more it was higher on
the pipe to tobacco than in the world
cigarette tobacco which was interesting
to us uh and we have since this I wrote
up these slides we have run um flower uh
versus pre-rolls we initially focused on
pre-rolls because the pre-rolls tend to
have a higher microbial fail if you look
through Sherman's data there's much
higher fail rate in pre-rolls I think
everyone just throws their their junk
into the pre-roll bucket um and so we
figured the numbers would be higher
there we looked at some like flower hemp
that we're able to get from Oregon um
and Oregon doesn't have they probably
the most lenient testing out there and
uh um those were equivalent so we didn't
see a big difference between pre-rolls
and flowers at least in that
circumstance but yeah tobacco has this
as well yeah to you you would see it in
pipe tobacco more because it's cured in
a different way than cigarette tobacco
no okay interesting
yeah okay I think uh oh Sherman's got a
question all right actually Kevin um I'd
like
to if I may u first of all thank you
very much for excellent talk on your
work i' like to just make a quick
comment from a regulatory
Viewpoint um there's a couple of States
because you mentioned in your talk that
remediation of uh flour you know can um
in killing the gram negative bacteria
could be a source of
endotoxins and there are a couple of
states that have much lower for example
total yeast and mold action levels of 10
to the three which may cause cultivators
to do this pre- remediation that's a
good point so maybe Illinois would be a
good place to look because there would
be more remediation going on there um
yeah sadly uh when we're looking at the
you know the hemp samples that that go
through no microbial screening versus
the ones in Massachusetts that uh
through the dispensary system we're
still getting very similar endotoxin
loads the plating is completely
different it's night and day on the on
the plates but um I I have a feeling
that's we we don't know this but I have
I'm assuming that someone is in fact
decontaminating the samples particularly
if they're if they're pre-rolls uh and
therefore we get nothing on plating and
we get endotoxins that are off the
chart all right
[Applause]