I would like to give you an overview of
cannabinoid research we have been
involved in it for the last 50 55 years
allow me to start by a poem by Rainer
Maria Rilke written about 120 years ago
and he said I live my life in widening
circles that reach out across the world
I may not complete the last one but I
give myself to it well it is as if in
some way his describing what's going on
with the cannabinoids they started with
a small circle and expanded and the
expansion is going on and on and on when
we started work many years ago there was
essentially no interest in cannabinoids
cannabinoid research the effects of
cannabinoids the matter of fact when I
asked for a grant I was told by NIH when
you have something more relevant to the
u.s. contact us it cannot be known so
cannabis is not of interest it's used
sometimes in Mexico but not in the US
well that changed quite fast and today
there is a huge huge interest in
cannabis as a matter of fact the journal
Nature had four reviews four scientific
reviews on this topic and here is one of
them which I wrote and it shows that the
brain and the cannabis growing out of
the brain now why is this change why
when has this happened well it seems
that it cannabinoids or the endogenous
cannabinoids and I'll be talking about
them are involved in a huge amount of
diseases as a matter of fact two senior
scientists at NIH recently wrote a
review and the review says modulating
endocannabinoid activity is essentially
involved in all human diseases well even
if this is 95 percent correct
then it is something of extreme
importance and I don't know of any other
neurotransmitter that we can say that it
is involved in so many diseases well
I'll be talking about on this topic for
a few moments later but let's go back
and start with three four thousand years
ago when the Assyrians actually used
cannabinoids or use cannabis for those
purposes that you we use them today they
use cannabis to cause what they said the
drug that takes away the mind which is
not such a bad definition actually for
getting high they used it for some
diseases apparently neurological
diseases and it seems that they used it
in some of their religious rites well
when we started work and cannabinoids I
was surprised to find out that well
morphine
had been isolated from opium almost 200
years previously and cocaine had been
isolated from coca leaves during the
19th century the active compound in
cannabis had never been purified -
extracted and its structure was unknown
so we went ahead and started isolating
the compounds present in cannabis and we
found about dozen compounds and only one
of these compounds tetrahydrocannabinol
which we isolated in pure form I believe
it for the first time turned out to be
psychoactive all the other compounds
were of not a major interest at that
time at least well we found out that in
you a Lebanese hashish which we received
from the police at which we used for
many years
contains two major constituents
cannabidiol and tetrahydrocannabinol THC
while THC as I said is a psychoactive
cannabidiol is not it has nothing to do
with a well-known a cannabis like
activity but it is a major drug and many
of the diseases that are being treated
today with cannabis actually affected by
cannabidiol and much less than by THC so
we went ahead looking for the activities
of these compounds and one of the first
activities we looked at was epilepsy
this was done in collaboration with a
group in South America and we looked
first in mice and then when we had
enough data we went to humans and we
found that in a group of 15 patients
half of them were placebos didn't get
any material and half of them got CBD at
high doses those eight patients that got
CBD 4 did not have any attacks or
essentially no attacks 3 had many less
attacks and one was not affected at all
so unfortunately these results were not
picked up by the neurologists for many
years and only in the last decade have
children with epilepsy being given
cannabis with high doses of cannabidiol
and a lot of them are being can I say
even saved by using this particular type
of cannabis well another group of
diseases that's being affected by
cannabidiol is graft-versus-host disease
unfortunately many cancer diseases were
them they should be a bone-marrow
transplant
now the body doesn't like it when a
bone-marrow transplant is done the body
attacks the new bone marrow the new bone
marrow attacks the body and the patient
is sick it's times very sick well but
this is a kind of an autoimmune disease
namely the body attacks something within
the body and so a group at one of the
hospitals here thought on the basis of
other effects which had been seen how to
immune effects of the same type
they decided to try cannabidiol
and they gave cannabidiol to a large
number of patients with that were being
that had bone marrow transplantation and
indeed in many cases they they showed
that these patients do not develop the
graft-versus-host disease and for
example here is something here some of
their results two and four grade is a
low-grade disease and while about a 50%
of patients that do not get cannabidiol
have graft-versus-host disease in a a
little bit of a mild form only a small
number only 12% of those that got
cannabidiol were affected those that had
a very serious graft-versus-host disease
which are about 10% only 5% got the
disease so here we have something
it's a clinical value of
at the moment this research is going on
and it is going on very successfully and
I sincerely believe that within a few
years
cannabidiol will become the central drug
the major drug in graft-versus-host
disease
now diabetes type 1 again is a outer
immune disease namely the body attacks
for reason that we do not know it takes
the cells that produce insulin and this
happens particularly in children it is
known speedy Ettrick diabetes and new
drugs are definitely needed for that
kind of disease and we tried in mice
unfortunately only we have not been able
to get into humans yet we found that in
mice that have it all of them they
develop diabetes type 1 if we give them
cannabidiol we can reduce the amount the
number of mice that get diabetes type 1
to about 30% if you look at the slide
you can see that the cells that produce
insulin and you can see that and the
last part of the slide the percent of
the cells that produce insulin and
partially destroyed the number is huge
77 percent of the cells are being
attacked and are not in fact anymore
those that guard cannabidiol only a 7 8
10 percent cut then the cells were
attacked so here we have a very
promising situation for a disease that
is not well treated nowadays these are
some of the diseases that cannabidiol
can be used for but cannabidiol has to
be used in a huge number of
a huge amount of material in in another
field in schizophrenia patients were
given seven to eight hundred milligrams
in order to get a good results and as it
happens with many other drugs one has to
develop derivatives which are can be
used at lower levels and indeed we
recently reported that if we take
cannabidiol and make a derivative a
derivative in which there is a fluorine
atom and the molecule the level the
amount of material needed is much lower
so I hope that within a few years we
shall have both cannabidiol and flora
cannabidiol on the market against many
of them to immune diseases and quite a
few others now for many years after the
chemistry of cannabinoids became known
we learned about the biochemistry the
pharmacology as I mentioned a few
clinical effects one thing that we
didn't know was what is the mechanism of
cannabis action whether it's THC or CBD
but particularly THC what is the
mechanism it was thought previously that
the mechanism is none specific whatever
that means
well nonspecific means that we cannot
really find any well-established
mechanism well this is how the one does
we'll look for nonspecific mechanism if
we have a molecule that can exist into
two types if you wish mirror images of
each other a nonspecific mode of action
both molecules will act for a specific
mode of action only one of them will act
well we found that indeed only the
natural cannot be dial
the natural THC work the mirror image
does not so we so we established that
there will be some specific mechanism
and indeed within a few years and in
howl it in the US found a receptor the
receptor was found in the brain and it
is widely spread in the brain probably
one of the most one of the air receptors
that fountain the highest amounts in the
brain but receptors don't exist because
there is a plant out there receptors a
disease because animals we produce
compounds that affect these receptors so
we went ahead looking for the compounds
in our body endogenous compounds which
will affect these receptors and after
work for quite a few years with
colleagues that came from the state and
a colleague that came from the Czech
State
we found a compound called which we
called Ananda mite and we found also
another compound which we called a - AG
these compounds found throughout the
body and particularly in the brain and
particularly in those areas of the brain
which you can see on the slide where the
receptor is found and these two
compounds have a completely different
structure than the natural / than the
natural plant product but they are they
have the same activity more or less and
they also like the plant Pradhan do not
dissolve in water they dissolve only
lipids and they act in the same way with
one difference they are formed when
needed they're broken when needed but
the plant material stays for a longer
period of time so there has been a huge
huge amount of work and are you you call
this particular research as the second
phase
of Cannavino it research the first phase
is the work on the plant canopy noise
the second phase is the work on the
endogenous cannabinoids and I will not
go into biochemistry of course oh except
one thing why are these compounds
whether it is the plant compound or
whether it these are the compounds that
we produce the endogenous cannabinoids
effective in so many a biological things
why are in so many diseases well one
thing they do is they regulate the
activities of many other
neurotransmitters a nerve is not a
string going from one place to another
nerves in the body are broken down and
that's called a synapse and the synapse
is in our body because in this way the
body can regulate nerve activity now the
synapse there is a there are chemicals
which move from one side to design it to
another these are the neuro compounds
that are neurotransmitters
well the endogenous cannabinoids
regulate the release of these compounds
they sit on the part of the sine X
cosine it's called when needed they move
to the pre synapse and there they
activate a receptor and a affect the
production of the release these
neurotransmitters the bottom line is
they endogenous cannabinoids regulate to
a large extent what's going on in the
brain was going on with
neurotransmitters so to make a long
story short the andhaka
endogenous cannabinoids sister today is
known to have two receptors the cb1
receptor is the one when stimulated
causes the activity the cannabinoid
activity the second one is a protective
is of a protective nature and it has
nothing to do with a psychoactivity of
cannabis then of course there are the
two endogenous compounds an endermite
and two AG and I talked about them there
of course that enzymes those enzymes
that form the endogenous compounds and
also enzymes that break them down and by
playing with these enzymes we can
actually and has the activity and hence
the amount of the endogenous compounds
or we can even leave them for a much
longer time in the body by blocking the
enzymes that break them down and of
course there is the THC and cannabidiol
so there is a huge amount of work going
on and these compounds and know now to
affect as I said previously a long list
of things that are going on in our body
and if you can look at the list that I
have on this slide it starts with
anxiety in blood pressure and the
digestive system etcetera etcetera
etcetera and it goes down to stress and
if I have a full list I'll probably need
another two or three slides now let me
tell you some of the activity of the
endogenous compounds one of the
activities of the endogenous compounds
is a protective effective 'ti a
protective activity in the brain
together with a colleague of mine
professor St Shore Army no we looked at
what happens to the brain when it has
been slightly damaged brain of mice and
we found that one of the endogenous
compounds the two AG and it is in the
red on the slide you have the two AG
goes up about ten times after even a
slight damage to the brain now is that
because the brain has been damaged and
it doesn't
do what it should do what is that some
kind of a protective mechanism so we
synthesized to a G and gave it to mice
that had undergone closed head injury
and we found that indeed those mice that
received cannabidiol had much less
damage in the brain the damage can be
seen in the white part in the slide in
the brain if the damage goes about 50%
less so here we have a typical effect of
the endogenous cannabinoids neuro
protection and we we and many other
groups looked at a huge number of
effects but some of them the effects
with not as strong as we expected for
example on brain injury there is
vasoconstriction of the blood vessels
and the endogenous cannabinoids to
affect whether constriction and
vasoconstriction is part of the damage
but they but the body seems to act to
have something that effects much more
that the brain so we started looking for
maybe we have additional compounds
additional end of cannabinoids and
indeed we found that their compounds
that are closely related to the
endocannabinoids but do not act as
endocannabinoid they do not bind to the
receptor they do not have many other
activities but they definitely act on
the vasoconstriction and one compound of
this type as you can see on the slide it
is closely related to the other compound
but it doesn't bind to the receptor it
is formed from a fatty acid bound to an
amino acid amino acid in this case is
serine and this particular compound we
see it and it has been accepted as a
endocannabinoid like compound found in
the body and
today we know that there is a huge huge
number of compounds of that type about
120 compounds at that time and we know
very little about the activities of
these compounds for example in this case
we know in that as I spoke about era as
RF you don't need searing it is not bind
to the receptor but its activity can be
blocked by an antagonist to the receptor
very strange because how can a compound
which does not bind to the receptor can
be blocked by an antagonist we don't
know why this happens but on the other
hand that's what it does so there is
something that we have to look at in a
completely different area bone
remodeling we were surprised to see that
osteoporosis can be affected by
compounds of this type this has a long
history it is known in the Middle East
that there is less osteoporosis then in
northern Europe and it is believed that
this happens because people in in the
Middle East
use more olive oil than others so we
looked at the presence of compounds of
this type in olive oil and we didn't
find anything but then we decided many
maybe one of the constituents of olive
oil in this case a compound called oleic
acid is metabolized in the body to a
compound that's very active and so we
prepared a few metabolites new compounds
and yes we found that a compound closely
related to an and amide and you can see
in the slide the structure of an animai
and the structure of this metabolite of
oleic acid serine which does not bind to
the receptor does not cause the effects
of an and amide but is a very potent
a compound if we have mice and we cause
osteoporosis in mice and our ways of
doing it and bones are affected and you
can see in the middle the red is the
affected bones if we start giving these
mice this particular a cannabinoid like
compound formed in the body formed in
the bones we can see that the bones
start recovering they are start re
growing ahead so here we have a huge
number of biological physiological
effects that have to be looked at
because we know as I've mentioned
previously that there are almost a
hundred and twenty compounds of this
type and we have looked at these two and
there are some many others that have to
be evaluated so let me try to summarize
what I have been talking about first the
endocannabinoids are involved in a huge
number of biological effects and we can
expect to have a to see many others as
many many groups are working in the
field we know that cannabidiol is an
important compound although it doesn't
cause the well-known effects of cannabis
and there is the third group of
compounds that people are just looking
into now and these are Ananda might like
compounds which are like Ananda might
formed from a fatty acid bound to an
amino acid or a derivative of amino acid
in these compounds seem to be effective
in a huge number of physiological
processes and I sincerely hope that
within the next three years we shall see
drugs particularly of this third type of
endocannabinoid like compounds and of
calm
that specifically under cb2 system which
has no marijuana like effects I would
like to thank many of my collaborators
this is a list of some of my
collaborators in Israel some of them of
my students some of them are colleagues
in departments and we want to say thanks
to many other colleagues abroad you can
see in the slide some of my
collaborators abroad and they conceded
they stretch from the UK in Aberdeen my
good friend Perth way through the Czech
State and Greece and Richemont
in the US and even Siberia I visited all
these places set Siberia it's too cold
for me thank you
you