[Music]
welcome to the caned Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I am the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and member of the
team that puts on the kmed
summit okay just a few reminders before
I introduce this episode's guest first
in honor of the holiday season we have
extended the early bird deadline for CED
24 through December
31st don't miss this chance to save
hundreds on your full Summit package
which includes access to the medical
practicum industry workshops oral
presentations poster presentations
networking events meals and a three
night stay at the JW Marriott Marco
Island resort with all the associated
amenities so head over to cam events.com
now to register and I hope to see you in
Florida this
may I also wanted to mention that we
have added details about the canmed 24
full day medical practicum on our
website this year we are thrilled to
welcome Dr Ethan Russo to the practicum
faculty and we look forward to him
sharing his extensive knowledge and
experience with canono
Therapeutics he will be joined by fellow
instructors Dr Bonnie Goldstein Dr
Dustin sulac and Eloise
th if you aren't familiar with those
names I invite you to read about them on
Kim and events.com and if you are
familiar then you already know that you
can't get any better instructors than in
this group again go to canet events.com
now to learn
more this episode I spoke with Dr
Patricia
diano Patricia is a scientist with the
Institute of Mental Health and policy
research at the center for addiction and
mental health she is also an assistant
professor in the department of
pharmacology and toxicology at the
University of
Toronto Patricia has a
multi-disciplinary background
and her general research area is
clinical trials and regulated studies
into the safety of cannabis and other
substances of
abuse earlier this year she co-authored
a study that evaluated the utility of
THC cof off levels in blood and saliva
for the detection of impaired
driving during our conversation we
discussed the different allowable limits
for THC levels in drivers the
relationship between THC levels and
impaired driving the best fluid to test
for THC levels the additive effects of
combining alcohol and cannabis on
driving impairment the differences in
how alcohol and cannabis affect driving
performance and
more before we get to my conversation
with Patricia I want to thank this
episode sponsor trusted Cana nurse
trusted Cana nurse was founded by Megan
bang and Arian Williams two nurses who
are dedicated to Bridging the Gap
between traditional medicine in the
world of cannabis and
psychedelics they specialize in creating
evidence-based treatment plans for all
ages that address chronic illness
treatment resistant conditions mental
health autism and more learn more at
trusted Canon nurse.com
okay and without any further Ado please
please enjoy my conversation with Dr
Patricia
[Music]
diano good afternoon Patricia thanks so
much for joining us on the podcast thank
you for having me all right so I'm
excited to talk with you today about
cannabis and driving this seems to be a
topic that comes up quite often as jur
different jurisdictions loosen their
restrictions on cannabis one of the
major concerns from lawmakers law
enforcement and the general public is
how do we keep impaired drivers off the
road and a lot of a lot of times the
question is is there an equivalent
breathalyzer test for cannabis and um I
think we all know it it turns out that
it's not that easy so you and your team
recently published a new study that
looks at this problem which I'm eager to
dive into but first I'd like to start
broadly and ask is there data that shows
that incidents of impair driving
increase in states or countries that
legalize
cannabis so that's an interesting
question and the data as most things in
the field is is not 100% you know clear
one way or the other I should say that
most of the research has been done uh up
till a couple years ago was mostly done
in the US so looking at uh states that
legalized cannabis either for medical
reasons number of years ago or more
recently for recreational Reas uh
purposes and compared pre- and post or
they compared legal versus non-legal
States so there are two different ways
to do this and some studies found that
the incidents of imp parent driving
after cannabis or driving under the
influence of cannabis went up with
legalization and others found that it
went down others found that it stayed
the same so it's actually not that clear
um you may ask why would it go down why
would um driving under the influence of
cannabis go down after legalization
there's three possible explanations one
is that people with increased access to
cannabis seem to be switching from using
alcohol to using cannabis and we know
that although cannabis is bad for
driving it does impair driving it's not
as bad as alcohol so perhaps we're
seeing fewer
arrests because the driving is is still
impaired but not as impaired um also
there could be more um increased
enforcement of driving under the
influence of cannabis in legal states
than non-legal States so we're we're
picking it up so we're we're just
there's more enforcement of it in those
States interesting okay and so no and
that's a good point you are you're
joining us from Canada and as I
understand it there are established
limits for THC concentration
for drivers in Canada what are those and
sort of you know based on your research
or your knowledge in the area um do you
have an opinion is that too low too high
or so the legal limits vary by
jurisdiction some some don't have limits
others have limits of blood THC so THC
being a psychoactive component of
cannabis that's thought too in par
driving um of five five nanograms per
Mill seems to be the the limit that most
people sort of um talk about and in
Canada we have two different limits one
is two nanograms per Mill which is sort
of the lower uh level of offense and
then five nanograms per Mill which is a
higher level of offense and so the
jurisdictions vary some have a zero
tolerance which has a zero nanogram per
Mill threshold and others have two
others have five um so in the paper that
you have mentioned uh what what we
looked at was whether or not there's a
relationship of THC and the blood to
impaired driving of course one way to
deter driving after the use of cannabis
is to look at blood THC um and and see
how that and see what the levels are so
if a police officer suspects somebody of
being impaired uh after cannabis they
can pull them over they can do a number
of roadside tests then they can take
them back to a lab to to have blood
drawn and what we found which is coming
out of the literature sure more and more
although it's not again it's not 100%
one way or the other is that as as blood
THC goes up we don't necessarily see an
exact relationship to changes in driving
so we look at weaving which is the
amount of departure from a lane which is
a measure that's very consistently
affected by cannabis and Other Drugs so
just how much you deviate when you're
moving in your lane so we call it
weaving the scientific term is standard
deviation of lateral position so we
looked at that and tried to see how that
relates to blood
THC and we didn't see that there was a
clear relationship so as blood THC
levels went up we didn't necessarily see
an exact correspondence of changes in
driving some people were impaired at
higher levels the blood THC others Wen
there wasn't an exact
relationship but if we sort of broke it
down by the 5 nanogram per Mill
threshold and looked at those who were
above versus those who were below we
found that those two groups were
different so there seems to be some
Merit in those limits that we do seem to
be detecting um some measure of
impairment although I have to put the
caveat in there that that was just for
smoked cannabis we may see differences
with Edibles or other roots of
administration interesting so as the
concentration goes up you don't
necessarily see um additional impairment
but that five nanogram uh per per Mill
or what was it five per Mill perfect um
that was kind of a clear cut off that
you're most likely going to be impaired
if if you if you go beyond that how does
that and now how does that Co how does
that compare with something that people
are probably more familiar with like
alcohol is there more of a linear linear
relationship there I believe that there
is with blood alcohol it's more
straightforward because um you're you're
measuring more directly sort of an a
vape that come off the breast so it's a
more clear relationship with with
cannabis you measuring blood THC which
has gets acted on by enzymes more in a
more different way so it's not quite
clear that what's in the blood is
necessarily reflecting what's in the
brain and what's working in terms of
impairment with canab with alcohol
there's more of a clear relationship
between the the what comes off the
breath and what is found in uh in
driving it's more it's more of a
challenge with
cannabis right yeah and I want to kind
of dig into that because I think there's
a number of different challenges if I'm
understand correctly and one of them
being that there's a number of different
fluids that can be tested and I know
that your your paper kind of looked at
this kind of saliva versus urine versus
uh blood so what is sort of the the best
one to use so right now at the roadside
uh what is happens I know in Canada for
sure I I think it's similar in the US if
a a officer suspect somebody of being
impaired they they pull them over and
they do a a standardized field sobriety
test which is the you know touching your
nose and looking at uh the stagis and
and your ability to walk in the one leg
stand uh you know your balance and
things like that which we've all seen on
TV I'm sure we're a little bit familiar
with what that looks like uh and then
they're also able to do at the roadside
and I know in Canada we use this it's a
saliva test that measures it gives you a
reading that says positive or negative
if you're above a certain level or not
and then there's the blood which they
can take you back to the lab and they
can look at the blood levels of THC as
well then there's urine of course um
which is a bit of a different Beast
because with urine you're measuring the
breakdown products of cannabis you're
measuring what it comes off the Cannabis
whereas with saliva and blood you're
measuring uh THC uh directly so for that
reason urine probably isn't a great
indicator of recent use also as we know
the these breakdown products of cannabis
of THC can last in the urine for days
weeks very a very long time so it is not
a great indicator of very recent use it
just says that somebody has used in the
past few days or potentially longer
whereas Salva tells you more of a small
short time window in the past sort of 12
hours and blood can give you a more
definitive timeline um you know if
somebody has very high levels of blood
THC then you know they've used fairly
recently or smoked fairly recently um
and and if they're lower than they would
have used at some point in the past day
or so so that's more of an accurate time
window for blood and
saliva right and now is it fairly easy
to kind of look at the concentrations in
the blood or saliva and sort of Trace
backwards how much cannabis the person
could have ingested again I'm I'm sorry
I'm gonna keep doing this I'm Gonna Keep
kind of doing the comparison to alcohol
but you know if you're at like a 08 um
alcohol level you can kind of kind of go
back and be like okay they've probably
had a few a few drinks at least in the
past hour or two can you do a similar
thing with cannabis it's really uh to to
estimate the last time of use and the
exact amount of use is quite challenging
with cannabis because the amount of THC
in blood and urine is really dependent
on a lot of factors including age sex
how often you use cannabis what form of
cannabis you've used so we know that
smoked and Vaped cannabis produce very
much higher levels very quickly in Blood
and saliva than with uh Edibles for
example but Edibles last very a lot
longer than smoked with smoked or Vaped
it's gone in five hours with Edibles
that's much it can last much longer so
if somebody comes up with 10 nanograms
per Mill of
THC uh it's really hard to know what
kind of cannabis they used and when they
last used it also um people who use
frequently the Cannabis might stick
around longer in the blood urine than
people who use infrequently so it's it's
it's very it's very challenging we we
can tell you've used recently but we
don't know exactly how much or when that
was excellent all right and so let's dig
into the study you did uh more
specifically so um please explain kind
of what is it that you looked at um and
sort of what makes this study maybe
different or more unique than the other
ones that have been been done kind of
more
recently so what we did differently was
we compared what the standard approach
is to look at relationships of left THC
to driving versus what we thought might
be informative in terms of what the
legal limits mean so traditionally what
people do is they do a correlation so a
statistical correlation they look for a
onetoone mapping of blood THC to uh
changes in driving so the person who has
the highest level of blood THC would
also have the highest level of change in
driving and the person with the lowest
would have blood THC would have the
lowest change in driving and everyone in
the middle would sort of map out you
know correspondingly incrementally
within that within that range um and
what we find is that correlation is very
is is is not necessarily so
straightforward so some people find
there is a correlation others don't so
we ask are the legal limits somehow
informative as opposed to just trying to
find a simple relationship between blood
THC and driving so um given that the you
know we have these legal limits in
Canada and other jurisdiction they help
us detect who is not capable or not fit
to drive at the time and the conclusion
was that those who were above the higher
the more uh greater offense of blood
THC were were definitely more impaired
than those who are below that level so
our conclusion was that these limits may
have some utility um of course we did
have you know our caveats in there it's
just for smoking right now we don't know
all of the roots of administration we
don't know difference in frequency of
use how that would affect it but just
basically that the limits may have some
utility great you and I'm curious too um
how did you sort of look at the the the
difference in time from when they
actually used and when the test was
administered was it like quickly after
or did you kind of give them time to
maybe sober up a little bit like how did
how was that how did that work so they
they all they were all invited to the
for standard test sessions there were
there were four test sessions um and
this was a part of a larger study
looking at the effects of alcohol and
cannabis combined so when you take
alcohol and cannabis together um does it
make driving a lot worse than just
alcohol or cannabis on their own and how
much worse is is it combining the two so
we had four conditions one in which they
just drank alcohol to a breath alcohol
of well the target Target was 008 which
is the legal limit in Canada which is
about three about three drinks I think
depending on the size of the person and
then the other condition they smoked uh
cannabis 12.5% THC joint they were given
and the other condition they had the two
combined and the fourth test session it
was just a placebo so it was just a fake
alcohol fake cannabis and they didn't
know what they were getting at each test
session so it was they they they were
just given a drink and it could have had
vodka or or could have just had lime
juice and they didn't know and similarly
with the Cannabis cigarette so uh they
didn't know what they were given on a
certain day and what we did was they
came in and they went to our what we
call our bar lab it's a lab which looks
like a bar basically and they drank um a
drink of vodka a vodka drink which
doesn't smell doesn't has very little
taste so we could mask it quite easily
with the non-alcohol condition and then
about half an hour later they were
invited uh to our smoking lab negative
pressure room where they were asked to
smoke the Cannabis and uh to to the
usual level of intoxication and to stop
if they felt sick and then about half an
hour later they drove the simulator so
it was very controlled for each person
was more or less the same interval
between each each um
event interesting and so now you said
that you evaluated whether the the
combination of alcohol and cannabis
would be worse than either of those
alone what were the results there so
that yeah so there's just to give you
some background there's a lot of um sort
of debate in the literature as to
whether combining alcohol and cannabis
produce what's called additive effects
so you just it's you know if you weave
or let's use the example of speed it's
probably easier to understand so if your
uh speed goes up by two miles an hour
under cannabis and two miles an hour
under alcohol if it's additive then
taking the two would increase the speed
by four but if it's interactive or
synergistic then it would be more than
four so it could be eight or 10 so the
two actually work to make each other a
lot worse than just the sum of their
parts so there's some debate in the
literature as to whether the effects
would be additive or synergistic and we
found that it was we believe it was
additive based on our data we didn't do
the full analysis on that but we believe
looking at the numbers it was additive
so their weaving uh doubled so to speak
with alcohol and cannabis like you just
added the numbers up together uh and we
published a review a couple years ago
where we looked at uh combining alcohol
and cannabis on driving cognition so
learning and memory and also intox
levels of intoxication and most papers
seem to show that it's an additive so
they're it's like summing the part parts
and combining the two is worse than
either one alone for sure great and then
how about cannabis versus alcohol who
who did
worse so we found they did similar there
in that one study the impairments were
similar so we found that cannabis
increased weaving which is a consistent
finding across almost all the studies
done with cannabis and driving and can
and alcohol also increased weaving which
is also very consistent uh with alcohol
it's pretty much Hallmark of of alcohol
and cannabis that's one of the things
that's usually uh impaired and they were
impaired to this more or less the same
degree after alcohol and cannabis and
then taking them together just D you
know doubled it doubled each one of
those um also what's generally found
with cannabis is that cannabis also in
slows your time to react to events on
the road we didn't find that but a lot
of studies do find that and it also uh
alers your ability to maintain a
distance proper distance with the car in
front of you and it also slows people
down uh because they're driving more
carefully people who use cannabis say
they're aware that they're intoxicated
so they slow down whereas with alcohol
they drive faster generally than than
slower so so that's interesting talking
about the the differences between
alcohol and cannabis yet again so how
are the impairing effects of alcohol and
cannabis different because I think
anyone who who's used both knows that
that they are different so um speak a
little bit about that so with respect to
driving um cannabis increases weaving as
does alcohol where they're different
mostly is that cannabis and the big one
of the big findings that we get from
Cannabis that seems to come out in a lot
of papers not all of them is that it
tends to slow people down because they
know they're
impaired uh so they're they're more
cautious on the Road doesn't mean
they're better driver it just means that
they know that they're impaired whereas
with alcohol they speed and they and
they're more they're much more reckless
drivers so I I at the beginning of the
interview we talked about um what the
effect legalization had on driving under
the influence of cannabis and I
mentioned
that in some jurisdictions the rate of
driving under the influence of cannabis
went down after legalization or with
legalization and that's because people
think that they're switching from
alcohol to cannabis so alcohol is much
worse because maybe they're not aware
that they're as impaired and they're
driving faster and they're weaving on
the road whereas with cannabis they're
aware and they're they're slowing down
they're compensating for their
impairment but they're still
impaired no and that's an interesting
point too because um that might actually
keep impaired drivers off the road right
if they know that they're impaired and
maybe shouldn't be driving maybe they'll
just choose not to
drive so I don't think we have data on
that but certainly I'm talking to the
participants in my studies they
definitely say that they don't drive
after they use cannabis and they're
aware that they're not driving very well
and they're very cautious about driving
after using cannabis and that tends to
be what we get a lot in in self-report
is people say that they're they're aware
although we do know that about 25% of
people who use cannabis do drive after
using cannabis
and especially with respect to medical
cannabis people believe that it doesn't
affect them so they will drive after
using cannabis for medical reasons
interesting um but could
it never mind we won't go there um so in
terms of measuring the concentrations in
the blood um it's my understanding too
that THC can be detected in the blood
for a a long time after use
so how do we sort of control for
that that's right so THC in the blood
can be detected in the blood blood for a
number of um days and i' I've seen
papers where it's above no one or or
it's above one or two nanograms per Mill
which is some of the cut offs for for
weeks
potentially it's generally in people who
use cannabis frequently so every every
day or more than once a day that we see
that these levels
continue and they persist so that is a
challenge I think um what's unknown is
the degree of impairment of people the
day after they've used cannabis it's
unknown right now if frequent users are
not good drivers the next day some
studies will have found that they are
impaired even though they haven't used
that day and there are some studies
looking at blood THC which have found
that people are um more impaired as the
blood THC goes up the day after uh using
cannabis so it's important that is a
good question and it's very relevant to
Medical users and very frequent users
who might have residual blood THC the
next day but that's a question that
still needs to be explored I think more
fully in terms of what the long-term uh
effects are of using
cannabis no and you're right and I just
recently spoke with a researcher in
Australia uh Danielle mcartney who did a
review of a lot of these um studies that
are looking at next day impairment and
um I mean one of her conclusions was
that we need more studies because they
weren't all of really great quality so
um hopefully she's gonna do some more
investigation into that and we can uh
get a more definitive answer but but you
did mention frequent users and I wanted
to ask you too of the participants in
your study were there um you know
cannabis naive users or more frequent
users and was there sort of a difference
in their
performance um so we the in the study
that we have talking about uh the
participants were required to use
cannabis at least once a week it's uh we
all of our studies need to get approval
by an Ethics board so we have to make
sure that our studies are ethical and
we're not putting our participants at
risk and I think one of the criteria
that ethics boards in my experience
usually have is that people who who use
cannabis and a research study have to
have experience with cannabis so you're
not potentially causing them you know
illness or or something an adverse event
in the lab so we generally recruit
people who use cannabis at least once a
week to ensure that they have experience
with cannabis um although that does vary
some people will use more frequent users
and some people will recruit people with
uh less who are less frequent users than
that we did not break it down in our
study by frequency of use and in terms
of the effect people have looked at that
and they have looked at occasional so
you know once a month users versus
frequent users so daily users or four
times a week more or more and and the
again as a lot of things the findings
are are inconclusive I believe uh of the
three or four studies done roughly half
find that frequent users are more
impaired and have find that they're less
impaired than the occasional user
we are looking at doing a study or we're
gearing up to do a study where we look
at frequency of use as a moderating
variable and also age so potentially the
age of the participant might interact
with how frequency of use influences uh
driving after using
cannabis great and that was going to be
my next question is sort of where do we
go from here and and what do you looking
at next and I think you just answered
that but if there's if there's other
things that you're investigating um
please I I think Agee is really
important we just finished a study
looking at older adults so over 65
people over 65 are the uh fastest or
grow fastest growing population of
cannabis users so the number of people
over 65 who use cannabis have has grown
exponentially in the past number of
years compared to the number of younger
users who are
increasing the compared to how many yeah
the increase in and younger adults but
yet they're generally overlooked in
research studies we know very little
about how cannabis affects older adults
so over 65 in terms of how it affects
memory
attention um and other cognitive
measures mostly memory and attention are
affected by cannabis we also don't know
very much about how it affects their
driving we finished a study and we just
finished a study where we showed that
people over 65 do show impairment in
driving but it's unclear as to whether
the amount of change in driving was less
than younger adults so maybe they're
less sensitive to cannabis that's not
clear uh and we don't know much about
how blood THC Works in older adults we
know that older adults have more more
body fat they have changes in metabolism
so that they're slower to metabolized
drugs so potentially blood THC could
break down differently in them we just
have very little information on older
adults
interesting all right um so Patricia I
do want to be very mindful of your time
I think I've I've kept you for uh for
the half hour that I U that I promised
but before I let you go um I wanted to
give you an opportunity to um share any
other additional resources on this topic
um that might be helpful for the
listeners or the viewers to to read more
about or um if there's a a website or
any way to get in touch with you um if
they have any additional questions or
just want to connect uh please plug away
so one resource that I use a lot which
is it's a Canadian Source but it might
be interesting to Americans in other
countries as well just in terms of
General statistics on cannabis use and
you know how many people drive after
using cannabis what age groups use
cannabis what kinds of cannabis do
people use why do they use cannabis uh
it's called the Canadian cannabis survey
and it's conducted by the sort of
National um in at the national level and
it's updated every year in about
November so if you just Google Canadian
cannabis survey you can see all kinds of
Statistics regarding cannabis use the
impact of legalization all those kinds
of questions people have again it's
Canadian Source but it it's I'm sure
that it's not that you know very
different across different countries so
could be
interesting excellent thanks I will put
a link to that in the show description
so people can find it all right Patricia
thanks again for joining us uh on the
podcast and U hope to talk to you again
soon thank you very much it was a
[Music]
pleasure I hope you enjoyed my
conversation with Patricia diano check
out the links in the show description to
learn more about the topics we discussed
and thanks again to this episode sponsor
trusted Canon nurse our next episode
drops December 26th that's 2 weeks from
today in the meantime go to canmed
events.com and register for the caned 24
Innovation and investment Summit before
December 31st to take advantage of our
early bird rate I also invite you to
follow us on social media we are on
Instagram LinkedIn Facebook Facebook and
Twitter just search for camed events and
lastly please rate review And subscribe
on whichever platform you use to listen
to or watch us we really appreciate it
all right until next time I hope you
have a safe and happy holiday and that
you'll come back for the next C Coffee
Talk
[Music]