[Music]
welcome to the cmed Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I am the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and proud member of
the team that puts on the camed
conference all right we do have a big
update off the top for today the
official camed 24 speaker lineup is now
live on camed events.com this year we
have a great mix of familiar names like
Dr Ethan Russo Dr Dustin sulac zamir
punja and TJ Martin to name a few and we
also have a number of new faces like
Kimberly Gwyn from the University of
Tennessee Dr janest Wilson King from
Victory Rejuvenation Center Tim lafever
from
nalo and more check out the full list at
canmed events.com and stay tuned to the
canmed Coffee Talk podcast as we will be
talking to the canmed 24 speakers
leading up to the event this
may by the way ticket packages are still
available for canmed 24 go to canmed
events.com to learn all about the
different packages that we have
available and all the amenities that
come with them and if you want to learn
more about what makes the canmed
Innovation and investment Summit unlike
any other Cannabis Conference available
check out the link in the show
description our marketing team put
together a great blog that highlights
all the ways that canmed is
unique Our Guest today is one of of
those familiar cammed names that I
referenced earlier Kevin mccaran is the
chief scientific officer and founder of
medicinal genomics Kevin has pioneered
the genomics of cannabis and hemp to
build a stronger scientific environment
for the study of cannabis-based
Therapeutics and using blockchain
Technologies for tracking and verifying
cannabis genetics a c 24 Kevin will
present understanding the prevalence and
risk RS associated with endotoxins on
cannabis flour which will include novel
research he did to measure the level of
endotoxins and store bought cannabis
flour our conversation covers what
inspired Kevin to look into endotoxin
levels on
cannabis the microbes that produce
endotoxins and their effect on
humans weather remediation techniques
mask endotoxin risks and and
more before we get to my conversation
with Kevin I want to thank this episode
sponsor agilant Technologies whether you
manufacture or test cannabis you face
the challenge of delivering highquality
products increasing sample volume and
meeting emergent
regulations agilant offers best in-class
cannabis and hemp analysis Solutions
featuring robust instruments software
services and
consumables their team of experts can
develop Implement and optimize methods
to get you up and running quickly learn
more at agilent.com
all right and without any further Ado
please enjoy my conversation with Kevin
[Music]
mccaran
good afternoon Kevin thanks for joining
us on the
podcast I don't know I don't know where
you guys find such trash to come on this
podcast but here I am oh you're too
modest you're one of our best guests and
you are our first guest
so all right they can never take that
one away from
you so I'm excited to talk with you
today about something that's a little
bit different because because in the
past your canmed presentations and when
you've come on the podcast before talked
a lot about sequencing whether it's
cannabis or mushrooms or even viroids
but this year at camed 24 you're
presenting on something a little bit
different we're talking about
endotoxins which isn't just a new topic
for you it seems like it's a new topic
for the industry overall um but before
we get into how or why the industry
should start thinking about endotoxins I
think it's it's important to explain
what they are and why you became
interested in in investigating
them okay so uh I'll start with the why
first and then lead to well now we do
let's do what they are first so people
know why we're anchoring into this so um
endotoxins are molecules that are found
on gram negative bacteria on their on
their cell wall all right so they embed
inside this this lipid Bayer and um
they're they're known to be really
potent anaphylaxis um agents if they're
if they're found in an injectable all
right so when I used to work at Ain
Court we had all this demand to make um
endotoxin-free plasmid purification kits
so we had a whole program and a whole
technology platform where we we built
these magnetic beads that stripped
endotoxins out of plasmid preps because
they're um if you need pharmaceutical gr
plasmas this is a real FDA concern you
got to test them for endotoxins and get
rid of the stuff but I never really
thought about it in terms of cannabis so
honestly had forgotten about it for like
a decade and then um and then the reason
they came to our attention is that um I
think it was on LinkedIn there was a
little bit of a back and forth going on
about decontamination and mot toxins um
uh and I think Tess had some really
interesting information saying hey we're
we're not looking at the right mot
toxins fusarium makes them bacteria make
endotoxins and then um another group in
Massachusetts um was asking a lot of
questions about you know what happened
in um the pre-roll facility
Massachusetts where someone died um this
is like created a big storm here in
Massachusetts the CDC is swept in to
start measuring things OSHA's involved
there's been fines handed out um so um
for those who aren't familiar with this
case um uh I won't add the patient's
name because I I noticed the CDC
documentation didn't do that so I'll
stick to their guidance here but a
patient it wasn't a patient I'm sorry it
was an employee that worked in a
pre-roll facility in Massachusetts um
had an allergic reaction in the facility
and and like died and um and I believe
she was a cannabis user so that everyone
everyone was really confused by that
like if this person was allergic to
cannabis she wouldn't be consuming it so
what the hell happened in the pre-
facility that suddenly made her um have
an asthmatic reaction um now they they
uh there's some debate whether they had
the proper masks and the proper HEPA
filters and all that and I don't I don't
know where that all that landed all I
know is that by the time the CDC got in
there to try to measure this
retrospectively um the facility had
already implemented some better HVAC to
try to address this so they they
responded to try to you know mitigate
whatever risk they could and and no one
really knew what it was like something
Airborne must have gotten to her um so
let's clean the
air um so that had a lot of people
asking us like what is this is there
some microbe that makes a toxin is there
uh is the microbial testing to blame um
pre-rolls are notoriously higher in
microbial content for whatever reason
they're either lower quality flowers
that don't have bag appeal or maybe
they're lower branches and there's
higher concentration you know we don't
know the answer for that but they tend
to have a higher microbial burden um and
uh maybe grinding them up is something
that liberates more of them and there is
this possibility that they're they're
often um decontaminated or radiated now
we don't have good labeling here in
Massachusetts to know if that was
happening here or not um so that was on
the table and we had a lot of people
just asking questions like what do we do
for uh you know we're not seeing
patients die but got if the employees
that are handling this stuff are dying
then you have to assume there may be
some artifacts that are hitting patients
and they're just not getting maybe
reported as being connected to their
Canabis use so um that got me digging
into the the literature a little bit on
this and um someone I know who's an
endotoxin specialist was like oh yeah
you you should you should know about
this I mean the tobacco Fields had to
deal with this all the time tobacco
cigarettes have endotoxin and in fact
they don't think it's the tobacco that's
killing people they think it's the
endotoxin I mean some small branch of
people believe this that they're that
the endotoxin is what's causing a a um
bronchial inflammation and it's it's not
really the nicotine that's doing this
this is uh the the other contaminants in
the tobacco that tend to come along for
the ride can create inflammation in the
lungs and COPD and Asthma and a host of
other problems so um that put me down a
rabbit hole of literature reading into
this um and then I stumbled across some
literature that implied 40% of the
bacteria on cannabis is gram negative so
it should be endotoxin loaded um which
shocked me I went over to our
informatics guy Steve and said is this
true like search our database for
everything we've ever sequenced the one
the one nice thing we have here at MDC
is there's like you know thousand
samples of cannabis that have been
sequenced mostly stems but some Roots
some flowers and and leaves uh where we
can measure like what's the microbiome
content of these things and is it true
that 40% of these things are in fact
gram negative and we comb through that
for about a day and we're like yeah the
guy's right there's actually a whole lot
of klebsiella there's a whole lot of um
these other gram negative bacteria that
we're finding in the microbiome data so
um that person spot on um what do what
do we do about this um so that's kind of
where the the the project started is we
said all right why don't we get
ourselves an endotoxin assay kit we can
run that on like a cubit which is one of
these portable fluorometers that's
probably the cheapest thing you could
ever purchase for a Laboratory um it's
about I don't know $7,000 or something
to buy this Cubit uh and uh we use those
for measuring DNA concentrations and RNA
concent they're they're kind of a
universal Swiss army knife really
affable um so we're like all right we
can run on that thing and assess um if
there's any endotoxin on on on on
pre-rolls or cannabis and uh that kind
of evolved into asking different
questions of like maybe we should look
at cannabis that comes out of the
dispensary system because we know it's
tested to have low cfu and let's look at
some stuff that's in the HP Market that
isn't tested and usually in our
experience the hemp Market in
Massachusetts has really high cfus
everything from from Total use in mole
total Ric counts it's it's um it's grown
Outdoors probably using a lot of organic
farming um so uh we went around and and
and got some samples from hemp
facilities and then purchased some from
dispensaries that had uh that had been
through testing we don't have any
knowledge of of whether they've using
any decontamination techniques but um we
uh one one would naturally assume that
when you contaminate these things you
prevent the microbes from growing but
whatever's there is uh has endotoxin so
the decontamination doesn't get rid of
that uh and so it's quite likely that um
it would it would be remaining so the
the hemp samples we picked up were like
screaming hot three million cfus per
gram like off the scale hot 30 times
above the limit and then of course
everything we pull from the dispensary
side was clean uh like so very very
clean like almost zero 100 maybe
thousands use at most um and then we
went about running quantitative PCR on
those plating those and then also
looking at live Dead with quantitive PCR
because one thing we noticed with um
modern Cana was that um we have this
live dead kit that gets rid of dead DNA
and when she was I think it was um um ah
Jenny Jenny uh I'm forgetting
her that's it glaris yeah um so the uh
what she she did a nice study that she
showed at camman last year where she was
using Liv dead PCR uh with grim reefer
to look at a radiated samples and she
noticed that in some cases the the the
Grim reefer didn't get rid of all the
DNA it lowered it but it's still in some
cases was testing hot uh whereas the
plating was completely blank and um that
got us looking into okay is our nucleus
not working are there viable but not
culturable cells there are there is
there something about um uh PCR that's
just the radiation can kill the organism
but not destroy the DNA enough so some
of the Dead DNA is still around and the
dnasis can't get to it we kind of went
down this Rabbit Hole trying to figure
out why can't we get the the live de
qpcr um to perfectly match plating after
radiation um what she I think concluded
from that study was that okay what we'll
have to do is uh enrich after um
radiation to know if there's anything
there um that's viable that way we can
we can use live dead PCR and a little
bit of enrichment and perhaps you know
sort this problem out but it's certainly
left um Tess and a few other people in
the field like worried that if we build
a a a pipeline in cannabis where people
can grow the dirtiest stuff possible and
then just blast it at the end uh just
because it can counterfeit a plating
system is that really safe like what if
what if it's loaded with mot toxins and
endotoxins and all this other garbage
and you're just finding a way to evade
the the detection tool that they're
using in the industry by doing this
radiation thing and then of course
there's concerns over it's not labeled
and the patients don't know about it so
um it got us looking looking in that
area a little bit more and uh I don't
know that's kind that's kind of how the
project snowballed yeah no and thanks
for that and you did write up a great
white paper um kind of summarizing this
whole this whole study which I'll put a
link in the show description so people
can read it and so I mean you mentioned
the results and and there's a there's a
great graph in here that kind of shows
that of sort of the endotoxin levels and
then the pre and post Grim reefer um
information here and I mean but when I
look at that and and tell me if I'm
reading this correctly that it looked
like on every sample there was a
significant level of endotoxins is that
right yeah it it was and that was kind
of the shocking thing that we found was
that there wasn't a sample that was free
of it um now it varied you know several
orders of magnitude between the samples
but the lowest sample was several orders
of magnitude over the decost limit which
you know we're going to have to assess
in the field like what what that limit
should be the decost limit for people
know is it's a European Standard for the
amount of um endotoxin that can be in
breathable air so they have it set at 90
eus per square meter yeah um you know
we're we're dealing with a gram of
cannabis which is a million times
smaller than a square meter so uh and
we're having numbers that are orders of
magnitude higher on on the Cannabis so
uh I don't know if they've set a
standard for like what that should be
for an inhalable product but I would
assume that the inhalable product should
should probably be close
to the the limit for what's tolerable
for the employees in the in the air um
and there are some some studies listed
in there from the CDC and from a couple
other parties where they went into to
look at the endotoxin levels just in the
air at certain work environments uh in
the Cannabis field uh the CC had one
study that showed that 40% of the
employees were exposed to levels that
were higher than um in the trimming
facility that were higher than the the
the decost limits um another study
looked at this in hemp um and a couple
other like lung diseases that were
showing up for workers that were that
were handling a lot of hemp so there's
there have been a couple other data
points looking at this um it's important
to know that when the CDC went into this
facility in Massachusetts that's the
that's what they began looking for um
they began looking at at for endotoxin
levels so um their radar is up on it and
that's what got us looking at it is we
said all right if they're if if that's
what they're coming in to investigate we
should probably get an understanding of
how much of this is actually just around
on the flowers because we can't really
find a whole lot of papers that speak to
that um we can find some things on
Tobacco and a couple studies that were
done in these environmental exposure
studies so um so yeah the the numbers
are are are very high um I I don't know
if this you know obviously if this were
so toxic there's a lot of cannabis use
out there people would be dropping like
flies we we don't see that um I think
what may have happened with this
unfortunate case is that this person may
have had a pre-existing condition of
some sort asthma and this just was the
hair that broke the camel's back it it
maybe exacerbated the problem and um we
we have to pay you know may maybe close
attention to Patient use in this case so
maybe the medical field needs to think a
little bit more carefully about this um
I mean the the other thing that came up
that wasn't really mentioned in the
paper that but we've been pondering
since then is um well can we use gr
positive bacteria as biocontrol agents
to like out compete this stuff so it's
not around and that's probably a really
good idea billus is something that's
commonly used as a as a um biocontrol
agent and billus is gram positive so
maybe you flood the plants with basilla
so you can knock out all the gram
negatives and then we don't have this
problem anymore um so it may it may lead
to better cultivation techniques um you
know the only challenge with billus our
PCR tests will hit it on the TAC uh
amplion it won't hit it on the eoli or
the sex stuff but the the TAC plates
from 3M will light up with billas so a
lot of people are penalized right now
for using bio control agents that might
mitigate this problem uh because the
testing Rec the testing tools they're
using will pick it up um and so it's
really ironic because they have this
testing platform that tries to grow
everything on plates and it's penalizing
for using the biocontrol agents that
could get rid of the gram negatives that
in fact the testing platform you can
then evade by radiating it's this big
like circular nonsense that we've got
high tack counts so we'll radiate it and
it doesn't get rid of the endotoxin now
you can put it on plates that uh that
basically don't show any growth when the
real answer may have been to actually
put billus on there that would fail your
your 3M plate and you wouldn't have the
endotoxin problem but um yeah we have a
lot to learn I think uh in the microbial
space and cannabis and what we do for
this but um there are some some
citations in the paper uh talking about
what these exposure levels are like what
they learn from the tobacco industry
about this and how they try and keep
those levels down um the tobacco
industry is obviously a little bit
different in that every tobacco
cigarette tends to tends to have a
filter on it which we don't necessarily
have on on the Cannabis stuff and we
don't know how much of that is is
scrubbing the endotoxin out of the out
of the smoke but they do run tests on
Sid stream and and stuff through filters
to see how much is coming through in
tobacco and they can in fact see it I've
not measured tobacco leaves themselves
to see how much is on there that's
something we may do next week when we
get some new kits in but um but yeah the
amount on cannabis flowers is High um it
does vary orders of magnitude but it all
seems to be above these decost limits
and um the next question is can you does
does pyrolytic kill this stuff right um
the the problem we have in the research
field is that endotoxin is one of these
things that when it's around you can't
autoclave your way out of it it tends to
survive autoclaves which is like high
pressure and heat and you know what
we're using to vaporize cannabis is like
low pressure and heat but it's heat for
like a brief period of time and it
doesn't doesn't torch the whole flower
it just tortures the tip so there's
possibility that a lot of endotoxin can
come out of smoke I mean that'd be a
really interesting study if people can
figure out how to capture um endotoxin
out of smoke stream some of the some of
the people studying the vape pens um
would be I think wise to do that there's
there's actually literature of
endotoxins in and tobacco vape pens oh
yeah that's the tobacco process of
people getting I don't know how that
happens because I don't think they're
extracting nicotine from from Plants I
thought figured it was just a chemical
synthesis they put those things but they
have they have noted endotoxin inside of
um tobacco vape pens uh in which case
I'm really curious to know how much of
this stuff actually ends up in the
canabo oils because it it it is it it's
a molecule that looks like it's going to
be more um lipophilic um and that it
likes to be in a lipid Bayer so will
will it end up in the extraction
enriched or will it end up in um you
know some other um fra fraction of the
distillation process I lot of lot more
questions than answers we have right now
yeah and that would be particularly
concerning because um I mean as I
understand it a lot of times if flow is
failing for microbial um sort of the
solution a lot of times is to extract it
or turn it into distillate and then you
know right I always assume that was the
S thing to do yeah yeah absolutely in
which case Ethan
Russo yeah Ethan Russo and I think maybe
it was Jeff
a couple people have done studies on
some of the risks of of extracting for
safety uh and and one of the concerns
was uh pesticides and myotoxins could
enrich differentially in the extraction
process like the cannabinoids might go
from 20% to 80% but you can see the
pesticides go from like you know parts
per Millions to parts per thousands like
they they would enrich to a higher
degree than the cannaboids themselves
and so they they raised concerns over um
differential capture of those things so
those are all good questions uh that we
have now for what this endotoxin can do
um so yeah again we've not seen people
dropping like FES from endotoxins but
there is this this fatality here in mass
and it has got the federal government uh
looking under uh you know the whole
production process here uh and if we are
at the stage of maybe descheduling or
going to schedule three and there's
going to be more Federal um overhang on
the Cannabis industry we probably have
to start paying attention to what
they're doing and and and start looking
at um the source of these of these
contaminants I mean I'm really intrigued
by the the biocontrol agents with
basilis just because um if you could
flood the plants with gr positives then
there's there's less likely for there to
be um an issue there and and likewise
there's a there's a I think a valid
point to many of the I think the points
you've seen Tess on on LinkedIn Rays is
like look it's never a good
manufacturing process to to to do things
dirty and mop up at the end right you
want to eventually build you know some
level of sterility into your grow I mean
it can't be perfectly sterile obviously
plants need microbes but um there is
such a wide variation in the genetics
that can
um that in terms of their cfu that you
get like the the work from zamir was
really interesting that he showed the
total yeast and mold ratios were or a
genetic characteristic of the plant so
he had plants that would always have
genetically would just have higher yeast
and mold burdens than other lines and it
was something that went the genetics of
of what they're growing so that tells
tells you something about um you know we
can find a way to breed cannabis that's
low in these microbial burdens so that
we don't have to mop up a mess at the
end and wonder if there's microt toxins
or endotoxins that are coming through
that we can't measure um I mean you know
there are good ways to measure mot
toxins and now endotoxins um it's just
uh one of those things that doesn't
shine through in every state I don't
think every state has mandatory microt
toxin testing um and no one has
endotoxin testing and frankly looking at
the data we have now I'd be like forget
the microtox look at the endotoxin
because it's everywhere it's when I talk
to people who run the microt toxin test
they're like we almost never get a hit
on those things it's just
like testing why is it that mot toxins
became you know something that's
required testing and endotoxins kind of
went
unnoticed it's a good question I mean
microt toxins made their way in into the
food industry and you know there's they
are more of an oral ingestion risk
because they they tend to have effects
on your liver um whereas endotoxin isn't
something that's that's really an oral
ingestion risk so you know like the
edible pipeline doesn't need to worry
about this it's really more of
inhalation and injection in fact
injection is the real thing that the FDA
worries about because you get
anaphylaxis and people drop but
inhalation is something I think has been
one of these areas where um I mean I
have to look up the farmer RS for like
uh the limits on this for for like
asthma inhalers and stuff stuff I'm sure
they're very low but I think when you
get into the realm of like tobacco and
cannabis you're like okay you guys are
inhaling like you know pyrolytic anyway
so who cares about about what what else
you're adding you I I just don't think
that they've had the same like scrutiny
it's it's almost as if You' you've
committed yourselves to performing at
something risky so you're probably not
too concerned about the other risks that
are there and there's always this
question the flame probably destroys it
all right uh it's probably not true
given the temperatures that people Vape
at but um it's adds a uh an element of
um the pyrolytic seems to sometimes
offer an out on on what's present so I
have a feeling it has something to do
with that just that um if you're
inhaling these if you're willing to
light something on fire inhale it anyway
then no one's got a whole lot of
sympathy if there's some contaminates
around but um I think the medicine when
it comes to actual ingestion uh it
probably does need to we need to think
about microt toxins if they're at high
levels I've not seen a lot of people who
test for those things so they come out
you know more than like one % positivity
in uh in testing I always hear of like
one in a thousand or one in 500 samples
might pop positive for a Mot toxin test
but uh it's nowhere near the um it
doesn't match the level of like 10%
failing for to Total yeast and mold You'
think if you had that much yeast and
mold everywhere you'd You' you'd have
some concordance with the actual um mot
toxin test so um what we can see from
this data is that yeah when there's
bacteria there um and and even when it's
been Zapped or it doesn't it doesn't
show like we can see in this paper there
is in some cases there is um bacterial
DNA present and it doesn't grow that
tells us okay someone probably
decontaminated this and the endotoxin is
screaming High um so the DNA can maybe
help navigate some of this um but uh you
know when it comes down
to um some samples that are just totally
you know no DNA uh no evidence of of
growth but they're screaming high with
endotoxin um that's I don't know that's
another matter and we probably have to
understand what the lower limit um can
be uh from from a patient
standpoint yeah and the other point too
when you talk about sort of the
pyrolytic or you know lighting it on
fire might take take care of the
endotoxins might you know eliminate them
but it doesn't solve the problem of the
people who are working in the production
facility or you know like the the person
in
Massachusetts yeah and I think you had a
you had a podcast on with an aspergillis
expert who who always brings up this
point that when they do these paralytic
test that yeah there's a very high
temperature at the very at the end of
The Joint but the rest of the joint is
getting an elevated temperature but not
hot enough to destroy the spores so you
can get active spores coming out of a
joint in fact we've seen this in the
Bakersville case where they had
cryptococcus infection of a patient um
and um that ended up with menitis um so
yeah the the pre-rolls seem to be the
part of the pipeline that's dirtiest uh
and where we see the most fails and
where we probably need to have the most
attention that happened in or too when
we looked at the whole Oregon story
theyve when they turned on aspergillis
testing they were having like 10 to 20%
failures in the pre-rolls but their
flowers were down at like two or three%
like California and it's just a a signal
that we tried to make clear to The
Regulators that look you have a
biological signal here that would
satisfy a Bradford Hill criteria for
causation you you have what's known to
be a dirtier process for making
pre-rolls from from all the scrap
material that's testing hot and you have
you know high quality um bag of Peel
flour that's testing low um this is this
is a sign of something that's going on
you know we should look into this and
and maybe the maybe the pre-rolls have
to go through a different
decontamination process and maybe extra
mot toxin checks or something but um I
think they've opted to just throw their
hands in the air and move on but um the
uh I mean the data that we're seeing
here in mass is is uh it's not something
we can turn away from I think the main
argument they had in Oregon is well no
one's ever found someone who got hurt
from this and that's that's a fine
argument if you put your head in the
sand and you don't look but we actually
have a fatality here in
Massachusetts and no one was necessarily
looking for it the person literally had
to drop dead on the floor at work for
people to pay attention to it we don't
know how many people are getting asthma
attacks outside of uh the workplace and
just consuming from consuming Purity
cannabis it's probably going um
unregistered and that that is a problem
with a lot of the the Cannabis
literature out there is that for all the
time of prohibition we didn't have
people running into the hospital
declaring I'm a cannabis user help me
they're hiding it because it could get
their kids taken away from them you know
so uh the uh the best we have right now
are studies from like the CDC that point
to Insurance data showing that okay
cannabis users have an elevated risk of
of um bungal infections and the icd10
codes like point of mucr micosis and
aspil losis as like the the the two top
um risk factors that are there um but
other than that it's a lot of people
sort of claiming well we never had to do
this during prohibition so why do we
have to do it now and um that's that's
that's fine if you want to socialize the
risks of the business but uh it's not
necessarily I think where things are
going to end up when um the FDA gets
involved if they ever get
involved yeah and so is that where
you're you're kind of hoping is one of
the results of of looking into this is
that we should kind of start looking or
at least you know consider that end
toxins might be a factor here I
definitely think others should look into
this no one should take our work uh
alone it's a pre-print right now it's it
needs to be reproduced and and it should
be reproduced in multiple jurisdictions
before any regulator gets crazy with
this because uh we don't know what this
means um I think what we want to see is
lots of reproduction in the academic
space or in um uh you know just in the
scientific literature uh and then get
some assessment as to is this is this
associated with other people having
asthma attacks um it is a very of all
the things that we can do in the
Cannabis field this is probably the
cheapest thing one can measure and I'm
sad to say we don't have any like
Revenue stream attached to this thing
because it is a uh it's not our it's not
our technology we're just buying this
stuff from Thermo um and uh but it's
it's very cheap it's very
um you know small format I don't know if
you guys can see this but uh right there
your background fighting against us here
yeah it is I have to put it on my face
so you see it over my
forehead people listening can't see this
but this is basically a standard curve
of a l assay it's it's it's one of these
assays that um has to use an enzyme if
you send me a picture I can superimpose
it up there for you oh yeah it's
probably one in the paper um but yeah
it's um so there there's this uh
clotting factor in the blood of the
horseshoe crab which is Blue Blood um
that actually when endotoxin shows up it
creates a clot Cascade and so they've
they've hijacked that that enzyme to to
to create this sort of fluorometric
assay that that basically um gives you
different color based on the amount of
endotoxins that's there so uh I mean
this is something that runs in a
portable uh fluorometer that's that you
could it's smaller than a PCR machine
it's probably the cheapest thing anyone
could Pro possibly put into a Cannabis
Testing laboratory and it only it's
probably only you know 10 bucks a sample
or something so it is it is really fast
and cheap to run this it's something
that is run quite frequently in the um
Pharmaceutical industry to make sure
there is an endotoxin in any of the
drugs um and any injectables uh so
there's a large industry behind how to
do this and do it properly I mean the
the one challenge that I think we've had
with the assay is that you you do have
to run this in Matrix um because the L
assay there isn't a really good way to
purify endotoxin away from all the other
stuff that it's with um which means
you're you're you're having to take
cannabis flow homogenize it dilute it
really we T we basically dilute it 1 to
10 after we've like put a gram of
cannabis in 10 MLS we take one micr of
that into and dilute it one to 10 and
pop it into this assay and we get these
screaming High signals um but if you do
if you do it any more concentrated in
that the the tpen or I don't know what
but something seems to be interfering
with the assay and you get you get an
underrecording of the event when you do
that um but you know other than that
we've been able to go through probably
two dozen samples now of um different
flowers to show that we can get we can
we can pick it up with this portable
device that um is uh is is fairly cheap
the the the the reagents are very time
sensitive so the moment you crack them
you got to use them otherwise you start
it's the aay starts taking off on on
kind of background endotoxin so um
that's the only downside of the one that
that we're using is it's you can't like
crack the vials and and and leave them
out on the bench for two days and expect
to get good results the next day you
have to kind of be really fast with it
but um so yeah I I don't know where
where it will go I I hope um the the
other side of this is that could be
really interesting as a collaboration
with a testing laboratory is that there
are other techniques out there that
measure endotoxin with mass spec and
they're far more accurate and better but
they're far more expensive and they're
not portable and you know this but but
they're really good tools to to like
validate like all right is this really
working the way we needed to with the
Cannabis background that's there um
that's always good to have a second
assay to kind of check the books on this
stuff um and so um to the extent any
other cannabis out there has done
endotoxin testing please reach out we'd
love to like share notes and how we
could try to calibrate these things to
each other um and see if there's uh you
know there might be a way people can
just turn on their turn their Mass specs
onto a different column or a different
assay and and uh read this with
equipment they already have um but it
would be helpful study because I think
as as more and more of these
decontamination tools come to
Market we have to understand what it is
we're hiding you know it's one thing to
get rid of total robot count total robot
count is one of these weird things where
it's like you don't really know if it's
harmful or not you're just counting
total microbes but um and and when you
start doing these cleanup techniques um
yeah you're getting rid of what can grow
but are you getting rid of what you're
most worried about which is the
endotoxin um it doesn't seem like this
this is you know we're blinding
ourselves perhaps and giving ourselves a
false sense of security with this uh so
this might be a tool that can help
either guide that process um I mean one
one thing that we're we're working on
next on this um and this is actually I
have to compliment um uh test I'm
forgetting I'm going to butcher her last
name but I think you know her from um
some of the great podcast she's done and
put on LinkedIn um she looked at her
paper and was like this is cool you know
you could do do more replicates which is
always good advice um and then what
about getting rid of the gram positive
bacteria out there would you get a
better PCR correlation uh if you look in
our paper our correlation between like
qpcr and endotoxin is like 043 it's it's
it's there but it's not like you could
use the qpcr to predict this uh I think
some of that lack of correlation is that
we're not segregating the gram negative
from the gram positive in our qpcr test
we're just measuring total aerobic count
um so we've gone and designed some PCR
primers that are going to do try to do a
better job of like only give me
amplification from Gram positives and
only give me amplification from Gram
negatives and then we can try to
correlate the endotoxin levels with
those PCR signals and maybe those
signals will like get a 6 or 7%
correlation and so the the quantitative
PCR tests would not only count all Tac
but would split them into two different
channels of positives and negatives uh
in in which case uh they may have a
little bit more predictive power to run
after after decontamination to know okay
how much how much residual DNA is here
that was gram negative because the gram
negative DNA is is what we want to make
sure is is really low uh that would tell
us that the plant started with very
little gram negative and therefore
that's unlikely to have
endotoxin um so we're poking around at
at um some assays like that to see if
they if they better inform on the topic
but um to be honest the the the PCR
might be helpful in the end the um the
endotox and stuff runs just as quickly
it's like a 30- minute assay uh and uh
it it runs on a on a device that's um uh
that's much like smaller footprint it's
just hard to parallelize like we can't
run 96 at a time without the reents kind
of you know going bad on you in the
process of setting up 96 assays so um we
have it's great for about eight at a
time uh and then um you have to probably
start over with another strip tube of
eight but um the PCR stuff we can really
crank through and it might help us
inform on um all right what's what's
going on with uh this the the whole
decontamination
process excellent well it seems like uh
definitely an interesting uh line of
inquiry that we're going to continue to
to look into um in the meantime is there
other resources you you would like to
point the audience to that they can
learn more about this or uh if you want
to share any ways that they can get in
touch with you uh please do well
certainly yeah you can find me at this
medicinal genomics um that address and
then um I think I put a substack up on
this but there's the there's the
preprint we have I'd start there I think
the preprint has a good list of like
what have other Regulators looked at in
the Cannabis field regarding endotoxin
what's in the tobacco field what are the
what are the limits people have had in
the past and um and our sort of first go
at this and I I would caution folks we
just started doing this in like November
so we're by no means experts at this but
we figured when the data came out like
as loud as it was we like all right we
gotta at least get this out there and
let others know and see if anyone else
can like tell us where we're wrong or
which direction we should go so uh if
others are interested in studying this
like bring us up uh we're we're open for
collaboration on this because uh this is
something that is is kind of uh new to
us at least in the Cannabis field
uh and uh we're kind of interested in
where this uh where this may lead so um
feel free to drop us a note at uh you
can get to my email at um kevin.
mckernin medicinal
genomics. excellent all right Kevin
thanks again for the time and um see you
around the office all right yeah take
[Music]
care
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Kevin mccurnin check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and thanks again
to this episode sponsor agilant
Technologies our next episode drops
February
7th in the meantime go to canmen
events.com and check out the cam med24
speaker lineup while you're there be
sure to sign up for email alerts to get
notified about future event
announcements and don't forget to
register for your canmed 24 ticket
package tickets are limited this year
and demand is high so don't wait also
we'd appreciate it if you follow us on
social media we are on LinkedIn
Instagram Facebook and X just search for
canmed events and finally we'd
appreciate it if you rate review And
subscribe on whichever platform you use
to consume the
podcast all right and that's it from us
until next time stay safe stay healthy
and be sure to join us for the next
camed Coffee
[Music]
Talk
I