hello can you hear me okay excellent so
I will be discussing health outcome
comparisons between epilepsy patients
who use versus do not use cannabinoid
therapy I have a disclosure I'm recently
a shareholder of C W health the reason
why I stand before you is this little
bundle of joy right here the little
inset picture is acai and my son on
steroids one of the reasons I was
attracted to cannabis his therapy is
because he did fairly well using
high-dose steroids but he was a little
60 year old man at the end of that he
had cataracts and bone loss and the
seizures returned anyway he has a rare
catastrophic form of early childhood
epilepsy called doza syndrome he
suffered seizures every single day most
of his life with the exception of about
eight months 500000 seizures by the time
he was 5 years old if you could imagine
by the time he was nine we had recycled
through 17 pharmaceuticals he was
transitioned to receiving hospice
palliative services and we wanted to
consider using cannabis as a quality of
life measure for Zakai that's him
getting an EEG in December of 2011 with
a service dog when the EEG showed
seizure activity every 10 seconds while
he was awake even seizures that we
weren't seeing and two to three times
that frequency while he slept so his
brain was on fire that's him an entire
swing recently he has used cannabidiol a
preparation that the whole plant
botanical extract for over six years
he's pharmaceutical free four of those
six years he was seizure free and then
puberty hit so we're kind of hanging on
white-knuckled through puberty and I
want to thank all of the researchers and
the scientists that are in the room and
is a complete honor to stand on this
stage and doctors like Bonnie Goldstein
and Dustin Sulak who have taken the
charge to help patients when their
doctors don't have this tool in their
toolkit my hat is off to you the
research I found on yes
the research I found on PubMed was the
light at an end of a very very dark
tunnel in my family's life so we created
the realm of caring foundation I want to
be extremely clear we are an independent
501c3 organization an independent
nonprofit we focus on research we're
currently enrolling in five different
studies so if you're a doctor and you're
trying to track patients hit our booth
please and if you are in the industry
and creating fabulous products you need
to stop by - because everyone needs to
be putting their data in this registry
so we do research so that we can educate
we operate a call center we field about
8,000 inquiries every single month we've
been on the phone over a million minutes
counseling families who are you trying
to use cannabis as therapy as well as
doctors and doctors are a third highest
referral source so they figured out
we're not a fringe group to get folks to
and we're building community so we
created an observational research
registry because the Kies story is just
a good story it's just an anecdotal
story what I call the amazingly amazing
anecdotal story but if we're not doing a
good job of collecting this data in a
scientific way I'm tracking what people
are actually using that they are
actually able to get out in a dispensary
or order through the mail then you know
I think we're doing a disservice so I'm
going to go over some data and our
general registry some epilepsy data from
our general registry we have an epilepsy
specific survey and then we have a
prospective cohort I we do have these
available at our booth we have a poster
boast that we can email you both on
epilepsy and autism so you can receive
this data dr. Bret did a pretty great
job of discussing what epilepsy is so
I'm going to save ourself a little bit
of time here it's important to realize
though that 30 percent sometimes up to
40% are they do have intractable
conditions on the other thing I'll
mention is that I believe statistically
this this still exists dr. Russo or
someone else can help us who's a
neurologist
that after the third failed
pharmaceutical you have less than a 1%
chance of finding one that's gonna work
so when I think about our fourteenth and
our 15th and our 16th and our 17th drug
that really makes me tear up we do have
quite a history of cannabis use in
epilepsy for thousands of years all the
way to of course you guys are aware of
an fda-approved drug for epilepsy
that's cannabis based so we do this in
collaboration with Johns Hopkins
University and the University of
Pennsylvania I'm biased I get it plants
saved my kid kind of loved the plant so
I looked for researchers who are very
very well published who had published on
the harms of cannabis as well as the
benefits of cannabis and so between my
two principal investigators there very
well published close to 500 articles
this we had a Natural History experiment
underway and an opportunity for phase
four data collection and so we're
comparing health-related outcomes of
cannabis users versus non users which is
unique about our registry we do have non
users or a control group most of the
prospective or observational studies
that are happening in this space don't
have that control group so we're looking
for trends and product views and dose
outcomes by health condition we're
evaluating those changes over time and
then we're evaluating the changes in
those who did a baseline survey who
we're not using cannabis as therapy and
then began using cannabis as therapy and
I think that's the richest dataset so
I'm going to orientate you to these
graphs real quickly so on your left hand
side is always going to be cannabis
users on the right hand side is non
users and then our p-value and/or our
statistical significance I've
highlighted there embolden there and
dark so this is all patient demographics
this dataset was locked at about two
years so we've been collecting the state
over two years this was locked at about
two years and there's 1,400 people in
this they are statistically
significantly older no real statistical
significance and race and they're and
they're more educated and that great I
did I didn't expect to see that so
that's pretty cool all patient outcome
comparisons again this is the the larger
registry we're seeing quality of life
statistically significantly improved
along with health satisfaction children
are sleeping better adults are sleeping
better anxieties anxiety is reduced and
depression is reduced so we hear these
anecdotal stories in the call center all
of the time but to be able to gather the
data use validated measures go through
the IRB process and have Johns Hopkins
statists
spit out this is wonderful for us we
don't see the medications show up yet
but we'll see that in a later slide this
is the primary medical conditions that
are in the overall registry so we're
serving mostly folks with neurological
disorder and that's due to a lot of the
national media we've been able to garner
over the last several years so you know
the first CNN special in 2013 and the
national story has been told in regards
to epilepsy quite a bit we have seen our
demographics change quite significantly
originally you know back in 2013 all
pediatric 89% and all catastrophic
epilepsy and we're now serving 65
percent adults and 35 percent children
chronic pain is a very large diagnosis
in fact in our adult population that's
just surpassed in our 50,000 families
that we serve pain is the highest that
people call in to the call center with
and then you can see some of the other
disorders there all where there are
strong mechanisms of action to indicate
cannabinoid use now this is the epilepsy
patient demographics and this is 397 so
400 participants in the study they are
slightly older and other than that the
demographics don't really show any
statistical significance so a wide
variety and many many different
diagnoses and seizure types there's 40
different seizure types and diagnoses we
see lennox-gastaut syndrome and dravet
syndrome doza syndrome which is what my
son has a car D epilepsy as a result of
traumatic brain injury
for example or brain malformation so we
see a lot of different diagnoses
represented in the registry we're
looking at cannabinoid therapy
characteristics so the vast majority of
people are using a high CBD product 38%
we do have some that are using a THC
product only 5% and I think that the
doctors who are taking care of patients
in this area you know obviously see that
as well
I was pleasantly surprised by this we
had a wonderful neurologist who did
everything that he could do for my son
in fact he made the first he was the
first neurologist to make a
recommendation back in 2012 for Zach I
for our state's cannabis license usually
you go to a doctor that's not practicing
who might just have a cannabis practice
so he did everything that he could in
this registry 23% did not have doctors
recommendations and 22% did when you're
looking at I think doctors are concerned
about folks just starting to use weed
and not using drugs specifically in
epilepsy that actually works 70 percent
of the time but we're not finding that
we're finding most people are turning to
this as a last resort 34 percent and
using it as an adjunct therapy so
they're adding it to their
pharmaceutical regimen a very small
percentage only 4% are using this as
frontline medications and 12% are using
it a second-line medication we have a
little girl named melody she has a cardi
syndrome generally a cardi has a very
poor outcome and they generally don't
walk and talk often they need feeding
tubes I just got a video of melody who
has sight words who's learned her
alphabet she's starting kindergarten
she's dancing and this was their second
line therapy they tried depakote and
then they turned right to cannabis and
so what I'm excited about elated about
is that people are turning to this
sooner they don't have to wait a decade
like we did where health outcomes are
significantly
affected for the rest of their life
Sakai will probably be dependent on us
you know into adulthood and then we've
got to figure that out afterwards so I'm
actually really excited that people are
turning to this as medicine sooner
rather than later
the reason why I did pull out the CW
hemp juice was because 61% of the
epilepsy population were using some sort
of product from CW and because it's a
regimented product we're able to see
exactly how many milligrams that is so I
wanted to give you some variances in
dosing if you attended the CME course
yesterday you learned that there's this
really really wide range and we see that
here as well this is when you turn these
into milligrams this is seven milligrams
a day up to 600 milligrams a day of CBD
the average is 2 milligrams per kilogram
and I think this is really important for
doctors to recognize because if you're
looking at double-blind
placebo-controlled trials to give dosing
for a whole plant botanical extract
where those don't met those don't match
up and so I think they start up a
dialect at 5 milligrams per kilogram and
we're seeing 20 or 25 milligrams per
kilogram so it's really important to
recognize there's quite a dosing
disparagement there people are of course
are using many different products some
are very difficult to figure out how
many milligrams they're using so a high
THC cannabis flowers the top 114 users
and so they would they would use 14
joints per day so of course that's
really difficult to figure out how many
milligrams they're using but people are
accessing what works for them which is I
think frustrating for people but
incredibly empowering to people like me
who I appreciate pharmaceutical I'm very
thankful for its role but it was a big
ball and chain for my family and I with
very severe side effects for a very long
time so the individualized medicine
piece kind of scares people the nice
part is this is individualized medicine
and you can figure out what's going to
work for you so health characteristics
we see health satisfaction statistically
significantly in
as well as children sleeping better and
adults sleeping better anxiety is
clinically improved but not
statistically significantly improved in
this population and then depression is
also statistically significantly
improved and then we don't see
prescriptions show up quite yet but we
do in a future slide healthcare service
utilization so this is economic data to
me so if they're on less pharmaceuticals
if they're going to the doctor less
emergency room visits and
hospitalizations that's a financial
burden often to Medicaid because a lot
of the families we serve have
disabilities and so we're seeing less
outpatient visits we're seeing less
emergency room visits and less hospital
admissions we're seeing a few less sick
days too although not statistically
significant now this is a relatively
small and it's 24 and in that large
registry we have an epilepsy specific
survey so we need to get more people
completing this additional survey but
hospital visits are down both
seizure-related outpatient visits ER
visits and hospital admissions we've got
the seizure activity is down so 42
seizures about 216 seizures so that's
statistically significant and then the
length of the seizure is decreased
that's about three minutes and 40
seconds to about less than two and a
half minutes so clinically significant
certainly if you've ever held a loved
one who's having a seizure and five of
these 24 reported no seizure activity in
the past month of the twenty-nine nine
users who initiated use quality of life
shows up here health satisfaction
statistically significantly improved as
well as children's sleep anxiety
statistically significantly improved
depression is off the charts there you
see prescription medications about 25
percent reduced over-the-counter
medications are statistically
significantly reduced and when asked 275
respondents this is free text so they
can just it's quantitative data they
could just type it in 50 they were asked
how has therapeutic use of cannabinoids
helped two hundred and
seventy-five respondents just typed
things in 52 percent reported reduction
in seizure activity 18 percent reported
an improvement in cognition which we've
heard from earlier speakers 13 percent
reported improved mood and 12 percent
reported a reduction in their seizure
duration when asked about harms caused
or problems associated with cannabinoid
use 64 percent typed in hey we don't
we're not having any issues but there is
a small percentage of folks that are
having issues four percent reported
increased seizure frequency usually at
initiation or at the time of a dose
increase which can level out four
percent reported a problem with cost
three percent reported consequences with
legality or concerns with legality and
then 2 percent so a very small side
effect profile GI related issues feeling
foggy or tired interactions with their
antiepileptic drugs or the stigma
associated with cannabis which
unfortunately still exists so in
conclusion this observational study was
conducted with a diverse group of
epilepsy patients cannabis therapy users
scored better on most health-related
outcomes measured compared with a
demographically similar control group
outcomes replicated and were
corroborated by the prospective study of
a sub group who were controls at
baseline and then initiated use so
that's always a little checkbox for us
to take a look at CBD products were used
by the majority of these folks often as
a last treatment choice and many cases
of substantial positive clinical and
quality of life impact for individuals
which is what our world revolves around
at realm of caring adverse consequences
are rare but they do certainly present
in a subset of participants so I think
it's important to look at that and we
definitely need a larger sample group
for more subgroup analysis so to just
pull out your one minute to just pull
out doza syndrome for example so some
limitations I definitely want to discuss
is that there are a variety of cannabis
products available and so dose
calculations fairly difficult it is a
convenient sample there certainly could
be some bias in reporting that should be
considered the data is limited
to self-reports either of themselves or
of a caregiver so there could be a lack
of objective assessment I think that's a
limitation but I think a true strength
of the study is that we're asking for a
report of current status and that's
going to minimize recall about bias and
there's really no incentive for them to
lie on the survey and certainly label
accuracy is also an issue so a special
thanks to my principal investigator ryan
van dree marcel von miller aaron and
nick joel from my team my entire team at
realm of caring we do have a booth so
please come check us out all the
participants who supported this body of
evidence and lest we forget
this isn't about cannabis it's about
community so thank you very much