[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben emerald i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
speaking of the canmed conference have
you gotten your tickets yet for
canmed2022
if yes then i can't wait to see you out
in pasadena this may for another
fantastic event
and if not what are you waiting for head
over to canmedevents.com now to get your
tickets
at cam ed 2022 you will learn from the
leading minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
and if you want proof of that look no
further than our keynote presenters
representing our science focus area we
have dr ethan rousseau presenting about
cannabis and psychiatry
representing our cultivation focus area
we have dr seth crawford talking about
innovations in hemp breeding
grace bandong our safety keynote
presenter will talk about building a
comprehensive analytical testing program
and finally dr bonnie goldstein will
discuss cannabis medicine for children
as our medical keynote
those presentations alone are worth the
price of admission but please go to kim
at events dot com to see the full
schedule
and if you want a preview of what you
can expect at kmed 2022 check out our
camed archive which is a searchable
video library of all the past canmed
presentations and panels find that at
cammannevents.com
at this year's event we are also
offering a full day pre-conference
medical practicum taking place on may
3rd
the medical practicum is led by dr
bonnie goldstein dr dustin sulak dr
kevin spellman and eloise
thiessen each of them will share the
latest medical cannabis research
including information on dosing drug
interactions and different product types
they will also share their clinical
experience they have acquired treating
patients with medical cannabis this
really is a must attend event for any
health care professionals who are
interested in recommending medical
cannabis but it's not limited to those
folks
anyone who is interested in learning
more about medical cannabis can and
should join us for this event head over
to kim at events dot com slash practicum
to learn more
of course if you can't make it to canmed
2022 we have a number of resources to
help you stay engaged with our community
and enjoy some world-class educational
content
you are already off to a good start
listening to the canmed coffee talk
podcast be sure to hit that subscribe
button so new episodes download to your
device automatically
second we have the canmed archive that i
mentioned earlier it's a searchable
video library of all the past kmed
presentations and panels that you can
find at kmedevents.com
while you're at canmedevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts that's the
best way to make sure you are up to date
on all the latest canmed news and
special offers
fourth we have our canmed community
facebook group which is a great place to
share and discuss news and topics
related to cannabis science the link to
that group is in the show description
and finally you can follow us on social
media we're on instagram facebook
twitter and linkedin just search for cam
at events
this episode i spoke with jamie brambila
who's the co-owner and founder of grace
health and wellness and heed cbd
jamie and his wife nicole specialize in
coaching and educating patients about
the clinical use of cannabinoids and
other plant-based medicines
the principal aspects of their mission
are to democratize plant-based medicine
and democratize the science taking the
complex pharmacological information and
breaking it down so everyone can
understand the therapeutic potential
at cam in 2022 jaime will present a case
study in which the combined use of
cannabis psilocybin a ketogenic diet and
conventional oncology treatments induced
remission in a stage 4 metastatic breast
cancer patient
that patient just so happens to be
jamie's wife nicole
during our conversation we discuss the
lack of awareness and training amongst
physicians about the clinical use of
cannabis the enduring stigma around
cannabis use
how cannabis can be used to treat cancer
how jamie and nicole built the
infrastructure necessary to have access
to consistent high quality
pharmaceutical grade cannabis medicines
to treat her cancer
we also talk about the barriers that
prevent other patients from accessing
that same quality consistent cannabis
medicine
and finally we discussed the
collaborative project that jamie and
nicole have assembled to take cannabis
formulations against cancer through the
drug approval process
before we get to my conversation with
jamie i wanted to thank this episode's
sponsor grace health and wellness
grace health and wellness aims to enrich
healthcare through compassion empathy
and scientific knowledge so we may turn
the corner and achieve a better age of
holistic well-being nourishing mind body
and soul
they do so by producing effective
plant-based medicines for individuals
seeking alternative therapies
learn more at grace gracehw.com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with jamie
brambila
[Music]
good afternoon jamie thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast
hi ben thank you for having me on
so i'm really excited to talk with you
today because i know you and your wife
nicole have had
an amazing cannabis journey that spans
both your professional and personal
lives
um so i think the best place to start is
for you to tell the audience about how
you got started in the cannabis field
and sort of the events that have got you
to where you are today
sure oh and first of all i wanted to
just uh
express my gratitude for being on your
podcast i think you really are doing a
great job on putting these podcasts
together for before the convention so
yeah
we got started in the uh cannabis space
back in 2016.
we had a small delivery service out in
southern california
and initially we had gotten into the
space because we thought it was a
a good business opportunity quickly we
found that that all that green rush uh
rhetoric was just an illusion
and we started um focusing on really
trying to help out people because we
started getting phone calls from people
that were in dire straits
looking for answers with cannabis
mothers that had children with epilepsy
autism people that had cancer severe
neurological disorders and so we really
wanted to
provide them with the best information
the most practical information for them
to find efficacy using cannabis
medicines
and that's kind of how we
got here
when in the middle of our research
trying to search for answers for
patients my wife nicole was diagnosed
with stage four metastatic breast cancer
and automatically you know it was a
no-brainer to
use all of the uh knowledge that we had
gained to help her uh because we knew
that can cannabis could save her life
well
so i think so you're obviously kind of
in a unique position there um having
had experience with medical cannabis and
knowing that it could be
effective for your wife's diagnosis how
did you first tackle that how did you
first apply the knowledge that you had
gained in the industry to helping her
so we we knew that uh even though it's a
pretty nascent science uh the
understanding the concept of cannabis
turning off a cancer cell
we understood enough to try to pursue
this um
you know there's no clear reference as
to what type of cannabis uh strain will
res positively response uh respond
against a
cancer cell line
so
we did our research um
you know we we placed it up to god and
and we gave it a chance and we had
excellent results as a result we were
privileged to
enjoy those results because we know that
for a lot of people that this uh
is not an option simply because they
don't have access to it
yeah and you know we always talk about
how there's sort of a number of
different variables here
in order to kind of find an effective
treatment right because first there's a
number of different types of cancer you
know you know cancer's sort of an
umbrella term that describes a lot of
different conditions and then of course
on the medicine side on the on the
strain side there's a lot of different
chemical profiles in these strains that
are all kind of grouped under cannabis
so
how did you go about you know
identifying which strains might be
effective for your particular case or
your wife's particular case
sure so we you know we were very
fortunate to have
uh people that were very knowledgeable
about
this subject around us um we have
uh we've been very privileged to have
the guidance
of practitioners that have a lot of
experience with this and
you know at the end of at the end of it
we had to make an educated guess to
figure out what to use for nicole
specifically because of all the all the
factors that you mentioned that are
involved
you know
i think that
as we go
uh further in exploring this topic we're
going to find out that there's a lot of
specificity between
you know the patient's genotype
the plant's genotype the chemotype
expression
how to bridge the gap between all those
three parameters right it almost seems
like it's individualized medicine uh
that we need to
adopt to figure this out
and so you know for us uh
it was it was just a matter of um doing
our homework um
we would focus on strains that have
really white profiles of um
minor cannabinoid groups
and uh you know
our strains are proprietary but i'll
tell you this um
there are strains that are closely
related to their wild ancestors if that
makes any sense
sure sure
so
you mentioned that you were fortunate to
have access to a lot of great doctors
who had you know experience using
medical cannabis um
what was your experience working with
other doctors who maybe weren't in the
cannabis space but you were you know in
the course of treatment telling them
that you were going to use cannabis what
was their reaction were they supportive
were they knowledgeable um
yeah that's that's a great question ben
it's actually
uh prompted us to take on our mission
really
because
we still have a medical system that
looks at cannabis regular cannabis use
as a cannabis substance use disorder
the idea
for physicians at large
to
use uh cannabis therapy
um on a consistent basis
we're still a long way to figuring that
out in the clinics we're still a long
wait for for doctors to adopt that
and from our personal experience i can
tell you that when we were trying to
look for uh the best cancer uh care for
nicole
you know we were living in southern
california at the time
we moved uh to the new york tri-state
area specifically to look for the best
cancer clinic that we could possibly
source for nicole
we had the opportunity of having an
oncologist that was a world-renowned
drug discovery
researcher very well versed in targeted
therapies
we exposed
the science to the doctor we explained
that we were using
cannabis in the context of trying to
find a solution for cancer
and you know even though she saw the
results she saw the scans with her own
eyes she couldn't explain the results
at the end of the day
you know she told us well you know
you're part of the
very few
and very lucky people that get a diagno
a result like this but i don't know
anything about the science so we still
have an old guard
in the
in the medical science community that's
still holding strong
and i really believe that it's because
of the stigma that cannabis um has tied
to it you know it even though this is
thoroughly researched in pre-clinical um
essays
we still have a medical community that
is unwilling to look at this
because they have their preconceived
notions about cannabis
yeah
how much of that do you think comes down
to like a lack of training as well
because i know that you know healthcare
professionals they're not learning about
the end of cannabinoid system in their
training correct that's that's uh that's
one of the big reasons
so we don't we don't have proper
training for
medical professionals to understand this
uh very complex system in our physiology
in fact you know we've we've done a lot
of advocacy and a lot of uh trying to
raise awareness for the benefit of
patients to
to have a an open relationship with
their physician about the use
and you know it's not um
it's not something that they can even
wrap their head around uh some doctors
believe that
you know
the endocannabinoid system or are
nowadays how we um
how we know it as the an endocannabinoid
dome
uh
is
is is too good to be true for them
in short and so
to understand such a complex system of
ligands and receptors
interacting and interacting compounds
cannabinoid mediators
you know all firing throughout our
system at the same time perfectly
choreographed to create a balance
throughout all of our physiology
it's a hard concept to bring across um
and so you know some universities are
adopting are looking at the science and
adopting courses to to educate uh people
that are willing to
to learn but it's still for the cannabis
enthusiast it's not part of a medical
curriculum yet
and so we need we need this to be
looked
as
a
as a viable uh clinical approach um
in medicine
that's the only way that we're gonna get
this into the clinics and this is a
reality that we have to grapple with if
we if we really wanna see this uh back
again in the u.s pharmacopoeia
yeah we agree 100 especially here on the
on the canmed side we're we're trying to
do our part we're partnering with uh our
good friends bonnie goldstein dustin
sulak kevin spellman and eloise thiessen
they're leading our one day medical
practicum where
we invite health care providers and
anyone who's interested to come and and
get sort of a one day
crash course master class whatever you
want to call it from you know some of
the real titans in the industry so
if there's any healthcare providers out
there who feel like they need they need
a primer on the endocannabinoid system
and all the things that cannabis can do
in the clinical setting please
definitely check that out
yeah that's that's a wonderful
opportunity that you guys offer because
you have
some of the most brilliant minds uh
giving instruction on this topic which
is you know it's a rare thing
yeah and like you said when you were
sort of early in your cannabis journey
when you were on the side of you know
being a medicine provider you you saw
firsthand that how many people
are lacking guidance for lack of a
better term and you know they know that
cannabis can be helpful for their
condition but they just don't know where
to turn
um so
i think we as a as a cannabis community
really need to do our part to help
educate those providers so that they can
so they can help their patients
right now that's such an important part
and um
you know bridging that gap of
you know giving enough information for
physicians to confidently prescribe this
to patients
we need to do a lot of work with it we
need to do a lot of work with it and you
know
the cannabis education plays a big role
having consistent and reliable supplies
of pharmaceutical grade botanical uh
drug preparations
you know it sounds like uh
letters there but
the the viability of having these
available in dispensaries we're still a
long way of uh from from having these
available to people um
at dispensaries you know they focus on
creating a cpg product that's going to
be good for the consumer that's going to
be that's going to sell
they're not looking at
you know consistent reproducible
reproducibility with chemotype
expression
so that
if a person that
uses this and is able to correct
symptoms of chronic disease they can go
back and source the same product over
and over we still have are a long way
from from
uh having access to that type of
formulation
and so we lived through that throughout
our own experience with nicole
i really want to just uh
emphasize this because we were very
lucky
to be in an industry uh to be
established in an industry to already
know
uh how to produce these formulations
and just to give you an example of all
the infrastructure that we had to build
all the know-how that we had to uh
create
all the parameters that we had to
consider
you know we had to
first we had to source the strains that
we thought were going to produce the
anti-cancer effect
we had to convince seed banks to share
their genetics with us
we had to source uh cultivators that had
the capabilities of growing these plants
in controlled environment
and that were willing to set aside a
production
space to exclusively grow these strains
for us
we had to learn sophisticated methods of
of extraction so that we made sure to
extract all the therapeutic compounds uh
from the flower
and while still maintaining uh
chemical integrity of the um
cannabinoid groups we really believe
that the acid cannabinoid groups have a
lot of potential
and you know to tie all this together we
had to figure out um
quality testing
to to really make sure that we were
getting the same chemo type expression
to make sure that the quality of the
product was always the same for nicole
and of course the clinical guidance
right you know how do you start off with
a particular dosage with a starting
dosage how do how do you titrate slowly
to avoid side effects and then how do
you make um such a
a robust cannabis regimen functional for
a person you know that those are the
those are the very critical points
that most patients do not have access to
you know right most people are not going
to build a lab to you know
uh
get consistent uh supply of cannabis
flowers to produce their own cannabis
medicines and put together all this
infrastructure it's just not
it's not uh realistic
so this is why we have to make these
available for people
yeah no that's that's amazing that you
were able to to put all that together
literally from like not seed to sale but
you know we say that term as kind of
you know
to express the whole life cycle of a
product but you've certainly done that
um
so yeah you're right i think the average
the average patient the average consumer
certainly doesn't have the resources or
the know-how to put something together
like that so
so what do they do
well so you know it's uh
it's it's a sad thing that we don't have
this available for patients because
you know we see it all the time we see
it in the infusion rooms when we see
people that are going through the
harshest of of cancer treatments
and doctors don't have the the effective
tools to deal with those side effects
yet so
we have antibiotics we have anti-pain
medication we have anti-anxiety
medication at the end of the day
it may or may not work for a patient
some patients take it diligently and you
know they become numb to their situation
you know that's the reality of the
situation
cannabis does such a great job at
getting rid of those um
those side effects and
doctors know this
you know we've we've known this since
the 80s since the 70s we've we you know
under the table
doctors will recommend to their patients
hey well why don't you try cannabis you
know maybe it'll leave some of the pain
or whatever
but really don't they don't go beyond
that um
and so
there is the sad reality is that
patients that don't have a lot of
resources to
to figure this out
don't have the best reference to
to gain the knowledge to gain the access
they look towards their medical
professionals
and they're not willing to talk to them
about this you know we we have
very few doctors that
do recognize it most of them because
they have seen positive results with
their patients and they're turned on to
it and so
you know they make a little bit time
during their really busy schedule to
to research a little bit about it
but that's just a select few so we
really need to raise awareness
so that we can give people uh
the knowledge and resources to figure
this out
yeah and that's a great point too um so
how primarily was nicole using medical
cannabis was it to sort of alleviate
some of the side effects of the other
treatments that she was using or was it
specific was it actually you know
targeted to try to actually reduce tumor
growth or or anything like that
yeah it was it was specifically so we
knew that um we we could try to use
cannabis to turn off um
cancer cells so
that was the end goal
uh to get to that point we had to
you know we had to slowly introduce her
to cannabis she
in nicole's particular situation she was
very sensitive to the effect of thc
so when you have a patient that's highly
susceptible to
to the psychoactive effect of cannabis
you have to move very carefully and very
slowly to titrate that
dosage up to the levels that we thought
were going to create an impact against
the cancer and usually these are levels
that surpass you know
400 milligrams of thc on a daily basis
or you know
the same amount and and the acid can
have in a group uh you know maybe
a thousand milligrams of cbda daily so
these are really high dosages to
uh to get a patient on
if you don't know what you're doing
you can really put off the patient with
a bad experience
so
we had to make sure that the strains
that we really understood the
therapeutic effect of the strains
whether it was a mood enhancement
profile or a mood depressing
profile that would create someone's for
example
uh we had to figure out how to
appropriately
dose each formulation throughout the day
so that we could
create this as a functional experience
for nicole
so i wonder if you could speak
specifically about the presentation that
you're going to be giving at canmed give
the listeners a little preview of what
they can expect there
sure so we we're gonna all the science
that we have uh research that we have
collected to figure out this this um
this project
uh we're gonna explain during our
presentation i'm gonna give an overview
of all the identified
mechanisms through which
cannabis can turn off a cancer cell or
create that programmed cell death
apoptosis
i'm also going to explain how we used
cannabis in combination with
psychedelics
we use psychedelics to create to
ameliorate
the depression that's really tight
to the side effect of standard cancer
therapies
and the prognosis of having a terminally
terminal a terminal disease because
metastatic breast cancer ism is a
terminal disease
we
where i'm going to explain how
psilocybin in particular has anti
possible anti-cancer mechanisms just
like uh cannabis and in fact
cannabis and psilocybin uh signaling
pathways to turn off a cancer cell
interlap
uh ironically so i'm gonna i'm gonna
speak about that
and then i'm gonna talk about uh
nicole's case study that is going
through peer review uh publication right
now
what we're doing is a result of our
experience
you know we have all this wonderful
knowledge
we've already uh solved this issue in
our minds right it's a no-brainer
cannabis needs to be in the clinic but
how are we going to do that that's
that's the biggest question so
you know i'll explain more of the
science aspect i really wanted to hone
in today and explain
the social issues that that are around
this and and how that needs to be
addressed so that we can get this into
the clinics
yeah absolutely and one of the things
that you mentioned is research right
that's one of the barriers to really
getting acceptance
from you know the greater medical
community or even you know
the society at large right everyone
wants to see more data but
the problem with that it's a bit of a
chicken in the egg situation right until
we can have you know
the legal
um
the legal framework opens up to allow
for more research we can't really
generate that data but you know so
we're in sort of this
this tough limbo right now and luckily
we have folks like you and the other
presenters at canmed who are are doing
the best with the limited resources and
support that they have to um
to try to get us there
yeah it you know it's it becomes a very
complex project because
taking cannabis
eventually what we want to do is provide
this for everybody and the only way that
we've identified that the medical
community can fully embrace this
is if we take cannabis
formulations against
cancer through the drug approval process
and that's a that's a big to do um
you know the infrastructure to to do
that is just barely being uh written
right now you know you have
fda coming up with task forces that
are evaluating projects like this on an
on an individual basis because the the
rules have not been well defined
and so
cannabis has a lot of nuances that
regular pharmaceuticals don't have to
deal with
there's a lot of heterogeneity and
the
compounds that
cannabis plant produces we're producing
from whole plant
formulations
so there's a lot of critical points to
make sure that you have sustainably
reproducible formulations
that can go through the rigor of of fda
approval
um
we we've really taken this on as our
mission
and so
we
as a result of that
we have committed to building a team
that is uh knowledgeable enough that it
has enough resources to actually take
this through the drug approval process
and so in order to do that we had to
partner up with some of the best
academic
clinical research institutions
some of the best science
research institutions in the united
states and in the uk
and you know
with a project like this you have to
you have to account for things like
stabilization of your cannabis genetics
you know uh
sustainably propagating your your plants
which probably isn't some sort of envy
true propagation
uh you have to have control uh
environment cultivation you have to have
the most rigorous uh screening methods
like a mass spectrometry analysis to
verify
that you are producing all the
chemotypes and all of your profiles
you need to have capabilities to
identify unknown cannabinoids uh because
we still don't know
100 of the content uh of for the
therapeutic compounds that come from a
particular cannabis strain
and so it's it's it's a complex process
that
traditional uh pharmaceutical
biopharmaceutical companies are really
not used to uh there is no president to
for this type of pipeline yet so we're
we're hoping to shed light on this and
really um you know be successful in in
our journey
yeah no you're right quite the
undertaking and
i know on a previous podcast i spoke
with daddy mary who's out in israel and
who's doing a lot of research
specifically on on cancer in treating
with cannabinoids and you mentioned that
you need the capability to identify
those minor cannabinoids and if i
remember correctly from my discussion
with him
some of the effective cannabinoids for
treating a particular type of cancer
that he was talking about they were
unnamed cannabinoids that you know
weren't even
really in the literature aren't
something that your average cannabis
testing lab is is looking for so
yeah i would imagine that your
capabilities on that side would need to
be pretty um
pretty impressive
that's correct ben you know luckily we
have the right people in every corner to
pull this together
uh we've partnered up with imperial
college of london uh they've agreed to
undertake our in vitro and in vivo
studies on eight of the cannabis
extracts that
we've successfully reproduced um at this
point and we we have now tracked uh
clinically
uh we've partnered up with the
university of connecticut
with
their organic chemistry department uh
molecular biology department
first to figure out um
how to reproduce the chemotype that
we're looking for in the plant
and then uh how to how to um screen for
these unknown compounds that you're that
you're mentioning we
we still are a long way
from knowing
a hundred percent
of these compounds and what they do we
haven't uh isolated most cannabinoids we
don't even know what they look like so
you know it's it is uh it's it's only
this is a project for only the most
seasoned um
scientists to participate in because
it's a a it's a discovery all throughout
uh the journey we don't we may
find out about things that we didn't
even think about it along this journey
but the commitment to to bringing these
uh medications to people is there
and we believe that we have a good shot
at this
yeah you're right and
you know i think that your story is very
um emblematic of what we're we're
talking about here in cammon because it
takes a village right you know you need
to work with the cultivators you need to
work with
the scientists the clinicians the
laboratory professionals um to really uh
make this thing happen so again that's
what we try to do in canmed is to bring
people from all the different
areas of the industry together so we can
kind of push this whole thing forward so
um i think that's a great it's a great
tie-in
oh yeah and i'll mention this ben you
know
as a cannabis uh community that's
focused on on research
sometimes we're we we clutch onto the
proprietary information that we have
right and we don't want to give you
but you know
if we just came together
and not placed our our projects um as
valuable but place the the patient
really as the valuable
as a valuable person here
you know if we could come together and
share the knowledge that we have we
could get there much easily and much
quicker than than the trend that we are
in right now
yeah i agree with that 100
um great place to stop but before i let
you go um i want to give you a chance to
share with the audience
any links to learn more about you and
grace health and wellness whether it's
social media your website or any
uh publications that you guys have done
i'd be happy to include it in the show
description so people can easily find
you
sure
please check out our website gracehw.com
we have a few articles uh that have been
published on our on the work that we do
in particular
there is a is an article on uh cannabis
science and technology magazine of an
interview that we uh recently gave
and it just pretty much describes um
uh
all the uh all the details that are that
revolve around this topic um
you know when when the day comes then
that we're able to dispense these
medications to people that really need
them
that's the day that we'll we'll be able
to ease a lot of suffering in the world
so
we'll be happy very happy to speak about
our work during the presentation at
canmed
and answer any questions uh
during the conference
excellent thanks again jamie for for
joining us on the podcast and can't wait
to see you about in pasadena
can't wait to see you guys out there
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
jamie brambila
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor grace health and
wellness
our next episode will drop april 27th
that's two weeks from today and it's our
last episode before our can mid 2022
event
again
if you haven't already bought your
tickets to canmed2022
do so now
in the meantime please do check out the
canmed archive and join the canmed
community facebook group to stay
connected with us
of course you can also stay in touch
with us on social media on facebook
instagram linkedin and twitter just
search for kim at events
sign up for email alerts on cam at
events.com to stay up to date with all
the latest news and please be sure to
rate review and subscribe on your
favorite podcast app doing so helps us
reach more listeners
i do sincerely hope to see all of you
out in pasadena this spring but until
then stay safe stay healthy and please
join us for the next canbed coffee talk
[Music]
you