good
uh thanks for having me so as a child
neurologist
it makes sense that we don't really come
into this profession with much
uh information or knowledge on cannabis
it's not part of our normal curriculum
certainly not taught in medical school
uh nor through residency
so where where do we learn this and it's
very simple as a pediatric neurologist
everything we learn that's decent
usually comes from the moms that we see
so any any of the good ideas that i've
really come across uh have typically
come from moms
i've seen some dads who've had ideas
also
i know and i'll leave it at that um
i'm a i'm a dad so i can i can get away
with that so
the the uh so my first experience here
really came from a mom who
was absolutely brilliant who came to me
with her son with autism who's
experiencing
uh significant challenges with
aggression so he was
at that time he uh he was coming to me
with reports from school he was
uh he was roughly eight years old at
that time but he was coming to me with
reports from school saying that they
were making no progress
he was having somewhere between 50 to
300 aggression aggressive episodes per
day
those would include things like biting
kicking trying to run out of the
classroom
the teachers had to wear taekwondo pads
just to protect themselves from the
biting
and his plan his individualized
education plan
was not be able to be followed it was
something that
he simply could not uh you know meet any
of the
goals that were being set for him
because the aggression overshadowed
everything else that was happening so we
talked about the standard approaches so
at that time it was a relatively uh
recent article from the new england
journal showing benefit for
respond for aggressive behaviors and
autism
the mom knew the article inside out she
she had read it and she'd reviewed it
and she had her own criticisms
which were quite good i have to say so
one of them was that it only enrolled of
49 children in the treatment arm and it
only followed them over eight weeks
and there really hadn't been and there
still aren't
very good long-term data for this this
issue
of aggression and autism is something
that is is a major epidemic
now we're seeing um when when you think
of when the autism epidemic hit
uh it was something that really picked
up 15 to 20 years ago
now we're seeing 15 to 20 year olds and
through adolescence we're seeing that
the
issues in autism do change over time so
the the young children
that we're seeing many times through
adolescents start to develop
increased aggressive behaviors this is
more commonly seen in boys
but we do see it in girls as well and a
lot of the boys who i've seen with this
had a history of of
regression autistic regression when
they're about two years old
many of them have history of epilepsy as
well
and when you look at what this does to
families
to the individual to the schools it's
it's a major challenge
it's not a minor thing at all and so
what happens with a lot of the kids
because i've seen many of these kids
who've
come from a background where they were
put on antipsychotics is the most common
side effect that you may know is weight
gain
so i can think of another patient that
came to me
who was at that time about 15
and he had gone up on through the use of
antipsychotics he had gone from about
150 pounds to
close to 300 pounds so now now he was
not only aggressive but he was
he could have actually played in the nfl
speaking he might that might be um
he could have been an offensive tackle
himself not only was he aggressive he
was a 300 pound aggressive
kid he was about six foot four 300
pounds non-verbal
he's but he's like my lovable grizzly
bear though he's a little like a grizzly
bear he he'll give you a hug
he's the sweetest kid he's got the
greatest heart but the aggressions of
course when you're 300 pounds and most
of the workers
in many of the schools that treat and
deal with children with autism
many times you see mostly women at those
schools and not many of men not many of
whom are six for 300 pounds to match
this guy
so it's frightening a lot of the moms so
that patient's mother
happened to weigh about 100 pounds uh
and when he became aggressive he would
hit her
violently uh in the head um i have other
moms
who are covering their scars uh with
makeup
and and i'm you know it's it's awful i
have moms who come to me who are afraid
to bring their kids to the emergency
room because they're afraid that their
their their husbands are going to be
suspected for for abusing them but it's
it's their sons
uh so there's there's an epidemic now of
women who are abused
by their sons with autism it's uh it
isolates a family
uh it brings massive anxiety to the
family massive dysfunction
uh can often result in divorce and then
of course in and whenever that occurs
it's it's the mother who's left alone to
cure for uh these challenges and
when you think of as children transition
towards adulthood
uh what you know what are the placements
for
a 22 year old violent or aggressive
nonverbal obese uh boy
and there really are none uh that exists
so
so we have we have a major challenge now
facing us with what happens
in the adult world so i have quite a bit
of i'm a really a pediatric
epileptologist by training
so i see and treat epilepsy that's my
specialty but
in doing so i've sort of accumulated
a large population of kids with autism
and aggressive behaviors and i had found
that my own experience in the use of
antipsychotics anti-depressants
was really limited we still faced major
challenges in terms of
improving those core symptoms and the
most important thing to note is that
the use of antipsychotics although they
had been shown in those
trials to reduce the aggressive
behaviors they really did nothing for
the core symptoms of autism
they didn't improve social relatedness
or communication
which are huge parts of what we want to
do the other the other thing too is the
increased appetite
in many kids drives because the child's
hunger is driven
you actually sometimes paradoxically
increase aggression because there are a
lot of aggressive episodes
driven towards food-seeking behaviors so
the refrigerator has to be chained
sometimes so this mom so the first mom
uh we worked together on this this was
sort of a journey it was new to me this
was in
uh she came to me in about 2005 uh when
this whole field of cannabis was very
unknown to me
uh she presented many good ideas we
started first with marinol
as as a treatment it actually worked for
a short time but
started to lose efficacy and then we
discussed
whether she could find a grower which
she did at that time
i was seeing her in rhode island at the
time which rhode island
had medical legalization in 2006 2007
in that range but we still didn't have
dispensaries that could work with
children that were open
but over time she's published the mom
has published on this so she did a
series for slate magazine
called why i give my nine-year-old
autistic son pot
and the series has now been in four
parts i recommend reading it it's it's a
great
uh description of her journey her
personal journey with this
and she's very honest it's not a
complete fix and that's not what she
presents but it's given
her family and her life the ability to
towards
something approaching normalization they
don't have to
to live in fear of those violent
aggressive outbursts every moment her
son's actually performing much better in
school
finally making progress finally
communicating and
it's it's really turned their lives
around
so as part of the experience in treating
patients with epilepsy
of course the epilepsy world really
opened up
very quickly after sanjay gupta's
documentary and the number of phone
calls was
tremendous and actually if you look at
the rates of autism and epilepsy
combined
there there's very common overlap so as
many as 25
of children with autism will have
epilepsy many kids
somewhere around 15 of all kids with
epilepsy have an autism spectrum
disorder
depending on the study you look at so
these two are shared in common
uh very commonly you see two peaks in
terms of
when these present so you have some
patients who first present with epilepsy
and later autism
that would be typical for a typical
example would be a child with
infantile spasms or dreve syndrome
that's very common to see
they have their their seizures present
at a very young age
and then you have some who present with
epilepsy much later so some who first
had autism and later epilepsy
and there's a variety of different
situations where that could occur
and so of the children with epilepsy who
were medically refractory to treatment
which is by the way roughly 30 percent
of
and so you're looking at the total
epilepsy population
in childhood is close to one percent of
which about
a third are medically refractory uh it's
kind of similar in autism too many of
them are
many the core symptoms are trying to
treat the children are medically
refractory they just don't respond to
the traditional
treatments so so there's a lot of
overlap in these conditions so as i
start to see more epilepsy patients and
i've now
treated uh in the range of about 40 to
50 for epilepsy
within that population i have
more than a handful that have also had
autism and
had poor symptoms of uh of
aggression as being one of the major
components of what we were trying to
treat
uh and of those i compiled my data which
i
had slides for you but we we're looking
at roughly 80
or more that have seen some improvement
in the behavioral aspects
not just in the seizures so it's it's
you're seeing a combined
improvement and and this is a very
important population i think to look at
for many reasons
one is that the autism and epilepsy
co-population
they share some underpinnings so it's
not these are not two separate disorders
this is really
there's one single unifying diagnosis
here and you're seeing a variety of
different diagnoses
and it becomes increasingly important to
understand what the nature of that
underlying diagnosis is and how each
individual may respond
so examples and there are many but one
of the most common examples that we look
at would be fragile x
which is really a an issue of
neurotransmitters
so amg receptor and so
in those cases in fragile x in
particular you see mouse models that
have shown
a response in terms of in terms of some
of the features of anxiety
uh to to cannabis as a treatment to
cannabidiol
as a treatment and so there may be
specific uh
therapies geared towards fragile x in
particular for other
types of conditions you have you have
mtor conditions such as tuberous
sclerosis or neurofibromatosis
another very common population that has
both autism and epilepsy
and again mtor is listed on the pathways
that we had seen earlier today
you have neuroimmunologic conditions
things like
nmda receptor encephalitis
very rare condition but there are many
other types of auto antibodies that
might contribute to both
epilepsy and autism things like
anti-thyroid antibodies or anti-gad
antibodies
and again looking at the now i mean
interestingly anti-gad antibodies gat
is an important component of gaba
synthesis
and anti-gad antibodies are causative
for type 1 diabetes which we saw earlier
today
slides of improvement in not only that
but they can also
lead to refractory epilepsy in some
patients
and so as you go through these of course
draeva or scn1a there's a fair
percentage of patients this would be
more of a channelopathy condition
sphere percentage of patients in drev
who also have autism
and it's going to become critically
important to follow those developmental
outcomes as many of them are treated for
their epilepsy
so in terms of what's needed uh for this
so
as we think about designing studies it
becomes critically important to
look at development as one of the
outcome measures
if you ask many of the parents that i
see what is the single most important
thing if i could fix one thing
i'd say more than half would say it's
not the seizure it's the development
that they'd want fixed
and so so if if we can improve
development
and seizures that would really be
revolutionary right now the medications
we have for seizures do nothing for
development
and so to have anything that would
actually improve both would be
would really be a major change so
we have to follow development in all
these studies that's not an outcome
that's currently being looked at but
it's an important one
the other thing that would be critically
important to follow would be the
importance of
eeg abnormalities so what we call spike
wave discharges that you see
on eg when you're not seeing seizures
the frequency of those spike waves and
how that translates to
developmental outcome and developmental
improvement will be another important
outcome measure to to look at
we don't have enough data there but i i
have for my epilepsy population i have a
fair number where i've done before and
after eegs
and i'm in the process of counting
spikes which is not a very fun task to
do
it's a bit laborious but it's i think
important to understand what are the
effects of the eg not just the seizure
counts
and so those outcome measures coupled
with
better detailed understanding of the
genetics and the underlying
underlying mechanisms of each child so
we can better understand
what works best for each child and
the thing i'd leave you with is that in
autism as well as epilepsy we really
each child is completely unique and is
completely individual
and so think of snowflakes in this case
and i like to think of a butterfly as a
great analogy because we hope
to see that metamorphosis and and see
the child sort of
take hold and grow wings and so
development again remains a
critical piece but each child is so
unique and so trying to determine
that individualized medication for each
child is
something that has become far more
complex
and and we can't really do that without
that understanding of their
individual biological underpinnings so
that's the uh synopsis and i did have
some
really great diagrams and slides and
pictures if you can believe me so
appreciate it
we do have a couple minutes for some
questions so if you have a question
please step up to the microphone
hi i'm kirsten velasco i just want you
to
specify when you say you have results
from
let's say clinical trials or just single
trials you say
cbd and i think all of us want to know
is this a whole plant
is it isolated 98 is it synthetic
thank you sure so um okay so
what i'm referring to in my own patients
who i've seen and treated
i've worked with the slater center uh in
rhode island uh
with so for the patients when i was
practicing in rhode island i'm still
licensed there
we worked with the compassion center
very closely primarily many of the kids
were
for epilepsy many kids initially started
with ac dc
usually in about a 20 to 1 ratio a lot
of them are now using a strain called
auto number two which is a little bit
more like a 30 or 40 to 1 ratio
of cbd to thc typically in epilepsy
we would start you know i'd say
the standard approach uh that we would
use would be to start them around a 20
to one ratio
and increase them first to you know we'd
start around
a quarter milligram per pound per day
do that for about a week or two go to
half go to
three quarters and then to one milligram
per pound per day usually as you get to
about one
milligram per pound per day you start to
see benefit but we
bring that up to somewhere in the two to
three milligram per pound per day range
for a lot of kids
it depends on the individual and then as
you get to those ranges depending on
their response you may
choose to add thc to their regimen
and so that's just a rule of thumb
approach and of course then we're
checking their levels of other
anti-seizure meds
we're following eg data and also
carefully monitoring their their seizure
control uh so i have when i talk about
data i'm just talking about my own
patients i'm trying to compile
what my own experience has been these
are the most refractory patients
and and i don't want to understate the
importance of this a lot of kids i mean
in drove a syndrome for example
charlotte treve went back
and looked at her original patients and
somewhere around 20
had died by the time they were an adult
a young adult
this is not insignificant this is a
serious serious condition
so i don't want to downplay that but we
we i have seen
uh better than 50 seizure reduction in
the majority of these patients who've
responded
literally to nothing else that's that's
ever come their way
um hi good morning as more of a lay
person and listening to you talk about
an epidemic in autism and aggression
related with autism
and its treatment could you give me an
understanding though of what
you see as the reason or basis or
causation
of this epidemic oh boy that that's like
a whole other
talk that that gets so complex i
but i would just say to simplify it
we we are a product of our genetics and
environment
and and it would be silly not to explore
both uh and
so our and our genetics is influenced by
environment epigenetics is a major
factor in in development so i i think
it it's it would be foolish not to think
that both factors play a major role for
most kids
um but as to the specific environmental
causes and we see a variety of genetic
causes
that's complex enough uh as to what
environmental factors might be out there
that's
a whole other talk
good morning the the title of your uh
talk also references legal hurdles i'm
wondering if you could spend a moment or
two
uh explaining some of those hurdles that
you had and how you surmounted them
so that and that too that's sort of a
whole other talk but i'll get into that
a little bit
so i decided to do something on autism
instead because i actually think that's
going to be a major growing area but the
legal
challenges to either epilepsy or autism
as a clinician or major
because first of all the d i have a da
license
and i can't practice or bill without my
dea license the dea is a federal agency
uh it for it's specific i'm specifically
prohibited from
recommending or prescribing any
treatment that is
a schedule one and i to do so i could
lose my license
now that means my language even though
i'm really overs or
nobody hears from the dea do we have any
agents
i i hope not so okay so before i say
this
so i can't i mean ethically how how
could i have a patient where what we're
being asked to do from the state level
is simply to say this patient
has a qualifying diagnosis and that's it
and have no discussion further as to
what specifically to try
what does to do how to introduce it what
to do with the other meds
i'm an expert in epilepsy i've seen and
treated a lot of kids with epilepsy i
kind of know how this goes in terms of
how you introduce a med how you taper
med and and how you follow levels
it would be really unfair for me to put
that part of the
management onto a compassion center or
onto a caregiver
it doesn't make a lot of sense i think
we have to be directly involved in that
process but the state
doesn't seem to think that's a good idea
for some inexplicable reason
the second thing that's really important
to me as a clinician is that the
hospitals are not on board with this at
all
hospitals also have d.a regulations they
have a lot of federal regulations a lot
of federal funding
there's zero interest in the hospitals
in dispensing or
holding or having anything to do with
any cannabis product
which means that we're forced to you
have a couple choices you could
have a patient with intractable epilepsy
and suddenly take their meds away
abruptly which as an epileptologist i
could say is not a good idea
and and really risks harming the patient
but that's what we're being asked to do
or or if i actually
actively recommend that they use it in
the hospital i would get into quite a
bit of trouble with administration
or we could do a don't ask don't tell
policy which is kind of where we've been
but don't ask don't tell it really is
not a
i mean that's a temporary measure that's
not going to play out very well over the
long term we we need something better
and nurses
and doctors need really need to know
what's going on with their patients
because they're this can influence our
other decision making if if we're not
aware of
exactly what's being given so we need
obviously we need this whole thing
corrected and a schedule change would be
a huge help to uh clinicians like myself
thank you