good afternoon everyone my name is amir
punja and i'm pleased to be here today
to
be able to talk to you about these
amazing
interesting and fascinating trichomes
that are produced on cannabis flowers
and what i'd like to do is show you some
incredible images that
if i can use the words uh awesome and
incredible
and beautiful and so on i'd like to be
able to share this information with you
today
feel free to have your cell phones ready
in case you want to take photographs of
these
amazing display of images that i'm going
to be showing you
and so here's a developing cannabis
plant this is a plant that's been grown
outdoors and the focus of this
presentation of course are the flowers
these are the flowers that are produced
at the terminal ends of these of these
particular plants
and similarly when plants are grown
indoors as you see here in this
controlled environment with lighting
the
cannabis flowers are produced in large
numbers
and uh will be ready for harvest uh in
in a very short period of time and of
course it's these cannabis flowers that
bear all of these trichomes that i'd
like to spend um the next 28 minutes or
so talking to you about
the work that i'll describe was
conducted on plants that were grown in
greenhouses and greenhouses such as this
where you see very controlled lighting
control nutrient regimes and control
growth overall and these plants are
basically going to be ready to be
harvested in about seven weeks
and just to illustrate how the cannabis
flower matures starting from when the
the lights are are switched off to give
a 12 hour for a period
over the course of three to four to
seven weeks these particular flowers or
inflorescences develop quite
dramatically as you can see here on the
bottom from about week three onwards
they increase tremendously
in size
we refer to these as flowers the correct
terminology is inflorescence which is
also used by some some individuals just
as flower buds but really what they are
are individual flowers that are
clustered together on this main stem and
i'll show you image in the next few
slides of these individual flowers
they're not true flowers in that they
don't produce petals but they have these
bracks and they have the stigmas which
are part of the the female flower
and so taking a closer look at the
inflorescence or the the flower head of
a cannabis plant you see the these
stigmas these are the female
structures that are going to be
collecting pollen uh if there's going to
be fertilization and i'll show you a
scanning electron micrograph of that so
this cannabis flower is pretty much a
cluster of individual smaller flowers
so these stigmas then as you see here
have these hair-like projections
and if you were to place pollen grains
as we did in this experiment you can see
the pollen grains germinate and they
will fertilize this particular stigmatic
surface and form seeds which is not
something we want in cannabis but we do
in hemp
in cannabis of course we cultivate just
the female flowers so there wouldn't be
any pollen germinating on these
particular on these particular stigmas
these are the plants that i showed you
earlier in the greenhouse this is week
seven ready for harvest you see the
stigmatic structures that are formed
here on the on the surface of the flower
and at harvest or after harvest these
are uh dried in this matter hung upside
down for a period of about five days at
which time then the flower buds will be
removed and they'll be ready for
packaging and shipping off for
use for medicine or recreational or
extraction
sometimes the flower buds are removed
prior to the dry and they're placed on
these trays and and put into a drying
room where then they'll be dried for
five days at which time these are then
ready for packaging up and shipping off
to to market
so this is what we refer to as the buds
which is the
essentially broken down inflorescence
that i showed you early on
now when the cannabis flower approaches
maturity those stigmas that i showed you
earlier take on sort of an orangey brown
color which indicates they're ready for
harvest but more importantly than that
you notice these trichomes these shiny
pinpoint like structures that are
covering the surface of the
inflorescence leaves and the bracks this
is the material that obviously that's
going to be
manufacturing and containing all of the
cannabinoids the thc the cbd and the
terpenes and that's the focus of my
study is to study the development of
these various trichomes on the cannabis
flower
so this is the cannabis bud in its in
its glory uh this is obviously ready to
be to be used for for recreational
purposes
you see the dried up stigmas here these
orangey brown structures and then of
course are the the trichomes which
you'll see close-ups off here uh in the
in the next in the next few minutes
so that was the focus of my work is to
study in detail what these trichomes
look like
here's a light uh
microscope image you can see again these
these spiny projections these other
trichomes they're they're produced on
these stocks you'll see close-up images
of these talks
when i go through my my slides
and most most producers will have seen
this
as they examine their their plants over
over a period of time so they're quite
obvious the trichomes are quite obvious
but what we wanted to do was to use the
scanning electron microscope this is a a
piece of equipment that actually
magnifies these trichomes considerably
when you look at the images on the
screen they're probably magnified over
100 000 times and this allows you to
really study detailed structure of what
these can
cannabis trichomes look like
now the scanning microscope is used
as shown here this is the the large
equipment various parts of it sample is
inserted into this chamber and the
images that are being produced can be
captured here on these computer screens
and then downloaded and saved and used
in presentations like the one i'm going
to show you today so this is what a
scanning electron microscope would look
like and within the machine itself
is the sample this is a tiny piece of
brack tissue that has trichomes
we coat this with gold or palladium very
very fine layer to allow these
electrons that are produced to be
scattered and emit images so the
electrons originate from an electron gun
and eventually what happens is the the
electrons that are released are detected
in the electron detector or images are
sent over to the screen where we can
then visualize what's going on in this
particular chamber
so i'll show you a couple of images done
by other researchers
where they looked at pollen grains these
are pollen grains of different plant
species you notice the very very fine
detail these spine-like structures the
size the shape all different in these
various different plant species but
notice how clear
and three-dimensional these particular
images are
and similarly if we use uh red blood
cells the red blood cells in your body
and my body
these are the platelets you can see sort
of a pancake shaped structure these are
magnified many many many times to show
you the actual
appearance of red blood cells in the
electron microscope
and so we wanted to use this technique
to study not just trichome development
but to look at things like trichome
density maturation and quality
and how potentially these various
features could be used to assess things
like thc and cbd that may be produced in
this particular plant
so once again this is the inflorescence
the entire structure
we're looking at very very small pieces
as you see here magnified over on the
right and these tiny spicules that you
see here are the trichomes that we're
now going to magnify in the scanning
electron microscope
and here's the first image this is the
trichomes the glandular trichomes that
are born on stocks as you see here this
is the surface of the the bract or the
leaf tissue this is a mid vein and you
can see how these trichome
glands or trichome heads appear under
the scanning electron microscope
now here's another image it shows you a
different type of trichome these are the
the the non-glandular trichomes what we
call the hairs
in the background these these structures
these little smiley faces these are the
stomata these are involved in
photosynthesis
excuse me this is how the plant takes up
carbon dioxide releases oxygen in
photosynthesis
these are other types of trichomes
called bubbles trichomes the trichomes
that i'm going to focus on are here
these large glandular circular
structures that we'll spend more time on
i'll show you a few close-up images of
these these hair-like structures
particularly on a leaf
this is a cannabis leaf that has many
many of these
non-glandular spines or hairs and you
can see
they do have a protective function they
will protect against insects and various
other other forms
but notice too that the leaves do have
these
globular round structures which are also
the the um sessile
trichomes that we'll we'll speak to in a
few minutes
a close-up if you're an insect this
would be a pretty dangerous territory to
enter into because of these these
various hairs that are meant to protect
the plant from attacked by by various
types of organisms and they're it's
quite effective
so back to the trichomes these are the
trichomes that the glandular trichomes
that we'll spend some time studying
these are the spiny projections that we
just saw that are most likely serving a
protective function
now these trichomes the heads of these
trichomes you can see
here in this image that is of a dried
cannabis flower or or a bud and you can
see how nicely they are distributed over
the surface of this particular sample uh
very uniform very nice and circular this
is a good sample this is a sample that
has probably the optimal amount of thc
and cbd and terpenes
here's a close-up of these
magnificent
trichome heads
and you can see they're surrounded by a
cuticle
these are individual uh individual
trichome heads
and i'll show you a close-up of the the
trichome head
sitting on the surface of a bract of
leaf you can almost visualize these
these miniature hot air balloons if you
wish that are starting to accumulate thc
and cbd
and all of this manufacturing is
occurring within the trichome
head itself the various enzymes are
produced and are working here within
within this particular structure
it's quite a magnificent site and the
next image that i'll show you is even
more magnificent because it shows you
now this particular tricom tricom head
is raised on a stock
and these stocks are very important in
not only pushing the trichome head
above the surface of the leaf but also
it's associated with maturation and
accumulation of various types of
cannabinoids so those of you working in
the medical field those of you using
cannabis for various purposes and using
it to make food or produce various types
of extracts this is the image that i
want you to visualize of this
magnificent trichome head that's sitting
on the surface of a stock
that's manufacturing all the materials
that this particular conference is all
about the thc the cbd various
cannabinoids and of course terpenes
i like to make an analogy of that
particular trichome
head to a lamp a lamp that's been
powered by electricity and the larger of
course the size of the bulb that you
place in here the larger is going to be
your amount of light that's emitted the
energy in a cannabis trichome comes from
the bottom of the plant the
photosynthesis that's being pushed up
and then the size of course of the
trichome head is going to illustrate how
much light or how much thc you're
actually going to be producing
so much so that an artist that i met a
few years ago was able to draw out these
particular trichome glands
on a stalk such as this and visualize
the light source emitting from a
trichome head and this would be the the
cannabinoids the thc and the cbd it'd be
a wonderful site to see these on our on
our streets
so here it is again uh these magnificent
structures on these stocks these other
trichome heads then that are going to be
producing these various types of
cannabinoids these are the small
bulbas trichomes that i talked about
that we don't really know what they're
they're doing so we're going to spend
most of our time now focusing on these
structures here
back in 2005 there was evidence
presented that the enzymes involved in
the manufacture of thc and cbd and
various other
terpenes are actually produced within
that globular structure which i'm
referring to as the trichome
trichome head so it's really a miniature
factory if you wish that's synthesizing
these very very important chemicals
so much so that you can visualize as
this trichome is being developed
the energy that's coming from the
epidermis and other cells in the plant
is being used to drive the manufacturer
of these cannabinoids within this
particular glandular structure that's
shown here
and then as i mentioned there is a stalk
that develops and this is very much
similar to a mushroom you can almost
visualize this mushroom gland starting
to form and the the stock cells are
derived from the epidermis
the layers of the leaf and so you can
see it pushing itself up
and as it gets
larger and more mature these stalks
continue to grow they grow upward
as the flower matures
and over time they get fairly large as
you see here these are all the cells
of the epidermis of the leaf cells that
have been used to form the stock this is
the large glandular head that's now
accumulating various types of
cannabinoids it's quite a quite an
impressive it's quite an impressive
structure
and here's a close-up this is now the
fully formed uh trichome head that's con
that contains all of the thc and
cannabinoids and various other things
that we want to use for medicine and
recreation here's the stock and you can
see it's attached here to the trichome
head
we looked at the development of these
stocks and the size of the trichome
heads over time and as the flower
matures going from three weeks to six
weeks what you see of course is an
increase in the in the length of the
stock and you also see an increase in
the size of the head that's being formed
on top of the stalks so maturation is
associated
with an expansion of the stock and an
expansion of the head
sort of like that hotter balloon that i
talked about
and so just to summarize then these uh
trichomes that we talked about they're
called capitate trichomes they're found
on both sides of the bracks the upper
and the lower they're circular in shape
surrounded by a cuticle and as the
flower matures these stalks begin to
elongate and the size of the head starts
to increase
this is a slide that illustrates there's
way more trichomes on the underside of
the bract than there is on the top i'm
not sure what the significance of this
is but you can see clearly there's way
more of these trichome heads here than
they are on the on the surface of the
of the um of the tissue
so we did some experiments where we
actually monitored and counted how many
of these trichome glands are actually
being produced and these are two
different strains and everywhere you see
these dots just signifies the the
location of these various trichomes and
you can see there's differences between
strains in terms of how many trichomes
are being produced
and this data is illustrated in a graph
form here
this is the number of trichomes over
time as the flowers mature the number of
trichomes goes up as you see to a
maximum at about seven weeks
and this just illustrates here the
underside
the underside of a trichome of a leaf
has way more trichomes than the upper
side as you see here so there is there
is a pretty significant difference on
whether you're looking at the the upper
surface of the lower surface
now there are some of these uh trichome
stocks that are absolutely crazy uh
here's one that is that is humongously
long uh there's another one right there
i'm not really sure what the
significance of this is but you can see
it's a it's a huge tricom stock compared
to some of the the other ones in the
background and whether there's a
significance to this or not i don't know
but
but the the importance of the stock is
that it's an indication of maturation of
those particular trichomes
so much so that this important study
that was published three years ago by
livingston and others demonstrated that
as these stocks get longer
the amount of terpenes and the amount of
cannabinoids that is that are produced
in the in the actual heads themselves
is increased significantly there's a
significant increase in the manufacture
of these terpenoids and cannabinoids as
a result of elongation of the stocks and
the reason for that is that as the
trichome stocks begin to grow
so do the number of secretory cells the
number of secretory cells that you see
here at the bottom of these trichome
heads the numbers go up
so that as the the stocks begin to
elongate and you have trichomes that are
maturing you have more of these
secretory cells that are producing all
these cannabinoids which is shown here
in this in this light blue color so this
is the thc and the cbd produced within
these glandular structures and here are
the stocks the stocks that we looked at
a few minutes ago
so quite a fascinating
developmental change over time
the other thing that happens as the
trichome
heads mature is that you can see a
difference in fluorescence under uv
light so when you shine uv light here on
the right you can actually pick out
where these glandular heads are as
opposed to where you have normal visible
light
and the reason for that is that these
trichome heads of course contain
cannabinoids which fluoresce at a
wavelength of around 430 nanometers and
so you can actually pick out these
individual trichome heads as shown here
and this was also demonstrated in this
paper that i described by by livingston
so here's a close-up of one of these
trichome heads here the secretory cells
you can see on the outside and they're
pumping out
these cannabinoids that are accumulating
in this hot air balloon as it starts to
develop and you can see here the stock
that the um the head is attached to
now this is the the base of the
uh or the top of the actual stock you
can see here this is where the the
trichome head was attached and in the
next image i show you a cross section
through this particular stock that shows
you it's it's consists of these various
cells so these are the cells that make
up the stock and this is this is where
the nutrients the photosynthetics are
going to flow
through the stock up into the trichome
head to provide energy for the
manufacturing of these various
cannabinoids it's quite an amazing
process
and here's the other side this is the
underside of the actual head and this is
where the trichome stock would attach
to the bottom of the of the trichome
head
this was illustrated quite nicely in
this paper that was published a few
years ago it indicates where the stock
is actually being attached to the
underside of the trichome head and you
can see right here the point of
connection
where the stock ends and the the head is
starting to form
and we can show that in this schematic
representation where you've got the
trichome head with the cuticle these are
the secretory cells that we talked about
these numbers go up as the length of the
trichome
stock increases and this balloon
structure starts to increase
the accumulation of various types of
cannabinoids
so here's a underside view of the
secretory cells you can see them right
here and they're all secreting various
cannabinoids that are filling this
particular
balloon or cavity over
time and here's a
a dried
cannabis
trichome stock as you see here with the
actual
trichome head still attached and you can
see you can almost visualize the
contents here which is obviously all the
the cannabinoids and
terpenes
now these things do become detached many
of you know that you can collect these
various
tricum heads and use it to make things
like hashes and so on you can see the
point of attachment of the stock
these things come off and here's another
illustration where it's come off from
the stock and now you've got your entire
tricom head that contains all of these
cannabinoids in it again very similar to
to a hot air balloon that's that's
become detached
so just to summarize the stock
development is an important part of
maturation uh when these stocks start to
develop you start to see tremendous
increase in the accumulation of these
various cannabinoids
what causes the stocks to elongate we
don't know why are some stocks longer
than others we don't know and why are we
why do we have more
trichomes on the underside of a bright
as opposed to the upper surface we're
not sure so there's still a lot of
research that still has to be done to
try to resolve these various aspects of
trichome development
and of course the heads do dehist the
process of the
the um glands coming off is called the
histance and of course uh if you if you
harvest these things and cause damage
then these trichome heads can break
off here's an example of a good sample a
sample that's well preserved you can see
all the trichome heads are still
attached this is a dried cannabis flower
and this is a flower where there's been
some abuse or not well taken care of and
you can see where all the heads have
broken off
leaving much less thc and other
cannabinoids in this particular sample
so have to be careful when we handle
these cannabis flowers
so the last thing i'd like to talk about
is the maturation
there is a phase where the trichomes
literally undergo a maturation or
senescence process and this is
accompanied by the accumulation of a
brown color within the the trichome
heads themselves and so we wanted to
study this under the electron microscope
here's the mature trichome head you can
actually see
little droplets of exudate starting to
form this is where now the resin is
starting to become pushed out of the um
the trichome head itself
and we can actually see that because
what happens is that when the resin
comes off it causes the surface of the
trichome head to become sticky and so
these little heads start to stick to one
another as you see here
and those of you that have handled
cannabis flowers that are developing you
know the sticky residue that's what's
being secreted out of those trichome
heads
and here's a close-up this bulging this
is the resin that's being actually
pushed out
through the through the head through the
cuticle
and here you can see actually the
exudate actually dribbling down
pouring down from the actual trichome
head itself it's it's quite quite an
amazing
view when you look at it here under the
scanning microscope
and what happens of course is because of
the sticky nature of the surface you
have what i consider these hot cross
buns
these trichome heads sticking together
as a result of the resin that's being
produced
and here again you get these large blobs
this is all because of resin that's come
off these strike heads have stuck to one
another to form these blobs and here's
another indication of that these are
large structures that are caused by the
exudation of that resin
and this happens at at maturity
and again just a low power shot to show
you the the sticking together of the
trichome heads as a result of secretion
of resin
the other thing that happens of course
is there is this process of senescence
which i consider aging this on the right
is a trichome that's starting to age on
the left is a trichome that's still
fairly fairly young in the developmental
process
and when you take a look at these aging
trichomes the actual heads themselves
you notice there's a wrinkling of the
surface of the cuticle almost like a
sort of a prune
shaped image as you see this is a very
very high powered magnification picture
this is what happens over time the
resonance material starts to condense
to form this cakey-like substance
and then over time it looks like this
this is a completely senescent or aging
trichome
head that has the resonance material
just completely sort of collapsed and
and baked down on the surface of the
trichome
and you can see this uh close up this
entire wrinkling is all the resonance
material the cuticle is broken off and
this is an older
aged
mature
trichome
head that's shown
any when you take a low power image of
this particular
view what you do see is
that these trichome heads that have
senesced or old can be seen here as the
shriveled up images
so again just to summarize droplets of
resident resin are released from these
trichome heads
causes them to become sticky
and it results in the formation of these
various blobs and the resin then causes
these particular trichome heads to
collapse which is basically the last
phase which is the the senescence
here's an example of a good
sample on the left where the trichome
heads are all intact on the right is a
sample that isn't uh processed very well
the trachum heads have broken off
there's very few of them left
the scanning microscope can actually
show you differences in quality between
a good sample on the left and a poor
sample on the right
the other thing that can be done
something we're looking at now before i
end is is using computer assisted
technology to determine the numbers of
trichomes on cannabis flowers and the
various types of maturation
phases so what we've done here is
circled the various trichome heads
whether they're mature in the red
whether they're immature in the white
and then the mature ones in between
which are the blue
and so using these computer enhanced
systems we can almost tell where
these various trichome heads are and how
many they are in a very very short
period of time and that's something that
we'd like to work on to demonstrate
how computer assisted technology can be
used to assess maturation of trichomes
so i'll end here with some images that
are generated through this computer
assistance method
these circles illustrate where the
trichomes are located you can see the
differences between these two samples
here's another image generated by the
computer that shows you the various
types of trichomes that are found
and then finally
this one that illustrates the senescence
mature trichome glands that are shown in
brown uh compared to the previous so i i
think this this image analysis using
computer technology is going to be very
important for us to decipher trichome
numbers and maturation
so finally uh trichomes are fascinating
structures i hope i've shown you some
amazing images to illustrate that
lots of things we don't know what what
initiates uh their development is their
effect of light other signals
why do these starcom stocks develop to
various extents
and can we use this kind of technology
to assess
trichome development and optimal time of
harvest that would be very very
important from a commercial perspective
various individuals have contributed to
this research various funding agencies
and various people have helped me with
collection of this these various images
so i hope what i've done with this
presentation is show you some of the
spectacular uh images of cannabis
trichome development and the various
things that go on that i think are going
to be commercially extremely important
um i'm sorry i wasn't able to attend the
meeting here um i hope this
this presentation will give you some
ideas for for thought
if you have questions please send them
along i'm going to be at my computer
right now as we speak you can send me
emails at punja p-u-n-j-a at sfu.ca and
i'll be happy to take questions answer
these either right away or any time when
you've had time to digest this
particular information
thank you for your attention and i wish
you all the best in the rest of the
conferences thank you