so
the spot you never want to have
is the last lecture of the day in the b
room
but here we are
and i'm honored that you're here uh so
let me uh let me walk you through a
little story here about um
ethanol extractions of cbd so clearly
there's a huge number of home gardens or
one of the areas where i got my biggest
education on
cannabis those home gardens were
actually home forests
of cannabis trees
and as a result of all this legalization
a lot of people are making stuff at home
and so
one of the things that
i've always at being an herbalist first
and then getting into cannabis so for me
cannabis is yet another medicinal plant
a special one but another one
you know i've been making tinctures
forever
and the medical scientist side of me was
like well
you know what's in these things so
start with this story so
back in the days when i was in between
university of exeter in the uk and
university of north carolina i was
working on echinacea and i drilled down
really hard for four years on echinacea
and um
one of the things i was doing i kept
extracting a bunch of different economic
echinacea angustifolia echinacea
purporia echinacea palada like all these
different species that are out there in
the market and by the way most of it is
purporia
and then there some research came out uh
just about the time i was starting my my
uh dissertation work
on
achillamides or alkalamides there's
uh you'll see you'll hear you'll hear
both pronunciations binding to cb2 so
suddenly echinacea was like you know a
cannabis medic or a phytocannabinoid you
could argue that but you know there was
a compound in there or actually several
compounds
these compounds that would bind cb2
i once had the owner of an herb company
come up to me and say
hey if i take echinacea is it going to
keep me from getting high
no don't worry it's that's not going to
happen
but so i started looking at these
compounds and i like i said i drill down
pretty heavily on them and
you can't see the way they're shaped now
but if you if you saw machulin's lecture
today when he was talking about all
these amides
you can see that that tail can fold and
you know
form kind of a partial ring it's not
really a ring but it's an open ring
right and so these bind cb2 rather well
and so one day i'm in the lab and i'm
tincturing yet some more echinacea so i
can run mass spec analysis on it and
then put it in biological assays
and i go to i tincture it i go home i go
to bed and i wake up in the middle of
the night and i go oh my god i just
missed an opportunity
because there's always been this
discussion in the industry
the medicinal plant industry is how long
do you have to macerate or steep
plant material and alcohol before it's
ready
and the traditional wisdom has been oh
two weeks is good and four weeks is even
better
and i used to have a close friend who
ran an herb company would say oh i do
stuff that's three months and it's even
better than the one month and i've done
six months and it's it just
just rocks
and so i've always been a little
skeptical and if you ask any chemist and
i know there's probably some chemists in
the room right now
they were they're rolling their eyes
right now
because because they already know know
better right
so um
so i woke up the next morning went right
into the lab when i took a sample of
this tincture that i had planned on ting
shrink for two weeks
okay so i got it at about 24 hours time
point
and
this publication is what came out of it
and this data was buried in a bunch of
mass spec data so nobody really saw this
data
i forget which which figure it was but
it was well into the map manuscript and
most people their eyes roll back by the
time they get to table two and they're
you know in figure figure three and
they're done um but you can see here day
two in other words 24 hours later
you can see that the the relative
concentration of
uh dodeca tetra tetraene
this alkalamide is
really kind of peaking
and you look at day seven
and you know there's really no
difference
and you look at day 14 two weeks which
is what we're supposed to do in the
industry and and by the way in the
industry
you've got barrels and barrels and all
these herb shops all these are
production facilities filling floor
space
because it's sitting there for weeks
um and then so i was like well and let's
make sure we go 21 days so that we can
show that there's really no difference
like i said the chemist in the room are
going yeah yeah what what's what's the
news here but the herbalists in the room
were blown away
right or not in this room but or maybe
you are already but um
when i
showed you the data i'm about to do um
you're going to be really quite
surprised so i went to the literature
and i said to myself self can i find any
bet anything better than 24 hours
and
found a couple of studies now they
weren't on cannabis but you know they're
pulling compounds that have some
lipophilicity to them
in this case we're looking at carnosol
and carnosic acid
and you know at
uh
in ethanol at 70 percent versus ethanol
at 100 percent
and then they've got a methanol in there
i typically ignore that because we're
not going to use that to make tinctures
right
hopefully
so you see that really at three hours
there's not a lot of difference between
six hours but six hours it really kind
of peaks and there's not really much
difference between six hours and 10
hours so now i'm going okay so we've got
something close to three hours and we've
got something close to six hours so how
many hours do we really need
um so here's another study and again
three hours in this particular case our
carnosic acid there's no difference
so
then i went to the cannabis literature
and i i looked at some literature and
there are there are some
tincture literatures out uh
research out there
but you know here
this one actually is really new i think
this is uh actually no sorry this is the
2008 one um they looked at 20 40 80
ethanol um and by the way before we
i think most people when they're
tincturing with ethanol they're usually
using 100 percent
and that's what we did and i'll tell you
why in a second but
um if you really want a full spectrum
extract
you're probably going to want to use
lower than 100 percent
now what will it cost you it'll cost you
some
small percentage of thc or thca
because of their lipophilicity but
you're also going to get more flavonoids
that way you're probably going to get
more terpenes that way
you know 80 70 to 80 percent tends to be
the sweet spot with a lot of different
compounds especially uh polyphenols
um and you know we see that here for the
most part in terms of
distribution of thc and thc
a
so
then i said let's take this to cannabis
and check it out so here's what we did
so we we took up a batch of cannabis and
this is hemp okay so cannabis sativa the
chemotype is cbd right
and we used a 400 um micron sieve
so
kind of
a coarse
grind
and uh homogenized that and when we got
done with homogenizing i homogenized it
some more because i knew this that the
whole thing had to depend on that
starting biomass it had to be mixed
really really well so we mixed it and
mixed it and mixed it
then we took 100 grams samples
collected
and added 500 grams of 95 ethanol
to that so that's going to steep so the
maceration treatment started but then we
also had an arm and i'm realizing now i
have that arm in the wrong place but we
also took
and did some percolation i'm going to
show you that data in a second but i
really want to focus on the maceration
right now so those of you who don't know
percolation i'll explain that process in
a second but i wanted to
try two different traditional
home used techniques the maceration and
the percolation
and then we went through a couple more
steps we we took we collected the mark
the mark if you're not familiar with
herbal medicine the mark is the the
plant material the biomass
and then you would press that mark
right and then you you'd get uh
the
the press from the mark and you'd also
get the pour off the liquor that you
poured off the the tincture and i'll
show you these steps if this doesn't
make sense just yet and and so what we
did is we did duplicate independent
duplicate
extracts and then we took triplicate
samples from each of those duplicates
and then we did triplicate
analysis of the triplicate samples
so
trying to really stick with with
some good statistics because i knew that
the herb industry would never believe me
so there's the cannabis
and this is the bio starting biomass
like i said we mixed and mixed and mixed
and here's what here's where we ended up
so it was about uh
about a eight point five percent your
average is eight point eight uh four
percent
um
cbd
and you can see our p-value is pretty
strong there
and then we ran it through the sieve a
four micro uh four micron or four
thousands gives me micron uh civ
and
um
so we had consistency and then to really
mimic home extractions we took ball jars
which is usually what herbalists use and
i've used forever and
and uh
fascinatingly my house used to be so
full of ball jars and then
and then when i partnered with a lovely
woman um i kind of let go of the ball
jars and now my house is full of jars
again because she can't
i'm just like those jars are menacing me
in the in the
dishwasher because i'm the guy that
deals with the dishwasher right
so then after we tinctured
we poured off the liquor or often called
the menstruum in herbal medicine
we poured that off
and then we took the mark which is in
wrapped in the um
the cheesecloth there
and we pressed that
and we bought a press that was easily
available so usually you have these high
top like five ton presses that you use
that are like car jack kind of things
well we just bought this wine press off
of amazon i think it was 74
so that we had something that was really
readily available and wasn't super
expensive
and you know actually it did okay i mean
there's presses it'll do much better
but it did okay
so we pressed the mark
and
you'll see on the left side of the
screen that's what we poured off from
the ball jar okay and on the right side
of the screen is now the
remaining liquid that was in the biomass
that got
pressed out
and there's a molecule we were looking
for cannabidiol now this cannabis was
decarboxylated
and so here's what we got
at three minutes
versus one hour versus two week
so in one hour
this extraction was done
and like i said the chemist in here
going yeah yeah
are you going to tell me something i
don't know yet
but at three minutes we had 94 of the
one hour
so
it always made me wonder because this
quick wash technique that you hear about
right cold wash
the cold wash or a quick wash
um
you know that's
faster than three minutes so
i would guess but i'd like to do this
study i would guess that they're
probably getting pretty high
uh yield
and then if you can compare the drain
versus the press cbd
and this is the problem that people have
at home pressing
right because what are you going to do i
mean some people take the cheesecloth
the plant materials wrapped in the
cheesecloth and they just turn it and
squeeze it right that's one way to do it
and you ca and you want to do that
because look at the amount of
cbd we got from the press
although it was much lower volume
the amount that we got was actually
pretty significant so you always want to
press and
it's not hard to do
um and then we looked at the mark so
this is the mark after it's been pressed
now if you looked at this you would
argue that it looks to me like that
two-week mark has got less cbd in it and
therefore it probably should have had a
higher yield
but it actually didn't
according to the data that we have
so did we lose some cbd somewhere
i don't know
but i'm still scratching my head on this
one
and actually i don't think these i don't
have the stat bars in here but i don't
think this was statistically significant
in terms of the one 1.16 to 0.98 so it
also may be a factor here
okay now let's turn to the percolation
okay so now what have we learned the one
thing that i really want you to get is
there might be a reason to run a
tincture for
longer than an hour or even i'm guessing
half an hour is enough but that's
another study there might be a reason to
do that but it's not chemistry
okay so people get into the moon cycles
and that so yeah great if that's what
you're into maybe that's the way to do
it right for your medicine the for the
medicine you want to give to people but
for chemistry
you don't need two weeks you don't need
a month
you just really need a few minutes
so
now how do you make a percolation con so
percolation cones they're in old
pharmacies you can still find them out
back in the back shelf hidden
with dust all over them because they
haven't been moved in like 40 years
but old pharmacies this is one of the
ways that we made medicine in the united
states that pharmacists made medicine in
the united states for
decades and decades is they would get a
big percolation cone and by big you know
they were
they were this size the one
the ones that i know of um and they're a
cone right and so there's
the trick here is the liquid flow
through that cone
because you've got moving liquid which
is one of the things you want you know
that's something i should tell you about
maceration every one of those
macerations were
stirred vigorously for one minute
and then the timing
started so in the same sort of way we
have movement here and movement is
important one of the things i was
talking about yesterday with extractions
is you know there's really four
crucial factors one is solvent one is
temperature one is pressure and one may
be agitation right so this is a sort of
agitation a movement
so
how do you make a percolation cone out
of a period bottle well you score the
top of it and herbalists have been doing
this forever you score the top of it and
now you have an opening at the top
and you
hang on to your cap
the um
the cap that you would use to close it
and that becomes a stop [ __ ] that
becomes a way of controlling your rate
okay
and so we ran that percolation and
there's been an age-old argument between
herbalist about what's better maceration
or percolation the thing about a
percolation is it only takes um
usually a couple of hours
so a couple hours and it's done and if
you're doing percolation right if you if
you go and you read the united states
pharmacopoeia from way back when that's
the way they were making medicine they
tell you to take the the biomass
and
just
really moisten it not it's not in liquid
it's just moistened with ethanol
and so if you think about that one of
the things that does is it breaks down
the cell walls
so once you do that then with that moist
stuff then you pack the cone and that
pack is key
if it's too loose it's just going to run
the liquids just going to run through
and if it's too tight the liquid is not
going to run so you get people get
really that do this for a living get
really good at packing these things
so
here's what we've got and we're
comparing it to the two-week
comparison here um so liquor recovery
was about 67 that's a total liquid that
we got right so the liquor recovery is
about 67 percent
um in the first extraction about 72 in
the next extraction in the perk it was
higher all around 76 and 74.
keep in mind that we actually tried to
press
the mark that came from the perk
we got zero milliliters from it
because it was already so dry so this is
another advantage not only do you not
need a press
but you can just
you've collected all the liquor that
you're going to possibly get from a
percolation cone
and then if we look at cbd recovery and
that's the darker gray there that you
want to look at
um the perk one we got about eighty
eighty percent 79.2 and park two we got
about 81 percent
as compared to about 61 versus 65 now
keep in mind this is not 61 cbd
this is 61 recovery of the cbd
right so we started with about 8.8
milligrams we got 61 percent of that
and then there's your your graph and i i
compared it here on the graph a one hour
versus a
versus the percolation and you can see
it's really
significantly uh higher i mean you got
about 15 percent more cbd in that
percolation
shorter time period doesn't take up a
bunch of space
so
future directions for this one of the
things i'd really like to do is i'd like
to do a quick wash comparison to a short
maceration just to see what's going on
there i'd also like to experiment with
percent ethanol
and i say that not so much because
i'm interested in the cannabinoid yield
although i am i'm more interested in
being able to look at the polyphenols
and comparing the polyphenol
content at 100 percent which is what
most people are using for their uh
cannabinoid extracts versus like 70 or
80 percent
and then i'd like to do
some studies with hot ethanol with cold
ethanol and then room temperature
ethanol in both a percolation method and
a maceration method
and that's it
ethan
kevin a couple of quickies it was quick
i didn't uh gather what the temperature
was of the ethanol you were using
room temperature okay
so um say you were using fresh material
rather than dried wouldn't it make sense
then to use the high proof ethanol
oh absolutely so and that's i thought
about showing some data like that from
uh some other work i've done
yeah if you if you're using fresh plant
material so
uh let's talk this through for a second
so i noticed that we did a one to five
this is traditional dry plant right
one to five and some people now we're
doing one to threes just to make things
stronger but
so one part is plant material five parts
is the um
uh the the solvent the the menstruum
when you use water
depending on what part of the plant you
are you've probably got somewhere
between 85 to 95
water content
so
we say in the industry that fresh plants
should be one to two
but if you really do the math there it's
really about a one to eleven
so
dry plant ends up being
chemically stronger there may be reasons
for example enzymatic action
in the drying process that breaks down
compounds
for doing a fresh plant versus a dry
plant
but
fresh plant even though it's one to two
with that ninety percent water content
right
is not really one to two
more like one to ten one to eleven
stupefied i see
it was amazing
yeah sure so if it's uh let's go back to
what the the percolation cone looks like
so if you're doing this right
and
doesn't have to be done this way but if
you're doing this right with the old
percolation cones they were really tall
so that you could pour all the solvent
or minstrum in there
and so you were done you could walk away
now with smaller bottles like perrier
you can't necessarily do that because
you don't necessarily depends on how
fault how full you fill the bottle with
the with the plant material
you can't necessarily do that
because if it's too full you're just
gonna have to stand there and keep
feeding it
right but if if if you get a proper
percolation cone and they're hard to
find and they're really expensive
you can
just pour it in and be done
thank you so much for sharing this
information because i i feel like you're
taking thoughts right out of my head so
one second hey can you turn that up
i can't hear
really and part of that is my age sorry
but um i don't know is that better
yeah can you hear me now yeah okay great
thanks um
so i really appreciate your talk thank
you so much i feel like you're pulling
thoughts right out of my head so i've
said for a long time i feel like
percolations
are a missing link in the industry so
i'm curious if you did other tests or
you did double washes because in
traditional percolation sometimes you do
a second wash through and then i'd be
curious the other things that you tested
for in the tincture like what other
compounds you're looking for etc you're
bringing up a great great point so um
so i ran a production facility for a
while co2
extraction
and we definitely looked at our mark to
see what was left
the cbd sitting in the in the mark
and
you know one of the things we found was
that we were only getting about half of
the cbd with the co2 extraction that we
were using
uh this is a supercritical fluid
extraction right co2 and so we started
running again
or we take it and we do it with ethanol
and we
yield more cbd right so so that that's
an option now in this case according to
this data and this model
um
it looks like there's not much left it
looks like there's you know less than
twenty percent of cbd left at the very
most
and so yeah you could run it again and
probably get more
um but i'm not sure how much more you
would get
you did you test for other compounds as
well besides no so that's something i
meant to say when i started this uh
very quick lecture
um
we didn't have any funding so uh you
know this was
all
out of pocket and uh
yeah we we did it as cheaply as possible
but i insisted on triplicate samples of
triplicate samples
so
thank you very much
sure so
it's it's really well so temperature
let's start from the 30 000 foot view
level it's really known that heat
it's well known that that heat uh
is a
factor that can pull out more yield in
terms of most compounds that you're
looking for
having said that you can also
use too much heat and destroy stuff you
know flavin flavonoids start to
polyphenols start to break ground around
140 to 160 depending on the polyphenol
terpenes as you know can be actually
much less than that
so
if you look at hot water versus cold
water extractions for example
marshmallow root right and i'm not
talking about craft marshmallows that
you throw on a yucky milk chocolate uh i
mean at least use dark chocolate um
you know
graham cracker and i'm talking about
actual althea alficianalas
cold extractions will pull out the
polysaccharides so it's believed
much better than a warm extraction and
if it's a hot extraction you've almost
destroyed the polysaccharide so for gut
relief the way people use it it really
needs to be a cold extraction or at
least that's a dogma in the industry i'd
like to do that study too
so it just depends on what you're after
right
hot versus cold and i'm going to throw
this out there because i this is
something that i don't believe but the
industry believes
and that is that if we use cold ethanol
we avoid um
we avoid uh chlorophyll
and chlorophyll gives it this accurate
taste well
you know if you can buy chlorophyll
liquid chlorophyll in the health food
store have you ever tasted that stuff it
is not acrid
and so
you know cannabinoids are accurate
so what is it that why are we so afraid
of chlorophyll i i i don't get it and if
somebody can explain that to me after
that would be great but i i don't
believe that cold ethanol
is effective at reducing uh chlorophyll
or maybe it is but
well let me rephrase that it may be
effective of reducing ethanol
to reduce and chlorophyll cold ethanol
may be effective reducing ethanol
but chlorophyll is not a bad thing that
that's what i don't believe
um so heat it just depends on what
you're doing
yep
and i'm rambling and it's time and i'm
going to call it quits thank you
[Applause]