good morning Russ thanks for joining us
on the podcast
morning Ben happy to be very happy to be
here
all right so I'm excited to talk with
you because I know that you and your
team you've done a lot of work
evaluating the use of field portable
testing Technologies on cannabis plants
which is is pretty exciting and I know
from from our end on the medicinal
genomic side with some of our testing
Technologies that's something The
Growers are always interested in
something that's portable something
that's easy so I'm excited to talk with
you about what you found before we get
into the specific types of instruments
you've evaluated can you set the table
explain the value of portable testing to
cannabis Growers and why were you and
your team interested in evaluating them
our first need was a selfish need as a
breeding program we wanted to be able to
select across large populations and the
typical GC or hplc platforms were too
expensive so we started trying to find
methods that were more economical to
look at a thousand plants instead of
just 10 or 20 plants so our first
interest was selfish to let us get the
genetic gained breeding selection
efficiency up but then our sponsor noted
very quickly hey dispensaries might want
that other seed companies might want
that and if we can get it good enough on
some of these tools then law enforcement
may want it so it's kind of an expansion
of that that interest
interesting so so you guys are are
breeding plants so what sort of traits
were you looking for and you know how
was some of this technology is helpful
for you
sure well in Texas we're uh one of those
people you have the 0.3 compliance for
industrial hemp uh so that was our first
first Target tool and we got lower cost
suitcase hplc systems in place which
were okay uh but still slow uh and more
than we'd like to pay so the interest
was trying to improve upon a couple of
other near-infrared instruments that are
on the market uh for that kind of a scan
and we've done that we think and then
try to improve selection for things of
interest more for the medical side the
trichomes in particular and then for us
as breeders we wanted to look at varying
the number of chromosomes in a plant so
deployee I've done that with perennial
grasses before working on hemp and I
think with hemp it has a lot of
value-added benefits for fiber and Grain
in particular so all three of our our
instruments we've developed to have
interest uh to our breeding program in
particular
all right excellent so yeah I think I if
you're growing hemp specifically there
is that
requirement that would be under 0.3 talk
a little bit about sort of what's at
stake there or how is that enforced um
are you know could people knock at your
door and start testing your plants and
you need to make sure that everything is
uh compliant uh they can and they have
and those tests have range anywhere from
the presumptive the little color metric
test that law enforcement uses which is
always fun those tests will tell you yes
this is cannabis and we're like well
great we know it's cannabis it's him
right something with a more diagnostic
test and we get more precise uh but yeah
we we uh abide by those those rules set
forth by the state and the federal
government and the Texas department of
Ag and the fun thing for us is a
breeding program is if we know it's hemp
coming in
we can breed with it
proceed with generations of selection
for other trades heat tolerance yield
whatever other trade we're interested in
and as long as we don't test for that
compliance we can keep going with
Generations before we ever release
anything as a cultivar of course we have
to do that but it lets us streamline our
Our Generation time
so that's interesting so once you're
when you're breeding with it you don't
have to continue to keep verifying that
attempt
we know the parents were him the project
the progeny May segregate we can select
the progeny for heat tolerance drought
tolerance height grain size whatever and
we can proceed several generations for a
breeding program and then once we decide
to release it as a cultivar then we test
those descendants and make sure they're
still compliant but we don't have to
test every single plant and every single
generation
that's interesting but it I mean
theoretically though if you're if you're
starting with hemp and you're breeding
both of them together they're not going
to suddenly turn into cannabis or are
they well that 0.3 is a it's a pretty uh
stringent threshold and you can get
plants that are low in in THC but
they're still above that 0.3 they can be
0.5 put eight or something and that's
happened with material we've looked at
from other regions we brought in
particularly from Asia some of those
they're below one percent but they're
not below 0.3 so we have to find the one
the ones that are and still that'll
that'll change with populations as you
work with them so there's always a need
to test them before we try to release
anything
yeah okay so yeah so talk a bit about
the the technologies that you're using
to sort of I guess verify that you're
working with hemp given that you know so
much is ex so much is at stake here
sure so we've had populations we know
that are high and low in CBD and our
goal is to get a bell curve from zero
percent to 25 of CBD and we've done the
same thing more recently with the THC
looking for bell curves and once we do
that we do two tests we do an hplc
so we know we know within that level of
precision what it is and then we will do
our method of sampling
and Sample preparation and our modified
Optics we use with the near infrared
spectrometer and use that and after that
it's just a matter of having two data
sets and then running the the statistics
and the calibration and the modeling and
the validation of those models
okay so so near infrared what is that
and how is it different from you know
hplc
sure it's reflectance but it's
reflecting light that we cannot see it's
a it's a faster wavelength than what we
see we see this UltraViolets down here
infrared is up here above it we don't
see it uh and some of the infrared gives
us heat signatures some of it gives us
other information but it's all based on
the fact that if you hit something with
that it's going to reflect back other
wavelengths and that's based on the
vibration of the electrons in these
molecules and the fun thing is if you're
looking at uh cannabis you can look at
particular molecules and they're going
to reflect different amounts of that
infrared the trick is really trying to
be as precise as possible it's it's been
shown before you can get to two or three
percent accuracy but that's not all that
great our goal has been to get below one
percent accuracy
and have you met that goal uh we have we
haven't we haven't quite breached that
0.3 we're approaching that and really
that's it's really uh the limitation is
we are
a breeding and genetics program we are
not a micro fabricator so there's
certain things with engineering we can't
do in my lab so we need to reach out to
other Engineers to do some fabrication
and once we can fabricate certain
components to certain levels of
precision at that stage then we can get
there I think okay so that's a that's a
good point of clarification here so are
you using sort of commercially available
Technologies and just sort of evaluating
how they work are you developing your
own
so the spectrometer we use is a handheld
spectrometer you can buy it off the
shelf
that's where it ends for off-the-shelf
methods the sampling method that we use
is different than what's out there so if
you're familiar with a little purple or
if you're familiar with the gem assert
those are both near infrared devices
they get you a little bit of information
but not that accurate so the
spectrometer is off the shelf it's small
and the cool thing is in the future your
iPhone your iPhone 25 is going to have a
near infrared spectrometer on it they
demonstrated they could put it on cell
phones back in 2016. so the technology
is there it's just a matter of putting
it in there but the Optics so the same
thing we do is a bit different and the
Optics is different in two ways that's
where we have our proprietary little
little widget with it the Optics are
different than both of those systems it
lets us be more accurate and then the
modeling we do is is similar to what's
been done for near infrared for other
Industries using infrared for forage
evaluation for all sorts of molecules so
the the equations the modeling and
validation is similar but it still ends
up being a bit unique for the
cannabinoids
excellent
um
now I forgot what I was going to ask
next
um so how difficult is are these
instruments to use like could the could
the average grower conceivably use this
reliably and get repeatable results
absolutely everything I do I repeat it
three times on every sample and you can
do uh one sample in about 30 seconds and
by the time you by the time you run the
analysis is still less than a minute so
from sampling uh to running the Optics
to doing the the analytics on it once
it's once it's all put together it can
be done in one minute or less we've got
it it's almost a two component system
right now it's just a matter of turning
a tool from proof of concept to
something that's more ergonomic uh and
and user friendly but the goal is to
make it to where anyone can use it
excellent and now how important is
at what stage of development in the
plant you're testing like are you
testing you know finished dried cured uh
flour or are you kind of testing it
throughout its life
sure so it gets back to uh we started
testing at week zero of flowering when
you know before us everything try comes
there and we start looking at every
three or four days so we went week zero
one two three four and five and really
there's not even with hpoc there's not a
lot of appreciable uh cannabinoids until
about week two of flowering sure
somewhere between week two and week
three you start to see it going up uh so
our goal has been to to calibrate it
starting in that period so any anything
from about week two and a half until a
finished flower we can we can sample and
quantify and the Beautiful point you
made was unlike the little purple and
hemisphere which require you to have
dried cured tissue which you grind up we
can do
dried or fresh tissue
thanks for that that's been a beautiful
gain for us to do things out in the
field on living plants
um all right I and now you mentioned you
know this is just one of I think three
different technologies that you are
evaluating correct is that correct sure
we've moved a lot into microelectronics
I guess since we uh applied to be a
participant in this conference we've got
a fourth device as well and we're on the
five percent but we'll throw that fiber
device out but the first one we started
using was everyone wanted to look at the
trichomes and it's pretty simple to add
a small
little microscope attachment onto your
cell phone now and there are some of
those that can get up to four or 600
magnification they're very clear so that
one's been kind of a fun little freebie
gimme it'll probably be open source
where you're just combining a cell phone
based microscope small attachment with
image processing so image J or some
other version of that that will do a few
things it will it will identify the
round pieces the diameter it'll classify
the trichome heads once it classifies
them it will get the diameter and the
volume that will give you the basic size
of it and they were also still in the
process but working at getting the color
of it so looking at the pixel color so
we can gauge maturity so the goal of
that one is just going to be an open
source cell phone attachment and an app
where you can use that and look at your
trichome and say this is how big it is
this is how mature it is so that's kind
of a fun open source thing it's been
undergraduates and graduates the third
device has been getting back to the the
increase in chromosome numbers so the
ploidy if if you think about cells if
you increase the DNA in those you
increase the amount of protein you
increase the amount of everything that's
involved with it in Plants you increase
the cell wall size so for fiber hemp
we're very interested in trying to see
if we can make the best and the herd
fiber in particular longer by extending
that cell wall and by doing the
chromosome doubling we now have a lot of
plants that are tetraploid they don't
have two sets of chromosomes they have
four
and those we have now confirmed can have
improved fiber and improve grain but to
do the classification is very difficult
after you hit them with the treatment to
induce a chromosome doubling you have to
figure out which ones have been doubled
the plants to the visual eye don't look
that different and the typical tool has
been used is called a flow cytometer it
is a capillary system it's based on Cell
sorting and for cannabis which is a
resin resinous crop you've got lots of
sticky things in that extract and you
put that through these capillaries and
just block locks it up it plugs up and
you just ruin the capillary systems in
your flow cytometer so if you can't do
that your lift what you're left with
looking at chromosomes under a
microscope which is long and tedious
or trying to use some kind of indirect
measure and what we're coming up with is
not a capillary system but a
microfluidic system everything is going
Micron everything is eventually going to
go Nano but taking the capillary system
and making it smaller you go to
microfluidic channels and once we do
that we're using these these small flow
cells to separate the cells and the fun
thing is if it's got four sets of
chromosomes it moves slower
if it's got two sets it moves faster so
it's just like hplc or GC you're just
flow sorting in that microfluiding
channel so
when we have that it's just a matter of
running a modif that fluidic channel and
then looking at the speed of movement of
them across that and we can estimate
whether they have had the chromosomes
doubled or not
all right no all right so a lot there
first thing as a as someone who has
dabbled with home growing
unsuccessfully I think I've given up but
one of the things I always struggled
with was the thing you mentioned about
trichomes is you know looking with that
magnifying glass is it milky is it not
so a tool like that I think would be
very valuable
um at least for for people who are on my
level
well my goal is to have either a video
of us doing it or actually have
something there in hand that we can
demonstrate during the during the
conference uh and just do live demos if
we can't do videos of it but yeah that
would be the one that we would bring
there with us and have for people to
play with and work with I think that
would be uh
perfect for anyone homeowners dispensary
breeders sea companies for those
trichomes excellent and now the
tetraploid which is really interesting
um we had a presenter at our last can
make
at our last cam Med Seth Crawford
talking about triploid genomics and some
of the value that comes with that so so
that's three sets obviously and this is
four so you mentioned some of the the
advantages there being you know better
fiber and grain
um now I know with with triploid that
makes the plant actually sterile or you
know that it can't reproduce same thing
for tetraploid or can you actually
breathe with those no no no trip we have
triploids as well I guess Oregon CBD
demonstrated triploids and others have
done it but basically you you take the
diploid and double it so you have one
parent with two sets and one with four
and you cross them you end up you want
with three that's your triploids and
that's a beautiful plant for marijuana
or drug types where you're going to be
cloning vegetatively or even some of
your higher value CBD which is kind of
questionable now if you're really going
to be colonly propagating CD CBD hemp
but triploids are beautiful for those
systems because they're steriles just
like seedless bananas seedless
watermelons seedless grapes those are
all triploids for the same reason you
have sterility so for certain uses the
triploids are interesting for us it's
more interesting to look at the
tetraploids that have four sets because
they are fertile you can get seed off of
those you can get grain and what we've
seen so far you can get larger grain
excellent so would you say that that
technology would be less useful for your
average grower unless they were going to
try to breed for tetraploid specifically
maybe most likely but I guess we are lab
we do some things for service and we
don't really charge much for them so
we've improved the method of chromosome
doubling so I could see a time where
if people want to do that they could
send us hemp seed and if things changed
into some other seed we can do the
actual treatment of double chromosomes
and confirm it and send you back your
tetravoid version of your favorite
strain or your favorite home variety
eventually I don't know it could be a
point where people do it both steps
themselves but we would have to sell
that microfluidic uh device which is
kind of a goal is to be able to sell it
but making that simple enough for
homeowners you raise a very good
question I'm not not sure yeah maybe not
so much for home Growers but you know
maybe your commercial cultivators who
want to get into that
um yeah and maybe that's a good segue
talk a bit more about some of the
different services and things that you
do over there at Texas A M
sure we do uh control crosses so we have
companies sending OC and they want us to
make specific Cross by cross and the fun
thing we've developed that isn't really
part of this abstract uh with cannabis
you really want to control the males and
the pollen yep and the industry
typically tries to put them in different
rooms so you end up sacrificing the
entire room for one pollinator one male
and we've developed what is called a
pollen control tent or a pollen you know
pollen containment tent and there's one
company in the UK that makes these and
they're very expensive and we've made
our own version and basically the the
mesh around it lets enough light through
the plant as happy it grows just fine
you get you get gas exchange there's
enough air in there but it's small
enough mesh it's less than one micron it
keeps the pollen from getting in or out
and cannabis Pawn is about 25 microns
this screen is less than one micron
what's that let us do we can put two
parents we want to cross in there a
female and a male no other pawns going
to get on that female or set the pollen
from the male you want and it can't leak
pollen and contaminate other plants you
have so as a result we have a green
analysis three thousand square feet
we're not using all of it yet and we are
currently increasing seed on 120 crosses
so instead of having 120 rooms one for
each cross we now have one modest sized
Greenhouse where we're doing hundreds of
individual crosses of different size
sometimes we do a single plant and we
inbreed it sometimes we do two or three
plants for synthetic hybrids and
sometimes we do populations in these but
uh it's been a beautiful tool wow that's
interesting so so you have the male and
the female under 110. we can do that and
the fun thing we've learned we can make
the female into a hermaphrodite make it
monicious or it has male and female
flowers we've learned how to work with
that so we can make a single female
plant pollinate itself so you can breed
it and we've learned more recently you
can make a male plant produce female
flowers and we've started selfing those
so in your crazy wild mind you might
think of an all-male cultivar instead of
feminized seed you might have masculine
ice seed for fiber nail plants in
general have better fiber quality
so our goal is to start doing some of
the inbreeding services that people want
us to do that as well but we can make
crosses for people different types of
crosses
for service and we can do the chromosome
doubling that that's also a service we
we have listed and really anything that
we get permission to do from the
University and the Texas department of
AG we can use it we can provide it as a
service and when you do that you send a
seed we get no IP we're just doing a
service you give us your seed we give
you seed back and you do whatever you
like with it
right no and you mentioned permission
and in regulation so you again you can
only work with hemp correct
so far yes we had to give approval from
the University and from the Texas
department of AG or TDA once we do that
any any project we propose and get
approved uh we've got green lights
and now what is the limiting factor
there is it Federal Regulation or state
like so for example if Texas were to go
um full adult use
um would that open things up for you or
is kind of the Federal Regulation
holding you back
that is a beautiful question so it would
be able pay grade sure yeah that would
be out to the department head or the
dean or the vice Chancellor because
actually the the the hemp research
license that we have is not me I'm just
a lowly faculty member uh it's actually
signed by our Dean so it's up to the
Comfort level of the dean if if I think
if the state approved made it legal uh
the TDA would give us a research or was
legal but it would still be a question
of whether our director and Dean would
let us do it so I think if we did that
uh we could we could do so and really
our Administration has been very uh
helpful they've not been setting up
Roblox they've not been saying we can't
do things they just said be compliant
and be careful
excellent
um I want to talk a bit about your your
background because I was reading your
bio before I I jumped on with you um you
know you didn't start in cannabis so
talk a bit about what you did before and
and what made you switch sure no I
actually started in Biochemistry and
then I went in the Army so I went
non-traditional came back to the Army
and got into plant sciences and really
uh I've been a grass breeder a perennial
grass breeder for over 15 years now and
I teach classes I always say I used to
always say I was the grass reader but
not the grass breeder three years ago
until or two and a half years ago Texas
greenlighted him and by that time I had
learned to use certain terpenes some are
from Cannabis some are from other plants
that have helped myself friends and
families for specific conditions so I
had a love for terpenes uh
from a nutraceutical standpoint and we
started looking at terpenes as trying to
make plasticizers of fibers to try to
work replacing some of these Plastics so
we kind of jumped into different bio
products as well with the grasses
because I had a job after my PhD turning
grass fiber into ethanol so trying to
not use cornstarch but trying to use
cellulose so I already had kind of an
interest in the terpenes and an interest
in the bile products and the fun thing
with him when it when it was legalized
to me you cannot make one thing or two
things you can make six or seven things
and if you have six or seven Commodities
off of one crop no one major company or
industry can shut you down when I was
working on ethanol corn ethanol they
always kept their margin and nickel
shorter than us every time we got ours a
little cheaper they made theirs even
cheaper so one Energy company could shut
us down with industrial hemp and
cannabis no one no one industry can do
that when you've got fiber you've got
grain you've got terpenes you've got
cannabinoids you've got all the bile
products so it's a beautiful crop to use
as a biorefinery I guess that's that's
my love for it
excellent and yeah with so many
different uses you need to be able to
you know breed optimally right and I
know you have some experience with
marker assisted breeding so what are
some of the traits or markers that
you're interested in or you think could
be you know the future
so there's a sorority markers for male
versus female there's already markers
for a CBD and THC the markers we're
really after for Texas in the southern
us are heat and drought most of the
varieties from Europe and Colorado just
do terrible down here particularly
Central Texas and further south and
it'll be the same going to Florida all
the way across the southern U.S so we're
really trying to focus on heat and
drought but other fun things are going
to be modified trichomes you know
there's interest in making a fiber and
grain type that has no cannabinoids at
that point it would be considered a type
5 hemp and that would be something that
would make Farmers not worry about it
being compliant that would make parents
not worry about milk having any residues
in them and it would give uh give the
DEA headaches because they couldn't try
to regulate there would be no schedule
one molecule in it so we could argue for
a different type of
classification of that
and the other thing we're
atrogenetically really is uniformity if
you look at Industrial Hemp on a big
acreage the plants are all over the map
for flowering for branching for size and
height we're trying to get cannabis to
be grown just like modern corn modern
major crops where you have completely
100 percent in breadline parents so
they're uniform you can propagate them
by sea just like rice or wheat you plant
the seed it looks just like the parent
you can't do that with cannabis now it
varies that's why it's all clonely
propagated but once we have in red lines
we can cross those and the f1s should be
larger they should have hybrid Vigor and
where no one's really confirmed that
we're going to take the risk and see if
we can and we've got uh
several pipelines going to make inbreds
so we should buy this time next year be
able to say yes you can inbreed to the
fifth or sixth generation to make
hybrids or or no you can't
well that's exciting that could be uh
that could be yet next year is can Med
topic
so so winding down here so I mean if
Growers are listening and they're kind
of excited by these different
technologies that you're putting
together
um you know are these going to be
available to them like how is that um
how is that process kind of work
we have a timeline you know I I'm
academius I'm way out of industry for
over a decade more than a decade now but
I'm very cognitive of trying to get
things pre-commercial or have some kind
of a commercial timeline particularly
for our sponsor and I guess the three we
have listed for this this program uh the
open source microscope to look at
trichomes and classify that should be
available this year so by the end of
2023 and that'll be easy the second one
is the nir platform which we've now
confirmed with utility for CBD and Delta
nine so we've got two of those and
that's really up to our sponsors so they
have the right to commercialize it as
they desire so it's that'll be
commercialized at their timeline it's
been it's been it's been disclosed it's
been released to them it's a matter of
how quickly they want to commercialize
it the third one for the DNA content
which may have a smaller audience not as
many people wanted to buy it that one
maybe a little further out but it was
still either be this year or next year
2023 or 2024. all right excellent and do
we want to give us a plug to your
sponsor real quick
oh well they they introduced me to can
Med and to uh Doug and you guys and the
company is rare earth genomics
based out of Texas and Houston
all right all right Ross well before I
let you go I want to give you a chance
to First share any other resources that
the listeners might be interested in if
they're you know interested in learning
more or reading up on some of the things
that we talked about I can always put
links into the show description
um that they can learn more and then
also please plug your your program or
you if you're on social media anything
like that so that people can learn more
about you and the work that your team's
doing
so I'm old enough my only social media
is LinkedIn but LinkedIn we do have
things we haven't talked about we've got
a conversion program you talked about
home grows we're taking donations and
making any donation of pollen we get
into compliant hemp and we're going to
release that so we're going to have a
public open source term plasma
collection uh start to come out this
year and it's called The Hemp conversion
programs that's on our LinkedIn or my
LinkedIn page if you just search
LinkedIn for hemp conversion program I
got a Federal grant to help expand it so
it's going to be bigger by next year
that's a fun one we have other products
going on so if they have interest you
know if anyone has interest in other
ideas or other bio products we're more
than happy to visit and develop those
ideas
all right all right thanks again Russ
for taking the time to be on the podcast
and I look forward to seeing you down in
Florida
as well Ben thank you very much