thank you all for coming get this
microphone adjusted a little bit today
we're gonna explore cannabis within pro
sports and in particular as a viable
alternative for pain management and pain
relief as an alternative obviously to
opiates my name is Jim MacAlpine to give
you just a very quick background on
myself on the 420 games are an advocacy
Roenick around the country where we go
4.20 miles to change the perception of
cannabis as stoners and show that
athletes and you know Jeff Sessions good
people do use cannabis it's amazing
honored to be here today at Harvard I've
spoken recently at Mill Valley Film
Festival I was at the Superbowl with
some of these guys and we just did South
by Southwest but being at a prestigious
place like this is really really moving
the needle so it's exciting for all of
us to helps spread some knowledge here
from here I want to go into the panel
and why don't we just go down the line
I'd like for these guys to give their
own introduction instead of me reading
theirs and you guys why don't you say
who you are you know your background and
also I think it's important why you're
here just give a little tidbit on that
as well start with you dr. Nathan
educator from Princeton New Jersey
originally from Philadelphia I did my
residency up here at Harvard so it's
good to be back I'm the president board
president and founder of doctors for
cannabis regulation which is the
nation's first and only organ a National
Organization for the regulation
legalization taxation of cannabis in the
United States
dr. Perry Solomon a board-certified
anesthesiologist and chief medical
officer at hello MD we're a health of
digital health and wellness platform
that allows patients members from all
over the world to ask questions on our
site that's answered by other patients
about what cannabis products work for
them by physicians to give them
recommendations
as well as from professional people who
product manufacturers about what
products they have we also do telehealth
evaluations in California and other
states that allow telehealth evaluations
for people who are interested in getting
their cannabis recommendations for their
medical conditions we have about 170,000
members and issued about 60,000
recommendations in the past two years hi
everybody I'm Evan Britton
I played six years in the NFL four years
with the Jacksonville Jaguars two years
with the Chicago Bears as an offensive
lineman tackle guard and a little bit of
tight end at the end just for starters
I'm here to try to grab the year of the
NFL and start to look at cannabis as an
alternative to opiates and prescription
anti-inflammatories as well as what it
can be as a solution to concussions and
CTE hello my name is Nate Jackson I
played six years also in the NFL all for
the Denver Broncos I was a all right we
got some Bronco fans in the house there
we go no Bears fans our Jacksonville but
I played six years receiver okay okay we
got I was a receiver and tight end and
throughout my career I used cannabis as
medication to deal with the variety of
injuries that I had when I would get
hurt oftentimes a career I'm sorry a
season-ending injury they hand me a
bottle of pills I went home and instead
consume cannabis to deal with my
injuries and found that I healed much
faster than when I did it with pills and
so it just got me thinking and after
retirement I started writing I am also a
writer I've written two books about my
experience in the NFL and I was honest
about the different medications that I
preferred and that's led me here because
I believe that football players current
and former need to arm themselves with
this information if they're going to be
able to stand up for themselves
everyone my name is Lance Johnstone play
eleven years six with Oakland and five
with the Minnesota Vikings I after a
retirement enough women as a broker at
Merrill Lynch from there I started doing
some angel investing adventures so
currently I'm we are part of an
accelerator for cannabis companies and
I'm here today to you know to continue
to help push awareness and you know as
you Cape helped educate not only some of
my fellow athletes but anyone that's
dealing with pain as in a turn on that
more natural alternative to you know
opioids so that's pretty much it so my
name is Ricky Williams and all you
Patriots fans should know who I am
because I used to come up here every
year when I play for the Dolphins also
played for the Saints in my last years
with the Baltimore Ravens I'm here
because I'm the captain of the NFL all
cannabis team
yeah that was a joke you know so no you
know I'm here to tell my story you know
back in 2002 2003 2004
I failed a couple drug tests and almost
ended my career and I was looking back
at some articles written at the time and
and what everyone is talking about now I
was saying that back then and so you
know it's real and I think I'm a I'm a
living breathing example of it I led the
NFL in rushing in 2002 using cannabis
instead of opioids instead of indocin
and tore it all and so I know it works
and that's why I'm here let's give them
all a hand look we know doctors are
smart because they're doctors but at
least they think they are sometimes yeah
just a joke but but these other guys are
incredibly intelligent as well and
really all four of these guys I respect
obviously as athletes and and as men but
all four of these guys I've gotten to
know and are really really intelligent
guys so it's a pleasure for me to be
able to moderate a panel with with the
quality we have right here today so
really you can break down the main
applications of cannabis within both pro
sports and really all athletics in my
opinion to two things and it's its focus
and recovery or the main applications
personally I'm I'm kind of more of an
extreme sports guy and I like to use
cannabis for focus and I talk about that
a lot normally maybe we'll dive in at
the end but today we're really gonna
have more of a laser focus on both the
NFL guys that thought at the pro level
and an alternative to opioid in the
recovery realm of cannabis
you know NFL's a brutal game extremely
violent causes severe injuries even to
the strongest of men and injury is the
biggest problem in NFL team faces
they're looking how do we keep these
guys on the field oftentimes not
thinking about the person that's behind
that number and really that's why we're
here today
so I looked at it I was walking with
Nate and eben and they were telling me
what happens when you get caught you get
a little tap on the shoulder and they
throw up
I get you and you get your stuff out of
the locker room and you're gone you know
and really I feel like they're looked at
as machines and you know you can replace
these parts and get them back on the
field but when it's too expensive when
we just get a new machine and the human
being right there is lost and and that
kind of disgust me about the NFL to be
honest and again why we're here today so
you know the the moral dilemma for these
guys is hey do I do whatever it takes
and shove these pills down my throat
because the NFL's telling me I have to
or do I do what it takes to go home to
my family and have you know my brain be
intact later on in life so Nate why
don't you tell us about I think it's an
interesting story just how drug tested
in the NFL works and then in particular
when you get caught what happens well
Rick you talk about when you get caught
my question I'll talk about I have a PhD
in the drug program yeah I'll talk about
how you beat it and then he'll talk
about how what it's like when you get
caught but it's actually so the NFL drug
testing comes in two and two facets one
is for street drugs and one is for
performance-enhancing drugs the street
drugs like cannabis and like other party
drugs is a once-a-year test and it
happens typically in May June or July
somewhere around many camps or training
camps and if you pass that one test then
you're good for the rest of the year and
you don't get tested again and so guys
you know abstain in advance of the test
and then once they pass that then they
can use it during the season to medicate
but for guys who get caught up in the
drug program the drug testing or the
drugs substance abuse program like
you'll talk about it's two three four
times every week you get tested all year
long for multiple years of clean test
before you're pulled off of that and so
it's those guys who get put in those
programs who can't use it and are given
more dangerous alternatives instead the
substance I'm sorry the
performance-enhancing drugs
happen all year long it can happen in
the off season it happened one time to
me in the off season and their protocol
is when they truck when they test you
you have to remove your shirt pull your
pants below your knees and they have to
stand perpendicular to you and watch the
urine exit your body
that's what they do and so they came to
my parents house in San Jose in the
offseason and came into the bathroom
that I grew up in and stood there and
watched me pee in a cup so it is a
little bit of an objectification going
on but I never got i never tested
positive and so i was able to use it
during the season where as ricky can
talk about what happens when you get
caught up in the system I tested
positive and I still continue to use it
I'm actually working on an article right
now for marijuana calm about how to pass
the drug test
although I failed for I passed probably
400 500 tests so when you when you get
cotton in the in the nfl's substance of
abuse program you get a letter in the
mail that says you're gonna go through
stage one to determine if you have a
substance abuse problem and so they send
you sent me to Atlanta and I spent a
whole day not with three different
psychiatrists filled out all this
paperwork just so that they can tell me
that I have a substance abuse problem
but no matter what the psychiatrists say
you have a substance abuse problem and
they put you in a drug treatment program
with the NFL for for two years and if
you stay clean for two years you're out
of that you're out of the program and so
when what happened to me is I was
playing for for New Orleans and the New
Orleans I tested in training camp which
was in late July and then I got traded
to Miami and in Miami they tested in May
and I didn't get the memo so I was in
the drug program and and you know it's
like Nate was saying I hated it when I
first got in I was I was actually
excited about the opportunity to talk to
someone because part of the program is
they give you someone to talk to you
once a week in a mandatory hour and uh
and then when I went to talk to him all
he talked to me about was how to not
fail the drug test all right and then I
was tested nine times a month and it's
wherever I go in the world I have to
call the NFL before I leave before I get
on a plane and say I'm going I'll be at
this address for this long this is when
I arrive this is when I leave and at the
address I give them no other address
they can call me anytime they want and I
have four hours to pee in a cup from
that time at that location so it's very
stressful
especially when you know failing a
second drug test you're fined one fourth
of your salary another test you're
suspended for games so it's very
stressful even even when I wasn't using
cannabis it was stressful because if I
couldn't get to that location in four
hours you know it was tough and I think
right now the NFL is is moving to the
NFL Players Association is moving to
propose that cannabis is taken off the
banned substance list and recognizing
that it's not as an abuse problem but
it's a health issue and in research even
though there hasn't been that much has
come to the point where we're divorced
Smith the executive director of the of
our union has finally like hopped on
board and said okay there's something we
have we have to look at this differently
and and finally the Union is taking a
step forward to to have the players
backs and I think that's a step in the
right direction to change this
antiquated punitive drug program that
doesn't help players just punishes them
for taking for trying to take care of
themselves yeah and you know yeah it's
I'll take it however we can get it it's
a little sad to me watching and really
seeing that it's it's a numbers game to
them it's not really a to me from what
I'm seeing about the people but when you
show them that this stuff actually will
save you money you know on opioids and
actually have your players in better
shape that's what they really care about
and that's the whole point here this
stuff does work and it's a very very
viable alternative to give you adjust of
some quick data 33,000 Americans die
every year of opioid overdoses that's a
that's a big number and that's a number
that does not have to happen NFL players
are over four times as likely to become
addicted to painkillers so what at the
point I wanted to come out of that story
is also once you're caught once now your
pigeon-holed into having those pills
shoved down your throat because you have
zero other alternatives to quitting and
I mean Ricky you pretty much did quit
and and walk away from it so that's why
I got a lot of respect for that and I
feel bad for these guys that are still
having that happen so that's why I'm
here today I want to see that change so
we're gonna get into some other stuff
empirical data charts and start letting
the doctors backup our stories here
is is there any stories that you guys
want to tell that are in particular one
that's very quick to me that just rings
of there's a problem here at the Super
Bowl there's a commercial for something
called oh I see it's opioid-induced
constipation so if you can't go poop
movant 'ok yeah there we go if you can't
go poop with your opiates we've got
another pill for you to take and man
when's the third one gonna come out so
any stories that you guys got that that
kind of you want to share with the
audience that exemplify these issues or
did we already kind of go through that
oh I'll share some stuff so you know
really the process and football is just
a daily process of managing pain and
dealing with pain whether you have a
severe injury like a dislocated shoulder
and a torn labrum or herniated disk in
your back and sciatica running down your
leg making your foot numb you know all
these things that each guy on here is
dealt with a severe an immense amount of
pain throughout his lifetime in his
career in football so what are you doing
to deal with that you're taking you know
handfuls of indocin and cata flam these
highly potent anti-inflammatories that
wreak havoc on your digestive system
your kidney and liver you know taking
opiates before the game day before the
game before the game after the game day
after the game this is how you're
getting out of pain and it's you know
basically just this vicious cycle and
for me really the painkillers the
opiates they made me feel insane they
made my mind crazy they made me really
angry towards my girlfriend at the time
my wife now towards my mother it's
people that were trying to care for me
in these really vulnerable times of
injury you know I wasn't able to
function you know I wasn't able to do
anything these things made it difficult
to sleep I was waking up at 3 o'clock in
the morning with withdrawal symptoms if
any of you have ever experienced that
something like a knife twisting in your
gut cold sweats chills all the above you
feel nuts juxtaposing that experience in
my experience when I consumed cannabis
was very healing and relaxed me there
eased my anxiety and my depression made
it easier to sleep ease the pain in my
physical body as well as rejuvenated me
emotionally and spiritually and gave me
the energy and the fulfillment I needed
to go out the next day and play and do
it again at a hundred percent cuz every
single day you've got to be out there
ready to give it everything you've got
in practice let alone Sunday so cannabis
can be a very profound solution to those
things and thanks in some layman's terms
and then I want to hand this over to the
doctors but the way I see this is I've
been on both I'm an athlete I'm not a
pro athlete but I've been hurt pretty
bad many times and I've been on opioids
and my bad back is an example and what
really people need to do is start
looking at their their whole body
strengthening themselves looking at more
of an Eastern philosophy on some levels
of taking care of your body versus
putting a pill in it to fix it fix your
body and opioids had always for me I'm a
little out of pain but I want to lie in
my bed and not don't want to do [ __ ]
really to put it bluntly and when when I
take cannabis I'm able to both be out of
pain but also mentally not have that fog
that allows me to work out and kind of
reiterating what I've been said there so
it allows us to still work out and be
athletic and strengthen the pieces of
our body whether we're pro or average
Joe to get healthy versus just relying
on a pill and now as we go to the
doctor's I will show a short here in a
minute but what I'd like to do is have
dr. Nathan and dr. Solomon explain
cannabis all cannabidiol CBD is what
most people know it has and also the
endocannabinoid system which is a pretty
interesting thing I think a lot of
physicians don't even hear about this
through medical school just because it's
kind of a hidden thing but it is in with
all within all of us so you guys want to
split it up and one of you talked a
little bit about CBD and the other about
the endocannabinoid system
I think needs to be brought out about
education and how the medical system is
essentially ignoring the whole issue and
doctors are coming out of medical school
even from you know probably or across
the street completely ignorant about the
endocannabinoid system and out of the
hundred and forty-four medical schools
in the country one teaches a course on
the endocannabinoid system and about 13%
of the other 144 mention it in passing
so a lot of the times the physicians are
coming out of medical school knowing
absolutely nothing about this whole
wonderful system that helps protect the
body CBD THC etc you know it's just that
they come out not knowing anything about
it so we encourage all the physicians
who are here and this is a great venue
to be able to get introduced to what's
going on and that it really is a science
and the endocannabinoid system has been
around since the nineteen or discover
the 1970s and it really does work to
help inflammation to help fight pain and
it just needs to be used by many for
more physicians and I understand there's
an issue about a doctor recommending it
in terms of player comes and sits there
and he's in pain and there's a
prescription pad and one of them is for
an opioid that's measurable it's easy
you're right one pill or two pills take
this it mean it's a known dose etc the
other side says well here's cannabis
well what are you right how can you
possibly tell someone what to do it's a
very individualistic mechanism that
works and it's not the same for every
single person so there's an education
process for the physician to understand
what's going on and it starts with
medical school and continues and places
like this and actually pick up on that
thread talking about education it was in
medical school where I think I was
turned from a drug warrior as we all
grew up or at least those of us who were
in the just say no generation and
thinking that drugs are bad and the
people who use them are bad and the
people who sell them are worse and
unworthy of their freedom and as I
proceeded through my residency in
psychiatry where
I studied a lot of substance abuse I was
really shocked that my teachers in a
highly respected residency program were
very much for the drug war and I'm
thinking you're trying to help these
people you're trying to help these
individuals who are struggling with
substances and you still want to punish
them do you think that's really gonna
help them and you know as Russell Brand
said if being in an alley with some
smelly people and injecting yourself
with God knows what using shared needles
if that's not enough to make you stop
the threat of the law putting you in a
room where you get food three times a
day and you get to shower and all of
that that's it that's not going to stop
you and I couldn't understand why my
teachers didn't understand that and then
as I proceeded through my career as a
psychiatrist is a general adult
psychiatrist in central New Jersey I
started seeing how lives were being
wrecked by marijuana and virtually none
of them were because of the effects of
the drug it was because of the effects
of the law and that's what really got me
thinking
[Applause]
that's what got me thinking that I think
I need to do something about this it was
bothering me so much especially because
I would think back to those teachers of
mine and what how they wanted to handle
even something like marijuana and I
realized that this is and this is an
issue of ethics morality and of course
it's an issue of the law because of the
way the laws are written and I started
getting involved in this realized that
there was no forum for doctors to speak
out comfortably in public about this
issue and I know that because I did it
and found out what happens when you do
that I wrote an op-ed for The Wall
Street Journal in 2010 that's really
what got the whole thing started for me
and when realizing that there was no
organizing force that's when I came up
with the idea for doctors for cannabis
regulation look up at DF CR you can see
our Declaration of Principles that was
signed almost exactly a year ago and it
was not long after that that somebody
who is not in this room Eugene Munroe
who some of you may know as actually a
very effective advocate among NFL errs
and he actually was the first active NFL
player to come out after which he was
cut had the opportunity to continue
playing but decided his body had had
enough and came to D F CR and said look
you know doctors and players we can
actually bring this message to the
public in a really effective way and he
said that will open the door and you
guys go through and I think what you're
seeing on this stage right now with
these four fantastic and eloquent
individuals telling their stories and
sharing what they've learned about
cannabis and us being able to back it up
with some of the science and I know you
asked about science this has been a
highly effective campaign that we
launched in November of last year
doctors and players for NFL cannabis
reform and a couple of days after we
launched the campaign the NFL
it's website as my son who loves
following everything football was
pointing out ran its first article
saying that you know we've said the
doctor that the NFL isn't gonna take any
action until our doctors tell us it's
okay right you know the doctors that
they pay are going to tell them you know
what what they think if that means
changing the status quo and and the
players who sorry lost my train of
thought
I haven't spoken in front of a group
this big in a very long time this is a
cannabis talk so you know we can
occasionally it's not bad
and yeah I want to bring it back guys I
do want to bring it back it's it's when
you know when Lance said that he wanted
to share some stuff Abid I'll I think a
lot of you know right cannabidiol is
mostly a CBD I'm sorry is mostly a
cannabinoid receptor antagonist and it
does it in such a way which is of course
complicated and not fully understood
that has effects that are somewhat
balancing to THC so I know that there's
not a lot of objective evidence I heard
a talk yesterday where people were
talking about that that there's not a
lot of objective evidence for the
entourage effect and that's true for a
lot of the assertions with the medical
effects of cannabis but I will say there
is plenty of anecdotal evidence there's
a lot of common sense involved and
actually there is a report that all of
you should read from the National
Academies of science engineering and
medicine from January of this year that
was a body that very critically looked
at this notion of of what cannabis can
be used for what are the health effects
and they came to conclusions that any
politician who would read it which is
probably none of them would have to come
to the conclusion that there is indeed
medical use and the policy doesn't make
sense and
as you guys probably know historically
this conversation every time doctors
have been asked to really critically
study this issue they come to the same
conclusion which is it really shouldn't
be against the law and it's with the
doctors and the players that we have
been highly effective I know we're
always going with that previous comment
which is that there is and I I'll shut
up after this that there is really a you
know if there's an ulterior motive for
doctors for cannabis regulation to be
doing what we're doing with the NFL
because you know 1500 1600 guys every
year are directly affected active
players and and all of the retired
players who are still dealing with the
injuries that they suffered it's not
just about them because what they
represent is a microcosm of society and
what society has had to deal with with
rules that make no sense evidenced by
the degree to which the enforcement of
this is so half-hearted that's why
they're telling us when we're going to
get our drug tests because they really
don't want to ban us but they know they
have to continue with this and nobody's
exactly sure why well I have some ideas
of why you know doing doing a lot of
these panels and hearing the discussion
I understand it's easy to look at the
NFL and say the NFL needs to change the
way it looks at cannabis but the NFL is
gonna follow or whatever wherever the
money is and whatever the fans are
saying and it's the same thing that's
that's what our government was built on
and I know for me coming out and talking
about my cannabis use even though
everyone knew it
for a long time still still took me a
while and it wasn't till two years ago
where I was finally like you know I
could pretend that I don't but everyone
already knows that I do so [ __ ] it and
so
it's uh I came and sat on the panel and
I was able to talk about it
and I and I treated the leave if all the
the closeted cannabis consumers would
just be honest things would change
faster than with any any of us can do
even if everyone in the NFL wanted to do
it it's really up to you it's up to the
people and so one of the reasons I'm
here talking is maybe one person in the
crowd talked to someone else to talk to
someone else and they finally step out
of the closet and her are honest about
about what cannabis is meant for them
and it's done for them you know I've
talked to a lot of people and I'm always
curious it's like how did you start
using cannabis like how did it become
something that was appealing to you and
across the board over ninety percent of
the people said I was hanging out with a
friend and I had some sort of injury a
knee injury ankle injury a broken heart
something going on in their lives and
they noticed that when they used when
they used cannabis recreationally that
whatever they were dealing with got
better and I think there's something
about us inherently that when something
works we tend to go back to it you know
to complement that Rickey I think like
let's go outside a cannabis like I've
watched cannabis acceptance happen and
I'm I lived in San Francisco and and
have watched you know through the AIDS
movement and and the gay rights and
everything that's happened kind of in
the epicenter of where I live in
acceptance no one should live in the
closet for anything and it's liberating
except out of the closet whatever you
may be in the closet for step out man it
feels good it was funny so we had a we
had a friend over at our house we
different over our house and um and we
were we were consuming cannabis together
and one of the things he talked about
was he's he's been smoking for over 20
years he had been married for I think 15
years and he's never consumed in front
of his wife she's not even against it
what stigma runs deep interesting thing
that goes on with football players is
that we are always taught to shut up
shut up and play don't talk about your
pain don't talk about how you feel and
so in the realm of cannabis in football
you have like Ricky was saying a lot of
guys in the Claus
who use it and find benefits from it but
don't feel comfortable talking because
there's this code of silence in the NFL
and in football at all levels that tell
you to shut up and follow the plan and
the plan is not for you to be an
individual human being talking about the
fact that you are in pain but football
players do feel the pain and we have to
manage it one way or the other and I
always found that I healed faster when I
was consuming cannabis than when I was
doing pills to heal you have to feel you
have to feel what's going on with your
body pain serves a purpose and so for
guys who professional athletes who
tinkered with every single kind of
medication to come to the conclusion the
cannabis worked for them I think is
something something huge and guys are
coming out of the Woodworks and I think
it's an important conversation and Nate
you you you're pointing you know it's
it's all retired players who are here
it's very hard to find active players
and you guys can comment on this it's
very hard because you'll get fired if
you're inside a locker room you don't do
anything to draw attention to yourself
whether it's cannabis or politics or
anything they don't want you to be a
human being and talk about your own
ideas so that's really hard when you
retire that's what they call it from
retiring from football but when you go
out into the real world we don't have
the words we don't know how to
articulate our ideas and that that
there's like a five year period from
when you're done playing to when you
finally start to feel comfortable
talking about your own ideas and
articulating yourself and so that's a
big obstacle that these guys face and
it's only I mean also it hasn't been
brought up that I think needs to be
addressed is opioids not only affect the
players who are taking since we're
talking about the NFL it affects their
families as well which is something that
wives and girlfriends know when they're
taking the opioids how it affects their
attitudes how it affects their emotions
and how it affects their relationships
is devastating to families in and of
itself other than the pain relief and
the opioid addiction that these players
are coming down with we're we have a
film that I might or might not show
there's two there's two subjects I'm
interested in covering but
where we show that that I think are
important so I'm actually gonna ask for
a show of hands because we don't we
haven't got a lot of time left I'm gonna
try and fit both in but I'm interested
to see we can talk about CTE and
concussion treatment and cannabis
relative to that or we can talk about
using it as focus as an athlete and
maybe talk little is it a PE D some
people think that some not and how maybe
we use cannabis when our training
regiments who here would rather hear
about CTE and the focus hands alright
alright see three wings today so this is
an interesting when I'm actually I'm
kind of glad we're going down this road
because there there's there's me and the
players here and there's the doctors and
the doctors have to stick to data and
empirical stuff and you know we're guys
that say we've lived this life we know
this works and it can say it that way
they can't really say it the way we can
say it so maybe they can yeah that's not
oh thank you that's not always true I
mean it depends on how much you listen
and how much you want to take what the
players and other people who are taking
the opioids or cannabis how it really
affects them in terms of you don't have
to be a rocket scientist to know hey I
took this it didn't work now I take this
and it worked I mean yes it's not a
study from across the street or from any
Stanford University but it's good enough
to be able to say yes let's try this
let's try something different
no no I'm not I'm I'm categorizing you
like the players you guys are are
handcuffed by what the institution
allows you to do it's kind of what I'm
trying to say so you do have to work
within a box you can't step just like
the players if you step out of that box
and start saying the wrong things you're
gone too you know and that's kind of
what I'm trying to purvey I don't know
if that's really true I mean being up
and speaking like Dustin Sulak to a lot
of people who came physicians who came
here to talk about that I think I don't
know if that's really stepping out of
the box it's just acknowledging one that
there's a problem and two that yes there
could be a solution and we may have the
solution to be able to help that problem
a lot of doctors are really trained that
we have to go with the evidence and it's
got to be evidence-based and I see heads
nodding right now and I appreciate that
and I grew up in the same ear and I do
feel that way and when I hear about
anecdotal evidence
you know I hesitate just a bit because
it hasn't been established in the
richer in the same way but I think that
the greatest argument for policy change
is not nitpicking over the details of
what exactly cannabis can do and that
book that came out earlier this year
from the National Academies really does
lay out the case for that fact we only
have a few minutes I want to get into
CTE so it's a non negative argument that
is actually the best it doesn't hurt
that bad and so why are we preventing
people from using it strong point and I
I agree with that but I just don't have
a lot of time and where I'm going with
this is because we're talking about CTE
there's going to be different levels of
commitment and and support for CBD and
its usage for CTE because there's not
empirical data behind it to the level we
should have and I wish we had time to
show you the marijuana that the I think
it's Mississippi and the only marijuana
these guys are allowed to research it's
it's in California we call a ditch weed
or schwag it's horrible and so they're
they're handcuffed to I mean what they
have to research is awful empirical data
well here's a study by su Sicilies do it
looking at PTSD on trauma traumatic
brain injury and from the University of
Mississippi the only place that they're
allowed to use the cannabis for she's
you know we've talked about what it is
that they send her and it's essentially
seed stems and planned ground together
in a little baggie that's fresh frozen
and shipped off to her with no
acknowledgement about what the
concentration of THC CBD any of the
terpenes anything at all but what's in
it
here's your cannabis here's what you're
allowed to use so the study that she's
running if it comes out negative doesn't
mean it's negative it just means the
product that was given to her was
useless versus something that yes let's
study something so everyone's hamstrung
in terms of what it is to be able to do
because they don't want the results
being shown yeah and as we go back to
CTE this this started everybody should
watch a movie called concussion if they
haven't seen it with Will Smith it's
it's an eye-opening tear-jerking movie
and it tells you really the way this all
unfolded and and it was ugly and at this
point there's you know it was jr. say oh
who really when he killed himself as a
basically hall-of-famer they couldn't
they couldn't wipe it under you know
scrape it under the rug
they did that with hundreds other before
hundreds of others before that Dave
Mirra who's an ex BMX guy just killed
himself because of concussions and
concussions go way outside of football
to extreme sports surfing skateboarding
everything soccer even and so the CT
stuffs a big one and talking about how
to use CBD as a neuro protectant to
something I'm interested in and and
that's kind of where I was talking about
the empirical data versus anecdotal
evidence but I want to have you guys
talk about neuro protectant and CBD
together why don't I like to have the
players start on this one and kind of do
any of you use CBD I know Evan you have
a CBD company and you know why don't you
start in about your own personal usage
of CBD and relate it to neuro protection
if you would do and do if you did indeed
you to use it that way well I think
probably most of you guys have read the
studies done by dr. McCollum and the
profound effects of the cannabinoids and
the brain and how they act as a neuro
protectant and an antioxidant you know
as a guy who consumed cannabis
throughout my NFL football career and a
guy who suffered you know handfuls of
concussions having my bell rung and I
was lucky enough never to be knocked
unconscious some of these guys might be
able to tell you a little bit more about
that but obviously concussions are an
incredibly prevalent issue with football
it's something that happens every single
play every single player is smashing
headfirst into another guy probably 6070
times a game so this is clearly
something that we need to find a
solution for I mean they've even done
studies that say 97% of the guys that
played in the NFL
are gonna come out on some scale with
CTE that's pretty scary being a guy who
spent 15 years in the game six years in
the league I was a very violent player I
don't think anybody gets that level
unless you're incredibly physical and
willing to put your body on the line
that being said you know the way that
concussions are dealt with is guys are
basically
sequestered your UCM walking around the
facility they'll have sunglasses on they
won't be allowed to go to meetings
they're not allowed to practice you're
not really allowed to do much of
anything you're kind of just stuck in a
dark hole somewhere in the training
facility but that being said like there
needs to be a solution and there is the
data there is the research we've seen a
every guy up here I think is an example
of the efficacy of cannabinoids on brain
trauma I know that I am very grateful
for my cannabis used to around my career
because really I came out of my career I
was able to get rid of all the pills I
got off all the pills you know some guys
are coming out of their career on
anti-anxiety meds and antidepressants
and painkillers and all this other [ __ ]
that is really taxing and destroying
their systems and their minds and their
families
you know guys are leaving the house they
can't get home because they can't
remember how to get back you know these
are realities of the game and it's not
just you know like Jim said jr. say oh I
think really shined a light on the
darkness that awaits football players in
their life after their careers if you're
not taking care of yourself if we're not
starting to address these issues with
cannabis because really it's the only
solution we're looking at and it needs
to be changed we need to start growing
up and looking at real solutions to
keeping these guys from losing their
minds and their lives
I think in this realm cannabis and
football is so interesting to study in
regards to brain injuries because on the
football field your most effective
weapon is your head and the higher up
you go the more your coach to attack
that other human and put him on his ass
and the way you do that is by hitting
him with your face as hard as you can
especially a guy who's larger so you
know you're gonna have repetitive head
trauma every day every week so how do
you treat that inevitable head trauma
and half of the guys are already using
cannabis but they can't tell anyone
about it the other half are not so how
do we study what's working for who in
the middle of this repetitive head
trauma every day so these guys have to
come out of the shadows to feel
comfortable sharing that data and that's
the only way we'll learn anything about
it I think and and beyond it you're
talking about neuroprotection and CBD
does the neuro protection however the
other thing that unfortunately this the
football players are getting is toradol
toradol is a nonsteroidal
antiinflammatory platelet inhibitor so
these guys are getting platelet
inhibitors getting hit in the head
causing concussions microbleeds in the
brain causing effects that yet they
don't even know what the result we know
what the results are but everyone lines
up for the T train yeah so in 2003 I was
playing for the for the Dolphins and so
2002 and 2003 I let the NFL and touches
and if you've ever seen me run I'm a
very physical runner so I was I was yeah
thank you so I remember sitting in the
in the training room one day for
practice okay and watching guys come in
one by one to get their toradol shot or
to get their pills and it occurred to me
like wow we need this strong
anti-inflammatory just to practice on a
daily basis and I decided you know what
I'm gonna see how long I can go in the
season without having to take these
these pills and I was able to make
through the whole season again leading
the NFL in in touches so what what
you're saying is so true and I think
what what Evan touched on is taking care
of yourself and I think for me when I
played and I would take toradol or I
would take vicodin it was more to mask
Payne because I was I was in a lot of
pain and when I used cannabis it was
more to sit down on the ground and to
think about my day to do a little bit of
stretching to release the stress of the
day to allow the inflammation to
dissipate and it was more holistic and
inclusive for me in my whole entire life
and like Nate said earlier it made it
easier to get back up the next day and
go at it again and I think football
players are a great example of people
living extreme lives having to deal with
a lot of different stressors physically
mentally and emotionally but I think all
of us in our lives are dealing with some
kind of stress and in some kind of pain
that inhibits our ability to recover and
heal and approach every day with with
vigor and you guys know like the energy
you have to have and you have to bring
on a daily basis
in the NFL and for that reason I think
we're prime examples of people who who
have through our own experiences have
learned to to use cannabis in a more
conscious way and I think that I was a
lot to do with education and people
telling their stories given that we've
got these wonderful football players
here and we have their attention we
thought we would spend we'll give you
another up until 3 o'clock to do a Q&amp;A
with the football players if you'd like
to we do have the break going on in the
in in sort of the lobby so if you do
want to take a break please feel free to
we're gonna have the QA if you do take a
break please be cognizant we've got the
camera running down the middle aisle
here and over the center but we figured
that we've got their attention so if
we've got questions we can fire away we
do have some mics in the audience and we
can roll the roll the mics around to
everybody who has questions as we one
two there we go as we end this I want it
there's a friend of mine named Steve
DeAngelo who's been a big figure and
almost a mentor to me in this space I
know Ricky's friends with Steve also and
what Steve taught me and I want to just
have this be the parting words because
again it transcends from the pros to
average Joes and every one of us in this
room you know I thought I was a STONER
for a long time and I realized I used
cannabis too
make my mind right and it helped me
study through college it helped me be a
better person it helped me be a better
husband I don't go drink alcohol I go
take little cannabis and I'm a more
engaged dad so when you look at your
cannabis use if you think you're a
STONER take another look at it and look
like there's a reason you use it you
come home maybe you have anxiety you're
tired your back hurts most people that
use cannabis are not stoners there's a
root cause that they use it and it's
because it's a beautiful plant so I want
to impart you on that and and yeah let's
go to questions for these guys and what
advice would you give to pee wee
football errs you know Greer out there
they're out there doing what you guys do
they're imitators and there but in their
heads and my one of my grandson's is
always already been hospitalized so what
advice do you give to them and how do we
approach cannabis as a neuroprotective
that's definitely one of my concerns as
well is you know that the little guys
but it's kind of in the same boat as you
know some kids that suffering from
seizures from epilepsy and so forth and
really should look at more to the CBD
it's more of the you know non
psychoactive part of the plant that
would be in my opinion more suitable for
you know the younger audience and you're
using it and it's also been you know
shown to have those neuroprotective
agents as well as that you know
antioxidants so that's part of you know
why you know I'm a real passionate about
using this platform to cause awareness
and education because it is you know I
don't expect no one to really feel sorry
for me for what I went through you know
we made this choice my biggest issue is
you know going back to the education and
I really think the NFL is missing the
opportunity to be a leader because they
have I think one of the you
best situations to prove out some of
this data for you know the game for
themselves but as well as you know the
general public so again a CBT or the
cannabidiol you heard people speak of I
will look into that more I think the
hard part about youth sports is you are
you are leaving it up to the coach and
and there are a lot of different coaches
that coach youth football some of them
are cognizant of head injuries and want
to see their players healthy some of
them want their kids to knock each other
out every day and you go and watch these
practices and these men whose football
careers didn't work out for them are
living through these kids they're
playing through these kids and that's
when it becomes dangerous some of the
drills they'll do at practice have a kid
running from there and a kid running
from there and meet in the middle
full-speed headfirst that can't be good
for a seven-year-old brain and so paying
attention to the coaches paying
attention to the medical services that
they provide or whatever hospitals or
doctors they're working with and if your
grandson has gone to the hospital for a
head injury consult that doctor and ask
if if he should be keep doing this
considering the way he responds to
hitting some guys are more susceptible
to brain injuries than others I found
that you know one guy will get hit and
pop right back up another guy gets the
same hit and he's woozy and he gets a
concussion so some kids are not suited
for it and we make the mistake of trying
to funnel all of our boys onto the
football field
because it's so popular because it's so
lucrative but not all boys are meant for
it so my personally personal believe is
eight-year-old shouldn't be smashing
heads but a lot of people love it it's
not a guarantee you're gonna have a
brain injury but you just have to be
diligent and pay attention to your child
that's it just one more note on that I
don't think kids should play football
until they're at least in high school
thank you guys for being here my
question is do you ever see a roll of
cannabis being a prevention for so as a
pretreatment before playing because we
do know of an endocannabinoid deficiency
is there a way that we can treat
football players before they go on the
field research being done of pure CBD to
be able to be taken prophylactically
hopefully those studies will come out so
the yes that would be able to like a
pill you take a capsule of CBD and you
take in an hour before they would have
sports and hopefully that would prevent
all the neuro degeneration that we saw I
think was yesterday
and yeah hopefully that's gonna
absolutely happen with pure CBD with no
THC activity whatsoever hopefully I
think it's gotta get federally
rescheduled or D scheduled before the
before the NFL is gonna really jump on
it you know there are 22 teams in the
NFL in which they play in states where
it is medically legal but for those
other ten the NFL is going to consider
that a lopsided product and it creates
an unfair and advantage for one team and
so I don't believe the NFL is gonna jump
all over that argument I think they're
kind of gonna wait and see they're not
gonna lead the charge on a social issue
the NFL just doesn't do that they lag
behind and then react I think it's
what's important is to arm the Union
with all of this knowledge to let them
come to the negotiating table and make
their case strongly as of yet they
haven't been able to do that Ricky was
touching on it they're starting to come
around to it but if they realized how
important this plant is for their league
and how much better it is for you than
what these players are being injected
with on company grounds then they'll
start to come around I will say Nate
when I talked to Dee last week on this
issue and one of the things he said is
the way the Players Association is
approaching it it's not a drug issue
it's a health issue and so they're
putting it on this on par with the
concussion issue and they're saying it's
not negotiable
you know like we shouldn't have to
negotiate to have concussion specialists
on the sidelines we shouldn't have to
negotiate to allow our players to not be
punished for using cannabis Jerry Jones
just stepped out in favor or said he
thinks I think basically it should be
legalized or authorized in the NFL
it's changed happened slowly but having
Jerry step out is one person so
hopefully the rest will follow soon
let's ask a question if I could I'm
Martin Lee the director of project CBD
and you know the study you're referring
to about CBT beam or protective there's
also study about THC being your
protective and antioxidant are you
emphasizing CBD so much because of the
possible legal opportunities there even
though it still is federally illegal it
makes it easier for sure well is it
better I'm concerned about is it better
for people in people's brains in terms
of what cushions well I think right now
what I've noticed least is it seems to
be some kind of taboo against altered
states of consciousness people aren't
willing to look at it or talk about it
so we just say CBD but you know we got a
lot of work to do is very important and
it's more of an Eastern philosophy
instead of isolating compounds from
things in nature let's look at nature
and use nature and and really that is
coming from a totally different
perspective of take this pill to fix you
and and I think that's a good question
because I do I believe for myself I use
THC all the time every day with CBD as
well and it affects for me it helps me a
lot more when there's THC included so I
think whole plant medicine is a really
important thing to think about I think I
think you'll find that's the case with
most football players who use it I don't
think they isolate with the CBD I think
they are believers in the whole plan hi
I have a question I just had a curiosity
while you were playing how were you able
to get guidance as to how to use the
cannabis were you using just
recreational versus medicinal grade and
could you talk about the difference no
guidance you're on your own but for
professional athletes who have been
tinkering with medication in their
bodies and optimal performance their
entire lives by the time you get to the
NFL you have a pretty good idea of what
works for your body and what does and at
least if you are medicating with
cannabis so I I did it on my own I did
it at home I don't know how these guys
did it but yeah it was it was in the
shadows so we did not talk about it at
work my name is Janice Knox and I am
mechana md's and also represent the HD
clinics which stand for American
cannabinoid clinics and I have two
points I want to make and why does that
athletes are incredible role models so
you guys are incredible role models for
all those young boys who are playing
football so my question is here what are
you doing to get the current players to
come out of the closet because they are
role models and even if you can't
because you're not clinicians advise
people to take CBD or THC or any of that
looking at the current football players
playing and role models admitting that
they use this for their health reasons
can you imagine what that would mean to
parents to coaches to to young kids
playing so my question is what are you
doing to encourage the current players
who may be using cannabis step out of
that closet I think just continuing to
do stuff like this continuing to get our
voices out there continuing to show guys
that it's safe to share your stories and
it's safe to talk about obviously the
current players have a number of hurdles
obviously one losing your jobs and then
two endorsements and all the companies
that sponsor these athletes you know
there's a lot of risk of having those
things pulled but I think you know this
this panel this this advocacy that we've
been doing it's grown probably over the
last two years since the first time I
stepped foot in a cannabis conference
talking about my experience and we're
just I think we're going to continue to
do that we're pretty passionate
dedicated guys to we want you know our
brothers in the leak to understand what
this is all about and changed the stigma
of what this plan can be
thank you oh hello yes thank you Bobby
West I have a question for you with all
the opiates and painkillers that they're
giving you guys in the NFL
when do they determine that you actually
have a drug problem because they sweeten
you all these opiates and stuff I mean
and it carries on how does it not until
you retire cuz the drug problem while
you're playing is a good thing it means
you're on the field so they have
basically they look at it where hey long
as you can play it so as you can plan
you stay out of trouble that that's the
NFL's main thing beyond the field stay
out of trouble so you can stay on the
field thank you I mean it's a political
issue and I think that well you guys may
know that there was a Harvard report
last year about NFL and and pain control
and there were two main conclusions one
that pain and and medical treatment and
the use of opioids versus cannabis
should not be something that's in the
collective bargaining agreement it
shouldn't be something that's negotiated
because it's about health it's not about
you know benefits some sort of selfish
motives on the parts of the players that
was one conclusion the other is that the
physicians who are examining the
patients and the physicians who are
setting the policy should not be
beholden to the NFL
you actually may have just answered my
question but um I was I was going to ask
how strongly is the opiate usage
encouraged by management staff and if
there were any ramifications for not
taking part in it well it's it's changed
I mean there's ramifications as far as
your being pain unless you can find an
alternative but the rules have changed
in the NFL there's they've gotten so
much slack that they've really tightened
up I mean there's a report out a couple
of weeks ago that they were you know
when you when you give out a controlled
substance you're supposed to take notes
about how much you gave so that you can
track how much someone is taking some
teams trainers did it some teams did it
but you know there was no oversight I
know when I played and I've been retired
for five years but like I said I carried
the ball so much when we got on the
plane on the ride home trainer would
just come up and give me a little bag
with three vicodin so it just depends on
on the team but the history is that
they've people when players are hurting
and they come and ask for it then
they're they're giving it and for me I
didn't have that much experience with
with opioids just a little vicodin after
the game but for me what concerned me
was the toor dhal and the henderson and
the strong anti-inflammatories that you
pretty much have to take almost every
day to feel to feel like you can go out
and practice I just had two basic
question um so I've had two severe head
injuries both are definitely severe
concussions one both of them have taken
care of like some of my long-term memory
and so forth
and I've consume cannabis ever since I
was a child my mother used to use it for
me when I was in her womb when I had
colic and when I was born it's been in
my life ever since I you know my whole
life after my concussions every time I
consumed anything with THC in it I get
unbelievably wretched headaches and
there's this aftermath of shakes and
chills and blurred vision and light
stigmatism but I take 120 milligrams of
CBD every day with less than a percent
THC and it you know it doesn't affect
but have you guys ever noticed any
effects with concussions were THC
because of the increased blood
vascularity or whatever it may be that's
actually increasing the pressures
causing that type of an effect
myself but the important point of that
is that the individual responds to THC
CBD the plan as a whole is going to be
very particular to an individual and so
I have no doubt that you're telling the
truth in that it's happening exactly as
you say but that's the effect on you it
could be completely different for
somebody else with another kind of head
injury yes good afternoon so I'm
wondering have you begun a conversation
with athletic directors high schools or
universities and if you have not how
would you encourage us to go back to our
local communities to share as parents
and participants in the community
cannabis activists what is safe healing
practices with cannabis because as Ricky
stated the zero tolerance it ends your
career it happened to me I got kicked
out of swim team and it jeopardizes your
collegiate opportunities and I think
it's so important that a conversation
begins at that level and if you haven't
started would you be willing to add even
language to your website so that each of
us can go back to our hometowns and say
oh please look at this yeah the amateur
the amateur issue is really hard to deal
with with cannabis because you got to be
21 years old to purchase it not in
Washington State but just advocating it
in schools is going to run up against a
lot of opposition I believe so but I
think it should be a parent issue with
if you believe in this product and your
kid is suffering from things that he
could benefit he or she could benefit
from the use of CBD then go ahead and
reach out to a doctor who can help you
with that but the amateur stuff is hard
when it comes to it because I actually
started using it when I was 14 years old
I used it for the first time about a
month before I had my first concussion
on the football field so my first
football injury was a concussion and I
started using canvas a month before and
my brain feels pretty good
right now and it felt good all along and
I've never gotten involved with the
pills
they never sunk in with me I never had
developed a taste for it I believe it's
because I was familiar with the other
side of the fence with cannabis the
whole time and I knew it worked for my
body now that's not something that
people are going to be open-minded to a
lot of people in high school is that
it's actually probably helping some high
school kids out there but I think that's
down the road I think we need to work on
changing the scheduling of it D
scheduling rescheduling it before we can
start at the NFL and then it will
trickle down we also need to establish
the difference between underage use when
it's for medicinal versus personal use
so we know that underage use
recreationally if cannabis can be
deleterious to development and I know
not everybody agrees with that but
that's my reading of the data is that
the younger you are and the more you do
it at a very young age the greater the
chance there's going to be an issue and
you know with what Nate's saying I mean
I keep starting at 14 I know somebody
who started at 12 or 13 and he just got
his PhD at Princeton and he's a
brilliant guy so it's highly variable
what we don't know is what the effect of
medical cannabis is in underage use and
I know Stacey Gruber she's out there
somewhere they're doing research right
now at McLean Hospital on this issue
trying to figure out is it different for
underage users when they're getting it
for a specific medical reason and
there's some actually there's some
evidence that it may not but we need
more research before you make a
conclusion like that and certainly on on
that note
Stacey's actually our next speaker I'd
love to keep this panel going because
it's been a wonderful discussion I would
like to thank everyone particularly for
coming out of the closet and helping us
move the industry