[Music]
welcome to the CED Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
ameral I am the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and proud member of
the team that puts on the camed
conference well Happy New Year everyone
I hope that year 2024 is off to a good
start we have certainly been busy here
at canmed putting together the program
for canmed 24 right now we are in the
process of notifying our oral presenters
and confirming their participation in
this year's event so stay tuned for for
that announcement it should be coming
out very soon within the next few
weeks but one part of the C 24 event
that has already been announced is the
capital markets Workshop this will be
the second year that we have had the
workshop after received raved reviews
last year once again Golden Eagle
Partners will lead this three-hour
Workshop which will cover the hurdles
issues and Concepts around funding
cannaboid and cannabis Innovation from a
global
perspective and our guest this episode
is David trailer who is the senior
managing director at Golden Eagle
partners and organizer of the capital
markets
Workshop after advising on various
transactions in the life science sector
David took an interest in the Cannabis
sector and started advising cannabis
companies before eventually refounding
Golden Eagle Partners in 2014 to focus
on advising companies across the
Cannabis sect sector before Golden Eagle
Partners David served at leading
Investment Banking firms including
Pacific growth equities Caris and
Company and Headwaters MB during his
banking tenures he has advised private
and public biotechnology and medical
device companies in various transactions
including IPOs public offerings private
offerings mergers and Acquisitions
totaling over 500 million in value
during our conversation we discuss what
attendees can expect from the capital
markets
Workshop redefining cannabis
nomenclature the likelihood the DEA will
reschedule cannabis this year Farmers
growing interest in the Cannabis drived
compounds and challenges cannabis
innovators face when raising Capital
before we get to my interview with David
I want to thank this episode sponsor
Golden Eagle Park
Partners Golden Eagle partners are
transactional experts specializing in
mergers Acquisitions reverse mergers
financings and incremental transactions
such as licensing joint ventures and
co-development Arrangements they have
combined experience in the early stages
of cannabis and life science sectors
which allows them to confidently close
strategic and financing transactions
that match the near and long-term goals
of their clients learn more at
goldeneagle partners.com
all right and without any further Ado
please enjoy my conversation with David
[Music]
trailer good morning David thanks again
for joining us on the podcast good
morning Ben happy New Year happy New
Year indeed um well we are so far what's
that so far so far you know we got this
far well we are excited to have you on
the podcast and excited to have you in
Golden Eagle Partners back for caned 24
leading the capital markets Workshop uh
it's a halfday affair where we talk
every about everything involved in
investing in cannaboid Innovation uh we
had a great respon last year I think
people got a lot of great value out of
it so I think everyone's really excited
to have you back again for Kim at 24 so
before we kind of dive into what folks
can expect at the capital markets
Workshop I want to give you the
opportunity to kind of talk a bit about
your background and why you're excited
to join us at CID sure thanks Ben and uh
I think the one thing to start off with
is yeah we've been one of our things
we've just been lucky uh to be where
we're at because it's hard to predict
where cannabis is going uh and again I
can talk here in a sec about how we
consider cannabis and break that down uh
but the reason why I say we're lucky
because you know last year we we jumped
into the you know organizing the capital
markets Workshop it was the first time
you guys had done it uh we thought it
was important to uh you know uh to
compete effectively with our other you
know big larger investment Banks and we
thought that was an important event to
be a part of and so my background just
fits well into that I have two undergrad
degrees in science got into biotech 15
years of operational experience in
biotech companies and then uh jumped
into Investment Banking
2005 uh and did biotech deals in San
Francisco Ben and then came back to
Colorado where I'm from in 2009 I was
leading a life science group a group
called Headwaters and found golden legle
Partners in 2012 and that's when
Colorado and Washington legalized adult
use right so uh we looked at it and we
consider cannabis to be very similar to
biotech and that's why we jumped in and
so we've done a number of deals 27 28
deals I think in the space uh we've had
cannabis clients on six of the seven
continents uh we've been doing a 10
years actually come uh last over 10
years uh we got into it December 2013
but we've also been doing it uh eight
years come this month our first Israeli
client was January
2016 so uh certainly we are the first
Investment Bank in the US to do cannabis
and again we're lucky to be where we're
at because the industry is just kind of
moving towards kind of the science and
the biotech and that's why we want to be
a part of canmed last year excellent no
and you mentioned that sort of cannabis
seemed like a natural fit coming from
biotech explain a bit about you know
what what the similarities are
there uh yeah well there's there's some
similarities some not but this also gets
to what we just mentioned to you uh
before we joined on this Ben that you
know we uh coming from a you know having
a biochemistry background one of the
things that you learn when you're in
chemistry class that they've started I
think in the late 1800s to come up with
a consistent nomenclature with all these
weird
molecules and uh this gets also to the
DA rescheduling issue but before we go
there I mean that's one thing we wanted
to kind of make a more better more
consistent nomenclature and so we
believe instead of saying marijuana is
cannabis or cannabis is marijuana and
you know can cannabinoids cannaboids you
know potato potato it's been kind of a
mess over the last 15 years yeah uh we
believe cannabis you know is it is the
genus and so we break it down pretty
easily to two sectors THC plus which is
you know delta8 Delta 9 Delta 10 thca
thcv and then you have the THC minus
which is a lot of people call hemp right
which you know you have the molecular
side and then you have the industrial
side and then you can have you know the
molecular side is flavonoids tpin so you
can really kind of uh if you really look
at the cannabis plant you know
flavonoids aren't in aren't just in
cannabis and in other plants but I think
if you set the table that way it makes
discussions uh much more simplistic but
you know looking at the as I mentioned
in the very beginning we saw this uh
cannabis is very similar to biotech if
you really break it down at least the
way way we saw it in 20 12 2013 is that
you know cannabis was is highly regular
ated it's a biological supply chain and
when you get down to
it uh you know it is a
drug right so that in itself I think is
is uh kind of the most most simpli
simple fact about but I think getting
into the other thing that we see the
importance of you know certainly camad
in biotech in
2024 is the fact that we we think that
we what we have Ben is the uh this what
we call call the three spokes is you
have all these amazing molecules as we
mentioned a lot of these different
molecules emanating from the cannabis
plant you have a lot of these
indications or diseases that need better
treatments and then you have each
individual has kind of a different
genetic makeup or they metabolize things
differently and that itself in the whole
thing scheme of things is a is a big
experiment a lot of experiments right
and so our our whole goal is to help
companies we're investment bankers right
so our goal is to help really good
companies that are trying to find
solutions to to provide data to solve
that big puzzle uh and find them very
good Capital so that kind of breaks it
down what we do and why we think
cannabis and biotech are similar yeah
excellent no and it's a great point that
you make there are so many different
compounds that are have potential for so
many different indications and then on
top of that you have the whole idea of
the Entourage effect where there is
multiple different compounds working to
kind of service those those targets too
so yeah it is it's a big project and
it's going to take a a lot of a lot of
smart people which is why we try to
bring them together I can man exactly no
that's and that's why we want to be
involved right excellent now so let's
talk a bit about the capital markets
workshop and kind of what you what you
have planned there so what can attendees
expect uh from the
workshop uh not much it's gonna be the
same it's a no uh well it's uh what
we're trying to do is well the the well
let's get back to the real Genesis is I
remember when I was talking to
Brendan and heard about camed for the
first time and thought well you know
it'd be good for to be a part of that
for the all the reasons we just talked
about but you know be in the previous
incarnations you know canmed was really
all about science which it should be but
you know the other thing is if you
practice you know and look in science
and biotech you realize that you know
it's innovation's not cheap it's
expensive so capital's always a big part
of this and since innovation's now
becoming more important part of cannabis
you know we you know that was proa
finally included in the agenda last year
uh we were lucky enough to beat out C
and steel to be the the main sponsor of
the event last year and that's like you
know last year we essentially did the
first event and you know the cool thing
about it was we pretty much put the
whole program together we had nine
panels
uh we essentially tried our best to put
the best and brightest but also men
women including more women uh because
they're not frankly included enough in a
lot of these panels whether it's
science-based or not in cannabis and so
the original idea was to kind of come
together with a lot of the the topics
that are important and again going back
to biotech Ben trying to kind of
replicate and say okay what are some of
the issues that have been important that
i' I've known about since being a part
of the biotech community back in late uh
1980s and so that includes IP you know
Innovation uh development kind of
looking at the past where we've been
where we're going to go you know talking
about
molecules uh so that was kind of the way
we set the table and this year you know
the interesting thing about camad is
that you guys have done such a nice job
with the event that there's a lot of
great topics going on at different times
or at same time so you know we've cut
down the the workshop to do six
presentations and they're a little Shor
this year but it's it's meant to allow
people to go across fertilize a lot of
different topics which you guys are
doing uh so what we're going to do is we
have six topics they're going to be a
little different excuse me I think we're
going to still include like last year
and this year we're going to still have
a a topic on cultivation or production
what we call alternative production
methods you know whether you're looking
at phyto sources or non-f sources some
people call it uh
um um synergistic compounds or
synthetics we don't really like that
nomenclature but then also another one
that we talked about last year another
topic we had which we're going to
replicate this year's intellectual
property that's going to continue to be
a big part of the industry and so I
think you know and by the by the way for
everybody listening I mean the the the
pro probably the best part about canmet
is the property that you guys put it on
in Marco Island the event is is amazing
the beach is the long the widest longest
beach we've ever seen or I've ever seen
it's awesome white sand too the white
sand uh and you guys also provide enough
time for people to to meet and greet and
so that's you know to be frank you know
we're we're looking at you know we
sponsored we were the lead
sponsor uh last year of what we believe
the most important events in cannabis
globally were uh one was benzinga Miami
another was ICBC and the GIF in Berlin
and then also canmed and uh right now
we've we certainly already committed
we'd like to replicate the same thing
with benzinga and ICBC but we've
certainly already signed up uh for camad
just because I think it's it's kind of a
part of the future of where cannabis is
going absolutely and we appreciate that
and you're right this was last year was
the first year that we included sort of
the investment angle but you're you're
absolutely right that it's it's
essential because research is not cheap
and for folks who are doing research
into cannaboids the sources of funding
are somewhat limited right because a lot
of it being because of the scheduling of
cannabis where you know you can't get
government grants or anything to do
research because it's a schedule one
drug so that is a nice little segue into
one of the topics that um it's really at
the top of a lot of people's minds as we
move into 2024 is this whole idea of the
possib ability of the DEA rescheduling
cannabis from a schedule one drug to a
schedule 3 um was interested to get your
thoughts on that um if you think that's
going to happen when maybe you think
that's going to happen and what does
that really mean for investment in the
uh in the industry well I mean first off
to say I think most people agree out
there that there's no crystal ball for
cannabis uh it's really a hard industry
to predict but that being said I was
looking through some old emails over the
holiday been and pulled up uh some
material that we've been asked to put
together for an ic3 event which is many
people in the no or not in the no but
they've been around the block in this
industry this was in New York in 20
October
2018 and uh Al foran was part of this uh
piece of paper uh that was put together
a number of us were asked to kind of
provide our predictions Tom Zuber uh VI
Desai a number of people and and one of
the things that we came out with looking
at is trying to predict in five years
what the sector is going to look like
one of the first things we started off
with was how many medical states are
there going to be in five years and we
did some simple math but we essentially
said that they're going to be 40 States
in in DC they're legal and Frankly
Speaking if you look back at it right
now and that was October 2018 five years
ago uh we hit the nail on the head
frankly and so not again there's no
Crystal Ball but the other thing that we
like to do at Golden Eagle Partners is
we're very quantitative again I have a
degree in Biochemistry and deg degree in
molecular biology luckily I have three
patents us patents to my name so we're
very analytical and quantitative and so
many of you may have seen uh the piece
that we put out on LinkedIn mid December
on trying to actually apply some of the
data that the DEA you know we looked at
the how many many uh compounds had been
scheduled rescheduled or descheduled in
the last 5 years and it was actually the
answer was
41 and then we looked at you know
applied when of those actually happen
What quarter of uh each calendar year
from 2018 on and uh and then we applied
that analysis to when we may might think
what this might happen and you know
again it's hard to predict but you know
coming of our analysis we thought you
know there's a 10% chance
that uh that it won't even be uh
schedule uh schedule three it might be a
schedule two uh but then if it's a
schedule three then you know when might
that happen what our thought was you
know there's probably 25% chance that if
they reschedule to schedule three it
might not even happen before the
election so that means and again this is
just kind of applying some trying to
sense to it and I think everybody would
agree listening to this that there's not
100% chance that the da is going to
reschedule this yeah uh before the
election uh but that that being said out
of the 75% chance we applied that to the
data that we saw and when these events
happen when the da announces these in
the Federal Register and our analysis
came up with the best chances in Q2 that
it will
be uh rescheduled a 41% chance that
it'll happen in Q2 now we've also heard
people thinking that the da is going to
announce a rescheduling of cannabus on
April uh you know 20th 420 but I can't
imagine that the the da is going to play
to the the Cannabis sector as a matter
of fact one of the points we don't think
they're going to play to the Cannabis
sector and that's one thing that during
the benzinga podcast with Hunter land
you know our thought is it's probably
not going to happen before the election
but one of the data points you know that
not many people saw is I think it was
December 12th just uh less than a month
ago the da announced adding another six
compound to schedule one and these are
cannabis
memetics now they're they're not
naturally occurring cannaboids and
they're not even cannabinoids they're
cannabis mics but mimetics but they do
hit the CB1 CB2
receptor and you know I I don't think
it's out of the realm of imagination to
assume that the da was thumbing their
nose at the Cannabis sector by throwing
these and essentially again to be clear
clear Ben it's a the da put these six
compounds on a temporary or preliminary
schedule one and after a year if they
their finings come to fruition they will
then keep it on or take it off schedule
one my guess is though that most people
don't realize that there are 43 cannabis
or cannabis mimetic canabo Associated
compounds on schedule one right now and
so now let's add to the 43 to the six so
now there's 49 43 was the number before
December uh and now there's 49 the other
thing that's so screwed up about this
whole thing that we we've want to make
him really important is that there's
over 500 compounds that are
scheduled uh by the DEA on schedule 1
through
five and of those there's only one of
those is not a compound that's cannabis
cannabis is not a compound cannabis is a
plant it's a Genus as we mentioned so
this whole thing about trying to apply
analysis and logic to what the da is
going to do this is really hard to do
because again the whole the whole logic
behind this again if you're applying the
the
biochemistry perspective on this
cannabis is not a compound it's a
collection of 500 plus compounds or more
than that probably right yeah and so
having them reschedule or deschedule
cannabis as itself you know it's
ridiculous so sorry that was a
long-winded explanation to it no but
it's interesting and you bring up a good
point one I wasn't aware of about the uh
cannabis mimetics that are on schedule
one but so allow me to play The Optimist
and if if the da if the DEA were to Q2
what's that Q2 but no go ahead if the
DEA were to reschedule cannabis from
schedule one to schedule three but keep
those mimetics on schedule one would
that be potentially a positive for those
of us who are uh you know rooting for
the Cannabis derived compounds because
there'll be three and the kind of
synthetic ones I know you don't like
that term but those will be sort of more
on the schedule one
well and that's a nuanced question
too uh it's you know a lot of well the
easy answer is absolutely with 28 now
the Assumption too is if they reschedule
from 1 to three that that requires that
the
IRS uh then get rid of 28 and as a
matter of fact a lot of people don't
understand that where 28 came from but
we don't probably need to get into that
but it was a drug dealer that got busted
in the early 80s when Reagan was the
president and just said no to drugs but
the drug dealer got away with a bunch of
money because he you know was fast with
his tax returns Etc so they wanted to
stop that but yeah I think uh the easy
answer is yeah if you get rescheduled a
three now if it goes to two the way 280
set up it doesn't do anything but if it
does go to schedule three it should be a
huge help for any plan touching uh
company that touches you know THC plus
as we call it uh in the US because it
should dramatically help their margins
the problem with that too though Ben is
that a lot of these companies that we
know since we've got in been in it so
long have rolled up some pretty
significant tax liabilities so even if
280 do 280e does get rolled back you
know I can guarantee you and I've had to
go to the IRS tax
Court uh on on on a thing before they're
not going to just immediately say oh you
know uh they're gonna forgive all the
back
taxes they're G to still require those
so 28 is going to be an interesting
thing but you know to be frank though
you know that's not a big part of canman
I mean the 280 and a lot of these
companies I mean the the one thing we
want to bring up too is the re the
importance of Biotech in in cannabis is
is incredibly important because in
especially going into 2024 because a lot
of people don't know about Switzerland
so Switzerland we believe is right now
at the Forefront of adult so we're just
talking about adult use and 280 and all
that stuff let's go to Switzerland so
Switzerland is
essentially uh is a has a program they
rolled out just last year just about a
year ago this year that's essentially
adult useth but it's very limited but
it's being tracked very effectively uh
it's being followed by the international
narcotics control board which is part of
the single Convention of 61 the fop
which is the federal Office of Public
Health in Switzerland is on board
tracking this so what they want to do is
have people will use this drug uh or you
know cannabis recreationally adult use
but then also track it over two years to
make sure that there's not any adverse
effects or anything which we know
there's really not going to be and we
think that appli like biotech really
stringent following of the adult use
Market is going to be one of the only
ways we get adult use to break out of
this kind of mess of overregulation by
the IRS overregulation by the UN over
ulation by the U EU over regulation by
almost every regulatory I mean in
Colorado the me still T over taxes
things so we think science and biotech
need to be applied to not only adult use
to but to the medical side to to dispel
a lot of the stigma that still stands in
the way of this amazing plan yeah no and
that's a a great Point kind of talking
about the distinction between medical
and adult use and folks I've talked to
before about about you know if and when
ever we get Federal legalization the
thought is that it will be medical first
before that before its adult use and you
know do you kind of see the the same see
it happening the same way that that's
sort of the first way to do it frankly I
you know what I don't care I mean you
know Matt doery works with me at at GP
thinks you know if we would the industry
would have put more emphasis on the
medical side then then we would not be
where we're at uh can't disagree with
that but you know I think we're a global
firm and what we're trying to do is you
know see how Regulators can open up
things I mean that like CBD in Australia
has been overregulation I won't go into
the full details but uh you know
globally you know we're seeing it kind
of you know uh come out of it shell but
the problem is too and we mentioned this
when I was in Davos in 2020 before the
during the world economic Forum before
the pandemic hit is that there's uh
three things we learned in North America
that might apply to Europe and one of
them is that geographies almost always
roll out a lot slower than you expect
them I mean if you look at Germany you
know they were expecting a year ago that
hey we're really talking about adult use
and then it continued to get stalled and
stalled and then they thought it might
be really going gang busters by now here
January 2024 and just in December last
year that got stalled off and again
we're talking about adult use yeah but
again I think let's get back to the main
point about canm it's about applying
technology and biotch to this amazing
plant in these compounds to find out
which compounds do which things and if
we can apply more really good data
behind all these different compounds
that are coming out then it will help us
dispel a lot of the
stigma and that and that is what we need
to do to get the regulator stop over
regulating to people have people new
adopters
adopt uh and for example there's a lot
of compounds that I haven't used yet
that I think that could be good for me
but it's hard to know which compounds
out of can cannabis compounds or
cannabinoids are good for which things I
don't even know that right yeah no and
there's a lot of them and that I know
that we're going to have a number of of
talks this year that are talking about
flavonoids so not not even canavs or
chines But but flavonoids so you know
the the number of different compounds
that have are showing potential it just
seems to be growing and growing every
year yeah well the other thing to talk
about 2024 and can that will be
interesting is that you know we're going
to be golden eagle Partners I'm going to
be at JP Morgan next week and JP Morgan
has become the de facto leading
conference in the
world uh as a matter of fact last night
I had a late night call with a leading
generics company out of India and
they're head of global uh Innovation is
going to be in San Francisco and
hopefully we'll have a call or a meeting
with them uh I used to be an investment
banker in biotech in San Francisco as I
mentioned and it was the biggest week of
the year you know when we're talking
about just biotech when we're talking
fizer we're talking mck kessen we're
talking large and small and biotech and
it's always been an interesting read of
how people see biotech but I think for
us it's going to be really interesting
because we haven't been there I haven't
been uh to JP Morgan since I got into
cannabis and it'll be interesting to see
what the the Scuttle butt is because you
know we do have meetings with some of
the leading Pharma
companies uh we have two clients that
are going to be there one client is out
of Australia that's trying to complete a
phase three clinical trial CBD and
another one's out of Canada that's
trying to start a phase one and do
preclinical with uh treating PTSD with
sosyan and eugal so again this is this
also and we've been in psychedelics for
three years too Ben just we we can't
cover all this in 30 minutes but again
the psych the Psychedelic sector is the
same it's the same it's it's same and
not I mean you know there there's a lot
of differences between the sectors but
the whole idea of trying to apply data
and really good High Fidelity data to
psychedelics to find out which compounds
can do which things for which people is
is this is the same same issue that we
need to overcome I believe yeah for sure
no and so you mentioned Farm so is there
a a growing interest in in cannabis from
the farmer
folks uh well I mean you know one thing
that people don't appreciate is the fact
that fizer and a Abbott Labs did quite a
bit of work back in the day and I even
think Ro did too in the 80s uh 70s and
80s uh and then they stopped and so I I
know these farming companies are looking
at it I think one of the big questions
with Pharma has been the fact a lot of
these compounds don't have composition
amount coverage which is usually a de
facto requirement by uh by Pharma to to
to do that to to find uh you know to
they need that to to support the drug
development of a drug okay I'm sorry
what is that oh sorry so composition of
matter coverage so when you have patents
you know mainly that you can break it
down to a method of use or composition
of matter and so method of use is like a
molecule and say okay well I'll use this
molecule for asthma and that coverage
can be tough because you know kind of uh
going after litigating somebody on how
they use it is tougher than saying okay
we have this molecule we have
composition of matter coverage which
means the the makeup of this molecule is
covered under patents so it's a much uh
more clear much more uh tougher thing to
get around although some people have
been able to get around stuff like that
in the past uh but you know it's it's
anybody's guess I mean that's why we're
going to JP Morgan Ben is that you know
it's it's hard to uh you know it's hard
to predict I mean we we talked to one of
the leading uh large Pharma VC
firms uh earlier this year less than six
months ago and uh I've known her for 20
years before I got into cannabis and I
asked her you know or them you know what
they about cannabis and they said they
essentially said still no and they said
well we don't have a stated interest so
you know and that's I'm sure that's not
just that company it's a lot of these
companies that they they a lot of these
Pharma companies are always looking at
Innovation and they're always need to
look at new areas uh to attack and to
make money a lot of people don't like to
hear that come from Cannabis because a
lot of people uh from Cannabis are um
you know are purist and I get that and
as you mentioned you have the Entourage
effect then you have the big the big
cannabis play too uh I think what we're
still trying to do though is help the
small companies and the private
companies come up with the appropriate
data or the business plan or you know
like for us you know we're not built on
data Golden Eagle Partners we want to
build a firm too that that can't be uh
run over by a Goldman Sachs or maril
Lynch uh we think we maybe been able to
achieve that with a relationships we
have globally and the expertise we have
going back to the 80s but that's no
guarantee we're not going to get run
over by Goldman when things maybe roll
back and that's same thing with any
small company in cannabis doing science
or otherwise adult use or medical right
right yeah and so I guess kind of to tie
it back all back to the uh the workshop
here so is that really sort of who
you're tailoring this this content for
is sort of the the small company who is
is starting up and is looking into some
of these novel compounds and they're
looking for funding they can come to the
workshop and kind of learn some best
practices to the best way to to get some
funding no actually it's meant to go
across the Spectrum it's meant to reach
out to biotech companies it meant to
reach out to Pharma companies it's meant
to reach out to small companies it's
meant to reach out to PNG you know
companies that are not biotech or Pharma
oriented that are out on the outside
looking in because what we've all been
about GP Golden Eagle partner has always
been about Ben is is help Prov providing
you know trying to find the best capital
for the best companies whether it's
inside or outside of cannabis and that
also means to be the purveyor of
objective information to a lot of these
companies that are on the outside
looking in that don't understand the
sector and frankly we understand it
better than a lot of people and and
Frankly Speaking whether it's a big
company or small company and they want
to get into cannabis the smartest thing
that they could do is come to Gold Neal
partners and say what should we do
instead of trying to go in there and
throw a lot of money at it and lose it
because I can guarant guarantee you one
thing is for sure in cannabis there's
been a lot of money lost by people that
have been too arrogant and with too
little arrogance and too much too too
much arrogance and too little humility
it's a fact so if if companies want to
understand the Canabis sector better
especially where the science is going
then yeah they would be prudent to show
up at the the cital markets
Workshop excellent well I think that's a
that's a good place to stop but before I
let you go David I want to give you a
chance to um plug any resources or
websites or anything that you think
might be um relevant to the folks who
are listening who want to learn more
about what it is you you do or want to
learn more about what they can expect
from the capital markets
Workshop uh thanks Ben no well I they
can if they want to learn more about the
the Capal markets Workshop they can
certainly go to CED uh 2024 website they
can come to www Golden Eagle
partners.com they can looked me up on
LinkedIn David trailer it's uh uh you
know you can look me up on a number of
uh different platforms but LinkedIn is
mainly what we use uh we we always
interested in taking the time to uh
connect with people as we mentioned we
had a good conversation last night to a
a global generics company that you know
is looking for ways to get smarter and
that's what we try to do so absolutely
yeah and I want to put links to that
LinkedIn post that you had talked about
talking about rescheduling um and the
podcast that you mentioned you did with
Hunter land I'd love to put that in the
show description so people can uh find
that and listen to those sure that'd be
great all but thanks for your time Ben
thanks yeah you too and can't wait to
see you down in Florida yeah I'm I'm
looking forward to it unfortunately it's
a few months out too bad it's not next
week it it it'll be here before we know
it no doubt all right thanks for your
time all
right
[Music]
New Hope you enjoyed my conversation
with David trailer check out the links
in the show description to learn more
about the topics we discussed and thanks
again to this episode sponsor Golden
Eagle Partners our next episode drops
January 24th that's 2 weeks from today
in the meantime go to camad events.com
now to learn all about the latest
information around the camed 24
Innovation and investment Summit while
you're there please sign up for email
alerts we will be announcing our full
speaker lineup within the next two weeks
and if you sign up for email alerts
you'll get that right in your
inbox I also invite you to follow us on
social media we are on Instagram
LinkedIn Facebook and Twitter just
search for cam at events and lastly we
appreciate it if you would rate review
And subscribe to the podcast on
whichever platform you use to consume us
all right until next time stay safe stay
healthy and be sure to join us for the
next C Coffee
Talk
[Music]