okay hello i am keith allen from front
range biosciences i'm going to talk
about something that's a little bit
different from what was in my
abstract but you know time moves on and
sometimes the science moves on with it
so what i'm going to talk about is gene
families underlying oil content in
cannabis specifically the cannabinoid
synthase
family and the terpene synthase family
i'm going to talk about just a little
bit of
of stuff
with that so the
objectives of this talk we've been doing
a bunch of work in both of these areas
i'm going to share some recent results
on the structure
the expression and the evolution of the
cannabinoid synthase family and put this
into the context of the larger
berberine bridge enzyme family and take
a quick peek at variation in the terpene
synthase family so i want to start with
a paper that came out last year um
origin and evolution of the cannabinoid
oxido
gene family excellent paper by van
veldson and schranz
so the oxido cannabinoid oxido cyclase
gene family is
the berberine bridge
enzyme family these are these are oxido
cyclases this is evolutionarily it's a
very old family that makes a variety
of um uh
plant
uh secondary
metabolites that tend to be in the 2025
carbon range or about the size of
cannabinoids so what they did in this
paper that is uh so useful i think
is um they took advantage of the fact
that we now have complete genomes for
cannabis humulus trema and parasponia
uh which um
together are the are the uh canobaceae
clade depending on how you um define it
uh
so if you're looking for the origins of
the cannabinoid synthesis
it's reasonable to ask
did the expansion of this family
happen
in cannabis itself or did it happen
earlier perhaps in humulus maybe in
tremor or parasponia so what the authors
did
is they looked for synthetic
relationships and they were able to find
in cumulus and in the other two species
they were able to find the region of the
genome that gave rise
to the cannabis to the cannabinoid
synthase
pathway and follow this through
with the satanic relationships and then
uh see basically so what happened here
was
cannabis inherited
well this big berberine bridge enzyme
family but there was one gene in
particular that ended up going through a
series of duplications
in order it originally gave a founder
set of cannabinoid synthases and then
there were subsequent duplications
that produce the family structure
that we have now so that the really
interesting finding of this paper is
that
the cannabinoid synthases
did evolve within the species cannabis
um
itself
and that's kind of an interesting thing
um in and of itself so looking at
uh the berberine bridge enzyme family in
cannabis
so this is doing
what i did here was gene discovery on a
cs10 genome
the reference genome and what i'm doing
here is
the um
this the genes that already have a name
that are published in the literature so
thc cbd
synthase of the cbc uh synthases um they
get a name
everybody else gets a number and that
number is the percent identity
to the thc
synthase then i've used um
expression data libraries that were
published in the
break at all paper on the kanba 2
genome
this is a nice set of libraries because
they have trichome flower libraries then
female leaf male leaf
and roots so you can do a little bit of
of tissue specificity kinds of questions
so
um
what i'm
running here that the kamba 2
expression data this is from a type 2
plant so you've got more or less equal
expression of thc and cbd synthases
very little expression
of the rest of the cannabinoid
genes but you look across the rest of
this of the berberine bridge enzyme and
cambio2 is a little bit of an outlier
because you have stronger expression in
trichomes
of some of these particularly this this
one at 43.503
but pretty much across the board you see
pretty
healthy levels of expression of these
completely uncharacterized burning
bridge enzymes in trichomes but also
elsewhere
elsewhere in the plant you see big
differences between
female leaf and male leaf and you see
that most of these berberine bridge
enzymes are expressed in the roots
these are secondary plant metabolites
which are primarily about
communicating with the environment in
one way or another so it's interesting
to see what you know what they're doing
in roots
if you look at this one down here 88.398
it has pretty healthy expression in
cannabis trichomes i don't see much of
anything anyplace else it turns out
this gene
is
about
85 percent identical to cbdas 88
identical to thc as
it's
not full length um it's missing
um it's missing the start codon part of
the um
secretions
uh signal it doesn't go all the way to
the stop codon and it has several stop
mutations in it stop codons
in it it cannot make
a functional protein
it's a pseudogene
but it's highly expressed well or at
least
has fairly reasonable
amounts of expression
so on that topic of expression here i'm
looking
using
the expression data published by zager
at all so this is nine different
trichome libraries
um only one of these
cannot sue here is a is a type two and
you see um expressions split between thc
and cbd synthase
but basically that the two big guys
um
which
we never see these present in more than
one copy
but they tend to have i mean to really
dominate
expression
overall
you also see that this pseudogene
there's always a certain amount of
expression on this thing and in some
strains it's actually can be
quite high
i have no idea
what this thing is doing but pseudogenes
express pseudogenes frequently play
regulatory roles
um and so
it's something that will have to be
looked at uh more to figure out i just
throw this out as you know
something that i found along the way
that
could be playing an interesting role
here
i don't know at this point what that is
so
in thinking about the evolution of the
cannabinoid synthases
from trauma
humus cumulus and parasponia
sequences
what i've done here is i've done an
alignment
of
just the active site residues
um
this is determined from the crystal
structure and this is things that are
close enough that they can be
interacting with either the the fad
molecule that is covalently linked into
the active site of these enzymes or with
the substrate itself and in the case of
the cannabinoid synthesis that's cbga
or the the varen
equivalent of that so looking across the
active site
um
there's
a bunch of things that are um pretty
well um um conserved like a hundred
percent um um conserved and
you know 50 of the residues in this
alignment are 100 conserved but some of
these so hiss 114 sis 176
here
and here
these guys are covalently linked to the
fad
they're a hundred percent conserved all
the way out to trauma
some of the others here
this tyrosine 417
they propose
is and this is from the shoyama
at all this is the crystal structure
paper they propose that this is involved
in hydrogen bonding and his 292
is also involved in hydrogen bonding
of your cbga
substrate here
his 292
well
you know it's replaced by an arginine
in the out species that could play the
same
hydrogen bonding role
tyrosine 417
is a tyrosine and humulus it goes to a
phenylalanine
well that could be doing a pi bonding
role but it couldn't be doing the
hydrogen bonding rule
these are probably
well it's hard to say it's hard to say
what the specificity of an enzyme is
going to be just by looking
at the active site but that's kind of an
important difference the most important
thing tyrosine 484 here this is the
catalytic base that
rips off a proton and starts the
reaction that leads you
to your uh your final product tyrosine
484 right here is conserved all the way
out uh to trauma
and amparismonia
so to take this a little bit further now
looking at um
both of these plots are going to take a
little um a little explaining here but
looking at how the cannabis um genes
compare
to
trauma parasponia what i did here is i
took all of the cannabis genes and this
is the entire berberine bridge
family here and i compared them
to
trema
and i says what is the percent identity
of the top hit
in trauma and that's
on this axis here is similarity to
trauma and then i also compared all of
them to thc synthase
um and this is again percent um
identity to uh thc synthase so this guy
out here at 100
that is thc synthase down here that's
the cbd synthase these are um the
clade c
genes back up a step because i've
forgotten to tell you
a part in thinking about
the uh
this paper the other thing that the van
velsson paper did
is
um they came up with a nomenclature for
talking about
about
the entire clade structure so basically
um
thc
and cbd constitute their own clades
the cbc synthase uh
uh group constitutes its own clade
and then these guys at 88 percent that
gets called clade c i tend to call them
the 88s but clade c
is is a better name for those
so
this is clade c
these are the cbc synthases and they're
all at around 58
identical to their top hip these couple
of these it's at 60.
so what you see here is a basically the
more you look like thc synthase
the less you look like anything from
parasponia or trauma
or cumulus and some of these genes that
are down in the 45
identity
to
thc
these are really very similar
uh to their their counterparts um
uh in uh
in in in the out species so this kind of
drives home a little bit more the part
where
the evolution of this family really
happened in cannabis
in the cannabis species and so that's
why these guys are going completely off
on their own and are getting further and
further away
from um
you know from the genes that they um
originally evolved from
so the next step in this is looking at
the kinds of changes that have happened
going i'm not showing you the complete
alignment but basically taking this set
of sequences and now aligning
the full sequences these things are in
the range of 545 amino acids long
they're all pretty much the same
the same length so an alignment of of
all of these is a nice well-behaved
thing so i went through this and i
looked every time in the alignment there
was a change say a to s a
to phenylalanine a to leucine
any of those changes what i did was i
kept track i wrote some code to use a
substitution matrix the blossom 62
substitution matrix
to sign a severity score
basically how big of a change
was this blossom 62 if you run a blast
search
at ncbi by default blossom 62 for a
protein
search
that's the substitution matrix that gets
gets used and basically what blossom 62
does is it it tells you i mean exactly
what i'm looking for there
how serious of a change um has taken
place here so if we just look at random
you just
basically just take the whole matrix and
say what do all the changes look like
generally
a score of zero means you don't lose any
points in your alignment it doesn't hurt
you but most of the time
you get a negative score if you just a
random change in amino acid
usually
it's going to hurt you
in terms of similarity to the original
um
the original protein and conservation of
the function of that protein sometimes
some of these scores
you know you can get a positive score
for a mis mismatch um leucine to
isoleucine um
for example
but usually
it hurts you now looking at
the berberine bridge enzyme family
including the out species and looking at
all the changes that happen there a
substantial shift
toward more positive scores that happens
here and in fact doing kolmograph
smirnoff test with the
standard test to compare two
distributions like this
i get a p-value on this of you know 2 to
the minus 16th which is tells me that
these are definitely different
distributions
what this tells us is that the evolution
of the family happening in cannabis
took place under selective pressure
that's the only way you can get
a departure from random
like what we're seeing here is if there
has been some kind of pressure on on
this
to push it that way
i think that's pretty interesting we've
suspected this for a long time but it's
nice to have it
actually
actually demonstrated and let me think i
think this is almost last thing i'm
going to tell you about the cannabinoid
synthesis um i went in
and i looked at the promoter regions
um
i used um uh the the meme suite um
to go in and then then i use there's a
a database of um arabidopsis
transcription factor binding
that have been experimentally
determined
and so i used the arabidopsis database
and went in it was a two-step process
to
map binding sites
within the promoters and you get a ton
of binding sites and i assume that a lot
of those are false positives and then
the second step is to go in and ask for
which binding sites occur more
frequently than you would expect
at random and that's that's what i'm i'm
showing here and so i'm showing you
examples of so the thc synthase and it's
you know from the start codon here at
zero to minus a thousand thousand bases
um
upstream and i'm showing it to you from
three different um genomes here and
basically
all the thc synthases look very similar
all the cbd synthases look very similar
but
they look different
from the thc synthase again the same
thing with cbc synthases there are some
differences
that you'll see but it's a different
picture
than the other two and again for the
clade c
so
this doesn't tell us a lot directly
about exactly how are these guys
regulated
but it does tell us that there are
that these guys are going to
respond differently
to
the regulatory environment because
they've got different different sets of
of binding sites in their promoters now
speaking of that regulatory environment
i just went in and i pulled out
a bunch of cannabis transcription
factors
and this was by similarity to a set of
arabidopsis transcription factors
um
i've now used um
both
the um the zager trichome libraries and
a set another set of five libraries
from judith booth at all and a little
bit more recent paper so i'm looking
across 14 different
trichome
mrna uh
data sets here
and
and then each of these genes i'm just
giving it um
whatever in my mouse i'm just giving it
the name of the top blast head i don't
actually know that much about
what these are so if you look at the
variation that's that's happening here i
mean basically
ah it doesn't look like there's that
much consistency going on but you need
to remember that rna-seq is kind of a
blunt instrument
and so basically anything less than
about four-fold is not really
a statistically significant
difference
and most of these vary by less than
about five-fold
so you say generally for most these
transcription factors you've got a fair
amount of consistency in how much of it
um
uh you know what it what is the
the expression level of this thing
but saying that most of them are
consistent
there's a substantial set of these about
a third of them
where
the differences that you see between
different trichome libraries is between
one and three orders of magnitude
so this is some of these are from all
the way off to
on at a pretty good level
so
part of the differences that we see
between different
different trichomes in terms of the
phenotype
it can be traced straight back to
the
the transcriptional regulation
environment
okay i'm going to switch over now to the
terpene synthase this is a slide i've
been using for a while
this is um i think it worked out to be
samples
this is when uh uh i was at steephill
labs we were testing labs so this is
mostly recreational
cannabis samples coming in the front
door for testing and having
a terpene
profile
done on them so the terpenes are ranked
here
by
total
amount mercine
caryophyllene limonene pinene you know
being
the most abundant ones
one of the interesting things about this
is like for mercene the number of of
enzymes that make mercene it's hard to
get a zero mercy in plant but you do get
some
that have not got very much that's kind
of interesting but you look down here at
terpenoline
when terpenoline is on
it tends to be really on when terpene is
on it tends to be the dominant
terpene
uh in that plant but there's a lot of
the time there's a lot of these where
there's
little bits
and there's a number of these where
there's
none
well it turns out
there's two enzymes that we know about
so far that make um terpenoline one of
them makes it as a side product and it's
not a lot
and the other one tps
makes terpenoline as its major
its major
product
and i'm going to in the interest of time
i'm going to
keep going here so
looking at
terpene synthase expression again this
is going across the same 14 trichome
libraries
you see large changes
in the amount
of expression
but you look at some of these like tps20
it can go from very strong
to zero
and
well
what's going on with that so
i think this this is close to my last
slide
um
what i did
we began to suspect that there was
substantial presence absence variation
going on in this family so what i did
was
i pulled together
six different genome assemblies and then
i did a gene discovery run using um
genome threader and exonerate
and then as my as my
bait i use the complete set of known
thc or
a terpene synthase
genes
so and in terms of gene discovery
the more similar
your bait gene is to what's in the
genome the higher the probability is
that you're going to pull out what
you're looking for so this is really
shooting fish in a barrel
if the gene is present in the genome
i'm going to find it
so looking first at
the
um the tree here so this works out to be
um about 46 genes but it's
it's hard to say exactly how many
terpene synthase genes there there are
in cannabis because every every line you
pick up has a different number
and then you have all of these genes
that
you know they're they're not the same in
each plant so you gotta ask you know
five snips it's probably the same gene
20 snips is it the same gene or is it
not it's kind of hard to tell
uh
so in terms of
the structure of this family um you've
got your uh
clade b here
this is um your monoterpene synthesis
down here
clade a
these are sesquiterpene uh
synthases and then clay g
these can make a mixture
of either and then the little
dots here the dark dot means that i was
able to find a chloroplast import signal
on it
and
the yellow dots means there was one well
the sesquiterpene synthases stay in the
cytoplasm
the monoterpene synthases go into the
plastid which is where
gpp
is made which is the precursor for the
monoterpene synthases
running out of time here but basically
what i found
is that so this is a heat map that is
not expression this is the number of
genes that i found within a 95
percent identity so light green means i
found one
white means i found
zero
medium green means i found two and then
dark green is three or more
so
and they're not necessarily identical
some of these like
tps 9
over here in jamaican lion there are two
copies that are almost completely um
identical some of these that's the like
you know 96 percent
identical
to each other
but uh
there is a tremendous amount of presence
absence variation going on here and tps
37 was not present in any of the genomes
that i looked at we have now
we've gone past this and we've we've
determined uh using pcr approaches uh
that
tps37 has strong presence absence
behavior and the reason some plants
don't have tropinolane is because they
lack the gene completely okay i need to
move on pretty quickly i'm running out
of time
so conclusions
while the cannabinoids are not specific
to cannabis the gene family responsible
for their production in cannabis seems
to be a specific innovation of the
species
the thc and cbd synthesis don't appear
to ever be present more than one copy
but the other two clays cbc synthase and
clad c groups are quite variable
in copy number each clade within the
cannabinoid family has its own promoter
structure
the evolution of the cannabinoid clade
occurred under strong selection
pressure
and there is substantial presence
absence variation in the terpene
synthase family and this along with the
expression
uh is is probably adequate to explain
the range of phenotypes that we see and
then in particular the on off behavior
of trapinolane seems to result from the
presence or absence of tps37 and that is
the end of my time thank you very much