[Music]
Welcome to the Canad Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science, medicine, cultivation,
and safety testing. I am your host, Ben
Amalt. I am the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on the CANMED
summit. Speaking of CANMED 25, we are
less than 80 days away from the event.
So, if you are planning to join us in
Puerto Rico this June, don't wait to
register. Our room block at the Windham
Resort is filling up fast and you do not
want to miss out. I believe we are about
70% full at the moment. Also, flights to
Puerto Rico are going to go up in price
as we get closer to the event. So, book
now and save a little money. Speaking of
saving money, I do have a promo code
that you can use to get $300 off of your
ticket package. Think of it as a thank
you for being a podcast listener. Use
the promo code coffee talk, all one
word, and get $300 off of your ticket
package. So, like I said, don't wait.
Pause the episode, use the link in the
show description to register. Pop in
that promo code coffee talk, all one
word. Get $300 off, and get ready to
join us in Puerto Rico for CAMED2.
And if you're still on the fence about
joining us for
CAMED2, I invite you to go to
cammedvents.com and check out all the
latest details. We have our speaker
lineup, our schedule, as well as our
unique networking opportunities that are
designed to connect you with the leaders
who are shaping the industry. While
you're there, also sign up for email
alerts to make sure you don't miss out
on any announcements between now and the
event. Our guest today is Michael
Peterson. Mike has over 38 years of
experience as a researcher and mentor in
both the private and public plant
biotech space. He has over 50 issued
patents and his work in plant
transformation and gene expression is a
passion. Mike has worked on many genetic
engineering and gene editing contracts
with entities across the globe. and now
he focuses on innovative hemp research.
At KMED2, Mike will share his team's
latest efforts to transform cannabis and
hemp plants using gene editing and
genetic engineering in a presentation
titled creation of novel traits through
genetic engineering and editing of
canabonoid tarpine and flavonoid
pathways in cannabis sativa.
He'll also be participating in the KMED
genomics workshop along with other
experts in plant
genomics. During our conversation, we
discussed the differences between gene
editing and genetic
engineering, how gene editing and
genetic engineering methods have changed
over the years, potential applications
of gene editing and genetic engineering
in cannabis and hemp. the benefits and
challenges versus traditional breeding
and the Wisconsin Crop Innovation C
Center's gene editing service, which is
available to researchers and
cultivators. Before we get to my
conversation with Mike, I'd like to
thank this episode sponsor,
canipedia.net. Canopedia.net NET is the
world's most comprehensive cannabis
genomic library, featuring more than
2,200 genomic reports on cannabis and
hemp varieties from around the globe.
Canopedia.net reports are easily
searchable and contain visualizations
and variant tables that highlight high
impact variants in genes of interest.
For example, you can see a report for
the Badger G variety that Mike
Peterson's team edited to break the CBD
synthace gene. In fact, you can actually
see the dropout in the CBDA coverage
chart on that report, which is pretty
cool. Visit
canopedia.net. That's
kn.net today to learn more.
Okay. And without any further ado,
please enjoy my conversation with Mike
Peterson.
[Music]
Good afternoon, Mike. Thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast. Hi, Ben.
Thanks for having me. excited to talk
with you today about gene editing and
genetic engineering in cannabis and hemp
plants. Uh, as I was telling you before,
it's an exciting topic, a controversial
topic, and probably a misunderstood
topic. So really excited to have you on
here to talk through some of these
things and um really give a nice preview
for the information that you're going to
be sharing this June in Puerto Rico as
part of CAMED 25 where you're going to
be sharing a lot of the work that you
and your team are doing on this topic
and you're also going to be a part of
our genomics workshop talking about
advanced breeding techniques. So we're
super excited about that as well. I'm
glad that we're keeping you busy.
Um, but uh before we get into sort of
the nitty-gritty here, I want to give
you an opportunity to share a bit about
your background and how you became
interested in cannabis and hemp
research. Sure, sounds good. Um, just
first off, I I really look forward for
CANMED 25. Last year was my first year
at CAM Med. Uh, and it was really
exciting. Really good conference. Lots
of good science, uh, lots of medical
stuff. So yeah, really looking forward
to uh sharing what I what our my team's
been doing in the last uh year up here
at uh Wisconsin Crop Innovation Center.
So uh but a little bit about myself. Um
I've been in the you know the the the
genetic engineering or molecular biology
uh all my all my career. So 35 plus
years. Uh I graduated from the
University of Wisconsin Madison with a
bacteriology degree. uh joined a a small
startup right here in Middleton,
Wisconsin, just outside of Madison,
where back in the early 80s, we were
basically really just trying to
understand how we could genetically
engineer plants or put genes into plants
to to make new traits or to enhance
traits that were that were already
there. Um, so spent a number of years
trying to figure that out and we
actually did uh we we invented a what
people call a gene gun uh that actually
put genes into plants and we were kind
of off to the races then um looking at
different uh traits mostly in row crops
at that time. So soybean, corn, uh those
types of things. Um the company was
bought uh I think about 10 years after I
joined it uh by a larger uh agricultural
company. I worked for that company for
20 years doing pretty much the same
thing. So gene engineering um and
editing came along after that. And then
uh recently in 2017
uh the the facility that I work in which
I've I've been here since the early 80s
uh was donated to the University of
Wisconsin Madison and I came along with
that uh to be the associate director of
the facility. Um so we called it the
Wisconsin Crop Innovation Center. Um we
right there and then basically became
the largest uh public facility that
offered uh both uh institutional people
as well as private companies uh access
to uh put their favorite gene or their
favorite trait into whatever uh crop
that they wanted to to put it into. So
for five years I was the associate
director of the facility. Um and then it
kind of gets into why I why I got into
cannabis. Uh so back in you know 2018
when the farm bill or 2017 18 when the
farm bill came to pass uh Wisconsin
farmers uh a lot of them in 18 were
going hot because of THC levels being
too hot. They had to destroy their
fields. So, there was a big outcry uh to
see if if there was any anything we
could do either in breeding or
engineering uh that could lower the THC
amounts in in cannabis for growers and
farmers in Wisconsin particularly and
and other states that that uh were into
CBD. Um so, so the Wisconsin the WCIC
uh since it could do lots of other crops
and was already doing it, we decided to,
you know, get our feet feet wet in in
cannabis and give it a shot. Um so uh
shortly after we started luckily we were
able to do it with sim similar protocols
that we used for other uh other species
like soybean. Um so you know from 2018
on uh we've been offering this as a
service to others that uh want to do
editing and uh gene engineering in
cannabis. I was just I was fascinated by
uh the cannabis plant. I never touched
the cannabis plant until probably 2017,
believe it or not. Um, and the plant
just has so many uh interesting
qualities um and potential uh to hit so
many different areas uh in our economy.
It's it's just it's really neat. So, I
actually I actually uh in 2021, I think
I I semi-retired, but I was so
interested in cannabis, I came back
part-time for two days a week, and my
lab's been been doing cannabis research
since then. Excellent. Excellent. So it
seems like that first problem that you
were tasked with solving was sort of um
either eliminating or turning off that
THCA synthace gene. Yeah, that was the
ask by the growers uh in the state and
that's really what kind of it was the
spring springboard for us to get into
seeing if we could if we could do it uh
through engineering or editing. Yeah.
Excellent. Excellent. And now now you
mentioned a gan gun.
What what is that? How does that work?
Yeah. So, so back in the 80s, um, there
were, you know, some different competing
people trying to figure out how to put
genes into plants. Um, someone at, I
believe, at Cornell came up with the
idea of, hey, let's let's
let's shoot genes through plant tissue
and see if they will if the the genes
will recombine in the plant. So they
actually devised almost like a a
crossman air gun, right? Where they they
they coded DNA, which are genes, onto
beads and they actually shot them uh
into plants. Um and that was that was
the first official gene gun. The one we
worked at here used um electricity to
propel gold beads that were that were
coated with the genes into plants. So
actually, you know, almost like a
shotgun approach uh to put genes into
plants. Yeah. And now at what stage of
growth are the plants when you're kind
of hitting them with these genes? I
imagine it's got to be pretty early on.
Yeah, it it it can it can vary widely
depending on what crop you're trying to
put the genes into. Some plants you
start out with very small protolasts,
which are single cells that you're
putting the gene into. They don't have a
cell wall. it's fairly easy to put the
gene in and then those protolasts like I
said in some species you can make grow
into a full-size plant right um other
species are are re what's called
recalcitrant to protolast transformation
cannabis is one of those um so we start
out with our group anyway starts out
with a small embryo so it's basically
the embryo that's within a a mature seed
you embibe it overnight in water, you
soak it. And if you've ever soaked seeds
in water, you start seeing a little a
little uh chute coming out of it, right?
That's the root radical, and that's part
of the embryo. So, we take that embryo
and we we can actually either introduce
the DNA with the gene gun into that
embryo and then that embryo will grow
into a plant like like we do with
cannabis or we use a different method
other than the gene gun. And this is our
our our favored method. We use a
bacteria that in nature naturally
infects plants and delivers the DNA uh
into the cells called bacterium. So
you've sort of hijacked the mechanism in
that bacteria to deliver this DNA.
Exactly. Right. Yeah. Yeah. We take out
certain genes that the bacteria would
normally insert into the plant and we
put in whatever gene uh we want to put
in whether it's a gene that affects
yield or uh insect resistance or you
know whatever that may be or a a gene
that could knock out THC for example.
Interesting. So now what is the source
of the gene that you're sort of um that
you're injecting? Is it sort of um
synthetic synthetically created or how
does that work?
the sky's is the limit. Um you can take
you can you know DNA is DNA um whether
it's your DNA or a bacteria DNA or plant
DNA uh you can take an existing gene uh
from another plant let's say u and and
put it into cannabis. um you know people
that would be a a a genetically modified
plant in by definition because you're
taking a gene that is from another plant
that normally wouldn't uh cross or
wouldn't breed with cannabis. Um so
that's considered a genetically modified
organism GMO. Um or in our case if we if
I again use the example of our our THC
free line um we actually just we
manipulate the gene that produces the
THC or and the CBD in in our case we
manipulate that. So we just turn it off
by by taking a single base from the DNA
out of the gene that makes the THC. And
that's and I don't know if we'll get
into that, but that's that's gene
editing. Um, and in our case, we use uh
a system called crisper casts, which uh
a lot of people are starting to hear
about, right? And so that crisper
um method different from the one you
described earlier where that uses the uh
the bacteria to sort of put the the gene
into the genome. Um it the way that you
put the the DNA into the genome is
exactly the same. So you can you can
either shoot it in with a gun or you can
uh have it delivered through
aggraacterium
transformation. But in a GMO case,
you're just taking that gene and
inserting it into the into the cannabis
plant and it'll and then it expresses or
makes the trait. Um with the crisper
method, you're introducing the actual
crisper. So it's an enzyme. It's a it's
an en enzyme that basically cuts DNA
like a scissors and you have a targeting
piece of RNA. It's called a guide RNA
that goes in with the crisper enzyme in
your through agroacterium transformation
goes into the plant cell and then that
guide RNA sits down on whatever gene
you're trying to edit. Right? So it sits
down on it and then the crisper enzyme
comes in and cuts it right at a precise
location. So in our case, we were
targeting the the CBD synthes, which
that's the enzyme that actually makes a
little bit of THC in CBD in type three
cannabis, right? So we were targeting
that CBD enzyme with that guide RNA. The
crisper came in and cut that CBD gene,
right? And when you cut a gene and it
doesn't come back together exactly the
same way, it shuts it off. So now that
enzyme is not active. It can't turn CBG
into CBD or THC anymore. So the plant
that we made was basically THC free, CBD
free, but it had a lot of CBG, which is
the precursor uh canabonoid to both THC
and CBD. Interesting. Okay. So same
delivery um mechanism. It's just instead
of introducing a new gene, you're
introducing the enzymes and everything
for that comes along with CASP. Exactly.
Crisper. Yeah. Yeah. And there are other
delivery methods that people use, but
that, you know, the one I described with
the gene gun and the aggroacterium,
those are the most most common.
Excellent. Very cool. Yeah. And I think
you sort of started to and and maybe you
did a good job, but I maybe want to um
uh just re-emphasize sort of the
different terms here and defining them
of like what is genetic engineering,
what is gene editing and sort of um you
know clarify those. Sure. Sure. Yeah.
So, so genetic engineering um is is I
guess is kind of defined as moving a
gene from one species to another. So for
instance, if I maybe if I give an
example. So back in the mid to late 80s,
uh the papaya plant was basically being
decimated by a virus called ringpot,
right? So the all the Hawaiian
plantations were were being devastated
at the time and they couldn't breed in a
a good resistant or bring in a good
resistant line. So the University of
Hawaii and uh Cornell I believe
identified a gene um not from papaya but
a a gene that would be resistant to the
papaya ringpot virus. So they put that
gene and this was actually with a gene
gun. um they put that gene into papaya
into a papaya plant um and and found out
that yes indeed that plant was resistant
fully resistant to uh the ringpot virus.
So that since that gene didn't come from
papaya, that's an example of a GMO or a
a genetically modified organism, right?
So now, you know, I don't know if you
you knew or people most people don't
know that, you know, most of the papaya
plants that we've been eating since uh
the late ' 80s are GMOs. Um but it's
it's it's you know, that one particular
gene that gives it resistance to that
papaya disease. Excellent. Another
example maybe, you know, is is a purple
tomato that came out recently last year.
Uh they came out with a purple tomato.
That was another uh genetically modified
tomato that was made through
aggroacterium transformation, but it
just put basically in genes that uh were
anthocyanin genes. And so they're making
purple tomatoes.
Excellent. And and on the on the flip
side, gene editing is is a little
different because now you're basically
just removing a little bit of sequence
or or adding sequence that's already
there into the existing cannabis plant
from its own genome. So you're not
bringing in an external gene. You're
just either, you know, cutting it and
deleting a few bases or bringing in a
gene that's uh that's in cannabis
already to give it a different different
trait. Okay. Okay, so that's the main
distinction then engineering introducing
genes from a different plant. Editing is
um just
editing the existing genome in that
plant. Yeah. And I guess a way to look
at it is the way that that um I guess
the FDA or USDA look at it is is um if
if the plant can be made by normal
breeding. Um because through normal
breeding, you know, when you take two
plants, two cannabis plants together and
breed them, there's going to be a lot of
shuffling of different genes and
amongst, you know, amongst their
genomes. So if it's if it's something
you can make through normal breeding,
which editing is because you're just um
you know taking out or adding a few
bases of its own genome, then they
consider that editing
and Yeah. No, and that's that's a good
point too in terms of um you know
regular breeding. It mixes up all the
genes and everything. So once you that
you've edited or engineered a new plant,
how do you go about propagating that
plant to ensure that um you know its
progeny inherit those traits? Yeah. You
know, it's really no different than than
traditional breeding. Um you know, you
you insert either the gene through
through genetic engineering or change it
through editing and then you find out,
you know, what the progyny look like,
what it what its children look like. uh
the next generation, you grow those out
in the greenhouse. Subsequent
generations, you grow out um and you you
look at what they look like. You
phenotype them, you genotype them
through uh sequencing uh and and just
basically, you know, see, have you have
you introduced the trait that you think
you're going to have? Um and then and
just take it out multiple generational
to see if it's stable, see if it does if
it doesn't change over time. um and then
eventually uh bring it to market or
launch it. Excellent. Um now you
mentioned before that you know you
started on different crops and then sort
of are applying it to cannabis. Is
cannabis any more or less difficult to
work with when you're doing editing or
engineering?
Yeah. Um for sure. Uh cannabis falls
into I mentioned you know the word
recalcitrance. Uh cannabis falls into
that that um definition because you know
we work we work in tissue culture either
with protolast or with embryos in
sterile culture right cannabis is a
plant that if you start out with a
protolast or start out with a leaf um
it's very difficult extremely difficult
to take that leaf and grow it into a
plant. It doesn't respond very well to
different hormones and things like that
to actually grow into a full-blown
plant. Um so fortunately for us um at at
at at this center we focused on that
embryo. We a lot of the a lot of the
plants we work with we focus on that
merist stem or that embryo uh to do the
to do the work with. And fortunately for
us, cannabis um if you take that embryo,
that embryo can grow directly into a
plant um be be uh fertile and h and have
progeny and transmit the its its genetic
makeup to to the children. Interesting.
Lots lots of groups are doing, you know,
tissue culture work. They're struggling
with it. I think um there's been a lot
of breakthroughs in the last few years
to figure out how to uh make those
recalcitin uh plants grow into plants.
So there's a lot of progress there I
think in it won't be too long uh in
cannabis uh people able to do that with
cannabis. Excellent. But is there
anything about the genome that makes it
any more or
less difficult or is it all sort of
ATC's and G's? Yeah, not really. Um, you
know, it's got a fairly small genome.
It's a diploid. Um, I don't think people
know to this date, uh, and maybe I'm
wrong here, but, uh, why certain plants,
uh, just don't respond well to growing
up, you know, from a single cell start
growing up into a into a full plant. Um
it's it's
definitely if you use that tissue
culture method when you're trying to
insert genes or to edit plants um
sometimes that tissue culture method
only works on certain genotypes. So a
certain cannabis genotype um may may
respond better in tissue culture than
another genotype. Yeah. For for our
embryo system we can basically do any
genotype. It just because you're not
starting out with that single cell,
you're starting with embryo. Uh we can
probably do I would say most genotypes.
Yeah. And now is that something that's
maybe more unique to cannabis and hemp
is just sort of the d variety of the
different cultivars that there are out
there.
Um you know, there certainly are a ton
of varieties out there. Cannabis is one
of these
um it's not it's not an an inbred uh
plant there. there there's so much uh
mix up of the genome and and most of the
cannabis varieties you have now are very
hetererozygous in nature. um they're not
like, you know, a corn or soybean where
you have inbredads, you cross these two
inbredads and you get this beautiful
hybrid plant, right? Um people are
really working hard in the cannabis
industry to get to those h that that
hybrid vigor uh by make trying to make
these inbredads, but it it'll come
sooner or later. But uh it you
know the thing about cannabis is
nobody's really been working on it you
know other than other than the folks um
you know that smoke it and and whatever
for 80 years there's been just no
research and thankfully in the last you
know five or 10 years that's really
starting to pick up um and I think a lot
of things will change you know for the
better. Excellent. Um, so I guess
briefly, can you explain some of the
benefits of genetic engineering and
editing over traditional breeding
techniques and and possibly some
drawbacks?
Um, benefits I think uh I I think it can
be a faster way to uh get to your end
point. So you know breeding takes many
many many years. um back in the 50s,
60s, 70s, many years, you know, pere
breeders, traditional breeders would go
out in the field and say, "Yep, I like
that plant. I like plant. Let's cross
them. Let's see what we get." Then
molecular breeding came into play where
everybody knew genome sequences and they
could pick out certain genes to put
together that they would, you know,
postulate would work really well. That
that speeded breeding up quite a bit.
Genetic engineering and editing, you're
targeting, you know, very specific genes
that you want to change. you're not
fiddling with with with much else. So
getting to that um getting to that that
final point is I think much quicker can
be much quicker than traditional
breeding because you're not bringing two
um uh dissimilar plants together. You
know, one may bring a lot of baggage,
right, with it and then you've got to go
through multiple generation to get rid
of that baggage. through genetic
engineering, you're just targeting that
that single gene or that that single
thing to change um and then see how it
how it changes. So, I think speed is
probably one of the big things. Um and
and you know, now that we know the
genome sequence um targeting those
particular genes is becoming much
easier. Are there any ever any like
unintended consequences of of kind of
changing or turning off a gene that kind
of affects something you weren't
expecting? Yeah. So far, I haven't had
any plants walk away on me. Um that's
that's what everybody, you know, back
back in the day was the Franken food,
you know, stuff. Um sure, there's
there's always there's always
um things that you don't expect um
because it's research. Um you may come
up with the best plan in the world and
you know there are thousands and
thousands of genes that interact with
each other. So by shutting down one
gene, you know, maybe you've got
different regulation going on and it's
not exactly what you would expect, but
you learn from that, you go forward. Um,
and then, you know, you try again. So
there have been lots of times where I
don't know if I'd I'd say, but um things
just don't work. You know, you think you
you you have a solution. Yeah. It just
doesn't work. Not sure why. You you you
go back to the drawing board and try to
figure it out. Yeah. No, but to your
point, I mean, it it must be much
quicker to iterate on some of those
those errors or misses rather than sort
of going through generations and
generations of breeding to finally
figure out this didn't work, you know.
Exactly. Yeah. Excellent.
Um, so step, so looking sort of big
picture here, um, how do you think gene
editing will shape the future of the
cannabis industry?
Um, I I think I think and I'm going to
probably use these both handinand
whether it's gene editing or whether
it's genetically modifying something.
Um, again, I think we can get to end end
points quicker. Um, I think we can start
thinking out of the box as far as what
we might be able to do with the cannabis
plant. Like I said, you know, for 80
years we haven't done any research
really or not not much research. I
shouldn't say any
because breeding breeding cannabis for
THC was remarkable, right? We've got
plants that are 30 plus THC plants and
that's all through through breeding and
and trial and error and stuff. Um, but
thinking about what the plant may not
may not do on its own very well. um
thinking about some of the rare
canabonoids that a lot of the you know I
saw last year at Can Med people were
interested in
CBG CBC
some of the THCV or CBDVs you know
things that the plant doesn't make very
much of we might be able to breed that
might be able to you know through many
years and many iterations of breeding
get to that point but I think with all
the information we have um with the pang
genome out there now we can really
narrow narrow down on how to make a
plant that's got, you know, uh 15 to 20%
CBC, which you know, we don't have
something like that now. I think uh uh
pharmaceutical companies would be really
interested to see, you know, what that
could do. Um make a plant that's disease
resistance, has disease resistance. PM
is is is out there, hopen vyroid is out
there. you know, are there are there
ways we can quickly try to uh change the
plant so that it's so it's doing
something it wouldn't normally do uh on
its own? Um and then not to speak of all
the other all the other things I think
um that are outside the medical world,
right? Uh
the industrial hemp I think is huge
steam and I it's it's all a matter of
time before we're growing hemp just like
we're growing uh corn and soybeans, I
think.
Excellent. Yeah. And so you mentioned
the service that you offer there at the
University of Wisconsin where you we'll
actually do sort of gene editing um for
companies or researchers or things like
that. So I mean I if you can divulge
what sort of traits are they interested
in in uh creating?
Yeah. Um so so we do we do work for
other people but we also have some
internal work going on as well and
that's what I'll I'll be presenting at
at CANMED this year. Um, but I hear a
lot of people uh like what I just said
are interested in a lot of the rares um
or something that you know the the plant
just doesn't produce very much of. Um
I've heard can flavven talked about
quite a bit. You know can flavven A and
B plant makes just a just a little bit
of it but they've been implicated at a
lot of different you know potentially
cancer cancer research um all kinds of
stuff. Um, and a lot of the rarers as
well, you know, inflammation. I hear a
lot of that for CBC, CBG. Um, and then,
uh, other interests might be, uh,
nutrition. Uh, you know, seeds, hemp
seeds, can can we, uh, make them even
more nutritious than they are? Can we
add certain amino acids that may not be
there for chickens, for instance?
Um and then you know industrial hemp
again
uh can can we can we make uh you know
the hemp plant uh sequester heavy metals
more than it does because we know it
does somewhat. Can we make it even
better? Um capturing carbon. Hemp hemp
is a wonderful you know it's a it's a
wonderful sustainable plant and it's got
a huge root mass. Um, and I think it's
be a great target for capturing carbon.
Wow. Yeah. A lot of lot of potential.
Yeah. Excellent. All right, Mike. Well,
winding down here. Before I let you go,
I want to give you the chance to share
any links or um resources that you think
that anyone listening or watching this
might be interested in reading more
about. Um, I'd be happy to put the links
in the show description so that they can
learn more. Uh, so please plug away.
Okay. Well, for sure I'll I'll plug the
Wisconsin Crop Innovation Center. So,
like I said, I've been here a long time.
We've got a service that we provide. Not
a lot of people know about it, and it's
probably because I I'm not a I'm not a
good marketer. I'm a scientist. Uh but,
uh you know, we provide this service. Uh
and I think we're one of the very few uh
that are able to actually edit um and
transform or or engineer hemp. There are
a couple others that are just now saying
they can do it. We've been doing it
since 18. We're very good at it. Um, so
and we do offer it as a service. So,
anybody can come to us and say, "Hey, I
I want to make a a powdery milde
resistant line and here's how I want to
do it." We'll take their gene. We'll
actually we have a a group here that
does molecular biology. we can make the
plasmid that we would put into the hemp
plant and then we would deliver you
plants um out the back end that you can
do research on or or whatever you want.
So I can give you that link um um to to
post on there and people can reach out
to me directly. Um excellent. And
definitely if you're interested in any
of these topics, we invite everyone to
come to to Canmed this year. Not only
will you hear Mike give his oral
presentation, but like I mentioned, we
have the genomics workshop, which is
going to be a a really great session. I
think we have a lot of heavy hitters and
a lot of the leading minds in um in
cannabis genomics. So, we're really
excited to have that and excited to have
you part of it, Mike. Great. Super.
Thank you very much. All right. Uh
thanks again and I look forward to
seeing you down in Puerto Rico. Okay.
We'll see you then.
[Music]