i am excited to be here today to the
oh it's like 30 of you left
to talk about thcv and some plants that
we're developing that our high thcv
let's see
there we go so philos is a
crop science company we are developing
new cultivars and also seed grown plants
that are uniform and can be planted out
in a field or your greenhouse
not pheno hence seeds but ones that will
give you consistent results
and
we've
built
this program off of evaluations of tens
of thousands of cultivars we
have
great relationships with some legacy
breeders and have unlicensed some of
their varieties and pay royalties on
those varieties as we use them in
breeding
i think that's important to mention in
this
industry
we also have
a pretty big focus on minor cannabinoids
and trying to bring those into the
majors so that we can see high levels of
cbdv thcv and others
and we have a pretty
serious focus on uh
customer support for new
growers that have been growing all
different kinds of plants
at their farms before and are ready to
move into cannabis and so we're trying
to bring them into the world of growing
cannabis
so today i'm going to talk about
thcb
i think a lot of you are probably very
familiar with this cannabinoid but i
want to talk just a little bit about
what it looks like
so thc is on the left
very familiar
there are only
two different there are only two carbon
differences between
thc and thcp so it's just got a shorter
side chain than thc makes a pretty big
difference in how it interacts in the
body and what kinds of receptors it
binds to and and how it activates those
receptors
but they are very similar looking and
you'll see
in the pathway for creating these
cannabinoids they
go through exactly the same pathway same
enzymes
so
this slide actually i would say thcb is
a really promising cannabinoid i don't
know if it's the most promising
cannabinoid i mean cbdv is amazing you
saw talk about cbg today
for topicals and skin irritations i
think that there are so many
cannabinoids like ones that daddy mary
is talking about that no one even knows
about that have potential even at super
low doses for being important in medical
applications
so
correct that slide and say that it's
promising cannabinoid
so there have been a few
clinical trials there's been a fair
amount of pre-clinical work in
laboratory and
rodent models to look at the potential
of thcv
so
this is a listing of
papers that or studies clinical trials
that have shown positive
responses for different diseases or
afflictions there are some
that have negative results and i think
that the conclusion that i've come to is
that dosing is really important so we
need more studies more doses really
looking at what it takes to get an
effect and where this cannabinoid is
going to be useful so you can see that
there's evidence for anti-convulsant
activity could be useful for epilepsy
from a hill at all paper in 2010 um a
lot of people talk about thcv as being a
skinny weed
and
you know i think the jury's still out a
little bit but uh but there definitely
seems to be better control for
blood sugar
some other markers of diabetes insulin
sensitivity glucose tolerance and then
there is one study that shows that there
are appetite suppressant effects
although there are other studies that
show that there is not an appetite
suppressant effect
there is a study that shows that
there may be improved social and
cognitive behaviors in the schizophrenia
model
and then
also
improvements in neuropathic pain and
finally something that i think is really
incredible is that it's it's a potential
for
treatment of pd but also for
reducing disease progression so not just
symptoms but possibly important for
slowing that disease down
so
like i said
these are
a lot of pre-clinical trials very few
clinical trials
um some of the clinical trials have used
very small doses and i think that you
know like i said before dosing is very
important and we need to look at more
doses they're doing a clinical trial
right now just to look at safety and um
and tolerance for up to 200 milligram
doses so that'll set the stage for doing
clinical trials with more
levels more arms
and then
oftentimes in the rodent models or in
the cell-based systems they're using
really high doses
actually i list the casio
paper and that's a you know two
milligrams per kilogram which is not
super high for somebody like me that's a
60 milligram dose yeah it's kind of high
but some of them are like a 25 milligram
per kilogram dose and that's like 1500
milligrams of thcv i'm not
i'm not convinced that
that that's going to be realistic in a
human mode and a
human model in a human clinical trial so
i think that we need to do
more studies more clinical trials look
at different doses
um i think that there is a recreational
potential also for thcv
and we're doing a little
observational study right now to look at
responses to
being active or sedentary
to being
interested in food and you know what
your appetite is like and then looking
kind of at the
just a
a sense of joy and and how you're
enjoying
a particular product with an even ratio
one to one of thc and thcv so so we're
doing that it's small
but i think that we also need a lot more
observational studies to look at the
effects of thcv as a recreational
recreationally
important
cannabinoid
so
the problem with thcv though is that
it's it's typically found in really low
percentages there are reports of some
cultivars having up to about seven
percent thcv
when we went out and looked um at what
was out there we were seeing
i mean obviously you see many varieties
that have zero but for the ones that had
them in some level it was about a half a
percent to four percent so still pretty
small amounts and so if you want to make
a full spectrum extract and put it in
something some kind of an edible or
something like that
um
you're still looking at having to
produce a lot of biomass to get to that
level of
of extract that would be
viable as a product
so we would like to bring this
cannabinoid into the majors we think
that it is important for medical and
recreational applications
but what do you need to do that you
really need the trait to be heritable
you need to have natural variation for
the amount of thcv we do
marker assisted breeding but that's all
on natural variation
needed to not be phytotoxic when it goes
to higher levels and we need to
understand that chemical pathway that
goes from the precursors all the way
down to the cannabinoids so that we know
where to look for genes that are
important for making this cannabinoid
so i'll start with the
with the pathway so i'm starting at the
top kind of and so you have these two
precursor molecules butanoic acid and
hexanoic acid and those eventually get
down
all the way to the bottom
and you get your either pentyl
cannabinoids the ones that we talk about
a lot thc cbd cbc
or you get to the varins
and so they start either with the
hexanoic acid for the pentals or the
butinoic acid to get down to the varens
next step so they're using the same
enzymes to get there so they have these
different starter molecules
and then they're using acell activating
enzyme
with the different starter molecules to
get to the next step so you can see
already they have this difference in
this carbon tail
so right at the beginning you've already
got the difference that you're going to
see in the end
and then you add you know
another
molecule
to myelinal coas and you add two more
enzymes and they're these same enzymes
and so then you get to diverinolic acid
or all vitolic acid depending on which
starter molecule you had
final step
is gpp on a parental transferase
and
taking those down to get to i'd say the
mothers of all cannabinoids we have cb
cbgv
and cbg
and then that final step is you're using
these same three enzymes these same
cannabinoid enzymes to get to the final
products either the three variants or
the three cannabinoids and please i know
that i'm simplifying this a lot there
are probably
140 160 different cannabinoids that we
know of now i'm only talking about a few
of them but what i'm just trying to
illustrate here is that you know we
start with this these two different
molecules and then use all the same
components to get down to the bottom
so what happens to get to those first
bits that seem like they're the
important determinants of the kinds of
cannabinoids that you're going to make
we have to go all the way back up to the
fatty acid elongation process and i
don't want to go through this whole
thing but the important thing is is that
it's starting at these really base
molecules and for butanoic acid to get
to the varens it only goes through the
cycle one time so it only adds the two
carbons on the end but to get to
hexanoic acid to get to your standard
cannabinoids it goes through the cycle
one more time just to add two more so
every time it goes through the cycle it
adds two more carbons to the end
so
this part of the pathway which sits on
top of what i just showed you
is what's really important for making
those precursor molecules
so
bottom right there that understand the
chemical pathway i think we have a
pretty good handle on that it's some
really like low level stuff right this
is important stuff for the cells
and then for these other things that are
really important for us to bring this
cannabinoid into the majors
we see natural variation for thcv we've
seen it all the way from a range from
zero to about six percent
um in our hands we only had zero to four
percent to start with um we see it as a
heritable trait so when we look at a
family it segregates in the family so
you see some plants with none some with
a little bit and some with more and then
for phytotoxicity we're making some
assumptions here but we know that
cannabis
thc can go to
35 or more percent of the plant
by dry weight and is not phytotoxic so
we think that for thcv we'll have no
problem getting that to a higher level
so we use marker assisted breeding
we find genetic markers that are
associated with the trait
and then we can use that to
grow a lot more plants than we could by
standard methods so if we have these
markers that are associated with a trait
we can grow tiny little seedlings
in 0.2 square feet per
seedling plug instead of having two
square feet per mature plant
and we can get you know 50 times more
plants processed in that way than if we
had to grow them all to maturity so
probably telling you things you already
know but it allows us to go faster
because we can grow more plants
so
after we
have tested them then we're able to
select for those plants that are
predicted to have high levels of thcv
grow them to maturity and test them
so the first part of this
is discovery of the genetic markers and
this is an example just with
photosensitive and and day neutral
plants that i wanted to go through just
really briefly to kind of describe what
we're doing
but we take a plant that say is
photosensitive one that's day neutral we
cross those
the f1 plant there is heterozygous for
being photosensitive and day neutral and
then you
stealth that plant
all the chromosomes
get mixed up recombination happens and
you can look for plants that are
day neutral
and look at what genetic markers are
associated with that trait and so you
can see here we've got these two little
day neutral plants the little p little
peas and they both share a marker
that on both of their chromosomes that
allows them to be day neutral
all right so we're doing this with um
we have thcv
crossing a no thcv plant with
a plant that makes some thcv and then
selfing the f1 and same kind of thing
letting genetics do its work to help us
identify this association between the
phenotype and the genotype
all right so our first
shot at this
we i feel like we got kind of lucky so
this was a population of plants that did
not make very much thcb at all
initially
that wasn't even the point of doing this
of making this family but we made this
family
and it's segregated for having no thcb
versus having some
and
and we use qtl mapping on this family
first made a linkage map with all the
individuals and then we had cannabinoid
data on 142 of those so we were able to
make a qtl map we found one really
strong peak i was shocked i can't
didn't expect for this to happen
and so we started taking a look
at
some additional germplasm that we had
you can see that for the qtl map you get
you know with 142 individuals you have
this giant swath of a chromosome
hard to pin down exactly what's going on
so what we needed to do was to go into
additional germplasm and uh
and look for and use the plants
recombination to mix up all these
um
all the genetic information so that we
could really see what's associated with
the trait and so we had
302 accessions from 67 different seed
lots did nested association mapping
that's like a combination kind of
between
qtl mapping and genome-wide association
studies that's making use of family
information but it's also making use of
the fact that you have lots of
recombination between the different
families
and
of those they still had pretty low
levels of thcv
but we were able to confirm that spot on
chromosome 4
and um and could start to narrow down
what gene
was likely responsible and it turns out
it's a gene called kr or fab g
and um
it is
part of
this fatty acid elongation chain pathway
so we got really fortunate with
our populations even low levels we were
able to do this
low levels of thcv
and then
we were able to identify a gene that is
in the pathway very likely to be
the gene that is responsible for
having some production of of thcv
i should note that an australian group
uh also
reported on this at relatively the same
time and voila they found kr as well so
um two independent
groups finding uh the same gene
all right
so what do we know we know that
in order to produce
thcv or cbdv or cvgv for that matter all
the same precursor you need to have this
particular allele of the kr gene
and that you can have either one copy of
it or two copies
and then
you know we have very low levels of
variants but we know that they get much
higher so what explains much higher
levels besides just making more
cannabinoids well it must be other genes
so we knew that we needed to do more
work and so we
looked at
additional small families same kind of
process
we also had another f2 population
and
evaluated those in the same way
we also did have some african land race
seed lots that showed some segregation
for varanz which is
where we think that the initial
varanz were located was in
southern part of
africa so we did that and what we
required is that all of the plants had
kr the kr
allele that would allow for production
of varin and so we first restricted to
that so we knew that every plant should
produce some thcb or cbdb
but um what we wanted to get at were
additional genes that would elevate that
that cannabinoid and so we found um
genetic markers on five additional in
five additional locations chromosome one
four six and um two markers on seven
seven is where we typically find the
cannabinoid synthase genes although
different location on the genes
and
we had in some of our crosses two
accessions that were positive for the
markers that we found and they can't
contain between ten and a half and about
eleven and a half percent barrens
so that is good news
so
what are we doing we are um continuing
this
cultivar development of high
thcv and cbdv
plants
we
we have
done additional validation and
additional crosses and in our validation
we found that
one of the plants had all the markers it
looked so positive so promising and then
it only made four and a half percent
thcv so
it's clear and then
sort of another thing is that we had a
plant that made 14 thc
and so
and it only had four of the markers so
very clearly there's something else
going on there are other genes that are
important there's more work to do
um
we're continuing along this path and uh
and hope to to nail this down and be
able to share more updates as we find
them
so the next steps i kind of just
summarize that
we
expect six genes at least to be involved
in in this pathway
we think that they're involved in that
sort of upper part of the pathway where
you're making the precursors and it you
know makes different ratios of the
hexanoic tobu noic acid but then we also
think maybe that there's something in
the cannabinoid pathways where some of
those genes maybe have more affinity to
different
numbers of carbons in the side chains so
there's a lot more to learn
we have
an application that we
that's published for the genetic markers
and we're having to discuss licensing um
we're
continuing to develop plants that have
high levels of barren um just this last
cycle we got two more or three three
more that have pretty high levels of
varin two more fourteen percent plants
and another
uh one to one that's about 11
and the kind of cool thing is that even
though our variant levels aren't going
higher the flower quality is getting
better so a lot of the barren plants
that have been out there have been tough
to grow they're sprawly they're
they make a lot of flower but it's
larvae it's difficult to work with and
so we're getting to plants that look
more like cannabis plants that you might
want to produce from and so it's pretty
exciting
so i want to give full credit to the
team that did all of this work
you see there with the long blonde hair
and the the black shirt that's erica
bocker
um all of the computation all of the
statistics that's that's all her work um
she's
incredible and has really brought to
light
all kinds of incredible findings she's
our senior director of gene discovery
the breeding team the next three people
there john jarrod and becca jared czar
our director of breeding and john's our
vp and
you know they're directing a lot of the
work so that we get the crosses done and
making all those all those decisions
using the markers
and then amy on the far right
leads the cultivation team
and
without a solid cultivation team none of
this would happen grateful for them
every day
it's been great hearing all about
cultivation at this meeting and
nutrients and and just all kinds of the
stuff that i want to take back to them
um and then i also want to mention sarah
she is our chemist and directs the lab
and uh has been incredible to work with
on all of these different cannabinoids
and terpenes that we're studying
and so i want to give full credit
without this team none of it happens i'm
just the person up here talking
all right
i think that's it so happy to take
questions
hey
hi thank you very much for presenting um
i noticed that on the recreational slide
that you talked about thcv
that it mentioned the clear energizing
focused effects and one of the chemovars
that's very well known for having thcv
durbin poison
in its terpene profile its primary
terpene is terpenoline which also has
the exact same description of effects um
was that result was that including
terpenoline or was that thcv on its own
or how did that come about yeah so
that's a great question i didn't mention
the dominant cannabinoids in the plants
that that we've been looking at and um
actually
it's dominant in mercene which is not
great yeah it's trapinoline limonene and
mercin are the three dominant terpenes
for durban i believe yeah so ours is is
myrcene and osamine and
beta-caryophyllene so
wow you would not think uplifting
energizing at all and so that's another
focus of the program is to like put in
those energizing terpenes
okay yes
all right thank you so much
[Applause]