good afternoon thanks for attending my
talk I'd also like to thank the can med
organizers for inviting me here today
the background image on my title slide
is actually not related to the core of
the talk I thought you might like to see
it this is a fossilized cannabis leaf
dating to the Elysian era approximately
30 million years ago the title of my
talk is not classifying cannabis for
genetics but that's okay we're going to
get into that a little bit anyways
[Music]
the title is ethno botanical mix and
cannabis I'm going to focus on the
genomic consequences of economics and
law as forces of selection during
cannabis domestication ethno botanical
word that I made up
it's a portmanteau of ethnobotany which
is the study of plants and human
interactions and genomics which is the
study of genomes so no key resource and
genome research is of course a reference
genome and so I'll spend a little bit
time talking about the reference that I
assembled and released last year the
project design included deep sequencing
of three haplotypes and two components
first the marijuana by hemp cross and
the genome assembly and physical mapping
of CBD rx the genetic map was based on
the sequencing of a recombinant f2
population developed by George we blends
group at the University of Minnesota
first to near isogenic lines were
developed by inbreeding skunk number one
and Carmen for several generations to
make their genomes homozygous these were
crossed produce a hybrid f1 an f1 female
is hermaphrodite is in colloidal silver
and and self pollinated seeds from the
f1 grew into the recombinant f2
population tree sequence with whole
genome low coverage Illumina we also
measure important agronomic traits in
the f2 population such as cannabinoid
profiles and plant architecture in this
slide on the right I show the genotypes
which are indicated in rows of 96 of the
f2 s each of which is indicated
a column in that square on the right is
a chromosome where you see blue those
regions of the genome inherited from the
marijuana grandparent and yellow as
hemp grandparent green is heterozygous
regions of the genome and transitions in
color indicates where crossover events
happen during meiosis in the f1 so each
row again is unique segregation pattern
of genes and have to population which
you can correlate with the segregation
of traits to determine the regions of
the genome contributing to those traits
the cord genome assembly was based on
the sequencing of a highly inbred line
from functional remedies called CBD rx
Todd Michel at the JC VI generated a
total of 100 x coverage of the CBD rx
genome with Oxford nanopore and Illumina
reads the Oxford nanopore minion is a
USB device about the stick of gum the
minion contains protein pores embedded
in a glass plate electrodes measure the
electrical resistance as DNA molecules
pass through the pore which is used to
model the DNA sequence the minion
generates the longest reads of any DNA
sequencing technology and long reads are
essential for assembling repeat rich
plant genomes but have a higher rate at
the nucleotide level so with some of the
long reads in the long context to get
the genome structure right and polished
the configs with highly accurate high
coverage Illumina data to perfect the
nucleotide sequence further satting with
a high C library from phaz genomics and
it ended up with a little less than
2,000 contexts that form the basis of
the physical map
so then I integrated the genetic and
physical maps to produce chromosome
scale pseudo molecules corresponding to
the 10 chromosomes of cannabis the
animation depicted in my slide shows
each chromosome in white with the genes
genetic position on the y axis shown in
centimorgans from the physical position
shown in mega base pairs on the x axis i
also show the recombination rate in red
is very important because it tells us
how tightly linked to positions in the
genome are which is very valuable for
designing breeding experiments involving
marker-assisted selection and for an
evolutionary inference in which I'll
most of the my talk will be on note the
extreme recombination suppression in the
centre of the chromosomes about 90% of
the genetic genetic recombination takes
place in about 10 percent of the genome
so the CBD rx genome was released late
last year and has proven a valuable
resource for the cannabis community one
of my favorite citations is this recent
preprint
that identified the sex chromosome as
chromosome one and their main figure
they share the expression of sex
specific genes and red and blue bars
there now several whole genomes
available for cannabis and we can use
them to cross validate each other on the
right is a figure that Kevin mckernon
presented yesterday in his talk to
synthetic blood of the Jamaican Lyon
Assembly against the CBD rx assembly
these diagonal lines indicate a high
level of agreement and validate the
structure of both so now I'm gonna
switch gears a little bit and put on my
evolutionary biologist hat I'd like to
review some key concepts so be helpful
for the rest of my talk at the center of
the slide is phenotype the composite of
an organism's traits and what I'm
guessing most of you are most interested
in plants phenotype is controlled in
large part by its genes definition of
evolution that I'm using today is change
in allele frequency over time
in an organism's interaction with its
environment is called the the niche the
ecological niche these interactions are
influenced a reproductive success to a
great degree and thus drive evolution at
the population level an ecological niche
includes its habitats such as
precipitation temperature day length
soil nutrients as well as interactions
with pollinators and predators now the
ecological needs of domesticated
organisms also includes his interaction
with human culture how it's used the
demand for its product how the product
is regulated here's a picture of some
wild cannabis drying in its native
habitat and Eurasian steppe this plant
is well adapted to a weedy life history
on this riverbank it doesn't look like a
particularly valuable crop it's short
and branching and makes small flowers
over the past few millennia humans have
selected for composite traits very
different from this and in the process
domesticated to very different crops
here's a picture of some fiber hemp it's
very tall doesn't branch much and can be
mechanically harvested with ease
most of the biomass is allocated to the
stems which the fibers are harvested
cannabinoids are typically undesirable
in fiber hemp and they gum up the
processing machines most hemp is not
very intoxicating so contrast this with
marijuana pictured here in general
marijuana is relatively short branches
more allocates a large proportion of
biomass those flowers the majority of
our precious cannabinoids are secreted
into glandular trichomes here's a
principal component analysis or PCA the
genetic data from about 300 individuals
from four different studies a PCA is a
statistical technique for compressing
millions of genetic variants down to a
few dimensions or principal components
that explain the most variance in the
data each individual is represented by a
single point in the plot and is colored
according to its functional class the
plot shows the top two principal
components you can conceptualize the y
axis is how far along the individual is
in the domestication process the x axis
corresponds to the primary principal
component and clearly separates
marijuana from
as humans selected for different
phenotypes to process and at different
products the populations of all
genetically the plot below is a more
granular view of each individual's
ancestry each column and the lower plot
is a stacked bar plot showing the
percent ancestry and its genome from
each of the three functional classes
here's another way to look at population
differentiation this is a population
branch statistic just based on how
similar allele frequencies and
populations are the longer the branch
the more differentiated the populations
are from each other notice the small
insect tree near the histogram this is
the genome-wide average of the
population statistic we know from the
previous slide that marijuana and hemp
are highly differentiated that is
reflected in the branch lengths the
large tree however is drawn in the same
scale as the small tree which shows the
population branch statistic at the
synthase locus it's an extreme outlier
and we look back at the histogram that
shows the distribution of branch lengths
in the marijuana line I've indicated the
99.9 fifth percentile and dotted line
and shown with an arrow where the
synthase locus lies in that distribution
what this tells me is that there's been
strong divergent selection for very
different phenotypes or alleles
producing those phenotypes at the
synthase locus we look at the land race
of the natural populations we actually
have a negative branch leg suggesting
that the locus evolves neutrally in the
wild is not under strong natural
selection so what about high CBD
cannabis high CBD cannabis plants
typically have mostly marijuana like
phenotypes the shorter more branching
the very large flowers and are high in
total cannabinoids however they're low
in THC and are non-intoxicating they
have a mosaic phenotype of both
marijuana like and hemp like traits how
did we get here this animation shows
changes in cannabis law in the United
States through time in the past five
years laws have been passed
progressively legalizing CBD as we all
know last year's farm bill legalized
hemp and
Beadie the law classifies HAMP is a
cannabis plant that produces less than
0.3 percent THC there's a bar plot
showing a steady increase in CBD sales
over time my core argument here is that
these two changes legalization of CBD
coupled with a steady increase in sales
opened up an unprecedented ecological
niche that is a new way for cannabis to
interact with human culture this is a
genome plot for the 10 CBD our X
chromosomes remember how I mentioned
that the genetic map could be used to
identify regions of the genome
responsible for functional traits from
this plot I show the low-side
responsible for traits pertinent tamera
producing the marijuana and hemp
phenotypes Louis I responsible for plant
architecture are indicated by green and
gold stars total cannabinoids by black
stars in the synthase locus with the red
star that's I colored the komak
chromosomes according to their ancestry
regions of the genome inherited from
marijuana ancestors are colored in blue
regions inherited from hemp ancestors
are colored in yellow we can see that
the CBD rx genome is about 90 percent
marijuana derived in about 10% hemp
derived
so just as high CBD plants have mosaic
phenotypes they also have mosaic genomes
mosaic patterns are the same here's a
graphical summary of the concept I just
discussed marijuana and hemp have long
been selected for very different
phenotypes and it diverged genetically
as indicated by the three colors the law
however is only concerned with percent
THC and the legal classification of
plants is indicated by the style of
shading the breeding history of high CBD
cannabis varieties involved the
introgression of hemp like synthase
Louis I into a predominantly marijuana
light genomic background this is a
schematic of my mental model of
population dynamics in cannabis the
right hand side illustrates the
domestication process which we have
covered now I'm also interested in
global patterns of biogeography and
dispersal I'll conclude my talk today
with some preliminary analyses of
old-world biogeography I scraped some
genetic data provided by the now that
defiant cope and cannabis project and
clustered approximately 100 individuals
based on shared ancestry in this matrix
each row or column is a single
individual cells are colored according
to the proportion of shared ancestry
with yellow indicating low-level shared
ancestry moderate shared ancestry and
red and high in anchored blue and this
plot I intentionally emitted elite hemp
and marijuana cultivars in order to
highlight the differences between land
races the samples loosely close the
cluster into eighteen groups and show a
pattern of isolation by distance the
most differentiated clusters are those
of Central Africa and Central Europe
notice the tree at the top of the plot I
overlaid this tree from the previous
slide under Geographic map to get this
figure the red arrows show hypothesized
dispersal routes but which cannabis
expanded its range you can also map the
old world physical biogeography on a
physical map of the genome this
animation and colored genomic segments
according the predicted ancestry found
the elite hemp cultivar to be centered
primarily from the Slavic lands
essential in Eastern Europe well the
elite marijuana cultivar is descended
mostly from South Asia and the Middle
East that's it thanks for attending my
talk I'm at Harvard University most of
this was done as a consultant for
sunrise genetics the genetic mapping
population was developed at the
University of Minnesota by jorts we
blend Todd Michael at the JCB I produced
most of the course sequencing data
functional remedies of Colorado provided
some funding and the CBD rx and of
course none of this would have been
possible without that all these amazing
sequencing technologies so
well I'll take questions okay of the
curious looking at the range of
phenotypes you're covering there at the
genetics do you have any sense of
whether you feel like there's limits on
kind of extreme phenotypes that you can
get out of plants so that's something
neck table I don't think that there's a
limit on it if you look at like Maisie
olds over the past century it's been a
linear relationship between yield and
time so I think if we keep pushing it
the plants will respond thank you first
of all fascinating talk Thanks I'm
curious if if you could go sort of back
in time why what were sort of the
original selective pressures that you've
identified from that wild type that you
showed a picture of that was essentially
nothing that anybody would resemble
nothing that anybody would consider to
be a yeah so I mean cannabis sativa is
you know I consider it a single species
with a lot of diversity the native range
is probably like the Eurasian steppe and
so depending on the where the population
was located that would dictate kind of
what it was adapted to so we see extreme
variation and day length and
precipitation and actually you you know
all of this wild term plasm potentially
could be a great source for for breeding
if we can collect the seeds thank you
you're welcome
okay
[Applause]