thank you it's an honor to be here
especially to follow
Rafi my mentor and surrogate uncle on
this slide you'll see my email I'd be
happy to hear from you afterwards part
of this talk is contained in an article
that was just published last week that
I'd be happy to send to each of you
so here I am on the high wire without a
net trying to do an hour presentation in
15 minutes so let's begin
I will there's some disparate threads
here I'll try to tie together and hope
that it becomes coherent at the end the
human gut harbors a hundred trillion
microorganisms and there are 10 to the
12 per milliliter of these their genome
exceeds that of the host humans a
hundredfold there's a difference in
obese humans they have more of a type of
bacteria called Bacteroides lower
Bacteroides and higher firma cuties this
fellow dr. Mohler did very interesting
study they actually went and sampled in
the field fecal samples from wild chimps
bonobos which are pygmy chimps our
closest genetic relatives gorillas and
human populations the microbiomes of
american humans are more different from
those of Malawi humans than the gut
microbiomes of Malawi humans are from
bonobos and you see the p-value there
you never see values like this unless it
is a clear finding looking at three
different continents in humans they were
lower microbial diversity than in Apes
in with respect to the bacterial phyla
classes orders families in general
there's a constriction of the diversity
Americans average 30 fewer bacterial
genera the lowest level of diversity
these changes have been associated
historically epidemiologically with vast
increases in gastrointestinal
disorders obesity and especially
autoimmune disorders the same group did
a subsequent study again showing that
there are also anatomical differences in
Apes the colon is greater than 50
percent of the intestinal volume versus
only 20 percent in humans it's clear
that several bacterial lineages have
seemingly followed evolutionary wise
with hominids over the last 15 million
years and again in industrial nations
humans Harbor the fewest general of any
primate on their to Bacteroides ACI
lineages and apes that have never been
found in the American human subspecies
as I like to call it that severity of
irritable bowel symptoms is inversely
related to the gut bacterial diversity
so this definitely has importance to
disease so what is a person to do well
I'd suggest these things first
probiotics that may be familiar to some
of you these are oral supplements of
beneficial gut bacteria that can be
supplied as capsules or in fermented
foods especially kefir lacto fermented
vegetables to replace the kind of thing
that is missing and then you need
something that those bacteria like to
eat and those are probiotics these are
oral vegetative matter into justice and
fiber fructooligosaccharides that serve
as a feedstock for the beneficial
bacteria some other studies looking at
the relationship between the microbiome
and psychology when people ingest bifida
bacterium and lactobacillus probiotics
it reduces negative mood a treatment for
depression probiotics these special
bacteria in elderly patients improved
attention and working
memory is compared to placebo and that
was statistically significant there's
some diseases particularly Clostridium
infections that are treated with fecal
transplantation when this was done in
autistic children there were
improvements in the behavioral and Gi
signs and symptoms over the course of
the ensuing eight weeks presumably this
is something that needed to be repeated
again the gut microbiota these different
bacteria fact neuropsychiatric status on
in such conditions as autism depression
stroke and schizophrenia and the
mechanism of action seems to be mediated
through the autonomic nervous system the
enteric nervous system the immune system
on relates to bacterial metabolites and
I'm going to suggest now that there's a
role for the endocannabinoid system here
again we've seen marked changes in the
human diet as compared to past centuries
on at the same time we've had
skyrocketing rates of chronic disease
specifically obesity inflammatory bowel
diseases other autoimmune diseases
allergies diabetes cancer depression and
neurodegenerative disorders and these
were not rare in past centuries merely
because we're living longer
it's demonstrable that they're more of
these per the population
apparently it's necessary to have
multiple probiotic species not single
ones to protect against pathogenic
bacteria like clostridia and to gain
these neuropsychiatric benefits so
additionally probiotics may help control
p-part gamma this is a nuclear receptor
you're going to be hearing a lot more
about it regulates gene transcription
recently was shown that cannabidiol and
also thca tetrahydrocannabinol ik acid
are
agnus of this receptor and it's been
called the master regulator of a Depot
Genesis the production of fat also
regulating tumor necrosis factor alpha
which is important in autoimmune
diseases and in inflammation free
biotics so this vegetative matter that
the bacteria like changed the microbiota
to reduce fat production and stabilize
the gut so that it doesn't leak and
allow toxic metabolites standar the
bloodstream we also know that CB to the
non-psychoactive cannabinoid receptor
levels correlate to concentrations of
lactobacillus what's in yogurt and
negatively with cluster aerial species
that are often pathogenic a study that
directly relates to the under
cannabinoid system it's this one from
2007 lactobacillus acidophilus common
component of yogurt a specific strain of
that was administered and induced CNR to
that's the gene that produces the cb2
receptor it's RNA expression above that
in the human h t29 epithelial cells and
that was statistically significant so
they demonstrated that as well as an
enhancement of morphine's pain-killing
effects in rats highly statistically
significant and that reduction in pain
was inhibited when a cb2 antagonist was
administered so that fits together a
very interesting study from 2011 looked
at obesity in cannabis users and non
cannabis users what they found was
obesity rates were only 14 3.3 percent
and 17.2 percent respectively among
participants using cannabis at least
three days a week such a one-third
reduction over nine users additionally
those who use cannabis had
significantly better body mass indices
do you know what yours is another study
directly relating cannabinoids to this
issue was done in Calgary on published
in 2015 by Nina Clooney and the group
there di o mice have a genetic
susceptibility to obesity they gain
weight on the same dietary intake that
doesn't affect others when administered
THC that altered their microbiome
balance affecting the Firma cuties and
Bacteroides ratio the THC essentially
prevented a ratio increase or weight
gain despite being on a high-fat diet so
this could help explain what we observe
in humans as we'll see from these
demonstrations people use cannabis
suffer from a variety of stereotypes the
most common one is the cannabis user as
a lazy slacker stoner as we see in the
illustration but another one is this
that of the skinny hippie and you see
that he's got a grocery bag full of
vegetables hopefully the right ones but
the truth is that the skinny hippie is
the more accurate representation of what
a cannabis user is likely to look like
as opposed to the slacker stoner again
how do we change the way things are and
this destiny that our diet has seemed to
impose upon us well in this prebiotic
array you see some vegetative matter
that may be quite unfamiliar to you
starting with acacia fiber in the upper
left chicory roots sometimes use as a
coffee substitute Sun chokes otherwise
known as Jerusalem artichokes then
dandelion greens burdock and then the
more familiar Lda CI your onions leeks
and garlic all of these feed the
beneficial bacteria and the gut
additionally another thing that's
changed about our diets is our
vegetables have become tasteless in
ancient times people ate what they could
gather and it included a lot of bitter
herbs and these are largely fallen out
of the diet particularly Americans like
things that are sweet and not bitter
this can be supplemented with herbal
bitters as demonstrated in the photo and
it's been shown that these are present
not only in the tongue but throughout
the gut and specifically in the brain
where they do such things as reduce
hunger drive that drive toward sugars
and also seem to correlate with reducing
such disorders as diabetes and even acne
in the face so the question is can
bitter herbs allay hunger via the
hypothalamic and ECS mediated mechanisms
and lead to weight loss and counteract
the metabolic syndrome and type 2
diabetes I believe the answer is yes
here are a couple of books on how to eat
nourishing traditions by Sally Fallon
which first came out in the 90s but
still presents a very relevant diet on
the more recent bestseller by Perlmutter
called brain maker correlating use of
this kind of diet with prebiotics and
probiotics to improvements in autism and
a variety of other neurologic conditions
my hypothesis would be that we're seeing
common mechanisms between the prebiotic
and probiotic diet and what cannabis can
do and this has led to this diagram that
was published last week what I like to
call the gut or grand unified theory
that relates the microbiome to treatment
of various diseases including especially
beta-amyloid for
maisha neurofibrillary tangles that are
associated with Alzheimer's disease and
a variety of other neurodegenerative
conditions and as you see from the
diagram it's not only beneficial
bacteria but there's abundant evidence
presented in the paper but not here
today that supplemental THC CBD and even
THC a may do similar things in a laying
these type of afflictions so this
suggests a new approach to neurological
therapeutics I have always said
throughout my career that it needs to be
a preventive and therapeutic specialty
rather than just a diagnostic one to
provide better treatment for epilepsy
tumors Alzheimer's disease Parkinson's
traumatic brain injury and crow meant
sorry chronic traumatic encephalopathy
part of this includes aerobic activity
which is known to stimulate the
endocannabinoids system education
throughout life seems to help prevent
dementia and above all an
anti-inflammatory prebiotic and
probiotic diet that should emphasize
saturated monounsaturated that's olive
oil as we heard previously also omega-3
essential fatty acids bioflavonoids from
things like berries fermented foods
protein and minimizing carbohydrates
which have only been used in abundance
by humans for about 3,000 years
additionally this can be supplemented
with cannabis extracts providing the THC
CBD THC a carry off lean and other
select terpenoids
3 minutes remaining well we made it
so I guess people can come to the
microphones then I'll attempt to answer
questions I did not plan that for to
come out within seconds
any questions
the microphones on this please talk
closer and Bacteroides level is a good
one in in that I would have lower
Bacteroides and higher for nikah ditties
if you took that and Transplant it and
did a fecal transplant into someone
obese what would happen they were to
expect an improvement and their weight
and intakes but again it might be a
temporary phenomenon now it works the
other way there is a rodent model of
Parkinson's disease and when you take
the fecal matter from the affected mice
and put it in those that that aren't
affected they become symptomatic so this
is being used a lot now in
gastroenterology practices to try and
improve situation the most common
situation is treating cluster aerial
infections that it really recalcitrant
and a lot of that is a function of
antibiotic use and I would point out
that part of the reason we're having so
much trouble with these autoimmune
disease is not just changes in diets but
overuse of antibiotics that are
suppressing normal and minute desirable
bacteria so follow-up question I was
surprised it and talked about
antibiotics more in this talk because
well we only had 15 minutes