[Music]
so I know that you don't want to reveal
uh too much of your findings got to save
that for caned which I completely
understand and appreciate um but can you
explain how or how and if you identified
some more toxic additives in some of
these Vapes and sort of what are the
implications there for consumer
health so we first analyzed um a variety
of different tping blands that are sold
on the market uh internally we have a
gcms inhouse that can do tpine analysis
so we first ran all the products inhouse
to analyze kind of the total composition
of these Blends then what I did is
narrowed down our Target list of
compounds to a select view that at true
Tarpin we choose not to use at all
because I think the safety profile um is
just not not there it's more hazardous
then it's worth using um so that is kind
of the target list that we uh started
with then we sent out a select of these
samples to third-party lab so we tested
them by two thirdparty labs to validate
and verify the results that we found in
house so you analyzing products on the
market for sort of a hit list of
compounds that are sort of known to be
um
risky yes more or less excellent okay um
and so you you mentioned that you at
true tpin you guys do not use those for
obvious reasons um why I mean I know you
can't really necessarily say why others
do but um you know is it because it's a
flavor enhancer or some other some other
reason for maybe some of these additives
yeah that's a great question so a lot of
these ingredients are really commonly
used in food so they have a safe history
of use they are approved by the FDA for
un food most of them are grass we've
heard that a lot generally recognized as
safe however none of those accounts for
inhaling these compounds so when I do
the risk assessment I go beyond just
oral application and I assess what would
it do if we inhale these compounds and
that's where we see a higher risk factor
[Music]
a