[Music]
and sort of talking about clinical
applications or maybe you know future
research has any of your findings led to
any clinical trials or real world
applications yet?
So yes and and both both questions are
the answer is yes it's lead to clinical
trials and it lead to real world
applications. So in three cases first of
all I want to take one step back okay
and to explain cannabis is a given name
to hundred or thousands of different
chemovs each one of them contain
different combination of molecules and
we just talked that this combination is
important for the effects okay cancer
it's a given name to thousands of
different diseases we have in our body
220ome different types of cells Each
type of cell have different types of
cancer. Our you know lung cancer, breast
cancer, skin cancer are totally
different. It's a different diseases.
But even in one type of cancer, breast
cancer, we have 20ome different types.
So altogether you're talking about
thousands of different chemovirus of
cannabis and thousands of different
diseases. And now my goal in my lab or
my what I'm trying is to
match a specific cannabis to a specific
cancer. So it's not that cannabis can
cure cancer or cannabis can treat
cancer. There are specific types of
cannabis or molecules in the cannabis
they might help or cure specific types
of cancer. So that's first of all let's
bring it back to earth. Okay. Right. But
if at least in three cases, three types
of cancers and mutation, we already know
which cannabis, which which combination
of
molecules can kill this cancer when you
have this mutation. So in leukemia with
a specific mutation called notch one
mutation, I already know what are the
molecules in the cannabis that will
always kill the cells. So if a leukemia
patient have a mutation called notch one
and 50% of the leukemia patient it's not
all the leukemia but it's around 60%
actually okay so this type of cancer
will treat as a chem chemotherapy or
radiation without all the side effects
and everything right but the idea it
would be the same it's killing the
cancer cells so we have three types of
cancers like that and and we are in two
of them we started the process I open a
company raise money we started the
process to go to clinical trials that's
one and on the other hand we created
products cannabis product extracts or or
flowers that we aiming the specific
patient not to take a general cannabis
to take this cannabis and usually I'm
very gentle on that. I'm I'm saying if
you have leukemia and you have this type
of leukemia and you're already going to
take cannabis and you don't know what
you're taking and you don't care, why
won't you take this? Okay, that we have
science on that and research and we know
it's no I'm not coming to the patient
this will cure you. I said if you're
taking it arbitrarily and you don't know
what you're taking and it's just you
know trial and error start with this.
Mhm. This I can think can help you and
then we are following on the p following
on the patient they're taking looking
the improvement and and and so and
so we are doing that. Yes. Excellent.
And it's again phenomenal. It's it's
amazing feeling you know a scientist
usually like me even when you finding
something and you have amazing findings
in the lab until a patient will touch it
it's 10 15 years something like that you
know when I did my posto in Toronto
father of one of the PhD student that
was that works with me and she's still a
good
He was a very important scientist in in
Vancouver
[Music]
and he was the ones that invent the the
Fiser COVID
19 vaccination. Okay. So he won you know
all the prizes in the world after that
he become a billionaire but this is a
different story. um he he came to give a
talk in my university a few months ago
and he he stand and he
said it's it's amazing how we succeed to
create a medicine in in eight months to
this virus but now in my talk I want to
show you that it took 40
years that it took me 40 years okay so
I'm coming back to what I say I meant to
say usually to a scientist in the
to have a results and to affect a
patient if he's lucky and if he's you
know amazing and and got a Nobel Prize
it's 15 20 years in my field in my work
sometimes we finding something and two
weeks after it can already be in in I
can already recommend the patient or
help a patient with that because the
product is on the shelf I just need to
point him to what we found and think and
and this is very unique situation very
unique feeling I'm very
very careful or you know I don't know
how to say that very I'm not saying
things that I'm not
100% sure about them when I not 100%
sure that it will help and not make do a
damage but when you know something and
you help. It's really good feeling. So
that's interesting. So it's a unique
situation that patients kind of have
access to this medicine um early on
where that's not typically the case with
other other compounds. They have they
have an access to the medicine before
you pure you prove it's really a
medicine. So yeah, they have the access
before they have the knowledge. Right.
Exactly.
[Music]