good afternoon everybody thank you so
much for coming to the session uh we'll
wait to see if my slides get queued up
here and see if i can
figure out this
um thank you so much my name is dr
marion mcnabb
and i'm the president of the cannabis
center of excellence
thank you
thanks for joining us
[Music]
there we
let's go
oh okay good
all right
all right so thank you so much so um i'm
here to present um data from a
healthcare provider medical cannabis
knowledge attitudes and practice study
so i'm the president of the cannabis
center of excellence we're a 501c3
nonprofit based out of massachusetts
that works to conduct cannabis research
studies education programs and social
justice work
so um this study
actually i'm very grateful to canmed and
medicinal genomics this was a
partnership together
with canmed
last year we
joined together forces to launch
the healthcare provider medical cannabis
study
these are some of the study partners
that have joined done over the year
to in support of the study and also to
help get the word out about it so thank
you to all of our partners and to canmed
and to medicinal genomics
so
i am a public health doctor by training
and i have been studying cannabis for
five years now based out of
massachusetts and i've conducted six
different research studies now the first
a couple of research studies this is
data that is presented from studies from
consumers and patients that i've led
over the last couple of years and what
this shows we asked in those studies
previously
where do you as a cannabis consumer or
patient find your information about
medical cannabis and on the slide you
can see
a majority of
those consumers and patients actually
access their information from a mobile
website or healthcare
a mobile website or
in a mobile application
and way far at the end you can see least
likely reported
are accessing information from their
clinician or healthcare provider so from
the last couple of years asking cannabis
consumers and patients you know you're
consuming cannabis for what health
condition etc
but they're not accessing their
information from a healthcare provider
pointing to the importance of
this study that we conducted
so the health care provider medical
cannabis study was launched in may of
last year and i'm here today to present
the preliminary findings
there are 354 health care providers that
took the survey
the study actually will end in august of
this year
and was approved by the university of
massachusetts
dartmouth institutional review board
again the study is led by the coe
medicinal genomics and umass dartmouth
so throughout
the last year we have several
co-investigators that have joined the
study that either contributed to the
design and the development of the study
tools and the instruments
or have really worked to help do
outreach for the study and raise
awareness to get health care providers
to take the study so thank you to all
the co-investigators some
of who are here presenting also at
canmed
and again thank you to the study
partners for helping to make this study
possible
so
what this is is an anonymous survey
asking healthcare providers what they
know what they want to know and how they
want to learn it about cannabis
and what we did over the last year was
think about some pretty innovative ways
to collect data and why do we do this
because we're in the middle of a code we
were and in the middle of a covid
pandemic our healthcare providers are
struggling they themselves have ptsd
and high levels of anxiety
and we're asking them to take a survey
and 10 minutes out of their time to
contribute to knowledge um so already
you know we're working with a population
that is um you know stressed and so we
wanted to work on as a public health
professional by training i also um think
about ways to not only conduct research
studies but also how do you drive policy
and education around the data that you
collect
and so we've implemented several
different innovative
data collection methodologies and
outreach for this particular study so
we've had flyers qr codes social media
blasts email blasts to healthcare
providers and systems
attended a number of community events
i'm based in massachusetts so raising
awareness at local community and asking
citizens to go talk to their healthcare
providers about it
and presented this study in several
different ways over the last year to
raise awareness and increase our sample
size
and one of the things that we've
launched in the last
year is something called the cannabis
citizen scientist which
is a program that we launched to inspire
um citizens and patients themselves to
be outreach data collectors so to speak
and raise awareness about
cannabis and about healthcare and their
healthcare communities
so of those events that i talked about
in the last year
have generated about 30 or so citizen
scientists
in massachusetts that have been helping
us to raise awareness and get the word
out about medical cannabis about the
center of excellence and about the study
this is our
one
sort of key citizen scientist who's done
a lot of work in calling hospitals and
health centers
around massachusetts to try and
raise awareness
we also formulated a partnership with a
cannabis transport company
that works with 90 of the cannabis
dispensaries and operations in
massachusetts to help us take study
packets out
to different outlets and asking
different cannabis outlets to then reach
out to their local
hospitals health centers and communities
to raise awareness about the study and
kind of start to drive conversation so
this partnership just launched this year
and they we've given 110 study packets
to them
last month and
they're in the process of distributing
all of these they're in the middle of it
and so far have reached almost every
corner of massachusetts getting the word
out
so this is really exciting it's kind of
a new innovative way we thought to
get the word out and so they've
delivered these study packets and
requested every single cannabis partner
that they have
to
you know share
with their local health care providers
and their local healthcare systems
so by the end of the study in august
hopefully we'll have some more
information about the you know how it
worked
you know whether or not it did raise
awareness or increase our sample size
and drive conversation in these local
communities
so diving right in uh from a year's
worth of data that we've collected so
far
we've had 354 respondents to the survey
to date the um
most common profession that has
responded is actually nurses at 25
go nurses and i'm giving thank you to
there's a lot of nurses that i know here
in the audience that are also
participating and helping so thank you
um you know i think nurses are a very
important uh part of our healthcare
system particularly when dealing with
cannabis patients because they're in day
to day
um we have had the most of our
respondents from california
interestingly
second followed by massachusetts and i
think with our targeted outreach in
massachusetts over the next few months
um
we might raise our numbers there
um the majority of the respondents so
far are women and we have um about 78
percent um whites fall by 10 percent
african american
in our sample size so far
uh 17
of the healthcare respondents actually
work for the veterans affairs
about 50 percent are below the age of 40
years and over about fifty percent have
an income less of a hundred thousand
dollars
um among the health care providers
themselves thirteen percent report that
they are veterans
and uh sixty-six percent are employed
full time
when we ask them type of of health care
facility um it's mainly the most common
is a private practice followed by a
government hospital
and about uh it looks like about less
than 40
um of our sample has been a healthcare
provider for six years or less so these
are fairly young providers um new in
their profession um but exciting that we
have such a large amount that's working
at the va
now
we asked and i i interestingly and i've
always asked this question whether or
not the healthcare provider themselves
actually consumes cannabis and this was
surprising to me 42
of the people healthcare providers in
our samoa reported that they themselves
are cannabis consumers or patients
now that's a really important and
interesting data point to note as we
move forward in some of the data
presented because this is a population
of cannabis consumers and patients that
find benefit themselves in addition to
being healthcare providers
of the sample i've actually um visited a
dispensary which is very good i know a
lot of healthcare providers that haven't
ever even visited one
and
out of those that report experience with
cannabis they've had a positive most
have had a positive or extremely
positive experience
so just in some we have majority
women um a high population of nurses
um we have a younger population that's
reporting um they're currently cannabis
consumers and you know have visited a
dispensary so pretty knowledgeable uh
respondents
so
we asked also are you licensed to
actually recommend medical cannabis in
your state 54
said they are licensed and none of those
that were not licensed to recommend
cannabis in their state
about half of them said that they
intended to become licensed in the
future
and when we asked you know what are some
barriers for you to actually accessing
licensure
some of them reported
you know one they didn't want to be
certified
state body doesn't recognize their
profession to be certified and so i
think that's an important one to note um
state by state barriers for you know
somebody who actually wants to become a
recommender and then there's other
issues such as
you know my healthcare facility or
organization prevents me from becoming a
recommender of cannabis
or don't ask don't tell policy at their
workplace
now when we asked all the healthcare
providers do you believe medical
cannabis has a role in medical care and
37 believe it has a role as a first-line
medical treatment
that's pretty yeah i mean that's a
pretty significant data point and then
right following that 30 believe that
there's some role for specific health
conditions and then 13
believe that there's a role if the first
line treatments fail there's a role for
medical cannabis and then 12 percent
said they just needed more scientific
evidence to actually make a decision
about this
out of the sample um you know the we
asked have you received formal education
training 60
had received some formal training and
out of those did they get cme credits
about 75 actually got cme credits
and 62 reported that their workplace had
a policy related to medical cannabis
now this is um actually
one of probably my favorite graph as
i've looked at this data quite a bit
but it's interesting because it shows
that
you know the majority of respondents
really believe that medical cannabis is
effective just said that you know about
the first line treatment
the majority also somewhat agree or
agree that medical cannabis can be a
beneficial tool in the opioid epidemic
and
by and large they largely
disagreed that cannabis is a gateway to
other illicit drugs so we're starting to
see potentially at least in this
population that shift away from
the cannabis is a gateway drug
there's still some uncertainty around
you know whether or not
from healthcare providers whether or not
an inhaled cannabis has the same risk as
tobacco or other combustible products
and that was a really interesting
presentation about the vapes earlier and
i think
having more training around vapes and
combustion
for healthcare providers and for
patients is actually really important
these graphs all like the top two
really
showing that
again the healthcare providers in these
samples really strongly agree or agree
that medical cannabis is a legitimate
medical therapy
and that they also agree that health
care providers should be offering
medical cannabis to manage
conditions
they you know again somewhat found the
process um to certify
patients within programs somewhat
difficult to navigate
and then
you know believe that um you know
a little it looks like a little less
than half uh strongly agree or agree
believe that the process to certify
patients in the program actually
prevents them from enrolling patients so
these are just regular you know
regulatory barriers to access or just
challenges just for even becoming a part
of the program
majority of the respondents in the
sample
regularly ask their patients about
medical cannabis use and report that
their patients feel comfortable talking
to them about their cannabis use but the
providers are you know
not strongly agreeing that their patient
is very knowledgeable about cannabis
so
these uh this group feels like maybe
more potential patient education
is warranted
we asked the providers how helpful do
they think
cannabinoids are and the treatment of a
variety of conditions
and there was a top few winners among
this is not an exhaustive list of
conditions
but cancer pain by and far providers
thought would be very helpful or
somewhat helpful medical cannabis for
then you can see seizures as well but
less so on glaucoma tourettes and others
chronic and intractable pain providers
thought that
the cannabis would be very helpful or
somewhat helpful for
and in addition terminal illness and
post-traumatic stress disorder
interestingly
post-traumatic stress disorder you know
is a complex
condition
and i have looked in this in the
veterans population specifically in the
past and i think there's a lot of
interesting nuances related to ptsd um
so interested to hear that this uh
cohort also thought that uh cannabis
could be very helpful or somewhat
helpful for that category
when looking at
these other types of
health conditions
als and parkinson's coming out as
top contenders so to speak
and alzheimer's as well
um but you can see you know
in all of these conditions um that we've
just seen these graphs you know more
than 50 of the sample believes that
medical cannabis has some role to play
either very helpful or somewhat helpful
so um you know looking at across a
myriad of health conditions a myriad of
symptoms and these providers are seeing
relief in this just underlines the point
of you know the endocannabinoid system
deficiencies and personalized medicine
and really paying attention to the
patient themselves
is important for cannabis medicine
so there's both
mental
health relief and physical symptom
relief
that you know patients and consumers in
the studies that i've run and others
have run find um you know cannabis is
helpful for
um so in this sample
not only um you know do clinicians think
it'll help improve physical functioning
and energy level
mood enjoyment of life social engagement
ability to work which i think is a big
one
when you want to you know improve
quality of life and return to work and
also the sense of hope
again just in summary you know about
over half of our sample has received
some formal training about medical
cannabis
about half are registered to recommend
medical cannabis by a state
37 percent believe medical cannabis can
be a first-line treatment um and 70
agree that cannabis can be used strongly
agree or agree that canvas can be used
to address the opioid epidemic
these were the top conditions that
you know
just presented around what came out to
be the most strongly agree or agree
related to the medical value of cannabis
but again cannabis is not a
one-size-fits-all um it's not for
everybody it's um you know uh and there
are some obviously concerns
that we should be aware of and
um
in this sample specifically
respondents um
were asked what do they think about the
risk of using cannabis does it increase
the risk of possible psychotic symptoms
depression memory problems respiratory
and motor vehicle accidents and by far
psychotic our psychotic symptoms and
motor vehicle accidents are among the
top concerns
uh among the sample
we also asked you know would this have
any um would cannabis use increase the
possible risk of low birth weight drug
overdose stoke stroke diabetes heart
attack and cancer
and you can see
um those results here as well
i think one of the major
one concerns of regulators of families
of parents also is the potential for
youth to have access or
the potential for recreational misuse um
so
here when we ask these healthcare
providers the um
you know it looks by and large that
potential for recreational misuse of
medical cannabis is is not of a big
concern
nor is the um possibility of diversion
which is quite interesting because when
you hear a lot of
critics you know these are the two two
of the main
areas that people tend to think about
possible risk
but
what is concerning to these healthcare
providers is lack of fda approval and
driving under the influence of cannabis
which are two very valid um concerns
and also asked about you know sort of
the use other other concerns about using
medical cannabis for those who have a
history of alcohol or drug dependence um
they're less likely concerned of that
but more concerned about their patients
being able to find and afford a
a regular medical cannabis supply
providers were also
worried about potential of losing their
medical license or legal repercussions
for becoming
a medical cannabis recommender
stigma related to supporting cannabis as
a medicine
and then again a youth access
causing health risks
so turning into um you know specific
data points around knowledge around
medical cannabis this is going to be a
lot of
data points thrown at you very quickly
and i know i'm also running out of time
so i'll try and do it as much justice as
possible
we asked okay what what do you know um
how do you want to learn about medical
cannabis in the future and this
healthcare provider sample prefers to
learn um
via lecture and scientific journals and
peer-reviewed publications as their top
ways then followed by news or national
curriculum or
industry training
well we ask their level of confidence
and certain key competencies related to
either knowledge or practice
so
um
the
uh yellow and the orange obviously being
confident and are completely confident
and fairly confident so this population
felt you know pretty confident about
knowing how to evaluate for drug
cannabis interactions
also how to retrieve drug information
for the use of medical cannabis
also
were
by and large more comfortable knowing
how to talk to a patient who uses
cannabis about the medical benefits
and knowing how to talk about the dosage
forms that are available for cannabis
but less so knowledgeable about
the effects of receptor activation on
neural neural function or the physiology
of the endocannabinoid system
and really
less knowledgeable on the pharmacology
and the receptors that they act upon
but more
and and less so obviously on mechanisms
of of action for different cannabinoids
and phytocannabinoids
here
we asked about um a variety of
physiology um like i said activation on
neurons um you know are they familiar
with the pharmacology of cannabinoids
and the receptors that they act upon
and all of these
felt you know right around the range of
uh 50 percent being yes i know and and
no really i i somewhat know and need
more information
when asked about
cannabis derived products and how
they're metabolized
issues around labeling and accuracy of
labeling
the stability of active ingredients and
hemp and artisanal products how hemp and
non-fda
cannabis products are produced
you can see all of these are hovering
really around half of this population
feels very confident or very
knowledgeable about it and and half not
and less so on the likelihood of um you
know important things like um
transmission of cannabis derived
products through breast milk which
actually a colleague presented recently
on in at canx
when asked about differences between um
you know fda
approved products and products that are
out on the market
less knowledgeable
really less knowledgeable also about
you know understanding the potential
role of terpenes and enhancing these
products
or again the uses of fda purified cbd
so some key takeaways um again over half
of our sample we have a very
knowledgeable sample i feel like about
medical cannabis
about key competencies about it half of
the group and the majority of these
data points around knowledge felt
very knowledgeable
or somewhat knowledgeable
but they were less likely to know the
mechanisms of action and
really unsure of you know really trying
to drill down between fda approved and
non-fda approved products
but to close out we asked whether or not
you know what should be sort of the next
steps around medical education and some
of these competencies
and um over 50 and these are over 60 of
our sample they still agree although
they felt like they were very
knowledgeable that they need more
education about medical cannabis more
education about the endocannabinoid
system more information about where to
find
data in the scientific literature
where to get
actual legitimate cme courses so thank
you to
um you know canmed for putting on this
conference we need more like this
um and you know um 60 said that of the
healthcare providers prefer to learn
actually through a cme course online but
they also were interested in learning
about medical cannabis in person through
in-person events
really everybody's interested in
learning cannabis a majority over half
are interested in learning cannabis
medical cannabis and its impacts on a
variety of conditions from cancer
pediatrics ptsd
chronic pain
even now with covid or
seniors 55 plus
so i think there's room for
all different types of specialties all
different types of healthcare providers
you know different health conditions
where this can be studied and continued
to be implemented in the in the future
in different care and treatment
paradigms
and
by and large majority agree that medical
cannabis education should be a part of
the required curriculum in the next five
years um that you know there should be
more education on how to discuss and
counsel the risks and benefits of
cannabis use to be included in in
healthcare provider curriculum
education around the pharmacology of
cannabinoids and cannabis use so i think
there's a real opportunity to
you know create
teams of healthcare providers the nurses
physicians pharmacists you know from a
variety of areas to maybe do clinical
case rounds and studies and have
discussions and bring in different areas
of
um you know education for
one within within a curriculum but also
within a healthcare center community
and uh 72 percent believe that students
should receive education not only about
medical cannabis but about their state
program laws and about their medical
cannas program which i think is really
critical to know what they can do what
they can't do um so not only you know
what are what are the science and
clinical aspects but what's the state
and regulations around it
so i'd like to thank the study partners
i'd like to thank the study
co-investigators um and everybody who's
been a part of this study to date and
has either taken the study i know some
people in the audience have filled out
the survey and some people in the
audience have helped us distribute the
survey as a co-investigator so thank you
to everybody and thank you to
the companies that are listed here that
are have been participating on this
study
for the next steps um as i mentioned we
we do have this partnership we're
raising awareness locally in
massachusetts um
through um a partnership with eagle eyes
transport and we'll be continuing to get
the word out um and data will be
collected until august 1st
then we will prepare a final report and
publication and make this data available
um so that the community can continue to
learn and develop education programs
that
might you know be able to utilize some
of this information to help help drive
the field forward so thank you very much
i know i'm a little over time so
appreciate the time
[Music]
yeah i think i'll take one question and
then
yes please
from an amazing woman thank you
thank you
hello okay i have uh six comments two
questions and a suggestion awesome just
kidding um thank you so much there's so
much in this that i want to dive into
i'm curious did you break down
the healthcare professionals that were
using admitted to using cannabis whether
or not they worked at the va
because you know so many of us have to
go through drug testing to be able to be
employed at these places that i'm
curious about how many of us are closet
you know cannabis users right because of
our profession is was there any data
points in there i haven't dug into that
but i will dig into that and that'll be
part of the final publication and um is
there an opportunity to get this out to
people here in the room who haven't
taken it yet
absolutely absolutely um yeah and i know
if um
canmed i've been talking with ben who's
organizing we can try and get the survey
out to everybody that has come to canmed
to see if they'd be interested to
yeah we'd love that i've heard um you
know that a lot of people that have come
to canmed this year this might actually
be their first time learning about
cannabis so
um yeah if anybody would be willing to
do if you're a healthcare provider in
the audience and you want to take the
study thank you please do we're
collecting data until august and we will
um prepare
a publication about it i have a question
yes
um can other folks outside of
massachusetts help with the citizen the
science
absolutely absolutely yes please reach
out um yeah any anybody we did it as a
pilot test in massachusetts um just to
see you know would people like this or
would they pick up on it and it has been
very interesting because i think when
you i was saying earlier when you're a
cannabis patient and the pecans patients
that i've interacted with and they find
that it really helps they become some of
the biggest champions and advocates and
so um you know this woman who
literally got off of all these opioids
and you know can walk again she's the
biggest advocate calling every hospital
and health center around you know kind
of raising awareness so for sure
um just reached out on
canadacenterofexcellence.org and we
could sign up there
yeah awesome well thank you all so much
i appreciate