hello and like the last two speakers
this is my first canmed uh talk so I am
delighted to be here and thank you to
the organizers for inviting
me um first I would like to acknowledge
my collaborat on this project Dewey Tren
is an undergraduate researcher in my
laboratory he's did the work on the army
worms that we'll discuss later uh Tony
Wong is a professor and an Institute
professor at the University of Tennessee
in the department of Food Science she
and her lab came up with the technology
to make the
nanoemulsions and Zach Hansen is a uh
plant pathologist and he did the work on
powdering mildew he was at the
University of Tennessee and now he's
associated with Cornell
University um we hear a lot in this
uh conference about the importance of
hemp and the importance to human health
it's also very important for animal
health so if we look at the one Health
con concept where I want to focus our
talk today is on the third component
which is the Environmental
Health in h we have have uh very good
products we have the
cannabinoids and but we also have a lot
of other things that are produced so we
have the spent hemp is which is now
being used in many states as animal feed
it can also be used to generate
fibers uh grower extractors recycle
their solvents so the things that are
left over are what we are using and that
is this small amount here which is the
byproduct of hemp extraction so if we
can find a good use for this then we
will have completed the entire cycle for
uh this particular plant so it has
little or no environmental
impact so that's what we decided to take
on we took the hemp plant we went to the
extractors and uh they took the products
and we took what was leftover I've often
called this our leftovers uh project we
submitted that to uh a
microfluidizer with uh grass uh
surfactant grass simply means generally
regarded as safe this is an incredibly
safe product you could eat it but I
don't recommend it but uh so what we did
in the microfluidizer is make simply
make this into a nanoemulsion these are
very very small molecules suspended in a
liquid
if you think about salad dressing when
you mix oil and water when you do that
you get that quick Emulsion well this is
a stable Emulsion that looks similar to
that uh what's in that Emulsion is
whatever is left over uh in this first
batch it was very high still in the
cannabinoids that particular extractor
didn't have a uh good extraction of the
full uh CBD that was mainly CBD so
so we did um a distillation to get rid
of the cannabinoids and really conf uh
concentrate on the tping because the
tping are the things that we are
interested in for insecticidal and
fungicidal
products so if we look at what happened
to our DPT which is this distilled uh
tpin we are mostly uh car offing visal
and hubing all cesa tpin the minor tpin
included mostly the mono tpin and uh
some other
terpenoids and I'm using tpine and
turpenoid interchangeably in this
talk they aren't the same and I and I
understand that so it I'll throughout
the talk I'll use several abbreviations
one is DPT and that is our distilled
byproduct uh TP which is our crude
byproduct NE is simply our negative
control which is uh surfactant only no
turpins and Ne which is our positive
control it is a well regarded U
biopesticide so one of the problems with
natural products is shelf life so with
the um Nano imulsion we get a stable
product it does get a little cloudy
after 30 days but I've used some of
these products up to 6 months to two
years and it's still they still have
activity um it's hard to see on this
thing but there's a little tiny yellow
bar there that is 20 microns so these
are very very small
molecules uh of these nanoemulsions
these liquid these surfactants and
Tarpin together suspended in
water so our first experiment was just a
proof of Concepts so we worked with Bean
Beetle we work with Bean Beetle for two
reasons uh it's available commercially
it's easy to get it's easy to rear and
it's a model insect for testing this
type of thing it is uh what we did is we
put the beans in the in a flask uh then
put that out on a piece of uh filter
paper after we dried them we put two
pairs of uh beetles in there so they
would mate and then we allowed
them to lay their eggs on the surface
this particular insect lays its eggs and
then the lar burry into the bean itself
completely making the bean uh
unacceptable for com
consumption and then at the end we did a
number of things we counted the numbers
of eggs and everything but what I'm
going to report today is basically our
data on uh how many adults emerged but
all this data is published
in the paper Fay uh at Al so basically
what we saw was with the we treated only
with a nano imulsion we got about 15
adults uh per dish that came out whereas
when we put these other uh treatments on
there we we lowered the amount uh with a
5% TP and a 5% uh
dtp so we were very excited about we
thought this is a great way to
um start thinking about this as a
potential uh control for this pest this
pest can cause a 90% loss of uh cow peas
in uh in storage so it's very important
for people who are legume storage
producers uh we looked at that in terms
of the economic loss as follows the
exact same data Trend as the adults per
dish
and basically uh we see that if we had
the uh economic loss of about you know
40% with the nanoemulsion alone then we
were down to less than 5% with our best
treatment which was the uh 5%
dtp so at the time uh Zack Hansen's uh
graduate student uh was dealing with
some powdery mildew of hemp he was
running uh trials so we said oh can we
put this in your trial so in the first
trial we had the TP in the trial but we
did not have the ne because we were just
jumping into the experiment
Midway and anyway so if we look at the
area under the this progress curve which
is a common way that plant Pathologists
measure how much disease is there then
we see that uh in the water we had a
very high response but with the the
biopesticides that he tested and this
was strictly biopesticides we saw a
reduction uh of our material very very
similar to that of the common
biopesticides that are used to treat
powdery mildew and hemp in the second
run of this the second trial we actually
looked at um our nanoemulsion and we saw
the same type type of response with our
Nano ulion alone and also our
nanoemulsion with the Turing so we feel
very confident that this is a great way
to control powdery mildew of him
and we uh decided to go a little bit
further but but this time we needed to
get a new formulation so we went to
another extractor so we have no control
over what's coming into our system so
the first thing we did was uh look at
this this time we sent it off to a a
company new bloom in uh chattan
Tennessee and we found that basically in
this time we have very few
cannabinoids and mostly cesco
Turin so we decided to use this without
doing the distillation because the
distillation if you're coming into
product formulation is a very
expensive um process so we decided to
look at uh pathogens and
pests so the pathogen
is uh powdering me another powdering
mildew and then we decided to look at
caterpillars or lepidopteran
larvey so with powdery Milo of squash if
you aren't a plant mythologist you
probably don't know this but powdery
Milos are very specific to their host so
uh this is not the same as the powdery
mildew of him uh but we got the same
response in this experiment though we
did add some chemical controls these are
shown in green the other biopesticides
are shown in gold and ours is in this
deep orange and we basically got with
our TP we got as good of control as you
get with a synthetic pesticide so once
again this tells us that we are doing
the right thing to control powdering
Builders uh and we can get a somewhat of
a benefit if we have the TP in there
compared to the Nano Emulsion but that
difference is not statistically
significant but is also not
statistically significant from the best
uh powdery mildew uh product that we
could find at that
time so we uh went to a different system
looking at uh toxicity so this is if we
feed it to the insect we make them eat
it what happens and in this case we used
the nanom Motions we incorporated it
into artificial diet this artificial
diet was used to rear the ri the insects
from third instar which is the hardest
instar one of the harder instars to kill
most people start do this in very early
in stars and
then uh we fed this and we watched what
happened and in this uh study we had
water as our control we had a
uh Nano ulion control and we had two
doses of the TP and the Nano Emulsion
the low dose and a high dose and we did
not see any statistical difference in
the uh mortality of the insects and the
low dose but in the high dose we did so
this high dose is uh very would be very
important for using to control fall army
worm uh if you don't know about fall
army worm fall army worm is a very
invasive pest you can in the US it's
estimated to uh cause losses of about
$200
million and that is uh one of the
reasons we targeted it also because it
is also a model insect and we can
compare to a lot of other
studies so we also decided to look at
beat army worm beat army worm is a very
close relative of the Fall Army worm uh
different different species in the same
genus and the bead army worm there was
no impact so we don't have a good
explanation for this as of yet we are we
are looking at some of the digestive
enzymes and this type of thing that
would uh help help us get a clue but we
don't have a reason for this yet so
we're trying to to uh to find that
out but it is also not a real
significant past of crops in the
US the last thing I'm going to talk
about is a uh we started looking at well
if if a uh biotrophic pathogen is uh
affected how what is the effect on a a
pathogen like
fusarium and so we did what we call a
poison food study poison food studies
are simply in this case we took the
Emulsion we spread it across the top of
the uh media and then we put a plug of
fusarium in the center and monitored its
growth and in this experiment uh the
first time we used a fusarium oxysporum
and it is an isolate that that we
received from uh Bonnie only and it is a
isolate that was derived from
strawberries and we measured the days
each day we measured The Colony growth
and it became very obvious that we did
have a reduction in growth but the
reduction in growth is is consistent so
on day two day three uh the Nano
Emulsion is equal to the uh TP on day
four four and that Trend consists all
the way through so we really don't think
this is a great product to control
something like
fusarium uh but it does slow it down but
it doesn't really control it so we went
to an isolet that we have from hemp it
is probably a spor troides and asked the
same question got exactly the same
result so while I think this is a great
pesticide for the for the powdery MOS
being able to treat something the for
fusarium um may not work uh we are
currently looking at this as a seed
treatment and seeing uh what happens
when we put uh fuse area seed that has
fuse areia into the uh treatment and see
if we can get rid of fusarium that
way so in summary we've had two proof of
concept with the first proof of concept
we had that there was activity against
the bean Beetle and it was basically ask
acting as a repellent in that system in
the second we looked at toxicity and it
is toxic the fall army worm uh we looked
in both cases we looked at fungicidal
activity on a powdery mildew remembering
that these are different organisms and
powdering mildew was uh of
him the we had almost complete control
and that was equal to any biopesticide
that was on the market at the time and
in the um acorn squash powdery mildew we
had uh consistent with what we someone
would use with if they were using what
was available as the best powdery me do
control at that
time so in summary what I'm have been
saying is that we do have uh byproducts
from CBD extraction we can create a use
for these products using the
nanoemulsion
technology and it's active against some
insects and some pathogens it's not a
universal uh insecticide or a universal
Fung side but it we can do acceptable
applications uh we work very hard to get
uh con use concentrations that are not
phytotoxic if you know anything about
putting Tarpin on plants tpin are very
phytotoxic when you apply them to the
surface so we have to to work on
adjusting that but we've got those
levels at this point and we have a great
potential I think for a
biopesticide uh development from him uh
like Mike I'm looking I'm came looking
for potential collaborators and and uh
and money to take this uh technology
further
and at that point I just wanted to say
that this if we can develop this we can
use this product then we can close the
loop and make
cannabis one of the few crops that can
be
fully uh fulfill the go goals of the one
Health
[Applause]
initiatives thank you for this nice
presentation but I was a little bit
confused because we have
many uh Canabis cult Wars very rich
inprints very very very rich interin but
100% susceptible to we do but now we are
saying using the same Terin we can
control the poing me do how that works
we are we are working on I think your
question is can we just use the tpin and
do this now I'm saying we have the
plants that they are rich in tpin they
are know naturally producing the terpins
in a very high level but they are
completely susceptible to P me as an
example yes but
yes and we don't know why because when
we first did the the hemp experiment I
fully expected it the powdering mildew
to not have any response at all um but
it is I think uh kind of related to the
fact that we have the an nanom Motion in
there and that allows a different uh
uptake by the pathogen than if it's just
exposed to the the Turpin and the glands
in like the hemp so I think that it's a
it's a ma it's a matter of exposure and
how much is uptake by the fun by the
fungus thank you very much for I think
there's there was somebody over here did
you have a question yes I do okay thank
you very much for your
presentation Dr G um for your ferium
studies did you perform a concentration
dependence
uh study using the hemp
biopesticide we did not use a we did not
do a concentration study what we did is
we took the same amount that we knew was
not phytotoxic and the the same
concentration that we used on the
powdering mildew on the plants for
powdering mildew anything above that was
phytotoxic so we didn't we also didn't
see how low we could go but since since
we didn't get great resp responses with
the highest concentration that we felt
we could use we didn't pursue it any
further now we don't have that kind of
data for seeds and seed and the effects
on seed germination so we will be using
higher concentrations in those
studies I have a question over here
Excuse me yes here yeah oh hi hi
wonderful talk I have a ton of questions
and um focusing on the
application um methodologies where um H
are you or have you looked at uh with
regard to seed uh fumigant versus uh
seed coating or delivery to plants soil
drenching effects versus Leaf spraying
effects and influences on micro risal
and
beneficial we have not looked at at at
beneficials uh and we are in the first
stages of the seeds what we are finding
because of some of my other interest in
other bioactive products we've been
looking at hemp seed uh and fusarium and
we find that if we do a a surface
sterilization of seed we still have
fusarium so we are uh concerned about
that as a
transmission and excuse me and so we are
hoping that if we can soak them in this
with the Nano Emulsion and uh and it
won't be toxic to seed germination
because we don't know that at this point
that we can perhaps get some better
control of those internally transmitted
fungi hi um do these types of molecules
have any uh prior use in this
application and do the pests ever show
any kind of resistance or tolerance over
Generations um yes uh there is a body of
literature on essential oils and these
are common components of different
essential
oils particularly the caropine that's
been a uh standard uh test in a lot of
the uh for the a lot of the insects so
yes there there is literature saying
that this is an insecticidal property
this is a unique blend so as we've
talked about with human medicine there
is an Entourage effect with it with
pesticide sides as well so we we don't
know what this specific uh comp has done
this is the first testing of those but
some of these individually and also as
components us sometimes major components
of other essential oils have been done
um usually with essential oils we don't
see resistance developing because the
different essential oils have diff
different Tarpin have different modes of
action so these are all sesat tping so
that might be a little U more risk of
developing
uh resistance but the fact is when we
have these with these are really
terpenoids when we have these oxygens at
least with fungi we found that they're
more fungicidal typically with these
oxygens and so we don't know exactly
what the risk of resistance for this is
we have not done the experiment where we
go back and uh take the m and and make
them and go back and and start looking
at generation after gener generation
I've been doing this work on insects I'm
a plant pathologist so that was just
beyond what I wanted to
do it's hard to see out there I can't
see anybody all right