[Music]
welcome to the C Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I am the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on the canmed
summit the canmed early bird deadline is
fast approaching which means prices will
jump $500 for all of our ticket packages
on February 20th so if you are planning
on joining us in Puerto Rico this June
don't wait buy your ticket today and
enjoy those savings and if you're still
on the fence I invite you to go to camet
events.com and check out our speaker
lineup our schedule and the unique
networking events we have put together
to connect you with the leaders who are
shaping the
industry just to heads up we will plan
to announce details about our cannabis
genomics Workshop later this week which
is going to be one of the greatest
collections of cannabis genomics experts
ever assembled if you are at all
interested or curious about how genomic
sequencing can be used to create novel
varieties protect IP and breed for Pest
and pathogen resistance this is a
workshop you don't want to miss sign up
for email alerts at camat events.com to
make sure you do not miss that and all
the other announcements Our Guest today
is Dr Puna
nachaa Puna is an associate professor at
Colorado State University and the dep
Department Of Agricultural
biology her research program focuses on
understanding the interactions between
plants and insect vectors to manage
plant pests and diseases in hemp at C
at25 Puna will present biology and
management of hoplon vroid which will
Describe the impact of hlvd on hemp
yield and canabo explain how thrips and
aphids transmit the vroid and evaluate
the efficacy of using chemical elicitors
to control hlvd infections
during our conversation we discussed how
hop Laten viroid has been reported in
every hemp grown state in the US and
Canada how hlvd spreads through infected
clones mechanical contact seeds and
insect vectors like aphids and
thrips possible reasons why hemp
varieties appear more resistant than
cannabis varieties including genetic
diversity and environmental factors the
trade-offs associated with using
chemical elicitors on Infected plants
and strategies for preventing hlvd
spread including strict sanitation
insect monitoring frequent testing and
breeding for genetic
resistance before we get to my
conversation with Puna I'd like to thank
this episode sponsor Advanced
Nutrients founded in 1999 Advanced
Nutrients was the first to develop a
complete nutrient system that unlocks
the true genetic potential of the
cannabis plant since its Inception the
brand has introduced more than 50
Innovations to the cultivation community
and continues to revolutionize the space
through proprietary scientific
discoveries learn more at Advanced
nutrients.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr Puna
nachaa
[Music]
good morning Puna thank you so much for
joining you on the podcast oh thank you
Ben uh it's been H several years that I
did my last podcast I'm happy to be back
here talking about another important
pathogen uh in the Cannabis and hemping
industry yeah that's right you were on
the podcast before talking about beat
curly top virus in hemp I'll put a link
to the show in the show description so
people can check that out and I remember
after we did that I was saying that you
need to come down to canmed and um and
that year it didn't work out but we're
excited that you're going to be in
Puerto Rico this year uh giving a top on
one of our favorite topics HP late and
vroid uh if people have been listening
to the podcast for a while we've done a
number of different talks on it it's a
an emerging problem in the Cannabis
space and it always gets a lot of um
viewers and listeners because it is so
interesting so excited for you to share
some new information that you've learned
about the viroid and that you'll be
sharing at ced2 but before we get into
the new stuff I was hoping for those new
listeners or new viewers you could
provide an overview of hoplon vroid and
explain its significance to the hemp in
cannabis industry yes we do uh as you
mentioned hop plate en viroid is an
emerging pathogen but probably doesn't
need much introduction because it's just
spread like wildfire I should no pun
intended we are La is battling these
fires but it's been such a bane uh to
the Cannabis industry originally as the
name sugges it was identified in hops
that's the uh first host but very
quickly jump from Hops uh to the nearest
relative of hops um cannabis and seems
to be having a more severe impact in
cannabis than it did in hops where it
did affect um the quality but in
cannabis it seems to have uh more
significant
impact I think it was identified or at
least um published reports was in 2019
but maybe the industry had an idea of
what was happening a couple of years
before before that so the first reports
came out in 2019 in cannabis and then my
lab subsequently found it in our field
survey of hemp here in Colorado in
2021 and now pretty much every hemp
growing state has um reported hoplon
virus so it's spread all all the way New
Mexico up to Washington and Canada has
also been um you know U ravaged by this
disease I think I saw somewhere that the
reported impact was $4 billion annually
to the Cannabis industry which is
staggering because it impacts uh the
flow really badly right causing that
so-called duding where the flow um it
impacts the tricomes and that's where
the canabo are made so CBD and THC
levels are reduced and not only that the
the biomass the the plant is stunted
there are issues um with the quality of
the plant all in all impacting economics
and uh Downstream
pharmacological um you know applications
as well so all this is well well
characterized in cannabis but in hemp
right with the THC legally classified as
um Cannabis sativa with the THC levels
of less than 3% rightweight we did not
know the actual impact although field
Studies have shown that we can ident we
can um report it or identify it in field
grown hemp so uh that was one of the
research areas U that we focused on in
the last couple of years to do a
systematic study to understand the
impact on um field grown
hemp yeah I I mean very I've been very
aware of the problem in the Cannabis
industry and of course growing indoors
growing from clone and how that's a you
know uh a great way for hlvd to spread I
wasn't quite aware that it was being
seen in outdoor
H all of the reports from uh these other
states at least you know the in the
universities were not allowed to work
work on cannabis so nothing over um 3%
THC in fact at the Department of
Agriculture here at Colorado State at at
Colorado
CDA uh will would periodically come and
test our plans to make sure we are under
the legal limit and the pl don't don't
go MH so all of the reports from
the UN from these different states were
made in field grown
hemp except the ones from California the
initial ones came from Cannabis um so we
are finding it in field grown hemp now
um we just published it's not out yet um
um what we call a metagenome or a
metavirome so we surveying hemp send it
out for sequencing and then try to
identify the viruses in the last one we
did uh this was 20 22
23 um we did not find opan viroid in
field grown hemp which is good news uh
at least for the hemp Growers but
there's a whole another uh Suite of new
viruses that we've found but not hopl
and viroid which we did back in
2021 oh interesting so you found it in
2021 but your more recent surveys is
that you're not finding it not finding
it here interesting yeah yeah any ideas
where it went um good question now um
this might segue into um you know um the
some of the data that I'll be presenting
in canmed where we did the field a field
study um to see the impact of hopl and
viid on him and guess
what the infection rate was very low in
him it was is really uh difficult to get
hemp
infected uh with hopl and viroid you
know supposedly highly transmissible
right it's the TMV tobacco mosaic virus
which is a highly trans transmissible
virus it's supposed often called the TMV
of the vroid world but we couldn't get
our plants infected I think it it might
have to do with the genetic diversity of
hem as opposed to the clonally propag
ated hydroponically grown uh cannabis
that could be one reason so I I mean
this um field well it's kind of a fe we
call it a CRA so it's part it can be
partly um covered or you keep it open so
you know it's it's I would say it's a
hybrid between a greenhouse and a field
but you plant the hemp in the soil so it
could be it can be considered field
grown hemp so in the study the plants
look just great I mean we may have
gotten like 10% infection rate so I feel
like the the healthy environment the
genetics of hemp made it just outgrow or
out compete um the virus so um then the
other aspect is you know we do these
surveys or just look going into our
Fields whatever variety The Grow has we
are sampling that but it could be that
certain varieties of hemp are more
susceptible and some are not so um
there's so much left you know to be um
research so we were very surprised not
to find any popen vroid in our second
metagenome interesting and what um what
tissues were you testing if I may ask a
good question so we always do the leaves
with hemp the roots and I know um in
cannabis you often do the root which
again you know because of the growing
conditions it's easier with hemp the
roots are much harder to extract from so
we only test we test the apical leaves
but we also sample from different parts
of the plant because we are seeing that
and this has already been known some of
Dr pun's work has shown it's not equally
distributed in all parts of the plant
sure so we are very confident about our
sampling and we also test the stem uh um
didn't find it and um
metagenomics is um highly sensitive
technique right you could get a few
reads right and we detected zero so
interesting yeah and I know that some
research and some of the research that
our CSO has done here um with you know
purposely inoculating some plants um the
vroid will go down into the roots right
and sometimes stay there you said it it
never kind of progresses up into the
later stages of the plant and it goes
through flower and it looks great if you
test the roots it's there but it never
really
emerges higher so it could be something
like that it could be something like
that in the in the hemp too we were
thinking about actually testing the soil
that we did our field study in yeah and
that's something we are planning to
do interesting um so one of my questions
were were any of your what were some of
your surprising findings in regs to your
study I think that's a very surprising
finding was there anything
else
um no well once we were you know my my
former Master student he just graduated
Luke dle did this work when we were
going out there I mean he just lived
there in that crao we knew that this is
you know we're not going to see any
significant changes in any of the um
yield p parameters cannabinoid we were
still unsure but then we decided to
separate out the symptomatics so we did
have a few symptomatic uh
plants when we separated out the
symptomatic plants and the asymptomatic
plants and both were hlvd positive by
PCR but when we did that we saw a
reduction in um CBD and um GC levels so
when you so it's a a little bit more
nuanced Than You Know Than Just positive
and negative so Growers have to really
keep an eye out for
um the symptoms because the asymptomatic
plants like you said just did
fine but they are indeed positive so
that was an interesting finding which I
think others are also figuring it out
but so many different things um you know
so many things were different between
our study and what's happening in
cannabis
um um and and this is not published data
and I don't know if I'm I could present
this in can in canmed we did a screen of
30 hemp genotypes that we got from one
of our collaborators here this it's a
hemp genetics company called New West
genetics that we work closely with here
in Port Collins and we do see um VAR
some genetic diversity some variation in
um popul viroid level so
um all of this was uh exciting and new
data for us excellent no and in reading
through your abstract as well um it said
that you found that cannabis aphids and
thrips can acquire and transmit hlvd as
well can you talk a bit more about the
significance of that
Discovery yes so this was um it was not
surprising in fact what was surprising
is was that in hops they found that that
Hop's apid did not transmit hop latent
vroid and this was published where my in
in our world I mean apid as you can see
in my background see how prolific they
are in the on hem and um they can pretty
much and they've been shown to transmit
other viroids so it was kind of
surprising that they that they didn't
find it in Hops and so we set out to um
test apids
and thrips and the reason we pick those
are they are the most common Greenhouse
pest right they love the greenhouse
environment because it's hot humid this
makes them the populations grow uh
faster they and there's a year round
supply of uh uh host host plants for
them within five minutes both insects
can acquire the the vroid which is
really interesting it is in the flm and
apids feed in the flm of the plant but
it's also in the but trips have much
shorter mouth Parts aphid's mouth parts
are like mosquitoes they're the
mosquitoes of the Plant World so they
can go all the way down to the flo and
suck up the vroid uh thps are not but
they must be picking it up from the
their cell content feeders they're going
to just suck up all the cell content
cytoplasm nucleus every all of it so
that so there are different mechanisms
by which they're acquiring the viroid
but both are doing doing it super
quickly um and and so that was that's
great any any any insect could acquire
it but the proof of the concept was to
then test uh transmission and to do that
we then starve the insects to to make
sure all of the gut content is is out of
the insect it's not just in there
transiently
right and then we place those insects on
healthy plants and sure enough both both
of them can transmit I think um my um my
other Master student is uh re retesting
some things but retesting some assays
but it's between 10 to 25% transmission
and we sequence every single amplicon we
you don't just rely on the band on the
PCR U uh gel band every single one is um
sequent so not entirely surprising the
other one that I'm very keen to test is
spidermites which is another huge
problem a huge Greenhouse pest um and we
also find it in outdoor hem um so couple
of other insects to test the other uh
interesting aspect is uh last year uh we
saw that hops can also infect other host
right some really important host host
plants like
tomatoes um and um cryan so we want to
see if these vectors cannabis AIDS or um
thps Can transmit it to other host
plants as well because it just takes um
a few minutes to acquire and seemingly a
few minutes to transmit too interesting
no and what about um I remember from our
last conversation the leaf Hoppers
because I know that those transmit the
beat curly top Ires
correct uh we did not we've not thought
about Lea Leaf Hoppers but I'm going to
make a note
yeah they are not a huge Greenhouse Pest
and they need so that's the big so but
um you know hovd is
outside um so we I would hypothesize
because they are floam feeders there's
no reason why they would not be able to
do it but the level of trans the
efficiency um would be different look at
you Ben you are a budding
entomol I just pay attention I guess um
uh and another thing that you that you
brought up the the significance of
starving the um the insects before you
kind of T Test the transmission so um
explain kind of the reason that's
important so um you know when insects
consume the plant sap or um you know
they chew the leaves like a caterpillar
wood whatever is in the leaf is in the
caterpillar or in the a in the aid you
if you were to grind it up and test it
they would be positive
for let's say h and viroid that doesn't
mean they can transmit it because once
they poop it out so goes the pathogen
with uh with the plant material does
that make sense so to be called a
vector the virus or the viroid have to
bind to the insect mouth part to the
stylid and then bind in the gut and then
bind and again find the salivary glands
and come out through that mechanism not
just be pooped or you know do it
transiently and to do that we allow like
a two to four hour starvation period
because it's shown to get rid of all the
gut content uh contents and then you go
ahead and you do your your assays
interesting okay so it's not that it's
just kind of taking infected blow or sap
from one plant and depositing it
elsewhere it's
actually systemic within the insect
exactly that's a great way to say it so
the way the process works um is insects
pick it up it attaches to the stylet
some you know stylight the mouth part
goes into the gut then it the virod will
then come out of the gut into the body
cavity where we have insects have
something called hemolymph which is the
blood of the insect H and then reach the
salivary
glands get into the salivary glands and
when the insect feeds on a healthy plant
through the saliva the vroid has to come
out this whole um mode of transmission
has to happen for it to be called a
vector
interesting okay all right very cool um
one thing I just wanted to add one thing
I wanted um so we've been doing
acquisition assays you know how quickly
they can acquired it how quickly they
can transmit it but what we want to know
like I told you the this mode of
transmission within the insect we are
doing some confocal microscopy where we
tag the the vroid with gfp you know the
green fluoresence protein that can glow
and show us all the different parts of
the insect body that the vroid is moving
through so we get a good understanding
of how it's circulating systemically in
the insect oh wow very cool yes I'm so
excited one of the other things that
kind of stood out from when I was
looking at your abstract was um using
potential chemical elicitors yes um to
kind of I guess mitigate some of the
negative effects of hlvd so please tell
us more about that yes so um chemical
elicitors or synthetic elicitors also
called plant growth Regulators as the
name suggest it's a chemical that mimics
plant
hormones so it's essentially giving the
plants a little boost to get their
defenses going and this is not you know
I didn't come up with this idea uh um
we've been using it in Plant Pathology
and in entomology research as a way to
trigger plant defenses give them a
little boost to get it get it
activated uh you could also think of it
as a way to Prime the plants and and can
protect against diseases and pathogens
because naturally plant hormones or what
we call phyto hormones are doing this
but they're doing it at a at a low level
so that you know the plant can um devote
all the resources to the different
functions we want to give it this boost
so it can get activated and the reason
that I was interested in this research
is because cannabis and hemp can be
considered organic um production Sy
systems right because the um the
repertoire of um insecticides and
pesticides are so limited right all we
have and so there are only a handful of
products we don't even know their
efficacy and it turns out that these
chemical elicitors are actually
registered oh for use so that's that's
one of the reasons we went um we were
interested in this and so our idea was
to just boost the plants innate inherent
immunity to better defend uh the viroid
is this prior to
infection um no we didn't do it prior so
we infected the plant and um a week
later so we got the plant um going with
the infection and then a week later we
sprayed these elicitors and then sprayed
every week for up to three weeks and
then subsequently I think at the fourth
or the fifth week we took uh tissue and
analyzed for hlvd levels using qpcr then
let the plants grow go to flowering and
then did the canabo analysis so you
could we we debated should we do it um
spray first then infect or infect and
then
spray uh we decided to do and I uh
decided to do um the former because so
we we got clones from infected plants so
they were already
infected um ready to go cuz that's
probably a more n we figured that's
probably more of the natural situation
the plants are already infected
excellent and so what were the
results oh my goodness so you you know
this already and this is how it goes
with research it's never yes perfect
result always more questions to be asked
offs right yes exactly but it's it's
great um we did two rounds of it and
we're actually getting ready to to do a
third round so the results were mixed
bag but very interesting what we found
was yes indeed a certain phyto hormones
or chemical elicitors reduced hlvd
levels interestingly they also increased
the
biomass um you know the yield of the the
plant which we were excited about but go
to look at the flow production and
cannabinoid levels and it was and are
the main major ones like CBD and THC was
actually
reduced how
much I don't remember the not I I don't
I could pull it up I'll tell you biomass
like almost 50% for salicylic acid the
biomass increased 50% yeah compared
compared to an infected yeah no they're
all infected compared to so the control
was ethanol because that's the solvent
salicylic acid
dissolved in in ethanol the biomass per
plant was 8.3 gram and in the salicylic
acid sprayed it was like
15% 15 grams oh wow yeah so almost
double almost double because these elic
these phyto hormones also cause the
plants to cause cell division in delay
sense and essentially giving it better
overall health
excellent so I'm just picking salicylic
acid uh they all look pretty much the
same some of the other ones I'm saying
brainol brassinolide was 12.8 gam
compared to eight so a little less than
50 so let's look at
um um canono we can again pick salicylic
acid okay so TC or THC a was ,00
microgram per gram in the control in
ethanol and in sa it
was,
1300 microgram per gram what is that
math
30% how much 30 30 Z
30% so a third so if basically 100%
increase in biomass yeah but a 30%
decrease in th yes in thca
interesting interesting yeah but not so
interesting because guess what just
after we did this in this is a this was
a two years study from 2022 just and he
graduated uh in in fall in Fall here
comes a really nice study and I can talk
about that showing that in fact higher
levels our goal was to cause induction
our our the aim of our study you know
because we were kind of going blind was
we wanted to make sure the plant the
these um Pathways in the plant salicylic
acid or what what have you was uh was
turned on so we we went a little high on
the dosage and then a paper came out
saying higher dosage can reduce canono
whereas a low
dosage so since that paper came out we
are now we've got to fine tune the the
rates it's not so over applying it can
improve um reduce hlvd levels and um
biomass but does not have the same
impact for canabo which is important so
you got to fine-tune this and so we're
redoing um that experiment it's already
started and I should have some new data
uh for Canin excellent so you so there
is some fine tuning in in figuring that
out but but some poti potential yes for
sure there's potential for instance um
we applied 10 m molar of um salicylic
acid and the papers are saying 1.5 is
probably the the better um uh you know
value better concentration to go so we
might not we may not see an induction in
a PCR gel of the salicylic acid pathway
marker Gene but that's the way to go so
we're going to play around with the
dosage and
timing uh to fine tune that because
Growers don't have too many options um
for these um for HD and the other nice
thing about these elicitors is they also
confer protection against pests my own
lab has shown like salicylic acid can
reduce um
thps J right so you are literally
jasmonic acid are good against aphid so
you can actually kill two birds with one
stone so it's just a matter of
fine-tuning great and now in terms of
accessibility to the these um these
compounds these chemicals what whatever
you we're calling them elicitors um are
they EAS easily accessible pretty pretty
affordable as well yes pretty affordable
um not all so we used um you know um
chem like chemicals standard grade uh
chemicals because this was um a
scientific study but these products are
available in the market to buy and and
apply some of them are commercially uh
available and actually for the this new
round of experiments we've got going on
I've asked my lab manager to try to get
uh the commercially available one so we
try to make it as um applicable uh to
Growers excellent all right so in terms
of practical advice to Growers who are
concerned about hlvd
dealing with hlvd um based on the
studies you've done and the research
you've done what are some sort of
practical strategies to prevent or um
eliminate an hlvd
infection so we are finding that plant
Health really is um you know is crucial
in in terms of our um field experiment
where we saw that healthy plants were
impossible to even get
infected so that was that was key and
then these elicitors that boosted well
there were these tradeoffs um you know
um keeping the plants healthy did see
reduction in the vroid um
levels and given that
um now we know that these insect PES are
vectors I think monitoring for both
early symptoms of the disease because it
just takes one plant to serve as a host
for secondary spread
right it's not just quarantine it but
it's it's it may be too late the insects
already have it and then they are going
around infecting it so I think
monitoring for insects so we have sticky
trap and we do this in my lab it's the
bane of my lab too we've never had this
much quarantining and uh care um
everything is in different places and I
I know Growers are already doing this so
keep your replay sticky cards often and
testing testing testing testing
testing which I know is expensive and we
actually have a project under way to
develop some um
onsite um field based Diagnostics you
know because it's getting it's even 20
what is it right now I think it's 25
dollars per sample it's so expensive and
timec
consuming so I think
um yeah I know there are some tests out
there but um we are trying to work
something out with some collab ators in
University of Wisconsin Madison so I
would say monitoring sanitation avoid
cross
contamination and testing uh based on
the research uh that I know I hope in
the coming years um you know some of the
things we've talked about um breeding
for that they would be resistant Vari
genotypes varieties and genetic
engineering I mean USDA approved um
these transgenic hemp right at least in
theory M so I think those are all uh
possibilities we'll have to look think
about the sort of social stigma of GMOs
that still
exist yeah of course and you know
interesting thing that we're adding to
this year's caned we're having a whole
genomics Workshop all about um um it's
kind of a halfday workshop exploring the
use of genomics in in breeding and in
different applications for cannabis so
we're going to be talking about about
you know genetic engineering and GMOs
and and and touching on those things so
uh I think it's going to be a great
session um to sort of have those
conversations because uh it seems like
that's the way things are eventually
going to go GNA go exactly no I thought
that I'm super excited about it I saw
Todd Michael is is coming yes so I'm
very excited yeah so I yeah this one
because it's so resilient and so yeah um
yeah no we need all the you know the
throw the whole kitchen sink approach uh
for it sorry no and no when you were
talking about plant health and it kind
of just clicked in my head and you know
I as I understand it outdoor hemp is
largely grown from seed whereas indoor
cannabis largely grown from clones and
there's always been the conversation of
you know growing from sea that have more
Vigor and our just more resilient plants
and I wonder if that could be you know
part of why you're seeing resilience in
in the in the H plants for sure so in in
our field study we the we had a um what
we call a dual purpose grain fiber hemp
uh variety which was grown from seed and
we had a high CBD line that was clonally
propagated so we tried to do both but it
but it didn't matter both the yeah dual
the seed grown and the clonally
propagated um High CBD line that we like
to use in in our
lab um did not have uh much diff any any
difference in the infection rate No but
you know this is just one clone right
but but yeah one yeah that's not the
case in the Cannabis industry so you are
AB I think there's something there about
the plant health and the conditions
excellent all right well pun winding
down here um I did want to give you an
opportunity to share any other resources
or links uh that you think might be
useful for anyone who's watching or
listening who wants to learn more about
this topic or your work please um go
ahead and share oh this is this is
perfect uh because um my team is putting
together um hemp entomology website um
through my lab uh website it's almost
ready to go it's essentially a curated
curation of all the reli you know
reliable resources for um pests and
diseases including some of our latest
research one thing we're planning to do
is have a newsletter to
Growers both cannabis and hemp uh we're
going to put put that out through this
is the Colorado Department of
Agriculture newsletter and so we get all
the hemp registrants but I would love to
reach the Cannabis industry so they can
you know um inter have more interaction
with the UN University folks who are
actually doing this this research with
um you know um for the betterment of The
Growers for the scientific um um
intellectual Merit of it um so once we
have we are still um finalizing some
aspects of this website but it's
essentially a way to just disseminate uh
our you know the current knowledge get
it out of the grow I would love to send
it to you and maybe in this stock have
it there so Growers can sign up uh for
for all the News latest research in my
lab and um you know other collaborators
lab so they don't have to go reading
scientific papers so that I'm I'm EXC
excited about that we are continuing to
work on the virus Vector interaction as
um I have already mentioned to you the
other interesting uh aspect is the seed
transmission which is probably very
surprising to everybody right to find
out that it's what over 80% seed
transmitted in hemp wow um and not seed
transmitted in hops the the first uh
host um so we are trying to look into
that and understand um the mechanism a
little better because right now I I
don't think any of the hemp is being the
seeds are being tested for you know
certification or
um what do you say um state um State
tostate trans Transportation so it could
become a big issue if we don't do
anything proactively wow you said 80% I
think so I'm I'm pretty sure it was it's
staggering in uh in
hemp so um so I think having um
certified seeds clean stocks start clean
would be the way to go and so the lines
we used in my field study the the high
CBD that was clonally propag propagated
came from a tissue culture lab so we
knew it did not have anything and so
with the seeds we made sure we tested to
make sure that they were in fact
negative but not to say that there are
um potentially hemp uh out
there that has H excellent all right
well Puna yes please do share the link
to that site be happy to put it in the
show description so it's easy for folks
to find um and thanks again for for
joining us on the podcast and sharing
this information and giving us a nice
preview of the information that you'll
be sharing at CED 25 down in Puerto Rico
yes we can't wait to um meet you in
person I don't think we have so and I
don't think so yes so that' be great and
no I really appreciate um you putting
this podcast together and really helping
um The Growers out which is the bottom
line right for all of us so appreciate
that excellent well thanks again and
we'll see you in June Bye by
[Music]