so we're going to go over the the
molecular biology that's going on with
hop and viid uh much of what we know
about hopl and vroid we are assuming
from what we know about other viroids
that infect other plants so um there is
there are some leaps that are being made
here um but I think you'll find by the
end of this that um they're they're
beginning to resonate with what we're
seeing in other in other plants okay so
I'm thankful for zamir actually giving
you a big background on the bioburden of
this um what I'm going to try to do is
describe what we think this is doing in
the plant and maybe that will guide us
in a direction of breeding away from
this problem so this is a picture of
hopl and vroid sequence through RNA fold
up there on the upper right uh it's not
very large it doesn't code for any
proteins it's just a piece of RNA so
what the heck is this doing in the plant
to create such a tremendous uh downfall
and yield the going hypothesis in other
viroids is that this is acting through
an RNA interference pathway it makes so
much of this RNA that that RNA
eventually hybridizes to some
transcripts that share sequence hology
with it and then some enzymes noin
argonot and dicer come in and dice up
this RNA and as in effect downregulate
the expression of genes that have
sequence homology to hop L and vroid so
when we were playing around with
designing primers for for more optimal
PCR with this I think it was either Liam
or Steve and our biomatics group blasted
this thing against uh the Jamaican lion
genome and came up with all these hits
saying we probably shouldn't put primers
here uh or we might amplify the Cannabis
genome and have a bad test um and lo and
behold that got us thinking well wait a
minute maybe that's actually
biologically meaningful outside of just
your primer design um maybe this
actually has uh a function going on so
this is a picture of a hop Laten vroid
genome with two mutations in it uh
compared to the reference that was
published in 1988 and what happens is
the structure of the vroid completely
changes I'll show you a comparison in
the next slide but um just to get
yourself a handle on some of the parts
of this VY there's a central controlled
region in the middle which is uh has two
overlapping quadruplex G structures
those structures are generally We
Believe ribozymes although this this
particular virid has not been reported
to have any ribosy activity it's still
unknown how this is replicating in the
plant the the belief is that a DNA
dependent RNA polymerase amplifies an
RNA template which is somewhat um not
very believable but that's the the going
thinking is that a enzyme that's
supposed to replicate DNA
somehow mistakenly replicates RNA into
more RNA and then this creates a long
linear template since this is circular
and that long linear template then gets
processed into smaller 256 base per
pieces and then re circularized and we
don't know any of the enzymes that are
doing that right now now what you'll
notice is we've decorated certain
portions of this vroid with the sequence
uh regions where they have homology to
certain genes in the Cannabis genome uh
and uh that's going to become important
as we step forward so I mentioned that
the variance in this can make a very big
impact if you just put two Snips in this
you will see the structure on the left
versus the structure on the right uh
this also changes the footprint that it
may have in the Cannabis reference
because we're dealing with very short
homologies here just 17 to 25 base par
homologies you switch one or two bases
in some of those regions and it goes to
completely different genes so uh the the
variation we need to keep track of in
the field to make sure that the
pathology of this doesn't shift over
time now if you take um all everything
that we found that are 17 bases and
higher there's 25 genes in the Cannabis
genome that this has homology to and it
may have some down regulation uh impact
on so we set out to measure that uh
we're going to touch on that a little
bit later the first part I want to touch
on is how much variation is there in the
population uh with hop and virid like
what are we dealing with are we dealing
with a covid that's like changing every
3 months from alpha to to to a nron or
dealing with a fairly consistent vroid
the literature implies this DNA
dependent RNA polymerase should make
lots of Errors copying this and so
people believe it's going to be a quas
species which means it's not doesn't
even share the same sequence within one
organism it begins to get heteroplasmic
within an organism we don't know if
that's true I think we're going to show
you some data that suggests we're very
skeptical of that uh this is a site that
we built called vedia uh when people are
are testing their their strains they
sometimes want to submit their hop lat
and viroid strains into us for
sequencing we sequence them and then put
them public so that we have a mechanism
to track the pandemic throughout the
industry uh and this also does some of
the RNA folding information and then
blasts those those novel variants
against the Cannabis genome to see if
you have any novel RNA locations that
may be at Bay um so it gives you a
little painted picture like this you can
see the color coding on the vroid those
are the color codings of the regions in
the genome that they have homology to so
three of the most common genes that we
find it's a gene known as cog7 that's a
gene involved in shoot apil merism
growth there's another one called
expansin which is involved in cell
development uh and growth and another
one called clasp uh and we'll touch on a
few more of the ones that were in that
long spreadsheet uh so there's there's
many genes that this is potentially
interacting with uh what does the
variation look like in ncbi well ncbi
has been collecting information on this
from I want to say late 1980s uh and
there's about 155 genomes in ncbi and
they all vary in length and they all
vary in uh sequence context dramatically
now uh we've been studying this for
quite a bit uh this is what the picture
looks like of the variation in ncbi and
every one of those white marks on the
sequins are a variant and all the little
dots are areas where there's just no
sequin at all uh this had people worried
that there was a lot of variation in the
length of the thyroid now I I think as
we've come to um study this more we're
recognizing that this is a very
difficult RNA molecule to sequence it's
a it's a hair pin so it's completely
self-complimentary in most places so
when you go to try and sequence this
even saying or sequencing chokes up on
this and creates a lot of air so I think
a lot of these we're finding are
potentially sequencing air that's that's
occurring trying to sequence this
circular RNA molecule um and instead
what we're seeing as we go about and and
categorize all these variants is the
vast majority of the variants are what
is known as can 2 so darkart Nursery
when they first came out with this said
we're seeing predominantly two variants
can one and can 2 can one is the is is
the the POA reference that was
discovered in hops in the late ' 80s and
can 2 is what they're they're finding in
the United States all the other variants
we see are minor variants uh it's kind
of hard to see in that graph but the
majority of those strains over 130 of
them all have this U 225a change known
as can 2 and the rest of them are a
bunch of uh I would say perhaps
sequencing artifacts or very rare rare
variants many of these variants are
actually condensing or consolidating
themselves under primers that have been
published in the literature for people
surveying this so there's probably
something going on with Sanger
sequencing where we get poor sequencing
over the primer sites and we have an a
higher uh increase in error rate on this
now when we chart these from the people
that send them in this is a
representation of about 18 different
locations that have sent samples in for
sequencing um these dots on the map
actually represent many many samples
that came from that location for
instance the the work in Massachusetts
uh from feno Express probably represent
stuff from all over New England uh
likewise the darkart is a nursery they
probably are getting samples from all
over California and the pack Northwest
so it's much more diverse and spread
apart than what you're seeing these dots
represent but the important thing is to
see here is can one and can 2 are all
over the world there isn't one
particular pocket of one variant versus
another uh they um they're in China
they're in the pack Northwest and um
they both seem to be spreading um
somewhat equally all right so how do we
validate a test to make sure we can pick
up all this variation uh important thing
is that you have very high sensitivity
but we don't want to confuse that with
specificity if you put primers in the
wrong place on this on this vroid you'll
you can get some background off the
Cannabis genome because there's a lot of
homology to the Cannabis genome uh you
also should have more than two primer
sets because you don't want to put some
of your primer sets on of those variants
and then they don't amplify and you're
only surveying can one versus can 2 and
missing any of the rare variants um RNA
tests need a lot more scrutiny DNA is
really easy to predict where your
primers are going to land RNA you can't
really predict where they're going to
land because we don't have complete
surveys of every transcriptome under
every condition out there you end up
with alternate splicing you end up with
circular rnas known as lariats so
getting primers to work in RNA you
really have to test them against real
living organisms you can't just do in
silica prediction so we've gone through
and tested this on 50 different organis
that were commonly found in cannabis to
show that they don't interact with that
and we even went through the painstaking
effort of of chemically synthesizing uh
25 different viroids um to prove that we
could hit those as well the reality is
only a couple of these really matter at
the moment we're not seeing High
prevalence of the other ones in space
third question is what do you survey in
the in the plants and this is actually
something that has evolved over time as
we've learned more about the plant uh
we've been involved in two or three
studies that showed really high CTS in I
should say higher virid loads in the
leaves than in The Roots all right um
we've been in one study where it showed
higher CTS in The Roots where things
were completely missed in the leaves and
I'm going to touch on another study that
we've been doing that shows some plants
that only Harbor this in the roots and
they don't even spread it out to the
leaves um and that may actually said
some light on some of the U the
tolerances is having um so at the moment
testing both tissues is probably makes a
lot of sense uh because uh we don't
actually know where this is always going
to always going to land um but we what
can we do now that we know about where
the homology is against the Cannabis
Gene and what you're seeing in these
gray boxes are the regions of the vroid
that have homology to different regions
in the Cannabis genome uh so we can
track for variants when they fall inside
those regions to know that if there's a
new variant circulating maybe this is
changing it's Target in the Cannabis
genome and then we have a Sanger
sequencing program in place to sequence
these things very quickly so that we can
survey if there's anything changing um
but in addition to this uh we wanted to
ask the question of what is happening
The genome from an RNA perspective when
you infect a plant versus a control
clone do you get different gene
expression and does that gene expression
to give you uh any sense of the
pathology of the viroid so we took a
Jamaican lion clone this is the mother
plant that we sequenced many years ago
and put the reference public uh this
thing is still circulating uh we're able
to get clones from the mother infect one
now we weren't able to actually infect
this plant we took um some of the advice
from zamir to try to use Q-tips and swab
vroid on on cut leaves and this would
not fact we tried that three times
waiting two weeks between each time and
it would not it would not go positive on
us so we finally broke a branch off the
bottom of a plant and used a p1000 to
inject the virid right into the stem uh
and we did that two weeks later we were
positive in The Roots but nowhere else
um so that was just an oddity we we we
weren't expecting uh now it turns out
throughout the course of this study what
we did is we sampled The Roots we
sampled the leaves we sampled the
flowers and the mar stems in triplicate
every single week for 10 weeks and
sequence those with over 40 to 50
million reads per sample so this is
about 80 libraries with um terabytes of
sequencing information um and what we're
trying to do is track this between
infected and non-infected and what we
saw through the course of time is that
this would continue to be negative when
we're doing you know basically 16 qpcrs
every week across the entire time scale
here this was always negative in the
leaves and only positive in The Roots uh
now what we did start to notice toward
the end of its life cycle is that the
flowers and the leaves just jacked up
the anthy in production okay we don't
know why this could be an immune
response but we're not seeing this as
heavily increased in the in the control
that's not infected all right so uh we
then at we push this Beyond its actual
flowering time and just said let it see
if it dies in The Vine and does it
finally make itself into the leaves like
Let It Go a couple weeks past flowering
and so as we did that we began testing
and every single tissue we tested uh 57
out of 57 of these were negative if the
tissue was purple uh then we found some
parts of the plant that were lower
branches that looked a little scraggly
like you can see there on the on the
upper I guess on your side the upper
right um and uh that particular Branch
seven out of seven were positive so to
after after flowering time when we
really stress this thing out we could
see a couple of the lower branches get
positive but the top canopy anything
that was purple and had anthro in
production was not testing positive for
us now we don't have good cannaboid
measurements on this so can't give you a
good sense of yield other than the
Growers that have handled this thing for
5 years do not see a measurable
Difference by eye of the flower weight
in the yield but we we clearly don't
have semms and hlc's on this to confirm
that so uh that that needs to be
probably repeated now that we have an
idea of what this experiment might yield
we didn't go into this anticipating um
this this outcome so there are some some
literature out there that tie virid
infection with increase in flavonoid
production and anthocyan production so
this we aren't the first to find this um
others have have listed genes that they
believe have different transcriptional
um loads when their viroids are
infecting them and they do point back to
flavonoid production we don't know if
this is a defense mechanism uh we don't
know if you know cause and effect here
but it's just an interesting observation
that um these may be playing a role
what's going on okay so if you're not
familiar with these types of plots these
are integrated genome viewers these are
plots of sequencing read coverage across
particular transcripts and so what we
wanted to see is is this RNA happening
like if are we going to see down
regulation of particular genes that have
homology to hopl and viroid and when we
scan across a few of these uh we can
certainly see in this case it's cog7 we
can see the ones that are hlv infected
there's a there's a decrease in in um
expression but note the decrease in
expression is only over that short
window of where there's interaction with
the virus the entire transcript isn't
gone it's just knocking out those that
particular region of the transcript this
was also seen in uh the clasp Gene we
can see some down regulation of the
window where there's ology to hlvd but
it does not kill the entire transcript
um still don't know what that means it's
just an interesting observation it's a
bit more of a global picture of this I'm
sorry that the fonts there aren't aren't
very helpful for you but you can see
that there this is differential gene
expression on on the 25 different genes
I had in that initial table and across
uh a variety of samples that are
infected versus non-infected in leaves
in Roots and in tissue um and if I could
do a better job with the laser here I'd
point out to you some features here but
what is happening is on the left side is
predominantly samples that are not
infected and on the right side are
samples that are infected and we're
still kind of combing through what all
this means but there does seem to be
some trends for changes in gene
expression um based on infection and
non- infection uh in in in tissue
specific as well so one question people
ask is you have this much RNA sequencing
data uh what is did you pick up any hopl
virid in there and we did we shouldn't
have because we used polya capture to do
this but some of the virid is at such
high concentration it comes through we
sequence it and it's all the same so
there is an Aquas a species thing going
on in this plant it's one clonal copy of
H hplvd across all the tissues that we
found it in um the other thing that
happens when you start looking for this
um type of contamination or I should say
sequence in there um is you begin asking
about the canabus variation so we have a
large database of 1834 genomes now that
we can then ask this question are there
variations underneath these hplvd
targets that may change the way this RNA
interference behaves um and in fact this
gives you kind of a picture of COG 7 all
the Snips down there at the bottom track
you can see it's this is a densely
covered area there's a snip probably
every 50 bases in our database so uh if
if you're dealing with you know 25 Ms
you're going to find some Snips in the
neighborhood of these things uh and
that's in fact the case so this is a
look uh an alignment of COG 7 across
just a window of some of the cultivars
that are in the canopia database and you
can see there are variants that exist in
the target of homology for hplvd these
would be nice targets to basically breed
and then challenge to see if they
actually have uh A reduced phenotype of
uh or or loss of loss of yield we can
see the same thing in the clasp Gene as
well you can March through every one of
these Gene targets and you can see that
there are variants that exist out in the
population that alter the footprint for
hplvd and they're they're candidates for
potential genetic um tolerance I would
say to this virus or viroid now you got
to keep in mind um the way this thing
replicates is we're not going to get
resistance it will probably get into a
plant and replicate but it may not have
RNA interference capacity to shut down
the the the the actual pathology or the
growth of the plant but it may still be
PCR positive uh this is what we've seen
in the Hop industry The Hop industry's
have this problem for 40 years it's
never gone away now that we know from
zamir that there seed transmission maybe
pollen transmission there's paper
suggesting viroids move in fungal
mycelium that they can move in fusarium
spores we're not going to you're not
going to bleach your way out of this
problem we're going to have to breed our
way out of the problem and that I think
is what has happened in the hot field
they have found cultivars up there that
just have reduced loss in secondary
metabolites they're not they're not
perfect but they they they take it from
being 40% loss down to like 5% loss and
then they work with those um now and
part of this discovery when you sequence
all the RNA and something is you find
out something that blows your entire
experiment apart and that is one of the
plants we were working with had cucumber
mosaic virus in it uh so this has never
been found in cannabis before and we now
have a good sequence of its genome it is
in fact in cannabis however its tissue
tropism is different while we're finding
hplvd in The Roots predominantly in our
plants this thing is not in the roots
it's in the other tissues uh and it's a
lot more polymorphic inside these
tissues than hop Len viroid all right
this has a snip almost every 20 bases
inside of its genome and it was
different enough that the primers we
designed to Target cucumber mosaic virus
off of other plants don't work on the V
the virus that's in the cannabis plant
it has mutated itself on its you know Z
zoonotic Quest into cannabis uh to be so
different that we've had to redesign
primers for this so um this infects
12200 plants this is this is goes
everywhere so this shouldn't be a
surprise to anybody it is in fact a quas
species it tends to be about 95%
identical to references when you find it
in in cannabis so um this is another one
that we should keep an eye on I can't I
don't think I can go backwards on this
can I I can so you'll notice some of
those leaves and upper lip picture that
we missed you can see a little bit of a
mosaic pattern there I think that's
what's going on is that plant actually
had CMV in it as we can detect but we
just didn't you know make not of those
we probably you know blame that on
something else and uh here we are so I
think I've got enough time but so in
conclusions um we don't see evidence of
hoped being a quasi species although
literature suggest otherwise but we're
just not seeing it from the sequencing
we've been doing please send in samples
we'll sequence more and track this for
the for the industry because it's going
to be important in case it does mutate
um some of the plants can keep hlv in
the roots and remain relatively
asymtomatic this is important if you're
going to cut and kill every plant that's
positive only in The Roots You might
lose the plants that are in fact most
tolerant to get us out of this so I
understand if you have you have
something like this in your grow you got
to clean everything out however uh in
the process of doing so um be aware of
this you might want an isolation room
where you can find the plants that have
very low viroid load and start greeing
with those and keep them away from your
facilities uh where you're doing your
production because that might be a
better long-term plan than just being on
a PCR treadmill the rest of your life um
there are phenotypes of CMV and hplvd
overlap we have to keep that in mind we
need to do more screening for CMV to see
what's out there um in sequencing some
of the mothers and the varies we think
can provide you a long-term strategy for
how to breed your way through this so I
think with that I'm going to skip over
the end of these slides and just thank
these people for uh for helping us out
in all this work I'll take questions
thank
you we might be short on time for
questions yeah okay he's giving me the
hook all right I'll be at lunch