[Music]
all right
well we've established the problem what
do we do about it so if you were a
grower and you you suspect that you have
an infected plant what are your options
right so there's there's many things
Growers can do I mean the first thing
they need to do for sure is confirm that
they've got population
so whatever plant they're dealing with
most likely it's a flowering plant
because that's usually when you see it
and they send it off for testing the
first thing would be to work backwards
and try to figure out where did where
did I get my my clones from from for
that particular plant or that particular
genotype what did I did I grow it
indoors did I purchase it from someone
else or did I start it from seed uh and
once you've sort of worked backwards you
can say to yourself all right let's
assume it came from clones within your
own facility that means the mother plant
definitely has Heartland so you work
backwards you then test your mother
plants uh depending on how big they are
and so on we can we can talk about
sampling strategies but you test your
mother plant and obviously if the mother
plant is infected
um the bad news is that I would say it's
got to be it's got to be thrown away
you've got to get rid of it
um there's really no proven ways right
now to to rescue a plant that has hot
latent in it I mean we've talked about
Mary stem culture and tissue culture and
so on it's possible but it hasn't been
demonstrated uh on a high level on a
high scale that you can you can rescue a
multiplied that's called public
so if you've proven that it's your
mother plan then obviously you get rid
of that
um the other possibility is that it
picked it up
um when the plant was in veg so let's
say you're vegging on the table and if
you're using Hydroponics then you've got
water or nutrient solution moving
between plants uh We've shown and others
have shown that it can't move with water
with recirculating water and so a veg
plant that's that's maybe two weeks old
could potentially have picked up hot
latent through the root system and and
the viral that makes its way into the
plant that way and then of course the
last alternative is a seed if you
started from seed you then test the
plant that came off the seed it could be
that that that gave rise to your
infected flowering plant
so it's it's a it's a detective sort of
a detective process or you know a
process of elimination deciding where
where did it come from you need to know
that that's number one
yeah and I think you kind of answered my
next question but I think it's a good
good thing to hammer home there really
doesn't seem to be any sort of treatment
or kind of remediation options available
yet right
yeah if you've got a heavy heavy
infected or even an infected mother
plant
um now you know people have tried and
people are trying taking cuttings from
different parts of the of the Big Planet
so you could you could definitely do
that you could take them from the top
they're actively growing you could take
it from the side the bottom but then you
have to go through and test all of those
to see if by chance and really it is a
chance if by a chance you are able to
get a clone that was free of of Health
label you know when the viral gets in
and we can discuss this now the first
place it goes is down into the roots
right so let's say let's say I infected
it through a cutting I went with my
tools and I transferred some sap onto a
cut surface and the first place that
goes is down into the roots and that
takes about two weeks
so let's say two weeks after uh it was
introduced it goes down into the roots
and then from The Roots it's moved
upward and the reason it's moved upward
is it it sort of follows the flow of of
sugar start sugars that are being
produced by photosynthesis in the plant
and that usually is towards the actively
growing shoots which are the young
shoots so you'll find it in the young
shoots probably around four weeks after
that initial infection occurred and then
it starts moving around the planet so
let's say by by six weeks it's now
pretty much everywhere but there are
cases where you know a branch gets
missed you've got a disease plan and all
of a sudden you know a healthy branch on
one side and I think I have a photo uh
in the presentation we can come back to
it in a second for some reason that
Branch got missed if you're lucky enough
you can get a cutting out of that a
clone out of that and you may have
escaped uh populate a distance in that
particular in that particular plant
um so it's not a uniform distribution
throughout it so
some producers will go through and take
clones from various parts of the of the
mother plant in the hopes that they can
find a few that don't have the uh the
thyroid
[Music]
thank you