[Music]
all right
I'm testing everything's coming back
negative everything is great okay but
now I'm finding oh no a few plants over
in this corner now they're infected
should I do more testing to make sure to
kind of mitigate this spread somehow or
well if it's surely if it's a definite
positive I would I would move it out I
would move it into another room and then
decide what you want to do don't leave
it there now
um it's interesting because I haven't
seen any data yet to suggest that the
viroid moves very effectively you know
down down the road for example if if
somebody's walking
you know they say with your clothes
brush up against the plant I don't know
that that is sufficient damage to the
leaf to to move properly it does for
many viruses and thyroids but there may
be data out there but I haven't seen it
yet and the reason I say that is because
I'm you know being I've walked into
facilities where they've got a few
infected plants here then everywhere if
this thing was moving with with people
brushing up against the plants every
damn plant in that location would be
infected and that's not the case we're
finding isolated spots Here There and
Everywhere that may have been introduced
through a a pruning tool sap sap the
movement of sap is super important so
when you brush up against a plant there
really is no sap coming being released
or or on your clothes that's gonna react
on a wound on another plant but sap on
your tools and sap on your gloves so
you've got obvious sap stuck to your
gloves and you touch another plant and
you damage it that will transmit it
damage is the key
the tissue has to be damaged usually I
think that it has to be the vascular
system has to be exposed in other words
there has to be a broken vein or a
broken off leaf that allows that Viral
to to enter in I think just putting the
viroid on the surface of a leaf and
letting it sit I don't believe is going
to cause an infection so you got to have
the wounding and you've got to have the
sap and water so these plants could have
picked it up if there was recirculating
water that has the viroid in it and and
somehow got into root contact and then
of course the viral is spread within the
uh within the plant so recirculating
water is a problem because
I haven't seen any treatments yet that
work so even 100 degrees Centigrade
heating doesn't do it uh UV doesn't do
it fluorination doesn't do it I don't
know yet what treatments could be made
to water to clean it up recirculating
water yet I mean there's there's
obviously a lot of companies working on
that and eventually we'll have an answer
but right now you have to be super
careful with water that's being
recirculated from an infected infected
mother or plant wow yeah that that seems
that seems like a massive issue now
in terms of that so in addition to
testing plants you should you should be
testing your water and your surfaces
your equipment things like that as well
yeah so
um definitely if you're recirculating
and you know you've got a high incidence
of hot blatant you're almost guaranteed
to to have it in the in the
recirculating water now we got to
remember it's not pure water that has
the viroid it's little flakes of small
pieces of roots and organic matter and
debris that's come off the roots that's
left off that's carrying the thyroid in
it
um and so when the water is recirculated
they're still it's still got a little
bit of particles and stuff in it that
potentially has the has the thyroid in
it we've seen it on surfaces on for
example on flood tables so if there's a
plant that's sitting on a table and and
there's water you know up against the
roots on the bottom you can find hot
latent on the surface of that table as
well as of course on tools for that
cleaning bleach does a pretty good job
or or work on two percent because that
comes in direct contact with with the
water or the you know the film of water
that's on the table
um it can eliminate hot latent viral
quite effectively on on tools and on the
on the surfaces of tables but in terms
of what does it do to sap if there's
infected sap
um I don't know how effective work on or
bleach are at this stage where you've
got visible sap being moved from plant
to plant whether whether those two
chemicals will completely eradicate uh
the viroid but for surfaces there's
definitely materials out there that will
work
excellent
[Music]