well i'm pleased to have this
opportunity to
talk with you about something a little
different
and about the potential impacts of
cannabis emissions in the atmosphere
which is something we need to understand
if we're going to have a sustainable
uh
cannabis industry
and so i'll be going through a little
background about the plant volatile
emissions and their environmental
impacts
the what we understand right now about
these cannabis emissions including that
that smell that cannabis smell which is
something we've figured out in the past
year
and then finally uh some solutions uh to
potential problems with cannabis
emissions
so plants emit hundreds of different
volatile compounds into the atmosphere
some of those you're very familiar with
uh things you smell in your kitchen from
plants out in your garden
floral scents are on obvious ones but
there are a lot of other ones as well
too some of those we really can't smell
uh very much
so there's a whole range of different
compounds
coming from different processes
so one one question is well why are
plants emitting all these various
compounds
some of them we we know quite well what
the physiological roles are uh what the
ecological roles are an obvious one is a
pollination right bringing in the birds
and bees and seed dispersers
but also a lot of it's for protection
purposes so these plants uh
have these compounds for for a reason
uh some of these we we know well uh for
defense some some of them we really
don't understand very well
but there are also the impacts on the
ambient environment
and
these impacts can include very large
impacts on chemistry of the atmosphere
greenhouse gases air pollutants
are impacted by these compounds but in a
clean environment
these compounds are emitted into the
environment they get oxidized chewed up
into carbon dioxide reabsorbed by the
atmosphere so they don't have an impact
so in a clean environment these plant
volatiles don't have an impact on
pollution but it's very different in a
polluted environment and we we study
this in a range of different places uh a
really nice place uh where we've we've
worked on this has been in the middle of
the amazon
so very clean pristine area around
just plant emissions
but then you have the city of manaus
about 2 million people
unregulated emissions so a lot of
pollution there
and we're able to go and do studies
these are studies
uh sponsored by the national science
foundation uh department of energy uh
and and brazilian science agencies we
have aircraft uh sampling systems
downwind and we could sit there and look
at what was going on in the pristine
environment and then see what happens
when the manaus plume goes over
and what happens when you get the
polluted environment mixing with these
plant volatiles you make a lot of ozone
a lot of particles these are two major
regional air quality problems and
they're also very important short-term
climate forcers
so very large impacts on on the
environment from this
um
uh my my colleague will viset is has
done work looking at on areas like here
in the u.s what are the impacts
and uh including uh cannabis cultivation
so he did a study looking at the
emission of these plant volatiles that
you get from cannabis cultivation
and for the particular location where
it's
has been grown in denver you can get a
significant impact on ozone
denver has an ozone problem it's right
on the edge of being in compliance for
ozone so a little bit of a push on ozone
is a huge problem uh for denver and and
colorado
and so the way these studies are done is
to go in measure what's being emitted
from the plants and then extrapolating
that with a regional air quality model
where you can
run the model without the cannabis
emissions and then run it with the
cannabis emissions and you can see the
impact of the cannabis
and that impact is is up to about a ppb
of of ozone
and so the take home message here is
that there's potential for
cannabis growing operations to have uh
impact on on air quality in some regions
not in all regions and again if this
were a clean area if this were
pristine
in the amazon not near manaus there
wouldn't be any impact at all of the
cannabis emissions but when you have it
in a dirty area particularly oxides of
nitrogen around which which we have a
lot of uh in our cities
then you can make ozone and and
particles
and so this the idea that uh these
volatile missions are important for
global uh the global environment is
something we've known for for decades
and so these these emissions are in all
the global climate models all the
regional air quality models and we've
kind of worked out you know the uh the
impact of forest and large-scale
vegetation
more recently though we've realized that
there also can be an impact on these
urban areas like denver like los angeles
and in the past we we kind of ignored
that uh both because it so complicated
to try to do the vegetation in an urban
area
but also because there was so much
emissions of vocs right
but because uh our regulators have done
such a great job of reducing the voc
emissions in our cities we're now at the
point
where we think here in los angeles
county the most populous county in the
u.s
about half of the emissions
of these vault organic compounds which
impact smog ozone and particles about
half of it's coming from plants
and the
and all these compounds are not equal in
terms of their impact on ozone and
particles and the ones coming from
plants are actually have more of an
impact uh than
those coming from cars and in fact
factories so we think it's actually more
than half of the impact
well because we've been studying this on
the global scales for for a long time
for these large
scale impacts we have models we have
models that we've developed
and again are in all the climate models
and regional air quality models
and basically look at how much
vegetation there is look at
the weather the heat temperature all the
things that would affect these emissions
and and we we do these studies going
from small scales understanding the
biochemistry of what's going on
to looking at large scales where we can
see how does it impact
because again these plant
voc on their own don't have an impact
but it's when they impact with
anthropogenic emissions there's a
problem so we do aircraft studies now we
have satellite data and so we can kind
of uh
expand and look at the large scale
impacts
uh again on the on the small scales
where we can use these enclosure
measurements and understand for
individual plants what they emit
and what controls it so temperature
light uh stress are are important part
of the controls so we have these models
and and we we uh using these enclosures
under controlled conditions we can
figure out what's what's controlling all
of these emissions
okay so now back to cannabis um we first
started studying this a couple years ago
and uh
one of the
uh interesting things was people didn't
really know what that odor was of the
skunky odor because of course with
cannabis there's this potential for air
quality impacts but also just local odor
impacts right is is an important issue
in a lot of areas
talking to people in in the cannabis
industry a lot of people thought well
it's this skunky terpene uh mercing was
thrown out is is a possibility well
i've got bottles of mercy in my lab i
can smell it it doesn't smell skunky at
all right cannabis yeah some of them may
be a little musty but nothing that
smells like a skunk
but of course we knew
well the odor of a skunk it's a file
right and there's a lot of different
sulfur compounds that have that kind of
odor skunky beer
are our thighs
so we kind of keyed in on that and
looking for that and indeed we could see
in these cannabis emissions both looking
at individual plants and looking in
facilities
we could see a
3-methyl2-butane 1-thial
321-mbt
uh is the key compound the key skunky
smell uh in cannabis and we could do
that by again isolating the plant
looking at the emissions so we know it's
really really coming directly from the
plant
and of course we use uh you know
analytical techniques uh
td gc top ms to work this out we can
look at the mass spectra compare to nist
to authentic
samples
i also compared it to a corona beer that
i stuck out in the sun for for a while
and um and and we can figure out what
what these styles are
uh also working with our colleagues who
do olfactometry and so olfactometry is
is a technique where you're not using
expensive analytical detectors you use
the person's nose right so we have these
experts uh who will go through and and
actually have this thing
going from the gas chromatograph which
which separates the compounds and
individual compounds and it goes to a
person knows and they write down
it's grassy it's piney it's skunky
and so this is key right because
we can analytically determine what's in
the sample but you know we need
something connected to a nose and a
human brain to say hey this is uh this
odor that uh is can be a be a a nuisance
issue
so a key part of this approach it was
combining these two right combining our
advanced analytical techniques
and uh combining uh human sensory uh
odor panels
and so we worked with with our our uh
colleagues jacik kozil and and uh don
wright and combining this into an astm
standard so astm is an organization that
develops these standard approaches that
people can use because one of the
problems right now with odor nuisance is
that there aren't standards so
you know in most cases the way agencies
deal with this is
somebody complains about it right our
monitoring system is the neighbor's nose
that's kind of what we're relying on
right now well the problem with that is
different people are going to respond
differently it's difficult to tell they
might send someone out uh with a nose
ranger and and try to breathe but it's
it's a problem right whereas in other
parts of air quality we we have uh
standards based on this much ozone is a
problem right we don't have that for for
odor until we develop standards where we
can actually uh quantitatively say you
know this is a problem here
there's an additional complication
though in in that um
the ratios of these odors are are
important
and uh so so one potential possibility
because these files are really difficult
to measure and they're at really low
concentrations
so one one possibility you might think
of is well let's just measure the
terpenes because cannabis is emitting
terpenes it's emitting files let's go
measure terpenes if we measure terpenes
well then probably there's a cannabis
odor but it doesn't work that way it's
the ratios and in fact
the terpenes can actually mask the
cannabis odor so sometimes right near
the source you can't detect that skunky
odor and it's when it goes downwind to
the uh
the elementary school a couple blocks
away right then
the odor can actually be greater than it
is right at the fence line
so it's it's somewhat complicated there
but using these include so
so how can we solve this issue um and
using these enclosure measurements we
can determine for different cannabis
strains what those ratios are and again
we're not just getting the amount of
file but the ratio of the file to the
terpenes because those those ratios are
are really important
uh it's it's a challenge these styles
are
at really low concentrations but we we
have analytical techniques that that can
do that
we use again going back to those models
that we develop for global climate
models and regional air quality models
we use a similar kind of approach so we
take this uh we're calling it the canopy
emission profiler basically we can get
for a facility for a greenhouse or a
field we can determine exactly
quantitatively what the mass emission of
files and and terpenes are
uh with using these these uh enclosure
measurements
and of course we can look at differences
in you know juvenile the flowering
obviously are different we need to
consider these different conditions
and the solution is well we have
techniques that that can remove
these compounds now one approach might
be well we have these techniques let's
just throw a bunch of it out there and
and remove everything we can
well well it costs money obviously to
put these out there it takes a lot of
energy to run these these carbon
scrubbers
they have to uh either regenerate or
dispose of the carbon so um it's really
important to well to one know the type
of carbon right so that you're
specifically targeting those files and
terpenes
but then right sizing it and so i've
been working on on getting well exactly
how much is going out there so we can
get the right amount of removal
technology but not too much
right so we don't have the cost we don't
have the uh inner
excess energy and sustainability issues
and again for example so we can just
quantitatively determine for the size of
a facility for the emission because we
know the individual plants what they're
emitting we can determine how many of
these molecular filtration systems you
need
and so so buyers has been working on on
developing improved systems right
and proved in terms of the efficiency
right so the power is lower uh uh
improving uh the
uh
the effectiveness of the carbon that
that's that's used in there and also the
ability to to reuse this carbon right
now typically it's just thrown away into
landfills so we can be able to uh
not do that anymore
and then of course third party testing
is is important to validate that we
really can remove these files we can
remove these terpenes
these these systems are are remarkably
effective
we can also also go beyond that to other
issues that are important for
cultivation uh getting rid of uh
pathogens
other kinds of things that might be
important for indoor air quality for
people so aspara is something that's
recently been
added to this system for removing
particles
biological particles and and other
and again using third-party uh testing
uh these are are remarkably effective so
we have solutions
uh for for getting rid of these odors
getting rid of these these particles and
our focus is on doing this effectively
and including the use of smart systems
that would say hey it's time to replace
the carbon in this system um
and and getting real-time data if
there's some kind of a leak or an issue
going on
then you can immediately you know that's
going to your phone and saying hey we've
got a problem in in the facility right
now
so that's
what i have and i'd be happy to uh take
any questions
[Applause]
all right good morning thank you uh i
have an outdoor cannabis farm in sonoma
county and i'm surrounded by vineyards
and we are constantly having the
conversation about our terpenes tainting
their grapes and the smell of skunky
smell knowing that that's thyles and
it's organic sulfur vinegar juice sulfur
to prevent powdery mildew is there an
argument to be made that our styles are
actually benefiting their grapes
they could be um yeah
yeah it's been really interesting to me
in kind of getting into this this field
and seeing how the vendors can dump all
kinds of stuff on the vineyards right
and they can't cast people can't but but
it's really yeah this terpene drift
issue is really interesting and and i
know they've been focusing a lot on
eucalyptol
as as one and
we've done some studies it's a really
minor component um i think it's can be
really rare you know and
in australia if you have a lot of
eucalyptus trees going around
it could be an issue but i think it's
unlikely with cannabis but again with
this kind of approach well then we can
tell right we can go see exactly what
are the terpenes and then we can model
exactly what's getting deposited on the
grapes and calculate that and and figure
out and
you know i think in most cases you can
clearly show that's that's not a problem
thank you
okay
thanks wonderful talk
i had a question it's slightly off topic
but i your expertise sounds like you may
be able to answer this pretty well yeah
this talk was kind of off top
conference too maybe but
a number of indoor cannabis grows in in
california are moving more and more
towards oxidizing agents as a way to a
odor control and be
be effective as a pesticide an
alternative to chemical pesticides
i was wondering in indoor facilities
where they're fairly clean
the use of oxidizers like a
number of different oxidizers i could
talk about clo2 gas is one that's
starting to be used more
are we putting workers potentially in
danger or are we basically creating
clean breakdown products when those
oxidizers are mixing with these uh
volatiles from the plants
yeah it's really good questioning so in
general when you use oxidizers oxidizers
to break down these things and just
because there's so much terpene load in
there and stuff like that including even
if you've moved the plants out right a
lot of that stuff is condensed uh into a
film on on everything right and that's
part of what they're trying to clean up
you're going to generate all these
aldehydes
in there which can be really toxic
and so i think it's a real issue it's
it's something people really haven't
been looking at
very much what's what's getting created
but i think
you know we don't really know but
there's good reason to suspect that that
that can really be a problem
sorry as a follow-up question can you
recommend any good uh sensors that we
can put in place in these facilities to
monitor for for the aldehydes and other
things that might be yeah
fortunately what we have right now there
are really good
sensors and they're really expensive
and then there are really cheap sensors
and they're really not very good and
that's kind of the state of the art
right now uh you know we need something
more in between uh that can be done
but what um so it'd be really and these
are kind of online continuous sensors
which would be nice to have
but uh what can be done is is kind of
just grab sampling right so going out
collecting samples and analyzing them
and that's probably right now that's
that's the way to go
you know another interesting thing that
that brings up though is that not only
you know people do this for cleaning and
you might do that in between your
harvest but other other people are
suggesting you should use some kind of
oxidant for just cleaning the air right
during the normal procedures
and that's definitely going to be
generating a lot of these aldehydes and
things like that and it's just that
really you know people need to be
careful with doing that we had looked
into that uh buyers has looked into that
and was you know thinking about that as
a potential thing to use and decided no
there's there's just too many risks
about
these products yeah you get rid of that
original compound you get rid of the
files but you're going to generate all
these these small aldehydes and it's
just not going to be a good thing