[Music]
all right
a lot of it isn't so much what happens
during the growing of the plant but it's
in the post-harvest activities uh the
drying the curing and the trimming
um I wonder if you could speak a bit
about what you found around that sort of
activity yeah yeah so that that's a
that's another aspect that's super
important so let's leave the grower
aside you know you've you've picked up a
whole batch of
harvested flour and now you're deciding
how am I going to trim this do I want to
do you know the standard wet trim where
you push all the flowers through into uh
into a trimmer and then dry the
individual the buds or do you want to
hang dry where everything is left intact
and then you know the moisture is taken
out and then you can trim off your your
leaves we found a pretty uh big
difference between
um hang dry and and wet trim the wet
trim creates some damage obviously to
the to the leaves and releases chemicals
or or nutrients that a lot of moles that
might be present particularly
penicillium start to feed on it and grow
so even on during the drying process
you're seeing buildup of these moles in
a flower that's been trimmed wet on the
other hand when you dry this thing first
uh you're not allowing these these wound
sites or broken off leaves as a source
for mold that needs to get in the entire
flower structure is dried you've you've
eliminated 90 of your yeast and mold and
then when you start trimming it as a as
a dry trim we found the the eastern wall
levels were way lower
so that's one thing that definitely will
make a difference a lot of Growers are
using the handguard system they'll
probably find they don't have as many as
much issues with yeast and mold
we didn't look at anything beyond that
in other words you know the curing
process or the packaging and storing
process I think All Growers know that
when you store inappropriate humidity or
temperatures you're gonna get build up
of yeast and mold and they know that if
you cure them too long or under high
moisture you're going to get yeast in
mold so we didn't really look at that
aspect we kind of stopped right at the
point where the flowers had been trimmed
whether it's wet or dry and then
collected data from that
no that's interesting so do you have any
idea like in terms of percentage what
Growers are typically doing is it more
common for them to be doing wet trimming
versus dry they're shifting a lot
towards dry trim because it's less work
in a sense you know you can bring the
flowers into the dryer rooms hang them
and then and then deal with them later
the drying process itself is very
detrimental to yeast and mode which is
obviously a good thing you know when you
have dry herbs and dry products dried
figs and they tend to last a lot longer
because the moisture is taken out of
them similarly with dried flour the
problem is that you never get down to
zero I've never seen a dried flower get
down to zero more Eastern more there's
always a fraction that still hangs
around and that that population can
always build up later on if if the
storage conditions aren't right
but if you're coming in with a very high
Eastern mole load then nothing you do
after harvest it's going to bring all of
it down to zero so there's two two
components try to reduce the Eastern
mold while you're growing and then after
you harvest and bring it in try to do
things that will reduce the yeast and
mold even further in that in that
product that you're handling
[Music]
all right