[Music]
so so what's your approach to creating a
homozygous um strain sure so we are also
a tissue culture laboratory so something
unique that we do everything's in vitro
so everything grows in cryo it's never
watered it's never fed it's never
touched it's never looked at for up to a
year at a time and because of this uh
we've been able to really really
maintain a large Vault of different
genetics we have about 2,000 strains
that we've hunted um from about 20
countries now the USA being one um and
so we get these um into their vessels
where they go through either a
multiplication phase or a rooting phase
but more importantly
100% sterile so we're able to sterilize
these genetics uh implementing aicle
maristone tissue culture we can get them
back to their generation zero uh which
is going to return that actual tissue
that plant that genotype to its original
Vigor um so we take a sterile approach
and then when we go to create a new line
we can pull from that Vault we get that
out of tissue uh we start What's called
the acclamation phase getting it used to
being out of that 100% relative humidity
vessel and then getting it into our
inbreeding Chambers uh we then will take
that specific strain and we will inbreed
it and we get it to about an S4 when we
get to an S4 we then get it back into
vitro and we hold it in that S4 um stage
so that when we come across another line
that really really checks all the boxes
for us we then do the cross there um and
so we're creating stabiliz ized
Offspring um in seed form um and yeah I
mean that's kind of our approach but we
also take that plasticity approach um
something very very unique that we're
doing and I've done an also traditional
a is we are taking I'll give you an
instance an example of how we do this
plasticity breeding in 35 gallon tubs we
are propagating and growing um fungus
larae we Harvest this fungus larae with
wire mesh and then we practice what we
call targeted releases so we might go
into one breeding chamber and we'll
disperse this larve and from start to
finish we're able to find that specific
genotype that shows the most resistance
towards that specific plant pressure uh
in this case being a fungus knat uh you
know they start in that larvae stage but
then they evolve into that adult mobile
stage where they're landing on your
plants they're eating the foliage
they're causing damage to your canopy
and so we're able to take that genotype
isolate it and then bring that over to
the next generation and breed again and
again and again and we're constantly
hunting for that genotype that has the
most resistance towards that plant
pressure wow so you are purposely
introducing uh a pest in this case right
to try to identify the plants that have
the trait that you're looking for that's
right and we're we're a completely
sealed facility so U I hope so yeah UVC
filtered HEPA filtered so we don't
really have too many past pressures that
come into our facilities but we're able
to control what does come in and then
create such such a high density of that
specific plant pressure that's allowing
us to do these inbs and we do this with
spider mites aphids uh we buy spores a
PM uh and we do this with every Garden
pressure um that a gr is going to
experience so that they have the
greatest tailored Offspring when it
comes to growing and so you do it with
all those different pathogens for every
line no so we have a Target right so
every strain there's a Target we might
do a PM Target and then we're also you
know hunting for yields or we're hunting
for tpin or canabo so there's always a
different Target um you know you go and
try to Target everything in one strain
it it would take so much longer to
achieve that um and then in many cases
you're kind of fighting one with the
other
[Music]