appreciate the opportunity to to talk to
doctors UN patients are the people who
are going to bring us to freedom and
better health and I appreciate your
attendance here I'm going to talk to you
about how to legally recommend cannabis
to your patients which is certainly more
about protecting your license than
protecting your patients
marijuana has a cannabis as a quite a
range of safety and the licensing issues
are more political than about the
carrier your clients I'm going to talk
about the scope of my talk is going to
be about talking about medical cannabis
practice in two contexts and first in
terms of the federal regulation of the
Controlled Substances licenses that many
of you have and secondly in terms of
state physician and healthcare provider
licensing boards the state level so that
would be in Massachusetts the board of
registration and medicine and the board
of registration in nursing and just a
footnote on that nurse practitioners
have had certifying authority since 2014
as a matter of state law and as a matter
of the nursing board regulations but the
Department of Public Health which is
tasked with overseeing the medical
cannabis law in Massachusetts has failed
to accommodate that in their regulations
there are regulations pending to do that
and my latest information is that
perhaps in June they will become final
so that that nurse practitioners can be
included as well so let me talk about
the feds hopefully quickly we all know
that cannabis is a Schedule one
designation with no medical use so
therefore there's no prescription
Authority for that and this is in spite
of the fact that the Department of
Health and Human Services of the federal
government has had a patent since 2003
for medical cannabis is antioxidant
effect this is also in spite of several
lawsuits that have documented the
medical benefits of cannabis and that
the federal courts have allowed to have
refused to get involved in the
rescheduling process so state medical
marijuana laws have been the workaround
West Virginia is about to become the
29th state but the first state was
California in 1996 and but to get back
to enable doctors and patients to get
access to cannabis state medical
cannabis laws authorized physicians and
healthcare providers to certify or
recommend patient access and this is
bypassing the prescription prohibition
so a certifying doctor unlike a
prescribing doctor simply finds that
cannabis finds that the patient has
ineligible condition finds that cannabis
can relieve that condition determines
that the benefits outweigh the risks and
discloses to the patient the risk
benefit analysis and access to but this
is a matter of access and not dosing my
colleague Val Romano is going to talk a
little bit more about the Massachusetts
regulations but again getting back to
the federal context for your work I
would say that you have a belt and spend
a suspender protection from federal
interference with what you do the belt
is what I would call the Conant versus
Walters decision a 2000 trial court
decision that was affirmed in 2002 by an
appellate court enforce the US Supreme
Court denied certiorari so it remains
the law and under that decision there is
a permanent injunction against federal
law enforcement officers and the
Department of Justice and administrative
agencies and they are enjoying them hate
to read this from either revoking a
physician's license to prescribe control
some PSA's or conducting an
investigation of a physician solely for
a physician's professional
recommendation for the use of marijuana
that's a permanent injunction that
protects your licenses the suspenders
for federal protection from interference
with your practice is the 2006
right-to-die case the Gonzalez versus
Oregon decision of the US Supreme Court
that was the second Bush
administration's reaction to Oregon's
right-to-die law and again
manure for me to read from the decision
so you can understand the scope of the
protection that the Federalist you have
from federal interference
congrat this is from the Gonzalez
decision congressional regulations of
medical congressional regulation of
medical practice in so far as it bars
doctors from using their prescription
writing powers as a means to engage in
illicit drug dealing that is the extent
of federal regulation beyond that bar
however the Controlled Substances Act
manifests no intent to regulate the
practice of medicine generally the CSAs
for the Controlled Substances acts
prescription requirement does not
authorize the Attorney General to bar
physicians from dispensing controlled
substances for assisted suicide in the
face of a state medical regime that
permits such conduct
so there's your belt-and-suspenders no
matter what anybody else tells you as
long as you're practicing within the
confines of a state law state law
permitting that type of medical practice
that type of medical treatment you are
essentially immune from federal
interference so let me talk now about
state law in Massachusetts as I
mentioned you've got the board
registration of medicine and nursing
you've got for the from the state
Medical Licensing Board no specific
cannabis medicine practice guidances you
simply have the state medical marijuana
law and again val is going to speak to
you more on that and you have the
Department of Public Health regulations
implementing that law and and while
those regulation is pretty much parent
the state law there is a continuing
medical education requirement that's in
there as well and I will refer you to
the access to these online and to vowels
presentation at the state level with
regard to criminal protections doctors
are immune from criminal prosecution as
a matter of a state statute for
authorizing controlled substance use for
a legitimate medical purpose in the
course of professional practice
there's no criminal risk there you have
protection under Massachusetts tort law
negligence law that no health care
provider will be liable to a third party
for a patient's negligence or abuse of
the medicine if if the risks of
impairment are disclosed by the health
care provider and documented with
additional documentation of the
patient's competency to understand that
that warning so if the warnings
documented and the patient's competency
you know have to have the patient repeat
back to you what you they understand to
be the warnings then that's all
documented in the chart that's your
defense to a negligence action and
there's really very little malpractice
risk because these recommendations and
certifications are not dosing
instructions they're simply accessed
with the patient able to self titrate so
your tort risk is similarly minimal the
best way to protect your license is
documentation I suggest a written
examination assessment and patient
disclosure protocol something that notes
that that provides you a outline of a
check series of checkboxes to go through
as you do your examinations and your
assessments and this protocol can be
used to do the tasks that will protect
you and then document the results of
each one of those tasks in your record
the first part of safe cannabis practice
cannabis medicine practice is a full
patient medical record review and in
that this is a particularly focused on
the condition or symptom that's being to
be treated with the cannabis and
particularly important is a condition
diagnosis in the medical record by a
specialist for that for that symptom for
that symptom for that condition
particularly so if it's beyond your
specialty you can piggyback on another
specialist diagnosis but if a patient is
coming into you for the first time with
the condition that a specialist hasn't
identified and you aren't a specialist
in that condition don't certify we
for the patient to a specialist and then
you can piggyback on the specialists
diagnosis and in person the next the
next important part of the documentation
is an in-person clinical examination
especially regarding the condition of
symptom to be treated and you should
also be looking for the patient's
pre-certification use of marijuana as
providing evidence for you that there
may be some efficacy in cannabis for
that patient the next thing to do in the
chart is to do to perform a literature
review of the benefits and risks of
medical cannabis for the symptom to be
treated and for the patient's other
pre-existing conditions its simply
practicing safe medicine and filling
your file with material in case there's
a review the next part is doing this
certification the certification is an
assessment of risks and benefits so the
chart should include a discussion a
listing of those your analysis as to why
you believe that the benefits outweigh
the risks and a disclosure to the
patient of that risk benefit analysis
lastly there should be something in the
nature of a treatment plan as you would
with any other patient that comes with
you that would include some metrics for
assessing the value of the cannabis
treatment whether it be symptom relief
quality of life improvement or even harm
reduction one of the ways to assist you
on that and involve the patient in that
process is to recommend strongly to a
patient that the patient keep a diary of
benefits and side-effects that is part
of keeping your continuing relationship
with the patient and giving you the
ability to monitor how things are going
with the patient and that also should
include trying to schedule you can't
compel the patients to come back but in
terms of the ongoing role in the
patient's treatment which is part of the
requirement under Massachusetts law
scheduling a minimum a two-week
follow-up to see how the experience with
the cannabis medicine is going and so
you can report that feedback into the
chart as well as a follow-up appointment
three to six months out you can't compel
the page
to come in but you can put those
recommendations in there in your
paperwork and have that on hand in case
someone comes as one of the licensing
board comes to look at you the most
important way to protect yourself
besides this documentation is
essentially also not to have contact
with the medicine not to touch the
cannabis as a doctor when the patient
asks you about supply in Massachusetts
you can simply refer them to the
licensing to the DPH licensed
distribution network there are only ten
in Massachusetts so far there are many
more in the pipeline
lastly the the the the point about why
licensing boards are looking at people
it's simply a matter of politics and a
matter of the suppression of doctor
participation in medical cannabis
practice one of the chief culprits for
this is the mass Medical Society which
has been against cannabis medicine ever
since the campaign for it
so that there are only a few doctors who
are participating in it they're
providing I mean 20 percent of the
doctors are providing 80 percent of the
recommendations those people get
targeted for those of you who choose in
Massachusetts to join this brigade of
courageous doctors what I've told you is
hopefully gonna help you if they come
after you if you've got the
documentation you are immune I can tell
you that doctors at least one doctor who
has been challenged by the board has had
the board's recommendation for
suspension dismissed by an
administrative law judge the the crime
there was not anything to do with
patient complaints and everything to do
with the doctors use of nurse
practitioners and as I mentioned the
nurse practitioner regulation should has
been published it's already permitted
under the nursing regs
it'll be permitted under the DPH regs
hopefully around June sometime so that's
what I have for the content of my talk
but we're trying to keep our talks short
so that we can give plenty of time for
questions thank you very much
[Applause]
I think does your mic work over there
that might hello can everybody hear me
oh great
my name is Valerio Romano I'm an
attorney with a VG our law firm we
represent about 1/3 of the dispensary
applicants and registration holders or
registration holders throughout the
Commonwealth work closely with this
process I'm also an attorney in
California although I live here been
doing something to do with medical
marijuana for probably 20 years now and
it was it was great when Massachusetts
passed our law in 2012 I want to say
first of all that you know thank you for
participating in this if it wasn't for
courageous doctors in evaluation centers
really stepping up we wouldn't have a
medical marijuana program we wouldn't
have any incentive for dispensaries to
try to open up we wouldn't have enough
patient access to actually collect any
data we wouldn't be moving things
forward at all partners for instance is
actually doing a study of medical
marijuana patients over the next few
months collecting data that wouldn't
work there wouldn't be enough patients
right now you can look on the Department
of Public Health website and every month
they actually Pat put up a dashboard to
show you what the status of the medical
marijuana program in Massachusetts is
for that month as of March 31st there
were forty thousand four hundred and
eleven patients most of those
certifications were written by just a
handful of doctors even though there are
in fact a hundred and eighty-nine
doctors who have registered to certify
patients in the Commonwealth with about
six six more added in March it's very
few of them that are actually doing the
work and Mike Cutler touched on dr.
Nodame who you know got in a little hot
water for working with nurse
practitioners and fortunately has been
vindicated and in fact nurse
practitioners were authorized under the
law and the Reg
from their inception it was merely
because there wasn't a process for
allowing nurses to do this that it
became a problem and so the supervision
that was going on at Kanna care was
called into question although ultimately
turned out to be vindicated and they
were doing the right thing so the
sources of information for you to sort
of get to kind of the nuts and bolts and
I didn't invite anyone to chime in as
well the sources of information you have
the rags for the medical use of
marijuana program 105 CMR 725 you have
243 CMR one two and three that are
specifically enumerated in the regs you
have Co net V Walters which Mike spoke
about which really created a First
Amendment privilege for you to discuss
treatment options with your patient it's
the beauty of that case you have the
Controlled Substances Act what title 21
in the United States Code you have the
Act for the humanitarian medical use of
marijuana that's essentially the law
that the voters passed in 2012 63
percent of people in the Commonwealth
agreed on something which is pretty cool
rarely happens and then you have
extensive board of registration policies
and then the DPH guidance for physicians
and they actually lay it out pretty well
they lay out there's there's some
documents on the DPH website where they
lay out what you can do what you can't
do and they actually lay out the process
for becoming a certifying physician
essentially certifying physician must be
a mass licensed physician they have to
hold an active full license with no
prescribing restrictions they have to
have a Massachusetts controlled
substance registration they have it have
to have at least one established place
of practice in Massachusetts they have
to complete a minimum of two hours of
category one continual continuing
professional development credits that
zme has to explain the proper use of
marijuana including side effects dosage
and contraindications including with
psych including with psycho psychotropic
drugs so and they have to register with
the medical use of marijuana program via
their website so that's what you have to
do you also have to have this bona fide
doctor-patient relationship and the mass
Medical Society chimed in a lot and so
the voters passed a five-page law in
2012 in 2013 the department of public
I went around the Commonwealth and had
listening sessions for how we're gonna
implement this five-page law and a lot
of people chimed in and there was a lot
of insightful information that was put
forward and one of the groups that
chimed in was the mass Medical Society
who I'm sure you all know better than I
do 25,000 doctors and med students and
they really wanted to make sure that
people had this what a bona fide
doctor-patient relationship would be so
unlike California where you can get a
certification or a recommendation over
Skype
I got doctors never even reviewed your
medical history he doesn't know you at
all doesn't have an ongoing role you
just give him there a couple hundred
bucks and you're getting you're getting
your privilege to use cannabis here the
the mass Medical Society wants you to
have conducted the clinical visit like
Mike said completed and documented the
full assessment of the patient's medical
history explained the benefits and harms
and has a role in the ongoing care and
treatment so they're really trying to
make it so you have to have that role
that that relationship with the doctor
and then they're supposed to use the
prescription monitoring program or or
mass Pat now before issuing that written
certification and so you know it sounds
like a lot of overhead and a lot of
doctors aren't engaging in it so it's
because of these evaluation centers like
I said early on and I'm thankful that
they're actually allowing patients who
otherwise their primary care doctor you
know I I'm sort of a cynic and I get
sort of you know enthusiastic about
these things but cannabis although we
call cannabis big business right now
it's not cannabis business does not have
you know a pretty 30 something year old
pharmaceutical rep coming into your
office offering free samples and to take
you out to lunch we probably should but
we don't and and so you know so that's
why you know cannabis is not actually
probably accepted as well as it could be
another reason is Rach V Gonzales which
is a case out of the the Ninth Circuit
or actually the United States Supreme
Court ultimately which held that the
purely intrastate production and use of
cannabis actually violates interstate
commerce right so why is why does
Congress have the authority to regulate
cannabis use if it's a purely intrastate
activity because of this print
and your doctors not lawyers but this is
Wickard principle which was started
somebody was growing wheat at home and
they said it's illegal for you to grow
wheat at home because ultimately you're
hurting the Interstate Commerce for
wheat so if I'm a medical marijuana
patient and big pharma has completely
failed me
and I'm growing cannabis at home I got a
few plants and it's helping me what
interstate commerce am I actually
harming well so it's it's again why we
need pharmaceutical reps so that we can
see the Interstate Commerce that we're
harming is the prescription of other
pills and other drugs and in fact there
was a great study there's a great study
last year and it's actually been
replicated and further analyzed but what
it said in medical marijuana states 1826
fewer pain pills prescribed per year per
doctor 1826 per doctor I know it's it's
awesome 562 fewer doses of anxiety pills
541 fewer doses of nausea nausea
medications it goes on and on and on and
so when we look at you know we're in
we're in Massachusetts we know we have
this horrible problem with opiates when
we look at what's going on in Mass if
the patient is never going down the road
of Vikes and perks and oxys and becoming
a heroin addict and then having their
insurance run out and I know I'm stating
the obvious to you but it's something
that needs is worth being repeated if
you never go down that road then that's
why we have 1800 fewer pain pills
prescribed in medical marijuana
jurisdictions that's why the Journal of
the American Medical Association came
out a few years ago and said 24.8% less
opiate mortalities in marijuana
jurisdictions a full 25 out of a hundred
fewer people dying in marijuana
jurisdictions and so the data is
overwhelming and don't let anybody tell
you otherwise because to find real
impartial data like peer-reviewed
studies out of major universities
the opponents don't have that kind of
data they have purely objective I'm not
not objective you know data with with a
particular focus so the data is there so
keep going what what else you need to
know as far as under the law and that's
sort of my soapboxing and I apologize
and uh so a qualifying patient has to be
a mass resident they have to be 18 years
or older or if they're under 18 you have
to have two physicians review see them
and say they have a life limiting
illness okay I'll finish up and I'll
pass it on and we can move to move to
questions so quickly evaluation centers
I just want to emphasize again the
important role that they're playing but
also the reason why there's only a few
doctors certifying most of the patients
we would love to have all of you get on
board this important treatment option
let's get together let's collect data so
that we don't have that argument against
cannabis anymore and let's figure out a
way that we can really make it clear to
the public as a whole even the ones who
are listening to the pretty
pharmaceutical rep that this is a good
thing for the populace so thanks for
listening
so we only a few minutes of Bonnie's
gonna give us some experience from from
California as well and her experiences
working with patients so I just a few
do's and don'ts and also some case cases
where doctors in California have been in
trouble and they are pretty egregious
and I don't think anybody here is gonna
do this but remember in California it
was the Wild West for quite some time
and a person could just walk in off the
street saying my back hurt you collected
their money and you gave them a letter
most of the doctors who are still
standing that are doing that that are
doing that kind of practice are going to
be out of business because it's it's
going to be legally available as of
January 1st and then the rest of us who
actually practice medicine just using
cannabis and our toolbox are going to be
the ones who still see patients I treat
every patient and go through the process
the same way history physical review of
medical records and I do highly
recommend that if you don't know the
person and they are coming to you
specifically for cannabis because you're
open to that and you're gonna help a lot
of people if you're open to that ask
them to fax or scan their medical
records ahead of time it makes it a lot
easier if you know what they have before
they come and then document the heck out
of your chart
i document medications that the patient
has tried that have not worked
i document surgical procedures i
document how many physicians they've
seen sometimes what major academic
centers they've gone to for for care for
for help that is documentation that will
help you if something happens be able to
back up your decision-making on every
chart I write patient if I decide that
they qualify patient qualifies for
medical cannabis based on California law
I usually write the benefits i assessing
it the benefit benefits outweigh the
risk and I also write that I've
discussed side-effects in my paperwork
that I give to a patient a new intake
form is seven pages it's two pages of
medical information medications a
but then it's five pages of informed
consent and an arbitration agreement and
so in I've been doing this for almost a
decade I have not been in trouble with
the Medical Board and I've not gotten
sued I know dr. Hogan rather is here in
the audience I see him he's been doing a
lot longer than I have and I know he
does it the right way too and it's not
gotten in trouble and really
documentation is your key I at one point
was a medical director of overseeing 15
different medical cannibis offices about
like six or seven years ago and we had
some doctors who did have problems but
documentation was what saved them and so
that is the key and where did those
problems come from so in one case it was
a parent calling saying my son does not
have what you said he has I found his
letter and so you may get a call from a
family member we obviously were not
gonna break HIPPA we don't know who that
person is on the phone so we say we
can't help you we can't disclose
anything but at one point there was a
complaint to the Medical Board and that
doctor did have the chart subpoenaed but
because that doctors medical records
were sound and the patient did bring in
medical records his his mother didn't
know the whole story and did not know
other medications he was on so that was
that was easy and it was dismissed a
couple cases that were just egregious
and ridiculous is we had a famous case I
don't know the doctor who a patient came
in and he said can you just give me a
blank caregiver letter and the guy it
was an undercover person from the
Medical Board and they got a blank
caregiver letter where they could just
put in somebody's name and they made
this ridiculous assumption they said
we're gonna write the dog's name in
there or something it was just
ridiculous and and the doctor got dinged
for that then he was on probation for
that so that was one case and then very
recently I was asked to write a letter
for a doctor which I declined to do
because it was a local physician near me
who saw who is an internal medicine
specialist who saw a five-year-old who
had no diagnosis but the family was
saying we're not we don't want a
diagnosis of a DD on the chart but the
school saying he has a DD
can you just give us a letter and he did
and it ended up that the school asked
well what medicine is he on and they
said he's on cookies and then it went to
Child Protective Services and became a
big deal the parents are thrilled with
the treatment it's just that the doctor
was not qualified to diagnose a
five-year-old with a DD so going back to
what Mike said here if you're not
qualified to make the diagnosis don't
make sure they see a specialist
make sure they have paperwork and again
in my practice anybody under 25 they
don't even get an appointment with me
unless they send in medical records
ahead of time and if that takes them
four months then so be it then that's
that's on them there's only so much you
can do okay unfortunately I think we're
going to take questions after this just
due to the incoming next panel that's up
so we're a little short on the time here
this is just a lunch collision
unfortunately but I do want to thank
everybody that's all the advice you guys
have given I think it's incredibly
important that we get this correct
having the the legal understanding of
the realms of what we can do is is
paramount to making patients have safer
access thank you
you