[Music]
how do you think Gene editing will shape
the future of the Cannabis
industry
um I I think I think and I'm GNA
probably use these both hand inand
whether it's Gene editing or whether
it's genetically modifying something um
again I think we can get to end end
points quicker um I think we can start
thinking out of the box as far as what
we might be able to do with the cannabis
plant like I said you know for 80 years
we haven't done any research really or
not not much research I shouldn't say
any
because breeding breeding cannabis for
THC was remarkable right we've got
plants that are 30 plus THC plants and
that's all through through breeding and
and trial andur and stuff um but
thinking about
what the plant may not may not do on its
own very well I'm thinking about some of
the rare canabo that a lot of the you
know I saw last year at canm people were
interested in
CBG
CBC some of the thcv or CBD vs you know
things that the plant doesn't make very
much of we might be able to breed that
might be able to you know through many
years and many iterations of breeding
get to that point but I think with all
the information we have um with the Pang
genome out there now we can really
narrow down on how to make a plant
that's got you know uh 15 to 20% CBC
which you know we don't have something
like that now I think uh uh
pharmaceutical companies would be really
interested to see you know what that
could do um make a plant that's disease
resistance has disease resistance PM is
is is out there hopl and vroid is out
there you know are there there ways we
can quickly try to uh change the plant
so that it's so it's doing something it
wouldn't normally do uh on its own um
and then not to speak of all the other
all the other things I think um that are
outside the medical world right uh right
the industrial hemp I think is gaining
huge Steam and I it's it's all a matter
of time before we're growing hemp just
like we're growing uh corn and soybeans
I think excellent yeah and so you
mentioned the service that you offer
there at the University of Wisconsin
where you will'll actually do sort of
Gene editing um for companies or
researchers or things like that so I
mean if you can divulge what sort of
traits are they interested in in uh
creating yeah um so so we do we do work
for other people but we also have some
internal work going on as well and
that's what I'll I'll be presenting at
at canmed this year um but I hear a lot
of people uh like what I just said are
interested in a lot of the rares um or
something that you know the the plant
just doesn't produce very much of um
I've heard can flavens talked about
quite a bit you know can flaven a and b
plant makes just a just a little bit of
it but they've been implicated at a lot
of different you know potentially cancer
cancer research um all kinds of stuff um
and a lot of their rares as well you
know inflammation I hear a lot of that
for CBC CBG
um and then uh other interests might be
uh nutrition uh you know seeds hemp
seeds can can we uh make them even more
nutritious than they are can we add
certain amino acids that may not be
there for chickens for instance um and
then you know Industrial Hemp again uh
can can we can we make uh you know the
hemp plant uh sequester heavy Metals
more than it does because we know it
does somewhat can we make it even better
um capturing carbon H has a wonderful
you know it's a it's a wonderful
sustainable plant and it's got a huge
root mass um and I think it's be a great
Target for capturing carbon wow
[Music]
a