[Music]
kind of how attitudes from the major
sports organizations have changed when
it comes to cannabis and do you have any
thoughts of kind of what was the Tipping
Point yeah I do have I got a lot of
thoughts on a lot of things but um yeah
so that you know by them saying that
there we don't have enough evidence to
change our policies that is true and
they stuck with that the NFL did and it
was actually the players that were
pressuring them saying okay fine like
you keep saying you don't have the data
get the data then like figure out how to
get the data because you can't just keep
saying you don't have the data you know
that's kind of sometimes people will say
that as it's like an excuse to just keep
bad policies in place it's the same as
people saying there's no research
there's tons of research we have tons of
research that is already in the
published literature if you just look
like that it's the it's excuses or these
talking points right to just kind of
leave things status quo because it is a
very disruptive space because it's very
misunderstood because we have that
commercial industry too right a
recreational industry um but the NFL it
was the players that kind of pressured
them and again why are we so many years
later and we don't have the data and
that is true and I think one of the most
complicated things with cannabis and
getting that data is the funding because
really clinical trials are expensive and
so the people that are going to fund
clinical trials would be the people that
ultimately somehow would have some
benefit from seeing the results right
one way or the other now the NFL truly
does want the data what they do with it
is up to them we're just you know we are
just here to get the data um and it'll
be really interesting to see what they
do with the data because you know you
still have other people that are well we
need more data we need more data so so
it's hard to say but I think that
ultimately right now because of the
shift in the laws our countries the
society is Shifting and so the policies
that they have in Pro Sports and even I
mean the NCAA just removed cannabis from
their prohibited list because those
policies no longer align with Society
like Society is changing their laws and
so in order to have fluidity amongst the
game and the place of the game in
society the dysfunction it it was
starting to become too much and so I
think that was one of the reasons why
they were you know they got interested
in okay well let's see maybe we can put
up some funding and find people to get
the data then because you
know it's the amount of money you know
and yeah and there's a lot of drug
design for sure being done with
cannaboid molecules because the
scaffolding of how they work will it
will I mean we have data already to show
in animal models that there there is a
ton of effect there in neuroinflammation
neurod degeneration you know we know
that they are active there those
molecules are active there we know that
we now drug design has some complicated
things like you know bioavailability you
have to have reproducible dose you have
to have reprod you know and then the
canono system itself is very complicated
and so that's a whole different thing
but when you look at funding the
clinical trial it's who would put money
into that because with a product that's
available to everybody right now with no
prescription needed and it will continue
to be like that industry is not going
away so whose benefit is it to put the
money up to do the research and even in
the commercial industry they don't
actually need any data whatsoever to
shelf a product they don't need to show
pharmacokinetic data they don't need to
show bioavailability they don't need to
show anything they can package a product
and sell it as long as they're following
the Food and Drug compliance but it's
not an FDA approved thing so like
there's no incentive for them to fund it
because they actually don't need it they
can make an edible product and just put
it on the shelf and so It's tricky to
find anybody that it would even would be
interested in doing it so I think the
NFL like I applaud them really for doing
it because it shows that their minds are
at least Progressive and they're not you
know for a long time the conversation
about cannabis as a medicine just had
the breaks on like nobody wanted to talk
about it or try to understand it you
know and it's no different than any
pharmacological agent it it is bioactive
and it should be treated that way it's
just that in society we've chosen to
make it available to everybody and
that's a different conversation but it
is a plant and perhaps should never have
been prohibited in the first place right
right so why we are in this place right
now is a different conversation but it's
like how do we get out of it and so I
applaud the NFL for wanting to actually
see the data and putting up you know the
call for research because it is not an
easy space to get funding for sure yeah
[Music]
a