all right so today we're gonna walk
through utilizing the Koji browser this
is a genome browser where we have a lot
of ties into canopy dia so much of the
data that was in this bio archive
preprint we have over here is now up in
viewable in encoding so this this
consists of well the paper at 42 genomes
there's now 47 genomes that are up in
Koji and that number will keep planning
but these are whole genome shotguns done
with Illumina all mapped to a packed bio
generated pan trio reference a pan
genome is just multiple genomes that are
that build a reference together and we
have a a maternal reference a paternal
reference and an offspring reference all
assembled with Pacific Biosciences here
these is a long Reed sequencer that
generates reference grade genomes and
the N 50 s of these genomes are really
contiguous the most contiguous genomes
and been put public so and 50 is the
average size of the context in the
genome and the average for these are
over a million bases or usually around 3
million bases in length and that number
goes a little bit further north if you
get rid of some of the small contexts so
anyway the the important thing to know
about these genomes is they have the
highest busco score out there busco is a
tool that's utilized to measure the
completeness of genomes ok so that can
be seen right here here's the mother
father and the offspring this is the end
50 number the average size the contact
lengths and again this is including a
lot of small context a lot of people
like to screen out the things that are
under 50 KB and these numbers climb a
little bit but we've left them in there
for completeness you can see the genome
size is very the the paternal genomes
are bigger because they have a Y
chromosome this one's a female and the
bosco scores is the percent completeness
by looking for around 2,400 or so genes
that should be in all plant genomes and
so this is approaching the highest we've
seen I don't think we've ever seen this
number and assembly go higher than
ninety seven point eight that's not a
reference that we're working on right
now that's a little bit a little bit
different than these but
no nevertheless this is the set of
references we're using to map all of the
other 40 genomes against this okay now
in addition to mapping those 40 whole
genomes shotguns against this data set
we have done I so seek which is single
molecule sequencing unpacked by all of
the RNA transcripts across five tissues
this gives us an idea of where the genes
are you can see we've got about 27,000
maternal genes and 32,000 paternal genes
the exome size is anywhere between 40 to
50 mega bases the coding size is a
little smarter than that
so the the c.d.s size is different than
the exome size because the exome can
have the 5 Prime and the three prime
untranslated regions all right these are
utrs
okay so you we make an RNA molecule you
often include the promoter in the
Terminator in the RNA which aren't
necessarily read into proteins they're
just used to regulate it that's how the
exome includes the the CD s so the CD s
is always the subset of the exome and
then if you look at how much genetic
distance these things span across since
genes can have large introns that means
these are the gaps in between the the
expressed regions there were the exons
this this this really spreads across 120
to 160 mega bases in the plant so a lot
of data in there a21 I want to share a
couple other points of this data set to
you this here is a copy number map of
all of the other genomes that we
sequenced against the Jamaican lion
paternal reference okay so this paternal
reference has y chromosomes in there and
you can see there's zero coverage over
any of those contexts in all of these
lines and it turns out those ones all
happen to be the males these ones we
know are female and I'm sorry these ones
all happen to be the females and these
ones happen to be the males male female
and you can see there's coverage of
those regions in the males and there
isn't any of the females that's how we
identify the Y chromosome it's actually
a little bit bigger than this there's
some some
versions of the y-chromosome that are
known as the pseudo autosomal region
which is still recombining with y which
means it still has some highs are y and
x those the portions of wine x are still
recombining which means it still has
some homology to the X chromosome and
then down here you can see the females
have twice the amount of coverage on
these contexts and they have they're
normally covered in the mail so this is
the putative X chromosome material as
well so the X chromosome probably
entails some of these other areas as
well it's usually around over 100 mega
bases and when we add up everything
that's going on the Y the Y's the
largest chromosome as well so al are
just a little bit larger than X that
copy number of maps just helps you to
identify which ones are definitively
male and female this is a pedigree that
was sequenced okay so we did PacBio
sequencing on this one this one in this
one this one is a runt it's a parent at
this stage in its life but you'll see
some pictures for that it's actually a
runt and we chose that as the offspring
of sequence because we thought we might
learn something about yield in that
genome since it seems to lack it and
then all the other ones we put through
Illumina sequencing and mapped it back
to the maternal or paternal reference
which you're going to see all of these
BAM files in this koji database a couple
different aspects that you're welcome to
read in this paper these are the single
nucleotide polymorphisms and the
insertions and deletions under 50 bases
that are found across all of the 40
genomes we've got the type ones the type
twos and the type 3 plants up here the
jamaican lion family is in here you can
see there's less variation amongst it's
their own family that's because we're
mapping the family back to its to its
parent and of course there's less
variance that way but as you begin to
map hemp samples and other type 1
samples against against this these
genomes you start to see a much much
more diversion in diversity so ok so you
will see VCF files inside koji that I'm
going to show you that describe some of
this data this is a coverage correlation
analysis of the whole genome sequencing
data now this is just here a note the
scale here this is very very high
leaking
in coverage across the genomes but
there's a couple genomes in here that
are some of the most diverse genomes
we've ever seen this is the the 83 set
this is a unique set of plants minimus
owns and they may have some some hops
heritage to them as well there's been
some really interesting crossbreeding
they've been trying to do hops but most
the sequence we're seeing is
predominantly cannabis but you can see
is of course the most divergent cannabis
sequence we have here so here's a
picture of a de you can see its leaves
kind of look like basil not serrated and
it's it's powdery mildew resistant its
neighbors that are loaded with it never
seem to transfer it over to here we've
also seen some of that in Jamaican Lyon
family they are powdery mildew resistant
we probably have some pictures of that
we can share as well this is jail five
which turned into being a hyper branched
runt when it came out of the growth
chamber it was grown in the same
conditions as all its siblings which are
towering over it in this photo so
there's some interesting things that we
learned about what might be driving the
lack of growth in that plant now that
you can read about more in the paper so
what you're gonna see are a variety of
heat maps that look like this throughout
the paper and these are largely heat
maps looking at copy number changes of
DNA in the genome what we noticed in
cannabis is that it loves to insert and
delete copies of genes in fact this is
how it did a can of cannabinoid
gene expansion in the plan is it just
kept making more copies of these things
and that's why there's upwards to 90 of
these genes in the genome that have a
what looks like an F ad binding domain
and a berberine bridge which is two of
the characteristics of cannabinoids and
phases there's a p fam domain that
searches for these in the genome and
that number ranks up there around 90 now
not all of those nine your active some
of them are broken or truncated it don't
have the proper start and stop codons
and so we've we've then filtered those
for a smaller set of genes that you'll
see that we're going to touch on in some
of these slides but nevertheless you can
do very interesting studies when you
have sequenced whole genome sequencing
data with very few PCR cycles that's an
important aspect of doing the method
prep here but when you do that you can
then throw the data up against the
Jamaican line reference and ask which
part
the genome were missing which genes are
missing on which genes are amplified
that's what you're looking at this heat
map here is that the genes that are that
are in red have been amplified quite a
bit and the genes that are blue have
been deleted so you can see already just
in these set of samples here that there
is kind of a characteristic of certain
TL peas being deleted and certain chitin
aces and mlo regions being amplified and
also some tightness that have been
perhaps deleted or amplified so now what
we've been doing is tracking powdery
mildew resistance status across multiple
cultivars to see if any of these
patterns map with resistance status and
the reason we're looking at chitin aces
and vomiting like proteins and mlo is
these are all the genes and hops that
have been hunted down over the years to
be involved in powder and mildew
resistance so we already have a few
candidates in here genes that we believe
are involved in the powdery mildew
resistance in Jamaican Lyon and we've
cloned those and expressed them and
demonstrate they actually destroy fungi
now that being said we think we have
found a reason for powdered mildew
resistance in Jamaican Lyon we believe
there's gonna be convergent evolution
when there's this many chitin aces and
this many tlps other plants are gonna
probably find a collection of these
things to amplify that give them
resistance as well but may not show the
same pattern that we see in the Jamaican
wine genetics ok so there's multiple
ways to probably scan the resistance cat
and while we think we found one of them
it probably may not be 100% reflective
of resistance in other lines okay so
here's a set that we pulled out that we
know that we believe are playing a role
so we've cloned a few of these in fact
this TLP 2563 has in fact been cloned
you'll see that work in this paper that
when it is cloned expressed in e.coli
and purified out of a coli and then
placed onto films that are growing
Penicillium and Fusarium we get this
type of inhibition in growth when these
chitin aces and TLPs are present
here's a few serie moxie sperm and it's
got less growth over here where we've
applied some of the compound than some
of the enzyme and we're put down here it
tends to change the the
a few sarin expression in Fusarium now
Fusarium is known that when you give it
mica sides it stops making these
pigments it's a sign of it going into
Apatow sis and cell death so there's
more to read about this in this paper
but if you really want to dig through
this data you want to get familiar with
koji which is the genome browser that
allows you to surf all this stuff now we
left off the last tutorial talking about
CBD and THC genetics this here is a heat
map looking at those three genes that we
scan in canopy dia the inactive CBD
synthase the active cvd synthase and the
active CBD synthase and you can see this
type of pattern here that is inversely
correlated and predicts the typing of
the plants the type 1 2 &amp; 3 status is
completely predictable by the presence
and absence of these genes you'll notice
this region isn't almost always
correlated of maybe not here there's a
little bit difference but the deletion
sometimes extends to be a little bit
shorter a little bit longer in this
region of the genome and we get a more
or less a very similar prediction with
the gene even right next door to THC
synthase ok now as I mentioned in the
last tutorial there's many other ways to
knock out THC synthase we have seen some
type 4 plants that have this gene in red
making you think that it's a type 1
plant but it actually has some point
mutations that knock out really key
amino acids and I want to show you how
you can take your VCF file from strains
each loaded into Koji and look for those
things because right now the tools we
have in the reports aren't digging that
deep yet the data is there in your in
your sequencing data but our software
tools haven't gotten smart enough to go
in there and identify the variants and
decide which ones really damaging and
which one is and to give you like a
23andme report on every single base
we're building that right now but in the
meantime we want to enable you to be
able to load this stuff into the Koji
genome browser and surf it yourself ok
so just to give you a sense the
complexity that's behind this these are
a very large set of cannabinoid synthase
genes 39 of them with 11 other genes
that our next-door neighbors to them
that
often times of disappear or appear with
them there in linkage okay so when these
jeans get deleted they sometimes delete
their neighbors too and that's important
to track because if you breed for
certain cannabinoids synthase genes to
be present or absence in your plants you
really kind of kind of keep track of the
neighbors it's dragon down with it okay
so this is a case here where these sets
of genes this is a gene on context
it looks at context 756 right there see
756 this is the cannabic roaming cluster
it's labeled as inactive THC synthase
because that's what NCBI first learned
of this as it was submitted as an
inactive THC synthase meaning it makes
very little or no THC synthase but it
might make some and that's something to
keep your eye on it's now been cloned
and it's known to be the cannabic Romijn
synthase cluster okay
so you'll see that many of the lines
have copies of this particularly some of
these ones where our are in fact hemp
lines so when you breed for hemp lines
you gotta make sure you if you're a hemp
line that still has eight of these
inactive ths and it's just they may
cause a problem they may leak on you and
and still be a slightly active right so
a lot of growers right now wanna breed
hemp lines that have this to megabase
deletion this there is a common deletion
in the population where this whole
cassette is knocked out it also happens
to knock out these other genes on contig
7:56 down here now our paper describes
these these other genes here are in fact
pathogen resistance genes okay they're
aquaporin receptors they are gibberellin
receptors there's you know they're
important features that go with them so
you want to be careful and look at your
plants to know if you are breeding for
one of these things you might want to
pick one that doesn't have as many of
those pathogen resistant genes knocked
out like this one here Tibor still has
many of those pathogens Susan's genes
but it doesn't have the inactive THC
synthase so the cannabic row means are
gone so this is a great line to perhaps
try and breed into a type 3 compliant a
hemp line it may not make a lot of resin
so it may need to be paired with
something that does alright you can also
see several type 1 plants often have the
cannabic Romijn cluster
and you would really never know if
they're making residual THC because you
already have a THC synthesis and they're
making plenty but you will see a lot of
plants that don't have the THC synthase
gene and do have a CVD synthase gene but
also have kinetic Romi that may be a
problem as we mentioned in the last
thing so anyway there's a lot of
cannabic an eye but chroming gene su are
a lot of cannabinoid synthase genes to
keep in mind as you're doing these
things and breeding because ultimately
these are going to be the source of pain
residual cannabinoid expression is not
just related to the major genes that are
producing these things many of these old
genes might be producing other
cannabinoids rare ones or small amounts
of THC and CBD synthase which could
wreak havoc in in a hemp compliance
program so okay so feel free to find
this paper at bio archive and let's go
to Koji so if you if you google koji co
GE comparative genomics you'll end up at
a site like this alright there is a
tutorial here but I'm going to try and
do that for you there's a lot of genomes
in here you see there's 50 1000 genomes
in this thing there happens to be a lot
of our cannabis genomes in here too
so if you search for cannabis genomes
you're gonna get a lot of them you want
to click on the one in here that's
certified so right down here there is a
Jamaican lion mother that's been
certified and there is a male that's
been certified the certification just
means that the koji team has combed over
the annotations and in the genome
structure and they believe it meets a
certain standard and they they certify
so these are the best
busco score and and fifty genomes out
there you will know we have not put them
into chromosomes yet while we are
playing with that or cautious on calling
the chromosomes because they're all very
similar sizes and as we just showed you
there are frequent to Megabass deletions
that may make you miss call chromosome 5
versus chromosome 6 because these things
are really close in size and when
there's a 2 Meg deletion there you can
quickly make chromosome 6 mistaken for
chromosome 5 I'm not saying they're on 5
or 6 and just as an example there are
a lot of these chromosomes are almost
identical in size and so the deletions
matter okay
you may see chromosome from us a little
bit later this year but for the most
part that level of resolution is a
little bit academic at the moment let's
open up one of these browsers okay so
this we're now into this genome it will
show you there's a couple different
annotations that we've thrown in here it
will also give you a handful of
experiments that are public and
available for you to surf if you want to
download this genome right there is a
download button there is a GFF download
in here as well we have had some people
report that downloading from GFS from
koji changes the format a little bit so
just be aware of that and there are two
different ways to download it there's
like through this tab and one other tab
that when you click on the actual
experiment itself I think when you
download that you get the exact file we
put in there if you download off of this
there might be some modification is that
Koji added so two different ways to
download those just be aware of it okay
so let's go browse this genome and this
is gonna bring up what's known as a
genome browser and what its gonna ask
you for are what coordinates do you want
to go to what part of the map are you
looking for okay so here we are this is
um it's a probably last thing we looked
at let's just go over to let's go to
kind of go to THC synthase that's what
everyone wants to see 741 I have to know
this is a four four one seven zero zero
okay
where are we oh there we go okay so this
shows you the ATC's and G's if you're
not familiar with this is an amino acid
translation in three different frames in
the top strand and three different
frames in the bottom strand you can read
three different frames of DNA when
you're trying to convert it into
proteins and these red marks are stop
codons
so usually genes don't have those and so
one way to know what frame your is just
look for the longest stretch that
doesn't have and you stop codons and
with T and sheets in space that's pretty
easy you can see there's some Athenian
right there you go further back to the
start of the gene zoom out a little bit
baby steps there you go so start the
gene stop at the gene if you click on
this you'll get a little messenger RNA
with a note of what the database thinks
this is we've done some annotation on
this and adjusted some of the start and
stop codons just to make sure that it's
it's in fact what is seen in the
literature you can download the sequence
of it by hitting that fast a button if
you want don't do something like this
there's the sequence in fact this is
what we use to clone some of those
powdery mildew resistance genes we just
clicked on the gene grab this from the
start codon set it off to Gen script to
get a cloned and sequenced and expressed
and now we have protein in a few weeks
okay so what are you looking at here
this is as I said the the coding
sequence c.d.s if you want to add more
features in here you can easily take
that C D s and it'll add it down here
you can remove that track if you want
put it back we'll end up down here and
then you can also see that we have all
of these other reads here this here is
female leaf RNA sequence okay this is
when we did I so seek sequencing all
these RNA molecules popped out from the
leaves that works
synthase that's to be expected this is a
type 2 plant
hello here is a whole genome shotgun of
grapes topper another genome that's been
aligned to this and you can kind of comb
through this and look for variants if
you want let's get that out here cuz it
takes up a lot of memory and work with
these
okay so here's th DS and thanks now
other things you might want to look at
well if you had your own sample you
could load that into the genome browser
a VCF file off a canapé dia and see
where all that all the snips are in your
genome then we're gonna do that in just
a moment let me just show you something
that functionality here okay so these
are all the public data possible we you
can hit the structural variation file
here we'll show you where the very
large-scale insertions and deletions are
on the genome and I don't think you're
gonna find any in Jamaican lion or over
TSU synthase but you may find some other
hits over here here's a here's a
deletion shows you its size and some of
its attributes now let's go into THC
synthase and let's ask her so what do we
have in the 40 genomes project in terms
of the VCF file VCF files are variant
call format sand they'll have some of
the snips let me see if that peppers
this with variants it does you see there
must be another one up here that does
that we have a forty genomes in public
oh oh there's some annotations in here
this may give you some the gene calls
okay it's kind of redundant oh there is
some work from a group I think 20 labs
that did some aspect profiling and you
can see how many of these genes have
they actually detected them aspect
peptide for and in fact THC synthase
pops out now in our experience 98.8% of
what been ours what has found and is
published we find in the RNA set in
Jamaican Lyon but we only found about
only about yeah he found about 12,000
peptides and you saw from her slides
over there that we we have like 27 to 32
thousand genes and so we're only about
40% of his proteins are or 40% of the
RNA that we have found is accounted for
the protein did it that's that's not
not unheard of some of the proteins may
not be heavily expressed and then the
sensitivity machine may and may not pick
him up otherwise so all right so we have
a variety of experiments here you can
throw on top of this we have the RNA
from the female flowers from the leaves
from the roots of course there's not a
lot of THC synthase expressed in the
roots
you can see down here let me just get
more room here so nothing from the roots
the seeded female flowers RNA went down
a little bit there not be surprised once
you start putting seeds out you can see
the expression goes down on THC synthase
not surprising and then there's male
flowers too and the male flowers aren't
making a whole lot of THC synthase all
right I think that's probably not
surprising to anyone in this field the
other thing we have in here are BAM
files this is these are binary after
mapping files okay of about 50 or so
strain seek samples that are public in
canopy dia so let's take a look at Queen
Jesus now Queen Jesus actually started
out that wants a type 2 3 plant santak
has a type 4 plant so those aren't gonna
have a lot of sequence over this this is
a THC synthase so let's have something
that's a type 1 so you can see what the
sequence looks like a type 1 may be
serious happiness would be a type 1 so
you can see there's some reads that are
covering this region and if we zoom in
on those reads you can see there's
sequence coverage now there is a region
of THC synthase that is a little bit
tricky to cover because it has homology
to a lot of other cannabinoids and face
genes and so it's hard to place reads in
some portions of it and sometimes the
coverage might be just be a little light
there let's see if we get another one
that's got a little bit more there you
go this region is all tile but there's
sometimes some lack of reads there in
the middle let's pull up or maybe
Liberty haze we'll have some depth there
yeah you can get a lot of these now if
you go to something like our Magnolia
I'm gonna bet you won't see any Ruiz
is a type 3 plant and it is deleted in
that region ok so this is the underlying
data that's behind the plots in canopy
dia now if we did something like put a
whole genome shotgun
this I think what you'll find these are
whole-genome shotguns right let's find a
whole genome shotgun that's a type one
and see what we see
reads tiled all the way across the
region why well whole genome shotgun
takes the whole genome and sequences it
so we don't have to try to fish
THC synthase out of the genome to get
coverage over it with a hybridization
capture system we just sequence
everything is well I'm more expensive
but it's a lot more thorough and it will
it will miss less snips as a result of
this particularly in genes that have lot
of homology okay so you can load up all
different types of samples here and look
for variants now let's talk about
looking at variants I think if you want
to look at variants we probably look at
a VCF file and alright so now that we're
looking at your VCF file I'm getting a
little more serious here and putting on
a professional look but in all
seriousness now well what we need to do
in Koji is to actually load up your VCF
file and you have to have a cyber
saccade a day in tukoji but it's really
simple fill out an email address you'll
get a koji account in the day and then
you can upload your own data to this
browser and overlay with all the data
that we have public so the way you do
that is you go over here to experiments
you click new you click new experiment
or load exp and this should bring up a
window that allows us to load up a file
so we're gonna hit the upload button
here and choose a file and you want to
pick your VCF file there's one right
there now these can be a little big
sometimes so we'll just let's just see
how well it soaks this up
we're in that range right now and once
this realizes this is the VCF file you
hit next fill out some meta information
now I already have a version of this
running that we can skip to all that
thing is thinking this is what you'll
ultimately receive when you're done
loading it after the files been loaded
up you'll have all this information and
it will it will collect some of the
metadata some of the metadata it asked
for you can see in the background here
ask for a name you could put a
description we didn't put much in
because it's just a test
a version the site that it was generated
to whether it's restricted we left it
it's private right here so you can load
your data in and you can view it against
all the data we have in our database
privately and you don't have to put your
put any of your findings public in this
regard okay so that's what that looks
like you'll see here this is an
important step I've bounced over to this
to this step here to make sure that's a
VCF file there's a lot of different
files you can upload but you want to
make sure you call it what this is and
when you go next it'll ask I haven't
really used these features yet this will
send you an email when it's done but it
only takes a few minutes for a VCF file
that's more important for BAM files I
can take an hour and there's notebook
features in here that I've not yet
explored and then when you hit next here
it's gonna start uploading I'm just
gonna actually cancel out of this
because we've already done that section
over here and then just hit OK so now
that we have that loaded up what we can
do is look for it
in a lot of the data that's up here and
I'm just gonna search for it I think
it's there we go right there so that's
the VCF file we load it up we're gonna
hit view data
we can even make it public just like
that real easy hit browse and it will
probably load up the genome with this
VCF file layered against it now it's a
variant call format that just means
every line is a list of a coordinate of
the genome with a particular base change
and some quality information about that
base change for instance is how many
reads are contributing to that base
change so when you're zoomed really far
out like this you start to get a density
plot of where all the polymorphisms are
now let's go again to our favorite gene
four four one seven now if you don't
recall four four one seven I have that
burned in my brain but you don't have to
have it burned into your brain you can
just go up here and say I like I like
take THC touch' hydro is search oh I
forgot to check all these and then hit
OK and it will come up with a list of
all the different THC like genes in the
content and I'm gonna bet that one's a
right no and that's not it that's it
right there that's the one that is the
active T issue synthase
I just kind of remember that by the
coordinate and let's see
let's get some of this play we want to
see what jeans are
feature c.d.s there we go the coding
sequence squish that back zoom this out
and what you're seeing here are
different variants c-to-t variant at
this coordinate near TSU synthase you
can see another one over here
and the blur here right now you zoom out
a lot in this you'll see many many more
snips
and each one of those is variant alright
so that's how you load your data into
Koji and there's a there's a ways to
load fast queues in here as well so it's
a it's a very helpful tool allows you to
search around the genome and look for
particular key genes by looking through
this feature function there's also some
other comparative genomic tools in here
that people should know about if you
were to actually go back there's
actually a tutorial on how use this so
I'm gonna point into the tutorial
because that's probably a better way to
do it but there are other comparative
genomic tools in here given this as the
comparative genomics genome browser if
you go up to I think tools up here
you'll see those likes in maps a very
good tool to do genome to genome
alignments in fact let's do one right
now takes in map and a line now it will
only do alignments of genomes that are
I'm going to use to map to that have
annotations on them and they're very few
of them have annotations right now my
instant map maybe it's in that 3d let me
see
oh that's crazy I don't want to do
three-dimensional genome
all righty sit map - we're on select
organisms so if you just go here and go
cannabis it's gonna bring you up a lot
of different versions of cannabis and
let's take what you're making lion as I
mean isn't one and then let's do the
same over here cannabis
and let me see no coatings let me see
they don't this one so CVT rx has
annotations purple kush just not of
annotations yet although they're in NCBI
this does not have annotations maybe
that one does now okay
so there let's put on CB DRX Jeremy it's
hidden map now this is gonna run a
program in the background and it will
get back to you the map now that
probably doesn't look very good to
anyone here so there are some features
in here that will make this compare them
and more meaningful way if you want this
at 24 or and for and I think the most
important feature you know you had total
chromosomes where 10 has that's a
now let's do some KNK s it's always fun
now let's give that a shot
now if you're if you've run an analysis
on here it will remember that and only
run the piece of your analysis that's
needed like this
Diana right now if it's been run before
and you happen to compare the same
genomes you know side by side it'll just
recall the old time that you ran that it
has a running memory of the analyses
that you front of the pass but if you
change any one of these numbers it's
going to have to rerun it
that would take a little time
close out of some of these now
and we may have to come back to that
later timing but this usually gives you
some dot plots comparing one genome to
another and you'll see some of these in
our manuscript actually so we don't have
to wait for this but there are actually
in one of our figures but you can see
Jamaican line lined up to to CBDR X it
just gives you an understanding of which
context in our genome are the
corresponding contexts and their genome
it actually gives you an excel file that
you can use to download if you ever want
to do you know comparative genomics
between two different genomes alright so
lots of good tools in there and we'll
leave it at that and probably put in a
another tutorial on some other
functionality on this as the eo3
thank you