[Music]
all right
so what made you interested in
investigating how cannabis can affect
longevity
well this actually started out with the
conversation with the FDA because you
know with uh with the legalization of
CBD or the removal from the controlled
substance act the FDA had a lot of
concerns with you know what happens if
you take CBD for an extended period of
time so 20 years 30 years is something
going to pop up down the road
that could be detrimental and um you
know it's obviously very difficult to do
this studies with humans and it's even
difficult to do them in rodents it's
very expensive it takes a
you know extended period of time maybe
three five years to look at at lifespan
depending on that specific species one
of the I would say best pre-clinical
whole organism models is the C elegans
model it's kind of like the canary and
the coal mine model
the EPA likes this for toxicity so for
example if there was potentially
contaminated water
if they don't know what they're testing
for it's difficult to determine you know
what the problem is and if it's really a
danger so they may use C elegans and if
they die early then you probably want to
stay away from the that particular water
it's also been used
um in the International Space Station by
NASA so you know what's the EXP what's
the the you know what happens when
you're at space for an extended period
of time we don't really know what that
means for humans but we can look at
other animal models so that was really
the the start of this work was hey is
this toxic and at what level would it be
toxic and how does that you know affect
um you know the life of these in this
particular model
interestingly enough what we found is it
wasn't really that toxic uh until you
went to Super physiological amounts and
still wasn't you know overtly toxic
um but then we started seeing this you
know increase in lifespan and health
span we also ran that model with canaba
Gerald a lesser-known cannabinoid and we
saw similar similar effects so both
appeared non-toxic and physiologically
relevant amounts and uh extended
lifespan and activity levels during that
life so
um you know rather as it would now again
this is a model but as it would apply to
humans it would be akin to you know a 80
year old acting more like a 60 year old
in terms of health span measures so not
only did they live longer they were more
active through that late stage of their
life
so the benefits of Health span and
lifespan it sounds like it was sort of
just a a happy coincidence like you were
originally looking at the toxicity but
then observed um this positive effect
sure we we wanted you know we obviously
wanted to to find out you know how safe
the compounds were were but obviously
when you when you find out that there's
a potentially larger more profound
benefit then that's uh then that's
something it's certainly important and
relevant
um for us within the cannabinoid
industry
[Music]