[Music]
now when did the dent Institute get
involved in cannabis and was that sort
of a logical fit for you guys illogical
it was not logical in any way shape or
form um only reason we got into it
because we take care of so many people
so when cannabis was was made legal in
New York State uh about six seven years
ago um we were getting phone calls 500 a
day I said no I have no idea about
cannabis i' you know I'm not a smoker
I'm not a user I'm not I don't even use
alcohol which makes me tremendously
boring so the the point is the next day
was another 500 phone calls the third
day another 500 phone calls now if you
run a business buiness you can imagine
how much money and energy that takes to
answer those phone calls so I had said
look let's get into cannabis let's make
a clinic let's start learning about it
so because we're you we're um our
business model is so private and not
institutional we're able to set up a
cannabis clinic and for the next six
seven years it took that amount of time
to understand the use of cannabis in
patients with neurological symptoms
including pain and we you know you're
self-taught I mean where are you going
to go medical school they don't teach it
there where so so the only good places
to learn is at these conferences and so
I was honored to be you know at these
conferences everywhere from Tel Aviv to
uh Malta Europe and the United States so
I've been part of this and I've been
learning as we go and now I feel I have
an expertise because how do Physicians
understand medicine they have to see
patients so right now in the clinic we
have over 13,000 patients on cannabis
for medical reasons so I don't deal with
recreational and I need to emphasize
that I'm purely on the medical side I'm
purely there to legitimize this whole
process excellent so was there a was
there a light bulb M or was there a
specific um piece of evidence that you
saw that you know kind of clicked in
your head that you know there's
something to this cannabis well as
you're seeing patients
as they come up to you and they throw
their arms around you and hug you that's
the changing moment that you found
something where patients said you
changed my life you got me off
opioids my quality of life has improved
and With Tears in their eyes they're
hugging you and saying thank you that's
the moment that every physician wants in
their life and I got that in cannabis
interesting enough uh you know I deal
with bad diseases I deal with uh you
know brain cancer answer it's one of my
specialties and it's it's you know you
never get that moment so yeah it changed
the way I practice uh I still do you
know brain tumor research and treatment
I do uh other things in neurology but
cannabis has been an eye-opening moment
where you can change the quality life of
individuals by understanding how
cannabis works on human
beings
[Music]
a