welcome back to the canmed coffee talk
lounge i am your host ben amarill host
of the canmed coffee talk podcast and i
am here with daddy mary teddy good to
see you thanks good to be here and nice
to be here in person no is this your
first conference back since the pandemic
no it's my third in the last three
months but it's for sure
the first day cannabis conference and
meeting all the friends here literally
it's
something that i missed and uh it's it's
amazing feeling face to face yeah and so
when you come to events like this you
know what are you trying to get out of
it is it just catching up with with
colleagues or
trying to see what the latest
innovations are what's what's the
biggest takeaway for you
i think it's all together first of all
it's a good opportunity to sit and
listen and learn
and
hear hear new
things
second is the
communication between you know
colleagues and then people
and we learned in the last two years
that it's
far from being the same
with zoom soaring
far away
here you like you finish the talk you
asking questions and then you getting
out you have another half an hour chat
about this and that and that small talks
and this is building their relationship
this is building
you know collaboration and it's
extremely important
absolutely um and you talked about the
presentations are there any in
particular at this year's canmed that
you're looking forward to
yeah there was there are a few that i'm
a big fan of them you know the regular
one but
also stacy gruber which i really a
big fan of her work and i think she's
going to present few new things
but they
don't understand me wrong mainly the you
know the the new science
there is a lot of fame
talks in these types of conference which
giving
big view about you know the
endocannabinoid system that this is
enough for me already yeah okay now
the details and and some of them i can
repeat the the talk by myself
but the new people the the people that
really showing new science and
unpublished downtime that is extremely
interesting for me yeah and you
mentioned stacy gruber um and there i
know that there are others here at kamed
that are presenting more clinical trials
which i know is sort of the gold
standard in terms of data when looking
at
medical cannabis
so yes
in the last
i would say
three years there is
a lot of
studying mature to be a real clinical
trial
and not the kind of clinical trials that
we were speaking
few years ago that is more observative
trials
we gave cannabis we see that this effect
and that effect these are real clinical
trials double-blind placebo we start
that
also the pharma or you know i would say
the physician will admire i think it's
extremely important it's
it's opened
the gate to
new
um
population new
types of patients that we willing to use
and try when we cross this barrier yeah
i think it's extremely important and
interesting absolutely
okay so your presentation is titled the
challenges in bridging the gap between
traditional and modern medicine in the
medicinal cannabis arena
it's a lot to unpack there but um first
could you describe the difference
between traditional and modern medicine
like what do you mean by that yeah so
that's exactly what i we just said about
the clinical trial you know there is a
difference between using a herb and
saying you know that the chinese believe
that it's good for that and that and
this is
traditional traditional is you know
drinking drinking drinking a baboon egg
and said it's good for stomach aches or
taking a henitia or other
ginseng and said this is good for that
and that
modern
it's
proven
facts okay like you're doing clinical
trials you know what is the molecules
you know what the mechanism of action
why it's doing that what are the side
effects what are the benefits and what
you're losing it's always
you know kind of of a balance
and and this is what we call modern okay
in in the last 100 years most of the i
will call it modern or pharma
was single molecules to single target
and plants are never a single molecule
single target it's more complicated
and think the pharma and the science
and physician
was afraid about this complexity of
molecules
what's happened in the last 20 years we
called it polypharmacology when more
than one compound showing an effect
combination
and what's happened in last 20 years is
computer
arrived in science
today to look on network of you know few
thousand
proteins molecules
people
are doing something it's something that
look to us
already kind of trivially right
networking of we use it for everything
also in medicine what looks very
complicated to look on three molecules
what they are doing
today it's not an excel file right three
molecules this is not a big
bioinformatic this
so this is a huge change to look on
complicated
action what we called in the cannabis
entourage effect
but what the meaning of that this is
polypharmacology few molecules are doing
a complicated effect
today with the ability the science
availability analytical ability in
computer
bioinformatics
it's not a border anymore we can cross
it easily
and this is what i think you know
bridging
the modern medicine with the traditional
one
right so it's using modern tools to
really be able to find the benefits or
the values
um that sort of the traditional
medicines were using where it was more
kind of herbal based right in less
single single compound exactly think
about the the the traditional physician
four thousand years ago or three
thousand years ago you come with
inflammation wouldn't give you a pill
with one compound right he will give you
a leaf
with a road with a root with a you know
another flower combine them together and
giving you would do what i call
polypharmacology will take actually a
few compounds from here three compounds
from here a few components from here it
didn't really take them but he combined
them together and give you something
complicated
maybe a lot of that's placebo but a lot
of that it's knowledge that accumulate
you know you combine this and this and
the patient die okay this is not good
until he found what is helping right
this is thousands of years that
accumulating data that in the last 100
years we put them aside okay this is too
complicated let's take the simplest one
but there are many diseases
neurodegenerative diseases like
alzheimer's als
cancer diseases other diseases that we
are
hitting our head to the wall for
many years doesn't matter how many
billions of dollars we're pouring on
that and we didn't find the compound the
single compounded doing that right and i
believe that the next generation of
of you know
medicines will come from complicate
and medicines cannabis is open the gate
for that in amazing way it's a
complicated plant with hundreds of
molecules that working in the synergism
or
with the you know
entourage effect with the you know
different
receptors hitting different receptors
and
and it's just open the window and the
gate to understand that plant medicinal
plants
are like that and today we have the
tools to
to deal with that yes so cannabis
brought money
and the concept
to build labs like my own at the
technion
and but other labs that have the ability
today to take a plant
to look
doing what we call metabolomics to look
on all the active compounds
to test them on different diseases to to
analyze the compounds to understand the
mechanism of action exactly what we did
with cannabis we can do with other
plants there is a lot to do still with
cannabis but i think
it's bigger than cannabis it's open and
window and gate
to bridge
the traditional medicine
the
yeah so
are you saying there could be some
opportunity to kind of look at you know
more
established medicinal plants that maybe
we have gotten some of those single
molecule compounds that have been
effective like let's go back and look at
are there other compounds in here that
we could have been missing or that could
have been
having some kind of synergistic effect
yes that's what i'm doing for my you
know
this is what i'm doing back home yeah so
my lab is not working just on cannabis
we are i have three phd students working
on algae and other plants
that we think are
important medicinal plants that were too
complicated and now we can break it down
and understand
why it's working and and so on so
cannabis is still very important you
know it's hitting the endocannabinoid
system that it's all over our body and
there is a lot to do and it's a very
unique special plant
but for sure there are
many other plants that we can benefit
from
the techniques and the knowledge that we
learn from cannabis to other plants
interesting now one of the
plants that's gotten a lot of attention
lately is
um psychoactive mushrooms silasippy or
other psilocybin-producing mushrooms are
you investigating that at all
yeah sure like part of my my lab and my
company is doing that it's the same idea
for me you know
first of all
seven years ago people said cannabis
states in cbd right yep
and it's the same thing as you said you
know psychedelic mushrooms or magic
mushrooms cellulosurbin mushrooms
what do you mean
sorbet mushrooms like to say thc
cannabis it's one molecules
so there are
in my lab only i have 135 different
types of cytosol mushrooms 11 different
families of
mushrooms
every one of them contain different
combination of active compound cell
sorbin it's one of them xylocytosol
cytosomia
but there is
we can recognize more than 70 molecules
from this family already
the combination is doing totally
different effects the heating specific
receptors like the cannabis is heating
the endocannabinoid system they are
heating the serotonin system you know
485 hd and all the family
and so on and so on so it's the same
idea
is cannabis
exactly we have a good idea that it's
very powerfully work on our body right
if you're taking two grams and you think
you're a dolphin it's probably powerful
right
and
and i understand where these
receptors are in our bodies so which
which
diseases it i can aim and and so and so
on so we're we are very strong on that
as well
excellent
all right well teddy thanks again for
taking the time to be with us here in
the coffee talk lounge looking forward
to your presentation later in the event
and thank you to our sponsor medicine
women health and the hemp coffee
exchange for sponsoring the camed coffee
talk lounge