[Music]
so yeah I I was curious how are people
using cannabis kind of to treat their
symptoms is it sort of like a a
preventative thing or like a a kind of
daily um usage just to kind of keep
symptoms at Bay or do they actually use
it um in an acute situation where like
you said having a panic attack or having
an episode ingesting cannabis to kind of
get back to Baseline that's a really
great question so first of all for the
the research study we just started
collecting patients in October so we're
we're still in the data collection um or
well I mean we don't even have any data
yet we're still in the patient
recruitment part of of that study um and
then once we get all the patients and we
sort of close off which I think we're
doing January first then we're going to
do um we have that like six months is
the survey so so there's that uh but in
my practice so I am um independent I
work as a consultant I'm a registered
nurse and I I coach people and work with
people alongside of their doctor
um as a bridge uh my my favorite thing
to say about nursing and cannabis is
well holistic and plant medicine overall
is is we are the bridge we're the bridge
between the provider and the dispensary
for the patient we're the bridge between
like uh traditional medicine and then
holistic and integrative medicine I'm
writing a book nurses are the bridge
coming soon hopefully by Puerto Rico uh
so as that nurse coach nurse educator in
in my practice with patients I have
many people that have um suffered from
like sexual
trauma domestic violence and
uh many of them are women and many of
them have like an overwhelming sense of
Doom every day W and that there really
aren't a good group of or a good
protocol for prescription medications
I'm I'm a plant medic a nurse but I'm
very much also for integrating
traditional Pharmaceuticals we just
don't have a lot of traditional
pharmaceutical that that work or that
you have to take so many or the side
effects are so much that that can
relieve the symptoms so I have people
getting back to your question that take
a a a low dose of just something
routinely which we have some pretty good
uh data and some of our our friends that
are very involved with uh canmed and
medicinal genomics would share that you
know one to one equal amounts of CBD and
THC have have been known in low doses to
be helpful for anxiety and so I do have
some people that that utilize those
types of routes of administration we're
getting more data more research recently
about another canono CBG being really
helpful also for
anxiety but to your point depending on
when their symptoms are worse generally
so if it's not that they just wake up
every day with that impending doom and
need something if it is more about being
in the world and being triggered like
potentially somebody that was in a
traumatic car accident uh might have
anxiety just every time they have to get
in the car and drive and
I'm not going to encourage people to
smoke a little bit before they get in
the car and drive we have to be
thoughtful right so in that case we
definitely would be considering a less
intoxicating um route uh less cannaboid
and and less intoxicating route we want
people to be safe on the road but if it
is that they're going to be uh home or
they're in an environment where they're
not the driver uh then potentially if
they are triggered having an inhalation
option available whether that is uh in
inhaling like a lot of times honestly I
tell people with um post-traumatic
stress disorder and like panic attacks
related to it to consider carrying a
vape pen like like it's an epip pen so
so have it on you you don't have again
in a legal state where you legally can
use it have it there just just knowing
you have it might help you you might not
even need to use it but it's easier and
more accessible than having to actually
light something and smoke it in
environments where with the state of our
country we would still not be be able to
do that
everywhere but I have had experience
with multiple uh patients where just
having it in their purse on their person
just knowing they have it has been
enough for their brain to release the
sympathetic nervous system get back to
um a more natural response um and and
feel feel better and or they can take a
puff or two and immediately have some
relief so I I think it can be used and
I'm interested to see this the survey uh
responses because I think it can be used
for like the in the moment but we would
be looking my my goal for for PE most
people is hopefully to prevent having to
even get to that having to prevent those
feelings because when our body is
releasing all that cortisol and going
through that that triggered response uh
it's it's unhealthy for us it doesn't
feel good I mean I've had panic attacks
it doesn't feel good so I I would prefer
it if we could just keep the edge off
that and utilize the tools of cannabis
medicine plant medicine and maybe
entheogenic medicine and some
psychedelics to to do the work do the
therapy retrain our brain to to learn a
new response
[Music]