foreign
[Music]
Coffee Talk podcast where we talk with
the leading Minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I am your host Ben amaralt I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the cam Med conference
a few important updates off the top to
tell you all about first the early bird
deadline for the can Med 23 Innovation
and investment Summit is this Friday
January 20th
don't miss this opportunity to save
hundreds on all of our ticket packages
which include access to executive level
Cuisine for all meals during the
conference our medical practicum and
immersive professional development
workshops oral and poster presentations
expanded exhibit hall and networking
events
but if you choose one of our lodging
packages you will also get access to the
world-class accommodations at the
Marriott Marco Island Beach Resort
including golf tennis bowling Beach spa
and so much more
if you have already received your
invitation use the link in the email
that you received to register for cam
med23 today and if you haven't gotten an
invitation yet head over to
canmedevents.com now to request one
while you're at canmedevents.com check
out our preliminary speaker list you
will see some familiar faces like Daddy
Mary Bonnie Goldstein and Ethan Russo
but you'll also see some new faces who
we got to know through our abstract
submission process like Soren Safi Akeem
Gardner and our guest today Lauren Sands
more on her in just a second We are
continuing to add names to the page
regularly so be sure to check in and be
sure to sign up for email alerts so you
receive notifications
lastly we have added details about the
laboratory and capital markets workshops
that will be taking place on the first
day of the summit May 15th
be sure to check out those details and
be sure to plan to join us at the
workshops
this episode's guest is Lauren Sands
Lauren is a senior laboratory technician
at safetiva labs in Westfield
Massachusetts
she works in both the biological and
chemical side of operations utilizing
PCR and chromatography to test cannabis
products
Laura received her Ms in plant science
with a focus in cannabis molecular
biology at the University of Connecticut
where she focused on how hormones affect
cannabinoid production
during our conversation we discuss the
process for how cannabis plants create
cannabinoids what role hormones play in
the cannabinoid synthase process
whether a hormone treatment could
increase cannabinoid levels the ethics
around treating plants with exogenous
hormones and how understanding hormones
can help guide breeders to create new
cannabis varieties
before we get to my conversation with
Lauren I'd like to thank this episode's
sponsor farmer Freeman
farmer Freeman is a plant genetic
testing laboratory serving home Growers
and Commercial cultivators
farmer Freeman offers plant sex testing
hop latent viroid testing and more to
customers around the world founded in
2015 in Washington DC farmer Freeman is
one of the oldest and most trusted
Laboratories in the Cannabis industry
use farmer Freeman's genetic testing
services to save time money and
resources in your grow learn more at
farmerfreeman.com
okay without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Lauren Sands
[Music]
good morning Lauren thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast
evening Ben thank you so much for having
me
of course yeah I'm actually really
excited to talk with you today because
you're going to be presenting some
pretty important findings at cambod23
this may that could help Growers
increase cannabinoid synthase in their
plants
but first I think to really understand
the work that you've done and what this
all means we should really lay some
groundwork for those who maybe aren't
familiar with how cannabis plants
produce cannabinoids so I was wondering
if to start could you give us a bit of a
Layman's explanation of how that process
works
absolutely so
and trichomes are small hairs on the
epidermis of the plant and so cannabis
plants make six different types of
trichomes but only three of these are
what we're really interested in these
three produce resin
and so these three are called capitate
stalked capitate sessile and bulbous
trichomes but we're we're really
interested in the capitate stock
trichomes those are like the mushroom
looking ones that really that's what
we're looking for in the plant that's
what's going to give us the most
cannabinoids the most rich resin
um for cultivators Growers anybody using
a cannabis plant
so as the female plant develops after
switching into the 12-12 agitated phase
more trichomes are produced and within
them the cannabinoids and terpenes are
produced alongside
so these trichomes are like factories
for cannabinoids and terpenes and during
flowering
here's where we get a little scientific
um there are two active enzymatic
Pathways working together at the base of
this head of the glandular trichome so
remember it looks like a mushroom and so
at the top we have the head of the
mushroom it looks like a little bold
so in the base of this trichome head
there's a rosette of cells and they
contain little organelles and so in
these rosette cells the organelles these
pathways are producing the precursors
that are needed for Downstream
cannabinoid production to in the end
make thca cbda and so in these small
organelles in the base of the trichome
head there's a precursor called
olivitalic acid and so this all of
italic acid is converted to cbga
cannabidrolic acid
and so cbda this is a cannabinoid in and
of itself but it's also a precursor for
many cannabinoids
and so
um you can use it as a medicinal benefit
but also you can the plant uses it to
produce thca and cbda
so this process of converting all of
italic acid to cbga is completed by an
enzyme so this enzyme is what I say for
my whole two years of my masters and
it's called prenal transferase and so
these are just little enzymes in the
trichomes but there's 10 of them in the
cannabis plant
and so there's really two that the
industry is focusing on it's just one in
four prenial transferase one and preno
transferase four
so this enzyme causes the reaction
between the olive atolic acid I
mentioned
and another substrate another Gene
called gpps and so this other gpps
um substrate is actually gears in two
directions so One Direction it actually
makes terpenes and then in the other
direction it's used in this reaction to
basically combine with olivitoic acid
and that produces cbga and so now we
have cbga in this rosette in the head of
the trichome
so after it's produced after this penal
transfers enzyme finishes its reaction
um it's basically transported into the
top of the head of the trichome now so
there's a base and then there's the top
and so now it's exported and cbga is the
precursor to our endpoint cannabinoids
and so with the help of certain enzymes
which you've probably heard about such
as thca synthase cbda synthase these
enzymes are taking cvga and converting
them to what we want thca cbda and
likewise with other cannabinoids such as
CBC CBN
and then there's other
genes and enzymes working there
so um
these enzymes produce the final acidic
forms of cannabinoids which are ready to
be used by individuals or used by
and so to tie it all back to like why is
the cannabis plant making cannabinoids
we understand all the how but these
cannabinoids are known to actually be
toxic to the cell and in the in the
trichome head so a byproduct of making
these cannabinoids is hydrogen peroxide
and so they don't want it in the base of
the cell it's going to kill the cell so
they want to export it to the to the
extracellular reservoir to get it away
from the plant
and so um the all the resin containing
the cannabinoids and terpenes are in the
top of the trichome head and so whenever
they break open
um one you smell all the terpenes you
smell the plant but also it's a sticky
resin that
um can be used to trap insects and also
the terpenes have antifung
Ally it's like a little
oh so if it it opens it can trap insects
it can protect the plant it can collect
the pollen
um and also
um
yeah honestly that's the why and how of
cannabinoid production in the plant the
intricate Pathways lead to a defense
against herbivory as well as a treat for
us humans
wow no that's that's awesome that was a
great explanation thank you so a lot
going on there's a lot going on here
um so I jotted down a few notes when you
were talking here and so do I understand
this correct where it's the same gene
that creates cbga also creates trichomes
um it doesn't actually create dry cones
so the trichomes just grow oh
you're fine
um so there's the enzyme that actually
produces cpga doesn't produce
um
terpenes but the the enzyme is using a
substrate that it's taking a substrate
from this gpps but then the gpps enzyme
is the beginning of the terpene
production it's basically
it's basically what cbga is to thca to
PPS is to terpene so it's just precursor
so but like it's really cool you're
seeing the two Pathways combine and then
kind of Go off into terpenes or
cannabinoids right and it's this whole
process of you know this this whole
pathway of creating cannabinoids that's
really kind of the basis of your work
here and kind of the
um
the foundation again for your findings
so all right let's stop beating around
the bush now that we've laid some
groundwork so tell us a bit about you
know what's the what's the main takeaway
um of your research here and why we
should be excited about it
so there's so many different aspects to
my research
um there's a lot of aspects before I
entered the lab the actual actually the
lab is the birkwood side at UConn I want
to uh give a call out to them so we did
all this research together
um we started a while ago basically
figuring out which genes produce which
cannabinoids which ones we should be
looking at
um
we'd have to go through all my research
to get to the end of why it's really
important but really I'm helping
scientists understand why the plant is
making cannabinoids as we'll get into a
bit later which hormones in the plant
are right decide like basically telling
the plant to make cannabinoids and then
also The Growers are beginning to
understand which genes we want to look
at
which will help us determine which
cannabinoids are going to be produced
um when they're going to be produced
whether we're going to increase or
decrease it
um a big thing is that we're figuring
out which genes can uh Downstream make
thca if we have hemp Growers we want to
reduce the amount of THC produced in the
plants they'll know what to do with
those genes if they want to like reduce
the amount of hormones going in
eventually down the road people will get
to like Gene editing and I know GMO in
cannabis plants is a big controversy but
it is possible it will be possible
eventually to genetically modify our
plants and potentially like knock out
genes so they don't produce THC so our
lab is really focusing on why the plant
makes THC and CBD
yeah
yeah and so in reading your abstract in
in a bit of the paper in in preparation
for this and just to learn more about
what's going to be presented at cambed
23 my main takeaway was it seems like
your team has identified a potential
hormone treatment that can increase
cannabinoid synthase is that correct
we yes
um we've looked at a bunch of different
the main hormone I looked at during my
research was is salicylic acid which is
a plant defense hormone so I went
through and um
I looked at a variety of different
things throughout the throughout the
plant so I looked at the promoter of
this prenal transfers 4 enzyme that I
mentioned and so if you don't know what
a promoter is it's this stretch of DNA
right before a gene which determines if
the gene is going to be activated or
repressed or if nothing's going to
happen so all of our genes in our bodies
and the plants are just hanging out
something needs to tell them to turn on
or like work less and so I looked at the
promoters of these enzymes and I figured
out
there are certain elements within this
promoter that are responsive to hormones
so basically if hormones are released
they'll activate certain Pathways to
then trigger a gene to turn on
and so I found out that this Gene this
enzyme that produces cbga I found out
that it's quite responsive to salicylic
acid treatment
and
um so I did two studies one I figured
out that the promoter can be activated
at high levels following treatment from
salicylic acid
and I also did full plant studies so the
promoter studies were just little gene
cloning tiny studies but the plant
studies were full flowering plants
um a wife hemp cultivar and so I also
gave the plants a root trench of
containing salicylic acid
and so in both cases we saw the
promoters activated which will
Downstream produce more cbga and more
thca and then also in the actual plants
we saw that through qpcr and examining
messenger RNA expression we saw that a
lot of the genes in the cannabinoid
synthesis pathway were activated at
larger levels than without the treatment
so we saw like
um
the Primal transferase genes were
activated at much higher levels after
being treated with salicylic acid we saw
that
the cbda and thca synthase genes were
activated large levels so really we're
seeing that this hormone can activate
these cannabinoid synthesis genes at
larger levels than normal so we've also
seen increased cannabinoid content in
the plants a lot of my research goes
into why the genes are activated not so
much can I get more THC out of the plant
um okay yeah I really want to know like
why the plant's doing what it's doing
not how can I get the most THC out of
the plant but I know that's what the
Growers form
right yeah
so so basically kind of introducing more
of this hormone is like a signal to the
plant to create more cbga which then
eventually is going to make it
Downstream to to turn into potentially
more cannabinoids correct yep yep
um yeah so that that can be the case
with a lot of hormones
um I also saw
um
a large response from one hormone called
cytokinin which some Growers can give to
their plants
basically just improves growth so that
can be the case for that as well
basically anything that's going to
activate this promoter is a really good
um source to potentially improve your
plants
um I actually one of the stemming
points of my research was from a
cannabis Forum where I just looked up
Growers and they're like yeah I've given
aspirin to my
style of silica acid and so they're
basic people have been doing this
already so they're actually giving their
plants little tablets of aspirin like
dissolving it giving it to the roots and
seeing improved plants so this has
already been done in like people's
basements and closets but we just we're
just making the research and Publishing
it so that it's actually known
throughout the world
um yeah
yeah and that's it's funny that's such a
common thing that we find like when I'm
talking to researchers
um is that they're sort of
they're explaining the why for some of
these little tricks or treatments that
you know these Legacy Growers who have
been doing it for so long may have
already figured out but maybe didn't
always understand what's what's going on
inside the plant to make that work and
so it's really cool to see how you know
Academia or more you know traditional
science is coming along and you know
first of all confirming what what these
folks have been seeing anecdotally and
then actually explaining what's going on
yeah
so I think that's a that's you know a
really important thing that we're seeing
in the industry and it's a it's a great
thing that I'm glad that can Med can be
a part of that we can sort of be pushing
this forward yeah so
I guess I do want to come back to this
idea of like okay
is there potentially a hormone treatment
that we might be able to figure out that
you know Growers can use to increase
their cannabinoid production are we
there yet or are we still in the early
stages
so I'd say we're still in the early
stages because
um you wouldn't really think it but
actually giving your plants hormones can
be like considered
like non-organic excuse me not organic
um like unethical
and because you're changing the natural
composition of the plant like a lot of
these Growers they've
gotten to where they are because they
care for the plant they want it to do
its own thing they just want to
encourage it so giving it external fact
like exogenous hormones giving changing
its natural composition is a big maybe
no no from some people I know in like
the big Industries people would see that
and be like oh yes let's give all the
plants sounds like
other hormone and just like pump the
plant as much as we can but then you can
like kind of relate that to say like the
chicken industry where they're pumping
the chickens full they want to get as
much out of the product and they don't
care about the the cute the organisms
anymore and so
I think we are getting to the point
where we could give the plants hormones
but it has to be done in a really smart
way
um you can do a mix of hormones my old
my co-worker at UConn was giving the
plants a mix of different hormones and
seeing the outcome of that and that was
actually a really good study so like he
was mixing like cytokine and South acid
and methyl Jasmine and seeing improved
plants and cannabinoid content so I
think I think in the next few years
we're getting out these studies some
companies are actually patenting these
uh hormone treatments I know CT Pharma
in Connecticut patented our Labs
methylgasmine a application to the
plants because they saw increased growth
and everything so I think if it's done
in an ethical way people care about
their plants they don't give it too much
of the constant like give it the right
concentrations of the hormones because
too much will definitely create toxic
effects
um and of course not too little because
then you won't see anything but yeah I
think it's a good
uh
good idea moving forward especially like
not going straight to like these all
like really non-organic methods of
helping the plants like because the
plants already have the hormones going
throughout them so right like it's in my
mind I think it's okay I think it's
totally fine to like increase it a
little bit but like
um
as I was thinking before like salicylic
acid is produced as a defense mechanism
in the plant so you don't want to like
pose a threat to the plant so that just
so it produces more salicylic acid to
produce more cannabinoids like you have
to do it in the right way of giving it
the salicylic acid not scaring the plant
you know right yeah
there's there's a point of diminishing
returns right where you're doing more
harm than good yeah I think so
no that's interesting I mean and then
you know I I wonder and you could tell
me if I'm on bit off base here like
would there be something like even
further Downstream like instead of just
like giving the hormone straight to the
plant is there something else that can
be
um provided maybe like in certain forms
of nutrients or whatever that will sort
of naturally raise their
um levels of these of these hormones
that would kind of more naturally create
what you're what you're looking for yeah
absolutely I think that's kind of
already in the market so like a lot of
what these
um nutrients and like help grow like I'm
not a grower I'm a scientist so I'm not
I don't know all the like products and
stuff
um but a lot of these nutrient products
that they're giving the plants are
actually going to increase hormones so
like a lot of the like increased growth
um external administering things to the
plants will help increase oxen which is
a growth hormone so really in the end
people have like they don't have these
products and they're going to be like oh
this directly increases this hormone the
like it's going to increase a bunch of
hormones it creates I mean hormones work
in an orchestra they're all working
together some repressed some work
together some you know so I think people
are already working on that like
giving plants products is going to
change their hormone networks it's going
to increase decrease it so yeah
yeah but then kind of going back to what
we were talking about earlier like
with these findings it's sort of just
like another way that we could measure
whether or not these products are
working right if we see an uptick of
these certain hormones that we know that
are going to help Downstream to create
more cannabinoids be like well we might
be onto something with this formulation
here because we're seeing this uptick
yeah yeah it all comes back to the
beginning like everybody's working
together in this
to look at for uh these cannabis plants
especially with how little knowledge is
actually out there
um I think it's a really good start
place to start looking at these genes
Growers looking at them like getting
more with their plan understanding when
hormones are produced during flowering
how to increase or decrease it based on
their environment yeah
yeah so you know I'm thinking that this
could be very useful information for you
know nutrient developers to you know as
part of their r d to be looking at
whether the hormone levels are raised so
yeah very cool
um I know one thing that we also kind of
when we were chatting over email before
before we were doing this one thing that
you mentioned too about these findings
is not only could it help you know
figure out how to increase cannabinoid
content but maybe potentially decrease
as well I was wondering if you could
kind of speak to that a bit yeah so
um there's a few points I'll make here
um
kind of going back to the promoter talk
because that's what I studied for two
years
um there's so there's parts of the
promoter that will activate the gene
those parts of the promoters that will
repress the Gene and so these hormones
they can a lot of them will activate the
gene increase the transcription to make
proteins to make it usable but some of
them will repress it and not let the
genes work
and so if you find out which hormones
are going to repress say the THC
synthase Gene the prenal transfers all
these enzymes then you can administer
these hormones and see a reduction in
cannabinoids
um and well THC if you're a hemp grower
maybe CB like maybe if you're trying to
create a strain that just has more
cannabinoid like CBG dominant strains
um but also there's another part of my
research that was really interesting
um in the promoter I was of this prenal
transferase Gene that made enzyme that
makes CBG I was actually able to mutate
part of it
um which then gets into the GMO stuff
and I know it's controversial but um
so I actually mutated the part of it
when we were doing like
um like petri dish stuff uh so I got rid
of the responsive element to salicylic
acid and then we saw no response to it
so if you can mutate these promoters and
then put them back in the plant which
they're not able to do yet they're
working on actually
um like genetically modifying uh the
cannabis plants
um whenever they're able to actually do
that you can take the gene
mutate it put it back in then it's no
longer responsive to this hormone and
then there's also other parts of the
promoters
that are responsive to other things like
these genes that'll bind and activate it
called transcription factors and so you
can also mutate those areas and so they
won't bind anymore and so they won't
activate G so
um all of these different methods you
can come up with Gene editing
um giving them different types of
hormones you can determine if the
plant's going to make make more or less
THC and as I said this is really
um making less THC is good for the hemp
Growers
making more THC is great for these
medical marijuana cultivations
so there's a lot of different things we
can do
um and yeah figuring out which enzymes
work to make which cannabinoids is
really important so then that's just the
Baseline you can go in so many different
directions from that right you know and
I know we talked about you know Gene
editing and how that's you know
controversial in a lot of ways too but I
think also you know some work that we're
kind of doing on the medicinal genomic
side with you know helping Growers
sequence their plants and maybe find you
know interesting novel mutations and
things like that I think that and you
correct me if I'm wrong if we understand
which parts of the gene or which genes
are implicated for for these things we
might be able to find naturally
occurring mutations in some of these
plants and then you know to kind of use
more traditional breeding or marker
assisted breeding to sort of get the end
result that we're looking for right yeah
I think developing the like the full
understanding of all the gene networks
and which genes do what is the best step
to start with and then like actually I
know there have been people breeding
some plants to like get rid of a thca
synthase Gene naturally and so that's
totally that's like that's I think
that's one of the best ways to go about
it and I know the plants can still make
some thca even if they don't have the
THC synthase Gene because the synthase
genes are very similar
um so you wouldn't get rid of all the
thci but in that case like you're still
working to get rid of some things that
you don't want you can add in different
things so I think breeding and like just
understanding the plants is one of the
best ways to go about all this cannabis
science
excellent all right Lauren so winding
down here um I did want to give you an
opportunity to uh plug any social media
or any you know websites or anything uh
that you're affiliated with or you're
posting your work about
um or just any other resources that you
know about that are sort of in a similar
vein to this that would be good for for
folks to read up on um please let us
know yeah so
um I just finished my masters at Uconn
and they have one of the best plant
science programs ever I had the best lab
with Dr Jerry Berkowitz and a few others
so I want to just say thank you to them
and go check out our research we've been
coming up with a lot of new cannabis
research we have one right in the works
this paper actually it's the pre-print
is posted we are currently actually
publishing it so it should be out soon
um I just want to also shout out to my
lab that I work at in Westfield
Massachusetts it's called safetyva Labs
we're a startup we've probably been open
for like two months now and we are one
of the best teams I've ever met
um
that we do all sorts of testing we do
um really competitive turnaround times
for anybody in the area that wants to
test with us we do pickups
um so yeah safety in the labs check us
out on Instagram
LinkedIn online
and yeah that's about it thanks to my
lab and UConn lab and of course thanks
to my family and friends
yeah excellent I will definitely put
links to the the social media and the
websites in the show notes so people can
find it quick and yeah I um I Echo your
sentiments about the work that's coming
out of Uconn
um I think we've had a a number of
submissions from folks out of that lab
and uh I expect that UConn's gonna be
well represented at cam mid 23 which
we're really absolutely yes me too
so all right so thanks again Lauren for
doing this and I look forward to seeing
you out at Marco Island thank you you as
well
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Lauren Sands check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor farmer Freeman our
next episode drops February 1st that's
two weeks from today
in the meantime head over to
canmedevents.com now to check out our
preliminary speaker list in details
about our professional development
workshops while you're there if you
haven't received an invitation yet you
can request your invitation for the
cammed 23 Innovation and investment
Summit
we are really excited about this year's
event and truly believe it has the power
to transform our industry through
collaboration and Innovation I sincerely
hope to see you there
but if you can't make it in person to
Marco Island we do hope that you will
continue to stay connected with us
through the podcast and through our
social media channels you can find us on
LinkedIn Twitter Facebook and Instagram
just search for cabinet events all right
and that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and be sure to come back for the
next can Med Coffee Talk
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]