welcome everybody and thank you for
having me and I just want to start off
by saying thank you to mckernon and
cordage in and to doug kennedy for
putting this together we're starting off
with a video that when Doug Kennedy
approached me about speaking he wanted
to do a little vignette on one of my
patients who's had success with cannabis
so I haven't seen the video yet so let's
all watch it together and I can tell you
more about the patient afterwards
Rhonda molar my daughter is Malia she is
7 and she was diagnosed with autism at 2
years 9 months she wasn't making eye
contact she wasn't responding to her
name and she just was lost in her own
world she was very active so she would
constantly be running up and down she
couldn't really sit down very long she
couldn't really stay focused on anything
we didn't want to try pharmaceuticals
but we were open to trying anything that
was alternative that might not be so
drastic but maybe had some changes in
her behavior and we tried restricting
her diet for gluten we tried restricting
you know casein you know something's
helped here and there but it was nothing
that helped with the overall picture of
her behavior there was a discussion
between some parents and I saw dr.
bonnie goldsmith name so we made the
appointment and went to go see her and
she was awesome she explained the whole
thing to me upon her accommodation we
tried a CBD oil
cannabidiol she told me well let's try
and add in the THC the THC is a
psychoactive component of cannabis
we found a ratio of THC the CBD that was
it was this life-changing for my
daughter she began to sit down and focus
her aggression that she was experiencing
before the cannabis that was gone
and I started hearing feedback from
therapists and teachers asking me
what's going on with your daughter like
what's changed she's no longer
aggressive she's no longer hitting
students she's no longer spitting at
people she's no longer yelling at staff
she's sitting down she's doing her work
and I was so excited that it was working
and I didn't care anymore
I didn't care so I just started telling
people that this is what we were doing
[Music]
[Applause]
so that was a family that came to me
fairly desperate many of the people that
come into my office are at that
desperate moment for this family
she said they didn't go anywhere with
their child they couldn't go to the
grocery store they couldn't go to Chuck
E Cheese going to school in the morning
was you know she woke up the mom woke up
with dread just getting their daughter
out of the house and so you have to
remember that it's not just the patient
that is struggling but the whole family
and what's amazing is I just saw this
family a few weeks ago and this little
girl graduated from ABA therapy because
there's no more therapy to correct are
no more behaviors to correct she's
starting to speak and although they
still have their challenges their life
has changed significantly
this mom now has become a huge advocate
and has started a Facebook page for
parents seeking help with children with
autism they've been collecting data and
they have data from over 850 families
using cannabis and they're looking at
the different cannabis strains that are
being used the terpenoids the ratios
trying to really dial in on what's
working best for these children and you
know I applaud this family because they
really went past the fear they tried it
out and I like the mom said it's been
life-changing so so I'm medical director
at counter centers and there's not a lot
of time so let me go through here I
opened my office in 2008 we have two
locations in Southern California we see
somewhere between 250 and 300 patients a
month between the two practices remember
I live in a large metropolitan city with
millions of people but also we get
people from all over the state and also
some out-of-state patients as well many
of the most of these patients are
returning patients over the you know
almost decade that we've been there we
see about 20 to 40 new patients a month
our youngest patient was a six week old
with a devastating genetic illness who
started having seizures probably in
utero first documented seizure within
two hours of birth and then our oldest
patient my oldest patient was a hundred
year old woman who was probably on oh I
don't know like 15 or 17 different
medications and the family came to me
and said is there any possible way we
could get her off some of these drugs
and we did do that successfully the
average age of adult patients is not 21
it's 58 we are seeing a lot of baby
boomers coming in who are saying I do
not want to be on these medications
anymore and I will tell you about 75
percent of patients come in are already
on multiple medications and they are
looking to get off those medications
because of either side effects or that
the drugs are ineffective or the
philosophically they just really don't
want to take that many medications
they're fine to take their blood
pressure medication or or their heart
medication but to take sleeping pills on
top of pain pills on top of other kinds
of quality of life medication that's one
of the biggest things that we see in the
practice and then definitely we're
seeing a changing demographic in
California I know some of my colleagues
and I have talked about this where
initially when I started in this
practice it was mostly people who are
already using cannabis and just wanted
to be legal they no longer wanted to be
part of a illicit drug market and now
what we're seeing is people who are what
we call cannabis naive they've not used
cannabis but they're seeing it as a
possibility and I'm very happy to say
that in the last two years I've gotten
more referrals from mainstream
physicians like rheumatologists
oncologists and neurologists than ever
before and so I really think that
cannabis is now becoming accepted and
it's no longer fringe here's a list of
adult conditions I'm not going to go
through all of them but if you think
about what dr. Michelle um talked about
this morning about the distribution of
receptors it corresponds with the
diseases that we're seeing in a medical
cannabis practice and so by far my adult
patients are chronic pain I would say
the top three are pain anxiety insomnia
which all run together and then of
course we're seeing a lot of patient
with autoimmune disease as well as
cancer in Pediatrics it's a it's a
little shorter list by far treatment
resistant epilepsy and autism are the
two most common conditions although I am
seeing a fair amount of patients being
referred for advanced cancers but I will
also tell you that a couple of the local
children's hospitals are now referring
patients for symptomatic relief of
nausea vomiting weight loss and pain
because we can really do some nice
things with very low dose CBD THC a and
THC and these children who are really
struggling who are non-verbal for the
most part and they're not able to tell
their parents they feel lousy from the
chemo or from the radiation and so we
are seeing a lot of those kids being
referred in and again part of it is the
parents asking as well when they're at
the doctor's office are you okay if
we're doing this and I'm definitely
seeing an openness that we did not see
before I'm also seeing a fair amount of
patients with pandas and pans and I'm
again because of time I can't go into
that but this is a pediatric autoimmune
disease that can be very quite
devastating attacks normal healthy
children and as is really devastating to
the family and we are seeing some really
nice response most of these kids I have
a couple of families where the children
were actually institutionalized and
we've been able to get them out and back
functioning in society now the goals of
treatment pretty common everything that
we think that cannabis does medically so
pain relief alleviating anxiety
depression improving sleep helping
appetite lessening nausea vomiting gut
symptoms now a lot of people don't think
about enhanced focus and concentration
but if you have an endocannabinoid
deficiency and you're suffering with a
DD but also autism and other conditions
where you can't focus and remember the
baseline status of the endocannabinoid
system is going to dictate how you
respond for many of these people they
say I'm able to do well I'm able to go
to work I'm able to study at school
parents are reporting to me also that
their children are doing much better in
school and of course reducing and
eliminating seizures when we see
patients who have intractable seizure
disorder
but there's also other other goals of
treatment and kind of behind the scenes
apart from just feeling better at the
moment that you take cannabis we're also
seeing some long-term effects mostly
anti-inflammatory and neuroprotective
and many patients just report we even
have a space on my intake form how does
cannabis affect your quality of life and
people actually right I have a sense of
well-being I just feel better and
sometimes it's hard to put it into words
less pain is easy but in general having
just a better quality of life and
feeling better this is coming from
balancing your endocannabinoid system
and achieving that and I will say that
there cannabis is not the only thing
that will balance your into a
cannabinoid system and my colleague
Dustin Sulak from Maine at his table out
there he has a wonderful I actually
brought it up here endocannabinoid ayat
and activities other things that can
enhance your endocannabinoid system so I
do encourage people to look at that
because it's not just cannabis cannabis
is a piece of the puzzle but one of the
main things is you know we can talk
about pain scales and these kinds of
things but one of the things that I see
in my practice that I find really
important is that when people come into
my office who are desperate they have
lost control of their daily life they
are not participating with family with
work in their social activities exercise
and what happens is it starts to spiral
out of control and what I'm finding with
cannabis is that even though the medical
condition is not being cured what's
happening is that shift of power that
control is going back to the patient
they're able to manage their condition
with less side effects they're not
worried about the medication long term
that they're putting into their body and
it's simple they take a little bit and
it works and if they feel well they can
skip it without worrying about feeling
withdrawal the next day or even for a
week and so that that power play between
the medical condition being in control
versus you having control of your life I
think is one of the most very important
essential things that I see
in this particular kind of specialty and
improvement of quality of life and a lot
of people come in and say I'm not better
I still have cancer I still have anxiety
but I am in control I am no longer being
led around by my medical condition so
it's very important that we that we
acknowledge that now here's a patient
report I had a 36 year old female came
into my office in 2013 10 year history
of fibromyalgia and saw me and anxiety
and as you can imagine she was having
frequent bouts of depression you can see
her list of multiple medications she
came in with a big bagging and she said
I'm on all this and it's not working I
feel terrible and she was extremely
nervous because the type of work she
does she did not want to be outed as a
cannabis user and within a week of
seeing her I got this email where she
sums it up I came in to see you last
week and went straight to the dispensary
that means she was pretty desperate I've
been trying all sorts of different
cannabis for my insomnia and pain I'm
very excited to report that my pain
levels have gone down so much that I
feel like a normal person again I don't
even have to do it every day it lasts
for two to three days and that is
something that I see is that patients
don't have to medicate all the time I
will tell you 80% of my patients are
night time users of cannabis and
probably at least 50% do not medicate
every day and then she what my my whole
life has changed thank you and I just
saw her probably maybe three months ago
and she's continued to do well and in
fact when she comes in she's like I'm
fine I want to talk about my brother who
needs to come see you so so it's almost
as and she still has her conditions it's
it's just that they're well managed and
they're easily managed with cannabis and
then here's a more recent patient who
just came to see me last year 44 year
old female with severe migraines she did
not respond to many pharmaceuticals and
what's interesting is she worked for one
of the large entertainment movie
companies out in California and she was
kind of a bigwig there but her migraines
were so debilitating that she had to
take a leave of absence and that was
devastating to her she was trying so
hard not to miss work and she had told
me she was missing at least 2 to 3 days
a week and they told her you know you
can't
we have to you know we're not getting
the work done we have to ask you to take
time off and so she was super stressed
when she came to see me not only from
the pain and the years of this but also
from the financial hit she was taking by
not working and so here's the email from
her it's been almost eight weeks since I
saw you I just want to give you an
update the CBD oil has been a miracle
and controlling my chronic migraines
I've only had three very mild migraines
since starting the oil this is a huge
improvement to the ten plus migraines I
was getting monthly I've titrated up to
about eighty milligrams daily and that's
important because you notice it's two
months in we start low dose and we
titrate up and this is where she found a
good spot and she adds a couple of drops
of THC when I feel that migraines coming
on I definitely feel more relaxed
overall and finally have quality restful
sleep and I was happy to I'm very happy
to say that she went back to work after
four months of starting cannabis oil now
in children I've listed here quotes from
emails and text messages from families I
won't go through all of them but as you
can see they're all pretty impressive
the big things are that what I am seeing
in Pediatrics and you know I talked last
year we don't know about long-term
effects but we know what long-term
effects of intractable seizures do we
know what long-term effects of a child
who is autistic at a young age and
unable to participate in therapy and
then becomes a teenager and gets large
size and and and difficult to control
and so what I'm seeing is that when
someone is a responder what we're seeing
is is a child moving forward in life and
I write in my book about a little girl
who came to me at nine years of age who
was not reading and writing and I write
in the book that she came to me and read
me a book and wrote her name in cursive
and that was a huge accomplishment so I
am seeing I do not see children
regressing with cannabis I see
children's brains progressing to reach
their full potential whatever that may
be for that particular child and here's
a patient report this is Thomas and the
Thomas's mom has given me permission to
talk about him this is a young boy who
was born with
congenital brain malformation and he was
having intractable seizures he one of
the main things that they came in for
was the seizures but the second thing
was the severe self injurious behavior
and so he had came in wearing arm braces
so that he couldn't bend his arm so his
hands couldn't be by his face because I
saw pictures that the mom showed me of
black eyes and hematomas on his ears
that they had to take him to the
emergency room to get drained I mean he
was really beating himself up um he also
had severe acid reflux to the point
where the family walked around with
little cups to catch his vomit all day
long the mom said they went through
thousands and thousands of cups every
year and he was also unable to walk he
had tried ten different seizure
medications we started him on cannabis
oil at age seven years this was February
2015 and again we start low dose and we
titrate up it takes time he was also on
seizure medications that we're being
weaned off but he had complete
resolution of vomiting this was just a
perk the mom was thrilled with that but
he had 90% reduction of seizures and
continues to have that and then it can
you play this video for me this is
Thomas who yep maybe I can do it oh here
it is I got it and this is Thomas he
learned to walk unassisted if I can get
it to go
oops sorry there we go and the mom sent
me this video cuz she was just so
shocked and surprised
tom is over here come here come here
come here come here good job keep going
[Music]
there's Mario come on keep going and so
apparently he discovered the mirror and
liked to go look at himself so and this
was a kid that really everybody had
written off and so one of the things
that the mom said in the last visit was
not only is it keep getting better she
says I have no idea what it what the
next year is gonna bring it just keeps
getting better and better and I think
part of it is where we want to see you
know more and more balanced and allow
him to reach his potential because I
just don't think that we know and you
know I thought about what dr. Michelle
um said in his video and he said some of
these kids are being saved and I we
really don't know what the future holds
because this is a whole new brand brand
new generation of children that are
getting intervention with cannabis now I
don't have a lot of time to go over this
but in California we have lots of
different oils there's no restrictions
some people say that's bad I say it's
good my patients can get medicine and so
I have divvied up the cannabis medicine
into four different groups just based on
the main cannabinoids the dominant
cannabinoids so THC rich in the top left
bottom left is the high ratio CBD to THC
bottom right is the low ratio CBD to THC
and the top right is the raw
cannabinoids because basically patients
need a road map what am i what's in this
product knife people come in who say oh
I've tried just about everything and I
came to you because I have a card but
nothing's working and really all they've
tried is just one of these categories
because they don't know how to read
labels and they're not sure what they're
getting and so when you break it up like
this it gives a patient a road map of
different things to try I've got 20
seconds so I'm going to
real quick here these are various
products you can see they're all labeled
and in California we went from not very
many labeled things about eight years
ago to now we're seeing labeled and also
January 2018 everything's going to be
tested that's on the market so we've
really made some progress in that regard
these are I was just going to mention
the terpenoids very important especially
in pediatric patients
it appears Lyn Tallulah Mir seen both
very calming are excellent for children
with epilepsy and autism and then people
often ask me which cannabinoid I don't
know I can make an educated guess but
your body's going to respond and so for
most patients you have to have a wide
variety of choices so that person can
find what works best for them and then
this is why we should have cannabis
right here it sums it up thank you very
much
you