[Music]
um can you describe how ferium affects
hemp plants um how does it infect and
you know what is sort of the
progression okay well let's start with
uh fusarium is a genus and it's a very
large genus with a lot of complexes so
lots of species within a fusarium
complex so most people when they hear
fusarium they think fusarium Wilt and
that's fusarium oxysporum different um
different special forms but fusarium
oxysporum or fusarium Wilt is a vascular
disease it starts in The Roots it's all
born it moves its way up the vascular
system and it causes Wilt um because of
just blocking water and nutrient uptake
to the top of the plant and necrosis of
the of the xylem fusarium headlight is
fusarium garum so that is infecting
flowers and grain from the outside um
it's a very very pathogen and remember
earlier I talked about fusarium salani a
Rootin Crown Rod so there are three
major fusarium species that affect hemp
or cannabis um but back to fusarium
headlight uh the fusarium headlight
pathogens we have identifi five um
fusarium garum is the common one that's
the one that you read so much that
affects um wheat and Cal crops um so
fusarium garum will infect um flowers
and grain we have found it to infect um
growing tips and leaves but primarily
it's going to be a flower and grain
disease interesting so different type
different different species of fusarium
will kind of attack the plant from from
different angles that's right that's
right and to not just say fusarium
because when we started working on
fusarium headlight the Assumption was
that it was the fusarium ox sisum the
fusarium W pathogen and they're very
very different even though that first
name even that though that genus is the
same interesting so what are some of the
economic impacts of fusarium on hemp
cultivation um so fusarium headlight as
we call it will blight out um and and
blight is kind of a rapid necrosis
that's what that kind of term means a
fusarium headlight will blight out a
flower head or a seed head um so so uh
early shattering more
brittle more brittle flowers or or grain
heads but we can have it at very low
levels as well um so that's remember I
mentioned mot toxins earlier so um
fusarium griin arum produces two
different mot toxins so a Mot toxin is a
toxin produced by um a fungus um so mot
toxins there are there's a history of
MOT toxins in fusarium um species uh the
trines for example um that can cause
vomiting um digestion issues both in
humans and in animals so in in hemp I'm
sorry in uh any feed it's highly
regulated so uh even low levels of
disease can cause high levels of toxins
and that's something that we're not
regulating here in the US not in Helm
not in cannabis so everyone is really
interested in looking at um
apoxin or or some of those other um
toxins which we're not finding um but we
are finding those fusaria myotoxins from
the headlight pathogens so again all the
Fus areia out there but that's our Focus
because that's what we're seeing the
most and that's what we feel is the most
important especially as hemp as an
animal feed is coming onto Market yeah
so you you mentioned that ferum could be
there in low levels so
might it sort of Escape some visual
detection and have some of those microt
toxins present I'm going to Spill the
Beans a little bit uh uh my graduate
student just came in with some year one
data from uh two different fields here
in um in Central Kentucky and he had
fusarium headlight at about 5% severity
so think about that whole seed head and
about visually 5% of that head had
symptoms um so very low something that a
grower would probably Overlook something
that I might have said oh well and he
ended up detecting um Dawn deoxy no
valinol uh he ended up detecting Dawn at
levels that are above the threshold for
human consumption in other grains so of
course we don't have that threshold for
him but that that threshold would I mean
that would have failed um um uh QC in a
cial grain market and so we're finding
those high levels of toxins and and in a
year of drought and extreme heat this
year we had low levels of disease wow
[Music]