I'm gonna focus on mostly synthetic
chemistry and finish up with a little
bit of biological activity in mice not
men ok so I'm here to tell you today
about a new cannabinoid that we've
discovered hexa hydro cannabinoid acid
or can have aknowledge acid which you
get from hydrogenation of tea HCA which
is the form of THC that's expressed in
the trichome so when this compound is
hydrogenated it makes hexahydrate
cannabinoid acid and that's what we're
going to talk about today is the
hydrogenation of cannabinoids which
turns the tetrahydrocannabinol that
we're very familiar with into hexa hydro
cannabinoids because we're adding a
molecule of hydrogen to the North double
bond of the ring when we do this on
cannabis extracts that contain terpenes
terpenoids and flavonoids those
compounds have double bonds too just to
get a little chemical on you what a
double bond is is that's two carbons
that are doubly bonded to each other and
when you react that with hydrogen it
saturates the double bond so in all of
these compounds terpenes and terpenoids
and flavonoids that are present in the
cannabis plant there are multiple double
bonds and so when we hydrogenate an
extract that's enriched with THC a or
CBD a if we're using that type of
variety
we also hydrogenate the the other
compounds there and what we'd like to do
is exploit what we call the ensembl
effect which we prefer over the
entourage effect of the multiple
compounds that are provided in the
cannabis plant that provides biological
activities so we do know that there is a
synergistic effect of these compounds
and what we'd like to do is explore
hydrogenation has a very simple scalable
widely practiced reaction to be able to
chemically transform the oil that we get
from extraction of the cannabis plant to
improve efficacy stability in the
pharmacokinetic profile
so where did this idea come from I
worked at DuPont central research for
about eighteen and a half years and one
of the projects I worked on was the
hydrogenation of cat monoi oil so cat
meant very similar to cannabis expresses
its oil and glandular trichomes on the
surface of the leaves it's enriched with
a monoterpene oide that we call in the
pate a lactone on the pate a lactone is
actually what's responsible for the
excitation in cats and by the way it
goes clear up the feline kingdom it's
not just your little domestic friend at
home but big cats when they're exposed
to cat mint want to listen to jazz and
eat Twinkies it's an interesting notion
too because these irid oh I'm sorry
go back these ear annoyed Munno terpenes
which paid a lactone are also found in
the secretion of insects so what we
found is that when we take cat monoi oil
which we harvest this is a field in the
punjab region of india where we were
developing a supply chain of cat monoi
oil here's some local workers who are
distilling the cat monoi oil and a steam
distillation we take the steam distill
cat monoi oil and we hydrogenate it and
when we hydrogenate it we take this
material now the hydrogenated Caplin oil
and here's some references that describe
the efficacy against biting takes we
have really good efficacy against the
mosquito that carries both West Nile
virus and the Zika virus as well so
hydrogenated cap monoi oil is a
registered insect repellent with the EPA
EPA regulates insect repellents because
it falls into the bucket of insecticides
and DuPont did not commercialize this
but they've licensed this to a company
called antumul and anthem all is
basically looking to develop a supply
chain both here in the West as well as
over in Asia of cat monoi oil you don't
just snap your fingers and have 80
million pounds of cat monoi oil you have
to basically build up the agronomy to be
able to deliver that but look for this
material to be launched in the next year
or two and to replace DEET as the
preferred insect repellent so that's
sort of like where this idea came from
in the hydrogenation of cat monoi oil is
carry Offaly which is a very ubiquitous
sesquiterpene oeid that's also found in
the extract of cannabis and so what we
found when we hydrogenate cat monoi oil
is we hydrogenate this terpene and we
were able to actually observe all four
of these diastereomers and NMR and we
grabbed a US patent on it too as well
and so I became known as the hydrogenate
er give me something and and I
hydrogenate it well
another thing we hydrogenated we take
the essential amino acid lysine and
notice there's no double bond and lysine
but what we have is a carboxylic acid
here and by changing our catalyst
conditions in the hydrogenation we could
reduce a carboxylic acid so we think
again by changing the conditions we can
now do different chemistry to
cannabinoid acids to reduce their acids
as it turns out we can take this diamine
which we call lyse and all and replace
petrochemical derived I amines that are
about three times more expensive in the
billion-dollar market of epoxy resins
worldwide this is currently being
commercialized
so yeah the hydrogenate ER when the only
tool you have is a hammer everything
looks like a nail so give me a
biological feedstock and I'm the
hydrogenate ER I'm gonna hydrogenate it
so that let's talk about hydrogenated
cannabis oil so this is my chemical
great-great-grandfather so my PhD
advisors advisor advisor I think that's
right chemical genealogy this is uh late
roger adams and you have to think that
again in 1940 these papers came out in
about 1942 41 look how close his
structure to THC was 20 years before
Michonne discovered it
you'll see that his structure of THC is
totally correct except for the placement
of the double bond which we know is
between these two carbons not between
these two distal carbons so Rafael Mushu
l'm in 1964 had the luxury of 60
megahertz NMR to be able to identify
where that double bond was but really
Rafi stands on the shoulders of Roger
Adams here because Roger Adams came up
with the structures of the cannabinoids
including the structure of CBD again
with the double bond in the wrong place
and here is the structure of the fully
hydrogenated material but notice it's
not the hydrogenated THC acid it's just
hydrogenated THC which we call hexa
hydro can have it all so the machine
group did look at hydrogenation and in
ninety or I'm sorry in 2006 reported
these hydrogenated derivatives of CBD
so it wasn't CBD acid it was CBD and
they hydrogenated CBD to make in this
case eight CBD what you see here is that
there's two sets of double bonds in CBD
and so you have this EXO cyclic
methylene and the cyclohexene and they
actually develop conditions to
selectively hydrogenate one olefin over
the other which is a nice little piece
of synthetic chemistry and they found
that these compounds again like CBD
controlled inflammation and other
anti-inflammatory activity so people had
looked at these hexa hydro cannabinoids
as potentially therapeutic targets the
Kim group later on looked at hexa hydro
cannabinol again not the cannabinol
acids but hexahydrate cannabinol notice
how this has got a wedge coming up and
that's got a hash going into the board
these are the diastereomers that you
make when you hydrogenate
THC you get a little bit of the methyl
up and you get a little bit of the
methyl down these can be separated by
comma tog Rafi and this group showed
that they were potent anti-cancer agents
and looked at models too
that we're looking at angiogenesis which
is the tumors ability to reroute
vascular plumbing to feed it with a
fresh blood supply so it looked like
this was going to be an area of
interesting interesting biological
activity so our concept was to basically
oh I'm sorry
go back our concept was to basically
take whole plant extract and not purify
the compounds but then do a direct
hydrogenation to make what we call 8co
or hydrogenated cannabis oil
alternatively we can take the whole
plant extract decarboxylate it to now
remove the co2 then do a hydrogenation
to make decarboxylated HCL and notion is
is that we're going to transform what
Mother Nature has already provided by
doing the heavy lifting providing these
wonderful compounds in the plant to do a
chemical modification of those compounds
to create hopefully something that has
improved properties so here is a
representation of a bunch of structures
that are found in the cannabis plant
most notably Delta 9 THC a delta 9 CBD a
and a host of variety of terpenes that I
point out here this is certainly not an
exclusive list there's many many
compounds in cannabis so when we take
this mixture and all of these things
where you see two lines between carbons
these are called double bonds and so
when we hydrogenate these it turns into
this so we've completely saturated all
of those double bonds and we've turned
the tetrahydrocannabinol ik acid into
hexahydrate cannabinol ik acid so it's
still a cannabinoid it's just a
cannabinoid that no longer has the
double bond here and it's important to
point out that with the carboxylic acid
here when I did a search and sciFinder
this is this is a thrilling thing for a
synthetic chemist like myself to do a
search on sciFinder and to find zero
hits in chemical abstract on this
which is a hydrogenation away from THC a
which is the star of the show so
realizing that this is a novel
composition of matter we had to file a
patent on it so our friends in the
pharmaceutical industry don't try to
scoot me anyone ever look at a billion
dollar molecule before come up and look
at it if you want to look at it it's a
little white crystals on the bottom of a
flask so hexahydrate can a banal ik acid
new composition of matter cool I think I
stumbled into something pretty valuable
okay so let's talk about the
hydrogenation of cannabis so what we do
is this is called a partial and all this
is is basically a vessel here that we
can put under a pressure of hydrogen and
shake it because we have a catalyst in
there and to get the catalyst mixing
with the elements in the reaction we
have to shake it so we use this thing
called a par shaker and what we see this
is called thin layer chromatography and
what happens is we spot the reactions
down here and then we elute with a
solvent in this direction and what we
find is that the starting material
doesn't run quite as fast as the
hydrogenated product this gives us an
indication that our reaction is complete
because here we have a mixture of both
the starting material and the product
here we have just the starting material
here's the product and we see no
starting material presence so we know
that our reactions complete and we could
isolate our product we run a lot of
what's called nuclear magnetic resonance
proton NMR proton NMR of this stuff is
amazingly clean amazingly clean I sound
like Donald Trump then I it's beautiful
great you're gonna love it okay so
here's the carbon three here's the
carbon 13 NMR which again is you know I
don't know the non synthetic chemists
may not be able to appreciate but this
is extremely extremely clean product
okay so here's what the material looks
like it's a white crystalline solid as a
sharp melting point between 60 and 63
degrees
here's we've made a bunch of the
material and I'm happy to report that
I've consumed this material and to tell
you that it gives me a psychological
effect similar to consuming a THC type
material I could feel at a very high dab
dose kind of like ringing in my limbs
and my beard feels crispy which is
interesting never felt the crispy beard
but okay again very very pure compound
I'm gonna skip through this okay we
identify things by its molecular weight
so the molecular weight is a unique
molecular weight because we've added a
mole of hydrogen here so the
corresponding THC a compound would be
358 we add a mole of hydrogen we move
the molecular weight up to 360 and you
know lo and behold we see M minus 1
which is 359 because this is in the
minus mode of the mass spectrometer this
is just high resolution mass spec which
you know again just identifies the
identifies the the compound as being the
correct one and then we decarboxylate
and when we decarboxylate we make hexa
hydro cannabinol which is this and you
can see there's two nice aromatic
signals two nice aromatic signals and
just a beautiful set of signals here
this is a very very very clean compound
also psychologically active or
psychoactive when we dab this we have
the same profound effect maybe a little
bit slower than then THC or and maybe
lasts a little bit longer okay so we've
done this the CBD as well orange light
yellow light so we did this to see CBD
and we've done this to THC now let's
talk about the biological effects of
these materials
so recall the Kim assay showed that
these compounds were anti-angiogenic I
think they speculated in a paper that it
was asked acting on V GE F but I don't
think they actually knew the mechanism
of its anti-angiogenic activity so what
we did is we we looked in in in these
little guys right here and looked at a
very aggressive form of brain tumor
called glioblastoma multiforme and we
did a test where we used the vehicle
that we're injecting into the mice just
as a control and then looked at
comparing th CA to the h8 CA and CB da
to the hydrogenated versions and here
all we're doing is we're sacrificing the
animals taking the tumours out and
weighing them and just looking for a
change
in tumor weight what we observe is that
left unchecked the tumors will grow but
when treated with cannabinoids at this
arbitrary rate of 10 milligrams per
kilogram body weight that we do see
lowering of the tumor sizes and in fact
it looks as though the hydrogenation
improves the activity of the
non-hydrogenated cannabinoids and that's
more more apparent in this chart right
here where you could see hydrogenation
providing a slight improvement to th CA
activity and hydrogenation here
providing a much more market improvement
to CBD a we're following up this work in
a collaboration with Professor Roger
Pertwee
University of Aberdeen in Scotland to
get cb1 binding numbers and we have a
bunch of assays sort of in the works and
we're also doing some more follow-up
work to understand what type of
mechanism might be at work in
controlling these tumor sizes
what was known quite some time ago in
1991 is hexa hydro cannabinol actually
does undergo metabolic oxidation similar
to that of THC and so what happens is is
apparently in this is the THC and what
you could see here is that the 11
hydroxy compound is the major oxidative
metabolite component when treated with
liver microsomes what we find with h8c
not the acid but with h8c is we see a
similar metabolic profile so even though
there is no double bond here we still
see oxidation at the 11th position and
oxidation here at the 8th position so
this is basically an indiscriminate
oxidation that's still oxidizing these
carbons even though there is no double
bond present but notice that our 11
hydroxy metabolite is a different 11
hydroxy metabolite then shows up on
urine tests so the idea here is you can
take this and pass the test get it get
it get it get it
okay so hydrogenated cannabis oil is
basically prepared by hydrogenation of
extracts it converts the
tetrahydrocannabinol at the hexahydrate
cannabinoids in this case we have a new
composition of matter a billion-dollar
molecule it has similar oxidative
metabolism to THC a I can tell you it
comes with a pretty fragrant and floral
taste and certainly the psychoactive
effects that are noted here on this
chart so now when you do a search for
this structure in chemical abstracts
what you find is one reference my patent
thank you very much and we got a notice
of allowance from the USPTO just a
couple of weeks ago saying that we have
an allowed patent here so this is really
cool when you're an inventor this is a
great thing to get so I would just like
to thank these folks shocker and and and
many who did the anti-angiogenic testing
at the Albany College of Pharmacy Chris
Barone who I collaborate he's from the
clear concentrates out in Los Angeles
this is his brand Baroni extract severe
high-quality cannabis extract dr. Chris
Whitner from discovery 64 one of my old
collaborators from Fort Collins Colorado
and my very talented patent attorney who
I'm greatly indebted to and you for your
attention thank you
you