[Music]
value of the the study that you're doing
is to try to identify what are those
good ratios and make sure that they're
available to people in other states
because I know that's not the case
everywhere you they might not have sort
of that high CBD low THC ratio like in
some some states uh it's just all THC
you're lucky if you find any CBD so I
think that's that would be a great
benefit of of this work is to really
figure out what that good ratio is and
inform the the industry yes that's one
of the things I'm really grateful I
because I'm independent uh I don't I'm
not uh like full-time employed by
anybody just me ask nurse Laura and I I
love that I get to work uh because
because with with nursing I can work in
in other states and talk to companies
and talk to
uh researchers about about the different
products also in the hemp space and and
what what's out there that we're seeing
as beneficial and where are those gaps
what's missing and to educate people on
how to be a smart um hemp consumer even
like how to to find a reliable hemp
company um thankfully in our Network we
have some good people that would have
some good products but there also is a
lot of garbage out there I did a secret
shopper campaign in the state of
Delaware and and for for hemp shops and
it was kind of scary what we found and
and it's a lot because it's not so
regulated
um so I just want to encourage people to
do their homework and and uh learn how
to dig into the details not just trust
you know like Google review use and and
not just trust a handshake you know we
need to know what we're getting what
we're putting in our body because even
if today it doesn't cause a negative
effect uh some of the the things that
might be in some of these products might
cause issues down the road that we don't
even know about yeah no that could be a
whole that could be a whole other
podcast and actually I think we should
do that uh I think it's really
interesting and um it was one of the
things I was going to ask but then I
remembered that you know that the study
is restricted to getting products from a
dispensary because I was curious you
know are people using hemp diive
cannaboids or sort of these synthetic
canabo like delta8 THC or some of these
other things for ptst I think that would
be interesting uh maybe a later
study yes yes we we you know well maybe
you don't know but when you're trying to
get approved by an
IRB it is an independent review board it
it's a lot of work and there are a lot
of specifics that you have to follow and
and we're trying to do everything like
this is our first study we hope to do so
many more research projects uh but you
have to do something to get off the
ground and so we had to find ways to
sort of level the playing field just a
little bit sure and we do have um
regulations so there's a a group called
uh canra the Cannabis Regulators
Association that brings together
cannabis Regulators from multiple States
uh and they talk and and hopefully at
some point we're going to have some more
standard across the country that's one
of the challenges that that I find is is
standards from state to state
accessibility from state to state it it
really is challenging and uh to to take
the time to figure out what the
regulations are like what what are the
standards in this state uh especially
for business owners so I have a contract
with Bright View Assisted Living because
they want their uh residents to be able
to access cannabis and utilize cannabis
in their facilities some of these people
are this is the end of their life is
going to be in this facility they want
them to have a good quality of life they
operate in eight states up and down the
east coast and even in the states they
all have medical programs but they have
different rules and different products
in each of their programs and trying to
standardize a policy and standardize
implement ation for them it is really
challenging
[Music]