hi I'm here to bring you guys back to
the world of cultivation my name is Sam
Hayden I work for the agricultural
biotechnology Lab at the University of
Connecticut
um I'd like to thank can Med for
inviting me and of course my Pi uh Dr
Gerald Berkowitz for funding me for this
wonderful Adventure
um so first I'd like to just go over a
little bit about what we do in the lab
our lab mostly deals with the regulation
of gene expression in cannabis and we
also study uh Gene
Gene function
um so what you're seeing here is some
work that we've done characterizing
transcription factors that induce
trichome morphogenesis in cannabis one
of these is a MIB transcription Factor
called mixta which is the focus of my
Master's thesis on the top left here
you're seeing a transient expression
study in the Oceana benthamana where we
showed the nuclear localization of this
protein
on the right you're seeing qpcr results
for the expression pattern of this Gene
over uh seven weeks of flowering and you
can see that it's peaking right about
the time the cannabinoid biosynthesis
tends to ramp up
and then um the bottom two photos you're
seeing are scanning electron micrographs
of trichomes of nicotiana tobacum leaves
and on the left you're seeing a wild
type Leaf
um with a normal distribution of
trichomes and normal branching in the
trichomes more importantly and then on
the right you're seeing a tobacco leaf
that is stably transformed and over
expressing this cannabis protein and
what you're seeing is a significantly
increased number of trichomes and also
increased trichome branching which I
think is the more important find there
um and so basically this is an example
of just what we do we we do expression
in heterologous systems to identify Gene
function and we use a lot of qpcr to
determine how these genes are regulated
how their expression is regulated and
what their expression patterns are we
are also interested in yeah enzymes
involved in cannabinoid biosynthesis
like Lauren Sands she's also from our
lab gave a presentation on pt4 so
interesting to note too is that all of
these genes are coordinated in this
wonderful Symphony
um and that you know cannabinoid
biosynthesis isn't actually just as
simple as the biosynthetic enzymes
because those enzymes themselves are
controlled by trichome genes which are
controlled by flowering genes so there's
really a complex system here and that's
more or less what we study
this here is made by Peter apicella he
was a student in our lab and he utilized
some of my data to create a correlation
Matrix which shows how this mixed Gene
it's labeled here as tfy is tightly
correlated with um
very important genes and cannabinoid
biosynthesis namely being adrenal
pyrophosphate synthase and Olive atolic
acid cyclase many of you here probably
know that those are the precursors for
cbga and we found the that the
expression of this mixed Gene was
actually tightly correlated with the
expression of those two genes which to
me was interesting because we've seen
from other research that cannabinoids
aren't really produced until the
trichome produces a stock so I'm
actually interested in seeing what
trichome genes are initiating the
development of the stock which may be
also thereby activating cannabinoid
biosynthesis genes but this is just a
good way to illustrate
the symphony again the of all of these
different enzymes and products that are
working in coordination to generate
these cannabinoids that we love so much
so moving on from what we do
um I'm going to talk about I'm going to
get into this spectral diet question I
mentioned genetic expression the
regulation of gene expression because
um what we're how we're looking at
spectral diet is a means of manipulating
gene expression in order to accomplish
crop steering outcomes so we hear this
buzzword a lot achieving full genetic
expression we want to achieve the full
expression of the genetic potential of
the plant people throw that term around
a lot and I don't think that they fully
understand what that means
um but we're going to get to the bottom
of it
so the way I look at it and the way many
people look at it is that you're
breeding in genotype selection is where
you determine the roof the potential to
you
can hope to live up to
um and in and the way to do that is by
removing limiting factors so limiting
factors being par nutrition uh
transpiration rates via VPD making sure
your CO2 levels are all adequate
um so theoretically by removing these
limiting factors we're allowing the
plant to achieve its fullest potential
foreign
and uh then after you've removed all of
these limiting factors what's next at
that point we're talking about crop
steering we're talking about actually
pushing that roof and increasing the
potential that we can hope to live up to
by modifying
um the way that the plant grows with
environmental signals and cues and a lot
of these cues uh deal with genetic
regulation
um so spectral diet is a method of crop
steering arroya defines this as being
the Strategic adjustment of the
environment to encourage plants to grow
in a specific pattern
so again we're we're trying to control
these growth patterns by controlling
gene expression because gene expression
is at the base of so much of this the
rapidity at which a flower starts to a
plant starts to flower is often
determined by the expression levels of
certain genes at certain times and how
they're regulated
um so one of the first examples I ever
saw of this was back in my medical
growing days when my gurus back then
would insist that we swap out every
other HPS with a CMH and this was really
common and It produced better flowers
nobody really knew why
um but we all presumed that it was
because of the wider spectral range that
you see in the metal halide spectrograph
there as opposed to HPS which is mostly
yellow
um and there wasn't really data behind
that people just did it because it
worked and I think that what we're
finding is there's actually maybe some
data to support that and then on the
left picture here you're seeing
um a greenhouse being supplementally lit
by red and far red LEDs this is a
strategy that's taken up by ornamental
Growers lots of Growers because red to
far red ratios affect the downstream
expression the expression of genes
Downstream of phytochrome which is
something I'm going to start talking
about in a moment but these strategies
have been taken up by other uh
Industries not only in terms of what
what spectral diet to give the plant at
a consistent rate but also ways that we
can give little shots of
um different wavelengths to elicit a
different response and this is a very
complex wide-reaching subject DLI photo
period fluency
Etc but what we're focused on in this
study reductive of course is blue to Red
ratios and red to far red ratios
and those ratios are known to affect two
signaling molecules in the plant known
as phytochrome and cryptochrome
um it turns out as it happens I think
that cryptochrome may actually be the
more important signaling molecule in
activating flowering
but uh we originally were pursuing red
far red ratios and phytochrome
phytochrome activity because it's very
well studied and because it has been
shown to be the origin of the shade
avoidance response if many of you have
heard of that I'm not sure but basically
the shade avoidance response is when the
plant registers that it's under shaded
light because of the increased ratio of
far red far red having a lower energy
and a longer wavelength is able to
penetrate deep into the canopy and red
light is not so the plant has evolved to
know that when it gets a lot of far red
that it's in the shade and so this
phytochrome molecule becomes inactivated
and that results in what's known as the
shade avoidance response where the stem
elongates and it attempts to escape that
poor light to get to the good light so
knowing that that was happening we
thought that this might be a good
candidate to Target for manipulation to
see if we can affect gene expression
also on the right you're seeing a
diagram of the current model for
flowering initiation and arabidopsis
which is a long day plant and that's
interesting to note because most of what
we know about these signaling Pathways
has been studied in arabidopsis which
has a different mechanism of flowering
than short day plants or cannabis right
and in general short day flowering is
much less well understood much less well
studied however
rice is a very good model species that
we can use to understand that because
it's also a short day plant and a model
species that has been heavily studied
and from that data from that literature
we know that Constance and ft are two
genes Downstream of both phytochrome and
cryptochrome which initiate flowering
and
um
and those two genes we we've actually
gone ahead and studied those in uh in in
in further studies but basically the
point is that these two genes although
they're present in uh short day plants
like Arab sorry like cannabis or rice
they have a slightly different signaling
methodology a different a different
signaling pathway and
um I think that creates a lot of good
opportunities for research because in
studying cannabis flowering we can learn
more about how short day plants flower
in general
um so why are we doing this hasn't this
already been done didn't Bruce bugbee
already cover all of this
uh it's a good question what have so the
question I have to ask myself is why
bother what what have previous studies
lacked and I think this is actually kind
of glaring like a big problem because
I've noticed that um most studies done
on light wavelengths are done using
different fixtures we're comparing HPS
to metal halide to different LED arrays
and generally there's a lot of variables
we're not just testing one variable
these these spectral diets vary in many
many different ways for instance this is
an example of a popular study which made
the conclusion that Inc sorry I say this
the three graphs you see at the bottom
are referring are a study that was done
which implied that the increasing blue
Photon fraction
decreases yields and um but if you take
a look at these graphs you'll see that
from left to right the blue Photon
fraction increases but the red Photon
fraction actually decreases so I'm
wondering how we're able to make
conclusions absolutely about blue Photon
fraction when there are other variables
that are also changing which have a
synergistic effect so I'm not confident
in these data I'm not confident that
decreasing blue Photon or increasing
blue Photon fraction will decrease
yields because we for instance we didn't
keep the red light constant in this case
the red light decreases and so the blue
to Red ratio is actually decreasing in
each of these so theoretically if you
wanted to you could possibly say that
the decreasing blue to Red ratio is
what's causing these yields yield losses
um I want to shout out to Adaptive so
the way we're getting around this is
that adaptive growth Technologies has
donated these lights to us which enable
us to use the exact same fixture with
different diode with the with the same
diode arrays but then to either turn on
or off different diodes in those lights
so we can control all of the different
spectral ratios except for one and so
that's what I think that's the advantage
we have at abl over other labs that are
trying to do this
um
so it's ironic that I say that because I
handed this off to a student who
um was going to pick up the project and
didn't and I asked them to set this up
to study high red ratios versus low red
ratios and they did that Unfortunately
they did not control for the blue to Red
ratio which was exactly the issue we've
been talking about so you can see here
there's a low in T1 the top figure
there's a there's a low red to far red
ratio meaning there's a lot of far red
light
but there's also a high blue to Red
ratio
and I'm almost happy he did this it was
a mistake but it ended up showing us
something that's worth knowing
um so because basically there's two
variables low red to far red high blue
to Red in the top figure compared to the
bottom and the results of this were
interesting they were very exciting
because we actually saw a pretty
significant increase in flower biomass
the leaf surface area is a phenotypic
change which is maybe not as important
but a significant and large increase in
flower biomass was was the result of
this treatment
and so the question becomes which of the
two variables is responsible for this
change is it the low red to far red
which is the opposite of what we
expected we thought that the low red to
far red would decrease yields
um or is it the blue to red and so that
is what we need to study now and that's
what we've continued to do so this is a
new experiment where I picked this up
and I controlled for the blue to Red
ratio and I manipulated only the red to
far red ratios
um because those are the two that we
consider to be biologically significant
and the result of this was
absolutely no change sorry for the
letdown not very exciting but basically
what we found is that red to far red
ratios are having no considerable impact
on yield but that also leads us to some
other interesting conclusions
so
um what we did also do is we studied the
cannabinoids and we found that this is
fresh flowers so all that was present
was the cbga thca and cbda we found no
change in cbda however by week six in
the high red to far red treatment we
actually saw a statistically significant
increase in cbga
um that's interesting because it
indicates there might be some gene
expression effect but it's also
interesting because we see that although
there's an increase in cbga there's no
increase in cbda we are concerned with
what's the rate limiting step in
cannabinoid biosynthesis and this kind
of gives us some information to chew on
to think about that
and again this is the same data but this
is on the composite dry flower so
instead of with the fresh flower we just
took the terminal flower with this
composite measurement we took each plant
dried and milled the whole plant
together and measured that composite
sample and we still find that there's
actually an even greater increase in
cbga in the composite sample
um however no change in anything else so
overall not that exciting but there's
more
so um I mentioned these genes that are
flowering genes that are Downstream of
cryptochrome and phytochrome and these
are also very interesting targets for
breeding and for potential biotechnology
technological work
um because these genes are what signal
the plant to start flowering
and this was interesting because in like
I said we are trying to manipulate gene
expression using spectrums
um not only to understand how to better
cultivate the plant but potentially to
better understand how the gene functions
or sorry how the plant functions and
what genes are doing and how they're
activating these flowering Cascades and
so interestingly enough we found that
Constance and ft expression were changed
significantly from the from this light
treatment
but more importantly this is the first
time that anybody's actually character
characterized the expression patterns of
these genes in cannabis so I'm pretty
excited to say that the expression
patterns of these genes so far line up
quite well with the rice model and so I
feel like we could actually use the rice
model to try and understand
um how to which which genes are actually
important for flowering in cannabis and
this is evidence to suggest that that
would actually be a good comparison
uh foragen is a critical night length
gated uh Gene and you can see that
before flowering at Day Zero uh its
expression was basically nothing and
then it increases to six thousand and
twelve thousand fold in the first week
of flowers so that indicates that
that these genes are probably important
however I will say that the sad thing is
that we although we saw the change in
expression of these genes we saw no
change in yield so
um in terms of commercial value maybe
we're not there yet but
um I think it's interesting to note that
although these genes expression were
changed they had no effect on yield
and so um coming to the end of the talk
here
um this is what we're doing right now as
we speak and I think that this will be
our our our best experiment because
um in the first experiment we had two
variables uh in the in the same
experiment in the second experiment we
had we reduced that to one variable and
in this experiment we're testing the
other variable and we saw an effect in
the first one no effect in the second
one I expect we'll see some change here
in contrast to the other study that I
mentioned I believe that in this case
the increasing blue Photon fraction will
actually increase yields and the reason
for that is that we've kept the red
constant so what we're looking at rather
than the total fluence at any different
wavelength we're actually looking at the
ratio of one wavelength to another which
I think is the more biologically
significant
factor to look at
um so I'm really excited about this I
think it's going to turn out great and
um this is I don't know and this is just
a photo of that happening right now in
our grow tents you can see on the right
you've got a much Bluer sort of looking
spectrum and on the left you've got this
white red it looks a little bit more
like what an HPS would
um because that's actually more similar
to what an HPS Spectrum actually looks
like
um so yeah in conclusion uh red to far
red seem to have no effect except for
increasing cbga which is interesting
um and although the expression of
constance and ft were changed it had no
impact on yield whatsoever however ft
and Constance have very similar
expression patterns in cannabis as they
do in rice so that's exciting and also
we believe that the increasing blue to
Red ratio is likely to increase yields
but don't quote me on that until I get
my data back because then we'll know for
sure
and uh yeah big thanks to Adaptive grow
Technologies for the lights to Gorilla
Grow for donating these tents to the
greenhouse staff at Uconn and also shout
out to Austin Shep from Rapid genomics
because he hooked me up with these um
Gene candidates for jeans Downstream of
phytochrome
and thanks to canmet this has been
awesome really appreciate the
opportunity