[Music]
welcome to the caned Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I'm the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on the canmed
summit well our canmed Advisory Board is
hard at work reviewing all the great
abstract submissions that we received
for caned 25 our goal is to have all of
our oral presenters selected by the end
of the year and to announce them in
January so stay tuned for those
announcements we are also working on a
number of great workshops that we will
be announcing very soon so if you have
not already sign up for email alerts at
canmen events.com so you don't miss any
of those and other
announcements also if you are planning
to join us at CED 25 next June in Puerto
Rico be sure to purchase your ticket
package today and take advantage of our
discounted early bird rate find more
details at camed events.com
Our Guest today is Dr Nicole go Nicole
is a professor and extension specialist
at the University of Kentucky her
program focuses on disease management of
specialty crops including fruits
vegetables and hemp in her extension
role she develops educational and
Outreach programs to help Growers manage
disease through
identification understanding of patho
systems and integration of management
strategies her research program focuses
on a range of hemp diseases including
fer headlight as well as stand
establishment and Scorn transmission
Nicole's resources can be found at the
University of Kentucky website which
I'll include a link in the show
description so that's it's easy to find
and she's also on Facebook and Twitter
at KY plant disease and on YouTube at
Nicole go Nicole's team at the
University of Kentucky recently
published a fact sheet about ferium in
hemp plants which cut my eye considering
many of the cultivators we work with at
medicinal genomics struggle with that
pathogen during our conversation we
discuss the financial impact of fusarium
on hemp and cannabis crops the public
health concerns due to fusarium
production of harmful mot
toxins how Growers often misidentify
ferum headlight as buritis due to
similar symptoms leading to ineffective
management
strategies Environmental conditions that
increase the likelihood of a fusarium
infection challenges for prevention and
management including a lack of effective
fungicides and resistant
cultivars and future research to better
understand fusarium spread genetic
resistance and management
techniques before we get to my
conversation with Nicole I'd like to
thank this episode sponsor Rare Earth
genomics Rare Earth genomics is a
Dynamic partnership formed with Texas
A&amp;M agrie one of the world's leading
research institutions to accelerate hemp
research and create tools for
Farmers their mission is to increase the
likelihood of a successful Harvest for
Farmers through genetic analysis and
rigorous Environmental Testing of
vigorous
cultivars learn more at rareearth
genomics. okay and without any further
ado please enjoy my conversation with
Nicole
[Music]
go good afternoon Nicole thanks so much
for joining me on the podcast hello how
are you I am great and I'm excited to
talk with you today about the work that
you and your team are doing to better
understand plant pathogens pathogens
affecting hemp plants your team recently
published a fact sheet about fusarium in
hemp plants which we are going to dive
into but I know that's only one of many
pathogens that your team studies so
maybe to start can you provide a brief
overview of the most common diseases
affecting hemp crops and why did you
decide to focus on fusarium this time
okay so um um hemp in in Kentucky most
everywhere is grown Outdoors um
primarily in the field so um in so when
I look at cannabis in general when I
look at hemp or or high THC low THC uh
whether it's floral or grain or Fiber um
we're essentially we essentially have
the same plant right so I look at it
from an outdoor standpoint um what what
pathogens can infect um then we can go
on the flip side and we can look at
indoor cannabis or indoor hemp however
you want to phrase it and an indoor um
environment is going to have its own set
of of pathogens because you have a very
different climate system so in Plant
Pathology uh most of our diseases are
driven by not just the presence of the
pathogen but also the uh the climate
right temperature and
humidity so in um in outdoor uh hemp we
see um stand establishment problems so
we can have pythium root Rod whatever
the nature of the the previous crop or
the history of that field so we can see
a lot of uh Seaborn seedling diseases
like um fusarium crowned root rot which
is not fusarium Wilt um so the fusarium
salon based Fus areia uh we can see a
RIS octonia crown and root rod and we
can also see some pythium root rods that
can affect seeds or seedlings um when we
get into a larger plants everybody knows
the leaf diseases so we have a history
of kind of all those Leaf diseases
that's what interests everyone and Leaf
Disease a septoria leaf spot and thos
circos leaf spot and then the big one
bipolaris leaf spot so those we've been
working on those for many years I've
been working on hemp since
2014 um and then when when we started
seeing this um headlight in Grain hemp
you know there was so much talk about
betrus um betrus grey mold and that was
like always the talk and so everyone was
seeing all of this fuzzy growth inside
of their their either their flower heads
or their seed heads they were just
automatically saying I've got Bettis
I've got Bettis and knowing that
pathogen because it is ubiquitous it
affects many different kinds of plants I
knew it's too hot it's too dry and so we
Dove a little bit deeper and that's when
we realized that we had a very
widespread disease and um not just the
blighting and so blighting is when it
kind of turns brown um not just the
blighting in the disease but also the
potential for mot toxins from those
pathogens so that kind of took us down a
um down a road that um you know we've
done a lot of work we're just starting
to publish that work but uh so yeah
we've been working with fusarium
headlight since about
2017 excellent so was I hearing that
correctly that Growers were
misdiagnosing bet fusarium as Bettis the
danger of the internet that's right the
danger of diagnosing by by symptoms and
pictures um so yeah it was just kind of
this blanket understanding that if it's
fuzzy and white it must be betrus and it
was not in fact I rarely find betrus in
the field um now I'm in I'm in a more um
Southern Climate than you know so we
could definitely see a lot more betrus
in the northern states but we overall
see betrus more in the greenhouse but
any of that fuzzy growth I'm seeing in
Kentucky Midwestern states midatlantic
states and definitely south of me it's
almost exclusively fusarium interesting
and how does that affect how one kind of
tries to manage the disease if it's one
or the
other um well both both of the pathogens
are true fungi so they are fungal
pathogens and overall they need about
the same temperatures and um humidity to
complete their life cycle um but trus
likes very high humidity um so about 85%
relative humidity so it's got to be very
wet but trius um is more of an
opportunity istic pathogen so when it
infects it's infecting it begins on
something like necrotic tissue maybe a a
dying leaf or something like that and so
it's kind of more opportunistic whereas
fusarium is more of a is pathogenic it's
highly pathogenic so it can invade a a
healthy plant versus betrus is more of
that kind of humidity lover and it it
needs a um it needs you to open the door
for it so it can't just like you know
bulldo its way into those plant cells
interesting all right well that's a good
segue um can you describe how ferium
affects hemp plants um how does it
infect and you know what is sort of the
progression okay well let's start with
uh fusarium is a genus and it's a very
large genus with a lot of complexes so
lots of species within a fusarium
complex so most people when they hear
fusarium they think of fusarium Wilt and
that's fusarium oxysporum different um
different special forms but fusarium
oxysporum or fusarium Wilt is a vascular
disease it starts in The Roots it's
allil born it moves its way up the
vascular system and it causes Wilt U
because of just blocking water and
nutrient uptake to the top of the plant
and necrosis of the of the xylem
fusarium headlight is fusarium garum so
that is infecting flowers and grain from
the outside um it's a very very
different pathogen and remember earlier
I talked about fusarium salani a Rootin
Crown Rod so there are three major
fusarium species that affect hemp or
cannabis um but back to fusarium
headlight uh the fusarium headlight
pathogens we have identified five um
fusarium garum is the common one that's
the one that you read so much that
affects um wheat and cereal crops um so
fusarium garum will infect um flowers
and grain we have found it to infect um
growing tips and leaves but primarily
it's going to be a flower and grain
disease interesting so different type
different different species of fusarium
will kind of attack the plant from from
different angles that's right that's
right and to not just say fusarium
because when we started working on
fusarium headlight the Assumption was
that it was the fusarium oxysporum The
fusarium W pathogen and they're very
very different even though that first
name even that though that genus is the
same interesting so what are some of the
economic impacts of fusarium on hemp
cultivation um so fusarium headlight as
we call it will blight out um and and
blight is kind of a rapid necrosis
that's what that kind of term means a
fusarium headlight will blight out a
flower head or a seed head um so uh
early shattering more
brittle more brittle flowers or or grain
heads but we can have it at very low
levels as well um so that's remember I
mentioned mot toxins earlier so um
fusarium garum produces two different
mot toxins so a myotoxin is a toxin
produced by um a fungus um so mot toxins
there are there's a history of myotoxins
in fusarium um species the tresin for
example um that can cause vomiting uh um
digestion issues both in humans and in
animals so in in hemp I'm sorry in uh
any feed it's highly regulated so uh
even low levels of disease can cause
high levels of toxins and that's
something that we're not regulating here
in the US not in h not in cannabis so
everyone is really interested in looking
at
um apoxin or or some of those other um
toxins which we're not finding um but we
are finding those fusarium Moto toxins
from the headlight pathogens so again
all the Fus area out there but that's
our Focus because that's what we're
seeing the most and that's what we feel
is the most important especially as hemp
as an animal feed is coming onto Market
yeah so you you mentioned that ferium
could be there in low levels so might it
sort of Escape some visual detection and
have some of those microt toxins
present I'm going to Spill the Beans a
little bit uh my graduate student just
came in with some year one data from uh
two different fields here in um in
Central Kentucky and he had fusarium
headlight at about 5% severity so think
about that whole seed head and about
visually 5% of that head had symptoms um
so very low something that a grower
would probably Overlook something that I
might have said oh well and he ended up
detecting um Dawn deoxy no valinol uh he
ended up detecting Dawn at levels that
are above the threshold for human
consumption in other grains so of course
we don't have that threshold for him but
that that threshold would I mean that
would have failed um um a QC in a Serial
grain market and so we're finding those
high levels of toxins and and in a year
of drought and extreme heat this year we
had low levels of disease
wow and so that is not being tested now
th those microt toxins aren't being
tested for in in hemp products that is
correct that is correct and so that was
one of our delays in um in releasing
some of our data we wanted to double
check and triple check and quadruple
check because we didn't want to send a
scare in the market we wanted to make
really sure that what uh we were seeing
was a trend and it wasn't just isolated
incidents um so um that is correct we
are not we're looking at a lot of microb
testing in in hemp in some states um it
seems like there's a huge interest in
apoxin right and some of the other
toxins and um we have we just don't have
those regulations in hemp anyway unless
it's at a state level but they're only a
few states that are regulating those
things but they're not talking about uh
fusarium toxins especially not the
tresin wow yeah that was going to be my
question where are those regulations
coming from are at a federal level or
state
level well you know we could do a whole
podcast on on regulations
right some states are are testing and so
we we hope that we can get the data out
that's um that's both going to help the
hemp industry not hurt the hemp industry
but also make sure that we are uh
producing Safe products for our end use
um end consumers which could be animals
or PL or or humans
excellent all right I think we've kind
of set the stage for the stakes um yes
um so what about prevention um what are
the best practices for preventing
fusarium in different growing
environments well that's the
million-dollar question right so um so
what we know about fusarium griin arum
is the most pop is the most common um
species that's causing fusarium
headlight so if I say fusarium gmin arum
that's kind of the big one um so we know
what we know about fusarium garum and
other headlight um producing uh fusaria
we know from wheat and barley and and
and cereals and corn so we we base a lot
of things off of that until we can
generate our own data so in wheat so I'm
going to give you a life cycle because
you know nerdy Pathologists so in wheat
wheat is a cool season crop yarum comes
in it really kind of infects during
anthesis which is when that anther is
kind of Pok out of that wheat flour um
and that's when infection occurs and in
Kentucky for example um that's happening
in May we're harvesting wheat in June
and then we've got a hemp crop that
really is not going in until July in
most cases so by the time hemp starts
flowering and is ultra susceptible to um
to fusarium infection it's July August
so how are we having this TW month or
more um
um division between that that wheat
infection and that hemp infection but we
are and what our research has told us is
that in in fields where there was wheat
or near Wheat we have a lot higher
incidents of um disease and toxin so so
there's a lot more fusarium garum when
there was wheat in the vcinity um and
what we're finding out now is that wheat
cover crops even though they were
terminated before they flowered are
still inducing a much higher amount of
disease so um I don't remember your
question
now what do we do about it um and that's
what we're trying to figure out what are
all the roles where is it coming from uh
what we do know about fusarium again
from the the serial grains uh research
is that those spores those canidia can
get really high up into the atmosphere
and they can move very long distances so
no one's safe right no Greenhouse is
safe if you've got a vent but the closer
we are that proximity to any wheat or
any other um any other um host plant uh
seems to be um really inducing a higher
level of
disease now is there any sort of um
sprays or bioagents that can be applied
to kind of prevent an
infection so right now so I'm G back up
just a little bit right now we don't
have any conventional fungicides or
pesticides labeled for for hemp um and
we definitely don't for um high THC um
cannabis so we don't have any products
anyway um in terms of Organics we've
been looking at a lot of Biologicals and
right now we're not finding anything
that is that is effective uh we have a
few years of field studies um and we're
we're trying lots of things we're
throwing a lot of things to see what
sticks and we just don't think we're
getting anything right now
interesting okay um so one of my
questions here how does it spread
between plants but it sounds like it's
Airborne Airborne yeah so these are
these are spores that can move um long
distances and I mean think about when
when disease spreads anyway right when
those spores spread it's usually wind
wind driven
rain so if you kind of think about and
we can look at so kind of overlaying
weather data with some of our sport
trapping data we can see that uh when
there's a rain event
that's what we'll see spikes in disease
um and you know that that's really
making a difference and you know a
drought year a calm year we can have a
lot lower disease but when we have a lot
more rain we can have a lot more disease
because remember fungi need at least 70%
relative humidity they need Leaf wetness
and they need moderate temperatures so
things cool down when it gets cloudy so
even though it's hot and dry in the
middle of the summer if we got a couple
of cloudy rainy days or even drizzly
it's
enough yeah that goes back to what you
were talking about earlier of indoor
versus outdoor um so the in an indoor
environment these are sort of um
conditions that you can control for or
you're not susceptible to the weather
yes yes that's right but greenh houses
are a lot or indoor environments rather
I'll just kind of lump those together
indoor environments are a lot more humid
right because we're not exchanging that
air uh the more we exchange air the more
we let things in we have identified
fusarium um headlight in green houses
we've identified it in Flowers By the
way for those of you who are growing
only to flower we have identified it
there and um we also know that it can be
seedborn that's a beginning of a it's
the beginning of a new research um
trajectory but uh we know that it can be
Seaborn now we're we're testing
commercial seed Lots we have not found
it in commercial seed Lots but coming
from harvested grain our plots we are
finding it so we're kind of we're kind
of at a Crossroads there um it'll be a
few years before we have that data
interesting okay
so identification so what are some of
the telltale signs of buium in hemp and
are there early detection um tools
available um right now there no tools
available but um a really nice hand lens
or a cheap hand lens or a magnifying
glass if that's what you've got
um and so to look inside that inside
that head and I'm just going to use the
word head in general for flowers or
grain looking inside kind of looking at
that stem looking at that rikus in there
and that's where it's going to start so
the more dense the seed head the more um
the more humid it is in there so if you
kind of separate out those flowers or
those um it usually starts when during
flowering so if you kind of separate out
those flowers just kind of pull it apart
and you can kind of see that fuzzy white
growth in there and that's really that's
how we look for it um now to identify
which species it is those kinds of
things it's always got to come back to
the lab it's always got to go under a
microscope but you can see that those
fuzzy seed headit uh those this fuzzy
growth that Melia in there but you're
GNA have to pull that U those flowers
apart and look inside between those
racings okay and then what do you do
after that you've you've identified it
oh this this plant has cerium what's
sort of the the next steps
we're research so we're trying to kill
our plants um so so our next steps are
very different if it's a grower I mean
unfortunately we're at a place where we
there's nothing that we can do right we
we don't have a recommendation we don't
have resistant cultivars um now we we're
looking at cultivars right and we're
kind of realizing that some are more
susceptible than others but um but
really if I'm working with the grower
we're talking about next year what do we
do next year we're making sure that uh
we don't have a cereal crop in the
vicinity and we're definitely saying not
to not to rotate with a susceptible crop
and not to use a a seral uh cover crop
and that's something very new because we
thought okay you know we're burning it
down and we're we're crimping it down
long before flowering and that's not
enough because that infection is present
even if it hasn't sort of emerged in the
flowers
it's there yes it's there now we have a
lot more we have a lot more research to
do in that in that vein I want to
mention before I forget um we did a
two-year study to look at Laten
infection so a Laten infection is that
dormant infection that time between
infection and symptom development and we
were looking at floral hemp um so we
weren't going to grain stage and so we
planted hemp every two weeks from April
until I think September
and then we sampled every week um so in
in theory we had we had every growth
stage at every week through the season
um and we looked at weather data we
looked at growth stage and so what we
found is that uh we can we are detecting
latent
infection six weeks or more before
symptom development we're detecting it
long before uh flower initiation so
we're finding it very early in the
season I think as early as May um for
those early planted um early planted uh
hemp so remember that was the same time
that wheat was in the field not in our
plots but in fields um so and to overl
weather data what we're finding out is
hemp does come become more susceptible
as it gets older um as it reaches
maturity and as it starts to produce th
it enters those reproductive phases but
also to layer those rainy events um
that's when we see huge spikes of of uh
fungal DNA within those plants so we're
were looking at the the DNA in latent
infections so the moral of that story is
it doesn't matter when it is um there
are times where it's more susceptible we
have more um infection and pathogen um
DNA in that plant which ultimately
becomes diseased um but anytime
infection can happen anytime and that's
really scary because um in a lot of your
cereals that you know they're always
targeting that anthesis uh when those
anthers start protruding but with hemp
it looks like latent infection is a lot
more common than we expected and so
that's going to take a lot of rethinking
on what a recommendation would look like
okay and so when those symptoms at what
stage in the plants development do those
symptoms tend to emerge is it during
sort of flowering reproductive stage yes
so um so it symptoms so disease is what
we call symptoms right so Laten so
infection is when we can detect the DNA
inside is that with qpcr yes with qpcr
excellent um and anybody listening
that's quantitative PCR it can detect
really low levels of DNA from plant
tissue whatever tissue we choose and in
that case it was leaves growing tips uh
male Flowers By the way can become
infected
and U female flowers
but um what was your question um I'm so
sorry I forgot your question no I think
we were talking about the latent um
identifying a latent infection um so I
can just I can just skip to the next
question so okay I'm sorry no that's
quite all right I went off on a tangent
I mean I think just for the purpose oh
now I remember what we were talking
about um when do the symptoms emerge at
what stage of development of the plant
and I think we we said it was during
sort of the reproductive stage so later
the later you go into the reproductive
stages of course induced by a rain event
but the heavier and more dense that uh
that seed head or flower head is the
more moisture it's holding um I think
there's a lot more symptoms in Grain um
so there must be something physiological
in there and of course I don't have any
data to back that up it's just
observational um but definitely the
bigger and denser and heavier it is at a
rainy event and or like you know when it
starts cooling off late in the summer
and you kind of get those foggy dewy
mornings that's kind of the same thing
right so add moisture and it it really
it really gets worse so the longer you
go into the season in general yeah I
think any of us in the Northeast who
have tried to grow hemper cannabis um
experience that once the fall Hits when
you have those dense um dense flowers
and those cool mornings cool wet
mornings that's when uh the fuzz starts
to come out so so yes going back to the
latent infection um
are can a plant with a latent infection
infect another plant or are they not um
infectious that technically that answer
is no so infection occurs when a Spore
uh Canadia which is an asexual Spore so
when a Spore moves so disease has to
develop the fungus has to sporulate and
release that Spore and that Spore land
on another plant and when that Spore
lands on the other plant they must have
moderate temperatures and free water in
order for that infection to occur so um
a latent infection plant know but what
we're finding is that if there is latent
infection it means there was a Spore
deposition event in some at some point
so we usually have widespread so maybe
one latent infection plant ends up
having disease symptoms in two weeks and
another one might develop symptoms in
four weeks so we don't know um we don't
know what connections are we have not
tracked individual spores we have not
tracked
movement okay yeah and you you touched
on before genetic resistance and that
there are no uh resistant genetics out
there right now but um are there certain
strains or certain physical
characteristics of the plant that can
make them less susceptible to uh an
infection so we um we we're accumulating
data so I am U part of a multi-state
group that that plants the same group of
um cultivars across many states and so
we have tap my working group has tapped
into that whole network so we're going
to start trying to uh understand which
of those cultivars these are hemp
cultivars by the way uh which of those
cultivars are more susceptible but what
we have found anecdotally uh over and
over is that the more uh heavy and dense
a seed head is the more disease you'll
have and you know you've always got
those Bly ones with that spacing in
between the the ray seams um there must
be more air circulation going there and
not having that humidity that's our
guess um so bigger chunkier seed heads
um are definitely going to have a lot
more disease than the more sply ones and
I would imagine it' be the same for for
flower as well exactly yeah um so and
and I mean that again that kind of goes
back to those principles of Plant
Pathology that free water that um
indirect you know Sun not being able to
penetrate and of course with a flower
flowers are um are wet and sticky uh
whereas when you get to the later season
with the with seed I mean they're
they're dry and crispy so that infection
event probably taking place when you've
got that higher moisture interesting
okay all right so I guess looking
forward here
um what are your sort of your next steps
or projects that you're working on to to
better understand this so um one of my
graduate students it has transformed um
the fungus with uh green fluorescent
protein so he is going to track
infection we're looking at seeds so
we're looking to see whether an infected
seed can actually carry uh the pathogen
and it if it can move its way up so
those are a couple of the things that
we're doing and we're we're looking for
connections and and better
identification of uh Dawn the mot toxin
um and it's especially hard in flowers
because you've got all those red that
affect the protocols um we're looking at
other mot toxins as well so we've
completed some surveys those kinds of
things um we would like to look more
into the animal feed Market because it
seems like that's where you're going to
have that bulk of um of of hemp product
they could really be taking some of this
fusarium um far and wide and have
probably the most effect so those are
kind of our big our big projects in the
future we're continuing a lot of our
field studies the for trapping those
types of things um we have looked at uh
we've done some genetic analyses on the
fusarium that's infecting hemp and it is
the same one that's affecting wheat so
we know that those populations are the
same um so so that's our immediate um
look forward um there are a lot more
questions right what happens if you're
using spent hemp like after the oil's
been pressed uh from flowers so if you
using byproducts to make animal feed you
know do you have that movement of those
uh mot toxins from there what does what
does stored hemp look like we've done
some stored hemp studies what is stored
hemp look like um and what is that
timing right so once you dry down um
those seeds or those flowers for to a
certain degree right less than you know
15 or 10% um moisture do you stop that
Dawn U toxin production because that's
what's happening in wheat so can we dry
it down more quickly and stop that and
production so lots of questions a
million questions and um we're trying to
prioritize um I'm an extension Professor
so my my questions connect directly to
Growers um so always trying to solve
those grower problems first and then
doing the fun curiosity science in
between excellent all right well winding
down here um Nicole please share any
other links or um studies or resources
um that you think would be helpful to
the listeners I'm happy to put the links
right in the show description so people
can easily find them okay definitely
will we have some new Publications in
the pipeline right now so check back on
some of these resources and these uh
links that I'm going to send and that
way you'll be able to see kind of as we
move
forward all right Nicole all right
thanks again for for taking the time to
talk to us about ferium and hemp
diseases and um absolutely I look
forward to doing this again fun thanks a
lot good to see you all right bye
[Music]