foreign
[Music]
Coffee Talk podcast where we talk with
the leading Minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I'm your host Ben amaralt I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the can Med team
my guest today is Dr Hunter land
Hunter is the vice president of research
and development at biopharmaceutical
research company one of the few DEA
schedule 1 FDA compliant cannabinoid
research and development companies
he has 20 years of r d expertise across
25 different indications as well as 12
years of cannabinoid Focus research
most notably
he was GW Farmer's first full-time r d
employee in the U.S where he played a
critical role in the development of
epidialax and sativx and co-authored
multiple protocols for the treatment of
refractory epilepsy multiple sclerosis
and pain
I came at 23 Hunter's presentation was
titled effect of cannabinoids and canned
flavins on neurodegeneration lifespan
and health span which is the basis of
our conversation today
you can find a link to that presentation
video in the show description
topics will be discussed include
defining lifespan Health span and
Longevity why C elegans are good
organisms for studying toxicity and
longevity
the Entourage effect more specifically
whether a combination of compounds has a
greater effect on longevity than single
compounds
how cannabis compounds compare to other
longevity drugs like metformin and
Resveratrol
weather cannabis compounds could be used
prophylactically for conditions like
Alzheimer's and Dementia
determining the ideal dosing range for
cannabinoids and finally whether CBD and
CBG could or should be incorporated into
a healthy lifestyle to improve longevity
before we get to my conversation with
Hunter I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor trulieve
trulieve strives to bring you the relief
that you need in a product that you can
trust
their plants are hand grown in a
facility with a controlled environment
specifically designed to reduce unwanted
chemicals in pests keeping the process
as natural as possible at every turn
their mission is to provide
Compassionate Care patients can trust
when traditional medicine is not enough
there are specially trained staff Works
hand in hand with your physician to
provide the right products at the
correct dosage to ensure you get the
Compassionate Care you need
to learn more visit trulief.com
and without any further Ado please enjoy
my conversation with Hunter land
[Music]
good morning Hunter thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast thanks for
having me Ben
right well I'm excited to talk with you
today about the potential for cannabis
compounds to enhance Health span and
lifespan but before we discuss the
research that your team's done I think
it's important that we Define those
terms for the audience so please uh if
you could please do sure there's some I
would say important intricacies uh the
difference between lifespan and um and
Longevity right so this is longevity is
a hot topic now uh lifestan span as you
would expect you know typically refers
to the length of life within a species
and when we talk about longevity it's
really focused on who exceeds that kind
of mean lifespan throughout that uh in
that specific species and obviously
that's a goal of many people
um because you know longer healthier
lives is something that most of us try
to achieve hellspan on the other end is
a measure of
activity and more around quality of life
so
um you may be able to extend life or
some people may live longer but actually
have very poor quality of life you know
what's what's the point of living longer
if it's
um if it's uh you know riddled with
hospitalizations and lack of activity so
that that could be a problem
great so what made you interested in
investigating how cannabis can affect
longevity well this actually started out
with the conversation with the FDA
because you know with uh with the
legalization of CBD or the removal from
the controlled substance act the FDA had
a lot of concerns with you know what
happens if you take CBD for an extended
period of time so 20 years 30 years is
something going to pop up down the road
that could be detrimental and um you
know it's obviously very difficult to do
those studies in humans and it's even
difficult to do them in rodents it's
very expensive it takes a you know
extended period of time maybe three five
years to look at at lifespan depending
on that specific species one of the I
would say best pre-clinical whole
organism models is the C elegans model
it's kind of like the canary and the
coal mine model
the EPA likes this for toxicity so for
example if there was potentially
contaminated water
if they don't know what they're testing
for it's difficult to determine you know
what the problem is and if it's really a
danger so they may use C elegans and if
they die early then you probably want to
stay away from the that particular water
it's also been used
um in the International Space Station by
NASA so you know what's the EXP what's
the the you know what happens when
you're at space for an extended period
of time we don't really know what that
means for humans but we can look at
other animal models so that was really
the the start of this work was hey is
this toxic and at what level would it be
toxic and how does that you know affect
um you know the life of these in this
particular model
interestingly enough what we found is it
wasn't really that toxic uh until you
went to Super physiological amounts and
still wasn't you know overtly toxic
um but then we started seeing this you
know increase in lifespan and health
span uh we also ran that model with
canaba Gerald a lesser-known cannabinoid
and we saw similar similar effects so
both appeared non-toxic and
physiologically relevant amounts and uh
extended lifespan and activity levels
during that life so
um you know rather as it would now again
this is a model but as it would apply to
humans it would be akin to you know a 80
year old acting more like a 60 year old
in terms of health span measures so not
only did they live longer they were more
active through that late stage of their
life
so the benefits of Health span and
lifespan it sounds like it was sort of
just a happy coincidence like you were
originally looking at the toxicity but
then observed um this positive effect
sure we we wanted you know we obviously
wanted to to find out you know how safe
the compounds were were but obviously
when you when you find out that there's
a potentially larger more profound
benefit then that's uh and that's
something it's certainly important and
relevant
um
for us within the cannabinoid industry
great and so prior to to this work had
any research been done into cannabis and
Longevity and if so what kind of makes
this research unique not not to my
knowledge
um I think this was the first you know
uh full duration lifespan model there
have since been several other repeats
where you see similar lifespan extension
some diving down into potential
mechanisms and and you know we took
those data you know following these
studies and said hey well if this could
help you know General longevity what
does it then do in a disease model right
so then could we apply this to something
like Alzheimer's Dementia or does this
have broader applications to different
disease States like traumatic brain
injury epilepsy those sorts of things
excellent and so
yeah I want to talk a little bit more
about Ciel against or they're also
called nematodes correct yeah they're
they're in nematode and so they have an
endocannabinoid system
uh they have something very Akin I would
say akin to the endocannabinoid system
but which I would say would probably be
less relevant for a compound like CBD or
cannabijerol because uh the primary
function is not through endocannabinoid
system you know there are some data
suggesting that CBD may be in negative
allosteric modulator but
um in humans it doesn't seem to it
doesn't seem to some of the recent data
presented in the last month or so CBD
may actually have like a pkpd
interaction with THC and and boost
exposure so it doesn't seem that CBD the
effect that CB1 is enough to really
bring down the effect of of THC so if it
does work on the endocannabinoid system
I would say that's probably a minor
contribution to its effects
okay and so and I think you already you
said this too but just so I want to make
sure I understand it correctly too that
you know
the C elegans in these nematodes it's
easier to study lifespan and then
because their lifespan is so short right
right
six seven days 20 days you know so you
can run a lot of different compounds
in an inexpensive model so if you wanted
to look at many combinations of
cannabinoids many different cannabinoids
or like more recently we looked at uh
can flavins you can do that kind of in
parallel within the same model
um and kind of get this determination of
which compound is most likely to win or
at least have a better chance to win and
and hopefully be less toxic
yeah and I wanted to talk about that too
because in your presentation you talk
about sort of this initial research that
you did with CBD and CBG on sort of the
the wild type c elegans
um and saw the benefit and then sort of
as you mentioned did that secondary
experiment on the the towel model to
kind of see how it could help with with
diseases
um and what I thought was interesting
about that one is that you weren't just
looking at isolates there of like single
compounds but you also looked at sort of
whole plant formulations and then with
canned flavins too so kind of um explain
how that one different from from the
first experiment you did well well sure
I mean there's I think for years now
there's been this interest in you know
rational polypharmacy as it applies to
cannabinoids or the Entourage effect and
and I've done quite a bit of work uh
thanks to my mentor ether Ethan Russo
years ago it certainly had a lot of
interest in this area and you know
sometimes we see an Entourage effect and
sometimes we see what I call like a
non-terrage effect and I think this is
most profound in interocular pressure
models where you see reduction and
interocular pressure with THC but if you
had CBD it it basically prevents that
effect that reduction in their ocular
pressure
so I think that's just one example of of
how you could see Synergy or or
something you know the opposite of
synergy right and um so so this
particular model the Tau model we really
wanted to dive in and see you know are
we seeing this additive or super
additive effect with a complex Botanical
mixture with known components
um we the primary components in this
Botanical mixture were THC CBG and
um CBD so and we pegged everything at
the CBD level so we you know based on
the previous model we use CBD as a
positive control
as we know it extended lifespan and wild
type we didn't know how it affected the
talusi elegans not many things are are
really that effective at increasing
survival rate and these you know highly
Affiliated nematodes uh so we did you
know kind of our best guess and then we
could use that to compare to both canned
flavins and these Botanical mixtures
again all pegged at that same CBD level
so
um
that led us to some pretty interesting
results where we do see you know this
profound effect with these Botanical
drug substances versus
um versus just the CBD alone
right so score one for the Entourage
effect
in this particular model in this
situation with these cannabinoids I
would say yeah I think that's a
clearly shows there is synergy or an
Entourage effect you know if you change
this ratio or use different cannabinoids
you know I think it's important to be
specific to you know Entourage isn't
necessarily like oh it's a mystery suit
but it came from a plant well you know
what components are there I mean if I
would have put CBN or CBE or some other
cannabinoid in there I've I have no idea
if that would have helped further if it
would have hindered some of these
results and when we you know we really
didn't see with the canned flavins so in
the second study you know CBDs showed
about a 10 survival rate versus four in
the wild type at day 16.
um and cam flavum was better than that
at day 14 it was about 14 or day 16 it
was about 14 percent
so you know we would hope that it would
have an added of a further additive
effect when you added it to the
Botanical drug substance but there was
really no there was no negative but
there wasn't much of an Entourage maybe
a little bit of improvement
um but not even to the point where you
know it's typically you would think of
additive as one plus one equals two in
terms of you know I'm taking a
medication for let's say pain and you've
got two different components they both
work on their own you add them together
one plus one equals two super additive
would be one plus one equals four
and that's what you would hope for and
that's what we saw with the Botanical
drug substance but we didn't see that
when we added in the can flap and so it
was somewhat better but not you know we
didn't go from 25 survival to 40
survival
great but there may be limits to how far
you can push this this kind of Entourage
effect
right and so this Botanical drug
formulation now is that a whole plant
extract or is that just combining
different isolates into like a
formulation so under the Botanical drug
guidance you can essentially blend to a
specification
um from extracts and that's kind of
that's probably the best way to keep
things consistent that's what we did
with satavex at GW so it was a high THC
came of war and a high CBD team of war
that were you know climate controlled
and consistent but then you blend to a
certain specification so you always have
that particular ratio and essentially
that's what we did here is we use
different extracts to blend to a
specific ratio and then we also use the
camflaven extract to blend into to this
for this particular study yeah because
the reason I ask is if it's you know
sort of a a whole plant extract is there
the possibility too that there is a
minor cannabinoid or some other minor
compound that's kind of doing some heavy
lifting that we're just not seeing could
absolutely uh absolutely be there I
don't know exactly what it would be and
and again with every plant being so
different you know you'd love to find
this you know highly potent Miracle
molecule that's in there
um which may or may not exist but um it
would have been interesting to run it
with you know three isolates in that
same ratio and see if we get you know
this difference because of these minor
components there have been a couple
studies that suggest that the the
mixtures may increase bioavailability a
bit and that may be because some of
these other compounds are inhibiting sip
enzymes so there could be
it could be you know direct receptor
interaction or it could be you know
pharmacokinetic interaction that may add
to the benefit of a Botanical drug
substance
so how do these results compare to other
drugs or compounds that have been
studied for this application
there really haven't been many in the
Tau model we see this is fairly the the
early studies with CBD and CBG are
fairly consistent
um maybe not quite as beneficial as
metformin
um for those of you know who don't know
that Foreman's a drug commonly uh
prescribed for metabolic syndromes like
type 2 diabetes but there's um there's a
thought that it makes in life and
there's a couple different ways it may
do that but one of the ways is through
this methionine and folate synthesis so
it seems to inhibit those two compounds
which apparently is important for Life
Extension ironically those are two known
or at least methionine synthesis and
folate one carbon metabolism are two
mechanisms known for CBD so there may be
a mechanistic overlap with metformin and
again both compounds extended Life
resveratrol is another compound it's a a
solenoid so it has some similar
components as cannabinoids in terms of
like uh the the terpene structure within
that compound I'm also seen to extend
life
not as applicable in humans because of
metabolism in the gut so that's
something you know we have to be careful
with these models just because it
extends life in Clans you know what
happens when you put it in a system like
humans what happens with metabolism in
the gut
um and bioavailability so all critical
considerations to take into account but
generally speaking it looks as good as
many of the other compounds that we
think May extend life at least in this
model
excellent and so
so what is the next step I mean if you
start with c elegans um do you kind of
move up the chain of complexity there
and kind of test it well we could
certainly look at different uh compounds
but I think you know different
combinations and and different models of
C elegans but um given that Tau appears
to be you know a piece of the underlying
etiology of many different diseases
it may be important to look at some of
these so for example example maybe an
Alzheimer's dementia maybe you look at
rodent models for human models because
we saw some effect here maybe in maybe
this is one of the underlying mechanisms
for uh traumatic brain injury or stroke
or you know a number of other things
even cancer seems to have this
towel seems to be important and you know
having these Tau Tangles seem to affect
cellular energetics and Longevity on the
cellular level so preventing those or
acting as a protectant could be critical
in a variety of disease States
yeah and I guess that brings up a good
point too so
are we are we saying that these
compounds would be beneficial in
preventing these diseases from occurring
or treating them in folks that already
have them
or both no I think that's an excellent
point the truth is we don't know
obviously prevention would be ideal
although you know generally speaking our
our Health Care Systems not entirely
focused on prevention
um but what we could potentially do is
prevent worsening right if you let's say
it does let's say we do find out that it
is genuinely protective and helpful in
something like Alzheimer's
um you know can we give it early onset
you know what about other conditions
like Ms or Parkinson's that you know you
have this neurodegenerative kind of
disease can we give it early and prevent
uh progression which which again would
be the
the you know certainly beneficial to
that population and maybe not a cure but
uh you know it could it could help until
something else is potentially better
that that is a cure arrives
yet another thing that you had mentioned
too is that sort of the results you were
seeing was equivalent to like an 80 year
old human feeling like a 60 year old so
early before you are 80 or can an 80
year old um
you know even how well that would would
translate you know we're not really sure
but um you know based on the data it
would seem that taking for a period of
time probably similar to exercising your
whole life or dieting your whole life
may be of benefit to what degree that
benefit exists in humans I think is is
unknown but um it's interesting
nonetheless and it must be so difficult
to to determine that in a human too
because there's just so many different
factors that go with variables you know
these epidemiological studies around
diet and vitamins and nutrition just
incredibly difficult to do so many
compounding factors that make that data
very difficult to determine but um I
think the key point for the early
studies is that it doesn't appear to be
overtly toxic at these levels uh there
we do know in humans that there are some
potential dangers around liver toxicity
with high doses of CBD especially with
certain drugs like valproic acid which
is also known a known liver toxin so you
know I wouldn't say that you know high
doses for you know your whole life are
safe there could be some complications
there but
um at low Doses and medium doses it
doesn't appear to be a problem based on
exclusively on this model but that's a
you know it's a big leap to say the the
same for humans but so far so good if it
looked toxic then there would be a lot
more alarm Bells I know it is difficult
to make that leap even though I I keep
trying to make you I keep trying to make
you do it
um and and looking at the results and we
you talked about dosing it seemed like
there was sort of a sweet spot range for
the dose that really got the best effect
it wasn't necessarily the highest dose
they got the best effect so I was
wondering if you could speak a bit to
that sure I mean this is we saw it
across both studies and Botanical drug
extract and in isolate and towel model
and not towel model and then it's uh
it's not really surprising because we do
expect just about everything at a
certain level to have toxicity
um and and what we see actually CBG
appears to be less toxic in this model
than CBD milligram per milligram
um but but again you know you can
there's an ld50 for water so
um as you go up eventually something's
going to get toxic but I would also say
in terms of efficacy but this is
it's been a theory for some time about
this kind of inverted you or kind of
biphasic effects with cannabinoids I
think they're more profound with THC I
think there's a you know a narrow dose
window for THC uh we know that you know
low amounts uh or moderate amounts
increase appetite they may help with
anxiety they may help with sleep but
when you start giving really high doses
of THC you get massive paranoia nausea
and vomiting I mean it's not pretty
there are a bunch of hospitalizations
for people that you know didn't know how
much was in their brownie so you you
know as with
um these sorts of of physiological
effects you may see the same thing in
lifespan taking too much may be a
hindrance
um or or maybe neutral in terms of being
a benefit we still don't know kind of
where that sweet spot would be
especially as it relates to CBD and CBG
in humans
okay so can't necessarily apply the
dosage that was effective in C elegans
to humans like is there like a
conversion there that you could take
with in terms of what the dose would be
yeah there is a conversion um it's kind
of complicated how you do it in C
elegans there's two ways you could
actually look at the exposure you could
spin them down and look at their
exposure or you could use it as a
correlate with with other compounds that
have similar
lipophilicity so
um it is complicated but that 40
nanograms per ml or 40 nanograms of 40
micro molar excuse me
um is it's certainly a physiologically
relevant amount and not the same as you
know if if I was doing work in a dish
right because
they're basically eating the medium so
that's concentration and the their food
essentially so
um not necessarily their exposure on the
cell level so when you see you know
cancer studies oftentimes we're applying
that and that would be the cell exposure
this is kind of the food exposure which
is relevant to their internal exposure
after metabolism
okay and
apologize if you already answered this
question but
um so what do we think is going on here
like what mechanism is being applied to
kind of improve the health span and
lifespan of these C elegans do we really
know that yet or I don't I don't think
we know I mean there's you know CBD and
CBG are are let's say promiscuous
molecules in terms of uh mechanism
unlike a lot of new chemical entities
and synthesized drugs they're not really
you know designed to work on one
receptor type they're not highly
selective for one thing I mean we know
that CBD has at least 68 known targets
um and none of them are really potent
um THC is certainly more clear that it
works primarily as a partial Agonist at
CB1 but also has some other quote
unquote off-target effects know even
less about CBG I think it's difficult to
to determine it may be relevant to
Cellular energetics or mitochondria we
know there's some Focus potential
mechanisms there there's nucleotide
receptors that may be important for
transcription translation so truth is we
don't know there's tons of possibilities
so many that are are countless I could
probably spend the rest of my life
trying to determine which combination of
you know 100 different mechanisms right
or contributing
um but something's going on and you know
how can we apply it to potentially make
a medicine to help people is uh it would
be great to know that's the I think
that's the next step right well good job
security you got plenty of things to
investigate probably work on this the
rest of my life and might who knows
excellent all right
um so I'm gonna I'm gonna do it again
and I'm sorry but what is so
I'm gonna I'm an otherwise healthy
person I I exercise I eat right I try to
take my vitamins and things like that so
can I should I
um incorporate CBD CBG into my routine
to potentially help uh my lifespan and
health span is it too early to tell or I
think it's I think it's still too early
I mean you certainly could do that I
things I would watch out for things like
drug drug interactions and you know
certain people with certain conditions
it may not be right for that individual
um and then also just knowing where to
get a quality thing that is labeled
appropriately also it can be expensive I
mean this is
um kind of diverging a little bit from
this conversation but these are fairly
High milligram Doses and and humans so
you know taking 10 milligrams of CBD in
a gummy
um may not be doing much if anything and
if you're willing to spend on you know
100 milligrams or hundreds of milligrams
per day it can get expensive I mean that
could be you know three four hundred
dollars a month and um then where do you
get it you know which company is the
most reputable that has CBD and CBG and
you know an idealistic ratio for for
health and I think that remains to be a
kind of industry-wide problem
wow is that is that the dosing level
that we're talking about here like
Uptown to hundreds of milligrams wow
yeah so not but who knows I mean we did
see effects at lower doses but um and
but yes it's probably not just 25
milligrams a day of CBD could be but um
you know we don't we don't really know
interesting all right well I'll hold off
then
maybe advisable maybe if nothing else
it'll probably save you some money
excellent all right Hunter Before I Let
You Go I want to give you a chance to
share any other resources um that might
be out there that folks could read up on
if they're interested in learning more
about this topic and uh then please also
plug any any ways that people can get in
touch with you and learn more about the
work that you're doing
um well unfortunately there aren't a lot
of resources in this area other than
maybe PubMed or Google Scholar we're
working to make more resources and you
know publish these data and we'll see
how it gets out to the general public
certainly you could attend can Med next
year and maybe there'll be some more
great presentations on these topics and
um we'll just keep going and if there
are any questions
um I'm on LinkedIn pretty easy to find
there aren't too many Hunter lands out
there so feel free to reach out there
and and uh and we'll keep you posted on
uh we should have some more data next
year
excellent will we look forward to that
data and I will make sure to put a link
to your presentation at canva 23 this
year in the show description so people
can check that out great thanks so much
ben all right Hunter thanks again and
we'll see you uh we'll see you down in
Canada next year okay great thank you
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Hunter land check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode's sponsor true leaf our
next episode drops July 19th that's two
weeks from today
in the meantime I invite you to check
out cannedevents.com and all the
resources that we have available there
most notably our kmed archive a
searchable database of all the video
recordings of the presentations that
have been delivered at our Canada events
there you can also sign up for email
alerts so you can be among the first to
get the news when we announce our plans
for Kim at 24.
we also hope you'll join us on social
media we're on Instagram Twitter
LinkedIn and Facebook just search for
cambed events
and also if you're on social media
please join our can Med community group
on Facebook there you can connect with
other members of the canned Community
share relevant links videos memes really
anything can Med in cannabis related
all right that's it from us stay safe
stay healthy and be sure to join us for
the next can ED Coffee Talk
thank you
[Music]