[Music]
Welcome to the Canad Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science, medicine, cultivation,
and safety testing. I am your host, Ben
Amaralt. I am the senior marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
CANMED summit. Well, we are getting
closer and closer to CANMED 25, which is
taking place at the Windham Resort in
Puerto Rico June 17th through the 20th.
If you are planning to join us in Puerto
Rico this June, don't wait to register.
Our room block at the resort is filling
up fast and you don't want to miss out
on this year's event. If you're still on
the fence, I invite you to go to
cammedvents.com and check out our
speaker lineup, our schedule, and our
unique networking events designed to
connect you with the leaders who are
shaping the industry. We really do have
something for everyone at CAMED2 this
year. We have the medical practicum
where doctors and nurses can earn up to
six continuing education credits. We
have the cannabis genomics workshop
featuring more than a dozen of the
world's leading experts on plant
genomics, breeding, and pathogen
resistance. We have a lab compliance
workshop covering lab shopping,
remediation, and other hot topics. And
we also have 20 curated oral
presentations from the top researchers
in cannabis science, medicine,
cultivation, and lab testing, and so
much more. And the great part about
CANMET is that all of these people from
the different areas of the industry come
together with the goal to advance
cannabis medicine and the industry as a
whole. And we really hope that you'll
join us this
year. And since you are a podcast
listener or watcher, we do have a
special offer for you. I have a promo
code that you can use to get $300 off
your ticket
package. That promo code is coffee talk.
All one word. If you put that in the
promo code box, when you buy your full
summit package, you will get $300 off.
So don't wait. Pause this episode. Use
the link in the description to go
register. Pop in the promo code, get
your discount, and get ready to join us
at
KMED2. Our guest today is Dr. Zamir
Punja. Zamir is a professor of plant
biotechnology at Simon Frasier
University in Canada. His research
interests include the edeology and
management of plant diseases on
vegetable and horicultural crops and the
application of plant biotechnology for
disease management. Since 2018, his work
has shifted to researching cannabis,
where his group has described a range of
previously unreported pathogens
affecting the crop and has evaluated
various methods for disease
management. Using next generation
sequencing, his team identified diverse
fungi, yeast, and bacteria across
multiple plant tissues. Their study
reveals that cannabis plants host
abundant microbial endoites which can
impact plant health and product quality.
Findings also highlight the influence of
growing substrates and biocrol agents on
the cannabis
microbiome. During our conversation, we
discuss what is the microbiome and how
do microbial endes affect plant health?
Identification of common microbes found
in cannabis samples including penicyium
and
fuserium. Whether merist stem tissue
culture is a viable microbial
sterilization
method. The influence of sterilized
versus non-sterilized growing
media. How growers can use microbiome
analysis for early interventions.
future research questions on microbial
balance and seed microbiome engineering
and
more. Before we get to my conversation
with Samir, I'd like to thank this
episode sponsor, Grow
Defender. Grow Defender provides
long-asting antimicrobial protection for
indoor cultivation and processing spaces
using patented gold shield technology.
Their EPA registered water-based
products protect surfaces from mold,
mildew, bacteria, and fungi for up to 90
days. For more information, visit
growdefender.com. Okay. And without any
further ado, please enjoy my
conversation with Dr. Zamir Punja.
[Music]
Good afternoon, Zamir. Thank you so much
for joining us on the podcast. Hi.
Thanks, man. Thanks for having me on
here. Glad to be here. Of course. Uh
it's great to have you back on the
podcast. You're one of our favorite
guests and favorite CANMED presenters.
You always have great information about
plant pathogens and plant health. And
you know, I don't know if I've told you
this before, but your KMED22
presentation on cannabis tricoms is the
most watched video on our YouTube page.
It has more than 300,000 views. That's
incredible. I mean I mean I know when I
was getting ready for it presenting it,
I had kind of goosebumps because some of
the images that we had presented were
just incredible. And so I'm I'm really
glad that people are catching on to look
at these fascinating um structures that
obviously contain all the canabonoids
and and tarpen and so on. So that's
good. That's good news. Yeah,
absolutely. It's a visual medium and
those those images are amazing. Um so
K25, we're happy to have you back. um
your presentation this year is going to
be about the cannabis microbiome and
specifically microbial endoes and how
they affect plant health. But first, for
those who may be unfamiliar with those
terms, I guess my first question is can
you briefly explain what the microbiome
is and how it affects plant health?
Yeah. So I mean that you know the
microbiome was a term that was coined um
a long time ago for human health because
as you know we have microbes in our gut
and elsewhere and those microbes
interact with various aspects of our
body and and and some physicians feel
that um that composition of microbes has
various implications for for health not
just physical health but in some cases
even your mood swings and and various
other things. So there's a complex
interaction with microbial organisms uh
within human human guts and so that's
carried on to plants. I mean plants
surprisingly or unsurprisingly also have
a collection of microbes that they seem
to interact with um quite a bit and and
those those microbes may be uh in the in
the on the outside. uh in in in the
human case it's all internal microbes
but in plants it can be a combination of
external uh primarily things in the soil
that get in through the roots but we
also have a subset of the microbiome
that's internal and we refer to that as
the endoes endo meaning inside fight
means plant so there's microbes inside
the plant that um to me are also pretty
interesting because what are they doing
there I mean are they are they
beneficials are they causing issues in
the land and that's kind of what drove
us to start this this whole area of
research.
Excellent. So yeah, what what do we
know? Are they what kind of purpose are
they are they serving? Are they helping
to carry out certain process processes
or or what's going on there? So again,
you know, there's a fair amount of
literature on these endopites and
microbiomes in other plant species. So
things like wheat and corn and tomato
and so we can learn stuff from those
plants because again with with cannabis
and hemp I think the the earliest
studies on microbiomes was around 2020.
So we've only been at it for four or
five years and and certainly for
cannabis or the the high THC strains uh
this has only been in progress for about
a year year and a half. So it's
relatively new for for these two crops.
But in other plants, there's these
microbes that sit on the root surface
that um seem to help absorb nutrients.
Um there's others that fight off uh you
know, pathogens that might try to gain
access to the roots. And then some of
these microbes enter into the roots, the
the beneficials or the the endopites.
And again, um some of the ideas are that
they do have some benefit. Um others,
why would they be there? So, we've taken
the the opposite approach is that there
may be some in there that are not
beneficial and some of those would
include pathogens, right, that also gain
access to to the inside of the root
structure. And so, there's probably a
battle that goes on between the good and
the bad um within the the plant
structures. That part we haven't quite
figured out yet. Um what we've done up
to now uh using actually medicinal
genomics uh platform is to go through
and and sequence these organisms that
are there using you know what they call
whole genome sequencing where um using
your platform we're able to actually um
determine what what the species of these
microbes are based on their sequences of
of DNA. And so we've come up with this
quite a large volume of information that
we're sort of sorting through. I mean
what what does this mean? What is is
this X? Is this Y? Is this Z? And
eventually we'll come up with some sort
of answer to explain what these microbes
are doing. Right. And now are you trying
to kind of correlate to um the findings
that you have in the microbiome with,
you know, symptoms or morphology of the
plants themselves to try to make some
connections there? Yeah, that's really
hard to do, you know, because what we're
finding is that we there's no plant
there's no cannabis plant that is that
doesn't have a microbiome. Yeah. So, you
don't have you don't have a starting
point that's zero. So, everything that
we take up already has a microbiome in
it. So, you ask the question, well, if I
was to add X and Y, is that going to
make a difference or not? But you've
already got, you know, A and B sitting
in there already. And so uh it it makes
the evaluation of these new microbes
that you add more complicated.
Um what what's A and B doing there? Uh
we don't know yet. And so when you add,
you know, X and Y, what does A plus B
plus X and Y do together? We're not
really 100% sure. Um there's about two
or three recent reports that show that
when you do add X and Y back to whatever
is there already, there is some benefits
that you they do see sort of a
enhancement of growth. There's also
apparently an increase in some of the
canabonoids, but we we we need to be
sure that it's a consistent trend that
when you add X and Y that you're
actually going to see what you think
you're going to see, right? It must be
hard to try to control for all those
different variables. There's a ton of
variables and and that doesn't even
include the environment or or the
cannabis strain that you're using or the
fertilizer that you might be adding. So
that adds a lot of complications to to
what we might see. And again, similar to
the microbiome in our gut, you know,
depending on your diet, depending on
whether you take in a lot of yogurt,
depending on whether you take
antibiotics, that's going to influence
your your microbiome. I know yours is
different from mine because our diets
are completely different. So, there's a
lot of variables that also apply to
plants.
Interesting. Yeah. And when I was
looking through your abstract, I I did
see that there are certain microbes that
you were finding in in all samples. I
believe it was penicyium and fuserium.
Um what's the potential implications of
that? Yeah, so that's that was
interesting as well. Um I mean the
fizerium we know is a pathogen. So, uh,
we need to watch out for that one. And I
guess in hindsight, it wasn't too
surprising because we know fizarium once
it gets into the mother plants, uh, you
take cutings from those plants, you have
a good chance of spreading that fuserium
off into the next cropping cycle. So, we
kind of knew that fizerium was there.
And we've also seen a lot of penicyium.
I mean, penicylium is is what we the
term we use is ubiquitous. It's kind of
everywhere. You know, you fight it in
the air, you fight it in the soil. We
use it to make cheese. We we use it for
various things but um we found
penicylium consistently and and probably
more interesting than that there was one
species penicyium chryogenum which uh in
the early literature back in the 50s and
60s. It was described as the species
that produces the antibiotic penicellin
which we all know is pretty pretty
useful for for helping us combat you
know bacterial infections and so on. So
what is this penicellin producing
penicyium inside the plant doing? Uh
maybe it's fighting off some of the
fuserium. Maybe it's fighting off
something else. But uh in that in those
two cases, you know, the consistency
suggests to me that there's there's a
role there's a function for that uh
penicylium inside the plant. And I don't
know if it's producing antibiotics.
Well, that's that's a harder question to
answer, but it's there. And so it must
be doing something. Yeah. And now and
you mentioned that fuserium is is
present in all the tissue samples and
that it is a pathogen. So are these
plants showing symptoms of like a
fuserium infection or is it potentially
at such low levels that it hasn't had a
chance to to cause harm? Yeah, I I think
it's there at such low levels and and
that brings up a good point. This
microbiome sequencing is very very
sensitive. M I mean the the level of
detection may be you know a few cells of
the of the species that are present
inside the plant. So um when we when we
see a positive of fizarium it doesn't
mean that plant's completely overtaken
by it. It means they may be well for
argument sake 10 spores that we we were
able to pick up with this with this
analytical analytical method. Um, so it
could be just dormant, could be maybe
it's being suppressed, you know, by the
penicellin uh that's inside and then
when you allow it to grow further, it
explodes. Um, we we know a lot of these
endopightes are not necessarily
expressing something all the time. The a
lot of them can be what we call latent.
Mhm. It's an infection that you have
kind of like what we used to have when
we had COVID with with no symptoms. You
know, the virus is there but it hasn't
exploded yet. Um, a lot of these
endopites do that. they they stay latent
and then if the plant is stressed or
there's some other environmental factor
they all of a sudden become active and
that could explain what the fizerium is
doing and and possibly the
penicellium. Yeah. And that was going to
be my question because I know that it's
been said before that you know if you
overwater your plants you have an overly
humid environment or it's particularly
damp um you're more prone to like a
fuserium infection. So is it that you
know if the conditions are right it can
sort of take off? Yeah. And and you know
it's really hard to get rid of the the
only time where we've actually been able
to see it completely eliminated and
again this is using the the U microbial
sequencing platform is is when you do
merist stem culture when you take the
meristan tip which which obviously is
for eradicating viruses and vyroids and
other things. What we found was that the
fusarium was was gone. um it was gone in
in those plants that came out the out of
the out of the tissue culture. And then
I'll just add something more to that and
I'm sure you're going to have a
follow-up question and that is that when
you put those plants out, they get
reinfected really fast. So there's
fizerium flying around in the
environment and for some reason those
marriage stem derived plants seem to be
and I haven't proven this yet more
sensitive to to being to be to being
reattacked. So it's almost like you've
cleaned your entire gut of the
microfllora. You've you've taken a ton
of antibiotics, right? And now the
danger is that whatever comes in next is
going to completely take over because
it's created this this biological
vacuum, right? So they always say when
you've done a dose of antibiotics, go
back in and and start taking these
beneficial probiotics, right? To to help
reestablish your your gut microfllora.
It may be the same in these plants. Once
you clean it up, you need to make sure
you put something useful back
beneficials which would include things
like tricoderma and and other beneficial
fungi. Yeah. No, and you're right. I was
definitely going to have a follow-up to
that, but before we sort of move on, I
just want to talk more about merist stem
tissue culture. Um, and sort of, you
know, the general idea behind that as I
understand it is you're taking such a
small piece of the newest growth that
you're potentially outrunning the
infection, right? The new growth is so
new new that the infection hasn't had a
chance to get there yet. Uh, which makes
a lot of sense. But if I read correctly
in your abstract, you were saying that
some of the bacteria is still present in
the merist stem. Yeah, there were still
a few bacterial cells and you know
bacteria first of all they're so
microscopic and they're very very easy
to move through the vascular tissues in
the plant. So unlike the fungi and maybe
some of the other viruses that sort of
lag behind uh some of these bacteria
were were seemingly making it through.
Um is that good or bad? I don't know. Um
it basically means that you know the the
merist stems aren't completely
completely completely sterile. there may
be some remnants of some bacterial
cells. Uh and we know even with viruses
and vyroids that you don't get 100%
success rate, you may be at 30 40% um
elimination, but the fungi because
they're larger organisms seem to be um
removed from those mar stem tips. Yeah.
No, and I suppose it makes sense too if
if the idea is that there's almost a
symbiotic relationship between the plant
and the microbes that it would be
present even in the new growth because
it may very well be essential. Yeah.
It's doing something that that we still
haven't quite figured out. Yeah. Yeah.
So, another thing that you had touched
on earlier was the idea of um taking
cutings. So if the if the mother plant
is infected with I I think it was
fuserium that we're talking about that
the the cutting is going to um have
those same symptoms. So what are some of
the implications there for for so for
growers who rely on that? Yeah. So
that's something where they you have to
be really careful with the with the
fizarium. Um but you know in addition to
fizerium you're also carrying over some
of the endoes the the the good and
possibly the the other bad ones. uh what
we found was that there was a really
high correlation between the overall
endopytes that you established using
this microbiome method and the endoyes
that were originally in the in the
mothers which I mean in hindsight you
could say yeah of course we know that
you know mother mother to progeny you
get the transmission but it also implies
that pathogens will move in that
direction as well and um you don't you
can't possibly tissue culture everything
I'm not suggesting we go and merrist
stem the entire
population of plants. But what you can
do early on uh you know at the time of
rooting is where we think a lot of these
endopyes and other microbi micro
microbiome members are getting
established is when the roots are
starting to to be formed. And so we're
thinking that um as you start rooting um
in addition to whatever may already be
there, you can supplement that with
beneficial microbes. Uh and again things
like tracherma, glyocladium, some of the
bacteria come to mind. Um add it in
early so that as the roots start to form
these microbes can get in there and uh
potentially out compete the fizarium and
and some of the other microbes that are
there.
Excellent. Um yeah, and that was another
thing I was going to bring up was this
idea of the grow the the growing medium.
Um because I think it it was said that
sterilizing the the cocoa fiber growing
medium actually
didn't sorry you mentioned that
sterilizing the cocoa fiber growing
medium didn't influence the microbiome
of the cutings grown in them. So what
does that mean in terms of Yeah. So that
so that one's a double-edged sword in in
the sense that um there's two aspects to
that. First is that if you've got a
mother plant that's already got
endopytes or other microbes in it and
you take cutings off of that, you'll be
moving along those those particular um
endopy. So we call that horizontal
transmission. It's sort of moving from
from one side to the next. Then if you
plant that in a in a substrate um what
you'll find is that the whatever is in
the substrate growing medium doesn't
really have a huge impact on whatever
has already been been established. In
other words, there's sort of a buffering
effect. So that that speaks to perhaps
the the the substrate not having a major
effect. However, if you go backwards and
consider the mother plant and the mother
plant before that, those plants, if
they're planted in a in a substrate that
has a lot of microbes in it, they'll
start absorbing those microbes from the
from the surrounding environment. So uh
if you look at a time course time A, the
substrate becomes very important because
the substrate will influence whatever is
getting into the plant at time A. But
when you take a whole bunch of cutings
all the way to W, X, Y, and Zed, those
microbes that came from that mother
plant seem to be somewhat well
established and then whatever is in the
substrate doesn't seem to make a huge
amount of difference because they're
already established, right? So yes and
no the substrate um can have an
influence um in in in getting that
initial population established. This is
where I think the best scenario would be
sterilizing that substrate just to be
sure and then adding back in there what
you feel are the beneficials whether
they be traced or glyocadiums. Get those
set up and then stick your plants in
those. And the idea would be that those
will try to out compete whatever is
already present in the cutings and and
make it a beneficial environment. Yeah,
I suppose that makes sense. If you keep
mom happy, you keep mom healthy when
you're creating your cutings. Try to
um recreate that same substrate for the
cutings and then hopefully that would
continue on. And and I think that's
where this whole idea of living soil
comes in. I mean, I've never
experimented with living soils myself
because we work with with hydroponic
systems where everything has to be, you
know, cleaned. But living soils have the
advantage that they they also carry a
huge uh complex of micro microbiomes or
microbes that can have some impact on
the plant that's subsequently grown in
that environment. The only difficulty I
have with living soils is that I don't
know totally what's in there. I think
what we need to do with the microbiome
studies is now start looking at living
soils and finding out exactly what it is
that that we're dealing with. I mean,
you know, living soils do differ. If
you've added a molasses solution to it
or you've added some other organic
fertilizer, that's going to influence
the microbial composition and that could
then impact the plant. So, certainly
they there needs to be more work in that
in that area. Excellent. Now I think
we've we've done a good job talking
about how endoites microbiome in impacts
plant health. What about concerns about
from a consumer standpoint?
Yeah. So I mean you know um one of the
because the the technique is so
sensitive we're finding a lot of
interesting things that we you wouldn't
have been able to culture or grow on
media and so on and so forth. So when
you first look at the data you go oh my
god there's so much stuff here. But we
can't lose can't lose sight of the fact
that every plant, every every vegetable,
every fruit product that we eat is
covered with microbes, right? There's
always a microbiome that's associated
with the tomato that you eat and the
cucumber that you eat. So, we can't lose
lose sight of that. But because cannabis
is more highly regulated, right, they
want to make sure that you don't have
the the negative uh microbiomes present.
um it could help uh address the issue of
um these micro micro microbes that like
aspiggilis that we're really concerned
about. How much of that actually
originates with the microbiome itself
and and how much of it is actually
coming in from the external environment.
The data we're seeing suggests that
aspiggillis is not huge. It's not huge
in the microbiome itself as the plants
are growing. So they're not like
harboring it and picking it up and
storing it like
penicyium. U it may be that the
aspigilus is an external factor, right?
It's coming in maybe through uh high
humidity conditions or poor growing
conditions or or poor drying conditions.
And if that's the case, then it it at
least allows growers to manage the
environment more than they have to be
worried about the plant itself. M so
we're we're hoping that some of this
microbiome eliminates causes for concern
uh even though you've got such sensitive
data that that you know you've got eight
or 10 cells of one microbe and it may
show up as a as a positive. Yeah. No,
and that's interesting you you mentioned
aspiggillis because one of the arguments
against doing aspiggilis testing is that
it's ubiquitous. It's everywhere. You
can't possibly be growing without it.
So, it's interesting to find uh for you
to not find it, I suppose. Yeah. I mean,
at the early stages anyway, of of plant
growth, it may establish itself later
on, but it's it's definitely not one of
the the high numbers. The ones that that
I see uh that we may end up spending
more time looking at is fuserium because
we are seeing fusarium early on all the
way through the plant and in some cases
getting into the flowers and we know
that happens the flower infections and
those species also produce various
micotoxins and so we know that one uh
can originate from in inside the plant
and to me that may be more concern in
the in the long term than perhaps
aspiggillis that that could be external
source of of inoculum.
Yeah, that is definitely interesting
because I know fuserium is is a problem
and a concern and you know we've
developed qPCR testing to try to screen
plants for it. Um which is why it's sort
of interesting that if it's so
ubiquitous perhaps there needs to be
some sort of cut off or um threshold
where um it's more of a concern but that
would take
that's the next the next step I mean we
don't want to add any more regulations
but I think what we want to do is make
sure that the regulations that are we
are using make make sense like make
biological sense um I know aspigillos is
up there because historically it's had
some some major issues on human health
But if it's not as prevalent or not
embedded in the plant and it's coming
from outside and perhaps not as much
concern, then maybe we need to reassess
uh what the important microbes are.
Yeah, absolutely. And now and I know too
that you've analyzed different tissue
types from roots to leaves to flowers,
stems. Um what are some of the insights
there from looking at the different
tissue types? Yeah. So there's there's a
fair amount of variation there and and
similar work has been done with hemp.
There's been a couple of papers that
have shown that there are tissue
specific groups of microbes. What that
means is that you might find one type
more more prevalent in the roots and
another type more common in the leaves
and so on. Uh definitely the roots have
the most. Mhm. Uh I would say the next
tissue that has high levels are stems
which kind of makes sense because that's
where the you know the transport is
occurring. and then uh less so in the
leaves. The leaves seem to have fewer of
these these endoyes and other microbes.
And we're only now in the process of
analyzing the flowers which is the the
you know the critical phase of the
analysis. But we have to be a little
careful with flowers because as I
mentioned there's a lot of external uh
introduction of these microbes from the
air from from water from whatever else.
So when we do the microbiome analysis of
flowers it's not showing only what's
internalized. they could be external um
things that that come into play for that
for that analysis.
So in terms of giving growers some
actionable items from your research like
what what I know we kind of touched on
some things about um you know using
tricoderma or beneficial microbes but in
addition to that what other sort of
advice could you give based on uh your
findings here? Yeah. So, I think you
know if growers have have some favorite
genetics, genetics that they've been
hanging on to that they really want to
keep going, it would be a not a bad idea
to test the microbiome of that
particular plant or series of plants.
you know, you can you can collect root
tissues or you can collect stem tissues
and send it off for for analysis and
it'll give it'll give them an idea of
what sort of the background um microbes
that are already established in the
mothers because we know that a good
proportion of that are going to move on
to the cutings and and then so on and so
forth. So, uh you know and it may also
reveal what other pathogens could be
could be present that they had no idea
were there. So um definitely for
favorite genetics uh that that are being
stored for a long time, go ahead and do
a microbiome analysis on it and see see
what you got. Um following that cutings
made from those plants, I would
definitely suggest they they be rooted
in a medium that has beneficials in it.
Um can't go into details about which
ones. Some growers have preferences over
what they consider beneficial.
Definitely have those on early. they,
you know, some growers tend to put it on
later when the plants are rooted and
they're getting ready to go into flower.
I would say put it on much earlier, um,
and get those established. Now, one, one
fungal organism that we didn't touch
upon is the is the microisy. The
microisy being those we know they're all
pretty much beneficial fungi. I was
surprised that there are mic there is
microisy present already in some of
these plants cannabis plants that that
um seem to have a favorable relationship
with the microisy and we're finding it
in the in the in the in the roots where
you'd expect. We're finding it in the
stems which we didn't expect and we're
even finding it higher up in the plant.
So it almost suggests these microisy may
be carried along uh you know through the
successive development of that plant
which to me was a surprise because we
always think of it just in the roots
like it's just there and that's
definitely a beneficial that that needs
to be looked at. Excellent. No and it's
great advice to kind of get your
microbiome an analyzed. Um, and not to
put you too much on the spot here, but
if someone were to do that and looked at
their report, are there any certain
microbes that would sort of be a red
flag um that they they potentially have
an issue and how would they go about
remedying something like that? Yeah. So,
you know, there's always surprises when
you get down to that level of analysis.
It's it's always uh concerning. Now, one
thing that I didn't mention that
probably is worth mentioning is that uh
when you do get the microbiome results
back, it also reflects um cells that may
be dead. In other words, the microbe may
have been there, but it's not there
anymore. So, you're getting a total
analysis of in the past and and the
present in terms of what could be there.
Um I mean we we haven't seen any super
surprising results um visav something
new and exotic that hasn't been reported
before in North America or some other
really bizarre. We're finding what we
would expect are microbes that grow in
substrates that are microbes that are in
in the um in the environment. Um it was
really interesting because the one of
the the hits we call it a hits meaning a
match. One of the matches we found in in
these samples was human DNA. I'm
thinking, okay, there's human DNA. Well,
it makes sense because people are
touching the plants. They're they're
watering them. They're doing things to
the flowers. So, some of our our skin
cells come off, right? And they they
land on the tissue. And sometimes they
can be mixed up with with the DNA that
we extract from the plant. So, there's
some some human DNA, which I mean,
somebody may freak out and think, what's
that doing there? It's not surprising.
So it's it's sensitive enough that you
know some cells from from human hair or
or skin cells could be it could show up
in the
analysis. Interesting. Um so looking
forward I know that you said that we're
still very early on in terms of looking
at the microbiome for cannabis and hemp.
So um what what are some questions that
you have that you're looking to answer
in the coming years?
So for sure we we need to find out what
the what a good balance of microbes is.
In other words, you know, you've got a I
I don't just throw a number out. We have
maybe let's say 50 50 different species
that are present in uh in a cannabis
plant. We need to narrow that down to
maybe the the optimal four or five that
we think are are always there that
they're serving a good purpose. One
being the penicellium, maybe the
microisy and then see if we can enhance
those. you know, in other words, favor
the the the plant so that it's going in
a in a different
direction. Um the interesting thing that
there was a report out of Europe just
last year. They compared um cannabis or
or hemp varieties that had been heavily
selected or bred over time versus some
that were more or less wild or hadn't
been successively bred over the years.
And they looked at the microbiome
differences between those two. And what
they found was that in the ones that
were heavily bred, uh, the microbiome
um, variability was way lower than what
you'd find in the natural plants or the
so-called the land races. So, one of the
things that's that's happening as we
evolve with more and more sophisticated
cannabis or hemp varieties is that we're
altering the microbiome
composition without even realizing we're
doing that. So, if we knew what some of
these beneficials were, we would
definitely want to add those back. to
that subset population that's being used
for breeding purposes to make sure that
that they have, you know, the necessary
background. The other thing I found
interesting was that seeds, there's a
there's a fair component of the
microbiome that ends up in the seed. Um,
and obviously that's carried over to the
next generation. And that to me is also
pretty fascinating. Can we modify the
seed microbiome early on to alter its
its characteristics so that maybe um you
know it it begins to it begins to show
favorable factors. Now one quick mention
of course is that we know from the
scanning microscopy uh studies we did
where we can look inside the plants
themselves. The reason they're in the
seed is because we pretty sure now
they're traveling through the vascular
system. They're getting into the xyllem
and finding their way into the seed. You
know, if this is a seed plant and and
finding their way inside the seed that
way. Wow. Oh, so we're going to see some
more great images
probably. I I haven't looked at the
seeds myself yet, but I'll bet you that
um there's there's definitely things in
there. But I can show you some really
nice images of the what we call the
plumbing system of the plant, which is
the xyllem. And you can actually find
these spores embedded. Wow. All
different kinds of spores in there that
nobody has ever seen before. It's a
visual confirmation that the microbes
the the microbiome is shifting moving up
the plant. Wow, that's really cool. This
video might break a million when you
have that. Well, let's see. I don't
think anything beats the tricoms, man.
Really, that stuff that stuff's the
best. The tricoms are are the I mean,
this is pretty cool, too. But the tricom
photos, uh, it still just blows me away.
Awesome. Yeah. And it's good you
mentioned seed because I had a question
earlier and we kind of had moved on but
when you were talking about how when you
take the cutings from the mother plant
and sort of introduce it the microbiome
sort of establish so um the substrate
microbiome it's not going to have as
much of an impact. Is the same true for
seed or um when you place a seed into a
growing medium is there more of a chance
that it could influence it? Yeah, that
that's a good I I would say that a seed
that's just starting to grow and putting
out a small root would be more
influenced by by the microbiome. In
other words, you can have positive and
negative effects at that young very
young stage because it's not as well
established as a cutting. the cutting
is, you know, 100 times larger and it's
it's got its own microbiome, but the
seed um could be influenced by by
external factors in the in the substrate
that would definitely make it make it
important. Excellent. Excellent. Okay,
Zamir, winding down here. Before I let
you go, I want to give you a chance uh
to share with the listeners or viewers
um any other resources on this topic
that you think might be useful. be happy
to put a link in the show description or
just links to any of the work that
you're doing or ways that they could
potentially get in touch with you. Yeah.
So, I mean I we we actually just
submitted uh not too long ago that that
paper that describes the the the ends
and other microbiomes in uh in cannabis
plants and um it's it's provisionally
being accepted. So, it it may come out
in the next uh week or or two. I what
I'll do is probably send you a link to
that that's got the latest uh
information on cannabis endopites and
maybe that link could u be hooked up to
the to the podcast. Excellent. Yeah, I
think people would love to see that. All
right, Samir, great stuff as always. Uh
thanks again for joining us on the
podcast and look forward to seeing you
down in Puerto Rico for CAM 25. Thanks a
lot, Ben. It's it's always great to talk
to you and it's nice to be able to cover
different topics every time we speak.
Absolutely. All right, we'll be seeing
you soon. Thanks a lot.
[Music]