so we're going to talk about botanical
medicine we're going to take a step back
we've been talking about a plant where
we haven't talked about botanical
medicine so let's take that step back
and actually talk about botanical
medicine as a field as a offering to
pharmacological activity this comes from
a lot of years of me thinking this
through and so I haven't had to cut this
I had some real world application in
here but I thought it was probably more
important that you've got some of the
foundation before he went into real
world this used to be an hour and
15-minute lecture it is now 45 minutes
so I'm gonna be moving fast so let's
talk about very abbreviated history of
botanical medicine and of course we go
back at least 5,000 years to the written
word and Chinese ru Vedic in those two
systems argue over who was first it
looks like if you look at the history
books that are Iveta Commodus n' was a
little bit ahead of chinese medicine but
that comes from an Arabic perspective on
my end but they had all kinds of
compounds and it turns out if you look
at our Vedic medicine and Chinese
medicine both they're still using
compounds that have now been turned into
drugs in their pharmacies and their
physicians are writing drugs from so
recert being printed for instance is
something that you may or may not use
anymore but there's a lot of drugs out
there that are really useful and some of
them turned into tools and labs as well
now here's where it gets interesting if
we really stop and think about the
number of plants in the world that have
been used as as metric as drugs it turns
out that about 80% of them matched the
ethno pharmacological or ethno botanical
uses now if you stop and think about
that we tend to have this idea of
barefoot traditional people as being
ignorant but I want to reframe that
because if 80 percent of 122 plants that
were using as drugs right now somebody
beat us to it that didn't understand
pharmacology and chemistry in isolation
it says a lot about what we have to
learn from method
botany moreover if you really look at
the developing world it turns out that
about 80% of the developing world uses
botanical medicines for primary care and
so I would say that in the US were
developmentally delayed in the sense of
being aware of other options besides Big
Pharma now if you also look at the the
drugs had been approved over the last 50
years excuse me 30 years about 50
percent of those are basically based off
natural products either directly where
they've isolated it from a plant or
indirectly where they has been able to
synthesize the exact same molecule or a
very close derivative of that molecule
because it was cheaper to do so in
oncology from about the 1940s to the
current date about 175 small molecules
have been improved and about half of
those are actually natural products so
for cancer as well so this this keeps
cannabis out of the picture we're not
talking about cannabis here at all we're
talking about other botanical medicines
but here's the thing that really alarms
me is there's an estimate that there's
somewhere between a quarter of a million
to half a million plants on the planet
and only about 6% of those have been
screened for biological activity now
that's all well and good but what's not
willing goes that we lose a plant
species a day and especially what's
going what's going on in Brazil right
now where for some reason they've taken
the control off burning that we're
losing species it's probably more than a
day one a day at this point anybody
recognize that turmeric that's right
looks a little bit like Ginger st.
family's and your Barry AC no I want you
to take us take a second here I feel so
tied to this I tend to move when I
lecture um once you take a second here
let your eyes adjust to this what you're
looking at is chemical space okay and
each of those graphs natural products
that are drugs natural products that are
derived drugs okay so they've been
changed slightly and natural product
inspires synthetic drugs and
completely synthetic drugs what I want
you to notice just in an overview is
look at the grouping between the first
graph and the last graph so what you see
is that we have when we're synthetically
making drugs we have a pretty narrow
range when nature is biosynthesized
compounds phytochemicals they're all
over the map
and I want you to think about that from
a couple of different angles I want you
to think about that number one from drug
targets because if you look at those
synthetic drugs about 35 to 50 percent
of those targets for those drugs that
are in the synthetics are all targeting
GPCRs so in other words what I'm telling
you is that we have narrowed our drug
therapies to what we know and there's
all this stuff that we don't know yet
that these natural products that are
scattered all over the chemical space
different characteristic different
properties have the potential to hit and
that and I would like to say there's
dark pharmacology going on with
medicinal plants not not dark as in
Darth Vader but dark in the sense that
the drunk is looking for his keys under
the light post
but there's everything else where the
keys probably are and we're stuck and
still stuck and looking under the light
post because we're just focusing on a
couple different types of targets so
this should really get us thinking too
about evolution evolutionarily if you
stop and think it through what we've
really been able to do is what plants
have really been able to do is derive a
broad-spectrum protective effect and so
that gets interesting now real-world
application here these are what you're
looking at is cannabinoids and this is
cannabinoids based on activity or and
what you're seeing there is that
cannabinoids have their unique space
whereas most of the other drugs again
they start to cluster and they cluster
away from cannabinoids so we really are
looking at unique pharmacology here with
cannabinoids the same same photo here in
terms of actual actions activities here
cannabinoids tend to be different
than the rest of the rest of the drugs
so it gets it gets very interesting very
quickly and I can do that for almost any
other plant as well by the way so let's
look at that evolutionary perspective so
while humans were still learning to walk
plants had figured it out
plants couldn't pick up their roots and
run away so they had to figure out a way
to adapt they had to figure out a way to
survive that harsh conditions of
evolution at times and if we look at
humans role in this so now we're we've
gone from 300 million years ago to you
know 10 million 5 million years ago
particle phytochemical intake for
Paleolithic humans was about 8 times and
I think this is a very conservative
estimate about 8 times greater than
modern humans now if we're talking about
a moderate modern human this eating the
standard American diet I'd say it might
be close to a hundred times right I had
the opportunity when I was I was working
as a professor and what I did you know
how freshmen will do almost anything for
you but by the time their juniors had
burnout well so I had all the freshmen
do food logs and I looked at what we did
is we broke it down to the number of
plants that they had in their diet and
it was about 10 4 for the best sometimes
I got up to 12 but about 10 plants now
your ancestors in the Paleolithic Age
it's somewhere between 80 to 220 plants
a year depending on what what continent
where they were but think about that
difference in terms of Plateau chemical
intake now speaking of that so what's
happened in terms of chronic disease and
this is really where I think it makes
starts to make sense because I would
postulate that phytochemical deficiency
is a root cause of chronic disease
remember all that dark pharmacology we
were just discussing it's absent in
people that just eat white bread and
fast food and so we have very different
conditions pharmacal physiological
context today in terms of what we're
putting in now consider that the African
hunter-gatherers body mass index is
about 19
and their serum cholesterol every
American's body mass index actually and
that's gone up since this is about 26
and and the Sam cholesterol is around
294 so again that physiological context
has changed dramatically and part of
that push towards that body mass index
and serum cholesterol is almost
certainly not just that we're eating
more fat and more cholesterol but that
we have absent from us phytochemicals
now think about adaptation because
really that's what evolution is right
we're adapting to conditions and so if
we think about that what it didn't know
it's almost necessarily what will in
fact necessarily is that structures
change now
dr. silic mentioned structure and
function right it's not just about
chemistry well our structure starts to
change based on what we're exposed to
and so this becomes very key and so
genes are modified can be modified by
what we're eating that's how part of our
structure changes so your ancestors what
they were eating is what you're carrying
now in terms of the structural changes
that came through and so if we think
about receptors that are responsive to
natural products think about opioid
receptors think about vanillite
receptors and those plants for each one
of you think about nicotinic receptors
think about dopamine receptors think
about cannabinoid receptors think about
type 2 cannabinoid receptors think about
esters and receptors think about
adenosine receptors think about gaba
receptors and think about P bar
receptors and in fact P bar is a
particular interest to me I spent a
number of years with my head inside the
nucleus almost figuratively
that's a funny image but people are is
particularly promiscuous you can
actually bind to ligands at one time in
a P bar binding pocket so people are
really is almost a phytochemical sensor
and if you recall people are gamma is an
important site for and by the way is
part into a cannabinoid system now is an
important site for not just diabetes
but also for inflammatory processes and
autoimmunity so we really do have the
series of adaptations due to what we
were eating and what we were exposed to
and today even at this point we can
still point to a lot of different
phytochemicals that we eat regularly
like for example quercetin quercetin by
the way I use for my allergies that
stabilizes mast cell membranes but it
also has an effect on gene expression so
daily we're exposed to our dietary broth
and that turns on and turns off genes
and the genes you're turning off and
turning on are different than the guy
who is eating at McDonald's right and so
that becomes a very interesting idea
right is that our dietary broth
basically is steeped every day are into
our genes are steeped every day by our
dietary broth now plants shape humans
and one of the really super obvious ways
that's low hanging fruit is the
cytochrome p450 system right we're
looking at at least 75 different genes
here for cytochrome p450 and cytochrome
p450 you may think of it as something
that's exogenously affected but remember
cytochrome p450 is huge in things like
breast cancers c 1 p 1 a 1 versus 1 B 1
is going to make make a D difference
between those fiery 16 hydroxyl
estrogens and those 2 and 4 hydroxyl
estrogens so it makes a huge difference
what we need to do is keep in mind that
these the the the inter-individual
variability in a cytochrome p450 system
is huge is very vast and it's very vast
because our ancestors developed eating
different plants depending on what
region they were in and so that really
points at for example caffeine
metabolism tends to vary about 60 fold
between an individual's
so you know people that can drink a cup
of coffee right before bed and have a
great night's sleep and you know people
they have one cup and actually you
probably don't know you probably don't
know that this is the issue but they're
gonna have one cup and and have a hard
time sleeping that night I think there's
a lot that goes on and now with
Starbucks you know and young people are
going well I need a triple shot in my
coffee of espresso right we're getting
up to 250 up to almost 300 milligrams of
coffee or caffeine per dose so huge
inter individual variation and we also
can alter metabolism as well as change
our biological fitness not just of
ourselves but also as dr. sumac just
pointed at the cannabinoid receptors
have a role in turning on turning off
potentially our microbiome in different
ways and so in the same sort of way all
these organisms that we carry really
respond to our phytochemistry now this
idea this phytochemical index was put
out by a guy named Mark McCarty and
McCarty dropped out of medical school
and made a good career for himself as a
research scientist and he dropped out of
medical school because they didn't think
what we he was doing was making sense to
him and the reason he said is we're
ignoring the idea of planets we're
ignoring the idea of of the
phytochemistry that were exposed to so
we came up with this idea of the P I the
phytochemical index and what he said was
well let's figure out how this alters
human fitness and so his idea basically
is we could use this epidemiologically
to understand disease processes even
more so and so he did that
here's his original paper but he moved
on to actually some proof of principle
and by the way he points out very cute
very Keeley is that non-nutritive
phytochemicals appear to be key
non-nutritive so there's there's a
nutrients there's the the vitamins and
minerals that we get but those
non-nutritive phytochemicals are
particularly of interest in that of
course is going to have a huge effect on
health now proof of principle so a
number of years later and it took a
while but
here you have something showing
inflammation and overweight young adults
and the phytochemical index is inversely
related to adiposity and oxidative
stress so the higher the P I the lower
the oxidative stress and the
inflammatory process here's another one
on breast cancer and again what you see
though is in the fourth quartile of
dietary phytochemical index in other
words the most phytochemical index had a
decreased risk of breast cancer and then
here's another one on hypertension
Dietary P I was inversely associate with
a hypertension center occurrence and
they again they point out synergistic
effects and we'll talk about that in a
couple of lectures here on
phytochemicals from different foods a
responsible for the inverse association
between high dietary P I and the risk of
hypertension and then we get to this
idea of insulin resistance and again we
see a very significant effect and this
shouldn't surprise you because what we
just talked about with people are gamma
again part of the endocannabinoids
system now but people are gamma being
almost a phytochemical sensor in the
body it's so promiscuous that it binds
so many different compounds and so what
we what would we see after and here's
the here's here's the shot here that
really makes a difference
hi purlins anemia in the first quartile
versus the fourth quartile insulin
sensitivity insulin resistance they all
show beta cell dysfunction they also
very significant decreases beneficial
decreases in activity based on
phytochemical index so this is where it
starts to get interesting is it just one
chemical and this is the way that we've
approached pharmacology is we've
approached it by saying well let's find
that the gem in the jungle of compounds
but that might be the wrong approach and
it might be the wrong approach and a lot
of people agree with that they say well
it might actually be an additive or
synergic effect that actually is having
me the activity so I just want to show
you all these compounds that are coming
up now they're all anti-cancer but
they're not just anti-cancer in one
mechanism they hit more than one pathway
every one of these compound
it's at least two different pathways at
least two different pathways so we're
talking about garlic here we're talking
about legumes in general people think
genestein is just soy but it's not we're
talking about wines right we're talking
about tomatoes
we're talking about peppers so all kinds
of compounds up here really have a
significant role and we're going to see
this with cannabinoids as well and early
exposure to phytochemistry so what
happens when we are exposed early on in
life versus not exposed to early on and
I love this and this is Waterland by the
way in Journal and they did they did a
great series of studies they showed
human empathy epidemiological data
indicates the susceptibility to Adeline
so a chronic disease is influenced by
persistent adaptations to prenatal and
early postnatal nutrition and then this
study came out and I'd like to see more
studies like this this was a 60-year
study by the way so you can imagine for
those of you who are researchers you can
imagine the funding issues around that
right higher childhood consumption of
fruit was associate with the reduced
risk of adult cancer in a study of
almost 4,000 adults and I wonder how
many they lost in that 60 years right
but these are the kinds of studies that
we actually need this is epidemiological
evidence at its best ten years
interesting 60 years that really gives
us some information so how do we fight
cancer speaking of cancer prevention
right and yet I don't see a lot of
activity in that direction honestly by
by our pharmaceutical companies and that
seems almost criminal to me knowing what
I know about the phytochemicals that are
very preventative it seems we really
need to be thinking more about
preventing breast cancer and other
cancers than treating it now treating it
is important but what if we could
prevent it and how much money could be
saved
well then somebody wouldn't be making a
lot of money sorry I guess I'm a little
twisted this today yeah the genetic
component of all complex traits just as
hypertension arthritis and cognitive
function is influenced by a broad range
of effects spread across many snips and
many genes now this is an important
point
to remember it's one more treating
chronic disease we're not going after
one target but this is what we do
currently in pharmacological approaches
we go after one target and it may be
exactly the wrong idea and that may be
why if you look at if you look at the
rates of chronic disease that's which by
the way are going up but you look at the
rates of visits to physicians 75 percent
of those visits are for chronic diseases
which means that they keep going back
because it's not working right and so we
really need to rethink this what if
every position had a nutritionist in
their office what if every nutrition
looked at the phytochemical index if
nothing else and said to their patient
you know you really need to eat more
fruits and vegetables and what if we had
to walk people and we would need to do
this I know for most people we'd have to
walk them by the hand to show them how
to do that most people don't even there
was a program that I was involved in in
Baltimore inner-city Baltimore for
addicts and they once they made it to a
certain point that got into a halfway
house and then people started donating
fruits and vegetables they threw out
almost all the vegetables because they
didn't know what to do with them
and I don't think this is unusual so
what's the evidence so number one herbal
medicine for caught the systemic review
and I'm going to I'm going to cruise
through these but basically there is
evidence or oral herbal herbal therapies
for treating osteoarthritis again there
is evidence herbal medicine for low back
pain even I was surprised by this one
but and this is not cannabis but there
is evidence a Cochrane review on
[Music]
congestive heart failure so what is it
about herbal medicine so that's actually
different than pharmaceuticals well
here's my main take we're treating
networks with herbal medicines we're not
treating one
it's target so and let's talk about
networks for a second if systems biology
has been a huge breakthrough especially
in ecology but it's starting to affect
other fields now and some of those other
fields that are affecting include
pharmacology we'll talk about that in a
second here but network biology
basically suggests that what you want to
do is massage alter modulate whatever
term you want to use multiple nodes in a
network at once and when you do that you
can start to look at aggregate behavior
now aggregate behavior is a another way
of thinking about emergent behavior
right what is emergence emergence is
when one plus one here's a here's a
simplified example that's that's got
some colloquial truth to it you put one
neuron or two neurons in a dish and it's
interesting you put three neurons in a
dish in a system is created and you see
behavior that you won't see with one or
two neurons alone and so that's what's
happening is we're creating
characteristics that we can't
acknowledge when we're just studying the
properties of one compound or one cell
or one receptor we're starting to see
networking activity that goes well
beyond what we might expect
and unfortunately the usual mathematical
techniques that we would use to do this
drawing a straight line on a graph which
unfortunately I've done a lot of in my
life
can't really explain this behavior and
so it tends to get ignored and tends to
get missed you know you know that one
that outlier on the graph that's what I
want to go after right what happened
there but we tend to throw it out now
here's a real living cellular network
this this is put out by a company that
does network analysis and it's stunning
it's beautiful isn't it that's what's
happening inside a cell so really what
starts what starts to happen and this is
molecular biology this is the field
right is what you're looking at is
signaling you're looking at cross
you're looking at relationships much as
physics shifted from the particle back
in the 60s and 70s to the relationship
between the particles that's what needs
to be happening in medicine at this
point is we need to be looking at the
relationships so we cut out the heart we
put it in a box and we study it we cut
out the kidneys we put it in a box and
we study it we study its weight its
property is its volume its but how are
we understanding the signaling is going
on and that's a huge piece we spend some
time there but we don't spend enough
time there here's a very simplified
model of immune network that certainly
would be affected by many different
compounds whether pharmacologically
synthetic or bio synthetic but what we
really need to start doing is thinking
in systems and not just thinking about
one target thinking broadly and so if
you really look at how we've managed
unresponsive patients and our clinical
practices a lot of times what we've done
is combinations of drugs because we're
thinking we start to think more in
systems right if we're my opinion if
we're thinking in the right direction
and I like to sing somebody once said
that a dirty drug is a drug that works
now what is meant by a dirty drug in
pharma a dirty drug is a target that
hits more than one at a drug that hits
more than one target and so think about
that for a second just think about the
name and we've given it that's not
something we want right but in fact if
we go back to evolution and the way that
we were eating and the phytochemicals
that we were exposed to that's exactly
what they were doing they were hitting
more than one target and think about it
from the plants perspective we'll do a
pollen esque a Michael Pollan desk model
of this why would the plants say to
itself well if I'm going to produce I'm
gonna spend all that ATP making a
compound it better be useful in more
than one place right it makes sense this
is how plants evolved to survive 300
million years
and by the way Gleevec is a great
example of a blockbuster blockbuster
drug the
only hit was designed to only hit one
target and when they started looking at
why it was so efficacious they
discovered that it was actually hitting
multiple targets
so thinking and system really means that
we needs to rethink how we go about this
rethink how we evaluate and how we think
one disease one drug is the model and
that really came from pest or in Ehrlich
but we need to move past that so let's
talk specifically about network
pharmacology now this field is probably
about 10 to 15 years old now and Dustin
and I are the only ones that I know at
this point talking about Network
pharmacology with cannabinoids but it
actually makes sense and I just have a
comment here Occam's razor was theology
you know what the idea of Occam's razor
is it's a simplified explanation right
the simplest explanation is what it is
and that's used in labs all over the
world and it's actually using clinics
all over the world as well but guess
what akhom the the man akhom he was a
theologian so are we really are we
taking scientific advice from a
theologian and I'll let you decide if
that's a good or bad thing so what is
network pharmacology the recognition
informed by systems biology that drugs
from many disease states may require
multiple activities to be efficacious
acting on the network of tissues cells
receptors enzymes and the genome and so
let's take an example here and let's
look at asthma targets so these are all
the targets that are known so this is
under the under the light post right
that we know of for asthma and then
here's all the drugs that we know of
that can actually treat these conditions
and so there's a number of drugs we can
we can use but what I'd like to do is
turn this on its head let's take the
common food grape and Vitus and let's
look at all the compounds that are anti
allergic anti osmotic asthmatic excuse
me that are anti Brahm Kotik they're
anti leukotriene and anti frenetic and
then antioxidants and more antioxidants
and to prostaglandins anti-spasmodics so
what do you think your plants make sense
and so could could and by the way I
don't think if I was going to treat
asthma as a clinician with herbal
medicines
I wouldn't use grapes I picked a really
simple food to you highlight this
example so this is this is a minimum of
what activity you might have versus an
herb that we see used to treat asthma so
does the patient that comes in with
asthma who's eating fast food respond
differently than the patient that's come
in it's eating a diet high in fruits and
vegetables has a high phytochemical
index I'd like to suggest to you that
they're going to respond very
differently to your your approach your
pharmacological approach based on what
they're eating you're either going to be
enhancing that effect or just really
trying to push hard to get an effect
when there's not much other activity
supporting that there's not a found
phytochemical foundation just support
the pharmacology that you might use so
Network pharmacology basically we're
looking at multiple targets versus
single targets and compared to that
Marshall multiple but partial
perturbations and I like this term
multiple but partial perturbations of
selected genes and network are almost
always more efficient than the knockout
of a single well selected target and
think that through basically what you've
got here is a nudge versus a
sledgehammer right when we go in with
one with one drug for one target we're
hitting it with a sledgehammer when we
go in with a bunch of broad-spectrum
phytochemicals we're massaging the
system we're nudging this system so that
it's not a hundred percent it's not even
80 percent inhibition for an enzyme for
example it might be more like twenty but
if we hit a bunch of enzymes in that
system
at 20% inhibition we actually have an
effect that turns out to be safer
so it's robust right and this is the
this is the issue here is redundant
pathways robust living molecular
networks have redundant pathways and so
when we try to knock out one pathway
with a single target drug we're almost
always going to lose efficacy efficacy
over time and if we look at this it
really does look like what we have been
doing with food plans forever in terms
of our in terms of our diet so I think
of it as ensembl properties I think of
it like music so when we put one
compound in what does that sound like
and then when we put multiple compounds
in that have grown together in a plant
is there some sort of chemical harmony
there now
this study came out and it made a lot of
noise and it came out and I think it was
2003 a strategy to reduce cardiovascular
disease by more than 80 percent
published in British Medical Journal and
basically what they suggested was that a
multi-component remedy a poly pill they
called it based on a single daily pill
containing six components those
components were statin three blood
pressures lowering drugs at half the
dose again partial nudges partial
inhibition folic acid in aspirin and
what was their conclusion now this was
all theoretical but their conclusion was
it would prevent 88% of heart attacks
and 80% of strokes okay that got
everybody's attention in fact there are
a couple of papers that came out after
this that made fun of this
multi-component remedy because it got
everybody's attention well how would it
really affect our epidemiology about 1
in 3 people would directly benefit each
on average gaining 11 to 12 years of
life without a heart attack or stroke
that's pretty darn profound and then
what would what would happen in terms of
the United States alone half of our
cardiovascular disease deaths in the
United States would be prevented pretty
profound and they say hey eating more
fruits and vegetables and whole grains
actually might make real sense and and
by the way getting salt and trans fats
and then here's the proof of principle
so somebody just did this study where
they find those on the poly pill had 1/3
fewer cardiac events or 5 years in the
control group and the poly pill group
with high adherence greater than 70
percent of adherence the reduction in
the risk of major cardiovascular events
was 57 percent fewer cardiac events than
control so they didn't we didn't get the
promised 80% but we got almost 60% and
that's really notable now let's take the
poly pill from a plant
here's garlic there's our your
cholesterol-lowering agents
there's your blood pressure lowering
agents there's your anti-inflammatory
agents in which by the way of course
would be a good idea with cardiovascular
disease
there's your anti-ag regrets there's
your antioxidants does it make sense
over 40% of drug targets and map with
disease genes mapped to more than one
disease so really when it comes down to
it and again I look at it from the
molecular biology there's a common theme
going on the molecular biology but yet
we name them differently and we treat
them differently right if we start
thinking on molecular biology level we
really start getting that gosh a lot of
these diseases have a common thread and
we can treat that common thread it might
depend on the weak link it might depend
on the snips that you've got it might
depend on the family inheritance that
you've got it might depend on the diet
that you've got physiological context is
all so a drug discovery approach that
MACT matches with a systems biology
approach is really going to give us
combinations of small molecules and you
start yours we're starting to see that
right we're seeing ACE inhibitors with
statins now we're seeing that look at
the drug cocktails for tuberculosis
resistant tuberculosis or cancers we're
starting to see this
okay so intervening in a network
pharmacological strategies with multiple
targets might have a better chance of
affecting a complex weeka Librium a
whole cellular networks and drugs and an
enhanced safety profile okay so let's
this looks like it I may have the old I
don't think this is the abbreviated
okay so differences is compared to
pharmaceuticals what's the differences
and I pull the case studies here I
apologize that slide is slightly in
error so here's what I want to leave you
off with here if there's differences and
some of those differences I put it
categorized into two broad categories
there's pharmacodynamic differences and
there's pharmacokinetic differences the
pharmacodynamic differences there's
multiple modes of activity in other
words biochemical convergence on a
single outcome okay but there's also
multiple constituents that can work on
one target so you can end up with
molecular multitasking on one hand and
target hitting getting hit by multiple
molecules then pharmacal kinetically we
affect things like absorption
distribution metabolism excretion and
toxicology a lot of what you're going to
see and if you think about this again
evolutionarily is that plants really
have this role in affecting the
accessory compounds in plants that not
the actors really have a role in
affecting pharmacokinetics so we may
improve bioavailability we may we may
delay metabolism of the count of the
actives so this is really super common
now keep in mind that 50% of all drugs
on the way to far on the way to the
market fail because of poor
pharmacokinetics so this is something we
should consider
I'm going to stop there I'm good why
don't we why don't we just because we're
a little behind schedule anyway are we
yeah I'm gonna I'm gonna call it quits
and we'll I think we have a break now
right yeah break time
like yeah
[Applause]