[Music]
welcome to the CB Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I am the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team team that puts on the canmed
Innovation and investment
Summit all right well registration for
canm med25 is now live check out camed
events.com to see details about next
year's event in the new location at the
Windam Resort in Rio Grande Puerto
Rico if you check out the ticket
packages page you'll be happy to see
that the price for this full Summit
package is lower than K 24 but that
package still includes three nights at
the resort full access to three days of
canmed presentations workshops and
networking events meals and Cocktails
and so much more now I know what you're
thinking the events in June I have
plenty of time yes you do but it's never
too early to purchase your ticket
package for cmed not only will you take
advantage of early bird pricing which
gets you another $500 off the full
Summit package but you'll also get the
satisfaction that comes with Crossing
something off of your to-do
list my guest today is Dr John Striker
John is a professor in the department of
pharmacology in the College of Medicine
at the University of
Arizona he has built a long-term
research program focused on finding
improved treatments for pain this has
encompassed multiple approaches over the
years including testing cannabinoid and
non-cannabinoid constituents of cannabis
identifying new ways to Target the
opioid receptor signaling and
identifying new receptor Targets in the
body for pain relief his lab works on
both the basic science knowledge of how
these systems work and also works to
create new drugs for human
therapy during our conversation we
discussed the basics of tpin what they
are and their rolling cannabis the
canomatic effects of tpin and their
synergistic effects with
cannabinoids what levels of tpin are
needed to get a therapeutic
effect a recent study showing tpes can
relieve chronic neuropathic
pain combining tpes with other drugs
such as opioids to get better pain
relief at lower Doses and which tpin
provide the best pain
relief before we get to my conversation
with John I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor healer.com
healer is a trusted physician developed
medicinal cannabis brand founded to
address the challenges of helping people
and health providers get the best
results with safe reliably dosable
products and education on how best to
use them healer hemp products are
available Nationwide and include a
step-by-step usage guide and response
tracker healer's distinctive product
formulations and education are based on
the latest research and work of leading
cannabis clinician Dr Dustin sulac for
more information visit healer.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr John
Striker
[Music]
good afternoon John thanks so much for
joining us on the
podcast thanks Ben really good to be
here appreciate the invite all right
well I'm excited to talk with you today
about Turin now we've talked about Turin
in a couple other previous episodes how
they contribute to cannabis Aroma how
they influence a user's experience even
how they're analyzed but we've yet to
really dive into the therapeutic effects
of tpes at least not as like Standalone
compounds which is what I think what
makes your recent study and your
abstract so interesting often tpes are
are seen as contributors to the
Entourage effect with other canabo but
your work suggests that they may have
therapeutic effects on their own own
which is really interesting but before
we get too deep into that for those in
the audience who perhaps haven't seen
those previous episodes on tpin could
you give us an overview of what they are
and what their role is in
cannabis yeah Ben absolutely so uh tpin
themselves are not unique to cannabis so
these are small molecules that are found
in essentially all plants at least all
plants that I know about what makes them
kind of unique for cannabis is there's a
lot of them in cannabis more of them
than there are tend to be in plants like
hops or or pine or whatever and so what
is a turpine a turpine is a small simple
uh molecule like it's small um very
aromatic very small very Hydro hydr
phobic SL lipophilic so small molecule
and it we've sort of known about these
molecules for many years because as you
just said they add to The Taste and
Aroma of the plant and so you have
something like you know even if you
don't know what tpin are you kind of
still experienced them so you you smell
that fresh lemony smell from a real
lemon not the not the stuff that comes
in a can and you know that's that's Del
lemoning right that's a that's a turpine
you smell that smell coming off of hops
that's Alpha huming uh you know the pine
tree smell that's beta pining and so on
so you've all experienced tping even if
you haven't run across that term before
and so in terms of what they do in
cannabis yes of course they add to that
unique Aroma and flavor although um
parenthetically they actually are not
what give cannabis that real skunky
smell so we've actually isol or we were
not the ones that isolated our
collaborators isolated that compound
called penal thol working with it
separately it actually has different
activity than either the Turpin or the
cannabinoids but just kind of a side
note there so it's not exactly that
skunky smell but some of the other taste
and Aroma elements of the plant are from
these turpins and so of course for many
years now people have been looking we
sort of knew that it did this taste and
Aroma but people have suspected that
these have had therapeutic and
pharmacological effects going back some
time and so those have been under active
investigation in the literature and um
and then what as also as you suggested
that people have suggested that these
turpins contribute to the Entourage
effect the idea that the turpins might
somehow combine with the canabo to give
you an effect unique to the plant that
you wouldn't get from either one
purified alone and so there were sort of
all these ideas floating around there
had been some studies particularly in
pain suggesting that tpin could relieve
pain even clinical studies had shown
this uh but there were some real
limitations in the literature and the
there still is no solid evidence whether
or not the Entourage effect actually
occurs in like a a cannabis extract that
you yourself are taking or smoking or
whatever and so we kind of surveyed this
landscape in about 2020 is when we
started our work in this I said okay you
know there's a lot of suggestions but
not a lot of hard data so let's drill
down and figure out what these molecules
are actually doing rather than just kind
of throwing around ideas and uh so we
started by isolating the Turpin and
studying each one individually rather
than as you say combined into this kind
of this mix of this extract so that we
could really figure out which each one
does alone before we start you know at
looking at them in combination and so we
published that initial work in 2021
showing that the Turpin have what we
call a canaba mtic effect that they they
behaviorally they look like a canabo
although they are not a canabo and their
mechanism is a little bit different than
a typical canabo but nonetheless it
produce some of these same effects in
animals like uh you know sedation the
kind of the couch lock or couch high
that you get um catalepsy decrease in
body temperature uh pain relief and so
on so it had these had these effects and
interestingly in terms of the Entourage
effect when we combined the turpine with
a canono a synthetic canabo we got a
higher impact than either one alone and
that's kind of what got us the most
attention in 2021 was this idea that
that you could comb that it was have
that the tripping were having this
effect and that the effect could be
greater when you combine them with a
canabo and so that's what really got our
journey started in in this
area excellent um so how do tpin
interact with the human body um
particularly in relation to
pain yeah so that is still you know
really a big unknown question right not
completely unknown so there have been as
I mentioned clinical studies other
studies showing that the tpes relieve
pain so even like say a study where they
would give a linol to um laboring women
like women in labor giving birth and it
show that they had this benefit and
there are other studies looking at
chronic pain patients and so on give the
tpine you see this benefit but there's
still even when you know that there's
still a lot of unknown questions first
of all like we all know that tpin have a
strong smell and we also know that
humans have a strong placebo effect uh
when they're exposed to what they think
is a medication like I haven't seen any
well-controlled studies that suggest
that the turpine effect is separate from
the placebo effect and mechanism is also
unknown right we don't know how this if
it is relieving pain how it's relieving
pain and that's something we try to
tackle in our own work by first of all
working with mice who do not kind of
have this this expectation that a human
being does they they don't know and
furthermore we were injecting the
turpine so they couldn't get like that
Aroma or that smell to sort of confound
the effect and then looking at the mice
and then also figuring out mechanism and
diving in and figuring out exactly what
these are interacting with and at least
in mice we now have data that suggests
that these are stimulating The cannaboid
receptors in your brain so sort of the
the known canabo that are going to be or
Sor known canabo receptors that are
going to be stimulated by drugs like THC
and also your endogenous cannaboids that
your own body produces uh and we also
know that they can bind to an activate a
receptor called the adenosine a2a
receptor and again this is one of those
targets all of you know about even if
you've never heard that word before
because that's the same drug or sorry
the same receptor that's targeted by
caffeine so we've all stimulated or
inhibited our Denine a2a receptors
whether you know it or not because we we
do it through caffeine and we found that
the turpine stimulate at least in the
mice this receptor to produce a strong
pain relief in a chronic and neuropathic
pain interesting all right a couple
things that you you touched on there
that I thought was interesting um so the
placebo effect I got to think especially
like like you mentioned I mean these are
these are aromatic compounds um it would
be hard to sort of have a sibo of that
compound without it actually being the
real thing right yeah so there's ways to
potentially get around that that I've
been thinking about right so um there's
a lot of different ways to take Tarpin
and indeed cannabis and other extracts
and so if we wanted to take away that
part we might say encapsulated into a
capsule and so I'm working with a
company right now called uh uh black
rock neutraceutical that are developing
an encapsulated as well as a tinctured
form of a beta carry offing that we're
going to be testing in in animals and
then eventually human beings and that
might be one way to get around it does
that change the bioavailability whether
or not you're inhaling it versus
ingesting it yeah it very well might but
that touches on another problem in the
turpine field is that there are very few
if really any studies that I can find
that actually look at the
bioavailability and the pharmacokinetics
and part of the reason perhaps for that
is that we found it's pretty challenging
to do so we started to do these
pharmacokinetic studies we're having
trouble detecting the molecules you
mentioned had previously uh discussed
how to how to sort of measure these
molecules and we use gas chromatography
Mass spectrometry uh but we have a lot
of trouble getting it to work
consistently maybe we're just idiots and
not doing it right but um that suggests
there could be a reason perhaps why
there are so few PK studies on tpin in
the
literature okay and then another thing
you mentioned is that you know that
these tpin they're stimulating some of
the same receptors that cannaboids are
now is that at similar levels or are the
cannaboids stimulating more how how does
that sort of compare yeah so
pound-for-pound at equivalent levels of
potency the turpins are stimulating less
so they are what we would call a partial
Agonist so whereas something actually
THD is technically a partial Agonist too
but whereas something like
anandamide diog glycerol or sorry not
not diog glycerol 2ag um those are going
to be full agonists uh and then I'm
trying to think if there's a synthetic
cannabinoid that that everyone would be
familiar with that might be a full
Agonist well THC is the closest to it
right right so those are going to
stimulate let's say 100% And what we're
getting with the tpin is more like 50 to
60% got it so you would need higher
concentrations of the chines to get a
similar effect yeah and that's what we
found so we actually have to use fairly
high concentrations both in animal
models when we inject as well as in uh
cell culture models when we're actually
looking at how the receptor itself is
stimulated by these drugs and and so
that leads into another issue right when
you're evaluating the Entourage effect
and we gotten this criticism in our work
they like okay you had to give a high
amount of tpin to the animals or to the
cells in order to see these effects in
an actual extract from real cannabis the
levels of tpine are fairly low right so
they're not at this this high level
where you're going to get get you get a
high dose and and then like so how can
we have this Entourage effect well that
even if that's true to me it's actually
not that important because we can design
these drugs or extracts whatever we can
design them however we want we can put
in higher levels T of Turpin to sort of
harness this Entourage like effect or
whatever you want to call it in order to
help people treat their pain better or
or whatever they need it
for now is the criticism more that you
know evidence for the Entourage effect
in cannabis itself that the turpins are
at such a low level we can't really um
attribute an effect to them in kind of a
natural product yeah that's the
criticism of my work specifically that
I've run into and again we kind of
answer by saying well it doesn't really
matter we're looking at what these
molecules do on their own
therapeutically we can design whatever
we want in order to help someone um but
uh so that's the criticism of my work
but then more broadly there's just a
lack of no not a total lack but a
general lack of Investigation into this
uh you know phenomena in the scientific
literature so you know you can go online
and find lots of people who will tell
you the entage effect is real you know
you um you get the I don't want to name
it in games but like you get you know
you put this tpine in your extract
you're going to get these effects
there's really not a lot or perhaps any
evidence for that and so that's Again
part of our motivation for doing this
work is to sort of fill in those gaps
put some scientific backing behind the
claims that are being made in the public
excellent okay so you mentioned that you
were doing some um some studies in mice
or rats or so mice talk a little bit
more about that and kind of what's the
next stage beyond what you've done so
far yeah absolutely so I I briefly
described our sort of our initial
research published in 2021 showing that
the Turin sort of cannaboid like and so
we were indeed we were giving those to
mice we have this battery of Behavioral
tests we give mice because you can't
just ask a mouse hey how high are you
right now like you feeling it bro um so
we have these behavioral tests that we
run in the mice that that cannabinoids
produce sort of these typical behaviors
and so we found that they're cannaboid
like Etc um however sort of more perhaps
more impactfully recently just a a month
or two ago we continued this work
publishing another paper showing the
impact of the tping on chronic pain and
so not not canono like not a sort of a
tail flick pain which is the the
analgesic assay that we run that's more
like hand on a hot stove pain so this is
trying to get it real patients who are
suffering and in particular we used a
model called chemotherapy induced
peripheral neuropathy so people that
have cancer they go on these
chemotherapy drugs like pxel um those
help the cancer right that's great but
many of those patients even a majority
of those patients get some kind of
chronic neuropathic pain sort of this
burn
numb electric shooting style pain
usually in the hands and the feet and
for some of those patients it never goes
away even after they sto taking their
their uh pet Axel or whatever their
chemotherapy drug is even after the ca
the Cancer's gone and that pain is
really difficult to treat it's not well
treated by opioids or other drugs and so
we wanted to again test a model that's
going to be relevant to to real people
and their concerns tested the Turpin in
that model and we found that they were
highly effective in relieving this typ
of neuropathic chronic pain we got
strong pain relief and since then this
work hasn't been published yet but we
also looked in other pain models too
like a postsurgical pain Model A
fibromyalgia like pain model and then uh
oh inflammatory pain so like you know
strong inflammation that was the one I'm
wasn't thinking of and so you know four
different chronic pain models all of
them relevant turpins produce strong
pain relief in all of them and and then
we have further dug into mechanism
that's published anyone can read this if
they want um but you know that's in mice
as you mentioned right so this is
exciting but this is in mice so where do
we take it next scientifically we want
to further explore turning these into
actual drugs and that's going to go
through several paths One path is going
to be scientific figuring out what is
their mechanism like exactly what
they're doing I mentioned the adenine
a2a receptor like how are they
stimulating that what does that look
like in your spinal cord what are the
the the neuronal circuits that are being
activated to relieve pain all of that um
and then we're also going to do more
therapeutic based um investigation
because it's not enough that a drug
relieves pain to be a good drug it also
has to have tolerable or preferably
lower no side effects right so if you
have a drug that relieves your pain but
makes you absolutely miserable that
doesn't do anyone any good and so we've
did some of this side effect testing
looking at tolerance and addiction
liability and they have no addiction
liability in our hands in fact we have
some unpublished research suggesting
that tpin can block the addiction
liability of opioid
and so that's an exciting future
direction that we're pursuing but we
need to look at other side effects you
know make sure this isn't making the
animals and thus you feel miserable um
you know making sure it's not toxic and
so on there's no reason to think it is
but all of that has to be tested and
then on the third sort of pathway is to
bring this to the clinic to to real
patients and so here at the University
of Arizona we have very active clinical
research programs uh and I can work with
Physicians here that do that type of
research to get these tpin into patient
and as far as tpin go we have a big
advantage in doing that because it's a
natural product so this isn't some new
drug that we whipped up in the lab that
we invented that has to go through all
this extensive safety toxicity testing
before it can be approved by the Food
and Drug Administration the tpin are
already on the FDA list of what's called
generally regarded as safe Gras and thus
we can take these right into the clinic
and give them to people without I mean
it still has to be approved by the
institution and so on but we can take
them right into people without having to
have that approval from the FDA and
that's going to shorten that timeline by
a lot and as I mentioned there have
already been some clinical studies with
tpin and so we'll be looking at their
impact in chronic pain and as part of
that we also want to make sure that they
can be delivered well so we've already
brought up the issue of pharmacokinetics
and bioavailability we're working to
also tweak the formulation to make sure
that it's going to be stable that it's
going to get into the brain and the
spinal cord and do what it needs to do
without being broken down mhm and so now
what what are you thinking is would be
the um the method of ingestion would it
be oral or inhaled or yeah so we're
exploring all options right now really
so as I mentioned we did this injected
but we also have tested oral Gage or
just oral oral delivery as well as
inhaled um version as well with all with
the mice and interestingly we found that
the oral in the inhaled had less
bioavailability like even at a high dose
it wasn't producing very much of an
effect just a small effect and so part
of our work needs to be to figure out if
this is also a limitation in humans and
if it is a limitation in humans ways to
get around that so I mentioned we're
working with companies one of them black
being black rock there's others to come
up with well formulated tpine drugs that
and you know therapies that will
hopefully avoid any of these issues and
and help people get the relief they need
excellent and now I I jot it down the
question but I feel like you kind of
answered it when you were kind of
explaining how um one of the benefits
with using tpin is that they're
generally regarded as safe and you don't
have to kind of go through that new drug
development so is the goal really to
kind of come up with a therapeutic that
is just tpin and not sort of in
combination with
cannabinoids so I think again there's
there's room to have a lot of different
things so I think there is definitely a
space for a pure turpine um our our work
suggests that should be beneficial
particularly geranial and little are the
ones in our hands that have the lowest
side effects and the highest pain relief
you know capacity and thus you could
make like an extract or a formulated
capsule or you know a tincture that you
could do under your tongue or perhaps a
vaporization cartridge like all these
options are out there right um but our
work suggests that these drugs can be
more effective when combined with others
so part of that that paper we recently
published we did a low dose of tarpine
with a low dose of opioid and we got
higher pain relief than either one alone
so the turpine was making the opioid or
perhaps the opioid making the turpine
who knows more effective in relieving
that pain but when you can give a lower
dose of each you're decreasing the side
effects and so you know decreased
potential of that opioid giving you
constipation tolerance um somnolence
where you can't you know get to sleep
nausea and of course addiction right
that's the one that everyone's most
concerned about and indeed as I
mentioned we have data now unpublished
but still data we're actively working on
the lab suggesting that shpping at least
beta caropine will block that rewarding
property of opioid so I'm envisioning
like a combination therapy where you
take say beta caropine with an opioid of
some kind you're going to get better
pain relief make it hopefully make it
non-addictive and perhaps decrease some
of the other side effects too um and
cannabinoid so that 2021 paper we
combined the opioid or sorry the tpine
with a cannabinoid Turpin with the
canabo and saw that increased pain
relief so I think there's a place for
that too um we are our combination
studies are sort of still in their
infancy we're mostly focused on the pure
tpping but that's an area of big
development that we're going to be
pursuing in the in the years to come
well that's exciting now and and you
mentioned that you know tpin they've
been around for a long time um I know
that you know the essential oils that
you purchase I mean those yeah those are
tpin um so why do you think that you
know they haven't been studied as a
therapeutic uh really to this
point well they have somewhat and there
are a lot of papers out there I don't
want to short anyone right or kind of be
insulting there are a lot of papers out
there um but they were still limited
right so it's like we're going to take a
A turpine or turpine extract we're going
to give a certain amount to patients and
then we see the pain relief but it for
whatever reason I don't fully understand
why those next steps weren't taken like
what are the side effects what's the
what's the pharmacokinetics you know
what's the minimal dose that we need to
be effective um you know and really like
formalize and systematize this
investigation so you could really turn
it into something um I'm just
spitballing here I don't have any
evidence for that but like one of the
reasons could be because it's generally
regarded as safe maybe you can't get a
drug company interested in making a
product because you know you can't they
can't patent it um and that's where I've
been work all the companies that I've
been working with in this space are all
smaller companies right that that care
about cannabis that care about tpin
they're not looking to be fiser maybe
that's why they're the ones that are
willing to tackle it and maybe that's
why they haven't been tackled in the
past with some of larger the larger you
know groups and it could also be the
possibility that funding has been harder
to come by I don't really know so we
were able to get funding from this work
from a portion of the National
Institutes of Health the nah uh called
the national Center for complimentary
and Integrative Health the
ncci so kind of a sub subpart of the
Niah and they had this program where
they were specifically interested in
looking at Turpin and minor cannaboids
and so I will say just in general the
Cannabis field cannabinoid field has
grown a lot recently you know the last
10 10 or so years all of that has grown
funding's become more available people
are becoming more interested and then
some of these minor components or or
understudied components of the cannabis
plant like tur beans and the minor
cannabinoids those have also been
growing very strongly as well with that
interest so maybe the time is just here
yeah well that's exciting and now so as
we mentioned too Turpin they're not
exclusive to cannabis they are in other
plants and you know there are other
sources for it I know they can be
synthetically derived too so um in the
the tpin that you're working with or
even in the vision of you know what you
think the Therapeutics will eventually
be will they be derived from Cannabis or
some other
way yeah um I mean we have some reason
to believe that the the the chemical
diversity of turpins that you get from
Cannabis seems to be better than from
other plants right so other plants will
have like a couple of tpping that are
sort of dominant cannabis tends to have
a lot like we've uh you know at least 10
or 15 um me measurable turpins in the
extracts that we're looking at and
working with um but I think a lot of
that might come down to the economics
and the legal landscape which I'm
interested in but not you know fully an
expert in and so obviously there are
companies out there that are you know
can work with hemp say you know that
falls under the 3% level for the farm
bill and can get these components um but
economically maybe it would be make more
sense to take it from hops or synthetics
I don't actually know um but I will add
to that that we mostly work with
purified turpins but we have done some
tpine blend work where we take these
extracts that are purified from Cannabis
different cultivars of of cannabis and
those mixes are also highly effective in
relieving pain uh that work is not yet
published but we're working on that and
so you know maybe there's a specific
justification to to take the tpine as a
blend as an extract from Cannabis um and
then lastly just economically speaking I
think it's generally easier to to grow
bunch of plants and extract from Plants
then to say synthesize all of this in
the
lab even at the concentrations that
you're looking to
use well it's easy to to process like
you know 100 kilograms 200 kilograms ton
two tons of plant material versus uh you
know that's relative I don't want to
underplay it like that's relatively easy
to process large amounts of plant
material versus having to you know get
in the lab and synthesize it and figure
out the synthetic process and you have
these giant you know bioreactors and
everything else and extraction is is
simpler generally great um so now
thinking maybe a little bit more
practically or maybe for folks who are
out there who are trying to M use
cannabis or trines to manage their pain
um are there
certain uh tpin or combinations thereof
that they could potentially be looking
for in products that might be more
beneficial based on the work that uh
that you've done yeah I mean I don't
want to over overstate things um all of
the workers in mice you know we're still
still got a long ways to go and I'm not
a physician so I want everyone to keep
that in mind when you're kind of
evaluating this and potentially
considering trying it for yourself but
on the other hand as I mentioned these
all of these tpin are out there like you
can get them um they're generally
regarded as safe so it's it's very
unlikely to hurt you to play around with
some of these products or available and
see if it helps for you and you know in
particular some of the patients that
that we've worked with through my
collaborators my commercial
collaborators say they get great pain
relief that that nothing else has worked
for so I don't think there's anything
wrong with trying it out and so things
to look for so first of all there's a
lot of companies that say a lot of stuff
because this is sort of in the natural
product supplement space really is how
most of this gets produced and marketed
and so that uh that means that there's
not a lot of um you know like U
regulation and you know work that the
company has to do to prove that their
products have what they say they have in
them a lot of times they don't really
have to do that and but there are
companies that interested in being
reliable and and doing that work so try
to find those companies right if you ask
them how do you evaluate your turpine
levels in your comp in your products
like well we send it to this lab and
they do Mass Spec that's a good answer
right and so if you find someone that
that validates their work to produce a
high high quality product that's the
first thing I'd look for and then in
terms of individual uh tpin uh beta
caropine seems to be very common in our
hands it's certainly good at relieving
pain um that's the tping we found that
blocks the opioid reward now I don't
recommend any one start taking opioids
on my say so um but you know that's the
one that we suggest could block the
opioid reward and then Jan alino in our
hands are also some of the best single
single product tpin in terms of
relieving pain with low side effects um
but there's a ton of them there's
there's literally hundreds of Turpin and
there are other you know at least dozens
that are sort of available um
commercially you might see like names
like eugenol or bizal all all these
products I I don't I can't evaluate them
all so ultimately at the end of the day
try to find a good product try it see if
it works for you and if it does you know
nothing wrong with that yeah no and as
you mentioned there are a lot of tpin a
lot of Turin in cannabis and a lot to be
investigated so uh a lot of work yet to
be done I'm sure
absolutely all right um John Before I
Let You Go I want to give you the
opportunity if there's other resources
um that you think the audience might uh
find useful um if they want to learn
more about this topic or even you know
if there's links or papers that you've
published um definitely you can mention
them here send me a link I'll put them
in the show description as well so
people can learn more yeah absolutely so
we do have some published work on this
um I I metion I've kind of been
describing some of it as I go along uh
we also have some published work on the
minor canabo which is kind of another
interesting area so you like canaban and
canaberal and some of these other other
chemicals so we can publish links to all
that people can read at their Leisure um
as far as larger resources there are not
yet a lot of those resources available
but we're trying to build them and so uh
a big uh announcement went out at the
NIH looking for people to establish a
national cannabis Center that would sort
of provide information to the public and
be sort of a central Clearing House for
data and knowledge about cannabis how to
research it how to you know give it to
prescribe it to patients and so on that
Center is not yet in existence but we
got a very good score in our application
to do that and there's a very good
chance that you're going to be hearing
about this Center in the next year or so
so keep your ear open for that and then
in the meantime we have a a
comprehensive Center for pain and
addiction at the University of Arizona
that also provides a lot of resources
and links to scientists and clinicians
and Physicians and public health
professionals and so on all that work in
pain addiction opioids and canono and we
can have all of that available to um for
all of you to check out yeah that sounds
that sounds excellent and that you know
that Center that you were talking about
uh that that sounds really exciting and
something that's long overdue so long
overdue good good luck with that I hope
we hope to see some news on that
soon all right John well thanks again
for this for sharing this um this great
research that you're doing um and hope
to see you down in canmed next year
absolutely I'm planning on being there
should be fun all right sounds good all
right thanks Ben
[Music]
a