[Music]
welcome to the canade Coffee Talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
Minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing I am your
host Ben Amaral I'm the senior marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed
summit okay a few updates to share first
registration for the caned 25 Innovation
and investment Summit is now live check
out canmed events.com to see details
about next year's event and the new
location the Windam Resort in Rio Grande
Puerto Rico purchase your ticket package
today to take advantage of early bird
pricing second our CED 25 Advisory Board
is now up on the website this year we
have a great mix of familiar faces and
new names who will help shape the event
and assemble our best program yet lastly
the camed 25 abstract submission portal
is now open so if you have novel
research or Innovations in the areas of
cannabis science medicine cultivation or
safety testing we want to hear from you
use the link in the show description or
visit canit events .c to learn more and
good luck Our Guest today is Laura
Barrett nurse Laura is the founder and
executive director of the national
Clinical Director Consortium she is the
owner and operator of ask nurse Laura
and she's on the board of multiple
nonprofits including the Connor
Sheffield
Foundation Laura has worked in each of
the plant touching cannabis fields from
growing processing and opening dis
sensories as well as sales marketing and
compliance Laura works with providers
patients caregivers cannabis businesses
and traditional workplaces to educate
inform and collaborate to find the best
options for improving quality of life in
a safe reliable
manner Laura is currently working with
the Connor Sheffield foundation on an
observational research study about the
use of cannabis to treat symptoms of
post truma atic stress disorder during
our conversation we discuss how can
avonoids affect trauma responses and
support cognitive therapy details about
the research study including who should
participate and how data will be
collected how patients use different
routes of administration cannabinoid
ratios and dosages to manage certain
symptoms of
PTSD the challenges of doing canabo
research and the need for
standardization across the US and more
before we get to my conversation with
Laura I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor mckin
RSA mckin is made up of regulatory
science veterans who apply Lessons
Learned in the nicotine space to help
cannabis manufacturers better understand
the toxical and societal implications of
their products they do that by
identifying base compounds extracts
flavors and tpin understanding in how
they interact and ensuring Effectiveness
for the intended use they also provide
dosing recommendations and established
guidelines for product
consistency learn more at mckin
rsa.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Laura Barrett
[Music]
good morning Laura thank you so much for
joining me on the
podcast uh thank you for having me I'm
excited to be here I'm excited to talk
with you today about a study that you're
doing to better understand how cannabis
can be used to treat PTSD um oddly
enough I did a quick search of our Ked
archive on the website site where we
have all the recordings of all the
different canid presentations over the
years and I was surprised I didn't find
one about PTSD I would think that over
the years that we've been doing this
that there would be one but that's not
the case um but maybe that'll change in
20125 our abstract portal is open by the
way um till November 15 so if you or
anyone else who's studying PTSD would
like to submit one um that would be
great to see but anyway back to back to
why you're here I was wondering if you
could provide an overview of the study
kind of what are the primary objectives
and what got you interested in exploring
PTSD uh yes so thank you for asking it's
such an important question and I just
want to say that so many people I I
believe have symptoms of
PTSD and they don't even know what PTSD
is like they don't a lot of people don't
attribute what they're feeling to this
post-traumatic stress disorder and so
often I think it's kind of like
depression we overutilize the term PTSD
oh it's PTSD or it's bipolar or oh it's
depression OCD right like is it
officially diagnosed even impostor
syndrome I find myself I I I just
responded to a friend on LinkedIn and I
said impostor like symptoms rather than
saying impostor syndrome I think PTS is
the same way and so when we so this is
not just me this is a nonprofit called
the Connor Sheffield Foundation based
out of Baltimore County in
Maryland and uh we came together a
couple years ago established the
foundation because of the person Conor
Sheffield and and his need as a a young
person for cannabis and cannaboid
medicine because it's the only thing
that helped him thrive like he was a
failure to thrive couldn't gain weight
pediatric stomach motility disorder very
rare and and the only thing that worked
were cannabinoids at first mostly uh
some you know cannabal but eventually
even some THC and and now he's you know
in his early 20s and thriving and still
really relies on on cannabis medicine
and so the family and then a bunch of
volunteers came together to establish
this Foundation to raise money to do
research on cannabinoids because we
don't have a lot of it and It's Tricky
um as many of uh my peers in in cannabis
Therapeutics and cannabis medicine and
you guys have spoken about it's really
tricky to do research yeah so at first
we were really hoping that my friends at
Hopkins would do a research project with
us and and I think eventually we will do
some collaboration with them at some at
some point but um it's so so time
consuming to get an academic research
project and with the the scheduling of
of cannabis at this time is really
challenging so we went through an
independent um you know with an IRB
process since it's on people and um came
up with just doing a smaller study first
an observational study so this is not a
controlled trial we are not providing
the medicine we are just um asking
people that have symptoms or diagnosis
so you don't actually have to have had a
doctor say you have post-traumatic
stress disorder you have to have
symptoms of post-traumatic stress which
could be fear anxiety uh
sleeplessness um outbursts triggers to a
an experience that brings you back to
Vivid memories of something that
happened in the past and for some people
which I I think we don't talk about this
enough uh but again the person that our
organization is founded off of um
struggles with this um some people have
medical post-traumatic stress disorder
like having had a medical crisis and and
and struggling with it you know like if
you had a heart attack or if you had a
stroke and you were covered the
challenge of not being afraid that
that's going to happen again because in
some cases it may right right um so um
there are people who are even challenged
just by getting their checkups going to
the doctor you know uh waiting for that
lab result waiting for that next
mamogram result and so a lot of people
have
symptoms of this post-traumatic stress
disorder and so we want to include
anyone that has symptoms like that
diagnosed or
undiagnosed that is considering or has
been using uh aboid medicine purchased
from a legal dispensary so once again
they do not have to be in a state where
they have um an adult use program or
necessarily a medical program they just
have to have legally licensed
dispensaries because we want it to have
a label and and hopefully be lab tested
which honestly not every state even
requires all of the lab testing but we
like a label we we we'd like it to be
purchased
legally uh so um and and just
observational data so we are doing three
surveys and mostly yes or no questions
we are not expecting to take a lot of
time um out of someone's life out of
their day 30 days 60 days and six months
30 days 90 days and six months um and
it's just a I think about 20 question
survey mostly yes or no questions and
we're trying to
establish which cannaboids are people
using because there are a couple there
there isn't a lot of research I mean we
know it's challenging with research but
this is such a varied diagnosis or
varied amount of symptoms so a lot of
times we're looking at fear and anxiety
and and how that's related and treating
that symptom and how does that help
relate to um resolving or or dealing
with the post-traumatic stress disorder
symptoms
but should I just keep going yeah yeah
yeah I have so there is I want to give
credit to a a more recent study out of
Wayne State University in Detroit
Michigan I want to give these these
folks some credit they did uh cannaboid
modulation of brain activation during
FAL regulation of netive negative affect
in trauma exposed adult so essentially
they were looking to see if they gave
some cannabis and they gave you a
trigger how did you respond if you we
knew you had a history of
trauma and and it's um it it's really
good information I mean what they meant
essentially we're looking at is this
emotional disregulation because that is
the the one of the main things that
happens with post-traumatic stress
disorder is you the person you uh has
trouble recovering like it's not like
some people like you could see a bear
and think ooh do I run do I freeze what
am I supposed to do and then think about
it and move on hopefully get away from
the bear but someone that is has post-
trumatic stress disorder can't like
loses their ability to function and and
would go to an extreme of extreme fear
or extreme uh physical reaction or
extreme
uh depression like something that that
then takes days you know tookes a lot of
time to to move out of and so so they
they looked at this and they they did
find that as we might expect and
anticipate and I've seen in some of my
patients that when people use it really
is the the THC not so much um C CBD a
little bit but really the THC uh really
does seem to help people
um work through uh therapy like
cognitive behavioral therapy work
through it um
better
than than not not having it and and so
in their study they they used um you
know they did both because this actually
was like a trial so they have patients
who uh were using cannabis and patients
who weren't and and they found that it
did increase the C cerebella activation
uh when they saw these images and they
they had less negative side effects so
um it it's a great little study I I'll
share the link so that people can yeah
absolutely it but I was I was pleased to
see that and our goal really is just to
have a better idea of which routes of
administration people are using and and
which ratio of cannabis if they're using
a ratio or not so in in some of the few
studies maybe in the past couple of
years where they have looked at cannabis
uh THC in particular they've been um if
it's been oral either synthetic or um
you know in a natural form it's been a
lowish dose between 5 to 10 milligrams
7.5 milligrams seems to be that The
Sweet Spot and also it's been like a lot
of inhaled cannabis which is really hard
to measure and especially as a nurse
like my goal isn't for people to to need
to just smoke all day you know that's
not really the goal we'd like to be able
to to find some some baseline like oh if
you take a a 4 to one tablet so four
times the THC to onetime CBD uh in this
low dose uh twice a day like maybe it'll
keep your symptoms at Bay so that you
could be functional at work and
functional taking care of your grandkids
and functional
just to to feel good in your life and
and potentially to use some of these
cannabinoids to do the uh n the the
regular more
traditional psychological therapy like
cognitive behavioral therapy to
potentially heal from recover from some
of these
issues I have some amazing uh veteran
patients you know because that's a big
population that is known to uh suffer
from post-traumatic stress disorder and
uh using some
THC again in in the right amount once we
kind of figure out what that right
amount is I have had stories from
patients who weren't able to sleep in
bed at night with their spouse because
of nightmares and outbursts and a fear
of injuring their spouse in the middle
of the night or or just scaring them
even from you
know yelling and um we have been able to
again not medical advice but with
encouragement and education uh have some
of these people I mean some amazing
Stories like I can sleep in bed with my
spouse now I used to have to sleep in
another room sometimes even with a
locked door I mean I've heard some
really extreme situations and um that
sleep piece and and pressing the the REM
sleep which is the dream sleep which is
a lot of times where the nightmares
occur uh seems to be really beneficial
so I I I have so many peers that are
more experts than I am in some of these
individual Fields uh but as a nurse just
trying to bring that holistic picture
together the whole person and looking at
how do we make them the most productive
in the daytime the best rested at night
uh to be uh the their best version of
themselves is is really the goal so
that's really interesting so you
mentioned that the THC is helpful
because it sort of suppresses the REM
sleep or so it's actually kind of
blocking them from getting uh into REM
sleep and having those dreams that can
trigger the the trauma yes that's my
understanding and and I think it's
really beautiful and there was a short
time which I needed to rely on some of
my expert peers uh which you know we
always have more to learn and we need
more research there was a short time
where I was concerned that uh so
many patients people consumers users
were using THC for sleep and maybe not
getting enough quality sleep right of
that but we have to look at each
individual person and look at if you
sleep well if you're not using cannabis
at nighttime and you sleep well my
recommendation education is don't start
like why why would you do that right if
you don't need to why would you do
that however many people use things like
alcohol because they think alcohol helps
them fall asleep and maybe it does help
them fall asleep but it really doesn't
give us quality sleep at all we know
that for a fact so for many people
cannabis can give them THC in particular
can give them better sleep than the
sleep that they are
getting right have to just look at those
individual things and figure out maybe
it is inhaled cannabis just a few hours
before bed that helps them fall asleep
if falling asleep is their issue or or
maybe it is some type of edible capsule
something that's going to last longer in
in uh even some cases uh an extracted
oil like RSO uh that will give them a
longer to help them stay asleep
specifically if they have pain or
post-traumatic stress disorder
nightmares other things maybe even uh
women's issues like menopausal symptoms
hot flashes might be helpful and I know
this whole episode isn't to talk about
sleep and cannabis however
post-traumatic stress disorder a lot of
people experience those symptoms during
the night that's a big part some people
have it just trying to fall asleep when
all of a sudden all the noise of the
world gets quiet and then suddenly all
the anxiety and fear and the racing
thoughts come in and the Cannabis THC in
particular helps to break those racing
thoughts stop that that in your head so
um it can be really beneficial and so
we're looking to
gather our minimum is 300 people I keep
telling everybody I want a thousand so
we really have no limitation it it's
very short amount of time yes or no
questions only three
surveys and I just hope that people will
consider it's all through uh the
tetragram app which which if if your
viewers if our viewers don't already
know um I want to give a plug to
tetragram the app uh because it's a
beautiful free app that consumers can
use where you can track like Journal
your cannabis uh medicine you can in
some cases scan the barcode on the
product and have all the data pull in
for you uh Physicians and and providers
can have group group of patients and
kind of share information and track
through groups like different types of
patients it it's really beneficial so
we're using that app to collect the data
so it's like on your phone or on your
iPad or computer really quick for
somebody to do and the more people we
have the more we'll be able to you know
have a better analysis of of what does
seem to work best for most people you
just have to be over 21 and purchasing
again from a legal
dispensary yeah and so so you mentioned
using the app and being able to journal
and and track your usage and everything
so I know that you also mentioned
there's sort of three different surveys
at different time points but are you
also kind of collecting data kind of in
between those points as well if people
are are journaling and and tracking
things in the app yes so in the app
anytime anyone logs anything like that
data will be there and they they have
the option you know in or opt out of
certain things right we we don't we want
to make sure that we keep privacy but we
we do we have lots of um points uh in
app that we can collect even as simple
as like age which is important it's good
to know you know is are these younger
people dealing with this are they older
people and the specific symptoms so you
have the option to say I'm using
cannabis to manage PTSD symptoms but
then more specifically which symptoms
are you having right because again some
people have more Outburst some people
have more um social anxiety disorder
like it just it just depends some people
have insomnia and they're not sleeping
because of it uh so so that's a part of
it you know is it preventing you from
working like those
things and then we also can even track
like by the state so we can see you know
which states and which products people
are using in which states uh to give us
an idea aide of where we need to
encourage more development of newer um
processed products because again in in
some cases people are inhaling and that
way they just have access to flour and
strains which can be great and they can
track in the app like different tpes and
the
ratios and then we also need to look at
is it is it better in a more edible form
or is it is anyone using a topical does
a does a topical
help someone that is being triggered
like if they put a topical rub on their
neck you know or or do a little bit of
self massage uh to to release and do
some breathing does that relieve their
symptoms I mean it could all the
different ways that you could support
your end endoc canabo system could help
so it's just interesting it'll be
interesting to see that that data we
just need people to sign up
yeah we'll put a link right in the show
description so people can easily get to
it and either participate or share it
with someone who uh they know that
they're a good fit for it so yeah I I
was curious how are people using
cannabis kind of to treat their symptoms
is it sort of like a a preventative
thing or like a a kind of
daily um usage just to kind of keep
symptoms at Bay or do they actually use
it um in an acute situation where like
you said having a panic attack or having
an episode ingesting cannabis to kind of
get back to Baseline that's a really
great question so first of all for the
the research study we just started
collecting patients in October so we're
we're still in the data collection um or
well Ian we don't even have any data yet
we we're still in the patient
recruitment part of of that study um and
then once we get all the patients and we
sort of close off which I think we're
doing January 1st then we're going to do
um we have that like six months is the
survey so so there's that uh but in my
practice so I am um independent I work
as a consultant I'm a registered nurse
and I I coach people and work with
people alongside of their doctor
um as a bridge my my favorite thing to
say about nursing and cannabis is well
holistic and plant medicine overall is
is we are the bridge we're the bridge
between the provider and the dispensary
for the patient we're the bridge between
like uh traditional medicine and then
holistic and integrative medicine I'm
writing a book nurses are the bridge
coming soon hopefully by Puerto Rico uh
so as that nurse coach nurse educator in
in my practice with patients I have
many people that that have um suffered
from like sexual
trauma domestic violence and
uh many of them are women and many of
them have like an overwhelming sense of
Doom every day and there really
aren't a good group of or a good
protocol for prescription medications
I'm I'm a medicine nurse but I'm very
much also for integrating traditional
Pharmaceuticals we just don't have a lot
of traditional
Pharmaceuticals that that work or that
you have to take so many or the side
effects are so much that that can
relieve the symptoms so I have people
getting back to your question that take
a a a low dose of just something
routinely which we have some pretty good
uh data and some of our our friends that
are very involved with uh canmed and
medicinal genomics would share that you
know one to one equal amounts of CBD and
THC have have been known in low doses to
be helpful for anxiety and so I do have
some people that that utilize those
types of routes of administration we're
getting more data more research recently
about another canono CB G being really
helpful also for
anxiety but to your point depending on
when their symptoms are worse generally
so if it's not that they just wake up
every day with that impending doom and
need something if it is more about being
in the world and being triggered like
potentially somebody that was in a
traumatic car accident uh might have
anxiety just every time they have to get
in the car and drive and
I'm not going to encourage people to
smoke a little bit before they get in
the car and drive we have to be
thoughtful right so in though that case
we definitely would be considering a
less
intoxicating um route uh less cannaboid
and and less intoxicating route we want
people to be safe on the road but if it
is that they're going to be uh home or
they're in an environment where they're
not the driver uh then potentially if
they are triggered how having an
inhalation option available whether that
is uh in inhaling like a lot of times
honestly I tell people with um
post-traumatic stress disorder and like
panic attacks related to it to consider
carrying a vape pen like like it's an
epip pen so so have it on you you don't
have again in a legal state where you
legally can use it have it there just
just knowing you have it might help you
you might not even need to use it but
it's easier and more accessible than
having to actually light something and
smoke it in environments where with the
state of our country we would still not
be be able to do that
everywhere but I have had experience
with multiple uh patients where just
having it in their purse on their person
just knowing they have it has been
enough for their brain to release the
sympathetic
nervous system get back to um a more
natural response um and and feel feel
better and or they can take a puff or
two and immediately have some relief so
I I think it can be used and I'm
interested to see the the survey uh
responses because I think it can be used
for like the in the moment but we would
be looking my my goal for PE most people
is hopefully to prevent having to even
get to that having to prevent those
feelings because when our body is
releasing all that cortisol and going
through that that triggered response uh
it's it's unhealthy for us it doesn't
feel good I mean I've had panic attacks
it doesn't feel good so I I would prefer
it if we could just keep the edge off
that and utilize the tools of cannabis
medicine plant medicine and maybe
entheogenic medicine some psychedelics
to to do the work do the therapy retrain
our brain to to learn a new
response yeah excellent another thing I
wanted to ask you about is is dosage and
probably kind of a corollary to that as
well would be sort of the the ratio of
the canono too I'm just speaking from
personal experience one of the things
that you talked about was sort of like
trying to sleep having racing thoughts
and things like that I've actually had
issues with that if I have too much THC
or if it's not the right strain for me I
can't fall asleep because I have those
racing thoughts and can't stop them so I
imagine with someone who struggles with
that uh with
PTSD finding the right ratio at the
right dosage is is
critical yes it's really important and
and that's why you know it's so
interesting to think about how many of
the dispensaries across the country sell
gummies that are 10 milligrams as like
the the starting dose 10 milligrams of
THC starting dose anybody walks in we
have all of these
seniors I think they like to be called
something else
now wise people over 65 who who you know
they smoked in college or they smoked
way back when and then now we have it
legal so they go to a dispensary and
they're like yeah I want to take a gummy
to sleep my neighbor does it it sounds
fun and they get this 10 milligram gummy
and they take it and and maybe even they
take half to start because somebody
maybe told them that and then they feel
nothing an hour later so they take the
other half and then for many people
instead of falling
asleep they start to feel a little
paranoid or anxious or their heart's
racing and thankfully it's not going to
hurt them but once again it doesn't feel
good and my goal is to help people feel
good that's what I want to do and and I
think at the dispensaries that the the
people that are working at the counter
they want people to feel good too it's
just that they have um their endoc
canono system is primed they know
they're ready and they don't always
think about when someone says oh yeah
I've used cannabis before because
they're at the counter trying to be cool
and feeling intimidated by the young
person standing behind the counter and
the store self uh so generally I
recommend super low THC doses with
higher CBD at first uh and and I'm I'm
just not even getting into like all of
the cbda and CBG there are so many
cannaboids it's it's too much to just
try to give a quick but for the most
part
CBD canabidol is very available uh from
hemp and from Cannabis in our study you
have have to be purchasing from a
cannabis dispensary uh however um higher
CBD uh uh generally like 25 milligrams
and up uh with just a tiny bit maybe 2.5
milligrams of
THC and again I have to say this because
I have a nursing license I'm not a
doctor this is not medical
advice this is just education something
for you to consider and so um that can
be a good starting Place uh the the
canabal can really be helpful for um
relaxation and reducing anxiety we know
it's good for anxiety and inflammation
and there are some connections between
anxiety and inflammation interestingly
enough too uh which is why some of the
other cannabinoids and gut brain health
um are worth
considering but usually I'll encourage
people to start with that and and try
that for at least least four days but
potentially a couple weeks and just see
are we getting any benefit and then we
work our way up and yes some people end
up at 10 milligrams of THC and and maybe
if if you take lower doses can of a dial
is is B phasic meaning at one dose it
does one thing at another dose it does
another thing and so lower doses can
also like make you want to stay up and
read a book all night which it might not
feel feel anxious but you're also not
sleeping or make you too creative so
it's important to to understand some of
that Dynamic and just do a little bit of
um homework on that or talk to somebody
like me and uh but for some people they
might end up going towards mostly all
THC and and for people with a lot of
pain again it all depends on the person
and what what is keeping them awake if
it's racing thoughts that's one thing if
it's pain I mean some people do take a
40 milligram gummy which they sell in
some of the medical markets uh for
bedtime because they have that much pain
so they're taking that instead of taking
a bunch of opioids at bedtime and benzo
you know benzos and all these other
medications and and that keeps the pain
at Bay and also helps them sleep so it
it is a range it really is important to
to start
start low and go slow
y um and see how your body responds and
give your body time to respond yep
there's a reason we keep saying
that it's because it's true but I think
one of the things you mentioned before
about the value of the the study that
you're doing is to try to identify what
are those good ratios and make sure that
they're available to people in other
states because I know that's not the
case everywhere you they might not have
sort of that High CBD low THC ratio like
in some some states uh it's just all THC
you're lucky if you find any CBD so I
think that's that would be a great
benefit of of this work is to really
figure out what that good ratio is and
inform the the industry yes that's one
of the things I'm really grateful I
because I'm independent uh I don't I'm
not uh like full-time employed by
anybody just me ask nurse Laura and I I
love that I get to work uh because with
with nursing I can work in in other
states and talk to companies and talk to
uh researchers about about the different
products also in the hemp space and and
what what's out there that we're seeing
as beneficial and where are those gaps
what's missing and to educate people on
how to be a smart um hemp consumer even
like how to to find a reliable hemp
company um thankfully in our Network we
have some good people that have some
good products but there also is a lot of
garbage out there I did a secret shopper
campaign in the state of
Delaware and and for for hemp shops and
it was kind of scary what we found and
and it's a lot because it's not so
regulated
um so I just want to encourage people to
do their homework and and uh learn how
to dig into the details not just trust
you know like Google reviews and and not
just trust a handshake you know we need
to know what we're getting what we're
putting in our body because even if
today it doesn't cause a negative effect
uh some of the the things that might be
in some of these products might cause
issues down the road that we don't even
know about yeah no that could be a whole
that could be a whole other podcast and
actually I think we should do that uh I
think it's really interesting and um it
was one of the things I was going to ask
but then I remembered that you know that
the study is restricted to getting
products from a dispensary because I was
curious you know are people using hemp
diive cannabinoids or sort of these
synthetic cannabinoids like delta8 THC
or some of these other things for ptst I
think that would be interesting uh maybe
a later
study yes yes we we you know well maybe
you don't know but when you're trying to
get approved by an
IRB it it is an independent review board
it it's a lot of work and there are a
lot of specifics that you have to follow
and and we're trying to do everything
like this is our first study we hope to
do so many more research projects uh but
you have to do something to get off the
ground and so we had to find ways to
sort of level the playing field just a
little bit sure and we do have
um regulations so there's a a group
called uh canra the Cannabis Regulators
Association that brings together
cannabis Reg Regulators from multiple
States uh and and they talk and and
hopefully at some point we're going to
have some more standard across the
country that's one of the challenges
that that I find is is standards from
state to state accessibility from state
to state it it really is challenging and
uh to to take the time to figure out
what the regulations are like what what
are the standards in this state uh
especially for business owners so I have
a contract with Bright View Assisted
Living because they want their uh
residents to be able to access cannabis
and utilize cannabis in their facilities
some of these people are this is the end
of their life is going to be in this
facility they want them to have a good
quality of life they operate in eight
states up and down the east coast and
even in the states they all have medical
programs but they have different rules
and different products in each of their
programs and trying to stand I a policy
and standardize implementation for them
it is really
challenging absolutely that's yeah we I
mean we deal with that medicinal
genomics you know making the testing
kits for all the different states and
trying to figure out what needs to be
tested in each of the different states
we have a tool on our website that tries
to make sense of it um but yeah it's
it's a full-time job I mean we have our
Regulatory Affairs team that's sort of
that's their job is to stay on top of
all the different changing regulations
and inform our R&amp;D about the different
tests it's yeah it's a hodg podge and I
think we're all dealing with it at at
different levels and we would love some
standardization it would really help us
yes and and it's interesting too because
it's in the cannaboids in the
dispensaries and also that the hemp is
just and again I'm a huge fan of hemp
derived canabo yeah just you have to
know the company
and really dig into where the hemp is
coming from how it's processed what it's
processed with who's testing it is it
really a third party is it really every
batch you know there's just
because at least shopping in a
dispensary depending on the state you
you know what the standards are that
they have to uphold and I'm lucky to
have started my journey in cannabis
healthc care and cannabis medicine in
Maryland that has some really strict
regulations around that um I actually
opened a grow facility and a processing
lab in three dispensaries when I first
came in about 10 years ago so I really
was like deep into the weeds like I was
the person with the lab coming to do our
samples and reading the reports so I I I
have some personal
experience and even that is kind of
interesting because if they're testing
it on day seven or day 10 of its curing
there are different results you know
absolutely or how much do we get to
reprocess and retest I mean it's it's
just it's a yeah that's a whole big
question and concern for health care
providers because I think that's part of
the reason that Physicians feel so
comfortable
prescribing prescriptions right for
giving out prescriptions because they
have gone through all these very
specific very regulated very precise
things to be replicated and with a plant
it's more challenging and with different
rules and regulations in every state
it's it's just much more challenging and
so we need nurses to be the
bridge absolutely absolutely we need you
need you to come to canmed and get
educated and meet some great people too
yeah all right um well Laura thanks so
much for doing this before I let you go
I just want to give you an opportunity
to um either plug the study or other
resources that people can can view if
they're interested in learning more
about this and then um other ways that
they can get in contact with you and uh
learn about what you're doing thank you
so much yes I want to say I mentioned
the Connor Sheffield foundation and I'm
sure we'll put links for that in the the
show notes um it is not just me I don't
want to I am just the face here today
it's a whole group of people uh Renee
rininger is our um Chief investigator
and then the the whole team the Connor
Sheffield family uh OA from tetragram we
have um Shena and uh quite a few other
people that are working with us so I
just want to make sure maybe I'll give
you a list of everyone I'd love for
everyone to have it's not just me I just
happen to be you know the nurse that's
here talking today and um yeah I I
really hope that people will sign up for
our study we'll have a link we have a QR
code again it's not that difficult not
that timec consuming
I also have my independent practice
which is ask nurse Laura you can find me
on all social media at ask nurse Laura
and uh and then a group called The
National Clinical Director Consortium
which is a group of healthcare providers
across the country nurses doctors and
pharmacists we might even after the last
conference I was um speaking to some
speech therapists and some physical
therapists who also want to be involved
because patients people are bringing up
cannaboid medicine they're talking to
the people that are helping them to heal
along all different
Journeys and we need to come together
and utilize each other as
resources so um I'll put a link to that
you can look that up see if you're any
type of healthc care provider interested
we we really just meet to sort of
support each other and talk about how
we're helping our patients and uh speak
at conferences and potentially help with
some advocacy work really big goal we've
been working on for years now is like
getting cannabis into hospitals and
health care
facilities and then last but not least
don't forget I'm writing a book coming
soon nurses are the bridge so hopefully
I'll get that
published wow you're
busy yeah excellent well happy to have
you on the podcast and excited to see
you down in Puerto Rico for CED
25 thank you so much thanks for having
me
[Music]