[Music]
is total abstinence from THC a a
solution I would say it is the textbook
solution um
how in your experience um with
abstinence uh
how do you people
do can be difficult leave some to be
desired right uh Megan Have You Ever
Seen I'm sure you've seen patients go
abstinent but have you ever seen anybody
you know not go abstinent um I mean all
the time people continue to to use often
not believing their diagnosis that's
right right or that they feel like they
can still continue to use low amounts
and manage their symtoms that way um but
for the like that is interestingly like
one of the only published criteria for
CHS is you know that symptoms if your
symptoms go away after six months of
abstinence then it's likely that you had
CHS six months ago so um but it is you
know if it's like the the presumed cause
then taking away the cause is likely
going to be the solution and I think
that for some reason that pisses a lot
of people off like we're actually
getting at the root cause of this and
they're like there's no cure for it well
you take away the cause of
it which is uh that's an interesting you
know Paradigm that I see um but but yeah
it's um that really is the only the only
known thing to help with CHS and it's
recovery is a roller coaster it's not
like you stop using and then your
symptoms go away and you know stopping
use can then trigger episodes down the
line and um and people are using their
cannabis to stop an episode from
happening and then they stop using and
then it triggers an episode or they have
stopped using for a couple of months and
then they e some food that triggers them
or alcohol or stressful event triggers a
CHS episode and they haven't used in
three months so recover now they don't
think they have CHS right right because
this disregulation or this imbalance
bance sort of lingers in our system for
an extended period of time patients
sometimes reporting 12 months before
they feel whole again from a GI
perspective the damage and the the
inflammation that went on during their
EP and you remember people suffered for
years without knowing right there are
people on these discussion boards that
suffered for 15 years with a condition
they'd seen every doctor no one knew
what it was right and they've been
taking medicine and had all the Scopes
and done everything um but the where did
I how did I get on this point Megan um
don't remember you just talking recovery
recovery being a roller coaster right so
so what I always counsel my patients on
is like you know we like patient
yesterday hadn't consumed cannabis in
nine days and she was in the middle of
an episode and it was triggered you know
at Disneyland from uh a hot burrito a
beia taco or something of this effect
right and that's what set her off into
into this this problem so so we don't
you know um we don't
fully know what the the timeline looks
like we're going to ask you questions
about this if you take our survey or you
send this to your friend we're going to
ask about how long after you quit did
you have symptoms but I can tell you in
my personal um you know practice
experience I am not a CS CHS sufferer
but in my experience talking to patients
that have it we're
seeing um easily seven days usually 21
to 30 days and sometimes 60 plus days of
oh I just had an episode again don't
know what it was didn't know maybe it
was stress like Megan said maybe it was
some weird food that you thought you
could try again because it made you sick
a long time ago but it happened we don't
know but we're trying to put that
together so we can use that to educate
patients help them know because
Physicians aren't telling patients to I
shouldn't say any most Physicians are
not not telling folks that hey you might
have more vomiting over the next few day
you should expect to have more vomiting
over the next few days even though I
believe you and you quit three days ago
and that conversation is not happening
because phans aren't aware enough or
frankly the data doesn't help them right
now there's not a lot of evidence for
them to lean on and say oh yeah most
patients will have another episode in
the next 21 days they don't have that
information so that's what again the
survey is trying to give them some info
to lean on to more quickly and
definitively know sort of how to
categorize and then how to treat as
opposed to throwing a label on something
throwing an anti psychotic to help get
them out of the emergency room and
sending people on their merry way which
unfortunately happens more often than
not yeah no that's that's new to me like
I said done a few episodes on this and
seen some canmed talks on it and
obviously seen other things um I didn't
realize that the the roller coaster of
recovery there I thought you know you
you abstain your your symptoms go away
um it's really interesting that other
things can sort of trigger it and I mean
not that I'm a clinician but my thought
with that and you could tell me if I'm
on the right track is you know other
things are interfacing with the endoc
canabo system not just cannabinoids and
other things can can kind of cause uh
spikes in your endoc can avonoids so do
you think that's perhaps what's going on
like certain stressors triggers um can
sort of
just disre I'll hit on on one point of
that is that um often times people in
recover
[Music]