[Music]
so you mentioned rescheduling and I
think that's something that we're all
sort of watching and hopeful for that
there we'll see some movement there but
so say um it does get rescheduled I
think what schedule three is one of is
what's on the table here how would
things change for you if if that were to
happen
well it's going to change a lot of
things um so schedule three is like
camine um and I think tan Cod number
three is in schedule three also so first
of all it's still going to be federally
legal
illegal but locally I could do a
prospective study looking at cannabis in
a treatment of I'm going to give you an
example I do have a protocol which I
wrote for this for chronic migraine
migraines defined by marting 15
headaches a month uh and I can look at a
uh Placebo or a 20 to1 1:1 ratio and 5
10 15 20 milligram that's a perspective
study there'll be several arms I could
do that you can ask me who's gonna fund
that I'm gonna say right now nobody
who's going to fund it we're GNA fund it
uh I have a benevolent um uh uh family
Dent family Dent was a uh philanthropist
back in the 60s who by the way had
Parkinson's diseas started Institute in
1963 and there is a family
non-for-profit Family Foundation that
supports research within the Institute
and they by the way for the last six
seven years have unequivocally supported
my research in cannabis and that and
that's
and that has given me the opportunity to
publish to put us on the map they still
support but we're not talk about
Millions we're talking about significant
amount but they do support us so yeah
I'm gonna get some seed money from them
to
support a study if I can do that if it
becomes a schedule three drug and then I
can publish that article prospectively
randomiz
study part of the money from seed money
from the dent Family Foundation
part of the money through the dent
cannabis clinic will you know we
readjust money to put it in research uh
so instead of putting it in our pockets
we'll put it in research self-funded if
you want to use the term and then we
could publish that once we publish that
I could show it to the insurance
companies I can show it to the medical
societies and then then let them
critique it and you know one of the
things is one of the problems I think
you may understand is cannabis medical
marijuana or medical cannabis programs
are too expensive for patients yeah now
I did it a way about I did a way you
don't have to pay me cash that's a
positive for the patient right but they
have to pay in cash and some of these
patients are paying $800 a month they
can't afford it and let me be honest
with you in the medical marijuana
program most of the people can't afford
it and because they can't afford it and
the insurance companies throw their arms
up say you know we're sympathetic we
know that if you put somebody on medical
marijuana they'll tell take less opioids
they'll take less Xanax they'll take
less sleeping pills they'll take less uh
anti-inflammatories so it's good for the
insurance companies but they fall back
on the fact no research yeah so if I
have a prospective study the first thing
I'm going to do is present it to every
CEO of every insurance companies because
let's pay for this because you a I say
gave you money I keep patients out of
emergency rooms they have less testing
because their quality of life have
improved and they're L using less drug
so that's the first thing I'll do so
that may change something uh at that
level then the medical societies will
look at it critique it uh it'll be
published in uh in peer review journals
which is very important and maybe we
start moving at the medical society
level uh so I'm optimistic that for me
it's going to be fine it's going to be a
step in the right direction I'm not sure
if it's going to help the business of
cannabis because that's still federally
legal there's still taxation
issues um um banking issues as you all
know and yeah I don't get involved in
that I just read what I read so but in
my perspective I think it's a positive
move yeah so will insurance companies
they will well I mean there's a lot that
goes into it but be it being a schedule
three drug which would not you know
preclude them from from covering
it it could be a schedule three drug but
it but anything you use it for it's off
label because it's off label because
it's not not been approved in that
disease for example uh what disease say
migraine that's makes it easy 36 million
migrain in this country 36 or 700,000
patient in the United States with FS
yeah that's a lot of
patients will they prove it they won't
because show me the research right right
right how can I prove a drug off label
that there's no science that shows it
works then you go testimonials well I
have patients who can't live without it
that doesn't count it doesn't
testimonials don't
count randomized phase two phase three
studies do count yeah so that's what
we'll have to do and we'll do
it
[Music]
a