thank you very much for having me here
for me it's quite moving you've event
because exactly 25 years ago I graduated
here from Kennedy School in my master
and public administration so to come
back after 25 years to this city and to
this event thank you very much for the
opportunity I used to call my lecture
from illegal substance in the promising
medication it's a process that we are
only beginning and this fascinating
process and we must do it as it was said
a minute ago we are not supposed to wait
to collect all the proofs and all the
data we have patients I'm a family
physician an active one for the last 40
years tomorrow and flying back and
Friday morning I'm going to see patients
again I believe that they good
administrators in medical services and
the center should see patients in Y that
were given the perspective of the human
relationship and on the all things
involved now Israel became kind of
pioneer in this process I think we owe
all the change to Professor McCollum was
the first one to describe to find THC
and his search guidelines for us at this
time we work with him even today in two
occasions that I attended I was told by
other people not Israelis that Professor
Milan ought to have a Nobel Prize for
his work but that he will never have I'm
sure
this audience is sympathetic
but he will never get it because of this
is being such a sexy but also
problematic issue about the recreational
use I told the story to Professor
McCollum and he laughed very much and
said unfortunately those who think so
I'm not sitting in Stockholm in the
Institute is a half million population
during the last ten years we approved
almost 30,000 50,000 licenses I'm
speaking about license because Israel is
also obliged by the International
Convention of narcotics and we cannot
allow it to be medication until the
International approach will be changed
and I believe that you with your
research and with the change of the
attitude of the American states one
after the other analysis should lead
this change in the international bodies
and then everything will be a lot
quicker at that point in my office
since being the chief medical adviser to
the Minister of Health I signed all
those licenses once again not a
prescription but a license to whole to
have illegal substance for medical
purposes every day on my desk we have
between 200 to 300 when we now we have a
holiday Passover as you know so I'm
expecting be coming back after the
holidays to have about two three
thousand requests on my desk of course I
don't do it by myself
27,000 are active patients active I mean
they took
the substance from the dispensary during
the last three months we were speaking
this morning about the process there is
a tremendous pressure from the media and
from politicians in Israel I suppose
partially it's also here to promote the
cannabis usage a for the last two years
we have Health Minister rabbi Richman
and when he came to the office I asked
him please I need to update you for new
things in the in the market in a medical
field and his first reaction was he
calls me Mickey we work together in
previous assignments and we I don't want
to hear a word about it
it took for him to year two weeks in the
office to call me urgently please come
here I want to know everything about it
because every news media person every
politician doesn't want to speak about
anything else just they ask me about
cannabis mostly for members of the
families and this is very crucial point
we presented our Minister a plan which
was later on adapted by the government
and since then we are promoting this
area I'll mention it later
we are very enthusiastic about research
I serve as a member in the Research
Committee which we have the home of the
professor McCollum is the chairman of
this committee and during the last year
we approved 130 research proposals 30
out of them clinical studies that are
now in process
I'm not speaking much about it you know
this single convention of narcotic drugs
the Israeli registration can be
something which is different but the
governmental decision allowed us to use
it according to the Minister of Health
indications instructions rules whatever
you want to call it and all of them are
published in our web so every physician
and every patient can look and say look
how beautiful the message section I'm
entitled to cannabis in the enjoy it we
have a problem with old-fashioned
physicians as you say thick and thick
old dog new tricks that is the verb it's
difficult I'm going from I go from one
meeting to another for in hospitals
Ejim O's weekends my my wife likes it
very much we spend the weekend I give a
lecture and trying to teach but nothing
is mentioned in medical schools and that
is part of the problem another problem
is this mix-up of issues like we talked
this morning there is this recreational
issue there is the medical I'm a medical
site only each time I open the
Parliament being the representative the
sending representative of the Minister
of Health the politician asked me what
about recreational use and my answer is
always look I'm a physician I'm in
charge of this medical part the
recreational use is a social decision
that should be done by politicians
elections
whatever you say not by me not by
physicians but when they press me well
you cannot sit here as a senior
presentative of the ministry not even an
open
in then I say okay it will have its
costs like an alcohol like nicotine this
also decision was that you can sell
nickels to every person over 18 okay you
have the results cannabis is a lot
better than alcohol but it has its own
price as well just few numbers the
evolution of the numbers numbers of
requests that during the last trees I'm
in my office for the last four years
it was increased from 32,000 to almost
55 licenses as I mentioned almost 28,000
average amount and this is very tricky
figure because I'm never sure exactly
when we approve 20 grams what is the
percentage of THC or CBD in those grams
so this is quite a tricky number in our
instructions for the next year it will
be mentioned very specifically hey
during the last year at least legally we
dispense almost one tonne of cannabis
928 kilos the average amount for
patients is 33 grams I have some
heritage from my friends that were
running this subject before with people
getting up to 200 grams a month
personally I'm very I have doubts about
the person using such amount alone
they usually have help
the evolution of cannabis as I mentioned
more patients smaller doses it is not
worth waste of administration well one
of the pictures disappeared
most probably illegal picture inhalation
sublingual and oral we do not we didn't
allow until now skin preparations and
were very afraid of cookies our general
director of the ministry was very
concerned about the problem that the
grandchildren eat grandma's cookies
which could be bed I want to mention
that if you think what what how do you
want to be taken but there is a
development now of an Israeli start
start up I will not change the name and
I don't have any part in this company
unfortunately they prepare inhalers you
all know this inventor in all those
asthma treatments they have this inhaler
with small heating device I suppose most
of you know that in order to reactivate
the substance you need to heat it to 184
Celsius degrees so they built a small
device which makes the heating and then
he can inhale exact amount very
efficient and I hope that in next few
years we will stop this smoking issue
which is a physician I don't like it and
give it in inhalation or many in other
ways how to get cannabis
we have a very structured process every
specialist in the country can recommend
a cannabis within his own specialization
oncologist pain control physician
neurologist pediatric neurologist
psychiatrist he needs to fill form
computerized form and said sent it to
our office with the whole medical
history of the patient why I insist on
the medical history because many times
the prescribing physician is very
distinguished specialist and he knows
everything about Neurology he knows
nothing about the sacked psychiatry
condition of the patient or his lung
situation so for that purpose I insist
on having the whole history of the
patient which we can check and approve
approve the usage in case of psychotic
history when I come to the main
contraindication today severe
psychiatric problems history of
addiction are in our opinion a relative
contraindication weiss a relative
because some psychiatrist can say okay
he was one see as the problem and now
he's okay we can give him cannabis if
he's in unstable condition maybe not at
that time
we have difference of opinion dr.
Resnick who is he'll is he believed that
it's almost not existent very small
numbers had the same more but some say
between one to ten percent of people of
patients with pre-existing psychiatric
conditions they tend
to be hospital not hospitalized but the
new treatment so this is today the most
significant contraindication to medical
treatment of cannabis and I believe that
infused and we'll know more about the
subtypes I mean about maybe some types
of THC will be consistent with this
situation but I don't know it
I have 15 physicians working for me they
see all the applications and after the
approve it it is it comes to my
signature unfortunately I'm the only one
allowed to sign it because all other
physician refused why because there was
a tremendous pressure intimidation for
them you must approve it otherwise so I
got all the pressure on me and my wife
not deny all the phone calls the nasty
phone calls telling her what they think
and Mary about my mother which is not
true I promise to you but but we
survived the license after a son is
transferred to one of the eight
companies today we have eight companies
distributing cannabis to the patients at
the beginning of treatment day each one
needs to have teaching one hour teaching
how to use it we found that in many
cases people didn't use it correctly and
at that point they didn't enjoy the
treatment after being after they learn
how to use it the percentage of success
is very very high since it is a license
and since we want them to be followed by
their physician we ask to renew the
license I mean to renew the
request for a continuation of treatment
every year sometimes every six months in
special cases this is basically medical
decision what is the interval between
the follow-up meetings increase of
dosage during the most of the patient
ask for higher doses of cannabis we
decided that it will be done gradually I
saw one of the presenters yesterday they
said start row and increase row
something like that and yes this is what
we believe
I wanted the follow-up responsibility to
be transferred to primary care
physicians family physicians like me
they are afraid they are afraid because
in those places when it was started a
lot of people came to us for cannabis
when the physician didn't think it was
appropriate the moment you have two
markets one medical market one
recreational market of course this kind
of leakage and kind of influence I
mentioned 28,000 patients being treated
according to our estimations we have 1
million people who use cannabis for
recreational use once a week once a
month even the party whatever and our
medical cannabis has a reputation of
being a good one so they try to bite and
for some patients it's quite the
temptation to sell part of the part of
the staff indication we have an
indication committee which I gather once
once a month every two months each time
I ask the physician to prepare homework
the best physician in this field they
prepare the homework and suggestion for
decision
we'd discuss it and then if it is
approved it appears in our web as an
indication as an approved education
sometimes people ask for comedies for
cannabis when they do not fit the
indication so it's not entirely my
decision I have a build committee and
all those cases that fall between the
chairs we discuss them the last meeting
we had 60 requests and 54 out of them
were approved so we really try to be
open to things that we know don't know
much enough about this expert committee
evaluates the nude indication and the
old one in one case only glaucoma the
American ophthalmology Association
decided that it is not useful in
glaucoma it does not reduce the
intraocular pressure and they stopped
cancer the indication we followed them
and this is the only case I remember
that we abolished stopped existing
indication oncology 40% of our patients
are oncology patients I don't have to
mention many things you know it helps
them to stop vomiting usually you can
stop the opiates and they they don't
have constipation anymore they can eat
they can sleep and they look better and
I find myself in the parliament asking
an answering question why don't you
allow cannabis for treatment of cancer
to all the patients and it is not that
simple to explain the Parliament members
the difference between a treating
cannabis letting the cancer and treating
symptoms and I really hope the next few
years will find what types of cancer
how can we help them with cannabis for
the time being
it's symptomatic treatment only primary
and secondary metastatic pain of course
end-of-life we do try to be as quick as
as helpful as possible then it's quite a
problem with this continuation of
treatment for example if I have a lady
after mastectomy she was given cannabis
with oncology person a patient and after
5 years she is perfectly okay as a
physician I believe she is completely
cured but to stop the cannabis it is a
problem not that much about habit
formation but kind of dependence I don't
know how to call it but it is quite a
problem and believe me it's no good to
argue with oncology patient especially
if all the media focused on your face
palliative treatment about 30 percent
are for treatment which was interact for
intractable pain our inception we demand
that the patient will be given all day
known medication not all of them but
some of them and only if you fail with
the regular then-known the proof
treatment then you start cannabis I
really believe that in a few months or a
year we will change this rule and
cannabis will become a first-line choice
for treatment not after exhausting all
other possibilities well the market is
full of promises full you have
advertising to telling people that
cannabis will cure every disease you
have my friends used to say they even it
will bring you back your last love
I'm not sure this is a proper indication
neurology multiple sclerosis Parkinson's
patients suffering
chronic pain caused by a rigidity to
read Tourette syndrome unbelievable
successful the treatment is unbelievable
success
I mentioned the problems of psychosis
epilepsy were proved for adults lately
Neurology it was mentioned yesterday and
I was very impressed we have the same
results with epileptic children autistic
spectrum they have any problem how to
define this spectrum which is very very
wide and very undefined we have now more
than 250 children treated for
intractable epilepsy a few months ago
ask the specialist to present results
intermediate results more than 50% of
the children were well if not
conventions free so less than 5
convulsions a day I mean those kids that
started with 2 300 convergence a day 30
percent the number of conversions went
down to less than 20 and about 10 to 20
percent didn't enjoy the treatment
well I'm physician if someone will tell
me that you have a treatment there's
good 400 percent of patients I won't
believe it neurology ALS Lou Gehrig's
disease fibromyalgia which is quite a
problem because the disease is not
defined enough we all don't have the
buret all says no other the stroke from
sores I'm running last anthology with
relative colitis very good results
psychiatry we have more than 1500 people
most of them victims of war soldiers
treated for PTSD following unsuccessful
psychological other treatments they
they enjoy it very much almost all of
them continue the treatment I mentioned
ophthalmology we have a problem with
pain clinics that are overcrowded I
mentioned our health minister Richmond
which he was the one to present it to
the government in that its approval just
shortly the numbers of our patients 8000
of them are treated for illogical
problems directly in the hospitals the
rest as you see oncology Crohn's disease
neuropathic pain HIV this is kind of
symptomatic treatment for very difficult
cases and PTSD I mentioned controversial
issues which we have problem with the
driving under influence of cannabis we
don't have enough data to make decisions
I hope maybe you were but I didn't see
it price of treatment
you don't recognize them I was asked by
the hospitals what to do about treating
patients with cannabis inside hospitals
because the physician some of them do
not like the rule I made is that only
with the approval of 13 of the physician
the department he can use the cannabis
they have the problem of smoke alarms in
the a export I believe that we will come
to that when will make a medication out
of it we wanted very much to start
export but our foreign ministry ministry
was very much opposed against it because
they were afraid Israel will be
portrayed all over the world as a
country exporting weapons and cannabis
it is not good for our image so if I
finish we are going from substance to me
to medicine startup and that's one
short story about older patient and she
was given cannabis for Debbie's were not
quite understood diagnosis so after
months people called her our people
called asking grandma does it help you
and her answer was look for the diseases
I don't know but my grandchildren are
coming to visit
thank you
you