thanks so much to the organizers of kin
med and cordage inand Doug Kennedy
forgetting everything so beautifully
organized so I have made two promises
one I will speak very quickly and stay
within our a lot of time because we are
running over and two I will make sure
that you have an excellent experience so
I don't have to tell this audience after
several days of this fantastic
conference that marijuana has been
around seemingly forever if you look at
newly discovered photographic evidence
you will see very closely that it
actually wasn't a fig leaf covering Adam
and Eve's most private parts that's
right that's right we have it we are
Harvard Medical School we know how to do
it if you look very closely at the
inside of the pyramids and of course
evidence from the Sistine Chapel you
will see that images related to cannabis
have been around for thousands of years
I'm only kidding of course but this is
just a way to transition into the idea
that in fact cannabis has been around
for thousands of years first documented
as medicine in 2700 BC was part of
mainstream medicine in the u.s. part of
the u.s. pharmacopoeia in 1850 which
meant that doctors could and did
prescribe cannabis for a range of
indications by 1942 it was out of the
pharmacopoeia and by 1970 it was
classified as a schedule 1 substance
under the then new controlled substance
act 1996 saw the first medical marijuana
laws in California and since that time
watch my beautifully animated slide we
have seen lots of changes across the
nation bringing us current to 2017 we
now have 28 states plus DC with fully
legalized medical marijuana laws another
17 with partial medical marijuana laws
allowing the use of things that are non
intoxicating like cannabidiol eight
states plus DC have allowed recreational
cannabis leaving only five states
without access that's the majority of
states very very important to keep in
mind not all marijuana is the same we
have this one term it really should be
termed cannabis but we call it marijuana
which means anything that comes from the
plant we won't go through the difference
in species since most of us already
agree at this point everything we see is
predominantly a hybrid of species more
importantly there are over 400 known
constituents in this magical plant a
hundred or more phyto cannabinoids these
are things that interact with our
endocannabinoid system and thankfully
for all my predecessors at this
conference I don't have
go through it but these are things that
interact with our brain and body system
of chemicals and receptors the two main
players no secret here Delta nine
tetrahydrocannabinol the main
psychoactive constituents in the plant
and cannabidiol the non-intoxicating
constituents shown to have tremendous
therapeutic potential the last thing
I'll say before we get into some
exciting data is that medical and
recreational marijuana should not be
considered the same I can't say that
enough they should not be considered the
same even though the products made me
identical the plants from which they're
derived are identical in fact the modes
of use may be identical the goal of use
is very different for our recreational
users than for our medical patients the
goal of recreational users I've been
doing recreational research sorry
recreational is research on recreational
cannabis users for 20-plus years their
goal is to feel altered high euphoric
our medical patients say I don't want to
be high most of them anyway I just want
to feel better
constituent profile is also very
different typically recreational strains
are prized for their THC potency we were
looking for high THC here in fact levels
of cannabidiol have all but disappeared
from recreational strains are dropping
about 46% since 1995 our medical
patients may have products that are high
in THC and or other CBD but there are
other constituents that factor into the
equation prominently age of onset
another very critical piece of the
puzzle typically our recreational users
begin using during adolescence or early
adulthood our medical marijuana patients
not exclusively but by and large begin
after age 25 that excludes of course our
pediatric samples I won't go through
what the national academy of science
engineering and medicine reported since
that's the three hundred ninety five
page paper back in January but many took
heart in the following there is
conclusive or substantial evidence that
cannabis or cannabinoids are effective
for what we call the big three treatment
of chronic pain treatment of nausea and
vomiting as a function of chemotherapy
and treatment of muscle related muscle
spasticity related to MS more recently
since the report was issued the senior
author of the paper Marie McCormack has
noted that in fact it seems to be useful
in reducing some forms of very severe
child seizure disorders too many of you
in the audience I know that is not a
surprise but to many out there it is and
it's good that we have it out there in
addition there's moderate or limited
evidence for a range of other conditions
suggesting that additional research is
needed I would say demanding that
additional research is needed so while
there have been a number of Medical
Marijuana studies to date research
really does remain in its infancy for
all the reasons you've heard here most
of them have to do with our current
status and some of the guidelines and
restrictions most studies have looked at
outcomes secondary to medical marijuana
use for a specific symptom illness or
indication limited sample sizes in
addition when we began this work we
could not find any studies that looked
at specifically the effects of the use
of cannabis for medical purposes on
cognitive performance was there a
difference in individuals who are using
medical marijuana in terms of their
ability to solve problems and do tasks
further no studies thus far had employed
a pre versus post treatment approach
enter the mind program marijuana
investigations for neuro scientific
discoveries of program I started at
McLean Hospital two and a half years ago
why it was designed to basically
understand the effects of medical
marijuana use on a range of things
including cognitive performance clinical
state quality of life where applicable
brain structure brain function and a
range of other measures we just don't
have this data available the program
supports a number of projects designed
to examine cannabinoid based therapies
for a range of indications and
conditions and we use longitudinal
observational cross-sectional survey and
clinical trial models but not all at the
same time that'd be a neat trick so I'm
gonna show you some data from an ongoing
longitudinal observational study that's
very exciting this study was
specifically designed really truly
really truly to look at the effect of
medical marijuana treatment on cognitive
performance as well as mood sleep
quality of life brain structure and
function in patients before they begin
using that's really important
this study is designed to follow
patients over a minimum of one year
we've now gotten permission to follow
them out for 18 months and 24 months
patients can use for any number of
indications and their choice of products
which we chart what they're using where
they got it what they're told is in it
so we have the information from the
dispensary we record it throughout the
course of the study how often it cetera
mode of use then we have their most
commonly used samples analyzed by an
outside laboratory our laboratory
representatives right here speaking in
this very session
the potential participants are referred
from local Medical Marijuana free
Marijuana certification centers or
physicians to some of whom are also here
we're eternally grateful for all of you
sending us patients the inclusion
exclusion criteria are simple patients
must have a valid certification for
medical marijuana use or plans to use
products that don't require a
certification for example industrial
hemp derived products certification can
be for any indication but they must be
marijuana naive at the outset of the
study this is important and if they have
any history of recreational marijuana
use it must be several years in the past
until very recently the average number
of years since heavy recreational use
was in excess of seven or eight now
we're down to about three so they have
to be THC negative at baseline we wrote
our first paper from this study at the
end of last year called splendor in the
grass it's been viewed just under
thirty-five thousand times to date and I
guess this issue was nominated for the
frontier spotlight award I only
mentioned this because it underscores
what the nation is interested in
learning which is about the effect of
the use of cannabis we need more
research so I have some updated data to
show you
we now have 38 patients who have
completed their baseline visit and 19
thus far who have completed their visit
to so they're naive at baseline then we
see them after three months of treatment
average age is about 50 predominantly
right-handed the indications range pain
anxiety PTSD sleep mood attention and
other what's other ulcerative colitis
chronic migraines petit mal seizures how
are they using they're using less than
everyday and we've heard some of that
earlier in this conference as well they
don't need to use every day they use
just a little less than twice a day they
use about nine times a week and they're
using about 1.6 grams what do they use
they smoke conventional flower product
they vaporize conventional flower
product they vaporize oils and
concentrates and you can see that there
there's other use of oils and
concentrates tinctures medical edibles
and topicals a lovely array of modes of
use here's an example of our product
analysis so we get constituent analysis
for ten of the cannabinoids which helps
us but what about the data I do not have
a pointer but I will guide your eye to
the important part of the slide if you
look the very first thing that jumps out
I see the point
is a significant reduction in depressive
symptoms so this is self-report this is
not examiner driven this isn't the study
doctor deciding that they look better
this is self-report significant
reduction in depressive symptoms between
baseline and after three months of
treatment we also see significant
improvements in self-reported sleep as
noted by the Pittsburgh sleep quality
index way up at the no that's wrong way
up at the top a significant improvement
in sleep we also see improvements on a
generalized health survey called the
sf-36
significant improvements in physical
role significant improvements in energy
significant improvements in social
functioning and significant improvements
in self-reported levels of pain let me
say really quickly we have a completely
separate subset of pain related scales
too much for me to show in this
particular presentation but this
patients all reports significant
improvement self-reported improvement in
pain related measures after three months
of treatment very importantly we also
see a notable decrease in their use of
conventional medications a 42 percent
reduction in opiate use that's again
self-report 46 percent reduction in
benzos 33 percent reduction in mood
stabilizers and a 22 percent reduction
in antidepressants I think this is quite
striking again very small sample sizes
but certainly enough of a signal for us
to be very excited so I won't belabor
the point too much other than to say we
were very interested in their cognitive
performance I spend a lot of time
thinking about frontal executive
functions the types of tasks that are
mediated by the frontal part of your
brain right behind your eyebrows things
that allow you to inhibit inappropriate
responses make good sound decisions and
detect conflict where appropriate so we
have lots of different measures of these
things including the controlled oral
word-association tasks basically the FAS
tasks I'm going to give you a letter of
the alphabet name as many words as you
can that begin with that letter digit
symbol substitution test patients are
basically asked to write as many symbols
as they can using a number symbol key as
many as they can do in 90 seconds letter
number sequencing subjects get a string
of mixed numbers and letters and they're
told they have to repeat them first the
numbers in order then the letters the
Stroop color word test the interference
condition everybody loves this one the
interference condition basically has
words printed in a different color ink
than they spell your brain wants you to
read it that's the most
automatic process you have I want you to
name the color of the ink harder than it
sounds
we also the trail making test Parts A
and B Part A is simply a test of
psychomotor speed how quickly can you
connect the dots
Part B introduces an alternating set
demand they have to alternate number
letter number letter 1a to be again
harder than it sounds see some people
saying oh oh that looks horrible doesn't
even make a nice picture let's start
with that
finally the Wisconsin card sorting task
one of my favorites considered for
decades to be the gold standard measure
of frontal executive function very
simple subjects are given a deck of
cards and for stimulus cards they are
asked to take one card at a time and
place it in front of one of the four
stimulus cards what they don't know
after being told correct or incorrect is
that the sorting principle has changed
and they have to utilize the feedback
from the examiner to change their
behavior that's the frontal function so
how do they do well again significant
improvement from baseline to three
months one day I'll get this right if
you look up here we see significant
improvements in the FAS tasks
significant improvements in letter
number sequencing significant
improvements in digit symbol
substitution the Stroop color word test
significantly higher accuracy and
significantly fewer errors of omission
we see a trend for faster response time
during trails let me stop and say one
quick thing as if this wasn't quick
enough we have alternate forms of all of
these tests so we don't see any practice
effect here okay they have alternate
forms of these measures at three months
this isn't a practice effect plus it's
been three months neuroimaging I run
something called the cognitive and
clinical neuroimaging core where I am
fortunate enough to work around lots of
lovely magnets retrofitted in such a way
that we can do structural functioning
like structural functional spectroscopic
and diffusion tensor imaging all with
what we call one-stop shopping so we can
take lots of different pieces of
information and put them together later
I'm going to show you some data from an
fMRI study that we did in all of the
patients who are able to complete visit
one and two so once again we have them
completed tasks while they're inside the
scanner this is called the multi source
interference task two conditions here in
the control task subjects basically get
three numbers two or zero and one is a
different number they have to report the
identity of the number with a button box
in the control task it's easy the number
that's different is in its correct
position as on the button
box simple now we have the interference
condition this time the two numbers that
are the same are not zeros and the
number to be relieved of one of these
things is not like the other right so
which one of these things is not like
the other except now it's not in its
correct position as on the button box so
they have to inhibit the overwhelming
tendency of the visual position and
instead report the identity how do they
do let's just go to the interference
task right here in the middle
significant improvements in percent
accuracy they go from eighty one point
eight to eighty seven point eight
significantly fewer errors of omission
significantly faster response time I
won't bore you with the derived
interference at the bottom but suffice
it to say it's quite impressive after
three months again no practice effect
expected what about their brain imaging
what do they look like so at baseline
this is at baseline so no marijuana on
board we should see some activation by
the way typically we see activation
right here in the cingulate cortex
during the completion of this task and
we see a little more activation
typically in the frontal cortex what
happens after three months of treatment
so we see a very striking difference you
don't have to be a neuroscientist to see
that these images are different right so
a very different pattern of activation
here in the cingulate and in the frontal
cortex significantly more quote voxels
activated if any one he wants a physics
primer afterwards come and see me but
just to summarize what this data shows
us we see generally demonstrated
improvements in a number of these
measures of executive function this is
important because a lot of our work and
previous work and work of my colleagues
has demonstrated alterations and
executive function in recreational users
demonstrating sort of impairment
participants also exhibited notable
increases in activation in the frontal
cortex including the cingulate which is
a region typically activated by healthy
controls this is our folk our group at
baseline this is our group after three
months this is a study I did in 2012 of
healthy controls okay this is our group
after three months of treatment this is
a study of healthy controls okay so
three months of treatment that's what we
say overall findings suggest that
participants are able to quantify and
report their medical marijuana use
throughout the study we see improvements
in cognitive performance that may occur
with potential quote normalization of
function with regard to mood sleep
quality of life we do see some
and very importantly we see a
significant reduction in self-reported
use of conventional medications
specifically a 42% reduction in opiates
given the current crisis I think that's
worth noting why are they improved
symptom alleviation I feel better so I
can think more clearly that's certainly
a possibility product choice we know
that unlike recreational strains many of
our medical marijuana patients are
choosing strains that are high in other
constituents including cannabidiol and
in fact a number of these folks are on
high CBD containing products certain
cannabinoids may actually exert a direct
or an indirect effect on cognitive
performance age of the consumer these
folks let's just say these folks are not
necessarily within the window of
neurodevelopmental vulnerability they're
not 20 or 22 the average age is 50 as
opposed to our recreational sample
significantly younger all of this to be
followed with further research
so just for my last minute I will tell
you what else were up to we have an
fda-approved clinical trial of a whole
plant derived botanical high in CBD
sublingual tincture approved by the FDA
approved by the IRB unfortunately on
hold with the DEA that's four that's
another talk see the collector grounds
at home that's another talk we also have
very exciting an observational study of
veterans using medical marijuana
products we are basically looking at the
impact of cannabinoids on clinical state
and cognition particularly those
afflicted with PTSD given the
extraordinary need we're looking at
folks who are either marijuana naive
that is they haven't begun yet or folks
who are on a standard regimen of
cannabinoids or cannabis products who
are looking to add an additional product
and we'll follow them in much the same
way as these other studies so our next
steps we'll continue to examine the
impact of medical marijuana on cognition
quality of life and related variables
we're not stopping now no way we'll
continue to do research that helps to
inform empirically based guidelines for
use including dosing product selection
and age restrictions very exciting we're
exploring cannabinoid based therapy
specifically for veterans specifically
for women's health issues and a range of
other indications hopefully using other
products that are currently on the
market additional clinical trial models
are currently being developed to assess
the impact of products which have shown
efficacy anecdotally at this point I
would say researchers knowledge and
knowledge is power and I would implore
all of
who are invested in this particular area
and you wouldn't be sitting here if you
weren't that this is the most important
thing we can do help those of us who are
attempting to do research push the ball
down the field not to use a horrible
thing from our our previous session but
really move the ball down the field it
is up to us as scientists and clinicians
to inform our patients they're using
it's up to us to allow them to use
safely and wisely and to educate them
and to help them make good and sound
decisions for themselves thank you
[Applause]
you