[Music]
canmed events presents the canmad
medical practicum taking place in
pasadena california on may 3rd 2022.
this full-day workshop will be led by
bonnie goldstein dustin sulak kevin
spellman eloise thiessen
each of the presenters will share the
latest research their clinical
experience and practice guidelines
related to cannabinoid therapeutics a
new section in this eight-hour course is
dedicated to reviewing the types of
extractions products and optimal dosing
of cannabinoids for various therapeutic
scenarios the canmed medical practicum
will conclude with the presentation team
discussing a number of topics in a panel
format open the q a from the attendees
continuing education credits this course
is approved by the california board of
registered nursing for 9.5 contact hours
purchase your ticket to the limited
capacity canmed medical practicum today
and consider joining us for the canmed
2022 main conference immediately
following the practicum on may 4th and
5th 2022 tickets to the canmed medical
practicum and the main conference can be
purchased at canmedevents.com
[Music]