thanks to the Koreans collectively and
especially Kevin for the invitation I
missed this event last year and it
looked really great and obviously when
you'd say I'm I think I'm miked up is it
being turned on no can you hear me now
okay so to repeat thanks to the mckernon
x' and kevin especially for organizing
this is great a really nice mix of you
know chemistry biomedical science and
what i'm going to talk about which is
plants I changed my title a little bit
because we had a paper come out in the
last week on terpenes and cannabis so I
won't just talk about cannabinoids and
trichomes but before that I thought I'd
show this slide this is um Richard Evans
shultiess who's who was a professor at
Harvard at the Botanical Museum sort of
just across the river obviously from
here this is a picture of Richard Evans
all teas in 1972 in Kandahar and
Afghanistan he was investigating the
differences between the species of you
know cannabis indica and sativa or
what's purportedly that those
differences and so it's you know it's I
think it's really cool that there's a
there was a pioneer of cannabis right
here in Boston he's he passed away in
2001 but was really the father of the
field of ethnobotany and and really got
a lot of people excited about medicinal
plants and and psychoactive plants and
hallucinogenic plants even though he was
extremely sort of conservative a Harvard
faculty member he went down to the
Amazon and used ayahuasca and all this
kind of thing so and in in 1972 he
quoted someone else to say the story of
marijuana is not yet written and I think
we're still seeing that we're still
writing that story and conferences like
this are really moving things along so
I'm interested in in cannabis as a
medicinal plant and and as others have
said this morning it's really a
metabolic factory it's a it's a factory
for compounds such as such as THC and
CBD cannabidiol other cannabinoids
there's a potentially a hundred and ten
or over a hundred of the cannabinoids
and then terpenes like mere scene and
Linna Luol and and
baby cart betta carry off leaning and
together they form this mixture of
bioactive metabolites that really
produce the effects of the plant that
people get when they consume it either
orally or in inhaled so you know those
effects of course are psychoactivity
pain relief and all the you know
potentially useful medical properties we
see and then when we look at that plant
on a you know chemical analysis and the
lab that I founded in Vancouver both
does genomics as I'll talk about in this
talk but we we do a lot of in-depth
chemical profiling this is sort of a
maybe a typical and analytical profile
of a cannabis plant
so the cannabinoids such as CBD a the
acid form of CBD and THC a in this plant
essentially you know sort of one-to-one
ratio so what would be called a chemo
type 2 plant and then we see like CBG a
candidature aaalac acid and can of
achromatic acid also present in that
plant so that you know there's a kind of
death although there's a hundred and
five cannabinoids them the major ones
are what what we see typically there's
sort of you know six or eight of the big
ones and then within the the terpenes we
see monoterpenes Mir seen typically
dominate and then that squirter pee and
things like beta-carotene and those are
all combining in that that mixture and
what my research program has really been
doing over the last decade or so I was
trying to figure out how cannabis makes
those compounds so what are the enzymes
what are the genes for the enzymes that
put these complex metabolites together
and the secret of that experimental
approach has been the focus on glandular
trichomes so this is a funky picture I
took of a strain called skunk number one
when I was a postdoc in Germany around
2000 or 1999 back you know that long ago
I started working on this plant we look
at those those female floral tissues we
see the stigmas where this you know that
receive the pollen as these white hairs
but those crystally kind of structures
on the floral tissues are trichomes we
look a little bit more closely and we
see those stalked trichomes
and then we look even more closely this
is actually these are hemp trichomes but
hemp is still cannabis after all we can
see that nice stalk and then a secretor
e disk of cells these are the cells that
are out
Ashley making cannabinoids and
terpenoids elzar the kind of the
cellular factories for cannabinoids and
then there's that storage site in that
that secrete re cavity
you know as consumers they would talk
about you know people talk about
crystals and and resin droplets they're
really like a balloon of chemicals or a
Safeway bag you know it's got a sort of
a thin almost plastic waxy skin on it to
contain the metabolites in there and you
can open them up just by you know poking
them or prodding them so what we did has
biochemists and Janome assist was saying
well you know those secretor e-cell
discs or where all the action takes
place that's where the factory is if we
can isolate them and then start probing
their biochemistry and specifically
looking at what genes are expressed we
can figure out how the metabolites that
are produced and then secreted their
cannabinoids interpreting the plant and
so that and that process and they go
back one slide shows you what we did was
we took female floral tissues of a high
THC strain put it in a bead beater which
is a glorified glorified blender cost a
lot more than your typical blender knock
the stuff apart the bag of goop opens up
that the discs separate from the top of
the stalk and then you can filter them
off and purify them into a relatively
pure form there kind of a sort of a
creamy color they're not even
photosynthetic and then we can isolate
RNA ribonucleic acid which is the
messenger from the genome through to the
protein it's kind of it's it's the
active form of gene expression so we got
RNA and then we started sequencing it
and then we had a gene expression
catalog so that gene expression catalog
from the glandular trichomes of high THC
cannabis was enriched for cannabinoid
pathway enzymes and the reason we knew
it was enriched was initially we only
had one enzyme in the pathway
identified it was done by the professor
show Yama's group and cue
to University in Japan around 2000 so
THC acid synthase is the last step in