[Music]
welcome to the CED Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
ameral I am the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and proud member of
the team that puts on the camed
conference first on behalf of medicinal
genomics and camed events I hope you all
had a safe and happy holiday as we wind
down 2023 be sure to take advantage of
our early bird pricing for the camed 24
Innovation and investment Summit taking
place this may in Marco Island Florida
that early bird pricing is available
through the remainder of the year so be
sure to get your ticket before the ball
drops in Time Square
we appreciate your support for cammed
whether it's listening to the podcast
following us on social media viewing the
presentation videos in the camed archive
or joining us for the annual Summit it's
truly an honor to provide a platform for
the brilliant clinicians and researchers
that participate in canmed the work they
do is transforming the industry and
bringing hope to many who suffer from
disease and illness and today's guest is
a great example of one of those
clinicians Bonnie Goldstein is one of
the country's most respected and
experienced medical cannabis Physicians
having treated thousands of patients
with medical cannabis she is the owner
and medical director of Cana centers
wellness and education she is the
clinical adviser to can formatics and
she is the author of the book titled
cannabis is medicine how medical
cannabis and CBD are healing everything
from anxiety to chronic pain
Bonnie has participated in every camed
event since we started in 2016 and she
leads the camed medical practicum again
this year during our conversation we
talked about what attendees can expect
from the camed medical practicum new
research that she is excited about
concerning thca and
cbda Bonnie's method for customizing
canono formulations for her patients the
many barriers preventing patients from
using medical
cannabis how the cannabinoid medicine
options have expanded over the last
decade and the difficulty of keeping up
with the Cannabis medicine
literature before we get to my
conversation with botney I would like to
thank this episode sponsor the dent
Institute with more than 300,000 patient
visits per year the dent neurologic
Institute ranks among the largest
Neuroscience centers in North America
its 24 subsp specialty clinics often
treat the most challenging neurologic
conditions including but not limited to
migraine chronic pain ALS Ms Parkinson's
dementia and
neurooncology with their mission of
advancing Neuroscience the dent
Institute established a cannabis clinic
in 2016 to Aid in the treatment of these
chronic conditions seen throughout the
Institute for more information visit the
dent institute.com
all right and without any further Ado
please enjoy my conversation with Dr
Bonnie
[Music]
Goldstein hello Bonnie welcome back to
the podcast thanks so much for having me
again bed of course we're thrilled to
have you coming back for caned 24 you
know I was watching your CED 23
presentation before we jumped on the
call today and at the start you
mentioned how much you Lov the location
and how you think it should that camed
should be at that that location every
year well you got your wish we're going
back to Marco Island for camed
24 really looking forward to it it was
you know there was this not only was the
location gorgeous right uh in fact it's
my screen saver on my phone right now I
took a picture of the sunset on the
beach and it was spectacular um but the
camaraderie um the kind of upbeat nature
of everybody that was there excited to
learn to
share um just excited to be around other
people who kind of understand cannabis
and are excited about cannabis and not
only that but like so you know I'm
living in the medical world but and
there's only so much I C uh bandwidth I
have to expand into learning everything
about the plant but yet I attend the
lectures uh from these uh brilliant phds
in plant biology and so on and I learned
so much and it just enhances the whole
my
whole ability to really understand um
everything about the plant it's just I
it's it's a great conference and I've
said that in fact the day that I went to
leave I you know talked to the
organizers and just said Spectacular
from top to bottom so I really encourage
people to go it's a really if you're if
you're only can go to one conference
this is the conference to go to
excellent yeah we we agree and um we're
hoping to have more opportunities for
some of that camaraderie and um
networking that you mentioned so um
we're really excited about this year
it's going to be a great event and of
course one of the pillars of the event
is the medical practicum which is going
to be taking place on Monday the 13th
and it's a full day workshop that's
really sort of a a crash course in
cannaboid medicine featuring you of
course Dr Dustin sulac Eloise th and new
this year Dr Ethan Ro Ethan rouso excuse
me which is quite the lineup um I was
hoping briefly can you tell the
listeners what they can expect from the
the medical
practicum sure so we uh at the medical
practicum break it down into kind of two
parts so one is the
basic um science that you need to
understand kind of like the first two
years of medical school where they teach
you all the biochemistry and Physiology
and you don't really get into
the um uh patient care just yet so we
have the morning lectures which are
about the physiology of the
endocannabinoid system the pharmacology
the plant um and then we and and a few
others and then we move into dosing um
how to approach a patient which
cannaboids you might want to choose for
which conditions or which symptoms um
and we share our clinical experience and
listen we know that we're behind in
research because of the prohibition the
schedule one status that is ongoing
still not allowed to do studies on THC
unless you jump through a thousand Hoops
with the government so although it's
getting a little bit better um what we
have in our art Aral is our clinical
experience and cannabis is not the same
as
Pharmaceuticals uh it's multiple
compounds in it it doesn't fit that you
know single molecule and where you can
do a randomized control trial it just
doesn't fit into that um and although
those trials are helpful I found that
clinically because cannabis is so safe
um if you just understand what you're
doing and learn from people who have
been doing it you can actually make a
difference in somebody's life somebody
who's suffering from a refractory
condition or somebody where the
treatment is almost worse than the
symptoms of the condition and so and
even then not just those kinds of
patients but just General Wellness for
your patients to keep them well right
and so I think it's a a really it's a
Powerhouse of a day there's a lot of
learning um and we make ourselves
available so Ethan Dustin myself and
Eloise all have oh gosh I don't even
know how many years have you put it
together experience in cannabis medicine
it's a lot um but you have the ability
to pick our brains and I think that's uh
really important absolutely and that's
something that we we hear about all the
time is the fact that people can walk up
to you or have a meal with you and you
know just continue to to pick your brain
and um and learn even Beyond just the
sessions um is such a a great part of
the event and uh and I like the point
that you made too about the practicum is
that you you start off with the basics
which you know even if you're if you're
new to cannabis if you're dipping your
toe it's a great place to start and
gives you a nice foundation for the
following day too where it gets into
sort of more more detailed research that
the oral presenters are giving um if you
attend the practicum it gives you a nice
kind of uh solid
foundation absolutely and you know we're
I hate to say it but we're all kind of
like nerds science nerds
and we focused on cannabis so if you
come up to me and I'm eating lunch and
you say hey can I pick your brain I'm
like all in you know let's go for it I
love sharing what I know because you
know I would joke around but it's true I
can't take care of everybody so we need
other clinicians we need other even if
it's not the first line treatment Like
It Is Well it's not first line in my
practice because I'm seeing people after
they've already failed first second and
third line but it's something that you
should be able to discuss with your
patients and and you need to have that
basic knowledge to have that
conversation for sure so maybe there are
some listeners out there who have
already attended canmed maybe even
already attended the practicum um but I
know
that the research is constantly changing
new things are always coming up so are
there new things in this year's
practicum that um you wanted to
highlight to that people should consider
if they're thinking about coming
back well we are spending a little bit
more time
on the clinical side of things so we do
have the basic science lectures but we
are you know trying to add more clinical
so case reports um and um uh Dr Ethan
Russo is doing a lecture highlighting
neurologic disease uh he's a neurologist
by uh training and uh he's so brilliant
um that he is able to impart that
knowledge about um how so many
neurologic disorders like dementia let's
say um certain brain cancers like we
really don't have good treatment you
know you your loved one gets diagnosed
dementia goes to the neurologist and
they kind of hand you some medications
that e don't really do great things
right maybe slight Improvement but
certainly not in everybody and lots of
side effects so um he's going to go
through how cannabinoids um can be
preventive uh and also can be um uh
provide a really great treatment for
people struggling with neurologic
conditions so I'm really excited to hear
that lecture i' I've heard parts of it
in the past but um I can't wait uh to
hear him talk about that yeah it's
always exciting to get to hear Dr Russo
talk he's sort of the sort of the Elder
Statesman not to not to date him but um
the guru he's my Guru he's my mentor
yeah he's he's phenomenal excellent and
so we we were talking about new
literature it's coming coming out all
the time and like I said I was watching
your cim at 23 presentation and you even
remarked that that morning you had to
add some new information into your
presentation because you were you were
looking at a paper and realized oh I
need to put that in there so literature
is changing all the time new research
all the time um are there any new
developments new research recently that
you're excited
about well kind of touching on that
dementia part of it a paper came out
very recently and it it's in mice but it
gives us some really nice information
that we didn't really have before so the
raw canabo cbda and thca so
cannabidiolic acid and
tetrahydrocannabinolic acid are
compounds that the plant gives us in its
unheated State way back when when I
started doing this in 2008 we actually
thought that these compounds were
inactive and I was taught so you have to
heat the plant in order to act activate
the medicinal properties kind of like
convert cbda to CBD convert thca to THC
through that heating
process and really um we find out that
that's not true cbda and thca have
potent anti-inflammatory antioxidant
effects neuroprotective effects and so
there's been a tremendous amount of
research looking at these what we call
the acidic cannabinoids that a at the
end stands for the acid um and what can
they do so they are woefully underst
studied but luckily there's a lot of
interest and they're it's moving forward
in terms of uh the research and a recent
study came out showing that both cbda
and thca in a mouse model of Alzheimer's
was actually quite protective and so it
lowered so when you get Alzheimer's or
dementia you what's happening is your
brain cells are becoming inflam flamed
and they're dying and with Alzheimer's
particularly there's these deposits of
these proteins in your brain that kind
of basically mess up cell function and
it turns out that cbda and
thca uh in mice that received those
compared to mice that didn't get those
compounds actually reduced or lowered
those protein depositions which is
amazing right because we don't really
have medicine to do
that and also um alleviated this um
abnormal calcium flow the calcium is
very important to your brain function
calcium moves in and out of your cells
it's not because of how much milk you
drink or how much Dairy you have or it's
really just how calcium Flows In and Out
of the cells and if that becomes
unregulated or out of balance you can
have a lot of problems neurologically
and so thca and CBJ were found to
alleviate that imbalance which is
amazing and also had neuro other
neuroprotective effects and in the study
they actually measured um memory loss
and resilience to these changes and the
mice that got these cannabinoids did
better and what I'll tell you just in my
own experience I use cbda and thca all
the time in my pediatric practice as
well as my adult practice mostly for
alleviation of
inflammation uh like let's say related
to
osteoarthritis in the Pediatric patients
um also many of my patients have neuron
inflammation neuroinflammation they have
especially the kids with autism have
have major dysfunction in their immune
systems and also cbda and THC appear to
also help with anxiety so that's another
reason that we use it non impairing
compounds but not like plant we don't
have to worry about going high dose and
making somebody uncomfortably high or or
too much psychoactivity and certainly
that's never the goal especially with
the Pediatric patient so here we have
this new data it's very
exciting yeah that is exciting and so
you mentioned that the the prevailing
wisdom before was that you know you need
to decarbox these compounds in order to
make them active now was that sort of
because it is true that and you made the
point yourself that thca is not
psychoactive until you decarbox it so
was the thought that okay if it's if
it's true in that case that it's not
going to be psychoactive unless we
decarbox it it's proba true for the
other medicinal effects too well and I
think that's was kind of a
generalization you know when you can't
study things you can't learn about them
so people went by how they felt so if
you were to take raw cannabis you didn't
feel anything same thing like with CBD
if you took some CBD and you say well I
don't feel anything well maybe it's not
it's not doing anything I don't feel
anything and what we know now is that
not only do these compounds just need a
little time but dosing matters so you
should know what your dosing is the prep
reparation matters is it actually what's
in the bottle exactly what they're it's
what's on the label right does that dive
so there's a lot to it but most of my
patients who are using non um impairing
canabo so basically everything but THC
and possibly CBN um they are they report
well I don't feel anything I said we
have to give it time it needs to this is
a plant it's not going to hit you like a
harsh pharmaceutical it's going to get
you into homeostasis over time right my
analogy is if I'm out of shape and I go
to the gym tomorrow I am not in shape
tomorrow night but if I hang in there I
will see in a month I feel better in two
months I feel even better and by three
months people are saying wow you're you
you've got muscles and you know wow you
look great and so you have to give
cannabis a chance it is a plant that it
we're asking it to change your either
your neurochemistry or your inflammatory
chemistry you got to give it a chance to
work so but I'll share with you in my I
have a couple of elderly patients that
have pretty severe pain from gout from
severe osteoarthritis bone on bone in
their knees or severe hip pain other
joint pain and they report that cbda is
amazing for that it's and it's and
there's no I just have not seen side
effects now in my autism patients
sometimes they we're hitting targets
that we might not want to hit so the
children may have worse behaviors that's
very unique to that condition but in
general cbda seems to be very well
tolerated when just one comment about
thca non impairing but thca likes to
convert to THC so you have to watch your
product make sure you keep it cold don't
let it get overheated don't leave it in
your car on a hot day but normally kind
of the ratio I like for thca to THC is
at least like a 20 to one so 20 parts
thca to one part THC that can be
measured of course tested medicine so
you know what's in the B model uh if you
don't have access to that there are uh
some people on YouTube who have done
some kind of they show you how they make
thca uh from um the raw cannabis uh
plant um
but it can uh have a psychoactive effect
if you go really high dose because
remember with every thca milligram let's
say some THC is coming along with it and
sometimes it will convert it doesn't
convert as fast as I think people think
it uh it does or how I used to think it
would convert pretty quickly but it
looks like it's you know as long as you
keep it in the fridge it should be okay
and in my patients who are using thca
for seizures I have one uh a couple kids
in my practice thca is the only thing
that helped with seizures CBD didn't
help THC didn't help but these kids are
not showing any signs of um of
impairment in fact what they're showing
is is improved neurocognitive function
because the seizures are
down now are you finding that in your
practice you're you're using the acid
forms more than the decarbox forms no I
would say that it's the kind of all lump
together it really depends on the
person's response I have a method I
describe in my book rule it in or rule
it out so we start with one compound we
dose it up we look for a sweet spot if
there is one if we can find some benefit
without side effects at a certain dose I
have ruled it in if it's either no
response at all at low medium high do
does or a negative response as long as
it's not from these nuances of cannabis
like basic properties where low doses do
one thing and high doses do another but
we try to sort all that out as we're
going through the process if it's ruled
out it's ruled out we get rid of it now
sometimes it could be the the the
particular product as you know because
not all CBD is the same they come from
different plant genetics and one might
suit your Chemistry better than another
so sometimes we'll try a new cannabinoid
sometimes we'll try a different product
in the same category
but uh Dr um uh sulac and I have a very
similar saying we treat the patient not
the condition because with cannabis it
truly is like an individual approach um
so it's interesting I have some patients
that don't tolerate um THC or CBD or CBG
but they do tolerate the acids and vice
versa and then some people just do a
they tolerate everything and it's just
we figure out what works best at what
what dose I do find that laying
cannabinoids just to add that in um for
some people is really a very good answer
because you can keep them lowd dose
because they synergize and you can get
sometimes better results from that
Synergy of the of those plant compounds
rather than one compound at a higher
dose yeah no I think it was ddy Mary who
had a graphic in one of his
presentations that really sort of showed
how the different canabo when used
together kind of layer on top of each
other and and kind of create the
Entourage effect which um we've all come
to know and
love yeah and it's important to
understand that all of that takes time
nobody can just kind of look at you and
go okay you should have take this this
and this I mean if they can then I would
say go to that person but in general it
has to be a little trial and error some
of my research with biomarkers on
children with autism is trying to help
dial that down a little bit to give us a
little more narrow um or a little more
uh insight into who might respond to
what but we're getting there yeah and so
is that approach one that's kind of
foreign to most Physicians are they are
they used to having a more clear sort of
standard of care that when they start
using canabo it's a little bit out of
their comfort zone yeah we're not taught
that way in medical school we're taught
okay here's the condition here's the
standard of care the approved
medications and uh I mean you can even
get sued for not following standard of
care so you know and for taking a
different pathway um and so that's kind
of how allopathic medicine works which
is that kind of you if you have this
condition here's the and and mostly
everything's evidence-based but you know
a lot of the Pharmaceuticals even as I
mentioned the treatment sometimes can be
worse than the condition yeah and to
treat somebody with a a medication that
now creates so you're treating them for
pain and now they have maybe their pain
is cut by 50% but now they have nausea
and constipation on top of it have you
really helped that patient right so with
cannabis one of the goals is to not have
side effects the goal is to and you can
do that if you learn how these compounds
work and you can manipulate them into a
regimen for a patient based on that
individual's response and again that's
treating the patient not necessarily the
condition so
I I think most you know I don't
magically come up with something I base
my clinical decision-making on what do
we know from the science and then what
do I know from other patients and but I
also explained to the patients the
parents it's going to be a little trial
and error but remember there's really
very little harm and that's one of the
things that I try to get across at the
conference and at in in just in general
anytime I speak cannabis is safe all of
this nonsense about it being unsafe is
ridiculous if you are a 15-year-old
abusing THC yes you're going to have
problems that is not the case for
medically uh uh supervised or even
patients using cannabis medically it is
not you cannot lump them into the same
basket it is completely
separate well said no and one of the
things you mentioned too this whole idea
of you know treating the patient not
necessarily in the condition and in your
presentations a lot of times you're
you're talking about patients who have a
laundry list of of conditions um you
call them unicorns just because they are
so unique um so speak a little bit about
that and how you know what that's like
sure so I think Dustin Dr sulac um
Eloise and myself who all practice you
know uh clinically um have all found as
well as many other uh cannabis
Physicians that you end up seeing
patients
who have not been uh kind of this the
typical patient who responds to other
treatments it's usually what we call a
refractory practice which is unfortunate
because why should somebody suffer for
years before they can find Cannabis it
should never be Last Resort um
especially for conditions for which the
treatment is not great and we know it's
not great look in taking care of
pediatric epilepsy patients I've read
just I try to read every single paper
and every paper says these medications
are burdensome in their side effects it
acknowledges it right there and then
goes on to recommend that medication and
I just find that like even as a parent
if I had a young child having seizures
is that excite me to put them on a
medicine that's going to slow down their
brain and potentially interfere with
their ability to learn well we know what
seizures do we know what these
medications can do and if cannabis can
play a Ro to help I don't know why
everybody's so afraid and they say oh
longterm longterm when they introduced
some of these um anti-seizure men they
didn't have long-term studies right and
we knew that they had bad side effects
so there seems to be this double
standard you know with cannabis to have
to kind of achieve this very high bar
but I'll tell you it achieves it people
who do not get good results they're
paying out of pocket they stop buying it
nobody is taking it just to take it yeah
now there are people who again there is
problematic THC use out there but that
is not Banning it or prohibiting it that
doesn't work we have to educate and we
have to educate kids when they're
between the ages of eight and 12 about
all substances and why they would
probably leave it alone if they're
healthy so that their brain can develop
and so on right but that if they're sick
that some of these compounds that are
being talked about that are quote bad
for you are not used medically and now
you know we're getting into that
psychedelic world where all the
psychedelics are being looked at yeah
you know coming around and saying there
is some benefit here especially when
it's medically supervised and used
appropriately so I think you know this
whole idea of it has to be FDA approved
and it has to be randomized control
trial with Placebo and all of that it it
life doesn't work that way for some of
these patients they can't sit around and
wait for us to discover a pharmaceutical
that works when cannabis can actually
give them a better quality of life and
I'm not talking even cure I'm talking
about just day-to-day functioning
feeling better being able to manage the
condition
well yeah and it's a great point you
make about the the bar being set very
high for cannabis medicine and yeah the
proofs in the pudding it it meets it
because like you said there are a lot of
things working against people who are
using cannabis as a medicine the cost uh
the the legality all of those things
access yeah right and they still
continue to use it because works that's
right that's right and they're using you
know there some f families who have kids
with epilepsy are spending upwards over
$1,000 dollar a month that is not easy
to do everything costs more these days
but just even over the past few years I
think about how much money people lay
out but why would they do that because
their child is doing better or because
their loved one is doing better and a at
some point you you say okay we won't go
out to eat anymore we won't take a
vacation I mean the terrible that you
have to give that up in order to take a
medicine that just about every study and
I can't even think of a study that
doesn't say this in a CL clinical
studies safe and well tolerated I see it
all the time if you go to PubMed or
Google Scholar and just look for some
clinical studies on cannabinoids it will
all say safe and well tolerated safe and
well tolerated now whether it worked
that sometimes depends on what
population that you've recruited for
your practice or for your study and also
what um product you're using is it the
right dose is it the right chovar you
know those questions come up but safe
and well tolerated is something that's
kind of standard to see in almost every
clinical uh study of of
cannabis yeah and the other thing you
mentioned too about how a lot of the
patients you see are these refractory
cases these people who have tried
everything else and it's just not work
working it makes me wonder about you
know the patients who maybe they are on
a medication and yeah it's working it's
reducing their symptoms but maybe it's
giving them some unwanted side effects
but they're like hey it's better than
nothing or it's better than what I had
before makes me wonder like how many of
those people could potentially be
benefiting from Cannabis but it just
didn't get bad enough that they sort of
turn to it yeah or there's the leftover
stigma like I don't want my doctor yeah
and yeah and I don't want my doctor to
think I'm a pothead and you know what
that's an extra $50 a month and I'm on a
fixed income because I'm disabled or you
know uh it's the the mountain that we
have made people have to climb to go for
cannabis is is crazy and um it's one of
the things that's really is never talked
about is just how much money cannabis is
saving the health care uh utilization
right so a child that gets hospitalized
every month with what we call status
epilepticus a severe seizure dis
disorder or a severe seizure that lasts
longer than 15 minutes and has to be put
on a ventilator and pumped full of drugs
and then a you know ICU and then a rehab
and the whole thing when you think about
the level of um illness and the high
cost of that illness in our Health Care
system and then you start a child on
cannabis and maybe they're not seizure
free but they're not ending up in the
hospital do you know how much money we
have saved Health Care at that point why
shouldn't some of that money go to help
pay for some of the medicines for these
kids
so yeah and adult and adults I don't
want to leave adults out sure of
course so kind of circling back to sort
of the the new research that's coming
out and sort of the new canono that
you're you're getting to work with again
I I keep coming back to the the camed
presentation I'll definitely put a link
in the show description so people can
check it out but um you were talking
about a patient case and you said you
know at the time I only had THC CBD and
thca to work with um so kind of when was
that and how has your toolbox sort of
expanded since then yeah it's really
been amazing so I've been doing this for
15 years and when I started in 2008 it
was THC that's what we had that's what
you took okay maybe a little CBD in
there but remember in 2008 nobody was
testing you would could walk into a
dispensary in California and you got
something a cookie or some cannabis
flower or whatever it was and you know
buy or beware then what ended up
happening was around
201122 the idea of testing cannabis
started to become more popular there was
no requirement by the state to test but
some companies were doing it so I was
pointing people in the direction of well
just go for the tested medicine the ones
that have a label the ones that look
like now of course they're labeling
issues and I admit that back then no no
problem but but really nobody was really
talking about CBD in 2012 and 2013 is
kind of the evolution of when we started
hearing more about CBD being medicinal
for seizures for
inflammation and I would say that I
treated my first pediatric epilepsy
patient with CBD oil in
2013 so and it was hard to get you know
the parents had to make a zillion calls
to figure out who had it where could I
get it and then of course we were like
is it clean do we trust it because we
didn't have testing um and luckily there
were a couple of uh companies that were
um dedicated to and devoted to these
pediatric epilepsy patients and so we
were able there were about two or three
oils I mean now there's thousands right
think about that just in just basically
the last decade right and then what
happened was thca became
available because there was some
evidence from people making their own
thca uh oil so there was a an article in
1979 that showed that thca stops
seizures in a rrap model or Mouse model
and you know when you're a desperate
parent and you're up at 3:00 in the
morning and you're searching through the
literature and you come across that and
you realize you can just go in
California get raw cannabis and make a
tincture out of it and then give it to
your kid they started hearing these
anecdotal stories of kids with thca uh
stopping their seizures or reducing them
so that was available then CBG came out
then
cbda um and now we have and then cbdv
and thcv and so like you know the
alphabet soup continues right and now
you know like CBN is available and we
have a lot CBC is available from a few
companies cbga raw um flower that is
before it you know starts to have thca
and cbda in it um and all of these
compounds have some evidence in the
scientific literature of all of them
anti-inflammatory um some of them Target
cannabinoid receptors some don't many of
them Target trip receptors and or trip
channels the trip channels are highly
involved in pain and inflammation they
kind of overlap in the areas of the body
where cannaboid receptors are and
they're targets of these cannaboids are
endoc canabo Target trip channels so
that makes sense um so it's now become
this what I call the wall of vitamins at
the at the store where I go in I look
and I go oh no I don't know which one to
get that's why it's so helpful to have
like a medical practicum so you can
really understand what maybe some of
these compounds do um I'm in general a
pretty neurotic uh physician but with
cannaboids I feel little less Neurosis
because of all this experience I have
but knowing that they're safe and always
start low titr trate up understand the
compound read everything you can about
it so you have an understanding but the
reality is sometimes you get an off
Target and the patient will tell you
they know and if they have anxiety or
they have say you know um it actually
made my pain worse or I feel nauseous
you're on the wrong path you got to
change something yeah no and I have to
imagine that you know with each new
cannaboid that comes online you know it
just gets that much more complicated you
have almost too much variety to choose
from that's why we need to come learn
about cannabis medicine so the patients
can have a guide remember they're going
to pretty much discover if you give them
the tools they can discover what works
for their own body you are s you're
empowering patients to be advocates for
their own health you're not just saying
here's a drug see in three months you
are helping them kind of explore this
and find their personalized or
customized regimen we've been you know
cancer treatment is now becoming very
personalized right it's should not be
cookie cutter when you have and and one
of the reasons I say I see refractory
patients is because they've been treated
with a cookie cutter type treatment and
but they don't fit okay they're not a
cookie right they're a piece of cake and
so we wanna we want to be able to help
those people as well and we don't want
to abandon them and I've had patients
come to me and say the medical
communities abandon us because either
our child or I don't respond to what
they gave us and now I've become like a
problem patient but for many of these
patients cannabis can turn things
around and having this huge arsenal of
different cannabinoids is so important
it's not just all about THC and CBD
anymore yeah no and I have to imagine
that you must constantly be reading up
on the latest research and that's why
you like going to conferences and things
like that is to make sure that you are
always expanding that
Arsenal it is very hard to keep up the
information is coming out at the speed
of light there are more clinical trials
coming out on uh cannabinoids and humans
um we have these studies like the one I
mentioned about dementia with cbda and
thca look my father's 93 and a half and
he's I last night I FaceTime with him
and he's doing great I have him on CBD
cbda
CBG and very Ultra lowd do THC at night
because there's some evidence that ultr
lowd do
THC can be benefit official for
neurocognition okay now he's not perfect
at 93 and a half but he's at home he
cooks dinner uh he Giggles along with us
I last time I visited we did a trivia
game so he grew up he's Lower East Side
of New York City he knows the city in
and out like he was a street kid you
know I mean he had a home but you know
he ran around on the streets let's say
you know back in the day and we're
talking a long time ago was born in 1930
um he could tell me straight he could
tell me the names of all the bridges he
could tell me the names of when they or
the year that they built the subway and
the year that they built this and that
and this building and that building I
mean pretty sharp yeah and some of that
I'm sure is genetics and some of that
I'm sure is living a pretty healthy
lifestyle is you know throughout his
years not being a heavy uh substance
abuser and not smoking cigarettes and so
on but it's amazing to me that he still
has it all together and this is on
cannabis so don't tell me that it's bad
for you it is not bad for you it is bad
for you if you have problematic use but
again medic medical use is is just can
be astounding for some people excellent
all right Bon I do want to be mindful of
your time um but winding down here um of
course in addition to come to the
practicum and make sure that you you you
meet with Bonnie and the other doctors
here but are there other resources or um
ways people people can maybe get in
touch with you or learn from you uh that
you want to share with the audience oh
that's great thank you so well first
thing is that the met the um some of the
lectures from canmed 2023 are available
and I recommend people looking at them I
go back to them all the time I went back
and looked at the Hop uh what is that
hop latent virus that plants have and I
was trying to educate some other people
and I said I'm just going to watch uh
the doctor's video uh presentation one
more time so I got all the details and
then I'm able to really talk about it in
a way that I understand and I supplement
that with reading but so I definitely
recommend the CED 2023 lectures that are
online whichever ones are online um I
actually not to cut you off but we have
all of the canmed lectures previous
years up on our website so great great
resource I yep I have a YouTube channel
under my name Bonnie Goldstein MD and
Bonnie's B and N without the e I also
have my Instagram account where I try to
post as much like new
studies um and just kind of give people
um okay this is what's coming out this
is what we can what what what
researchers are working on so I try to
put out um anything new out there that I
think might be helpful for people and
then of course my book which is in your
background and of I'm embarrassed I
don't have a copy sitting here at my
desk um but uh my book cannabis's
medicine um gives you a very nice uh
walk through the endocannabinoid system
the plant there's a chapter called how
to use cannabis as medicine it explains
what ratios are like what does it mean
to have a CBD to THC ratio what is a
concentration how many milligrams in in
an ML and gives people like just kind of
a stepbystep approach to how to start a
cannabis regimen and then there's about
31 ailments I think that I cover with
some of the research it's very hard to
have a book out there in that there's
new research coming out all the time and
you know you have to you know like stop
adding things so hopefully a rewrite is
coming up soon and I'll be able to
update it this is the second book
cannabis's medicine updated from my
first book cannabis revealed so um and
then um just come see me at canmed I'm
really excited to go and um uh my actual
I think I'm going to drag my husband
along this year because it's his uh
birthday and so I'm making him come with
me so we can celebrate his birthday
while we're there yeah that's excellent
uh I'm going to put links to all those
resources in the show description so
people can check it out and Yeah Bonnie
thanks again for doing it uh for doing
the podcast I should say and and doing
what you do as well thank you for that
um and being a great supporter of camid
over the years we really couldn't do it
without you and uh I really look forward
to seeing you down in Florida I know no
I can't wait um we have to get through
the winter first so we'll we'll see each
other in in the spring thanks so much
for what you do and what uh medical uh
medicinal genomics does and canmed um we
have to have um this kind of support
because we can't get the word out
otherwise and uh it's just so important
and again uh I hope everybody who's
listening will consider coming to canmed
2024 it's really a wonderful wonderful
conference not just for clinicians and
scientists but also for anybody
interested in cannabis um
medicine all right well said thanks
again Bonnie thanks so much see you have
a great holiday yes you too
[Music]
byebye hope you enjoy my conversation
with Dr Bonnie Goldstein
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor the dent Institute
our next episode drops January 10th
that's 2 weeks from
today in the meantime go to camed
events.com now to learn all about the
camed 24 Innovation and investment
Summit be sure to register before
December 31st to take advantage of our
early bird rape also I invite you to
follow us on social media we are on
Instagram Twitter LinkedIn and Facebook
just search for camet events and lastly
we'd appreciate it if you would rate
review And subscribe to the podcast it
really helps all right that's it from us
until next time stay safe stay healthy
and be sure to join us for the next
camed Coffee
Talk
[Music]