hi everybody
thanks for uh coming to my talk
so i'm going to be talking about
cannabis medicine for children i think
you guys all know my background so i'm
not going to spend any time on that but
um i wanted to do something a little bit
different today i think just even for my
own entertainment to um mix it up a
little bit because i talk about a lot of
the same things over and over and i'm
sorry to those who were here
tuesday for the practicum there will be
a little overlap but i i do try to go
into more detail since i have a little
more time
so
i wanted to start with something
i've been doing this now about 14 years
and i've been a physician for 30 plus
years and
i just want to share with you all a few
things i've learned
working with cannabis and working with
sick people including very sick children
and so this is like my favorite part of
my show right here
this is why we all do what we do and
thank you to all the researchers to
medical genomics for putting on this
conference for all the sponsors for
everybody here who does their part in
cannabis i know we're all like-minded
and these are
the most vulnerable patients and some of
these kids have cancer some have
epilepsy some have autism some have
you know irreversible brain damage it's
um
this is why we all should be doing what
we're doing and i know we all have our
stories we have our our mother was sick
or our best friend or our brother but
really um this is what drives me
to try to make it better to try to get
better products to try to get more
research and so on so
um i'm just gonna tell you about a few
things i've learned so sorry about that
other thing shouldn't be there but i
guess i screwed up on my animations but
what it what have i learned cannabis is
good medicine right now you could say
it's great medicine
but i say good medicine i'm talking
about you know when you say oh that that
that's a good person or she's good
people this is good medicine why is it
good medicine because
we routinely witness improvements in
symptoms and quality of life even when
you don't even know what you're doing
with it
right you can go in and buy some
cannabis and walk out and you say oh you
know i didn't know what i was doing i
slept great and i was nicer to my
husband the next day and i didn't yell
at the kids
it's important to know that
many people are able to lower doses or
discontinue other medication
how many here know somebody whether it's
a family member yourself or somebody
you've helped raise your hand if you
know somebody has been able to stop or
lower dose of other medication right
just about everybody who's worked with
patients or just even talking to people
and then also patient satisfaction is
exceptionally high
it's easy to say this anecdotally but
there was a study back in 2014 86
percent i don't know of any other drug
where you get an 86
patient satisfaction and that's because
even if you miss your dose of cannabis
probably likely nothing bad is going to
happen if you overdose on it likely
nothing bad is going to happen so
it's a very easy medicine to work with
and i'm still kind of
i think i said this on tuesday i'm kind
of over it already trying to convince
people this we have enough data and
enough research to show that
patients want this
um there's a study out of stacy gruber's
group with i think it's how you say
cigar
12 months of medical cannabis resulted
in significant improvements on measures
of executive function and clinical state
including sleep pain and quality of life
these are people who were measured and
tested and stacy talks about them being
the most studied group of patients on
the planet
before they start medical cannabis and
then she measured it at three months six
months and here's her 12-month study
that came out last year
clinical improvement was associated with
higher cbd use
cognitive improvements were associated
with clinical improvement
and what they concluded was medical
cannabis patients may exhibit enhanced
rather than impaired executive function
over time we see this over and over i
see this in my pediatric patients they
take mega-high doses of cannabis and
guess what they can finally get back to
school and learning it's the exact
opposite of what we have been taught and
what we've been
propagandized over all these years
second thing i've learned medical
cannabis is safe
now you could argue with me about
problematic use or misuse that's fine
but i'm talking about medical cannabis
someone who is using it specifically to
treat medical condition and so i wanted
to show you
kind of world we live in so when you
think about medical cannabis and people
get really i still get from people
really oh is it safe oh i don't know the
world we live in has drugs that are so
scary look at this a new anti-epileptic
medication is linked to turning you blue
there's something called blue person
syndrome okay now luckily this came this
was taken off the market but
how this got through our regulatory
institutions is beyond me
i mean i guess it's okay if you want to
be blue but
i don't want to be blue how about this
one painful erections while being
treated for ocd i don't know you talking
about trading one condition for another
yes
this is a great one warning this
parkinson's drug can make you addicted
to gambling sex or food so
i
read this article and this poor elderly
woman who's struggling with parkinson's
turns into a gambling addict she lost
250 000 at the local casino
on the slots and when they discontinued
the drug guess what she never gambled
again
but yet this is acceptable and i i find
that fascinating and then here's my
favorite everybody
loss of fingerprints
okay
and this is with a cancer drug and luck
hopefully none of you ever have to take
this but i don't know you know pick your
poison right
cannabis doesn't do any of this
help with the slides
am i doing something wrong
it's stuck
how do i unstuck it oh there we go okay
so i just pulled out a few articles and
any
anybody who sits and read the reads the
medical cannabis literature you're going
to see these words over and over and
over again safe and efficacious well
tolerated mild side effects we really
don't see blue person or loss of
fingerprints or
gambling addiction
here is a study that showed 27 over 2
hundred elderly patients safe and
efficacious and look what it says
cannabis use may decrease the use of
other prescription medicines including
opioids here's another one
uh 2900 cancer patients cannabis just
for palliation well tolerated effective
and safe but
95.9 reported improvement in their
condition
here's another one
this is 367 fibromyalgia patients
medical cannabis appears to be safe and
effective and here's another one
for autism that just came out this year
a review of cannabis for autism
cannabinoid therapy for autism is
associated with low adverse side effects
and reduction in concomitant medication
and if you read through the literature
and even if you just sat for an hour
looking you're going to see these same
words over again so
this idea that cannabis medicine is
fringe that it is should be last resort
it's it's just a bunch of nonsense this
medicine is safe and well tolerated
especially under medical supervision and
even without medical supervision it's
usually very safe and well tolerated
how do we keep it safe all right so see
somebody who does a medical history so
they know what drugs you're taking they
know what treatments you tried they do a
physical exam a review of all your
medications and lifestyle prior to onset
so you can get the best result possible
only use tested products that have a
transparent coa if you don't know what's
in it and you can't reproduce that it's
unlikely to be sustainable medication i
had a patient who
a pediatric patient who has seizures
in fact his picture is one of the
pictures on my initial slide and his
mother was afraid to tell me this but
she eventually told me that she was
taking the oils like i had recommended
and then a cousin handed her a little
bit of rso oil and she just decided to
give it to him and he had a significant
reductions in seizures had she told me
about it we could have gotten it tested
and figured out what it was she used it
up told me about it six months later and
i was like well
that's really not medicine because you
don't have it anymore so it's very
important that we're using products that
we know what's in it we know that it's
reproducible and consistent over time
start low and go slow titration prevents
thc dosing errors
this is important in pediatrics in
elderly patients and really anybody who
is still a little skeptical just this
past thanksgiving i have friends who
i've told them never give a gummy to an
elderly person without cutting it into
pieces but they didn't listen
they gave the night before thanksgiving
he gave his mother with sleep problems
and anxiety and depression a 10
milligram gummy and she basically
had a terrible reaction thanksgiving was
cancelled the next day and they just
kind of babysat her but now she's turned
off to it so remember start low and go
slow especially in those patients who
are cannabis naive
side effects are very rare with
non-impairing cannabinoids like cbd cbg
cbda and so on
also side effects are easily mitigated
everybody's heard me say this change the
dose change the timing change the
product you can mitigate you don't have
to have side effects
first time you're trying something new
or someone you know is trying something
new they should be at home
they shouldn't have like a test in two
hours right or uh you know you're
meeting the in-laws for the first time
you want to try it
at home first see how you feel even
something that you know may be
non-impairing you may you may be
sensitive to it so it's important to
keep it safe that way
and then get help if you don't know
where to start or you haven't found
relief there's so many healthcare
practitioners here today there's so many
nurses and nurse practitioners so many
people to ask for help so please ask for
help if you're not sure what you're
doing or if you think you're doing it
right and you're not getting relief it's
helpful to bounce it off someone else
all right everybody knows this one treat
the patient not the diagnosis we do like
to have an understanding of if you have
this condition or that condition that
maybe you should go in this direction or
that direction is dictated by clinical
experience or by the latest scientific
information but in general we know
personalized individual regimens based
on a patient's response is the way to go
with cannabis and one size does not fit
all and i'm just going to show you this
slide here this is i'm going to be
talking about this this comes from my
autism research
and you can see the patients age 6 to 12
kind of listed and what sex they are in
their dosages per day but if you look at
the cannabinoid content these are all
children with autism
we these are none of these children have
epilepsy because we that was an
exclusion criteria in our in our um
group
but um you can see they're all on
different
cannabinoid
regimens how did that happen well we
followed my rule it in or rule it out
you start with one thing you titrate up
you look if there's any benefit what
dose is that at can i do better than
that now often with most patients you
hit a point at which you start to have
side effects and then we know that
you're at the ceiling dose cbd can have
a ceiling for some patients i have
patients that get gi upset if you go
past a certain dose or they get very
sedated if you go past that's their
ceiling dose we're going to stay below
that let's say that only helps them 75
percent they're only 75 percent improved
well there's room for improvement then
we add a second cannabinoid or we might
try a different product within the same
category all of these patients were on
cannabis for at least a year and during
that year
was as or even
if it was longer than that we worked on
ruling it in ruling it out dialing in on
the products
so always
don't ever think that just because
somebody has one diagnosis this is what
they should be on in the cannabis
world it really should be dialed in
and certainly there's what's happened
now is that when i first started doing
this it was really just thc on the
market and then around 2013 there was
some cbd available and then we started
to see the other compounds come out
now there's so many to choose from so it
makes it a little more difficult but
pick one start there and then go through
and that's why i always say it is
worthwhile if you're dealing with a
significant medical condition to have at
least one consultation with a doctor
nurse practitioner somebody that knows
about this that can at least give you
the lay of the land where does the
research stand and what should i be
looking at so just to get some signaling
on that
all right my next is take care of your
gut and you will have a happy
endocannabinoid system
they are intimately related and is very
important you cannot say oh i'm using
cannabis and it's not helping me while
you're eating a cheeseburger and french
fries from the greasiest place in town
it's uh you have to help your gut
to move forward so that you can have a
healthy endocannabinoid system
and so there's a article that came out
last year that here's a quote the
endocannabinoid system encompasses a key
interface between the gut microbiota the
immune system and homeostasis of the
human host very important for your gut
to be part of this
endocannabinoids and phytocannabinoids
modulate gut inflammation the microbiota
stabilizing the blood-brain barrier
pathway and reducing neuro-inflammation
we think about inflammation
we are
kind of i once had a doctor an
oncologist tell me that we live in a
cesspool of chemicals right now by the
time you leave your house in the morning
you've probably been exposed to 300
chemicals you might not be able to
control some of that but you can control
what you put as my friend says in your
pie hole so it's important to
understand that you want to take care of
your gut and here's just a nice
graphic of this was a article that
looked at how hiv affects the immune
system the gut and ultimately the brain
but as you can see what's at the center
of all of it the endocannabinoid system
and if you're using uh
cannabinoids and you're not finding
benefit think about
taking better care of your gut it's
important because between those two
things you can often
mitigate illness
all right and then there's two very nice
articles so dr russo's beyond cannabis
plants in the endocannabinoid system
excellent talking about this very uh
thing and then also an article that's a
little bit older but i find it to be a
really great article the care and
feeding of the endocannabinoid system so
uh two very nice articles that are
uh help you understand the interplay
between
the various systems in your body and
your endocannabinoid system
and then oh let me go back one here so
my number five and before i get on to
the kids is respect your receptors so
i've been joking around about this for
years respect your receptors so um what
this slide shows i don't know let's see
is there a pointer i don't know if you
can see
i don't think it's working
but anyway what you can see here is the
cell
and on the cell wall are cannabinoid
receptors that you can see they kind of
look they're the like little neon yellow
and then
jwh-0108 is a synthetic
thc like compound so it binds to the
type 1 receptor so what you can see on
there is that with this is showing acute
administration in a cannabis naive rat
if you give them this compound all of
the jwh goes ahead and sticks on to the
cannabinoid receptors
and then what happens is with chronic
use look what's happening here so we
went from a whole bunch of receptors on
the cell wall to just a few a lot of the
compound ligand is still floating around
looking for a place to bind and if
you'll notice the little neon
cannabinoid receptors are now
internalized inside the cell
and this comes from uh what this is the
concept of tolerance okay sometimes down
regulating your receptors can be helpful
but for the most part if you want a good
medicinal effect you want to try to
maintain a decent amount of cannabinoid
receptors that are not down regulated
and so
in the medical world i don't see too
much tolerance but here and there i do
especially those patients who happen to
be thc responders there are people out
there that do very well with thc i
always try to include some cbd in there
because it does seem to help mitigate
some of the tolerance i always hate to
do it what we call it a tolerance break
especially let's say in a child who's
getting very good results with either
epilepsy or autism because if you take
away their medicine
what happens is event they end up back
at their baseline prior to cannabis use
and so parents will say to me oh there's
no way i'm doing a tolerance break
because i can't do 48 hours of horrific
behaviors because i've now lived three
months without that it's like it's
causing them more trauma so what we do
is we do try to use other tools to
changing chemovars or adding in
um
non-thc cannabinoids to try to help do
some of the heavy lifting to try to help
maintain
uh the res the receptors and then when i
often talk with teenagers so if
we get teenagers that come in who um as
i said the other day they know more than
me about their endocannabinoid system so
um they just think all thc all the time
and what ends up happening i actually
had a child who ended up suicidal
he was home
i put him on i said you can use your
vape pen to go to sleep that's fine but
you have to take your cbd in the morning
he had terrible anxiety depression and
it had one suicide attempt years prior
and was just reluctant to take any more
pharmaceuticals
and he was okay with
using cbd added in and after about a
month he decided i don't want to take
the cbd anymore and he's a 17 year old
boy so good luck getting him to take it
and the parents weren't really paying
attention and next phone call i got
about a month later was he was being
held on a you know 51.50 hold for
suicidal but what he had done was
totally escalated his thc use dabbing
and whatnot that the whole rest of that
month so
you know i feel very strongly about this
and i joke around for years that i was
going to make a t-shirt and there's your
t-shirt respect your receptors people
so okay let's get on with the talk for
children and i just want to point out
this is one of my patients a teenager
with epilepsy and autism drew this
picture to tell me just how much
cannabis impacted his life so how nice
is that it's not a beautiful photo or a
beautiful picture that he drew so the
most common conditions we see in
pediatrics by far intractable epilepsy
and autism they often run together
also cancer either for side effects or
to treat a child who has been given a
very poor prognosis
gi disorders attention deficit and
tourette also
anxiety depression chronic pain genetic
conditions and certainly end of life
um
i'm going to focus on epilepsy and
autism that's where we have the most
data a 2000 study done by quantum brodie
showed only 64 of epilepsy patients
respond to uh medications
and then they repeated the study in 2018
to see since there were many new
anti-epileptic drugs on the market and
they found the same thing overall
outcomes and newly diagnosed epilepsy
have not improved and more than one
third of patients experience epilepsy
that remains uncontrolled and this is
where we have to think out of the box i
have many patients that are
up for getting brain surgery
or a device implanted in their chest and
i always say why not try the benign
plant first before you do anything
invasive
i have one child who has has had three
brain surgeries and she was good for one
week after the brain surgery and then
the
seizures came back with a vengeance i'm
not sure how they go back two and three
times because this is certainly not
reversible cannabis has been somewhat
helpful for her condition
this is just a
graph that i made looking at the number
of publications if you just google
cannabidiol and epilepsy or go to pubmed
and you look at the research look at you
know kind of where it course correlates
and
you can see 2013 is when uh cnn aired
the weed documentary with dr sanjay
gupta and it was kind of that kind of
opened the floodgates a bit as he gave
the stamp of mainstream approval there
and as you can see the
scientific and medical community has
responded with research so bravo to us
all of us who have participated in that
and now
certainly clinical research supports the
use of cbd to treat refractive
refractory epilepsy this is now
considered to be a very viable
anti-epileptic drug
and i'm just going to go through some of
the latest studies from the past couple
of years that summarize
what we have learned over the last
decade of watching and and listening
and
researching cbd and other cannabinoids
for epilepsy so
gaston et al
they used purified cbd in 89 children
and 80 adults over two years and they
saw significant mean reduction in
seizure frequency at one month one year
and two years all statistic highly
statistically significant and you can
just see greater than 50 percent seizure
reduction is considered the clinical
standard so you can see in children one
month on cbd 46
and it goes up after two years so if you
have patients in the beginning that are
saying well we're not getting the best
results hang in there look in adults it
went from 31 to 52
and some of that also too is of course
dosing titrating up slowly over time
there was a significant difference in
seizure severity reduction at one year
with adults reporting greater
improvement in seizure severity and that
was highly significant as well
and here you can see just two charts the
first chart is the percentage change in
seizure frequency and and the um you can
see on the uh axis there the percentage
reduction
from baseline so
from zero
um and it drops how how uh down so it's
minus 60 but that's the percentage
reduction and this is over time over two
years and you can see adults is the um
uh dashed line and pediatrics is the uh
solid line and you can certainly see
that
in the in terms of seizure frequency
it's almost equivalent but in the
second graph you can see that adult
severity went down and that's important
because
often these are people who have
struggled with seizures their whole life
and have not had uh any good results
okay how about eeg changes and effect on
sleep so cbd use decreased interactal
epileptic form discharges it's a
mouthful but this is basically evidence
of a neuroexcitatory brain that was
highly significant and then cbd use
improves sleep microstructure and 84.6
percent of those patients with abnormal
sleep again a very high number
here we have
an evaluation on cognitive and
behavioral tests before and after cbd so
this was before and after just three
months looking at patients 89
remained stable or showed reliable
improvement after three months on cbd
very high percentage right cognitive and
behavioral changes were not
significantly correlated to the cbd
dosing which is always very interesting
improvements in short-term and working
memory significantly related to better
therapy response and there was no
adverse group level effects on cbd
reported uh in this study
what about long term so
there was a signaling maybe around i
want to say there was a study that came
out of israel a few years ago that said
maybe cbd effects wear off after three
years and i would tell you that here and
there i saw patients who maybe at the
two or three year mark seem to
maybe lose efficacy and remember in
children they're also growing and
changing and hormones and so on so what
is it is it the medicine doesn't really
work after three years well we have now
this study published last year cbd does
not lose efficacy during treatment
period up to five years
most patients in their group were able
to at least decrease the dose of at
least one other pharmaceutical that they
were using for epilepsy
and certainly again here's those words
well tolerated effective and safe for
long-term use and so that definitely
gives those people out there who are
still reluctant
uh to think about cbd as an
anti-epileptic it gives us the assurance
and i'm just going to share with you i
so i trained at children's hospital
right here in la
and i gave grand rounds the month before
a covet hit
nobody from the neurology department
would come to my talk
okay yeah they they boycotted my talk
now it was standing room only but the
neurology department actually said to
the head of the hospital how is how are
you how are you even justifying this
this is what bothers me the literature's
there right the support is there so just
be aware that we're still in that uphill
battle despite looking at all this
research
all right and here's one that came out
looking at an observational cohort study
of epilepsy patients using this is
artisanal cbd so this is cbd from whole
plant
280 patients using cbd and 138 who did
not and compared to controls the cbd
users had higher quality of life lower
psychiatric symptoms severity better
sleep
better medication tolerability improved
health outcomes longitudinally use of
fewer prescriptions and reduced
healthcare utilization i i think i'm
beating a dead horse here right so i
think we've we've figured out what's
going on
now um dr russo mentioned this the other
day pamplona's study looking at cbd rich
cannabis extracts over purified cbd and
treatment resistant epilepsy
and this was a review of 11 sources with
670 patients pooled the cbd dosing range
was very wide 1 to 50 milligram per kilo
per day
and that just tells you about cbd's very
wide dosing if it doesn't work at a low
dose go up
and the treatment length on the mean was
six months 64
reported improvement in frequency of
seizures and there was more improvement
with the cbd extract 71 then with the
purified cbd at 46 and this was
statistically significant but if you
apply what's called the standard
clinical threshold of greater than 50 or
more reduction of seizures there was no
difference so then i ask you well if
there's no difference then what are we
going to do how do you choose
go ahead and look cbd extract patients
use a significantly lower dose six
milligram per kilo per day versus the
purified which is at 25 milligram per
kilo per day and in terms of the side
effect profile the side effect profile
for artisanal cbd was significantly
better than for uh purified cbd
i find the only reason that i'm
referring patients now to get the
purified cbd epidialex
and it is only approved for three
conditions right now which is um lennox
gastow syndrome dravet syndrome and
tuberous sclerosis
but they will you can get it off label
for other severe epilepsies
what i'm doing is when a patient needs a
very high dose like we're talking 1200
milligrams a day or 1600 milligrams a
day in some of my big teenagers
that is very difficult to afford so what
we do is
we will do some of the dosing as
epidiolex that is
they get help
it's part of the insurance company and
the other part we do with the whole
plant nobody ever said you can't mix
them so i do and it works out well so
the parents don't have such a high
financial burden
and so i initially wasn't too happy with
epidiolex because i don't like that
there's
alcohol and some sucralose in it which
is not great but at the same time if it
helps a family
with the burden of paying for a high
dose and keeps that child off a
multitude of other anti-epileptics it
certainly is the lesser
evil of of
epidiolex versus
other drugs so
all right and now let's move on to drug
drug interactions this was a big concern
when i first started doing this we
really didn't have any data so we were
super super careful with patients
this is a review of six trials looking
at the interactions between cannabidiol
and enzyme inducers or inhibitors and
common anti-seizure drugs
cbd in this study was or review of these
six trials was not found to affect the
cyp3a4 activity
except for the case of a drug called
clobazam clobazam the brand name is anfi
it's a pretty potent benzodiazepine
it's a heavy duty drug it causes a lot
of sedation and slowing down of a
child's brain but it can be quite
effective for seizures
when you mix cbd and clobazam cbd
clobazam is like is a drug in and of
itself but it's also a pro drug in that
when you take it your liver converts
clobazam to a secondary metabolite
called endosmethyl clobazam which is an
anticonvulsant in its own right but
endus methylclobazam is heavily sedating
cbd seems to drive the liver to convert
more clobazam to its metabolite endus
methyl so you can't just give somebody
extra of that second drug the liver has
to make that and so what happens when
they're taken together is there's an
increased exposure to the major
metabolites of both compounds which can
be beneficial for the patient because
now the patient's getting more of that
secondary metabolite which is
anticonvulsant and if they respond to
that sometimes by adding cbd and
boosting up that endos methyl you will
see
some improvement in seizures and you
don't know whether it's the cbd or the
other or both
sometimes you have to reduce the dosing
of clobazam because as you drive up that
secondary metabolite the patients can
get very sedated forty percent of
patients in the epidiolex trials require
dialing back of their omfi dose and so i
it doesn't happen right away it's not
like oh we upped the dose of cbd and the
next day the child sedated it is when
usually a week or two later
cbd and valproate so this is
valproic acid or depakote
there's been a lot of talk about that
because in the epidialex trials they put
in acute liver injury because they did
see
some elevation of the test looking at
liver function and liver enzymes
but in this review it did not cause
clinically important changes in the
pharmacokinetics of either i will tell
you that in my patient population
depakote is very popular being used by
many neurologists and those children
usually get blood work every six months
anyway i have yet to see any issues i
know in the
article that dustin and i co-authored
with
dr seneto out of seattle children's
hospital he's a neurologist he did not
see any changes in
liver tests and children taking
artisanal cbd and i just haven't seen it
it seems to be more so related to the
epidiolex i never say never i just
haven't seen it myself
only time i've actually ever seen
elevated
liver function tests in patients taking
very high dose cvd is in children who
are also on liver toxic chemotherapy so
that combination can cause that
elevation as well and so their
conclusion was quote these trials
indicate an overall low potential for
drug drug interactions between cbd and
anti-seizure drugs except for clobazam
all right now let's talk about delta9
thca which i'm going to call just thca
from now on it was first mentioned back
in 1979 in a mouse
model of
seizures and it was anti-convulsant at
200 milligram per kilo and then of
course there's many anecdotal reports
and i have many patients that take thca
as either their main anti-epilepsy drug
or as part of their regimen
a study that came out this year used
highly purified thca or a mixture of
thca and thc looking at mice that have
what's called dravet syndrome which is a
severe genetic
pediatric epilepsy very very difficult
to treat these children have heat and do
seizures i once had a patient my air
conditioning in my office was out and
the parents came walk came rolling into
my you know the child's in a wheelchair
i say rolling in
and they felt the temperature in my
office and said no way are we even
sitting in this room because she will
have a seizure so those kids are that
sensitive
um so um
the mixture was found to be
anti-convulsant in what's called the six
hertz uh threshold this is for partial
epilepsy this kind of test in the mice
and pretty much on everything else it
really uh didn't appear to work it's
always important to look at dosing and
what does purified mean does that mean
there really isn't any thc in there or
maybe there's still a little bit
because remember thca wants to change to
thc so it's very hard to study it all by
itself
but certainly in my uh in in clinical
practice thca does help a lot of my
patients and because it it's either has
a higher potency or because it's more
bioavailable
you can take a lower dose
it's easier to get into the body than
cbd now looking at cbda the first
published report of its anti-convulsive
activity was actually in a patent back
in 2019
looking at a mouse model of generalized
tonic-clonic seizures we think the
mechanism of action is enhanced
serotonin receptor activation which
appears to be even better than with cbd
and then
in this study which is again a mouse
model of dravet
the cbda brain plasma ratio in an oil
vehicle so this is cbd in just an oil
extract which is usually what's
available on the market
is
this low ratio suggests poor brain
penetration but the question is is it
hitting serotonin receptors in the gut
which is then talking to the brain
but the cbda they tried another vehicle
which was which is something called
tween 20 which is a non-ionic surfactant
emulsifying agent
that's often used to stabilize oil and
water
extractions or
preparations
the brain plasma ratio was much higher
and in this
with this product
they found it was anti-convulsant
against the heat induced seizures in
this dravay model
and then another study that came out
looking at the mouse what's called the
mes seizure this is for generalized
tonic clonic seizures they compared
three different products so look at the
first product that they labeled
chilobinoid that's what they called it
so it's almost 75 cbda
and has other minor cannabinoids and
then they use magnesium as like this
kind of a binder to help penetrate
through the lipid layers and then they
used a purified cbda and i want to point
out to you that in the carlobinoid you
see 75
and in the second one you see not almost
93 percent so the second one is a higher
potency right
and then they compared it to basically a
cbd isolate
and what they found was the kylobinoid
was more effective
than the uh kind of pure cbda
in reducing seizures and this supports
the entourage effect because if you the
lower potency but with the minor
cannabinoids
uh seem to work better
than the higher potency so that supports
the idea that when you have that whole
plant that you can actually let all
those compounds do some of the heavy
lifting
for symptoms and then they also found
that it was comparable to cbd i have
started using cbda in my pediatric
patients and i am seeing some of these
patients have good results not only for
lowering seizure frequency but also
severity and duration as well as parents
starting to report they feel like their
child has less anxiety
and also sleeping better so again it's
hard to know when you're adding
something into an already established
regimen
is it synergy is it that compound again
very hard to know but when we're going
in the right direction and by the way
too i'm also seeing some good results in
the kids who have autism who don't have
epilepsy with cbda mostly the the most
common
report is my child's less anxious
and so i'm finding that i've now kind of
moved cbda up in the list of what to try
a little bit higher uh priority
all right and then let's just talk about
thc for seizures everybody a lot of
neurologists are telling patients oh thc
causes seizures even a low dose and i
just don't see that
and we don't see that of being borne out
by the research so in preclinical
findings looking at six species and 34
discrete animal models 21 studies found
anti-convulsant effects
one study pro-convulsant one mixed and
11 studies didn't find any any effect on
seizures a report from 2016 was
observational looking at 292 adult
patients 190 with epilepsy 64 with
what's called psychogenic non-epileptic
seizures and 26 with both these were
patients who mostly inhaled about 1 gram
a day
84 of the patients using thc reported
improvement in seizures it's a very high
number
almost 73 percent of the ones with
psychogenic non-epileptic seizures are
reported improvements
and then here we have a study just from
two years ago looking at retrospective
reports of using thc in patients with
um what i would call in track severe
intractable epilepsy so a 21 year old
with epileptic and this comes out of
italy epileptic and encephalopathy since
infancy the seizures went from 20 a
month to seven a month with thc alone
an 18 year old with west syndrome with
another severe pediatric epilepsy since
infancy reduction of seizures from 13 a
day to two a day and this last one is
amazing here 25 year old with juvenile
absence epilepsy in rare
maybe twice a year generalized
tonic-clonic seizures went from 20
seizures a day to only four a month very
impactful uh for that uh for that
patient and certainly for their family
so we think the mechanism of action is
decreases glutamate via cb1 activation
i'm sure there's other mechanisms but i
find thc to be very clinically helpful
in my pediatric patients sometimes just
adding a little bit reduces seizures
and also if they're weaning off
anti-epileptic drugs they're going
they're going to have withdrawal those
drugs are very difficult to get off of
and i use low-dose thc parents we
usually put the kids on some regular
regimen maybe morning and night but i
also tell the parents you can spot treat
any time as needed treatment when you
see your child having any difficulty and
remember you don't have to stay on that
that's something just to get them
through the weaning
and often parents seek benefits and say
oh can we just make it part of the
regimen and so it's just easier for them
to have it part of the regimen
day-to-day and then of course there is
some tolerance that can occur if it's
the only medication that's being used
there's a little boy i take care of that
has a multitude of medical issues and
the only thing that's helped his
seizures is thc
but he's on a very high dose we're still
getting good control but i'm a little
afraid that we may lose the medicinal
effect but we'll just have to wait and
see what happens
now we're going to switch to autism so
the cdc now the latest numbers 1 in 44.
it was 1 in 54 the last time i spoke in
person so that's a little disheartening
boys are four times
more likely to be diagnosed than girls
there are no approved medications to
treat the core symptoms
there are two fda approved medications
that treat irritability they are
atypical antipsychotics that have a lot
of side effects
also off-label medications like
stimulants anti-depressants anti-anxiety
drugs
are being used
but often have low efficacy and a risk
of side effects new pharmaceutical
studies show low efficacy except for
crossover there was one study uh
reported in this
uh report this year that said all these
other drugs aren't really working but
the cannabinoid study shows promise so
that's always good to be included and
then we know these patients have more
inflammation including neuroinflammation
and gut issues
so i'm going to speed up a little bit
because i want to get to my research
this is another
graph just to look at when did we start
seeing publications on autism and
cannabis and it's not so long ago right
2019 is really when it took off just a
few reports before that so there's a lot
of interest now and it's
i think do one parents are going to use
it they don't have a lot of choices and
again safe well tolerated efficacious
so let's look at this so we know that
type 2
receptors are upregulated in children
with
autism
evidence of endocannabinoid system
dysfunction and then we have a study
from 2018 from stanford that measured
plasma anandamide levels not an easy
thing to do
and they found that the anandamide
endocannabinoid levels were
statistically significantly lower in
children with autism to the point where
they could basically pick out the kids
who had autism based on their blood work
without looking at the child
and another report out of israel lower
circulating endocannabinoid levels in
children with autism spectrum so now we
can see that there is clearly some
endocannabinoid dysfunction in these
patients
if you just compare a few studies that
came out between 2018 and 2019 these are
just all
studies looking at children taking high
cbd low thc preparations
if you look there 20 to 1 mostly the
very last one out of south america was
75 to 1 ratio
in this first study though they did add
in thc if the patient did not have a
good result with
just the high cbd and they found 52
percent improved on 20 to 1 and by
adding in thc another 33 percent so this
idea of no thc for these patients
remember they're low in anandamide dr
micholem teaches us over and over that
anandamide and thc mimic each other and
why would you leave a child deficient so
i'm really anti-cbd only laws because
that really limits
um how um
leaving a lot of patients out who could
really benefit from cannabis medicine
and then i'm just going to go through if
you see in this first study 73 remained
on treatment again satisfaction patient
satisfaction right or at least parental
satisfaction
overall improvements in 75 percent
82 plus per uh percent remained in
treatment in this study and then 77.7
remained on treatment and if you go
through side effects mild mild mild and
again in a study sometimes nobody's
manipulating the medication to eliminate
the side effect but certainly we do that
in clinical practice
and now i just want to talk about the
last 15 minutes here talk about my
research so i'm working with a group
called campformatics and my two research
partners are sitting here dr izak kurek
and ken epstein
and they approached me actually at a
canmed conference a number of years ago
and asking me to do research on what we
call pharmacometabolomics it's a
mouthful as well looking at the impact
of medical cannabis on
children who use
medical cannabis to treat autism and we
published two papers
one at the end of last year and one just
i think a month or two ago looking at
what's called cannabis responsive
biomarkers that we collect in saliva
and so what are are these cannabis
responsive biomarkers and what is
pharmacometabolomics so basically what
you're doing is you're just collecting
chemicals from the body and you can use
urine you can use blood you can use
tissue you can we chose to use saliva
and what you're looking at is this these
compounds called that make up what's
called the metabolome which is a group
of compounds that allows us to see bio
like the metabolites of the biochemical
pathways so one of the ways to look at
this is that if you look at your dna you
can see what is potential but these
biomarkers tell you actually what is
going on in that human actual data as
what their body is doing in terms of
those pathways and so these biomarkers
allow a clinician to kind of see where a
patient is at baseline where they are
after treatment if you stop treatment
what happens and it allows you to see
whether or not maybe
there's a build up of a certain chemical
that's causing toxicity it allows you to
personalize treatment based on
what we call the collecting it before
treatment and then following after and
it gives you numbers it gives you data
not and i
i'm the first person to argue what my
the parents tell me is the truth they
are struggling and they are trying to
find an answer they do not lie
especially with out-of-pocket costly
medication when it's not working i hear
about it okay so
don't i always people say oh it's
wishful thinking so they tell you
that it's um it's better that is not
true that is not my experience i'm sure
the clinicians in the audience can tell
you when patients are not it's not
working they tell you but this actually
gives us hard and fast objective data
and so this is not new there are
numerous studies that are published
looking at metabolomics especially for
autism and you can see here one that's
looking at blood and one looking at
urine and i don't know if if you tell a
parent of a child with autism that you
have to have to go get blood work they
will look at you and say well you're
going to go with my child i'm not going
because that can be very very difficult
these children have a lot of fear people
come at them with needles and so on more
so than just children without autism so
it is nice to be able to collect saliva
at home very easy the parents can do it
and so what we did was he had 15
children with autism who were on medical
cannabis treatment that was deemed to be
pretty successful
pre meant we did a uh behavioral survey
and saliva collection before they got
their medical cannabis in the morning
and you can see on the right what we did
was no medical cannabis for at least
eight hours and no food
or high sugar drinks and then we had
them rinse their mouth to try to
minimize any noise in that in that
saliva and then peak was the same thing
a behavior survey done by the parents
and then saliva collection 90 minutes
after we had nine children typically
developed who gave us saliva to
establish what we call the physiologic
range and we looked at what's called
cannabis responsive biomarkers that
measured different pathways so chemicals
involved in neuronal dysfunction
pain aggression and inflammation and
again here is
what the
patient population looked like it was
mostly boys when you look at dosage
times per day some kids took one dose in
the morning some took two throughout the
day some took three
edible or tincture edible just meant
they were putting all these kids around
tincture that they were putting their
medicine into food and then swallowing
it so and then you can see as i've shown
you already the regimen was very
different from most of these kids
now this is the behavioral rating scales
before so this is in the morning before
they get their medical cannabis dose and
so
11 children were rated severe one child
moderate and two children mild you can
see red is kind of the severe scores and
so you can see that this chart and by
the way so along the top this is each
child a1 is this one of the
six-year-olds a2 a3 a4 and so on
and and you can see what a heterogeneous
group right so it's very different from
child to child
now looking this is after they took
their medical cannabis and the behavior
ratings so you can see a lot more blue
right what we saw was 11 children
improved two children had mixed response
depending on the symptoms being asked
about and two kids had bad days they
just exhibited increased difficulties on
that day and who knows maybe asking them
to give saliva threw them off a little
bit or you know they were just didn't
get enough sleep the night before it's
hard to know but overall we have uh
predominant that patients were doing um
it that they improved
now let's look at this real quick so
this is
uh our typically developing group so you
can see on the bottom one through nine
those are our patients that gave saliva
and uh overall this is their biomarkers
and you can see they all kind of fall in
within two standard deviations of each
other right there's not a lot of
variance in the typically developing
children
and if you go all the way to the right
you can see the children with autism the
dark blue that's where they fell for
most of their biomarkers and then to the
right as after you see the peak that's
after cannabis
and so you can see that it corrected and
really what we say is it shifted towards
the physiologic range
right established by those children
without autism so here's one example so
n acetyl asper aspartic acid naa this is
an abundant neurotransmitter and it
reflects neurodensity and viability
basically neuronal dysfunction
and reading the research you can have
low levels in autism you can have high
levels and high functioning autism you
really don't want it to be outside of
that physiologic range because that
indicates some neuronal dysfunction and
what we saw was two distinct groups so
if you look at the dark bars right the
dark bars is they're either very
significantly elevated or
kind of close to the typically
developing but in all cases the cannabis
treatment modulated both groups towards
the rain the physiologic range which
suggests that the cannabis treatment is
homeostatic if it's low it's coming up
and if it's high it's coming down it's
stabilizing so it's very fascinating you
can see the in this um uh graft all the
way to the right those are the uh that
typically developing groups so you can
compare and you can see the differences
with before and after so this is very
exciting and this is
nice to see that it's not just anecdotal
anymore that's very important and again
this is preliminary study so i don't
want to overstate but we were very
excited with these results and here's
just another way of looking at it this
is three of our older kids
so um the arrow pointing down that kind
of teal arrow pointing down that's the
physiologic mean and then minus two to
plus two standard deviations which all
of the children and typically developing
fell within and you can see these are uh
to the left is the list of biomarkers
you can see all these biomarkers are
kind of off the charts on these kids
right
and then
i really like the slide because it
really shows this is after medical
cannabis this is amazing
right to see that their biomarkers shift
and it correlated with the behavioral
survey
so important
all right and here's another one this
comes from our second paper looking at
lipid based
salivary biomarkers so we had a lot of
biomarkers to look at so we separated
them and these are the lipid base these
are
compounds that are inherently involved
with the endocannabinoid system as well
so here you can see the patients
are listed on the left a1 through a18
and you can see the
biomarker on the legend at the bottom
the various
sphingosines i think is that right
and then again here you see after they
take their medical cannabis so what we
saw was that medical cannabis optimized
levels of these biomarkers in 94 of
patients so this is a tool to be used to
help us personalize medicine
finally after 26 years of
trial and error we may be able to start
using this tool at some point
as we grow our
database
and then one last thing i want to show
you is this predictive
and again early data but if you look at
the first patient as
so these are all the biomarkers listed
in gray
and the first column which is mostly red
that's our patient one of our oldest
patients a 12 year old and what you can
see is all those biomarkers are
significantly out of the standard
deviation
and remember the light blue is optimal
the dark blue is like um
is bordering and then the red is way out
and so what you can see is that the
likelihood of this patient pre so this
is at pre
and what we determined was that this
patient is 93 percent likely to respond
to cannabis this would be a very helpful
tool to be able to determine who to try
cannabis in and who you may say you know
what maybe you want to pursue another
treatment because remember it's time
consuming and it's costly
and so this is a very nice
early
result that we're hoping that with more
data collection that we'll be able to
really see if we can
justify
checking a patient beforehand to see if
there is some predictive value there
these are our study limitations small
sample size doesn't reflect the
heterogeneity of autism
unable to associate cannabinoid regimen
with specific biomarker responses at
this point although there was some
signaling
now some patients the parents
after you're on you know cannabis for a
while that parents know the dose so they
kind of eyeball it with the eyedropper
and i'm usually like really a stickler
for that using that 1ml syringe so
they're measuring it properly but
it may have not been an accurate
reflection of the dose and then in this
study we gave equal impact to all the
biomarkers because at this point we're
still trying to sort out which ones are
really important in this particular
population of patients
and that's it thank you very much
[Applause]
you have a question dr biermann
yeah
this is epilepsy
right
autism
uh by the way you did a great job on
that expert witness thing
is um the um
i have some patients that just get thc
and a lot of improvement i'm thinking of
two particular ones one was a
nine-year-old girl she got 10 milligrams
the parents and the teachers said she
had a 30 improvement in one week and the
other one was the grandson of a
physician
and he required 30 milligrams of thc
twice a day and he lived in a uh
residential living facility and when he
ran out once they called me up and said
hey hey it was in it was in a a a candy
bar so will you will you rewrite it i
did so uh i guess i put in a good word
for thc and i want to know what
what you think about it because these
studies
are all based on
different doses and uh
you know we don't know what
actually causes some of these things
and that's it
thank you dr biermann so i agree with
you thc is an incredible
compound
and we can no longer live in this world
that tried to make it cbd good and thc
bad
no absolutely not thc can do what cbd
cannot sometimes
a lot of the parents that i see look i i
could tell i can i hate to say this but
i can pick out a cop and an attorney
really easily
i worked in the pediatric er for a
really long time you start to understand
personalities you know within about five
minutes of walking into the room
i've had fathers who come in you know
they come in for the first consultation
with their child having horrific
seizures and
when i bring up thc there's this
what what
like what are you doing and i'm like oh
you're a law enforcement
i can tell right away
they truly have this it's been drilled
into them right thc is useful th i
always try to include thc the problem
with thc right now believe it or not
my patients are having a harder time
accessing
good quality low potency thc tinctures
than before legalization
yeah right
what happened to all the good thc
tinctures in
california right they kind of
disappeared there's like three companies
that where you can measure one milligram
two milligrams three milligrams there's
a great product on the market it's 75
milligrams per 1 ml
how do i dose that 0.1 ml is 7.5
milligrams
i don't want to start with that dose in
a three-year-old right so
um i love thc i'm very upset that it's
starting to become
uh difficult to access for my patients
because again dosing is key i these
patients are that i take care of they
are very complex and it can be the
difference of like
.05 mls on a syringe the difference
between having a good day and having a
bad day so we want to be able to measure
the thc and know the dosing and keep up
with that especially as they grow
hi bonnie it's ethan great job
um
you'd mentioned a problem with sucralose
and epidiolex was that related to its
interference with the gut microbiome
yes that's exactly what parents are
concerned about because you know they'll
go and read all the ingredients you have
to remember a lot of these patients are
kids that have mult a multitude of
issues like mitochondrial disorders
i have a patient who literally the mom
tries one drop in the mouth and he's had
bad reaction to one drop this is a
child with what's called pans or pandas
he has mitochondrial disorder he has
autism and epilepsy and a multitude of
other issues
they hear sucralose and they go running
in the other direction that's what it is
and they're worried about the gut and
they're worried about the liver
because when you read about sucralose
it's not exactly a liver friendly right
and then just to comment and see
what you think
um
you know i i was really struck by the
carla study that pointed out that thca
required an anti-convulsant dose of 200
milligrams per kilogram per day and
you're using nothing like that
uh you know it really appears that the
ramp model is no good uh rodents barely
have a cerebral cortex
thca
does not appear to cross the blood-brain
barrier when it's intact but in severe
epilepsy it's not intact and that's why
i think it works at these lower doses
does that make sense to you i agree i
think uh these patients that have
excessive neural inflammation probably
have a compromised blood-brain barrier i
don't know how we're going to prove that
i think the only way that we would be
able to do that is to join up with a
neurosurgeon who is doing uh surgery on
either pediatric or adult patients who
where they go in and they remove the you
know the loci or the focus of where the
seizures are coming from
after the brain mapping is done and
maybe we can try to get to look at some
uh the blend barrier and see if we can
find out if it's uh compromised i don't
know of any other way to do it in humans
sure thank you thank you
hi dr goldstein catalano here um for
your patients with autism you who you
said reported about a 75
improvement what sorts of uh clinical
outcomes were you
were you looking at for them yeah great
question so we look at aggression
we look at self-injurious behavior
we look at ability to transition from
one act activity to another that's a big
thing
uh you know i've had parents who tell me
their kids are getting thrown out of
school because they the child can't go
from one activity to another and throws
a chair at the teacher trying to move
from one activity to another
sleep
and then one of the biggest ones is
anxiety kids with autism suffer suffer
some terrible anxiety it's just
i call them ferraris going down the
freeway at the with you know um what is
that pedal to the metal
and remember a lot of the drugs that
we're using for these patients just kind
of put them parked we don't want that we
just want them to go speed limit right
we want them to be able to function and
integrate into a classroom and learn and
basically what we want is them to reach
their potential and a lot of these kids
are written off they're non-verbal
and maybe they're not following
directions or they're super anxious and
people write them off as you know
intellectually disabled and the vast
majority of my patients are not
intellectually disabled they can get the
work done they can learn
i have a patient right now who's 11
years old who has the vocabulary of a
phd student i mean he's amazing when he
types
but he gets no credit for anything
because he has all of this other stuff
that it when people see it they just go
oh yeah you know he's not even worth the
time of day and
he has done incredibly well on cannabis
so he was a child who
actually had such severe self-injurious
behavior he broke his own arm
and i mean this is what people are
dealing with and so um when we look at
these behaviors you're basically scaling
irritability and aggression and
uh anxiety and so on
does that answer your question it does
thank you and have a second question if
i can sure
when you integrate the how do you
integrate the medical cannabis regimen
when they're already on other
medications when they're on their
medication yeah so i leave medication
alone for the most part
and i start with the cannabis and i just
say we're just gonna i know you're
anxious to wean it but let's just leave
it alone because if you start weaning
and you're adding cannabinoids and
something goes south you don't know
what's what so my general rule of thumb
is one change at a time occasionally i
break that rule
but what i'll do is i'll usually just
based on the patient's symptoms if
they're very aggressive or
self-injurious or not sleeping at night
i will lean more towards like a cbd thc
low ratio
if it's a child who's not having a lot
of that aggression or self-injurious um
or is still is sleeping okay i'll lean
towards more of a high cbd low thc
because about half the kids will respond
with that and i was going to say i was
going to say this with dr biermann asked
me about thc
my point about saying there's not a lot
of thc
um uh
preparations out there that are are
useful now for pediatrics there's some
i have parents like waiting for a
dispensary to call them that they got
the product in and there's people here
who live on that side where i text them
and say are you are you going to get
this in because these people ran out and
they're using something else and the kid
lost a week of his life because he
couldn't go to school because all his
behaviors came back because he doesn't
have the proper medicine
cbd from the hemp world if you know you
look at the coas and you follow
companies for a while there's a lot of
good cbd out there and the parents can
order it online or go pick it up at the
local
health food store
and it just makes it so much easier and
in california they're not paying that
crazy high state tax along with the
other taxes that go with it so as much
as i can i do try to incorporate
products that are from the hemp market
because it's just easier for the
families right
but if something needs to come from the
dispensary so that's thc thca and any of
the low ratios it makes it a little more
difficult for families but basically i
just try to go through each
cannabinoid and i
we didn't really talk about this but cbg
is a very helpful cannabinoid in autism
it's anti-inflammatory i have patients
who've become verbal on it
i see
focus with cbg
and again what are the mechanisms you
know we heard some lectures today about
cbg certainly a wonderful cannabinoid
easily accessed by parents as well right
on the hemp market you can i i don't
know if you can get it in a dispensary i
don't think so
so
the whole idea behind the regimen takes
into all these factors right it's just
not one size fits all i try to start
with what the patient's needs are
where the family lives their access
their lifestyle do they travel a lot
because again you're not going to be
traveling all over the world with thc
because that might get confiscated and
then you're stuck somewhere without it
so there's a lot of things that go into
how you create a
regimen for a patient but it is
basically rule it in or rule it out if
something works we keep it and then we
move on to the next i usually don't wean
drugs for at least i'd like to see a few
months of stability
and when you get that improvement
parents always say how am i going to
know i'm like you know you know your
child right so we all know our loved
ones we know when they're having a good
day and a bad day and so if you watch
over time after a few months and the
child's doing well you can start to wean
don't be surprised if you have to give
more thc while you're weaning a drug or
more cbd because sometimes it is doing a
little bit for the patient or just
removing it you have to start you know
it throws them out of balance and you
have to get back into balance
thank you very much you're welcome
hi uh marley colt i'm from utah but i
asked you a question yesterday and i
think that your answer was just
phenomenal and i think everyone could
benefit from it
so your
opinion on medical cannabis inhalation
for children and how
young they can inhale for acute symptoms
obviously we don't want them smoking a
joint or a bong or something but still
would you prefer them try vape
cartridges and or a dry herb vaporizer
um yeah just elaborate on that so my
experience with vaping in children is
pretty extensive so i have a handful of
pediatric
epilepsy teenagers who get auras which
is the sensation that a seizure is
coming and if they vape thc
or a one to one cbd thc it stops the
seizure from happening and that has i've
seen it over and over in certain
patients so i have no problem with them
using
an uh vaporizer and either it there's a
i don't want to endorse a company here
there's a company here that if you take
a puff the device
vibrates kind of like your phone
vibrates and that's like about two and a
half milligrams depending on the makeup
and a lot of parents like that because
they know oh okay it's kind of close to
do it's a dose right they're not just
not sucking on the thing and then i do
have uh some patients who have
rage with autism they're aware of their
rage they know that they get into this
you know kind of escalated
they feel that anxiety and they will ask
for a take a puff they will go to their
parent and they either use a
flower
vaporizer with flour or they'll use one
of these other vape cartridge devices i
have not seen any issues in these
patients
using inhaled for
basically rescue think about right we're
rescuing it's rescue medicine so
this is not unusual in epilepsy there's
nasal rescue medication there's rectal
valium there's all kinds of rescue
medicine out there so
certainly there's no reason that we
can't use this and it is quite
successful now when you ask me the age i
don't think i've ever had anybody under
eight use a vaporizer i'm not sure
dustin have you had any patients younger
than eight no yeah so um i you know they
have to be able to do it now i do have a
family and i showed them on tuesday this
uh
brother's sister so the brother has
epilepsy autism cyclical vomiting
syndrome and a genetic abnormality he's
done incredibly well he's in my book his
name is gavin
and when he gets a cyclical a cyclical
vomiting episode the parents have a
volcano vaporizer they have homegrown
gran uh what is it granddaddy purple
and
they put him in the bathroom
and they ramp up their volcano
this has they've been able to avoid
emergency room
i mean they were at the er every month
for the longest time and he's on high
dose cbd and thc whatever it is that
triggers him
when it goes it goes
and so this has really helped
his sister when she got covid had a
seizure first seizure in four years
and she caught it at school even with
the mask on and she
had her seizure
and she seemed like she was going to
cluster a little bit so i said go ahead
and just use the volcano on her
and she recovered she didn't have any
further seizures no clusters no nothing
i mean it works now they both don't like
it they scream bloody murder and that's
why they go in the bathroom because they
don't want the neighbors calling the
cops that the kids are getting
but they don't like the device over you
know so what they did was they took the
volcano and they kind of rigged up a
little pediatric oxygen mask to it and
there is a video online that you can see
a patient in texas who's very well known
a young lady with severe autism is very
self-injurious and her parents have the
volcano always ready to go and they just
kind of got some tubing they got a
pediatric
mask and they give her the vape and you
see her very unhappy to very happy very
quickly so i think it's something that
we cannot disregard it's something that
should be included in many of these
pediatric cases
yeah thanks a lot for the presentation i
just want uh to uh we might clarify your
comment regarding uh the effects of cbd
on the patient
uh microbiome
uh because i i sort of hear you were
saying something regarding the
uh susceptibility of the patient
uh due to uh mitochondria so that i
would just you know key with someone
sorry i don't understand the question
uh the question like what does cbd do to
the microbiome yeah what is this well by
enhancing so remember cbd enhances your
end i mean cbd has a as tons of targets
in your body
in autism patients in autism and then
the first part and the second part of
the question is uh we have a panel
earlier today that talk about uh how uh
regulation in different state in this
country now right now there is no
difference in guinea you know across
this country for microbial contaminant
testing for recreational and medical
cannabis i was just wondering if you
have any insight you know moving forward
should there be a different guideline
for medical cannabinoid recreational
cannabis thank you right oh that's a
good question i don't know that i'm the
right person to ask to answer that
second question
i would say i will tell you that so far
i haven't had anybody get sick even in
the unregulated market because we're
always very careful with pediatric
patients we we never really use a
product unless the parents doing it like
went rogue and is doing it on their own
for me it's a deal breaker if i don't
have a coa
that's it so i have a coa so i can
always see what the patient is on and we
can also look at batch to batch to see
if there's any change you know early on
back in 2008 or i should say really 2013
i had patients that would start with one
product and get great results and go
right back to the same company or the
same cultivator processor and get the
oil exactly labeled exactly the same
thing and they say oh my child's not
responding anymore it's not the same but
it's different it's a different team of
r d it was made different we don't even
know what's in there we have to get a
coa and that's when i started looking at
coas was very early on
when my patients were getting very
inconsistent results um in terms of the
microbiome that's like a whole lecture
and i would refer you to ethan russo's
paper and also to the care and feeding
but basically
remember cbd enhances your
endocannabinoid system by allowing
anandamide to hang around a little
longer it blocks the um breakdown of an
andamide or encourages that pathway and
so by establishing uh an enhanced
endocannabinoid system i mean that's the
whole idea behind cannabis is that we're
augmenting the endocannabinoid system to
get it back into balance
hi um
so
about 10 years ago i was having all
these ibs symptoms and so i started
reading about people juicing
and um
so i decided i would juice and this was
before i was going into the office and i
figured oh it's thca i'll be i'll be
fine
because it was fresh material
and i ended up getting really stoned and
i was like what the hell is happening i
figured oh there must be some
decarboxylated material
in here
and so i tried it again
i got stoned again and
anyway it led me to question whether in
people with certain acidic
uh stomach conditions
uh whether there could be thca
essentially decarboxylating in the gut
and um ethan's question about
you know why thca appears to maybe be
effective
um
and
you know the hypothesis that maybe it
has to do with the uh blood brain
barrier you know
having a break a breakdown in these
kinds of patients i think we might also
look at variability in terms of ph
levels in the gut of these patients
because obviously we know
that ph is associated with microbiomes
et cetera so i'm wondering if you've if
you've seen anybody take thca and get
high
and um second whether you think that
that might be a a good
hypothesis for somebody to pursue now
that i'm not in the cannabis game i'd
love to see somebody pursue that
research well i think it's already been
done and i think that we've discounted
that it does not appear that thca
converts to thc in the body and nor does
cbda convert to cbd in the body
so that those i could look up those
references and share that with you um in
terms of getting high on thca sure i've
had patients get high on what's reported
to be thca because remember by the time
my patients get it they're usually not
using whole plant or raw or
plant material it's usually been
processed somewhere along the line and
depends on how long it was sitting on a
shelf what the was it kept in a
refrigerator did it get exposed like was
it sitting in a truck where it sat
outside a distribution center in the hot
southern california weather so it's hard
to know because there will be conversion
in that bottle there's always some thca
i'm sorry thc in a bottle of thc
we just don't know how much now there's
one product that i've been using with my
patients that's like a 20 to 1 thca to
thc
but there's also products out there that
have thca and cbd there's products out
there that have thca one to one with thc
so we have to read labels you have to
know what you're getting and i highly
recommend keeping it in a refrigerator
if it's not in a dark bottle put it in a
dark bottle or wrap it in tin foil
because every time you open and close
the refrigerator there's some light
getting in so
in order to maintain it as close to as
like when you purchased it but again
before buying it in a dispenser you have
no idea what happened to it so it
certainly could contain a lot of thc
and that's why i always tell patients to
always start with a low dose i'm not
sure why you became so intoxicated maybe
you're
maybe dustin has a you have a qui an
answer dustin
um
yeah it i i suppose it could have been
cavitation from from juicing i you know
i was lucky enough to have access to a
mass spec and so i
took what i had and i
looked at it and it was thca wow so um i
i think that the the and i'm familiar
with the data that you're talking about
um i don't think that that data uh at
all accounted for uh people with um
gut conditions specifically yeah there's
probably some variability sure yeah so i
think that there's potentially a ph
issue happening because when i tried the
thca when i wasn't in an acute um
you know episode i it didn't get me high
yeah that's interesting
and i tell people like i have parents
that say is this going to make my child
high or is it going to make them
agitated is this going to make them calm
i say all bets are off don't guess just
try it and see because it's very hard to
guess with cannabis
right it's a it's polypharmaceutical to
start with right too many there's lots
and lots of compounds we want them all
in there but you just don't know which
person's going to be sensitive to what
and then you know last night listening
to daddy speak you know he found these
go to sleep one and go to sleep too
we're not even accounting for all of the
compounds that we have no idea
right and that and but i
really believe again
the um
the information we have at this time is
that cannabis is safe it's well
tolerated and i don't really have any
qualms about treating pediatric patients
with it especially under medical
supervision because really things don't
go south too often so
thank you for your question
thank you
excuse me thank you bonnie for all your
work with pediatrics uh you and i share
that field uh um but i had a question uh
twofold um with the biomarkers that you
saw is uh you think that might help with
early detection of autistic children and
also um
would we look at maybe dosing these
children early on
very early ages and will we slow down
the progression of autism or at least
help
with development yeah great questions
thank you so yes i do think that these
can be used as biomarkers once we have
more data and we're able to really see
which ones are very highly elevated and
are consistently elevated across
remember it's a spectrum disorder so we
want to be able to have the best idea of
which biomarkers correlate the best i
absolutely think that would be great and
i mentioned this the other day that you
might be able to use plasma anandamide
levels as a bio as a
biomarker for autism as well so there
are a number of things that we can look
at maybe we do anandamide and biomarkers
and we see if there's some correlation
there as well i'm sorry what was your
second question
oh right
yeah i do think starting them earlier uh
would be helpful and someone might say
how early i mean the youngest patient
i've ever treated was a six week old
with a severe
genetic
seizure disorder that was likely having
seizures in utero i couldn't treat them
until i had the diagnosis at six weeks
is when the genetics came back and we
started treatment and that child did
fairly well it was a devastating
metabolic syndrome so i don't know how
good we're going to be able to get that
child but i certainly wasn't going to
wait and let him continue to have he's
having hundreds of seizures on his eeg a
day
and you know and then what are you going
to are you going to give a six-month-old
a multitude of um
anti-epileptic drugs i mean
right do no harm
um so he did okay i mean he had much
less seizures we never got him
seizure-free and it's not
it the this group of patients that have
refractory epilepsy look i have had
patients that have tried up to 22
different anti-epileptics you're talking
about a long time to try these you're
losing brain cells as you go
to me if you're really hardcore and want
to try one or two go right out of the
gate
but i do always think that it's worth a
conversation in the beginning why not
use the benign plan
now that we have so much data why not
try it what if your child is the child
that's going to respond and you don't
have to go down that pathway of those
hardcore drugs that do cause a lot of
somnolence and
all all other kinds of side effects
hi well thank you for all your work
first of all uh my question was
regarding the marker for your research
study on about sleep
how do you guys measure the sleep
efficiency in autistic children was that
a study that i quoted for sleep i i
believe you asked actually yo you
answered the question about the markers
and one of your markers for your
research study was sleep for the
improvement remember which one it's talk
do you have
did we have a biomarker for sleep
no i think it was inflammation pain
neuronal dysfunction
okay sorry i thought you mentioned sleep
so i was just wondering if it was
polysonography or it was uh actually
sleep diaries yeah it's a good question
i i did mention sleep in one of the eeg
reports
and what they did was they had
the children or the patients in that
report did where the eeg suit through
sleep
and so they did have
brain waves looking at the quality of
the sleep and what they call the
microstructure and it was like something
over 75 percent of those patients had
improvement in their sleep micro
microstructure based on an eeg
okay okay okay was that just a portable
unit probably right yeah okay
yes i'm not sure where they did that
yeah
hi again thank you amazing work
um
the gut microbiome being so important
are any of these kids following a
special diet like a
low-carb
vegetable-rich diet or is that just
impossible no it's not impossible it's
you know
it's hard when you have a special needs
child to then also control everything
that goes into their mouth
especially when they are super super
super picky yeah and they have problems
with textures and so on
um some of my patients are gluten-free
dairy-free sugar-free
and some are
the exact opposite and come in my office
with the ring of cheetos around their
mouth and i try not to look
because that's not even real food but um
[Music]
i always tell parents to try dietary i
always encourage it
just give it three months of gluten free
it's a lot easier to do gluten-free now
than it ever was because there's so many
gluten-free options even here there's
gluten free and you go out to dinner
they mark on the you know on a
menu
but many people are reluctant to do it
and i think part of that is they don't
want to do gluten-free and they don't
want to have to prepare a meal for their
child
that is special and then everybody else
is eating something different oh no that
won't work yeah that won't work either
so it's a challenge it's a great
question um
and some people do it hardcore and other
people when i mention it just say that's
last resort so do you find that the ones
that are doing it get better results
it's a good question i would say that
the ones that stick to it are sticking
to it for a reason because they see
and remember too that once your child's
old enough you don't have control over
what they eat right they go to a
birthday party or they go to a
you know they're in high school yeah um
and so again that so it's a very hard
thing um more so in the pediatric uh
autism i'm sorry epilepsy group is the
ketogenic diet yeah yeah but that is a
parents will do that at all costs
because when you live with intractable
seizures if just changing tweaking the
diet
and you have usually for ketogenic diet
they have a dietitian as part of their
neurology appointment and they just get
so much assistance for that
i i don't see as many parents seeking
that kind of nutritional assistance um
with children with autism although you
could i'm sure that you could see a a
nutritionist or a dietitian to help you
with that but this is a great question i
think it's a whole picture right you
know how for autism one of their um
their little logo is the puzzle piece
yeah that's what it is yeah cannabis is
just another puzzle piece and so is the
diet cool thank you thank you
any other questions
thank you very much everybody