well it's an honor to be here
um I'm humbled by holding the position
that's previously uh been taken by
Rafael mashulum I hope that you're all
there last night to appreciate the
testimonial
so
um I have an interesting task I hope you
bear with me for the next 30 minutes
as I critique the Cannabis industry and
offer some not so humble remedies
so here we have Miss America 1980
um
benefiting from virtual plastic surgery
but faded pulchritude does not equate to
competence in a new industry which is
very complex
would you buy a cannabidiol from this
man
this guy stole my suit you can tell me
you can tell me later who wore it better
foreign
we're in the unfortunate situation of uh
not having our pronouncements taken with
any uh credulity by the people who make
the decisions and this is always going
to be the problem when politicians are
tasked with trying to make sense of
complex scientific principles and so
we're always going to be behind the
curve
as decisions are being made
we have a situation now of an industry
that's trying to make do
despite these obstacles of politicians
continued opposition from law
enforcement
um the legal industry can be Pro or con
you need to seek out the ones that are
going to be a help rather than any
hindrance
the states who have legalized are
grabbing more than their share and that
for example has strangled the industry
in California as we'll see
and we have a situation now where the
FDA had the opportunity to say something
useful about cannabidil and others and
it totally passed the proverbial buck
meanwhile the people who have spent
decades learning how to grow this plant
medicinally have suffered and we have
the situation now in Mendocino County
where nine out of 10 farmers are
unlicensed
um and many of the ones who are licensed
have gone out of business so this has
led to an exodus from the industry uh I
can tell you that personally it took us
seven tries to get a bank that would
take our business account
we have a cash only economy that puts
Bud tenders and other people at risk of
of robbery or murder
we also have a lot of unscrupulous
people in the industry that don't pay
their bills
um and this just leads to endless
rip-offs and inability to get insurance
again prohibitive tax structure and a
situation where there are no margins in
this industry so that very few people
are actually making money
and then they're the promises that
people make
in general timelines are rarely met
um and uh people need cash on the
barrelhead rather than stock options
which rarely come to pass
also there's a problem with diversity in
the industry so here we have the rare
black farmer
and there's still this
the commodity of which we speak is still
federally illegal irrespective of state
laws
so that's as much railing as I'm going
to do how about Solutions well this is a
scene we'd like to see more of acres and
Acres as far as the I can see of a
beautiful crop and an aromatic one
but a lot of the acreage has been taken
up with cannabidiol now nobody will say
more than me that this is a remarkable
and versatile compound but it has severe
limitations as an isolate very high
dosages are needed
it does not work as well on its own and
um with the high cost access becomes a
very difficult problem for patients
and we have a situation now that uh CBD
has been commoditized no one can come
into the market and be preeminent or
even successful it doesn't matter how
talented you were in another industry
also we've had the situation where the
farm bill has been co-opted so that a
lot of the CBD which has been a glut on
the market has been turned into Delta
eight
um and other synthetic cannabinoids that
have no place in in human health
application and can be outright
dangerous and again I follow the
politicians for not having the foresight
to understand this and do something
about it proactively
I think that the future really lies in
diversity diversification
uh to different cannabinoids and these
can all be attained with conventional
breeding I'm going to take the position
that we don't need biosynthetics
um there are
chemovars of cannabis that are available
through standard breeding that provide
very cheap sources for these uh
different phytochemicals that can be
commoditized as well
so really people need to do something
different and that's what I like to say
sometimes you need to zag instead of Zig
so here uh from a paper from a few years
ago I did with jaehan Marco
these are 12 of the phytocannabinoids
about which we know some degree of their
pharmacology
but that ignores at least
138 other ones
um but every phytocannabinoid that's
been discovered so far has some unique
therapeutic properties so we really
have not yet
fully assess the potential of this plant
so we're going to talk about a couple of
possibilities the first is
tetrahydrocannabiferin or thcv
this was discovered by my friend Roger
pertwy in 1970. now how Charmed the
position was this this was his first
publication and it was in nature
as old as I am I've never had a
publication in nature at that time they
were they thought there were six
pharmacologically Active Components of
cannabis
um they discovered this one thcv which
has a three carbon propyl side chain
instead of the Pentel five carbon side
chain
um this was from uh tincture of cannabis
that had been grown in Pakistan
um they showed that it was active in
mice but less potent than THC but that
was more than 50 years ago we've learned
something since but basically this was
on the Shelf with no attention for more
than 30 years
so this is the normal pathway a journal
pyrophosphate combining with olivitalic
acid to produce the the five carbon side
chain uh cannabinoids
alternatively thcv is made by this
pathway so General pyrophosphate was
which is the parent compound to the
cannabinoids as well as the terpenoids
in cannabis combines with divernic acid
to produce can cannabidiarolic acid and
onward to the others
um just to summarize the activity
um again this was discovered in
Pakistani cannabis
in the first paper
um they noted that CB1 was an antagonist
at I'm sorry
um that thcv is an antagonist at the CB1
receptor at low doses but a couple of
years later they figured out that it was
an Agonist at high doses so this is a
nice demonstration of the biphasic dose
response curves of many of the
cannabinoids different effects at
different Doses and that can be
leveraged in in various ways or it can
be a problem with side effects
um in various animal work uh it was
shown that this produces weight loss
decreased body fat and serum leptin
concentrations with increased energy
expenditure in mice that are genetically
prone to obesity it was also shown to
have anticonvulsive properties as do
many components of cannabis it also
treated neuropathic pain decreasing
swelling and and over uh overly
sensitive responses to pain
um our friend uh John mcpartland in 2015
showed that this lacks the side effect
profile of the prior drugs that were
used in this fashion the inverse
agonists Ramona band which was briefly
on the European market never made it to
the U.S market because of disastrous
side effects it actually lowers
endocannabinoid tone so yeah people lost
weight but they were depressed they were
anxious they had the lower seizure
threshold and a couple developed Ms who
hadn't had it before
now despite this not being freely
available there are thcv cultivars
um as long ago as 15 years ago
thcv predominant plants have been
developed again this hasn't had the
attention by breeders that it deserves
let's compare this to cannabidiol so
these both can attenuate THC sequelae
reducing side effect prototype profile
but again tcv is what's known as a
neutral antagonist at the CB1 receptor
whereas CBD is a negative allosteric
modulator it it lodges on a different
component of the receptor and makes it a
little harder for THC to bind
they both affect trip channels
particularly uh trip V1
but thcv is much more potent which
medically only means that you need fewer
milligrams as compared to CBD for it to
be active
both of these
phytocannabinoids can be used to treat
pain inflammation and epilepsy and both
have shown been shown in the animal work
and anecdotally in humans to help treat
addiction to other substances
uh it Remains the case that it's very
hard to remove THC entirely from
cannabidiol Plants because the cbda
synthase makes THC in a small amount
with thcv it may be possible to get it
to the point that it's considered hemp
under the farm bill rules
tcv
should be a useful and adjunct to THC
chemovars because it can complement the
therapeutic properties and reduce side
effects thereby increasing the
therapeutic index of THC in other words
the difference between the dose that's
effective in treating symptoms and that
which produces side effects
what do I see as the future here well
thcv has a variety of properties that
make it potentially very useful in
treating type 2 diabetes obesity the
metabolic syndrome things that are an
Affliction of the affluence of Western
culture also treating addiction and
there is one report indicating the
likelihood of benefit Parkinson's
disease
so all of these areas require better
safer products
because it is such a safe compound and
so versatile I think it's something that
we should be adding to cannabis-based
preparations
um this doohickey if you want to put
your camera on it will give you access
um to this page in more detail and less
blurry
this is a cultivar called pink boost
goddess available through Breeder's best
I'm the medical director of that company
as a disclaimer on if you can see
carefully this is about a one-to-one
with good titers of both THC and thcv
um people have used this this cultivar
um like it very much and find it very
easy to handle and and beneficial for a
variety of conditions
the next one we're going to talk about
that I think is the next big thing as
canaba gerol or CBG
what I like to call the mother of all
cannabinoids
now people are well aware that professor
michulum in the middle uh discovered the
the true structure and synthesized THC
in 1964 but with his
um research partner uh yahil gayangi
both pictured here in 2010 one of my
proudest moments
in 1964 they also discovered CBG and I I
want you to understand how prescient
they were so they extracted this from
Lebanese hashish that had been seized on
they put it through this process and
figured out the following quote
Canaveral represents the primary product
and The Missing Link in the formation of
cannabis constituents conversion into
cannabidiol tetrah drug cannabinol and
cannabinol is biogenetically plausible
exactly right cannabinol of course is an
oxidative breakdown product of THC but
to me this is amazing with the
technology that was available
essentially 60 years ago
um this is from a study that uh we
published a couple of years ago and it
was actually the first study in humans
of the effects of CBG therapeutic that
was published
um so we had 127 patients who said we
asked that they only participate if they
had used material that was at least 50
percent CBG
um and again the biosynthetic pathway of
cannabidural uh basically from
cannabidiarolic Acid under heater light
producing decarboxylation you get
cannabidural that's a photo of a CBG
only chemovar that may surprise you to
know that this was available like 15
years ago
why are we not seeing it in Commerce
universally
in our survey we saw this long list of
some 30 conditions that people had that
they used CBG to treat
um over half the people were using it
medicinally only 6.3 percent thought uh
we're just using it recreationally but
uh you know the vast majority we're
using it to treat something
as you might expect the most common
conditions for anxiety pain depression
and insomnia which is basically the
profile of of many
cannabis using patients
now the thing that surprised us with the
degree of efficacy and if we look at the
big ones you see p-values of .001
for many of these conditions depression
anxiety and pain
what that means for people who aren't
familiar it means there's only one
chance in a thousand that the results
were due to chance that's pretty
convincing and again these are only
self-reports it's not a double-blind
randomized controlled trial however
this is real
and for the other conditions we see that
the vast majority were improved were
much improved or very much improved
um although there were only a few
patients with each we saw big signals
for endometriosis with two-thirds noting
very high efficacy also for inflammatory
bowel diseases and irritable bowel
syndrome
and no one thought that conventional
medicine in these instances was better
than the CBG preparation that they were
taking
now some people reported side effects
but they were ones that were obviously
attributable to THC in people that were
using a mixed preparation and you know
they were dry mouth red eyes uh sedation
these were not seen among the people who
were using CBG only products so our
conclusions were
um first of all this is becoming more
popular particularly in the Pacific
Northwest where I live
um again this is the first study in
humans anxiety pain depression and
insomnia were the most common symptoms
and efficacy was very high with very
very few reported side effects
um it was interesting the reports of
benefit and inflammatory bowel disease
are supported by animal work
and apparently this seems to be mediated
through both the CB1 and the pipar gamma
receptor which is a nuclear receptor
that affects Gene transcription
um we felt that this provided a good
foundation for the safety of CBG for
future randomized controlled trials so
no one at the FDA can say well nobody's
ever taken it so
um you need 10 years of development to
show that it's safe
um comparing CBG to CBD again both may
be used to treat pain anxiety and need
sleep
CBD on its own does not treat sleep
except perhaps at extreme doses at lower
doses it's actually stimulating again
both affect trip channels both have
antibiotic properties and both are
cytotoxic for cancer cells without being
destructive of normal cells
in both
inhibit
fatty acid Amino hydrolase so the enzyme
that breaks down in neandamides so they
may increase
cannabinoid endocannabinoid tone again
cannabigirol is much more potent in CBD
if we're talking about isolates 10
milligrams of CBG is an effective dose
for anxiety whereas it might take 200
milligrams or more of CBD as an isolate
and there are CBG only cannabis scheme
of ours that are available as we'll see
um issues of CBG and THC
at this point I feel the cannabigirol is
a useful adjunct to almost all THC
chemovars again because of synergy and
providing benefit on pain sleep mood Etc
um particularly the anti-anxiety effects
May really notably increase the
therapeutic index of THC
economic prospects well I like to say
that what the world's needs now
particularly in the pandemic year as a
safe non-sedating non-addictive agent
for anxiety and CBG seems to be it
because it's so safe and versatile I
think it should be a most uh
combinations
formulations and this is the way we're
doing our formulation
uh I think that it's an impressive
impressive agent for treatment of
primary cancer especially the prostate
um
because it affects uh trip M8 receptor
which is a key marker in prostate cancer
also CBG has very prominent antibiotic
effects
particularly against gram positives but
there are ways now to make it affect
gram negatives but it really shines in
treatment of methicillin resistance
staph aureus and Vancomycin resistant I
I'm sorry yeah Vancomycin resistant
enterococcus again disclaimer
I'm the chief medical officer for
anterior Pharmaceuticals which is
working in both of these areas
here is a CBG only chemovar called
anomaly again available if you scan the
doohickey and if you can see the fine
print you'll see that basically all the
cannabinoid content is is CBG again
there was no genetic modification here
this is just good mendelian breeding
um right
um
another problem in the industry is
extraction and there were a lot of
questions in the session I was in
yesterday about how do we best extract
to
save the key ingredients
well with my colleague Jeremy Plum who's
in the audience somewhere
we did this study a couple of years ago
a process that that we call cryo-kef
which was just trademarked
um so the idea behind this was whether
really necessary or not it's become
traditional for all cannabis for use has
been dried and cured well it's been
known for ages that when you do that you
may lose as much as 50 percent of the
mono terpenoid content if you believe in
the Entourage effect as I do following
the dictates of Professor micholum then
you need that stuff and a chimpy
squandered if you're not going to be
smoking or vaporizing the material
so
the process that we went through uh that
we call cryokief involved
exposing freshly cut cannabis
immediately through a whole cold chain
and exposing it to dry ice vapor for up
to 48 Hours
the idea of being of fixing the
trichomes making them brittle so that
they'll fall off properly also
decreasing some of the water content
then we went through a sifting process
using this pollinator machine a very
simple device you know I think that this
can be done
um in a much more sophisticated fashion
we wanted the biggest trichomes which
are 150 microns in size
um and these are collected as kief the
Moroccan name for hashish
if you wanted to call it something else
you could call it an enriched trichrome
preparation term coined by David Potter
um I'm just going to provide one example
we did six different chemovars and
chemovars will vary in how tightly they
hold on to their trichomes so this may
be a process that's better for uh
material that say might have had Afghan
genetics where uh in that culture uh
it's a traditional to
um sift cannabis to produce hashish
now if you look carefully at the uh bars
and the table you'll see that we started
off with a cannabinoid total of 11.5
percent which is almost all thca
and that was vastly increased by this
process to 58.5
of the total weight
um now the we in other team of ours we
were able to show again concentration of
of CBD or even CBG through this process
we did comparisons with material that
was dried
previously and subjected to the same
process
um and the yields were not as great at
all
with the terpenoids we went from a terp
total of 1.38 a little bit low but that
doubled to 2.87 and you'll see with each
of the component the components that the
the
um the gray the cryo Keith uh was was
higher
um than for all the other processes and
this
article is available free online if you
go to
ethanrusso.org at the library tab you
can see the full details of this
now more importantly a graphic
presentation on the left we have the
cryo Keith on the right the more
traditional approach to dried Kief and I
think you'll agree that these look
considerably different
in the dried Keith there's a lot of
particulate matter from the plant that
is not something you necessarily want in
your lungs and certainly isn't necessary
to the medicinal effects
ultimately we got a yield that would be
comparable to what's done with water
hash uh but without all the water
um and again we were using relatively
crude techniques as a proof of concept
and I think that this can be uh yet
refined
so what we were able to show
um was that quietkeep isolated the
trichomes and highly concentrated both
the cannabinoids and terpenoid
components we think that this would be a
very uh good product on two levels one
would be for the Cannabis connoisseur
that instead of
um uh
and isolate with uh
butane or some other solvent would be
clean
it would also offer the ability to have
very good quality acid cannabinoids
um which if wanted could be secondarily
decarboxylated but particularly with
preservation of the full complement of
monoterpenoids and this could be subject
to secondary processing of various types
um interestingly the material that's
left after the cryo Creek keep process
still had plenty of of activity itself
and that could be solvent extracted or
CO2 extracted so really this is
producing a value-added product
um and yet
um
not leaving waste that it just needs to
be composted for example
um
again this offers the ability to combine
acid and neutral cannabinoids for
whatever kind of therapeutic purposes
now I want to talk a little bit again
disclaimer this material comes from a
breeders best headed by Dale Hunt
I am the medical director of that
company
um this is what he's called the new
cannabinoid Discovery program the idea
being to gain the ability to isolate
novel cannabinoids for future
generations to carry on After I'm Gone
uh this is a technique that uses
receptors to identify the compounds and
without exaggeration this is a million
times more sensitive than standard
techniques
and instrumentation so whereas the
latter
gets things down to the Nano molar level
this is the femtomolar level or 10 to
the minus 15th
the idea being to gain the ability to
identify rare cannabinoids
that may refine to cannabinoid and other
receptors because not all
phytocannabinoids work through that
mechanism
um and the idea would be to screen
reader submissions for this
um this is an animation I'm just going
to go through quickly if you look at the
economics
THC uh is expected to earn 7 73.6
billion dollars by 2027
with CBD uh 9.7 billion by 2025 there
are about 10 others that have increasing
demand as we've discussed and then over
a hundred of others that we have yet to
explore
a lot of these are near or below
detection limits with standard
instrumentation uh they may come from
rare genetics
the mindset has been really occupied
with just CBD and 2E THC to the
exclusion of others with breeders best
the ideas to uh to license and provide
intellectual property protection for
Unique team of ours on help them get
developed
um
and this is a way to again to screen for
the future of Commerce so it all starts
with the cannabis plant
um after a research license uh various
tissues from the plant Not Just Flowers
um there's potential for the roots and
other parts of the plant so this can be
sampled and acid maybe we find a novel
cannabinoid and then it's possible to
selectively breed to increase its
concentration
producing progeny which can be
subsequently studied and go through the
process again until you get it to the
point where it's economically viable
so purification
studying its effects and eventually
getting it to humans for new products
and medicine and even producing new
Industries
and hopefully producing a better quality
of life for patients and their families
and with commercial opportunities
foreign
and I wanted to close with some
discussion of formulation
it is very important to know for anybody
who's interested in pharmaceutical
development of cannabinoids that there
are certain roles and that is to produce
a Botanical it all has to be from one
species
so it is not a place where you could
could combine phytocannab or
cannabinoids from two different
biosynthetic sources and put them
together without going through programs
identifying the toxicity and therapeutic
effects of each and that that's not uh a
good path towards approval
so it's also true in New York state that
any the Cannabis products need to be
cannabis derived so that would mean that
you wouldn't be combining uh
cannabinoids with linole from lavender
for example
so the path ahead for True Botanicals is
by using all these components from
cannabis itself but it doesn't need to
be from the same plant I would point out
that satavex is actually a combination
of two different chemovars one Ranch in
THC one rich in cannabidiol and these
are combined and that's been accepted as
a unitary formulation by Regulators in
30 different countries
um
so really I think one of the best paths
ahead is creative combinations of
phytocannabinoids and terpenoids and
flavonoids as we'll hear more about
later that can be optimized for any
particular clinical indication and this
is exactly the approach that we're using
a credoscience in our formulation now
so selective mendelian breeding without
genetic modification
and the new cannabinoid Discovery
program would be the suppliers of the
components or approaches like these
um
it is essential as we've heard yesterday
in some of the sessions uh the industry
requires good manufacturing practice
standards and the availability of active
pharmaceutical ingredients
um so the company that is first able to
supply API quality phytocannabinoids and
terpenoids derived from Cannabis is
going to be in the proverbial driver's
seat for uh future Commerce in this area
so
um I hope that a few oxes were oxen were
gourd in this but hopefully not fatally
and with that I'm surprised but it looks
like we may have a few minutes for
questions so thank you
Bonnie
sure so tcv again is a neutral
antagonist that's a way at low doses
that's a way of saying it takes up space
on the receptor but it'd be different
than CBD which isn't actually just
making it a little harder to bind by
changing the confirmation so it's a
technical difference
um in this instance I guess you'd say
the thcv is taking up space that THC
would normally want now you might think
from that that it's going to really
reduce the clinical efficacy of the THC
but that's not what we see clinically
because there are a lot of people using
these mixed chemovars that have both and
boy they're usually very happy with how
it makes them feel or treating whatever
their condition is
please
thank you thank you sorry that what
delivery system for thcv has the most
efficacy whether it's sublingual edible
you know that type of thing
boyet that's hard to say I mean there
really are not a lot of commercial
products
um yet available with thcv you know
they're always going to be issues of
bioavailability if someone's taking it
orally or advice would be that
cannabinoids are better absorbed with
food certainly with concomitant fats but
again these materials can often have a
certain degree of absorption or a
mucosally sublingually
um
yeah topically I don't know about thcv
topically but in general the
cannabinoids are great on the skin
they're not absorbs the stem
systemically at this point very
effectively at all
um so there we need more work if you are
experimenting in this area it would
really encourage you to let people know
what you think works
brick and mortar basis two milligrams of
thcv isolate in a dark chocolate is
amazing for Focus I have nursing
students that take it instead of their
Adderall
I'm sorry 20 milligrams thcv
for Focus two milligrams to five
milligrams of isolate for not weight
loss but appetite suppression and it
totally works no no that's nice
very good next
High Ethan over here
thank you for the talk that was
wonderful I'm curious to hear what you
think the priorities are for human
clinical research both observational and
experimental
well big topic that'd be the next hour
well you know I've always said um I
think the priority areas that haven't
had the attention they deserve or
Obstetrics and Gynecology which has been
a forbidden area
um for far too long on the other area of
Psychiatry broadly and you know again I
think that just based on the numbers at
the top of the list anxiety treatment we
can do so much better than the current
uh dangerous and addictive anti-anxiety
agents so those those are the ones I'd
highlight
thank you you bet
nice presentation and do you think that
CBG may be useful to a Gad
to to trade which a g a g
and E productivity and
ADHD sure thank you
um yeah I mean I think it may be that
wasn't one of the listed ones among the
127 patients that we had but certainly
anxiety is a big component of ADHD for
many children and adults with residual
adhds so I think that there's a good
likelihood
um you know we know that THC and low
doses Works while CBD can have a role so
I I couldn't tell you what the the ideal
combination would be but I think it's a
good bet that CBG would be a useful
component
oh
hi there I was just wondering if you've
done any work or your thoughts on the
cannabinoid Quinones and their
therapeutic values for targeted ailments
I'm sorry I missed a word the
cannabinoid Queen owns Quinones
uh
it's a difficult topic for me there I
have a history with this in general the
Quinones
um is a chemical group
um have certain toxicities I I'd be
really hesitant go there
um Again part of this is my bias I think
that the the cannabinoids as the plant
produces them are plenty adequate and
I'm not a fan of semi-synthetics at this
point which invariably are going to be
isolets and could not possibly have the
broad range of therapeutic effects that
uh properly constituted uh cannabis
extract would have so that's my bias
thank you
foreign
thank you so much Dr Russo it's great
presentation and I learned a lot
um in a general question how do you
recommend as an expert to speak to other
physician practitioners and providers on
the use of medical cannabis when they're
resistant to want to hear about it who
walk out of the room you know obviously
those who how do you get caught across
to them that this is not a recreational
drug that everybody our patients are
just getting high which is a lot of
doctors are and practitioners think is
happening yeah well it's difficult I've
been doing this for 27 years and we've
only made incremental improvements
unfortunately on with politicians
the sad fact is until they or a family
member is has got cancer and needs
cannabis they're rarely going to become
convinced and this is just the story you
see repeatedly or if you have very
sympathetic patients that are able to
connect with a politician one-on-one and
bring them on board so it takes
tremendous lobbying effort so anyway it
sounds like you're involved in that and
I just encourage you to persist
I'll try and steal the last question
over here I'm very curious about these
Femme to molar sensitivity scanning
tools you have Ethan can they also find
uh or or explore the tryptamine space we
have in the leaves there was some
wonderful paper last year about
cyanurenic acid in the leaves yeah I
mean the this technology was borrowed uh
from other areas so this receptor
approach to analysis
um as could be applied to cannabinoids
or anything else on and maybe it's the
future of uh exploration for Trace
components in a variety of medicinal
plants
I want to have a question about your
opinion about covid-19 and cannabis
because I have some discussion with
mushroom and they take me some idea and
in my practice I see Morocco yeah you
have no covid wouldn't have okay I
haven't fixed it out
um I think both Bonnie and Dustin can
give much better answers on this but you
know
um
you may hear
um of certain cannabis components that
will help prevent uh binding of the
virus
um to the receptor so that's one aspect
and then
um in terms of long covid there again
may be a role but I think we should
um I'll confine my answer to that
um there are people that that are in the
trenches and and have much more
experience with this I think there's a
role but I could not Define it for you
at this point
so I think that's our time thank you
again for your attention