hello thank you for coming
hope we are ready to go
i'm seth crawford my brother and i
co-founded oregon cbd in 2015
where oregon's oldest continually
operating hemp farm in the nation's
leading supplier feminized cannabis seed
when i was here last in 2018 i delivered
a presentation about the promise and
potential of developing non-thc
varieties grown as hemp this work can be
seen as an extension of the
well-documented breeding program
published by etienne de meyer at gw
pharmaceuticals which is itself the
culmination of work started at hortafarm
in the netherlands by dave watson and
rob clark in the 1990s
our intent was not to just develop
clones with novel chemotypes like
hortifarm did rather the goal was to
produce field-ready f-1 versions that
would allow farmers to maximize their
yields in a way that brought these
cannabinoids into the mainstream
we set out to accomplish that task by
applying classical plant breeding
strategies to cannabis
isolating individuals and
self-pollinating through multiple inbred
generations in hopes of attaining higher
excuse me higher rates of homozygosity
fixing chemical composition enabling
uniform flowering responses in our
hybrids
and attempting to maximize heterosis
through careful selection of final
parents
we've been engaged in the project for
about eight years now and can report
that the first phase is complete we have
cbd cbdv cbg and cbgv parental stock of
inbred photo period and day neutral
lines developed for hybrid f1 seed
production
the results of this approach have
yielded commercial varieties that set
the benchmark for both field
productivity and total cannabinoid
content in university field trials
across the country
concurrently they've ushered in a new
era where non-psychoactive trim flowers
can actually compete on par with their
thc counterparts
for consumer attention
farmers have received over 40 different
awards with our varieties around the us
including a really cool landmark win at
the cultivation classic in 2020 by horn
creek hemp taking the blind tasting
flagship category of most credible
cultivar with our cbd dominant sour
space candy this beat out a field
dominated by thc specimens because of
its consistently relaxing and positive
effect
[Music]
we're a small r d operation with an
oversized influence on the hemp market
in large part due to our attention to
detail in the breeding process and our
desire to collaborate with other
scientists to better our collective
understanding of this incredible plan
we've built out facilities that include
over 275 000 square feet of next
generation indoor greenhouse space 600
isolation tents for controlled crosses a
tissue culture employee manipulation lab
whole genome sequencing and molecular
lab capabilities and full chemical
analysis at our little 49-acre farm in
independence oregon
we've basically been lucky enough to
build a professional life that the
20-year-old version
of ourselves couldn't have dreamed up
and we're tremendously thankful to have
been born in the right place at the
right time who knew that a couple kids
raised in an electricity-less log cabin
in the woods of southern oregon would
get such an amazing opportunity so big
thanks to mom and dad
i'd also like to thank the entire canmed
event team for hosting what is to me the
most outstanding cannabis conference in
the country and thank all of you for
taking the time to listen today many of
the best and brightest minds in the
cannabis space are here and we're all
very lucky to get first-hand first-hand
accounts of the work being accomplished
right now i'd also like to thank
everybody on our whole team at oregon
cbd past present and future for their
contributions to the work that's going
to be discussed today and say thanks to
all of our collaborators over the past
few years there's too many to mention
right now but they're going to be
acknowledged throughout this
presentation
so the title of today's talk is phrased
as a question 2022 the golden year of
cannabis
full disclosure it had been 2020
the golden year of cannabis uh and then
a couple years of epidemiological
history got in our way
um i want to address the question at the
outset so everybody's able to
concentrate on the rest of the talk
yes this is the golden year
last year was two and the year before
that and next year probably be as well
um
it can be true regardless of your world
view whether the glass is truly half
full or totally empty as long as we can
grow for another season and build on
what we collectively learned last year
it's always going to be the golden year
all dialectical meanderings aside we do
stand at an absolutely sublime moment in
time for cannabis research in no small
part due to the rise of hemp in the u.s
the general framework for today includes
a brief overview of that program a more
in-depth dive into the use of ploidy
manipulation as a breeding tool with
triploids as the primary example and
finally we'll finish up with some
thoughts about the next phases double
entendre there on purpose genomics and
plants that will push our industry
forward it's going to be ample time at
the end for both public questions uh and
we do have a break conveniently
scheduled afterwards so it doesn't get
addressed in the public comment section
please come find me at the end i'm happy
to answer anything
the u.s hemp timeline so industrial hemp
was federally legalized in the u.s via
the 2014 farm bill passed in december of
that year with a maximum allowable thc
limit of 0.3
or less
with the late passage many states took a
number of months to adopt conforming
policies and start issuing licenses to
growers making 2016 the first production
year in any meaningful sense
a strange patchwork of state enforced
rules were the name of the game from
then until this year which is the first
to be conducted under final usda rules
these gray
gray market area years led to variable
sampling methodologies compliance test
timing and reporting requirements across
the country with significant confusion
amongst regulators and farmers alike
occasionally leading to whole crop
destruction when plants tested over the
thc threshold
as has been established by many this thc
limited
thc limit is demonstrably arbitrary and
not grounded in science but that's what
we have to work with until congress
updates the rules
the biggest watershed moment on this
timeline occurs at the end of 2018 with
passage of the most recent farm bill
which did away with the research pilot
aspect of the original law and placed
fully legalized temp production in the
u.s under the jurisdiction of the usda
moving forward
usda issued an interim final rule for
producers on halloween of 2019 was
definitely a scare proposed that
sampling occur within six days of
harvest and be taken from the top two
inches of terminal flowers so basically
no economically valuable cbd varieties
that were being grown in the us at that
time would pass testing the public
comment period was intense farmers were
pissed and luckily this time around we
had some help from universities studying
the crop for the first time
after reviewing public feedback and
coordinating with other affected federal
agencies usda concretized the final
final rules on january 19 2021.
these require that all states with hemp
programs submit a control plan for usda
approval which most have completed at
this point would-be producers in states
without formal programs are able to
apply for a license directly from the
usda
the final rules made compliance sampling
much more uniform nationally with a
28-day pre-harvest when uh window
instituted
in a sampling protocol that calls for
the top five to eight inches of of the
main female cola while some variability
still exists from state to state and
from sampler to sampler
it's been tamped down substantially
through this harmonization
in a parallel effort the national
institutes for standards and testing
started a voluntary program for cannabis
testing labs in may of 2019 called the
canna qap or cannabis quality assurance
program
the goal of this program is to establish
uniformity in analytical measurement
through distributed testing of material
with known cannabinoid profiles and
publicly releasing the results
taken together it's clear to see that
federal agencies are preparing for
national legalization and hemp is
serving as the test case
from 2020 on
a number of previously unavailable
cannabinoids entered the marketplace so
delta 8 thc delta 10 thc thco
hydrogenated cannabinoids if you can
name it enterprising chemists with
varying levels of skill and equipment
we're making it out of hemp derived
precursors while there's been
significant consternation about the
safety of these products largely due to
residual residual contaminants and
unknown compounds being generated in the
conversion process
movements by individual states to rein
in potentially intoxicating hemp
derivatives
uh have really been met by a lot of
permissiveness by the federal uh with
the federal response the last note on
this timeline directly addresses these
new compounds and essentially any other
product made from cannabis grown as hemp
on january 6th of this year the dea sent
a policy determination letter to a hemp
product manufacturer that clearly stated
the agency does not have enforcement
authority over hemp in any way delta 8
thc derived
including delta 8 thc derived from the
isomerization of cbd
so this obviously has significant
implications
production of hemp over this same period
of time underwent a absolutely meteoric
ascent peaking in the summer of 2019
following passage of the new farm bill
overproduction ensued prices plummeted
and in action by the fda created a
cacophony of doubt amongst established
product manufacturers over the future of
hemp-derived cannabinoids
the initial rapid expansion in
production was met with an equally
precipitous decline in total acres
registered and farmgate prices to the
point where it's not economical to grow
for most farmers
biomass prices so this is the floral
material destined for extraction
bottomed out around 50 cents per pound
earlier this year and are slowly
creeping up as the tremendous glut of
material finally starts to dissipate
the trimmed hemp flower market is still
holding on but is a very small
proportion of the total acres planted
each year
registered acres as you can see
in 2022 are currently estimated to be
slightly more than 2017
but still quite a bit less than 2018.
the few farmers who have held on over
the last three years are desperately
hoping for a solid price rebound but at
this point who really knows what's going
to transpire
if anything the tendency of boom and
bust cycles with recently opened
cannabis markets is a stark reminder
that efficiency marketability and
novelty are all mandatory for growers to
simply stay in business
the silver lining here despite the
market collapse is that hemp viewed as a
vehicle for research has absolutely
exploded during this production collapse
as universities join industry and their
ability to handle the plant in a
relatively uninhibited way
a key regulatory scientific and
practical farming question has been
where does residual thc come from in
type 3 and type 4 plants
the question was of critical importance
while the usda was proposing rules for
the hemp industries their initial
versions would have essentially ended
cbd production and we believe in this
case that some good science actually
affected national policy for once
uh no free and co-authors gave us some
tantalizing clues in their 2015 survey
of gw pharmaceuticals diverse germplasm
library
demonstrating a relationship between
cannabinoid synthase variation in
quantitative chemotype in essence
certain single-letter nucleotide changes
in the genes responsible for cbd-a and
thca production lead to different
cannabinoid purities ranging from 66 to
90 percent in the case of cbda in type 3
plants leaving up to 10 percent of the
total cannabinoid fraction as other
compounds even in the purest cbd
producers
zurple's 2018 paper demonstrates that
cbd as the gene responsible for cbd
production
in vitro produces
cbd a thca cbca and five other unknown
compounds in ratios affected by
substrate ph but reportedly normalized
to 20 to 1 1-1 for the known products
larry smart's lab at cornell
has done some great work over the past
three years cataloging and
characterizing commercially available
hemp varieties and getting great
graduate student publications in the
process
their work on time series cannabinoid
accumulation in field trials shows that
most type 3 germplasm grown in the u.s
tested about 25 to 1 cbd to thc
throughout its flowering period
taken together we now know that most thc
produced in these high cbd varieties is
coming from the gene responsible for
cbda production you can't have one
without the other but their co-presence
is predictable
during this time we spent a lot of
energy in these intervening years
developing varieties that would meet a
stringent 0.3
day of harvest limit since that was the
initial direction proposed by the usda
we were successful in doing so with cbg
dominant varieties as well as cbdv rich
varieties
our cbg varieties are made possible
through a synthase variant we found in
one of our inbred populations it's a
full length thcas with a single snip at
1064 base pairs responsible for
significant loss of function with final
flowers averaging 100 to 1 cbga to thca
ratios and always compliant when grown
as hem
our work with high varying content
varieties has shown that unlike their
pencil counterparts the cannabinoid
fraction undergoes dramatic changes over
the course of flowering the varying
proportion of total cannabinoids
decreases as flowers mature from a
compliance perspective this is a really
beneficial outcome since thcva is not
included in the 0.3 total thc harvest
limit in this example thc va is present
at levels three times higher than thca
at that critical 28-day pre-harvest
window but the two dropped to an equal
one-to-one ratio by the end of flowering
the shift in federal policy to a 28-day
pre-harvest test allows nearly all type
3 plants to test below the legal limit
if varieties are fully mature in eight
weeks even with high cannabinoid content
hemp and we believe that this is a good
compromise until congress can be
convinced to implement a one percent
total thc rule across the board
other recent research has significantly
contributed to our understanding of
specific traits and relative genomic
location
the grasa widebands team
grasso weiblen team's excellent
publication accompanying the cs10
reference genome release found total
cannabinoid potency markers present on
chromosomes 3 4 6 9 and the x chromosome
there have also been some really great
papers on terpene synthase pathways
recently with the allen booth and zagger
research
three independent papers really standing
out as the most useful these help us
place many of the mono and sesquiterpene
tps variants on chromosomes 1 5 and 6
with some dye terpenes on chromosomes 4
and 7.
the van velv van velzen paper on
cannabinoid oxido cyclase gene families
places the cbgas synthase on the x
chromosome as well
our team used lighthouse genomics snip
chip data from a segregating f2
population to co-publish with dewey
scientific and identify pm1 the first
powdery mildew resistance gene in
cannabis
and show that its location is on
chromosome 2.
our urofins snip chip validation run on
a different f2 population containing day
neutral individuals place the mechanisms
controlling that particular flowering
response on chromosome well
chromosome one as well
subsequent aluminum shotgun sequencing
of the same population by nrgene and
data analysis with our collaborators at
osu and the vining lab yielded markers
associated with elevated total propyl
cannabinoid fractions which we know from
other publications to be a polygenic
trait on chromosomes 3 4 5 7 8
and 9 with a single marker on chromosome
3 having the greatest impact
between the shifting policy landscape
and research developments cannabis
essential oil breeding programs are
quickly moving from an opaque guessing
game requiring multiple methods of
triangulation
to one where many traits can be
determined at the seedling stage with
targeted pcr tests and particular
crosses can be designed in a way that
maximizes successful outcomes while not
getting mired down in impossible dreams
this becomes even more important as we
consider that the frontier of production
of all cannabinoid plant types will most
likely be polyploid and much more
genetically complex than the diploids we
all know and love
so why triploids let's turn to triploids
triploids are cannabis plants that are
basically incredibly resistant to
pollination as well as have
exciting attributes brought on by extra
genome copies
our development of triploids was born
out of the trauma of losing several
crops to cross-pollination events in
2016 and 2018 and hearing horror stories
from growers year after year
if you've grown cannabis you likely
understand how devastating
pollen drift can be on crops and it can
travel hundreds of miles in the right
conditions
fully pollinated plants produce 50
percent less flower weight and 30
percent less cannabinoids a seeded crop
is essentially worthless if you're
growing for trim flowers and still
devastating if your end goal is biomass
and extraction
as we've also seen in the first seven
years of production in oregon feral
populations of cannabis are regularly
establishing themselves in fallow fields
and become a big enough concern that our
department of agriculture is now working
on rules and penalties for landowners
who fail to control rogue plants
in newly opened midwestern production
areas previous research has shown that
over a third of all airborne pollen
in the summertime in the month of august
is derived from feral hemp
having a plant that's relatively
incapable of being pollinated could fix
a lot of those issues and threats and
let farmers put their energy into
growing great crops instead of worrying
so to understand triploids we need to
establish some basic terminology and i
apologize
to anyone who this is uh easy for me it
is not it's been a long a long trip
chromosomes are packed together
collections of dna so dna is the
underlying genetic instructions for life
it's helpful to think of chromosomes as
books of code which make up the library
that is an organism
every species has a unique number of
books in its library humans have 46
naked mole rats have 60 and cannabis has
20 in the diploid state
this library
size is referred to as the chromosome
sat number
ploiety refers to the number of
homologous sets of chromosomes in an
organism
organisms with a single set are referred
to as haploid
two is diploid three sets triploid four
sets tetraploid so on and so forth
any organism with a ploidy higher than
two is referred to as a polyploid
in sexually reproducing species one half
of the chromosome sets are inherited
from each respective parent for humans
this means our individual genome is
actually a fusion of two different
genomes cut in half during reproduction
we're truly one half of both parents the
same is true for diploid plants
while most vertebrates are diploid many
many plants are polyploid these include
major agricultural crops of critical
importance to humans such as coffee
bananas strawberries bread wheat oats
citrus potatoes and tobacco to just name
a few
the main point to understand is that
polyploidization is a natural phenomenon
that has occurred many times in nature
and has led to the creation of the
ancestors of many modern crops
polyploid induction in nature tends to
correspond with extreme climate events
or natural disasters and lead to
increased diversity within a species
the only documented naturally occurring
tetraploid cannabis population was found
at 14 000 feet in elevation in the
himalayas by
an indian research effort about 10 years
ago
the extreme climate and altitude may
have been the causal agent responsible
for that particular event
we can think of this as nature's way of
creating options for diverse responses
under changing circumstances
it's also important to note that these
events are not changing the underlying
dna in any way or introducing new genes
they're simply whole genome duplications
of what was already present
in the case of polyploids more gene
copies is believed to confer better
adaptability and resilience
plant breeders became aware of the
remarkable superiority of polyploids in
the mid 20th century and have induced
polyploidy and or used natural
polyploids in many ways to obtain
increasingly improved plant cultivars
some of the most important consequences
of polyploidy for plant breeding are the
increased size of plant organs so bigger
flowers bigger leaves bigger stems the
buffering of deleterious mutations
increased heterozygosity and superior
heterosis or hybrid vigor
cultivars have been generated with
higher yields improved product quality
and increase tolerance to both biotic
and abiotic stresses
polyploidy is a tried and true method of
improvement in many crops
an important bonus to all this is that
plants with odd chromosome set numbers
so triploids pentaploids and so on often
prove to be infertile this is what makes
seedless watermelons bananas hops and
now cannabis a reality
[Music]
the only thing you need to know about
this is that the haploid cannabis genome
is 800 megabases in size we'll save some
time
our polyploid development program was
designed and led by dr shen chen osu
grad who's now an assistant professor at
nc state
um our goal was to convert our diploid
breeding stock these you know take three
to four years to develop on their own
but our goal was to convert these into
tetraploids and beyond
test the fertility of various ploidies
and controlled environments and to test
the agronomic traits of various ploities
via controlled crosses and initial field
trials
this work began in early 2019 and was
occurring simultaneously to the efforts
at canopy growth corporation and jessica
level brands lab at the university of
connecticut both of whom have recently
published papers describing their
processes and we did as well
i say this is a is a way of not so
subtly conveying some disapproval of the
most recent claim to emerge from a large
purveyor of clones here in california
who if you were at the emerald cup last
december you probably know what i'm
talking about just launched what they
purported to be the world's first
triploid cannabis
in a day and age so rife with
misinformation history will probably not
care one way or the other but for some
of us truth is more important than
marketing efforts and i i for one
believe it's important to acknowledge
the labor of others that led to
increased knowledge that benefits us all
on that note while our company was
actually the first to offer triple-a
cannabis commercially in 2021 the harder
farm group that i had previously
mentioned
led by dave watson
were likely the first to test triploids
back in the 1990s and i'd like to
publicly acknowledge that effort and his
encouragement of our program as we went
through the r d phase
so that aside let's get into the details
and our findings from the past three
years on cannabis polity research
controlled genome doubling events
require initial plants a cell division
inhibitor steady hands patients and a
flow cytometer which is a really cool
piece of equipment capable of measuring
an organism's cell size
hundreds of asexually propagated clones
of a target plant genotype are pruned
back until a single growth point remains
and then colchicine is applied to that
growth point
most plants die within a month
the few survivors are screened by flow
cytometry and any confirmed tetraploids
move on to the stabilization process
at each step plants are re-screened
repeatedly as they have a tendency to
revert to lower or mixed pleiades until
fixed a term i use lightly is diploid
reversion is always a possibility under
stressful conditions
if a plant has 10 shoots all 10 shoots
are tested this continues until that
relative stability is attained and then
the plants are ready for seed production
in our case but not before a final flow
testing
to date we've now successfully created
tetraploid versions of all of our
classic cbd cbg cbdv and cbgv production
mothers as well as a long list of type 1
plants in our germplasm library and have
incorporated the streamlined conversion
process into our breeding program start
to finish this process takes about eight
months it's not the breeding that leads
up to it but just the conversion process
is about eight months
if you guys have time everybody have
time we've got about a three minute
video clip
okay cool everybody's got time
this is brendan rojas he is our employee
lab manager and he's going to walk you
through
a very quick description of what it
looks like in the greenhouse in the lab
to actually convert and test these
plants
i'm going to go through the process for
converting plants the first step is
after we've gotten the plants is we'll
trim it down to just a single meristem
for this plant you can see it's right at
the top just right here this one single
meristem and after that what we'll do is
we'll take a piece of cotton and we'll
just wrap it right around that one
single meristem and then come in with
colchicine and add just a little bit of
colchicine to fully hydrate that cotton
swab
so after everything's been treated we
we need to keep the plants moist and
warm so that they have a good
environment to grow in to do that we use
a second one of these black trays and we
prop it up with cinder blocks and then
we use this plastic to wrap all the way
around to ensure that it
holds that humidity inside
once once everything's uh been treated
we do the treatments for
four days in a row at the end of the
fourth day we pull the cotton off and
then rinse the meristems with water so
that we rinse off any of that excess
colchicine and then after
after they've been treated
in about two weeks we'll start to see
growth from those points and with that
growth we'll take them up to the tissue
culture building to start running flow
on them and to check our results so at
this point i've gotten i've got a plant
that's been treated with colchicine uh
just one single meristem was treated and
then
what we have in front of us is a plant
that's grown up from that single stem
and what i'll do is i'll come in with a
pair of scissors
and i'll take just one leaf sample the
samples can range in size
we don't need a whole leaf i can use as
little as just
a leaf tip very small
we have two buffers that the sample goes
into
the first one's an extraction buffer
that just helps make sure that when
you're chopping the plant material the
nuclei in the plant material don't
break apart and the second one is a
fluorescent stain buffer
which dyes the
nuclei of the cells within the plant
material which makes it possible for our
flow cytometer to
actually read the
genetic material in the nuclei
so this is the extraction buffer
it goes into a petri dish
it gets chopped
[Applause]
the nuclei gets stained
we then run the plant material through a
filter
so we don't clog up our machine
[Applause]
goes
into the sample cell
and then
it should start running
so after the sample has been prepared
and we put it into the flow machine what
the flow cytometer actually does is it
it takes the liquid that we just
prepared and it runs it through a very
small cuvette in a single file line
where it lines up all the nuclei
in just one row and then it shoots a uv
light through the nucleus as it goes
through this one cuvette
so based off of how the uv light
reflects off of the nuclei that we just
prepared
that's how it gets the readout and we
get the results on a graph so it's kind
of like a relative peak of the genetic
material within the nuclei
awesome thank you brendan it's oregon
cannabis breeding duct tape zip ties and
now with laser beams
our lab's been operating with the two
quantum p flow cytometer units for the
past couple years we just recently added
a high-throughput cytoflex v2 with two
lasers which i'm told is great it's a
higher throughput allows us to use
standard 96 well plates to be able to
have a much much
larger number of plants get screened at
any given time
you can see in these images
the resulting peaks generated by that
flow cytometer when testing plant
material in various ploieties so fluid
cytometer results in the far left and
then some chromosome squash
pictures from pictures from microscope
in the middle there
using multiple methods to validate
ploidy levels is especially necessary
when creating bass lines for further
analysis but the chromosome pictures
here help to convey the cellular changes
present in these polyplates there's
really a lot more genetic information in
these plants and you can see it when you
get close enough
diploid cannabis plants contain about 60
000 genes and have a genome size of 1.6
gigabases
triploids contain about 90 000 genes and
have a genome size of 2.4 gigabases
tetraploids contain 120 000 genes and
have a genome size of 3.2 gigabases or
roughly half the size of humans
these extra gene copies are what is
believed to drive resilience and
adaptability in polyploids
[Music]
so seedlessness and triple-a cannabis
would be an awesome thing right but we
had to design some experiments that
would adequately test that claim
to do so we created six crossing
combinations to assess seed production
and viability diploid triploid and
tetraploid versions of the same f1
hybrid were pollinated by diploid and
tetrapoid pollen donors these trials
were conducted in sealed greenhouses and
the target plants were subjected to
massive amounts of pollen this was
intended to simulate a flower crop grown
side by side with a large grain farm or
dense feral populations
the results show that diploids
pollinated by diploids produce about two
times as many seeds as tetraploids
pollinated by tetraploids suggesting
that ploidy increases result in lower
fertility in cannabis
tetraploids are not viable as a pollen
donor for diploids but are able to
induce many problematically empty seeds
the key finding is that seed production
was essentially non-existent in
triploids when pollinated by either a
diploid or a tetraploid in this
experiment
even under substantial duress they
remain nearly seed free with a maximum
average of six seeds per triploid plant
when pollinated by diploids in the
controlled pollen inundation zone
in addition to significantly impeded
fertility triploids also demonstrated
superiority in many key agronomic traits
relative to their diploid counterparts
we conducted outdoor field trials at our
campus in 2020 with several different
diploid triploid and tetraploid crossing
combinations
flower production increased between 30
to 100 percent although that was variety
dependent with the largest leaves seen
in day neutral varieties
the yield differences are statistically
significant but the visual differences
in plant size larger leaves larger
flowers thicker stems denser trichome
coverage
tells you all you need to know about
triploid vigor
there's a slight increase in total
cannabinoid content in flowers and a
market increase
in
excuse me
in trichome density on sugar leaves near
flowers
additionally olfactory compounds were
noticeably more abundant in triploids
and tetraploids compared to diploids but
we did not test for total terpene
content in this study because terpenes
tell us less than half the story and
most of the major aroma components of
our varieties are not terpenes at all
there's more about that to come we don't
have enough time for the entire story
today but we'll get into it with a
little bit more detail later
these early results suggested
that triploids are much more resilient
to any challenges they face relative to
diploid counterparts
in 2021 we followed up with extended
field trials at north carolina state
university cornell and the university of
kentucky as part of our founding
membership of the far sponsored hemp
research consortium
the study designed at all three
institutions were very similar with
diploid and triploid versions of our
feminized varieties planted on four-foot
centers at two separate outdoor field
sites in each study one field was
designated as a negative pollen control
and the other was purposefully planted
at a high density with male female
diploid grain
grain varieties immediately adjacent to
the trial locations
final research reports from all three
institutions will be available on their
extension website soon but they were
kind enough to grant us some of the
preliminary data for today
in north carolina the goldsboro location
served as the positive pollen
environment and salisbury the negative
control
white cbg's super haze and lifter
varieties were trialled in both diploid
and triploid form thanks to david
souchoff and his team for their work on
this trial and the subsequent data
at the negative pollen control salisbury
site differences in biomass defined as
non-stem flower foliage and any seed
produced
differences in biomass between the two
ploidies at harvest was not
statistically significant but it is
worth noting that the amount of
variation was greater in the triploids
at the positive pollen goldsboro
location biomass production was greater
in triploids by about a quarter pound
per plant and the difference was
statistically significant
differences in seeding were all
statistically significant pollinated
diploids produced about 2500 seeds per
plant while triploids were around 50 or
about 2 percent relative to their
diploid counterparts
seed weight per plant followed a
genotype specific pattern that at this
point generates more questions than
answers
relative seed size between the genotypes
varies with lifter seed much smaller
than white cbg in general which may
account for some of the variation seen
here but there also seems to be an
unexplainable element at play as well
note the single outlier with much higher
seed
seed weight present in the triploid
super haze variety it's just a little
line up there on the triploid section on
the far right
trials at cornell included lifter super
haze and white cbg in both diploid and
triploid forms as well as sour lifter
sour super haze and sour rna as
triploids only
thanks to larry smart and his lab for
their work on this project
this particular trial is a great example
of the phrase farming happens
strip biomass yields highlight this as
triploids did not fare as well compared
to their diploid counterparts with super
haze being the lone exception
the problem here was that large portions
of the negative pollen trial site were
subjected to catastrophic flooding
multiple multiple times this past summer
and we're eager to follow up next year
to get improved data
that said it's definitely an example of
a time where negative environmental
events do seem to impact triploids more
than diploids
in terms of seed counts and weight
triploids again demonstrated their
remarkable infertility relative to
diploids at the pollen positive site
triploids contain an average of 11.3
percent as many seeds as diploids and
produce 10.5 percent as much seed weight
as diploids
while a good result for triploids the
seed amounts are significantly higher
than those reported at nc state
in kentucky the north farm location
served as the positive pollen
environment and the south farm the
negative control in this study lifter
and white cbg were trialed as diploids
and triploids while our new forbidden v
and pinewalker cbdv dominant triploid
varieties were also included thanks to
bob pierce and his team for their work
on this trial and data collection
biomass and seed yields were reported as
pounds per acre in this study with the
exception of diploid lifter overall
biomass yields were higher at the
pollinated site relative to the negative
negative pollen control site which when
taking the underlying seed weights into
account suggests that environmental
conditions may have contributed to this
particular outcome as well
that said triploids consistently
produced more biomass than their diploid
counterparts in both locations and again
produced very few seeds when subjected
to pollen challenge
one of the interesting unanticipated
pieces of information that we receive
from the kentucky trial is some
observations on relative disease
resistance between diploid and triploid
cultivars
during the 2021 growing season uh
university of kentucky observed that
triploid versions of lifter appeared to
be significantly more resistant to leaf
spot diseases than their diploid
counterparts as measured by the
percentage of the leaf affected by the
disease
this pattern of resistance was true for
three of the most important foliar
fungal pathogens observed in the
southern region of the united states
circuspora bipolaris and septoria
these three pathogens each of which
cause leaf spots where spores land on
the leaf surface and colonize the
surrounding tissue are some of the most
economically important pathogens of the
southern part of the country
their relative importance to each other
is still being investigated but as you
can see in the photograph they have the
ability to cause major reductions in
economic yield and likely exist in
disease complexes whereby several of the
pathogens are present at the same time
causing disease
the same trend was not seen for white
cbg
the diploid and triplet counterparts
were approximately equal in terms of
their susceptibility to these particular
pathogens furthermore while we don't
have diploid comparisons for our cbd-v
cultivars those are all triploids
they appear to be extremely resistant to
all three fungal pathogens
increases in employee have been
implicated in increases in disease
resistance in other cropping systems for
example in hops the most closely related
plan of economic importance to cannabis
research has shown that the effect of
ploidy on disease resistance can be
highly dependent and not only
it's dependent not only on the crop
species but can vary even amongst
varieties within the same species
in this way it's not surprising to see
this impact of ployity on lifter
and not white cbg um kevin mckiernan's
team uh in their pre-print a couple
years ago
noted a
an interesting correlation between cbcas
cassettes on chromosome 7 and disease
resistance in cannabis plants there's
still a lot of inquiry into that line of
reasoning but what i wanted to mention
is fairly interesting and
not entirely proven at this point but
our cbdv dominant varieties have
basically four copies of that cbcas
cassette over and above what a normal
type 3 plant would have so it's a fairly
interesting correlation
these initial data from kentucky helped
give us important insight into disease
resistance in cannabis and how we may
start to leverage this leverage this
information for future breeding goals to
make more robust varieties for farmers
[Music]
uh the farmer experience in 2021
the quote at the very top sort of says
it all everything else we grew last year
got seeded
it was kind of the experience with folks
that were growing triploids and diploids
side by side that underwent pollen
challenges with a few exceptions
farmers relayed nearly universal acclaim
on performance especially when subjected
to unplanned pollen challenges they
report qualitative improvement in
overall aroma character and intensity
faster maturation of flowers larger
yields and probably most importantly
dense top grade flowers even on lower
branches
the main drawbacks reported are that
triploids tend to perform worse than
diploids in low light conditions so
again another situation where the
environment ends up impacting
plants that have higher ploidies in a
little bit more profound way
there were also a small number of
isolated cosmetically undesirable
hermaphroditic flowers flower sports on
these triploids compared to the diploid
counterparts
farmers outdoor experiences were very
positive and relative triploid
infertility seemed to prevent seed
formation for most including several in
colorado with intensive feral hemp
populations that have been decimated the
last couple years
outdoor flowering response was slower to
trigger by about two weeks largely
driven by the underlying genome
imbalance of our hybrids
so two genomes are derived from the
photoperiod photoperiod parent and one
from the day neutral parent the opposite
is true when the pairing is reversed so
two day neutral genome copies in one
photoperiod genome copy leads to earlier
flower formation with a late august
early september harvest time at 45
degrees north in the experimental
varieties we tried last summer in
general farmers loved triploids and many
swear to never grow diploids again and
honestly myself included in production
environments
there were several outliers worth noting
because as awesome as these higher
ploidy plants are nothing is a cure-all
we had reports from about 12 farmers uh
out of hundreds last year who were
seated at levels that were higher than
sporadic
not as bad as diploids under full
pollination but more effective than we'd
previously previously seen including at
the university field trials
so emory garcia our client support
expert and andrea garfinkel the director
of r d for us
visited most of these farms in person
collected samples and got as much detail
as possible from the farmers
leaf samples from the affected plants
were confirmed as triploids by flow
cytometry
some seeds were capable of germination
this is pretty interesting and tested
between diploid and
triploid making them alloploids with
more than two sets of homologous
chromosomes but less than three
the pollen pressure impacting the farms
were equally mixed between very large
feral populations in the midwest and the
surrounding areas
intense localized pressure from
neighboring farms and what we termed
paranormal triploid self-pollination
where no other discernible explanation
could be identified
continued field trials and data
collection are necessary to better
understand these anomalies but i think
it's safe to say that they're definitely
outliers from the overwhelmingly
positive results most farmers
experienced
but definitely not the only anomalies
we've seen
this plant just never ceases to amaze a
small case in point
in the summer of 2020 my my brother eric
picked out four absolutely outstanding
plants in a highly inbred diploid
uh in a
highly inbred diploid population of day
neutral type 4 plants grown from seed in
our breeding program during a seed
multiplication run this is a parallel
breeding line to the pollen donor that
we use to create white cbg and stem cell
cbg
this is going to be the final selection
out of about 3 000 plants these were
literally the best and you know what's
going to happen here right the plants
had larger leaves and flowers more resin
content and far stronger aroma than any
of the others
ploidy screening revealed that all four
were tetraploid while the remaining
population were diploid as expected
seeds produced on these tetraploids were
screened and they came back as triploid
why were there tetraploids in this
population of diploids
fast forward to last spring we submitted
our first commercial triploid seed for
germination purity employee screening to
the oregon state university seed lab and
received these results
relative rates of triploidy in seed
produced from tetraploid seed carriers
and diploid pollen parents
appears linked to the pollen donor
lineage
in this example super haze and lifter
both of which share the same erb day
neutral pollen donor tested at 100
triploid
the sour versions of both which utilizes
the same tetraploid production mothers
but switches pollen donors to a unique
terpenoline dominant day neutral variety
resulted in 97 and 93 triploidy rates
respectively while the remaining three
to seven percent tested as tetraploids
so i guess we were also the first to
release tetraploids
didn't really mean to do that though
the same is true in stem cells cbg and
white cbg varieties where one to five
percent respectively tested as
tetraploids
so armed with this confusing new
knowledge we implemented a new step in
our commercial seed production program
this year where every pollen donor was
ploidy screen to confirm diploid status
while no tetraploids were found in any
populations
triploids were present in both donor
lines at rates less than 0.5 percent
even with the offenders removed from our
process the resulting seed continues to
throw low rates of tetraploids in
certain genotype combinations
it's just fascinating to me
this is made even more confusing when
the breeding history of the pollen
donors interrogated these are lines
produced via multiple generations of
self-pollination of single plants in
isolation tents with hepa filters
that only i have access to like i made
all these seeds um i know with 100
certainty and we confirmed it via flow
cytometry that the parent was a diploid
we've done whole genome sequencing on
both the parent and resulting offspring
we know that these plants are from the
same source
there's
there's no good explanation what we've
received from oregon state university
is we've been told that it's
i consider it a speculative alternative
related to a non-disjunction during
meiosis like okay
i know that has something to do with
pollen and cell division there's got to
be a fascinating dissertation for
someone in there to figure out what's
really going on
but what i'm absolutely awestruck by is
that nature does find a way in this case
the first triploid cannabis was actually
released by cannabis itself probably
millions of times over and long before
humans existed in modern form so
it's a good one for cannabis
in summary on triploids um we're seeing
dramatically reduced fertility although
not 100 seedless
uh
it's just that's that's the reality it's
very close but not quite
relatively unchanged cannabinoid content
uh between diploids and triploids and
even tetracloids although there is some
evidence that suggests that there's a
slight increase and i think we need to
do more replications of that to get to
the bottom of it
in our experience yields are higher but
come with that slightly delayed
flowering response the most dramatic
example of yield can be found in our day
neutral varieties
our best 2018 day neutral diploid uh
yielded about 250 grams of flour which
is really good for uh for a day neutral
this is an autoflowering variety very
good but the improved triploid version
this past summer produced over 658 grams
of usable flour and my brother did not
change sizes between those two pictures
lost a little bit of hair with two two
newborns but same size guy for uh
scale
olfactory compounds
seem to be qualitatively heightened and
i say qualitatively this is a sticky
issue
likely due to combinatorial effects of
unique aroma pathways being multiplied
we don't have enough time today to get
into the details and it's not my story
to fully tell but if you want
breadcrumbs do search for unfunded usda
grants on hemp aroma compounds
but the general point is that terpenes
contribute about 50
of the total
of the total aroma in cannabis
most analytical reports on them are not
very helpful because there's only eight
to ten terpenes depending on the variety
of cannabis but about eight to ten
terpenes that are even above the
detectable odor threshold so when you're
looking at a terpene test result that
has you know point zero five percent
depending on the compound you may not be
smelling that and so a lot of the
analytical data that we see commercially
available for folks isn't actually
capturing what's responsible for those
underlying aromas
the rest of the aroma is comprised of
things like esters sulfur-containing
compounds that were described earlier
today aldehydes and others that can
dramatically impact the sensory
experience even when present in trace
amounts we're talking like parts per
billion
the hypothesis here is because unique
precursor pathways are responsible for
many of these compounds their presence
and diversity could be driving the
overall loudness of aroma which would
then be magnified by increased copy
numbers in polyploids there's obviously
much more work to be done in this area
but the early findings lend support to
this view
there's obviously some big mysteries to
be figured out regarding pollen ploidy
and identification of cannabis most
efficient employee level for various
production purposes but our work to date
strongly suggests that lower pleiades so
haploids and diploids are best for
breeding work while higher pleiades
triploids and tetraploids so far with
pentaploids and octopoids to be tested
next seem to be better suited for
commercial production
[Music]
i'd like to wind down today's talk with
some yet to be completed research that's
near and dear to my heart and what i
personally believe will be one of the
lasting legacies we can leave
to future generations of cannabis
breeders
new advances in sequencing technology
and bioinformatics pipelines are
allowing for the deepest most accurate
exploration of organisms that we've ever
seen to the point where the data is
actually pretty useful and reasonably
priced relative to the return on your
investment
in our lab these advancements allowed us
to shrink our computing needs from a 384
core computing cluster the size of a
negative adc freezer
pictured here down to a well
well-equipped laptop the wall time for
assembly has gone from over a week to
just under five hours
the quality of the assembled genome is
improved from synthetic haploids to
partially phased diploids using a pack
bio sql ii and the freely available hifi
asm assembler
the order of magnitude increase and
efficiency and highly accurate reads are
moving us from an era of a single
reference genome serving as a
representative of an entire species to
one where the full diversity of a
species can be represented through
hundreds or even thousands of reference
quality assemblies
this is the new era of pan genomes
important agricultural crops like corn
soy cotton and apples are some of the
first plants to undergo this process
fortuitous historical circumstances have
made it possible for cannabis to be
brought into the club as well
greg concepcion of pak bio recorded a
talk after the cancellation of pag this
year where he outlines the basic steps
of pan genome construction and
pan genome tool application in plants
using cannabis is the example as the
example species and our genome
collection is the initial library if you
haven't seen it yet please check it out
greg's been contributing to the cannabis
genome research efforts for years now
and we're all really lucky to have his
expertise directed at our collective
genomics problems
we've generated very high quality hi-fi
whole genome assemblies for over 100
diverse cannabis plants in our sql 2
derived from our internal breeding
efforts and some key publicly available
clones to build the library for initial
pan genome construction
these include representatives of all
chemotypes one through five plants with
pencil and propyl cannabinoids and what
we believe to be the pantheon of
potential photoperiod responses unique
phenotypical expressions like australian
bastard cannabis and fasciated specimens
and many diverse aroma palettes
busco assessments of completeness
demonstrate that these assemblies offer
significant improvements over the
previous reference
the irony of pangenomic promises to move
away from a single reference standard is
that doing so requires at least one good
reference for bioinformatics packages to
map new reads to so while we've all been
talking about cannabis pan genomes for
the last three years progress has been
agonizingly slow
the current reference cs10 is
substantially more complete than
previous publicly available assemblies
and incredibly useful for many types of
inquiries but appears to lack
concordance with more recent higher
quality sequencing work
kovalchuk's 2020 review of assemblies is
a great starting point for understanding
the legitimate debate about the nature
of these issues but the implications of
subpar genome representation is critical
for plant breeders a great example of
this can be illustrated by an alignment
of chromosome 7 from cs10 both of which
are type 3 plants with one of our type 3
sorry cs10 is a type 3 so is the plant
that we are comparing to from one of our
assemblies
chromosome 7 is the physical location of
thcas cbdas cbcas phytochrome e several
dye terpene synthases a propyl precursor
gene and a marker for overall potency
the different colored rectangles
represent localized collinear blocks
which are conserved genomic regions
between the two
this particular alignment suggests that
the contents of each chromosome are
similar but also structurally divergent
which if real and not an artifact of the
sequencing and assembly process
would indicate widespread and recurrent
rearrangements throughout
we suspect that this is attributable to
the lower quality sequencing approach
used on cs10 which was
an older oxford nanopore chemistry as
well as assembly artifacts that arise
when collapsing two real haplotypes into
a single synthetic haploid so in other
words the two underlying haploid genomes
of a diploid plant that are real get
combined via software into one
not real
software representation of what the
plant actually is
this this ability to do diploid plants
is a brand new opportunity there's very
few other genomes in terms of reference
genomes that have been fully phased and
released as both haplotypes
so we used
yeah there we go we used several
sequencing approaches to build a new pan
genome anchor reference and brought in
collaborators from pac bio bio nano
dovetail nc state cornell and oregon
state university
the plant serving as reference is the
same f1 hybrid we self-pollinated to
generate our segregating f2 breeding
population yielding autoflower and varan
markers and has a genome size of
1.4456 gigabases as estimated by
shenzhen at nc state
the two parents won a type 1 hypropyl 16
week flowering nightmare of a plant and
the other a day neutral type 3 plant
that flowers in about six weeks were
sequenced using pacbio's clr technology
the f1 itself was sequenced twice using
pacbio's hifi process generating two
full smart cells of data hifi asm using
both clr
parental data sets as input guides
excuse me hifi sm was then used at the
trio bin function using those two
parental assemblies as input guides
high c data on the f1 was generated by
dovetail genomics and was used to
scaffold contigs into pseudochromosomes
for both haplotypes and the resulting
draft assemblies are now being verified
against optical maps uh created by bio
nano and these are amazing they're
really cool they don't give you any
indication of nucleotide identity but
they'll tell you basically the full
length and size of chromosomes
but we're also using linkage maps
constructed by dustin wilkerson at
cornell generated from nrgine aluminum
shotgun reads of 289 of the f2 s1
individuals from our reference example
dovetail is currently annotating both
haplotypes using multiple tissue rna-seq
runs
so the project's nearing the finish line
and we're really excited to release this
first phased diploid cannabis genome for
everyone to use
but the initial results have already
proven useful for us and allowed the
deployment of some promising pan genome
tools most importantly the results are
suggesting most cannabis chromosomes are
fairly stable relative to what many of
us previously believed here's the same
comparison of chromosome 7 from the two
haplotypes
of our draft reference assembly just to
highlight the improvement experienced
where the previous chromosome 7
alignment produced acid reflux the
alignment between haplotypes and our
assembly is more like a sigh of relief
and i that's my interpretation here
despite the fact that one is thca
containing and the other is cbda
containing more technical details on
this entire project will be released by
a much more competent scientists who are
working with us uh we're looking we're
shooting for a fall 2022 to an early
winter 2023 release of all this data and
the creation of the first publicly
available
cannabis pan genome
[Music]
now i'm almost done
says i have two minutes we'll see here
speaking of fall 2022 one last
announcement
uh we're using this information gleaned
from these all to all comparisons to
help us design varieties to maximize
heterosis
mash is one of these pan genomic tools
that estimates genomic distance and
mutation rates within our plant library
giving us unparalleled insight into the
relatedness of particular plants
results from early analysis suggested
that the inbred photoperiod line
developed for a white cbg hybrid seed
is the most genetically distant from
others in our library so to take
advantage of that we paired it with two
cbd dominant day neutral pollen donor
lines to create two new hybrid type
three lines uh we field trial these in
2021 and we're really really impressed
with the results they were standouts in
the field for yield and flower structure
these positive results along with our
internal analysis of the underlying
whole genome data are aiding or breeding
decisions as we move forward with
commercial type 1 and type 2 varieties
our first release of type 1 and type 2
f1 triploid seed will take place this
fall with a specific eye towards the thc
flower market and a pairing of classic
classic flavor architectures with
exciting twists informed by our internal
flavor development program
initial tetraploid production mothers
for these projects include a number of
really interesting
inbred lineages derived from chem d
triangle cush durbin poison california
orange trainwreck urkel
and some of our own internal lines as
well
so we're really excited to pair these
tetraploid production mothers with some
special new
day neutral varieties to create
basically the same type of award-winning
hybrids that we've done in the hemp
market but bring them to the thc side
so while these advancements offer a lot
of hope for the future of cannabis
production we're really stoked to make
it possible they're happening in real
time and subjected to the whims of an
unpredictable market which fundamentally
challenges every producer's right to
exist on a daily basis
we hope that these plants will give
farmers a fighting chance to realize
their own dreams as well
with that
we'll end for today and take questions
thank you
[Applause]
hi thank you you did mention at the last
part of your uh
closing here about the thc market
and
does this mean that the triploid
um the triploid intention is not really
available in the thc market
uh it's currently not available in
triploid form that's correct yeah
about about three months
meaning no one else is doing it either
you're as far as you know
as far as you know that's correct
there's one other company that's working
on it right now i'm sure there's other
companies working on it it is the future
but in terms of being available in the
market there are none right now yeah
yeah
thank you so much for the presentation
very very nice talk
so uh my question is uh i want to ask
about the
environmental suitability of the tripod
so
since the string that you're starting
with
in fact no string that we are growing
right now in the u.s
none of them are selected for
the growing environment the u.s i was
just wondering have you looked into the
growth the environmental parameter that
would be suitable i mean that that that
would fit the grow environment the u.s
what's the range that you can possibly
grow this
tripoi plant in the us and if not
is there any interest for research to
look into those parameters let's figure
out where
we can grow this in united states
i want to apologize the audio is
terrible up here i can't uh i i guess i
just want to ask
about the uh environmental suitability
of the tripoi uh a very very nice talk
by the way i i was wondering have you
figured out where we can grow this in
the u.s like in terms of the temperature
ring photo period you know like those
gotcha yeah no that's perfect thank you
you can grow them anywhere in the united
states the photo period response is
similar regardless of whether you're in
vermont or florida so these are they're
hybrids that have been designed in a
very particular way to allow farmers to
grow them and get them basically
harvested and out of fields by early
october
what you're specifically talking about
and i saw the previous presentation it
was awesome you can basically grow
industrial hemp which is cannabis it's
the same thing there's just a single
gene difference between in most cases a
single gene difference you can grow them
anywhere with a hemp license so anywhere
in the united states
um that was awesome so
i appreciate the whole thing so i'm
actually an environmental biologist um
and everything you just said and the
exact question that he just asked is
exactly where i'm going with this so i'm
actually part of the midwest hemp
database program
we use
uh
surfer haze and
white cbg i think it is as part of our
cultivar check program
we send those seeds across the midwest
and grow them in different environments
to this point have you all looked at any
epigenetic data
as to why some of these changes because
again they are still all compliant right
but they're showing different levels
have you all looked at it into any
different epigenetic stuff in those
different environments
so it's a really good question um
no
we'll talk afterwards then well what's
really cool it's worth mentioning pac
bio just released a brand new tool that
goes along with their sequencing that
allows for the detection of methylation
in whole genome reads
which is opening up a whole like this is
this is like
everything they've been doing has been
revolutionary this is the next phase in
revolutionary sequencing it's going to
be pretty incredible but to directly
answer the questions in terms of
different varieties the problem that we
ran into is that different varieties in
different locations ended up producing
some seeds in certain circumstances so
it wasn't there were genotype specific
differences but what we ended up seeing
is that the genotype differences
sometimes would change depending on
which area that it was in there weren't
enough samples to be able to really pull
that apart so we do need more data
and we didn't see the same outcome in
the university field trials or our own
internal trials so it's basically one of
those unfortunate situations where you
just have to say
we need more data to make a good claim
but at this point there is something
interesting going on and we just don't
know awesome thanks thank you
hi sharon's my name um curious question
the culture scene that you're using
at the initial stage is that the same
anti-inflammatory
drug yeah it's great for gout right
and
so are you using it as the
anti-inflammatory to suppress or
uh
in specific doses it stops microtubule i
can't i i was going to i was going to
pretend that i know what i'm talking
about uh
well don't think basically it stops it
stops chromosomes from dividing stops
cells from dividing and so instead of
getting that division phase you
basically just get a replication phase
and you end up with four sets instead of
two
so rather than an anti-inflammatory it's
actually
at a at a cellular level stopping things
from dividing
the reason i asked that question is
colchicine just recently
well it's it's being used in
cardiovascular disease
which is an off-market claim
and that's on the endothelial or the
vascular system to stop that plaque
replication so
it was an interesting thank you
yeah it's funny how certain things that
are developed for one application can
end up having a million different uses
and in the plant plant-breeding world
it's widely used for stopping cell
division
yeah
please
thank you for sharing such amazing
information with the public it's really
it's an honorable thing that you're
doing
um my question was about germination
rates and maybe i missed uh did you have
any issues with germination rates or
failure to thrive with some of the uh
triploids yes that is a great question
so what we've noticed is even in
diploids we have varying rates of
basically
conditioning that has to happen for
certain varieties of seeds some are
immediately ready you can germinate them
the week after they're harvested and
you'll get 100 germination others you
have to wait up to six months they have
to go through a conditioning process
stratification process
triploids are more impacted by that
tetraploids even more impacted by that
we're seeing it in regeneration as well
taking cuttings
are much faster to basically
clone tetraploids are a little bit
slower and as we go up the ploidy chain
the higher you go the more difficult
they are to work with so most definitely
a ploidy relationship between dormancy
and
seed for sure awesome thank you
fascinating thank you yeah
hi um really appreciate the talk um my
question is building off the cultism uh
as well um curious if you're seeing any
other um notable mutations following
that and maybe that might be involved in
your environmental uh
you know epigenetic expressions that
you're seeing too yeah that's a
fantastic question that was one of my
biggest concerns i've just spent the
last three and a half years developing
this plant line breeding it now you're
going to put a mutagen on it and expect
us to make seed with it get out of here
right
we have sequenced the
using the older clr technology we
sequenced the first tetraploid that we
made
didn't see any differences but i don't
trust the older technology we're in the
process of
getting sequencing data and doing the
comparison right now through it's a
graduate student project at oregon state
university taking a cannabinoid free
plant that we basically gave the
university to work with that went
through the same process
we have underlying sequence data from
the diploid form and now we're going to
be doing the sequencing and comparing it
so far we haven't seen we do see some
strange things when it doesn't stick so
like if you have a reversion on part of
the plant you'll end up seeing
phenotypical differences but for the
most part there really isn't uh
widespread mutations that that people
would sometimes think about like with
gamma radiation or something like that
it seems to be true to type uh
phenotypically anyway
just better like if you if you have a
diploid plant that's great best way to
make it better is to turn it into a
tetraploid
perfect thank you yeah
hi um over here fantastic talk thanks so
much
my question is about the the thc seeds
that you uh referred to at the end
do you have a distribution model set up
that we could get seeds in california
for example or yeah go to a gtrseeds.com
enter your credit card information and
we'd happily take your money
fantastic but um
seriously from a regulatory compliance
standpoint if we're bringing in seeds
into california that's coming from
another state how are we going to get
that into our
metric systems and compliance is all
that going to be taken care of through
interstate it's this is part of the
problem is that it's state to state
right it's dependent
on each individual state the only thing
that we're covering our backsides on is
our legality to make sure that we can
send them out they're sent out as
industrial hemp seeds which are
completely 100 legal in the united
states it's up to the individual
cultivators or home growers who buy them
to check with their local authorities
and regulations before popping the seeds
okay thanks yeah great question though
thank you
[Music]
thank you thank you for your nice talk
on nice work
my question is related to the
natural tetraploid plant that you're
isolated from himalaya did you sequence
the genome and did you mine for good
alleles that could explain its
resilience to this climatic
climate to this climate you know it can
the resilience can be due to the
doubling the number of genes but also
accepting mutations in the second
genome without being lethal for the
plants so i was wondering if you're mine
for very good allele
that was in reference to the to the
indian yeah
population no um
and honestly i haven't been able to get
in contact with that that group that did
the research and we've been we've been
trying for about two years so if anybody
has any way to get a hold of them that
would be great okay i'm very curious
because it's such a unique population
for all those reasons it would be
amazing to get
just get the germplasm so that we can
look at what makes it different
i'm sure i'm sure it has evolved a lot
and the second genome has
accumulated some potential beneficial
mutations and it would be nice to
sequence this
yeah also do you have an idea why
tetraploids haven't evolved
every everywhere on earth you know
either producing
more even more resilient why
the evolution didn't make this
tetraploid
to colonize
earth and i'm i'm really sorry i'm sorry
yeah i have a strong accent on the top
so
i'm usually really good
didn't
i was wondering why evolution didn't
keep tetraploid instead of deployed if
you either growing better having a in in
the triploid population no why just
tetraploids
oven colonized earth
oh oh god that's a huge question that's
a really big one
and i'm not an expert in the area i
would defer to people who who really do
study polyploidy um my best guess at
this and from everything that i've
gathered is that you have more gene
copies it makes you more resilient in
places where there's challenges what we
see is that a lot of the invasive
species that really make headway across
ecological regions are polyploids and
they end up for whatever reason being
better at uh
at
succeeding in those areas which is super
interesting because fertility is almost
universally lower in higher ploidy
plants so they're making up for that
lowered fertility with a better
adaptability is what it seems like
between seed production and resilience
yeah yeah it's it's fascinating
you only have so many years right so you
got to choose your uh choose your
investigations wisely
hi thank you
for your great presentation
i work in indoor cultivation i'm just
curious to know if
you guys have studied using triploid
plants in indoor cultivation or if you
have any plans to do so and what kinds
of advantages do you think there would
be to using away plants in indoors
using triploid plants indoors
tripled plants and i would say
tetraploid plants are dramatically
superior to diploid plants we just
obtained a couple thc production
licenses in oregon specifically in
preparation for national legalization
and we don't grow anything except
converted tetraploids in that facility
that's it
triploids are great as well but in terms
of getting something true to type very
quickly the fastest thing for us to do
is develop a plant variety at the
diploid phase convert it to a tetraploid
and then put it into production and
honestly you have never experienced
cannabis until you walk into a
greenhouse full of triploids or
tetrapods
compared to a diploid environment it's
it's like the ultimate expression
we're about to flower the 8x plant the
octopoid if it's better i'll tell you
next year but
so far so good
yeah great thank you awesome thank you
guys really appreciate it