well welcome to my coming out party
after six 26 months uh doing zoom
meetings
um
this is welcome to cannabis and
psychiatry the final frontier
q sound effects
psychiatry
the final frontier
these are the voyages of the starship
cannabis
its eternal botanical mission to explore
strange new worlds dimensions and
recesses of consciousness to seek out
better life and new models of
civilization to go boldly where no
tardigrade fungal mycelium
sentient being nor split infinitive has
gone before
a couple of disclaimers
[Applause]
nothing i'm discussing is fda approved
your results may vary
i have as a [ __ ] of industry i have
many commercial relationships
but what i'm going to tell you is true
to the best of my ability
i'll read this one there's a world of
difference between
recreational studies of cannabis wherein
the intention is to attain intoxication
release or an altered state of
consciousness
as compared to its therapeutic
application wherein the intent is to
attain symptom relief at much lower
dosages without adverse events including
psychiatric symptoms
to briefly introduce the canal
endocannabinoid system
uh it all began with a plant we call
cannabis it produces the glandular
trichomes and of course thc
uh it works analogously to the
endogenous cannabinoids particularly
anandamide both
as
weak partial agonists at the cb1
receptor
but there are many other components of
the system
that we'll discuss in another talk
the cb1 receptor where anandamide and
thc work is densely packed in the
central nervous system particularly in
limbic areas that subserve emotional
function
it also is very important in regulating
the release of glutamate and
gaba in particular so is neuromodulatory
especially on mood
what we know about cannabis extends back
at least 4 000 years in written
documentation
on the right you see a tablet
from the sumerians in what is now iraq
and there were various descriptions of
what we believed to be cannabis
including this key line
for and against panic
which is a 4 000 year old representation
of the biphasic dose response curve
of thc a little is anxiolytic
too much is anxiogenic
just a couple of historical references
to continue this is uh from the oral
tradition in china 2700 bce
fan taking much of it one may
make one the whole ghost which is the
chinese term for hallucinations
and frenetically run about
protracted taking may make one fat
strong and never senile a
neuroprotective effect
uh from the atarva veda in india uh five
kingdoms of herbs headed by soma
and including banga
that may release us from anxiety
from the persian in the 18th century
maksan allahuia it is said that bang is
one of the best of god's gifts it
quickens the fancy deepens thought and
sharpens judgment
this is far from reefer madness
now numerous times you'll see slides
from this key paper
from 2017.
yes there's been additional information
since then but this is the best review
on the subject of mental medical
cannabis and mental health by zach walsh
at all
we're going to start off with
neurocognition
does cannabis produce impairment and
you'll see that he separates these into
therapeutic use and non-medical use
but as we'll demonstrate the results are
much milder
and surprising in terms of impairment
that
cannabis produces and whether that
remains with the individual or not
i'd like to review some studies that are
very little known these were actually
sponsored by the national institute in
drug abuse in the 70s
and after they did several of these and
the results weren't what they wanted
they stopped funding them and these
books actually disappeared from
libraries it took me years to obtain
them on the antiquarian book market
this one jamaica ganja and jamaica
they looked looked at 60 men
and had them in the hospital to do all
kinds of tests they were using three
spliffs a day
we'd consider this low potency but i
don't know where they were getting their
spliffs there was better material
available in jamaica as i can attest to
personally at the time
but
the key thing for today is that there
were no
significant differences in
neuropsychological tests
the users of cannabis actually had
increased wechsler
adult
intelligence scales
on the digit span
something you think would be hard to
remember if you're high there was a
study from greece with hashish
again
moderately low potency but these are
people that used a lot
there weren't a lot of
electroencephalographic changes
on the neuropsyc testing
users
were better than controls on
the waist
similarities digits symbol substitution
and verbal iq
these observations do not provide
evidence of deterioration of mental
abilities in the hashish users
another one from costa rica again
relatively mild quality cannabis
but high volume of usage ultimately
enough thc was getting in
there were no
immunologic or endocrine changes on
neuropsych again quote we failed to
uncover significant differences between
user and non-user groups even in those
subjects who had consumed cannabis for
over 18 years
on this study from jamaica melanie
dreyer who became the dean of
nursing school subsequent to this
working meninganja
in the study she showed that the work
capacity for working in the fields in a
hot
humid environment was enhanced
by cannabis
and very interestingly among rustifarian
women who used high volumes of cannabis
ganja
but did not use alcohol
their children actually were advanced in
their
neurodevelopment as compared to control
children
a study that our group did in missoula
montana back in 2001
we took
four patients
from the compassionate youth
investigational new drug program that
got legal cannabis from the government
again relatively low potency by modern
standards but they were using upwards of
nine grams a day
and these are the profiles of the
patients
these are all the tests we subject them
them to excuse the 20 year old
technology but you see all the neuro
psychological tests that we did
quite
an intensive investigation
in those findings
all four patients had mild difficulty
with attention and concentration however
they were medicating the whole time that
we were doing this so this is not
surprising
there was at least minimal impairment
and acquisition of complex new verbal
material but the
important things higher level
executive functions were totally within
normal limits and two of the four
and none were depressed i'll demonstrate
that later
on it was the judgment of the
neuropsychologists that there were no
attributable sequelae to their cannabis
usage
to follow up in 2018
and these are the ages patient a b and d
had lost access to knight of cannabis
but patient a continued daily use from
other sources
possibly of higher potency
patients b and d were reported
cognitively intact
by the nurse on the study was mary lynn
mathery
and i interviewed patients a and c
and as a neurologist i can say that they
were quite sharp mentally patient c
is an active vice president of an
investment firm
so
people rely on him to manage their money
now some studies
poke at all and this is an older study
but
it's very well done
they looked at current and past heavy
users of cannabis with light past users
and got
neuropsychological tests there were some
cognitive deficits in the current heavy
users that persisted for a week
but were totally gone by 30 days quote
our findings do not support the
hypothesis that long-term heavy cannabis
use causes irreversible
changes excuse me
igor grant who is the chairman of
psychiatry at uc san diego
did this
meta-analysis
on
intensively looked at published studies
and crunched the numbers on them
quote the results of our meta-analytics
study failed to reveal a substantial
systematic effect of long-term regular
cannabis consumption on the
neurocognitive function of users who are
not acutely intoxicated and then a key
finding differentiating this quote
recreational usage from therapeutic
usage
quote these findings are not likely to
generalize to more limited
administration of cannabis compounds as
would be seen in a medical setting in
other words medical patients used less
and would be less likely to have
impairment
a more recent study with very big
numbers over 2000 cannabis users a young
age 20 compared to almost 7 000 controls
looking again at
meta-analysis of of studies of
neuropsychological function
in studies examining abstinence of
greater than three days there were no
significant difference from abstainers
uh the overall effect size was very low
in terms of any reduction of cognitive
function in frequent or heavy users
ultimately any changes between the
groups were below one-third of a
standard deviation meaning
from a statistical standpoint there
there's no difference quote previous
studies of cannabis and youth may have
overstated the magnitude and persistence
of cognitive deficits associated with
use reported deficits may reflect
residual effects from acute use or
withdrawal
and quote these results do not support a
heightened risk for for poor cognitive
outcomes and cannabis using adolescents
compare with adults
does that mean it's fine for teenagers
to do multiple bong hits after school
instead of doing sports is studying no
nobody was saying that however in terms
of damage
there's no evidence for the same
my colleague kirsten mueller fall in
germany has studied tourette syndrome
extensively
um they were using a pure thc
preparation if there were going to be a
problem you'd expect it to be related to
that however
they saw no detrimental effects on
neuropsych function
our friend donald abrams
did a study of pain and
hiv this required smoking of knight of
cannabis all the patients had prior
experience with cannabis and it was
helpful in decreasing acute pain
the problem was smoking isn't the best
way to treat most medical conditions
because of the rapid increase in
pharmacogenetics
pharmacokinetics
and as you see here there was 25 anxiety
54 percent uh sedation disorientation 16
percent this is not the kind of profile
that the fda is likely ever to approve
um turning to some studies of
nabiximoles or sativex which is an ear
mucosal spray with equal amounts of thc
cbd scattered cannabinoids and
terpenoids this is a study of
neuropathic pain and multiple sclerosis
66 patients
there were no significant difference in
hamilton anxiety depression scores and
in neurologic disability scales
there was improvement in selective
reminding portion of the brief
repeatable misspelled battery of
neuropsychological traits
so that was encouraging
in this comparison
we looked at
long-term use of nabixamol sativex as
compared to smoke cannabis in the dutch
and canadian programs over the long term
the hot
colors are the smoked cannabis and the
cool colors are nepiximals
as you see the side effects including
psychiatric associations were much
higher in smoke cannabis
and these were both medical populations
again looking at namixamols the
difference between early studies with
fast titration and higher allowance they
found that more than 12 sprays which
would be about 32.4 milligrams of thc a
day
above that you had more side effects
than benefits
when
a slower titration with limits were
placed on the studies you see that
dizziness fatigue somnolence etc were
cut markedly
um a very comprehensive study was done
post-marketing of nepiximals by recant
at all
and this was done in europe
they looked at 150 patients in clinical
trials and 900 post marketing
the doses that were used
in practice were actually lower than in
the clinical trials
there was one case of suicidal ideation
but that person was on placebo
long-term treatment with thc cbd spray
was not associated with cognitive
decline depression or significant mood
changes
looking at driving another area of
contention
there was only one small decrease in
visual pursuit not statistically
significant you see that all the other
parameters of driving were improved and
determination was statistically
significantly improved
these patients were better drivers
uh during their treatment after their
treatment of multiple sclerosis with the
big smalls
again neuropsychological testing this is
the passat the paste
auditory serial addition test
glad to get that out
no significant difference uh placebo or
after treatment
but these patients with multiple
sclerosis spasticity were clearly better
the general impression of change by
patients physicians and their caregivers
side effects
in terms one person in 40 had
significant psychiatric
side effects
and xero in this cohort had
any suicidal ideation
a
study in children
from israel this was actually done with
delta athc but this was pure it would be
unlike preparations currently in vogue
in this country
they treated eight children with
hematologic malignancies there were 400
in total 80 dope
dose applications with
almost total
abrogation of the nausea and vomiting
associated with the
chemotherapy their doses were actually
very high compared to what happens in
adults and this points out that children
under 10 are highly resistant to
psychoactive side effects of thc
maybe kids are naturally high
um we've got a bunch of studies
observational work from israel
and this was cannabis and autism 180
patients mostly taking an oil cbd
predominant but with you know a decent
dose of thc three times a day
after six months
the vast majority were continuing
treatment their
moods were improved in almost two-thirds
improved activities of daily living good
sleep and concentration
eighty percent were significantly
improved
this is an old study
of sativax
and
you'll see that in almost every instance
in a variety of different conditions
there was improvement in sleep
parameters and almost every study of
cannabis use therapeutically will have
similar findings
now let's look at posttraumatic stress
previous research has been done in
either animals or humans um working
animals showed extinction of aversive
memories which are a hallmark of the
disorder
also stress-induced analgesia was
demonstrated reduction in pain
and blew it
posited the idea of a central anatomic
deficiency predicting predicting
stress-induced anxiety
so let's dig into specific studies
this is walsh's review of the data
available then
[Music]
a substantial portion of people
with ptsd use cannabis with good
outcomes particularly improving sleep
and reducing nightmares one of the
effects of thc is reducing somewhat
rapid eye movement sleep of dreaming and
night marriage so this is quite sensible
matt hillen
looked at world trade center
survivors uh compared the people who
developed post-traumatic stress to those
who didn't
and also normal controls
and they looked at anandamide levels
there was a negative relationship
between the inanimate levels and
intrusive symptoms
they felt that the results showed a good
correlation of lower
anamide levels to
increase
cb1 receptor binding sites in the the
central nervous system in other words
providing evidence for
clinical endocannabinoid deficiency in
ptsd
this was an imaging study
done with positron emission tomography
again in post-traumatic stress
versus
trauma patients that
didn't have ptsd
again healthy controls
this is complicated but the cb1
selective radial ligand showed a higher
volume of distribution with lower
nandomite tone and ptsd that was highly
statistically significant over healthy
controls and the trauma exposed controls
that didn't have ptsd
and they went on to suggest that agents
increasing anandamide availability were
possible therapeutics that would include
things like
cannabidiol and
cannabidiol
what walsh had all said about depression
and there were improvements noted um
there have been allegations of an
association of cannabis use with
depression but no evidence specifically
of causation and this is always an
important distinction
so let's look back at the chronic youth
study
again
for patients
middle to
age to older
who are using many grams of nida supply
cannabis a day
they had very bad diseases that would
make anyone depressed
two of the four patients had been
addicted to opioids one intravenous
opioids in the past none were taking
anything of the kind
so if we look at the depres
back depression inventory 2 mild
depression is is 18.
moderate 27 severe 34.
we had patient a with a score of six not
depressed and the other three scores of
zero
hardly at all depressed
um
this is a study i wish i'd done i had
this idea 20 years ago but no way to
look at it i was struck by the fact that
electroconvulsive treatment
uh
shock therapy
is still effective in intractable
depression where drugs haven't worked
so what does it do
well people's mood improves
number one number two
when there's too much treatment they
have short-term memory impairment
usually temporary what does that sound
like it sounds like
cannabis
um
so you know i thought if we could test
these people there's
a cerebrospinal fluid with spinal taps
lumbar punctures we could demonstrate
that but we'd never get it through
an institutional review board ethics
committee well they were able to do it
in germany
so they looked at 12 depressed depressed
patients who had cerebral spinal fluid
exam before and after electroconvulsive
therapy
the ect increased anamide levels
significantly and nearly significantly
on the two-eric adonal glycerol
and
the number of treatments correlated with
these kinds of differences their
conclusion was that
electroconvulsive
therapy modulates the endocannabinoid
system to alleviate depression
well the whales are calling me but
they'll have to wait
looking at the issue of psychosis
everyone knows that too much cannabis
can make people crazy temporarily
but it's been much more controversial as
to whether you
generate de novo cases of schizophrenia
related to cannabis usage best evidence
is if there's an underlying
susceptibility
it will unmask it earlier
in this study done in the united kingdom
they looked at 600 000 patient visits
that represent 2.3 percent of the entire
population of the country
what they noted was the incidence and
prevalence of schizophrenia was stable
or actually declined somewhat in the
10-year interval 96-2005
and this is keeping in mind that there
was an 18-fold increase in cannabis
usage
between 1972 and 2002.
so
schizophrenia incidents down cannabis
use up
doesn't seem to indicate a problem
quote the most parsimonious explanation
of the results reported here are that
the schizophrenia psychosis data
presented here are valid and the causal
models linking cannabis with
schizophrenia
psychosis are not supported by this
study
another analysis
from
england
they looked at male heavy users of
cannabis and and looked at the number
needed to prevent a case of
schizophrenia
uh
and this ranged from 2800 to 4700 people
depending on their age and females
with somewhere between five and ten
thousand people you'd have to stop from
using cannabis at all to prevent a case
of schizophrenia that's hardly
convincing as an association
how about therapeutic use well there
have been two randomized controlled
trials of
pure cannabidiol in schizophrenia both
phase two
using very high doses
on this one by levica at all in germany
800 milligrams of cannabidiol a day
compared to the atypical antipsychotic
amy sulpride
in 42 patients over four weeks
there were improvements in positive and
negative
syndrome scores
in each
but the negative symptoms were notably
better on cannabidiol and there were
many fewer side effects on prolactin
elevation the atypical antipsychotics
are tough drugs that produce weight gain
sometimes diabetes patients don't like
them
and we have a real possible alternative
here
the dosing probably could be a great
deal lower with a more complete whole
cannabis extract
another study from england
this time
a thousand milligrams of pure cbd
divided twice a day over six weeks
and they were compared to control
patients who were on standard
antipsychotics
positive psychotic symptoms decreased on
cbd
clinicians ratings favored cbd over
conventional agents and motor speed also
improved on
cbd
how about acute craziness what's called
the toxic psychosis from excesses of thc
in this i compared
marinol which is pure synthetic thc
which has been known to cause
toxic psychosis
paranoia delusions
in patients with as little as 10 or 15
milligrams of pure thc
in the study by sellers we had to give
18 sprays all at once
to show that there were no heart rhythm
abnormalities
and there were four episodes of toxic
psychosis out of 260 exposures so that
would be 48 milligrams of thc
sometimes in p people would never use
cannabis at all
but everyone was fine the next day
that's the difference that cannabidiol
and terpenoids make
walsh on anxiety
eight cross-sectional studies and
medical use to non-medical use
in the non-medical use there was a small
positive association between cannabis
use and anxiety but again no evidence of
causation
um
a lot of work on cannabidiol was done in
brazil
this was another study with pure cbd and
they were looking at social people with
social anxiety
[Music]
something a lot of people have a small
study normal controls and 24 with social
anxiety
some got
cbd and some
didn't but they use 600 milligrams of
cbd that'd be an awful expensive
proposition to use regularly
cbd pre-treatment before trying to make
them anxious
significantly reduced anxiety cognitive
impairment and discomfort in their
public speaking
performance
i'm speaking today without benefit of
cbd or anything else i've just gotten
used to this over time
study of feingold
looking at cannabis use
in people with anxiety disorders they
started with a large sample 3
723 americans a small percentage had a
diagnosis
of uh anxiety disorder and were using
cannabis regularly but there was no
significant difference
in anxiety remission rates compared to
other users and non-users
no significant difference on suicidality
on quality of life emotional and mental
health sub skills and functioning scales
were significantly higher
in the cannabis users than people who
did not use it
in this study in canada
again
big numbers 888 people with anxiety
looking at their use rates of other
drugs
61 percent
had completely replaced a drug that was
prescribed for their condition
obviously the most frequently replaced
were antidepressants and benzodiazepines
as you see
what about abuse
um this was from the clinical trials of
uh nepixemol satellites that were done
in this country
and this was the only episode
in uh
some hundreds and hundreds of patient
exposures uh
attempted abuse in the big smalls
uh but the perpetrator didn't get inside
the bottle
and there he is
a little white dog
so there was no abuse or diversion in
the entire program of of three
phase three clinical trials
um historically
uh interesting relations between
cannabis and addiction
j.b madison uh who worked in
st louis on the 19th century
he used cannabis to treat cocaine
chloral hydrate and opiate addiction
quote in these often it has proved an
efficient substitute for the poppy
uh crothers wrote the key textbook on
addiction
from the early 20th century
the only mention of cannabis was not as
a drug of abuse but rather as a
treatment for other addictions quote
cannabis indica can often be used with
very good effect
in treating morphinism
especially the temporary removal of the
worse symptoms
can someone use cannabis medicinally if
they've had a prior problem with
cannabis or opioids
well yes they can be used quite
successfully together even people have
had medical dependency on one or the
other
but after a point at which the patient
has improvement in their symptoms most
notably pain
it's reasonable to taper the opioids but
many patients do this on their own and
clinicians here will attest to this
if someone has a clear cannabis use
disorder or it displays tolerance to
high doses
dustin sulak has a resensitization
procedure
which you can find online basically as
them stop for just 48 hours
and resume at half the prior dose and
usually with equal protection against
the problem for which they've been
treating these are again from nepyximal
studies
addiction usually comes from some kind
of intoxication well if you're not
intoxicated you're highly unlikely to
become dependent on the bottom you'll
see intoxication scores of nebyximals in
clinical trials compared to placebo
on this scale visual analog scale
is you feel something 80 is what a
person usually wants
if they're using cannabis recreationally
and you'll see that we're looking at
single digits no significant difference
between placebo and nubiximals
addiction usually implies dose
escalation
on top we see number of sprays a day of
nabiximals over a year and a half
and what you see is the slope actually
goes down a little over time people find
that they do with less and don't
increase
their use rates
another study from israel
looking at pain and quality life
166 israeli patients with pain that
qualified for treatment with cannabis
average of just a gram and a half a day
of mainly by smoking
pain symptom scores improved along with
family social disability emotional
disability
outcome satisfaction and sleep problems
of the 73 patients were on opioids 44
discontinued them that was highly
statistically significant and the median
oral morphine dose equivalence decreased
from 60 to 45 milligrams a day obviously
less likelihood
of problems related to that
banky at all
looked at opioid usage in again in
patients with chronic pain
118 patients there was a 64 reduction in
opioids and a 45 increase in quality of
life measures some of that could be
related to um fewer side effects related
to the opioids but we'll take it any way
we can get it
the brilliant stacey gruber who we'll be
hearing from tomorrow
did this study she always has funny
titles the grass might be greener
they looked at
patients who were using cannabis
medicinally for a variety of problems
over three months
there were marked improvements on
depression on the back scale impulsivity
sleep quality of life
and energy fuse fewer physical
limitations
for patients who are in opioids the
intake was reduced almost by half again
almost by half on benzodiazepines
a quarter on antidepressants and mood
stimulizers after three months of
treatment
and again some improvement
in cognitive function could be
because of reductions of other drugs
another observational study from israel
these are patients with cancer and
associated pain
of the 344 patients that were on opioids
beginning the study 36
discontinued them and only nine
nine point nine percent i'm sorry nine
point nine percent decrease their dosage
only one point one percent increased it
and fifty one percent remain stable
meanwhile anxiety and depression
declined 84.2 percent
another study from israel this time in
fibromyalgia
26 patients getting a mean dose of 26
grams a day so less than a gram a day
26 grams a month less than a gram a day
46 percent found their work capacity
increased and there was substantial
opioid sparing and decreased use of
adjunctive drugs you see under strong
opiates a p-value of zero
meaning no chance this was a chance
finding
this was an animal study
from
xi'adol
looking at cb2 receptor modulation of
cocaine activity in
mice cb2 is expressed in the ventral
tegmental area and nucleus accumben
dopaminergic neurons that pertain to
addiction
so when cb2 is activated by the
synthetic agent
it either
dosed systemically
in the nose or micro injection into the
nucleus accumbens and inhibited dopamine
release and cocaine self-administration
a natural agent in cannabis
caryophyllene is a
an agonist of the cb2 receptor and we
believe would do the same thing
this is from a prior paper just some
suggestions on what could be used from
cannabis to treat different conditions
for depression
small amounts of thc cbd cbg and
limonene for anxiety cbd with limonene
and linalool i would add something we're
going to see in a moment
for agitation alzheimer's disease
various things help thc cbd limonene
pinene
for sleep many different agents and for
addiction particularly cbd
and caryophylline
to finish up with
some
new data give you something new this
study was published last year this was
done with my colleagues
at the
washington state university in uc san
diego
it was the first study the
systematically examine cannabidiol
in humans
127 patients
they were required to report only on
material that was at least 50 percent
cbg
so some had
pure cbg
uh with
uh terpenoids some were mixed with thc
um
you see this long list of conditions
that people used to
treat it with cannabidiol
said that their use was medical
only 6.3
claimed it to be recreational and for
36.2 percent both
the most common conditions treated were
anxiety pain depression and insomnia
um
but a whole bunch of other things were
tried what happened well the majority of
conditions were much or very much
improved
the highest efficacy on a percentage
basis were for endometriosis
inflammatory bowel disease and irritable
bowel but those were low numbers among
the high numbers the
insomnia you see a p-value of .001
one chance in a thousand that this was a
spurious result
for depression and anxiety again
p-values of .001
in every instance
patients felt that cbg was superior to
conventional medicine that they'd used
to treat their conditions
and a lot got off of those other
medicines
i'll close by saying
this bugger you see depicted here is
still around
um if you don't believe in vaccines
please be advised that i'm a jewish
space laser operator
thank you for your attention i hope
we've left a little time for questions
[Applause]
from the floor
i think that they've got microphones set
up if you'd like to step up
oh bad sign shy audience
chella
hi thank you
and thank you for all of this
uh could you please let these folks know
a little more specifically about how
cannabis helps dementia
sure
um
i wrote a paper basically on
cannabis and neurology and its promise
um i it really didn't fit into this talk
well
but there have been extensive studies
that support the idea that both thc
and cbd might actually be
neuroprotective
in alzheimer's disease by preventing the
buildup of toxic
proteins in the brain that are part one
of the hallmarks of the
pathology of alzheimer's disease
we also know that both of them help a
great deal
symptomatically
uh in treating dementia
our friend
jeff hergen rather
treats
a bunch of patients in a nursing home in
sonoma county
the nurses love it the families of the
patients love it because the patients
are more attractable
they require less nursing care they
sleep some of them sing some of them are
showing a resumption of skills they'd
already lost
so there is practical information to
support the use of specific
cannabis based
treatments in dementia for both
symptomatic
benefits and also as possible
neuroprotective agents so thanks for the
question thank you so much
i can't see because there's light in my
eyes but please go ahead
hi um in your presentation you
referenced some studies there was a nida
issued cannabis for these studies and i
wondered um the amount of thc that was
actually
administered or was a part of that study
so
can you estimate what is the
amount of thc in the national institute
of drug abuse issued cannabis
yeah it's a good question it's a complex
one so you know the stuff was under four
percent that they utilized but high
volumes nine grams a day you can start
calculating even with a reduced
bioavailability
uh in joints some
you know
at a minimum it had to be in the
30 to 50 milligrams of thc a day
i'd say minimum
but
the patients had almost complete
tolerance to intoxication you know we
could demonstrate minor differences when
they were actually smoking on the nerve
psych test
but
they all functioned
really well
and far better than they had
before such treatment
you know we're talking about miserable
diseases to get into this program you
had to exhaust every medical possibility
and prove that to a skeptical government
so it was a high bar indeed very helpful
thank you
thank you ethan wonderful presentation
i'm over here
ah i recognize the voice
the um
the need for safe and effective
psychiatric treatments is probably more
now than ever and the field of
psychiatry from my experience is the
most reluctant to even consider cannabis
as a useful option meanwhile physicians
have the highest rate of suicide among
any profession so we're
we're also miserable in this field not
us specifically but our colleagues are
how do you see
this information and this treatment
making its way to the patients that need
it how do you see at a macro level the
the healing of this uh health care
approach to mental health
yeah it's really tough i mean i've been
doing this for 26 years and i have to
say that the roadblocks to research
remain
largely the same as they were in the
late 90s when i began this
which is a very sad state of affairs
we shouldn't be ceding the ability to
investigate cannabis medicinally to
other countries
even now sue sicily did a recent study
of post-traumatic stress she had to use
knight of cannabis the study was not
successful everybody knows that cannabis
can be used successfully to treat ptsd
so it's a severe mismatch here and it
remains the case if i have a preparation
that i think is going to be good
for treating a specific condition and i
want to get fda approval
can't be made in this country right this
moment
this explains why for a majority of the
last 26 years i've worked for foreign
companies
it's not the way it should be
i think we have to be doggedly
persistent
i think i have been but you know i'm 70
years old now and i'm get tired from
time to time
so
we need
young
physicians who are dedicated like
dr sulak goldstein and many others
to carry on
but
it just takes
dogged determination
that's it
uh hopefully some legislative change but
i wouldn't be hanging my hat on that not
the way things are going
[Music]
dr russo um
can you cite some studies of the effect
of cannabis on
bipolar disorder types one and two
um
yeah that's
a tougher one um
is hard to treat with anything
you know we hear reports of benefit and
specific patients everything is
dependent
on the preparation
i would really have to think about um
i think it needs to be individualized
with bipolarity there are
just vast differences
in the cycles that people have some are
rapid cyclers some have predominantly
depression some are predominantly manic
for better or worse a lot of people with
bipolar disorder don't want to medicate
because they
like how they feel when they're manic
so it's a very tough problem it doesn't
mean it shouldn't be investigated it's
just right now we have only anecdotal
evidence
thank you very much sure
[Music]
hey ethan
other side
no worries um
just the question kind of for the room
um
as far as the problem of studying whole
plant or full spectrum products
what do you think about
so you can do a clinical trial of
marinol
clearly it's done regularly
you can also
use
full spectrum hemp extract so the below
the 0.3 thc
and that's acceptable
can you dial in the dose of thc that you
want mix that together with
a full spectrum hemp extract as an
excipient combine that product pretty
much approximate a full spectrum
cannabis product and do a study with
that
and i would tell you that i've talked to
the dea and the fda on this and they
have
gone ahead and said yeah you can
do that legally they don't have a
problem with that what do you think
about that as a potential way through
the regulatory nuisance of
the federal government well
what i'd say initially is you shouldn't
be having to jump through all these
hoops
but beyond that
um
i'm a firm believer in full spectrum
products i'm also
believe and you can mix and match
for example it's not commonly known that
nabiximals is a combination of
high thc chemovar and a high cbd
chemovar that's allowed as long as it
comes from one species i.e cannabis
sativa
i have to make a bold statement which is
i think that very few studies
of cannabis used therapeutically have
used optimized preparations
um
i have strong opinions about what you
need for a given condition and
the profiles of the materials used are
rarely jibed with what i think is is
going to be best
but
again
i think the best approach is look at the
disorder what is needed
what is the combination of cannabinoids
keeping in mind that
if you need thc like with ptsd you've
got to have thc for it to be effective
you need to suppress dream and nightmare
activity uh to some degree but tiny
doses are necessary and maybe with
higher doses of cbd uh canabaderol and
with a good terpenoid profile
you know that's an ignored
aspect of this we have studies underway
that we hope will definitively show
the contributions and synergy between
the terpenoids and thc
so i i'd like to see a lot more thought
go into the preparations and not just
some generic cannabis that
comes from a barrel at nida
hi dr russo thank you for your speech
today and all of your hard work um i'm
very fascinated by this tolerance uh in
adolescence under 10. i was wondering if
you could elucidate upon any studies on
longitudinal studies on psychiatric
effects of use of cannabis from the age
of 10.
i'm not aware of any evidence of
particularly in therapeutic use of any
kind of neuropsychological sequelae
and again the evidence from if we look
at the recreational data that we saw
with much higher doses and it would
include people that started at age 10 or
12.
there was no evidence of significant
adverse effects
that were attributable to it that
doesn't mean everyone should do it
it means that cannabis is a
reasonable and can be a safe alternative
for treating serious medical conditions
of children again under 10 it's not just
that one study that showed the
phenomenon that
children are highly resistant to
problems
at a young age that was noted
back
in 1840 by o'shaughnessy in india
they had a child
infant in fact with convulsions that
took a dose that would have laid out uh
an adult um
so it it can happen you know this idea
that we've got to protect the children
usually you're treating diseases that
are far worse and more dangerous um to
their lives than cannabis would be in
any preparation thank you
so picking off of it sorry about that so
piggybacking off of what alex said where
does
uh where's cannabis role in treating
this sort of pediatric mental health
crisis that we're going through i'm
working a pediatric emergency department
i can tell you that we're dealing with
more and more issues and i know cannabis
has a role i was curious to get your
take on it
i'm sorry um the monitors are in front
of me and it's a little boomy uh if you
could repeat
sure sorry about that so essentially uh
we have a mental health crisis
particularly amongst pediatric
population and i wanted to know your
take on where exactly cannabis plays a
role and if it is
cbd dominant type 2 type 3 et cetera
ah sure you know at this point um
cannabidiol as a pure preparation
epidialex 97 cbd is
fda approved for gervais
and lennox gastow syndromes and
treatment of seizures and tuberous
sclerosis
nobody objected much to that
however pamplona indicated through his
meta-analysis that similar results could
be obtained with doses that were of cbd
that were about 80 percent lower
when it was a full spectrum
uh preparation
um
uh
you know using uh 1500 milligrams of cbd
a day is prohibitively expensive
you know
i think that we have to be more
reasonable about the cost-benefit ratio
and
whether it is
intractable seizures
autism
any serious disorder of childhood
that cannabis might help i think is a
proper
area to investigate it's my feeling
specifically related to mental health i
was curious
okay well you know if we have a
self-destructive
destructive autistic child um you know
that
is on the verge of being uh
institutionalized
yeah they should be treated with
something that's going to work
conventional medicine is notoriously
poor
at helping those children
dr goldstein in particular can attest to
the benefit she's seen in that kind of
context
thank you
thank you dr russo judge thompson i'm a
newbie to the conference and appreciate
the evolutionary aspect of the clinical
studies that you presented
i guess my questions from the health
care utilization health services
perspective is anybody doing work to
document reduction in health care
utilization
to quantify the cost effectiveness that
you just mentioned and make the argument
for broader support yeah there's been
good evidence um
particularly the studies of bradford and
bradford
looking at populate medicaid and
medicare populations and use rates
of narcotics
marked reductions have been noted in
states with legal medical access
also reduction in overdose deaths now
you have to be careful there the deaths
have clearly gone down you can't claim
causation but it's a reasonable
inference
that
the reductions might be due to cannabis
availability and many of us believe that
to be the case
now i'm not sure how i'm we're cutting
into the break by a bit i will defer to
the powers that be to say when i should
stop
we're done
okay thank you again for your attention