good morning everyone and thank you for
coming at 8 30 in the morning to listen
to
some
really um well we'll dive into some
hazards analysis
later on today and
first of all thank you to the organizers
of canmed for inviting me and giving me
this chance to
talk about
some contaminants and
how we approach contaminants in in
cannabis
so
my talk today is going to be about um a
hazardous based analysis um for building
an and comprehensive analytical testing
program
so i've been i've spent most of my life
in the analytical world
in the food industry
and i've
for close to 30 years now
working with pesticides and other
contaminants or things that you don't
want in
in in your food or any product that you
consume or you use
for
on yourself but um and so i've
i've often been called the past lady
because that's what i
i focus a lot on pesticides i can
remember the names of pesticides and
at times when i forget the names of my
children
that's how much i work on pesticides
but um so and currently i am with um i
work with for europeans
and um i know if many of you familiar
with your fins we're a
global
network of laboratories we have about
800 laboratories across the globe and i
promise that's the only pitch i have for
for your offense and
so let's move on so today like
we said we're going to be talking about
hazards analysis
and
the background for this i kind of
borrowed it from my background in the
food industry and in 2011 the food
safety modernization act was signed
and
usually when we talk about
[Music]
health and safety we focus on
the microbial risks
because the effects are immediate and
contaminants and chemical hazards are
are usually forgotten
but they are important for the product
for safety and quality of of products
and in 2011
food safety modernization act fesma
included contaminants specifically
chemical hazards and added that
requirement for the food industry in
general
and
they required a risk-based hazard
analysis
so and in addition to that the
verification of ingredients and
suppliers and the development of
specifications which is usually a
challenge when you are when you have a
product and you have various ingredients
in the product you um
you want to know what you want in it
but the challenge is sometimes
what we don't want in it that could
affect the safety and not only sometimes
and more importantly the safety but also
your
the value of your business the marketing
value of your business
if you guys remember a while back dr oz
and heavy metals in apple juice so they
wanted us to label our apple juice us
with a sign that
this could be carcinogenic
so um which is
who would want to drink apple juice that
says this could potentially expose you
to cancer
and so borrowing that um the background
for this is um the process is that they
required is you identify your hazards
you figure out how to control the
hazards you manage it and you verify
that you're managing of your hazards is
working and then usually if you have
various ingredients in your products
that your supply chain
is
following all the controls that you're
wanting to do
and i've been working with
people setting up analytical quality
monitoring programs like i said for
close to 30 years and these are the
three well there's really four
the three questions that i get asked
more often what do i test how do i test
how often do i test oh and by the way i
only have this amount of money to spend
for for this program so what this also
the risk-based hazard analysis also
helps you get the most value for
whatever budget you have
for your testing because you can't you
know if we
had unlimited budget we could test every
lot every ingredient every time we open
a packet of um supply that we have we
could just test them but it could get
very costly
and so this um
based on using the hazardous analysis
you could
rank
enables you to rank your ingredients or
your products
and categorize them as low risk medium
risk and high risk so when you have a
limited budget you focus on your high
risk then a little bit on the medium and
maybe alternate some of the low risk and
this year we do testing next year
we don't and all that good stuff or use
our data and figure out where we can
[Music]
mitigate risk without having to do
actual testing and spending money
and so this is the chemical i'm sorry
that my slides are kind of like off they
look fine when i
send them
but the chemical risk assessment this is
the chemical risk assessment process
that we follow
and
the
phase one is the hazard characterization
and id and then determination of
exposure and that step involves a lot of
data review document review and in the
food world one of my favorite reading
puts me to sleep at night
is the fda import alerts
because that tells you what's being held
and detained at the ports
for illegal substances or for violative
substances and then they're not getting
allowed to enter the country and there's
a whole long list of them and it's quite
interesting reading and and then
at this phase you identify your risk
factors and
phase two you classify them as you rank
your ingredients
whether they're high medium or low and
then your follow-up activities anything
that involves all these ingredients to
your suppliers and then your
verification or testing program and then
the
your suppliers are very are very key
to for you being able to have a
high quality and safe product
and
so
going back to cannabis
slash hemp we can do the um
we can apply this borrow what we've done
in the food industry to
cannabis and so we start off with
assessing sources of contamination from
ground to shelf
basically
we start from soil all the way to when
we put the product in the shelf and look
at every phase of that and see what are
potential exposure to hazards and one of
the
risk factors that is always part of
hazard analysis is the inherent risk
related to that
product or ingredient
and
how we use that thinking
is
we asked this three questions
how likely is it to occur
how likely am i going to remove it from
processing
and are there multiple hazards occurring
at one time these three questions i cop
we
copied as we were creating this tool
from the codex approach but usually it's
about
how likely is it to cause death how
likely are and so but we've applied it
here for
so the likelihood of occurrence of that
chemical or that contaminant or that
hazard in that particular product or
ingredient
and if i process it would i remove it or
would i concentrate it
for example when you're making apple
juice concentrate and you have heavy
metals let's say lead in your product in
the apples themselves and that you
extract them and you make your
concentrate
and and they go with your
extraction process they carry over you
will in fact concentrate the presence of
lead in the concentrate because if it's
soluble in the you know final juice that
you have and sometimes lead does carry
over or a pesticide that's water soluble
that for example metamodifies which is
for a while a problem pesticide in the
food industry because it is water
soluble and when you do use your
concentrates it does concentrate in the
product and then multiple hazards
occurring at one time for example
vegetables or
cannabis could be exposed both to heavy
metals and to pesticides and to other
stuff that it will pick up from the
ground
and so when you have this series of
answers so if it's likely to occur you
can't remove it from processing and
multiple hazards occur at one time
it is a very high risk so the inherent
risk becomes three uh this we just
categorize it from one low medium high
so one two and three and so if it's
unlikely to occur and even though you
can't remove it but it's not likely to
be there anyway and then there's no
possibility of multiple hazards
occurring then there's
very minimal
little or no risk to that ingredient
so let's apply and borrow this for our
cannabis um luckily when we look at
cannabis we're only looking at one
material
let's start with the plan discipline
um uh
we like to call it the you know it's
considered a rack rock or cultural
commodity i'd like to consider it that
way
so we go and we look at the face
you know that previous graph i told i
took you from soil to shelf let's start
with soil and then the plant grows we
all know cannabis is a phytoremediator
so we will absorb things that are on the
ground
and
so in the soil usually the biggest risk
that you have
are usually heavy metals and pesticides
in 2019
i partnered with the company and we did
testing of about 300 soil samples
and um
tested it for pesticides and for heavy
metals and then
on the other end we
tested the by the product that came out
from the soil we tested about 700
biomass samples and what we found this
is actually a poster we presented at
aoac and if you're interested
to look at those numbers i could
uh let me know send me here and i'll
send you the information and it did
translate for example one um pesticide
chloranth neoliberal
was in the soil already because it was
there not that it was applied during
planting but it was there um because of
the previous crops that were used
it came through
to the final mass
the final
plant material
about 35 percent
and then
also um
we found some ddt in the soil luckily
ddt did not translate to the product so
it's a good thing
so and um and and so those are some of
the things and um it's the same trend
with heavy metals although the heavy
metals it's very difficult
to predict the
there's no
linear correlation from soil to the
actual plant material itself
and then of course because during the
plant growth although we know that
you don't usually apply pesticides as
you're growing your crop but
depending on the neighboring
crops that you have
they may be applying pesticides they're
allowed to apply pesticides and
there's an advertent drift that we call
so when they're spraying up in the air
and the wind is just the right direction
the right strength and the right speed
it could land in your crop
and it could stay there and luckily some
of those if they're
they're just surface they could be
removed by washing or maybe processing
but if you're doing extraction they will
probably go through all the way to the
extract
and that's the challenge
and so so the risks that we've
determined
asking all those questions about
inherent risk is
at this phase heavy heavy on heavy
metals and pesticides and
fertilizers some of them also fall into
the categories of the pesticides when
you do pesticide screen there are some
fertilizers included in there
or fertilizer type structure pesticides
and now we move on to the after you
harvest it and you store it and some of
the issues that we
look into and um this is how we
after we did the inherent risk um
questions asking them
mold
bacteria and once again pesticides
because
the reason for pesticides in during
harvest and storage is sometimes
we've i've encountered some of this
where
we had a problem
on
some cranberries
and the supplier swore no pesticide was
used in that crop it didn't come in
contact
nothing was used as it was growing
well
the crate that they used
for storing
their
and transporting their product
was sprayed with a wax that had some
pesticides in it
and those little cranberries absorb the
little pesticides and we we saw them you
know they wanted to blame it in the labs
like no your results are wrong you're
not correct you're not doing your job
correctly
but you know so those are things to
think about and even sometimes
another example is coffee which is um
you're
ex we're pouring coffee and they're on
the barges and all the stuff sometimes
they do clean those barges and they
don't spray
cleaners on them and coffee likes to
absorb you know when there's the oily
outside it's like so it adds to the
flavor of the coffee i'm just kidding
but anyway you could pick it up from
there and then the mycotoxins of course
are directly related to the molds and
the bacteria that um
it could be produced and um
and um so and the mycotoxins stay and
they are hazard a health hazard
then we move on to processing and then
manufacture and then ultimately shelf
and then when you take your plant
material
and you extract it so you expose it to
solvents and the mycotoxins are still
there because sometimes they're being
stored and if the microtoxins have
already formed and they're there there's
a big chance that it will carry over to
your extract
so try to store them properly which is i
think everybody's goal as well so
and then the pesticides and heavy metals
where they come in is when you add
ingredients
and when you start to make your complex
products or you add flavors or you have
some olive oil as a carrier or
i may be using
off-the-cuff examples here but um
the idea is that the more you have and
this is where another level of
risk-based analysis
is is a good to do because when you have
ingredients and you have exposure to
pesticides and heavy metals especially
if you're importing
ingredients
from outside of the united states to add
into your products
the risk goes up because the regulations
for pesticides or for contaminants is
different there's usually a difference
in the different countries so the
geography is a source of risk
so one example i always like to give is
um i i worked a lot in apples and in
south america i used to go to south
america every year to look at apple
crops and um
for pesticide diphenoconazole
is allowed for use in brazil
and um
and so and it carries over when they
make the concentrate it's usually there
and also they methylate the nomenclature
which has been all
their methods been revoked here in the
u.s and
but it carries over to the concentrate
totally allowed perfectly good in brazil
now they go on the tanker they come to
the u.s
the fda gets a hold of them and tests
them well diphenylconozole and like i
said that method of method has been
revoked
those pesticides are perfectly
legal in brazil
are now violative in the u.s
which makes the product unusable here in
the u.s so that's a that's
something to think about is there
differences in regulations heavy metals
is not as simple because the u.s does
not have regulations for heavy metals we
have suggestions we have um levels that
we want and fda has a trend to zero for
heavy metals especially um with the
recent baby food concern for heavy
metals and and so those two are um
are a concern and at in ads for your
contaminant risk
so
based on all of this we've come up with
the contaminant pro
using the risk-based hazards analysis
and i think this is familiar
to all of you this is a contaminant
profile that's really good
to apply to cannabis
and
you don't have to test
for all of them in all phases
some
like for example you don't need to test
residual you don't need to test your
raw plant material for residual solvents
because there would be no um exposure or
risk of exposure for it if you use those
questions
that um you know that then my
four or five slides before um you'll be
able to determine what phase you want to
uh test them and um i usually uh though
microbiology is there in the profile i
don't
i won't speak to microbiology because
i may be giving you
incorrect information
so i will focus on my contaminants and
my pesticides as we do this so now that
we've we've gone through this complete
the risk hazard thought process and then
we have our contaminant profile
we go this allows you to take you to
testing
and
i will take some of my time to talk
about testing because
not all testing's the same
and um pro methods and procedures and
all this is important to be aware of
those things so i'll take you through
some
testing and
advances in testing for the contaminant
profile for cannabis
and i will start with
the residual solvents
so um you know like the exposure of your
product is when you do your extraction
this residual solvents are usually from
the extraction process
and
the most
that we see
usually is ethanol butane
propane
and
methanol in the pharma industry
sometimes we get asked to do methanol as
well and then supercritical
co2 which usually will not leave a
residue
and then
the reason for the concern for residual
solvents is that you
after you've extracted it and you think
you're trying you're removing all those
solvents that you've used for extraction
sometimes they don't all quite go away
and so this is a list i the list that i
have there is
the bcc
bcc list of solvents some other
regulations um ask for the full usb 467
usb 467 list of solvents which is about
five times more
um
components than that but that's a
compendial method for usb usually used
in the in the pharma industry for a full
um length for um four six seven and so
this is the kind of testing that you do
and residual solvents is usually tested
by headspace which makes sense you know
because you want a solvent so you take
your product and um you add your
solvents to it and um seal it
make sure you seal it properly
in the lab we make sure it's sealed
because when you heat it a little bit so
that you release some of those residual
solvents as they're there and then you
all this are done closed and then you
have the that big
thing t thing on top is your auto
sampler pretty fancy auto sampler it
runs about it's more expensive than the
gc system
the auto sampler because the your
analysis is very dependent on that on
that auto sampler that it does what it
does and delivers the whatever residual
solvent to the instrument that measures
it i i
was looking at a quote last week
um
the gc was i think i don't know 40k they
told me but the auto sampler was 80k
and i'm like
i may be able to build the gc but the
auto sampler we'll see but anyway you do
need that setup though to to give you
your um precision and your rsds that are
proper
a good auto sampler is very important in
the residual solvent testing
then the next one we go to is mycotoxins
and the mic
though there are as you can see there
there's about
12 16 mycotoxins that are commonly
tested for in the cannabis world most of
the regulations only focus on
the five
the atlas and okra and um
we
where i work we also work with infant
formula so i love the limits of the
cannabis world because they're
significantly higher than infant formula
and so
i wouldn't say easy
but a little bit simpler to get to than
what we try to do for infant formula but
mycotoxins are
highly toxic natural compounds and
especially if you're allergic to it
it's not very good you know if you have
like a i don't know peanut a nut that
sometimes a little mold in there some
micro toxin and you eat it and your body
doesn't like it you could have
issues in your in your mouth after taste
or you could actually get sick it's
every now and then you could see it in
in the food
come out and they are they are not easy
to destroy
you can't heat them out
they'll stay
the molecule is very persistent and
to test them we do use a very simple
extraction and do lcms analysis for it
and that allows us
the lcms allows us to
get to the
limit
the action limits that most of the
regulations from the different state
regulations offer
and then we go to heavy metals and
generally
the heavy metals is
the testing is involves the digestion
with some acid nitric acid usually and
then
you transfer it and send it off to your
icp ms
well we do it icp ms or other detection
systems that you can do although they
are less sensitive
actually we also do msms we do tandem ms
because
like i said in my lab we also work with
infant formula and in front formula they
want zero
well which is not real
so we go to one ppv
we want pbb whereas in in cannabis i
think
these are limits of um quants for the
samples that we do and 510
lead five arsenic 10 that's total
arsenic by the way um
although for those of you in cannabis
that are concerned with prop 65 prop 65
looks for inorganic arsenic
which if your
total arsenic is
below
what that threshold is for inorganic
arsenic for prop 65 then you can
have a good
safety you know feel good that you are
under that inorganic arsenic threshold
and then cadmium and this lev limit of
plants are actually
well below many of the state regulations
if not all so there's no problem
heavy metals
analysis is not an issue
there's good quality and there's many
labs that can do it there and it's very
established system
but um
but you still need to have um
a good quality control in your digestion
and your blanks and controls um to
follow that but it's generally tested
using um icpms acid digestion and icp
mass spec
and then
we go to my favorite part
because this is nowadays is a very big
question um in in the cannabis world in
the canvas world in the hemp world
because of many regulations
many each state has different sets of
pesticides what pesticides do you test
and which list are you going to go
through what limit of quant do you want
to use
and if you're in colorado
that is the biggest challenge you have
because the limit of quants that the
that colorado requires for the
certification is very very difficult to
achieve it's very very low many some of
the compounds are are low but
you know you can get to it if you work
hard enough
so pesticides
now this is a general background you can
just um see it and it's transferred to
hemp based products
you know we talked about the risk how it
could get into there at the soil and
during your
planning and exposure
but um
currently
there are 1600 parent compounds well
there's really six thou over six
thousand registered pesticides in the
united states
and
i don't think there's
a synthetic pesticide that's registered
for cannabis there are some biological
pesticides that are registered but i the
last time i checked there was not a
synthetic pesticide that's allowed for
use in him which means any pesticides
you detect could be considered violative
but luckily states from state to state
to state to state they have what they
call action limits
so that's what you use and you try to
fall under
well under the action limits
like i said colorado is the challenge
because their action limits or their
limits of quant requirement is quite low
and and then their list is also very
extensive and the same with florida
there's also an extensive list so
people always ask me do we really need
to test breast size there's really not a
law that tells you you have to test for
pesticides you know unlike
um micro you're required to test for
micro and some of that stuff aflatoxin
there is a regulation that tells you but
the reason that you test for pesticides
is it's actually codified
and it falls under the definition of
adulterated food if you're if you're if
you want to take your final product your
cannabis put it into food and
a raw
is deemed adulterated and subject to
enforcement if it contains either a
pesticide
that's
a level greater than the tolerance well
there's no tolerance so any pesticides
greater than level tolerance
or
that that's what it is a pesticide for
which there is no tolerance exemption or
food additive regulation
it is considered adulterated
and it is not legal
to distribute adulterated food
at least in the us well eu i guess
everywhere i think and then the shea if
you're in the dietary supplement world
the shay tells you the same thing
if it's a dollar rated it's considered
misbranded and you do not want
misbranded products out there
and so there really is
a reason
it's codified
you need to be concerned about
pesticides
and
at least be aware of what your pesticide
profile is of your product just so no
surprises for you
and
then
as i mentioned already there are
many different sets of analyzed list
and then action limits specific to
individual states and colorado has
the most and i think florida is a close
second and
washington state washington's not there
but it also has a long list
of pesticides they're they're
similar
but
sometimes two or three compounds
different enough but luckily
you can screen for pesticides
and so
for here the pesticide residue analysis
is the most complex of all the
contaminants that we did because
unlike
for example mycotoxins there were only
five components we were interested in in
heavy metals there were only four
components we were interested in in
residual solvents maybe eight to
12 to 15 at the most maybe
20.
pesticide residues usually screen for
about 500 compounds
to be comprehensive because there are so
many to pick so so many pesticides out
there to pick from and there are
two approaches that we
we kind of define the approaches to
pesticide residue testing as the
classical approach which was
my time i started with a classical
approach 30 years ago where you actually
do um
liquid liquid chemical separation you
use a ton of methylene chloride acetone
put it in a chef panel it's those
pictures of of scientists that you see
and then we actually do a chemistry um
this
solvent chemistry to separate um
that but then now we have they have the
modern approach the the advent of the of
technology of lcms and gcms and in the
classical approach the reason for all
those mixing with lots of amounts of
acetone and methylene chloride is to
clean up you know you take your ham your
hands like
green
or and and and you know those colors
come from compounds
and those compounds
um sometimes interfere with analysis and
you wanna that's why you do a lot of the
extraction methanol or
acetone huge amounts so you can shake
them off and you can separate the
organics from the pesticides that you
want and you end up with
if you did it your job right a colorless
liquid at the end because our
instruments don't like those highly
colored stuff because they mess your
instruments up
and then
um
you know because of concerns for the
environment and we want to be
responsible
in the last 15 20 years they they
did away with a lot of those solvents
used only a little bit they went to
about from 100 mils to about 5 to 10
mils and that's for those if
any of you guys here in the best side
world um the advent of lcms and then
captures
um
because
the
in our lab what we we like is
when you dilute dilution it's the best
manner of cleanup
because you don't use chemicals and all
this stuff and the only way you are able
to do that is if you have a gcms
if you have the ms and or 10 mms and
that's what they call the modern
approach because it is very very
dependent on the instrument that you use
at the end
whereas the classical approach is
dependent your ability to screen for
pesticides dependent on the first part
on the extraction and how good you do
that and how good you separate it out
and there's a multi-residue method like
i said there's 500 plus compounds
there's labs in the eu that can do 700
compounds at one time
and it's mind-boggling to look at that
the data the chromatography that comes
out for a bit and it's also optimized
for analysis of complex samples and when
you're doing pesticides um it is really
best if you want to cover a wide range
of um of components
to do um two platforms gcms and lcms
often in the cannabis world we
we see where we
tend to only use lc the lcm sms platform
and that
if you
only use one platform it give it puts
you a little bit of a disadvantage
because there are compounds pesticides
that are not amenable to
lc you need the gc to get them out and
have a recovery and
some of them i see some headshaking in
the audience but
many of them really the recoveries they
don't make it quite through and
and then
what when you have both of them when
you're using both of them you can
immediately do a confirmation
you know you have when you see a
positive and if it also comes out in the
gc
you can look at what the g c transitions
are and if they match then you have an
immediate confirmation if you have a gc
and it also works in lc as we have about
235 analytes
and
i think 90 percent
of the lists that are in the state
the list for the states for the
pesticides that they have 90 of those do
fall into the uh word they can be done
by both uh either gc or lc but there is
there's just a few of them enough
that you have to use one or the other
and you want to use up gc one of them
and i'm pretty sure
i'll have people disagree with me is
bifentrine as an example
it's rare and which and bifentrine is
one of those compounds that show up in
cannabis
and and it is a g
it's best on the gcm sms you can
survive with lcm sms but your recoveries
are could be low and um
yes so it the accuracy is not
quite there
and
because cannabis is such a complex
matrix you do have to validate a full
validate so you can
determine the analyte
the analyte you want in the presence of
other components and the limit of font
that you want and you can assess
the difference
and those are the that's those are the
terms that we
need to define when we validate how
selective the method is what our limit
of quant what the accuracy what the
precision and the robustness is the
robustness that we do we have a very uh
because we
also have to meet sante requirements for
the eu when we do our validation um it's
over three days
and two to three analysts that we have
to repeat the whole process and and and
look at the rsds between
our
analysts
and
method validation takes quite a lot of
effort
um to do that but it does at the end
give you
a confidence in your method that your
your method is is doing what it's meant
to do
and and that what you're seeing as your
pesticides if you're not seeing any
pesticides you're confident that there
really is no pesticide in there because
you validated the method and you have
criteria based on the validation you
define criteria for acceptance of your
analytical test
and
for pesticides residue we we have to do
this is just an example of what could go
on in the lab because like i said
cannabis hemp is a difficult matrix and
we
use the the base is the catcher's sample
preparation which is very simple you
take your matrix you add a little
nitrile you add salt
and
you shake them for a little bit and then
you take them through a solid face
extraction then you have a clean extra
and then that layer on the top you take
it you shoot it to your machine
and there are different combinations
that you could use for um for cleanup um
you know you just vary the salts and
that you have depending on the
structure of the pesticides you want to
capture
and what you want to focus and sometimes
for the
to meet the colorado requirements we've
had to use
at least three of those combinations so
you often have to go back twice to to
meet them but you can't can be done
and then
we keep putting difficult sample because
it is a difficult matrix and this is one
of the things how we get away with false
positives
um oh actually this is the gc part which
is
this is for matrix interference that we
do that so you you do split purge this
is kind of
really deep into the chemistry but
there's a technique that we use
into separating them we we use pressure
and we split we do the purge and all the
bad stuff that we don't want goes to the
other side and the good stuff that we
want goes to the to the guard um often
you need a guard column
before your column when you do
chromatography so you don't ruin your
actual analytical column because the
guard column is usually i don't know
maybe just as an example
fifty dollars
and your analytical column could be
upwards of five hundred dollars so
there's a tennis so but the guard column
kind of
absorbs a lot of the gunk
and um this just in case you want to set
up your own pesticide test
but
you know and it's this is a very simple
simplified diagram of it and there is a
lot of experience that's in the back of
that when you're interpreting
chromatograms
and
this one is the one
you do
besides your ms which is
the
you have transitions
how i
try to describe ms for those of you that
are not really familiar with it is you
have this little
compound for example and then you
send it through it's like
having chill daughters so you're
and then you do something and then you
have that and then if you take it
further you have um on down the road so
their their fingerprints are very uh
specific to that so what we do is when
we do our lc or gc you have a compound
in there it has what you expect the
transitions to be and if the ratio or
something is not off is not right based
on the criteria that we've set it
triggers
another um
transition
and then you end up
at the end with more transitions to
confirm your compound and this is a
simplified um
here so when you do we have the standard
below and then the sample the kind first
second and third squares they all kind
of look the same until you go to that
final step
where the fingerprint i call them
fingerprint
don't match
anymore so you take them further and um
i am not an expert in this i have quite
a few experts in my lab
i just understand the surface of it so
if you have any questions about it send
it to me and i will send it to the
proper people
to answer your questions
and then on top of all of that to give
confidence to your testing or if you
have a lab or in-house lab where you're
looking at other labs there's always the
accreditation that helps and the
accredited accreditation if you can read
that is just demonstrates the competence
of labs you know it basically
standardizes labs
for the requirements and it's just a
systematic approach to documentation and
that um and then the only thing that's
important to remember is that
accreditation the iso accreditation
is
there's a general accreditation that you
can have for a site
but more importantly the methods
they are
method specific
the iso accreditation and often can go
down to the matrix
that you have for your accreditation
it's just another another an added layer
of confidence that you have that there's
a consistency in the practices of the
lab in the testing and if you have an
in-house lab if you want to
have your own it's it's a good thing to
help you be consistent
and at the end
so we went through the risk base and
that's the that's important to
understand what your potential hazards
are and that the
it is important that you test your raw
materials or at least know based the
baseline of your products if you
if the budget doesn't allow for every
lot or everything at least get the
baseline and understand
when it's related to your suppliers
where you're sourcing it you don't have
to test them
every day or all the time just have an
understanding of your baseline and then
because of the complexity of the hemp
matrix and the hemp extracts and the
isolates that we
get from them
we need to sometimes go look for
technology to help us into figuring out
those contaminants
knowing what the contaminants are in our
products
and
it's really important to use validated
methods or the term fit for purpose so
you know that
what you have is important and then the
iso accreditation adds another level of
confidence for staff
and
that's it and thank you for listening
so i think we have a little bit of time
for questions
hi good morning good morning enjoyed
your presentation by the way um
love to get a copy of that study that
you mentioned at the beginning of your
talk
sure we'll i'll send it to it was a
poster aoc poster and i can send you a
copy of it okay um
yeah i do have a question um i publish a
lot
in the field of heavy metals in cannabis
and hemp
and
[Music]
i think there's compelling evidence out
there that we need to be expanding the
elemental panel beyond the big four
there's a lot of information in the
public domain
how the pharmaceutical industry
approached that using a risk assessment
strategy which to me
is is guidance to the industry but it's
convincing
the industry that they should think
about expanding the elemental panel and
um
yeah i can publish and i can talk about
it
in your conferences and i have a talk
this afternoon at three o'clock but i
just like to get your thoughts and input
how we can convince the cannabis
industry
that they need to be expanding that
elemental panel
yes up to to date actually if we if we
go through to follow the
pharma industry um we are currently
doing a validation study and it has 17
elements in it
included for just for the release of
their product which is um
which is
the trend so um
going from four i i do agree with you
that we there are some elements that we
need to add
to the four and
but currently though the regulations
only ask for the four and that may be
once when state to state regulations
move to adding more elements then we
would definitely have to to take a look
at it luckily the methods
the ic the heavy metal methods are
easily extended
to include more elements in the testing
so it's not a big jump
um to go from four to a few more
compounds except for you know maybe
selenium and molybdenum and some of that
which you may need a different mode of
testing
so i believe your talk is at 3 pm this
afternoon
yes so if you're interested to hear
learn more about heavy metals 3 pm this
afternoon
any other questions
well i think the next part is coffee
break
so i think we should
go and get our coffee break early thank
you
[Applause]