everybody thank you very much it's a
pleasure to be back here actually quite
impressive audience after lunch I don't
think that I would come if I would
instead of you especially which I gave
this talk a year ago and signs not move
so fast unfortunately so I hope we have
a little bit new audience and I won't be
too boring so I want I want in this talk
in this hour that I have to show you how
I think the medical cannabis will be in
five years from now it's my opinion and
my father said that if you argue with
somebody 50% that you are wrong so it
might be that I'm wrong but that's how I
see it and I want to show it in a way of
to risk to a specific research that we
did in the lab in the last two years and
every one of them I think tank the
cannabis the medical cannabis to a
different angle and think to my opinion
we will see two different sides of the
coin in few years of medical cannabis so
let's start with this is okay just a
moment okay I will start with a very
short introduction but I think this
introduction actually I built it for
this conference a year ago as that was
my talk but today I want to show it as
introduction the cannabis plant is
amazing plant is a unique plant actually
Ruffy spoke this morning and said that
and talked about addiction and people
said that there is no addiction to
cannabis but I think it's it's wrong I
don't know anyone that started to work
with with this plant and not become
addicted to his work
so it's a unique plant
it's a crazy plant that affect our body
in many many ways and when I started to
work on cannabis and I read that is
doing everything reducing pain increase
appetite change your mood I didn't
believe it it didn't make sense to me
but four years later when I know how
it's affecting the endocannabinoid
system I understand why it's doing that
so our body and I'm sure everybody here
knows about it and also Rafi's spoke
about it so I would mention it too much
our body produces the same compounds
very similar actually they are not so
similar the three dimension structure is
similar but they are doing similar
effects in our body the endocannabinoid
system it's a regulation state system
it's a homo static system
the balancing outer system but it's
actually involved in almost every system
in our body and balancing it it I'm
always giving the same example so I'm
sorry about that but it's the most clear
one that when we move near a barbecue
and we smell the barbecue smell small
molecules entering to our nose going to
our ala factory system signaling to
neurons that produce specific
endocannabinoid that will bind specific
neurons that will produce specific
signal to our liver and there is a
ningke's insulin a sorry to our Congress
would create insulin there is feedback
loop that increase our appetite so this
is the endocannabinoid system so it's
not surprised that cannabis increase and
our appetite so the endocannabinoid
system it's actually system that it's
signaling between cells one cell is send
the signal send a message to another
cells and this message is the real
material
it's a compound it's a secondary
metabolite we call it cannabinoids in
the endocannabinoid system so these
cannabinoids these chemical compounds to
have a pointer yeah this can
endocannabinoids will release from one
cell and bind a protein that will know
how to read this message and to signal
to the cell to do something this is the
endocannabinoid system it's involving so
many system and affect our body
regulation I think it's quite clear to
everybody that sit in the audience about
this system I'm just coming from
Baltimore last week from the NIH one of
the people that is a Nobel Prize
scientist and I don't I won't mentioned
his name because the story that I'm
going to tell when I showed this and
talk about the endocannabinoid system he
said [ __ ] said why he said I learned
medicine and I am a scientist I have a
Nobel no way there is a system that I
never heard about it said there were
three more than 3000 papers about this
system what do you mean said there is
like and there is receptors this is a
system right and we had this argue it
took me 15 minutes stopping my talk to
explain that there is a system in our
body that is working to regulate it so I
will go on this system have major to
compound there is the ligand and there
is the receptors mainly we are showing
these two receptors but there is other
many receptors that are playing a role
in the endocannabinoid system there are
GPR 55 GPR 3 and the TRP V family and
they more and more if you're doing a
bioinformatics we can find around 28
different receptors that participate in
the endocannabinoid action do we call
them endocannabinoid receptors no that's
a part of the endocannabinoid system
that regulates the system binding and
under my two AG other endocannabinoids
the answer is yes
if we're taking a GLAAD symbols and we
check how many nights how many messages
like that our body produce we can
analyze under up to 150 endocannabinoids
endocannabinoids like or enzyme that
participate in this process so 150
Campos that participate in this action
we call that endo can cannot be done
like proteome or metabolome because it's
so wide so it's a very very complicated
system in the body in very tight
regulation that signaling and balancing
other mechanism and system in our body
the cannabis plant is producing similar
compounds the feat of cannabinoids this
is the THC in other compounds we can
analyze at least 10 different families
of fetal cannabinoids in the plant and
altogether over than 140 feet of
cannabis from the plant and these
cannabis is just mimic the action that
is net-net native to our body natural to
our body instead of getting in out in
the end and the signals from the output
surrounding like a pain or like a smell
it will bind the receptor and will send
a signal as we smell a barbecue now just
a moment
and doing a mess here okay tonight we
smell the barbecuing the same signal
will enter so Rafi started to talk about
the end to the in terrassa fact which in
the past people show then we know it
from the patient Rafi have few papers
about the shine that if you taking one
compound is not working as good as the
whole extract but the reason or the way
its act usually the talaikan in a
receptor like a lock-and-key
we call it the locally key principle so
you need a one molecule that will fit to
the rest
in order to operate it and actually if
you have a key that is very similar to
the keys that operate but it's a little
bit different it will usually will enter
the lock but will stuck it we call it
agonist and antagonist or inhibitors and
activators so one molecule can activate
the receptors and the other one can
block it even though they looked
extremely extremely similar this is
biology basic biology but it's the same
in the endocannabinoid system and when
we adjust cannabis were not entering one
compound many compounds will enter on
our our body and will bind the receptors
on the cells and because I showed you
that there is many receptors and there
are many compounds every one of them
will bind different receptors and send
say a different signal to the cell and
we're getting a very complicated action
for me this is a major part of the in
terrassa fact this is the reason that
one compound is not acting as the whole
extract it's a complicated system we
call it synergism it's not a synergism
it's a complicated system we know
already at least from our epilepsy row
work that sometimes there's our
compounds as I showed you that blocking
the receptors and it can be in the same
extract a compounded blocking the
receptors and compounds that activating
the receptors there it there is a
competition between them so we have at
least one strain in Israel that when I'm
giving to the mice it should reduce
seizures a lot of high CBD there is also
CBD v all the integrators that I think
will block the seizures of the mats but
it's not working so what we did we
separate it to two parts 50 compounds in
50 compounds here and then one part is
working very well and the other part is
not working you put them together it's
not working anymore because in this side
there is something that inhibiting the
action so sometimes we get a different
action
not just because there is more component
activating but also there is things that
blocking or changing so again we are
talking about very complicated machinery
in our body so when we started to do
research four years ago we started and
asking what is the anti-cancer
properties of cannabis in Israel we have
many many patients almost 20,000 that
getting the cancer patient that getting
cannabis but they are getting cannabis
as palliative care as improving quality
of life on top of the chemotherapy that
getting cannabis to reduce say nausea to
increase appetite to reduce pain but our
question was whether cannabis can have
can have effect on the real tumor but as
I told you there is many types of
cannabis and every one of them have many
compounds in cancer it's a given name to
hundreds of different diseases just in
breast cancer I'm familiar with more
than 40 types of breast cancer so how to
start and I'm sure that everyone that
know me show so these images already so
we'll do it fast with taking the cancer
cells that we are growing in a plate in
a plate like that there is between 3
million to 10 million cells depend on
the type of the cancer and we are
creating extract we are extracting the
active compound from the cannabis and
we're adding to the cancer so if we look
on colon cancer we see every dot here is
a cancer cell we adding the cannabis
extract number one and it's kill all the
colon cancers where the extract number
two we saw the same effect we add extra
number three and it didn't affect the
cells we did the same thing with breast
cancer and you show we saw very similar
effect
we took a prostate cancer and now the
one that didn't kill that sorry that
killed the colon cancer in the breast
cancer didn't affect the prostate cancer
the same thing with the second one but
the third one they did enough
the colon didn't affect the breasts now
killing the prostate cancer when we took
colon cells and not cancerous the
cannabis didn't affect them in that
amount so we ask ourself okay what is
doing this effect we read five compounds
four years ago and we saw that actually
extract number two and extract number
three are not different on the main find
fit of cannabinoids CBD and THC but it's
not surprising I already showed you that
there is many cannabinoids Fito
cannabinoids from the plant but also
there is turpan reads and there is
flavonoids all together around 500
active compounds in the extract so we
can't look just on five so we if you
taking 20 of these strains that we have
we have over the 900 different genetics
in my lab today
if you taking 20 of them and you measure
the Phaedo cannabinoids and we create a
system to do that a method to do that so
what you see here is the different Fito
cannabinoids and here are every line
it's a different genetic of cannabis and
you see when it's dark the meaning that
these feet of cannabis and highly
expressed here when it's why the meaning
it's not expressing here and you can see
the differences between the genetic how
much the active compound the Phaedo can
be no is it different between different
genetics of cannabis so actually it's
not surprising that one is killing and
the other is not but also I told you
that it's probably not the CBD indeed
see so if we want to measure it faster
we can do high-throughput screening we
can take a machine that can take fast
images from the plate and I won't go to
the details and we can put markers for
fluorescent markers and we just say that
every time that the cell is blue the
meaning is is alive and every time that
is read the meaning it's going through
apoptosis and is dying
and you see the control is blue these
train kill the cells very fast and this
trend not effective if we go to the stat
every color here it's a different
genetics different strain of cannabis
and with
take 4 micro gram per ml you can see
that there is few strains the didn't
affect they this melon or myself there
is few strains that kill 50 percent in
few strains that were very efficient
very similar to what I showed you if we
align these strains by the amount of CBD
indeed see we see that there is no
correlation between the amount it's in
CVD if we are taking one strain that
killed 70 percent of these cells and
we're extracting with purifying the T
it's in the CBD and we put them together
on these cells even if we put 20 times
small of this CBD and THC on these cells
it's not affecting the cells so it's not
that it's in CBD or it's not it's in CBD
alone maybe it's the interest maybe we
need everything if we're going now and
look on different types of cancer we see
the same problem different types of
cancer will act differently even though
it's the same genetic of the cancer so
we look on now couples these two just a
moment here these two are what is it
dissident cancer these two are melanoma
cancer these two are colon cancer and
you see that in these colon cancer there
is few extract they are very efficient
to kill them but on these colon cancer
we screened over than 800 different
extract none of them affect the cells so
even in the same cancer with a huge
difference so you can say hey that the
whisky extract what for work for colon
cancer we type of which types of colon
has what are the mutation which receptor
expressing on this one if a one don't
know it I don't know to fit it so how we
can do the research we can go narrow
deeper and deeper and deeper look on
what we call personal medicine we will
take a cancer let's say leukemia with a
specific mutations
specific phenotype and then we will
start to screening so in this case okay
before that we can take all the cannabis
that we have the 900 different genetic
lining can tell the computer in London
in group not its ECB dissimilarity all
the compounds and you can see by eye
that we're getting around five different
groups of cannabis not by T it's in CBD
all the compounds all the terpenes can
be new itself livening flavonoids we get
in groups so first of all we can choose
then from here then from here and from
here and then from here to start
screening and then we're taking one
types of cancer with specific mutation
and we started to screen on them so you
see here it's survivors so if the line
is lower the meaning more cells died
this is leukemia cells and you see that
most of the extracts that we use didn't
affect this leukemia but one extract was
very efficient to kill it and when we
find it something like that we are going
after the mechanism which receptors is
bind what is the pathway that being
operated which protein is upregulated
which protein is down regulator we're
taking and we prove terms of what we see
is right so now we tried on one cell
with one with specific mutation we're
taking the same type of cancer without
this mutation we see that it's not
affecting we're taking other two cells
with the same mutation we see on them
it's affecting we're repeating it on
other cells with the same mutation or
different mutation we're doing rescue
we're bringing back the protein we're
doing everything to prove ourselves that
the down-regulating proteins on these
specific cancer is going down that we
changing the mechanism we are proving
myself i don't want to go deeper in the
biology but we're doing everything to
prove ourself which proteins are polite
that which protein down regulated what
change in the ER that now it's blocking
these cancer non normal cells is not
doing we're doing everything to
understand what's happened
these specific cells and when we're done
with that we're going to mice model and
we're creating these tumors specific
tumors in these specific types of cancer
and we show that treating with this
extract reducing dramatically the size
of the tumors this is the start and this
is a representative image because it's
Willie leukemia we did a bone marrow
inter implantation we create the
Leukemia in this mice and we change many
many parameters of this leukemia we're
taking the tumors and we stain and we
see that there is a correlation of the
cannabinoids in these tumors there is
accumulation we injected to the cannabis
to the valley of the to of the of the
page of them sorry patient my patients
have four legs and the tail so we inject
the mice to the valley of the mice the
cannabis and still accumulate on the
tumors which are on his back with this
is very surprising and I cannot explain
why it's accumulate this very lipophilic
the tumors are oily its makes sense but
we find the cannabinoids in the tumors
we see reduction of all the parameters
and so on but now the 100 million dollar
question usually I would say 1 million
dollar question but when the cannabis
field is nobody worked for 1 million
dollar
I tried to set 1 million but they didn't
listen to me so I change it so the
question why this train is different so
remember the group that we have so we
are going to make and we take all the
strengths that we have on that group and
we measure them and we see that we were
lacking the beginning to choose the best
one that we had so even though the same
amount CBD teets here and other
compounds is very similar there is one
that's working much better so do we need
all the compounds the in terrassa fact
do we need one special one do we need
two five seven I don't know what I do
know that I want to know
so my slogan to my students I want the
minimum compounds the doing the maximum
effect I don't want to reduce the effect
but I want to know what are the minimum
compound so how we're doing that with
fractionating the oil we taking the 100
compounds in the extract and we're
separating to four tubes 25 in each cube
you run it on HPLC preparative and you
dis a sect the XR the compound the first
25 will be in the fur in the first tube
the second one will be in the same in
the second 25 on the second tube and
then you've gone back to the cell zone
to demise and you check them so now
every color it's a fraction of this
extract the red one is the whole extract
and the other Carlos is a fraction so
you see the just one fraction is working
as good as the whole extract so you will
already eliminate 75% of the compound
that we don't need and you go and we
going back to this fraction and we cut
it again
so we now left with 25 compounds we
separate five five five and five and
going back to the cells and so on and so
on until we reach in this specific
research
two three cannabinoid three cannabinoid
that you need the three of them in order
to get the same action as the whole
extract if you we purified 100% of the
three compound it's the same action of
the whole extract but if you take one of
them out it's not working as good as the
three of them you need the three of them
and we understand the mechanism one of
them binds cb1 receptors operating the
map and has the other one binded trpv1
changing the calcium release and this is
the reason in the ER it's signalling
when the standard mechanism but you need
the three of them to bind at least two
different receptors we used cannabis
plant extract one in just one in Israel
working for us for twenty half years
it's work perfect after two and a half
years eight months ago my student came
to me said that he all the last
experiment that I did didn't work he
didn't kill the cells okay Ellie did you
tried not just in the mice did you try
out the cells yes I tried they don't
work
let's check it and we checking the
extract and I didn't tell you that one
of the compound it's even unknown
compound we call it three three one
eight B this is my students my chemists
they are not you know they're not
thinking out of the box instead of
killing this master killer try the sauce
I don't know you know twin three 180 now
we all stuck with it forever so this one
is a unique compound that you must have
it so after two and a half years the
glory the greenhouse in Israel we change
the regulation never mind they need to
move for one place to another place they
change the greenhouse the whole the hell
no what they change this soil the water
the light I don't know their strain is
not producing this compound anymore it's
not working
c4 wouldn't know
to analyze it and to know what is
missing I would say to early Haley you
were the great guy go to doing somewhere
else
eh deeds done sorry life sucks you know
I have my PhD but it's not working that
way now other students won't come to you
anymore so you can't so by knowing
exactly the compounds I can go to my
database tell to my student all go and
screen in all their extracts that we
have in the lab all the genetic which
one have these highly expressed so I
don't have the combination of the of
them in any of the strains but I have
other strengths at producing this one
one phone call to the Gloria I'm asking
one kilo of this strain next day I got
it you're fighting this adding it to the
other two from another extract when we
get in the same action exactly the same
one reducing the size of the tumor
hearing the leukemia and this is a proof
of a concept you can take one compound
room from here adding to here it's
working the same we need the three of
them doesn't matter where they're come
from we need the three of them they're
not not for a question
but it doesn't matter whether where
these come from so all these talk till
now I can show in many many other
example that we our work in our lab in
epilepsy different strain the same
amount of CBD and THC 20 to 1 ratio 5
milligram per kilogram CBD to 2m eyes to
a kilogram you can see different extract
effect differently the mice as long as I
won't go to the parameter that I will
said that the bar is higher the meaning
it's reducing more seizures same high
CBD low THC ratio 20 to 1 5 milligrams
per kilogram totally different action I
can show it in Alzheimer in epilepsy in
sleep disorder it's not just the CBD and
THC ratios it's other compounds it's
much more complicated
so everything that they showed you till
now was a very accurate scientific
approach and the second speaker today
that Dampier he did a PhD in the same
faculty that I did my PhD so when I
started he finished I admired him you
have one of the best laboratories in
Israel one of the best scientists in
Israel for sure and it's a privilege for
us that he started to work on cannabis
but he said something that he's a
newcomer okay said if it's not accurate
compound that I can't produce synthetic
who cares 51,000 patient in Israel care
1,300 the lab tech kid in Israel care
they're not kidding single compound
ain't getting a whole extract with
reduced the seizures that help them to
maintain the day when they're getting
chemotherapy cannabis is a unique
situation that the world didn't face
till today we are treating hundreds of
thousands of patient not with a specific
compound that we produce synthetic in
the lab this is reality who cares what
you think this is reality the patient
get it every day if you didn't go to
this today to the dispensary you didn't
spoke with the patient you didn't get
seven calls every day from patient that
taking cannabis and need to know what is
the what to take how much then you can
said I can do it synthetically in the
lab who cares but if you walk in with
the patient with the hospital and
participate in 14 different clinical
trials you can't say who care but more
than that cannabis is a unique situation
I have one hour already I think forty
minutes so I'm fine with that I've come
is not running so let me check just how
much I have I don't have right now I
have half a now
so cannabis is a unique situation and I
see the cannabis going sorry in two
different roads it's a monster with two
heads one of them I just showed you
accurate science specific compound
binding specific receptors but the other
side it's the cannabis that most of us
familiar two years ago I started a
clinical trial we on pain patient with
Professor a long Eisenberg the head of
the the pain department of Rambam
Hospital today is the head of the
Medical School of the Technion and his
student is a nurse in the hospital a PhD
student and we started to follow up on
2,000 pain patients how they react to
cannabis so if you go to this pencil you
speak with the glowers and I've in my
lab a database project which we are
following on many many patient you
hearing amazing stories in Israel there
is just one dispensary it's a mental
health health hospital the patient need
to come and they get the cannabis there
every glow wave eight authorized growers
will have a butcher that the patient
will come to get it from there
so we have to option all to get it to
your home or to count to come to pick it
so in this dispense we have two workers
that walking and questioning you the
patients when you are walking there and
you speak with the patient it's amazing
every patient tell you how he change his
life how he took opiates nothing helped
him and now it's taking cannabis and
totally change his life and in Israel
the medical cannabis is different from
the stage of Canada these are real
patient in order to get cannabis for
pain in Israel you need at least one
year to be treated with other medicine
under hospital care so you need to have
chronic pain for at least one year
treated by many other medicine that
didn't help you
then you can get cannibus if you're a
poletik kid you need at least to try
five different medicine before you can
get cannabis so these are kids at
resistance to other medicine so these
are very severe patient and these are
amazing stories you're going to have a
banana hospital you speak with the
patient I am doing once a month and
these are amazing stories a pities
depletion that told you how we can't get
out live of the house if two baby seals
did not let anyone to touch them every
time that is getting medicine is getting
to their hospitals because is becoming
now and now the cannabis changes live
all these stories and you think to
yourself while we are giving other
medicines if this is working so good
this is because we are not doing really
clinical trials we don't do really bill
we are not really doing what medicine
physician need to do we look just on the
patient that it was a success
how many patient trying didn't work for
them we don't know who is coming to
dispensary to take cannabis every month
just the one that tried and it worked
for him who is feeling the questionnaire
just the one that he tried and worked
for him this is not a real trial
how many tried and it didn't work for
him how many tried and it make harm from
them one of my students and work on the
way on the bar informatics in my lab
came to me is the Italian guy very sweet
guy came to me daddy I know what we need
to publish at South except on the pizza
what else he said daddy cannabis is very
very safe said why are you saying that
sound said if I look on all the 5000
patient in our database
none of them tell that the cannabis made
any harm so oh this is very cool so how
many patients feel five out of the
question me they are feeling every month
if I've got the question you stop query
every feeling said I don't know except
press the button tell me it said to me
357 patients that you know they all died
right said no why not the field
items and disappear no cannabis is not
killing said no no it's not killing but
you know that they have a bleeding in
the valley and they went to the hospital
this is the reason they stopped taking
cannabis no cannabis not wear any harm
guys this is not science this we
deciding what will be the answer we
don't know what's happened to the
patient that didn't feel the question
near the disappear we assuming what we
assuming why the stop if it was so good
we don't know we're doing science
without really doing science so we
started to do a clinical trial on pain
patient from the moment that the
physician is decided to prescribe
cannabis they treating one year of other
medicines and after one when you Raylan
said you know what I think it's time to
start cannabis from that moment we
started to follow and actually
unfortunately it's a very very very
disappointing result just 45 of the
patient describing improve of the pain
and in these forty five percent of the
patient so fifty-five tried said didn't
help I don't want anymore
45 percent described that it's helped
them just forty five percent the one
that described it it's helped them
saying that it reduced something like 25
percent of the pain in order that the
medicine for pain to be authorized to
pass the threshold we need to reduce
more than thirty percent of the pain so
actually none of the strains in Israel
none of the patient cross the threshold
so actually cannabis it's not a good
medicine for pain
that's the results 45% just 45% did help
them the one that helped them it didn't
really help them in vain there is almost
40% placebo so 45 is not far from the
placebo so now I need to ask myself and
mainly I need to ask me kid or that
sitting here good friend of mine that
authorized all the patient in Israel why
we have almost 20,000 patient pain
patient that getting cannabis in Israel
it doesn't make sense right and how come
that you speaking with them they telling
you that they save their lives it's not
make sense but if you going forward and
ask the other parameter that we are
asking how it's always effect your
anxiety how it's effect your depression
how its effect your disability you see
that in any one of them we have an
improvement not a big one not the best
treatment for depression not the best
treatment for anxiety but in all of them
we have a reduction we have improvement
if you look on sleep it's improved sleep
so actually if you look on Adam medicine
that this patient are taking there is a
huge drop-off of the add medicine look
on the opioids so if it wouldn't help
them how come the 20,000 patient in
Israel isn't a small quantity 20,000th
like 80% of our population right
[Music]
so how come that we have such a big
amount of pay of patient that withdrawal
other if it wouldn't reduce the pain why
they stopping taking our the medicines
so if we look on one important parameter
this is the improvement of the pain you
see that the improvement is very very
minor but this is called cut
catastrophism okay
the meaning is how the patient see his
pain what do you think about this pain
okay
I know that there is a lot of Israelis
here we call it the effector Paulo knee
how much you complain about your pain
and you see that there is a huge
improvement of how the patient see oh
what is the concept of the pain in the
beginning and what is the concept of the
pain there in the end there is a huge
improvement and I will give you one
example this improvement changing
something this is critical is changing
the quality of life I will give you one
example one patient that I know from
this questionnaire 20 years old patient
did suffering from neuropathic pain in
his back his living is in the basement
of his parents he's not working almost
not getting out of his bed he's putting
a earphones and and earrings earphones
hearing earphones and in here music most
of the dasie music
he said that it's reducing his pain very
loud music he stopped working he is high
depression taking medicine for
depression and he starting to take
cannabis the cannabis improved a little
bit the pain
but his improve his sleep disorder
reduce the depression he stopped taking
the medicine for the depression he
starting eating better he starting
feeling better he's starting to go to
work again he started to have money
he's starting to go out with his friend
he met a girl in the pub he became his
boyfriend they moved to to live together
and now that two weeks before the
wedding so he's still very happy is two
weeks before the wedding it's before
getting down the table but think about
it seriously
the huge change of the quality of life
this guy before that in his bed
depression not working now live with his
girlfriend full-time job have a normal
life and now you ask him what you think
about his pain sorry what oops no good
just a moment this is the next talk in
Arizona and if you ask him what you
think about his pain in the beginning it
was he horrible but it's improved he
don't care about the pain anymore
this is cannabis and this is a different
road if you ask me how I see it in five
years
these are 85% of the patient in Israel
patient that get cannabis for improving
the quality of life this obtain patient
Lisa
dissipation with PTSD dissipation that
getting chemotherapy and getting
cannabis to improve all the effect the
side effect of the chemotherapy these
are the majority of the patient so if
you ask me how is it in five years there
is two road there will be cannabis as a
medicine in the pharmacist but there
will be two types of medicine they will
be very accurate may be synthetic maybe
not synthetic but very accurate three
molecules in
in the bottle measured exactly the
amount milligram per ml that you will
take to treat cancer that you take to
treat epilepsy that you take to treat
insomnia very specific illnesses and
there will be cannabis which much more
holistic the whole extract because we
are the scientists will never be able to
put our finger on all of these because
these three compounds will improve the
appetite and these two is a changing the
sleep disorder and these five is
increasing decreasing the depression and
all together you get something to change
the quality of life all the ripple
cancer patient
it is the patient pain patient we use
probably this cannabis but this is not
saying that we need to stop working on
that we need also here to improve it and
to bring it to the level that it will be
medicine accurate that every time that
you going and buying a bottle it will be
the same the girl we need to improve the
way they grow it this must be accurate
that all the compounds inside will be
the same we will be able to measure I am
able to measure today so will the world
will know how to do that we will know
how to grow it more efficient cheaper
without pesticides that all the time it
will be the same and we can make it also
more accurate and I want to give one
sample what we did occur with the
collaboration with Professor Dan lavitus
we create a nano beads that having
inside of them a whole extract these
nano beads capture a whole extract and
these nano beads release the extract in
slow release
so actually where the whole extract all
the chickens are flavonoid in
cannabinoids but these nano beads now
release all the active compounds
slowly slowly so if we're taking these
nano beads and inject under the skin of
the mice that have epilepsy and we
measure we see that the coup that they
built in two weeks
slowly slowly releasing the cannabis
they can't be new it's Japanese and
flavonoids and we can measure it in the
blood if we look on the seizures we see
that actually the whole extract in the
beads working better than the whole
extract that been giving on the daily
basis to the mice so we're we're giving
it one in two weeks
and here it's months one every day it's
the same extract but this one worked
better because you don't have the peak
of getting and going down and up an hour
down and up in the blood it's the
sustainable amount if we measure the CBD
and other compounds in the blood we see
that in the bitter is much more than
when we're injecting them so this is
just a small example to show you that
even when we stand in the whole extract
we will find a way to make it more
accurate better matches to vipe it
better whatever we need even in that
road to be much more accurate to bring
it to the level that the physician will
trust what is giving will know what is
giving how it's acting the patient we
know it's good to him but we know to go
back and to buy all the time the same
product we don't have it today so I want
to thank my amazing team that did all of
this work this is dr. Shirley where I
usually surely be a bellman they did all
the analysis in the Phaedo cannabinoids
an endocannabinoid dr. lee Rhonda Rhonda
did all the work of the cancer together
with the early
this is the student dr. Gil Levin who's
doing all the neurobiology in the lab
and you see the epilepsy and all my
amazing team thank you very much
[Applause]
questions hello
I had a question about this slide that
you showed that had the red bars and the
blue bars
it appeared that after 120 days on the
blue side you actually saw a greater
amount of catastrophizing I don't know
if that was interpreted correctly and
then my second question is the imaging
that you did was that using an in cell
what was that using just a woman this is
what you asked you so this is improved
in the catastrophe
this is improve oh I see I see okay I
did a large argument with my students I
said improve I want to see it up so even
though the catastrophe oh yeah I missed
seeing that okay improvement I guess
yeah there was no indication there so
improving pain and improving the
catastrophe okay
the other question was what was it the
imaging that you did what was that using
which which equipment yes where many
where thank you side with the
molecular device I forgot the name we
have like three different this one form
the molecular device what kind of
instrument was it my wife said that that
will never will have Alzheimer because I
remember nothing okay you can I will
catch me after I will check for you okay
[Music]
hi over here it's Matt Gordon again I
had a question about you've discovered
uh you've narrowed it down by the
process of elimination and discovered
three cannabinoids that worked as good
as the whole and what happens if you
took that profile that you knew was
killing that type of cancer and you
mixed it with some other oil would that
suddenly change the profile and make it
not kill that cancer anymore it's not
it's not changing the profile but it's
will dilute the specific cannabinoids to
a different amount so you will need to
give more this is first and second its
might be that in the other extract there
will be things that competing with the
receptors and will block it it might be
I never tried it so I don't know to tell
okay III well I didn't try to mix it
with other world that's a common thing
as you know in the United States people
take five or six or twenty strains make
oil and combine it all together to
hopefully hit all the receptors are cure
you know for cancer they take sixty
grams and 90 days of ethanol extract
right Rick Simpson oil and I was just
wondering into me it's remind it remind
me a joke that we telling in Israel that
again I need to go to do a P exam that
how you saying that that yeah that's the
terminology so he's coming and said I
brought all the family check it all
together so
I don't know if it's smart you know yeah
so what do you but you haven't you guys
haven't mixed oils and seen if it was
still effective or in the end if you had
something that cured another cancer like
a completely different compound after
mixing 20 different strains or what have
you it's a good idea I need another 45
students I will work on that okay thank
you we didn't thank you thank you hi hi
I see nothing so I'm just that's okay
nice yeah so for some of the diseases
are complaints that you were talking
about pain and epilepsy those the
medicines that are often prescribed for
those types of things have really bad
side effect profiles destroy organs and
things like that so my question is why
is cannabis a last resort with such a
benign side-effect profile for cannabis
why is cannabis the last choice so it's
- good answer for that first we don't
know that the damage is cannabis is
doing we don't really know we're
assuming it's not doing which is not
really true if you really following on
Rick Simpson oil patient they have a lot
of bleeding in their intestines and
there is damage that cannabis can do and
we we're not we don't know yet okay I
showed in in their publication with
Professor Gilbert Sela a few months ago
that if you taking immunotherapy with
cannabis cannabis is actually blocking
the immunity issue said why not to give
everybody I'm not sure it's it's right
thing second because we're better
medicines in other illnesses sometimes
work a physician need to check is
patient and to choose the best medicine
that's working the best for this patient
it's not always the cannabis and and you
know it's nice in these conferences we
said why not to give but it's the
physician responsibility to choose what
they think is the best for the for this
patient and I hope they are doing that
and unless we will have more data to
know and what were to give in which
patient which will take more time and
I'm quite aligned with the physician on
and there is a lot of I don't know how
to set it in English but this
information and things about cannabis
that caused the physician not to give
them and I'm giving free to do to the
mine so I don't have this problem thank
you hi I was just curious if you'd
identified a molecular target yet for
your 331 b8 compound or if you know
mechanistically how that's working no I
know it's binding trpv1 but I don't know
mechanistically it's binding and the
releasing calcium I don't know exactly I
know that when I'm blocking trpv1 then
it's not binding and whether I'm not
there yet it took me a lot of time to be
able to purify that in a good way and to
have it really purified in my hand
actually it's just a few months and
every time it take me around three weeks
to get it so still there is there is
technical things that takes a lot of
time if I'm summarize what I succeed to
do in the last four years is not the
results is to build the tools to ask the
questions few months ago I think four or
five months ago I sat with my students
said they show results that we reached
the point that we can really start ask
questions and answer that when we are we
have the ability to measure the
endocannabinoids the receptors the Fito
cannabis to analyze them to separate
them before that we didn't have the
tools thank you the dr. Mary Kristen
Walsh Lange all hearts is Hawaii now I
can imagine who is talking yes
so long from the back an interesting
thing happened last year and I don't
know if you've seen it or if you might
be curious about it I have an irregular
heartbeat since youth needed a pacemaker
but this was before we knew I needed
that I'd stopped my beta blocker and it
coincidentally I was with an implant at
cardiac monitor 24-hour monitoring
recorded bottom line is I stopped the
beta blocker so the doctor could see my
rhythm and my rhythm stopped misbehaving
turned out I had simultaneously started
using a dilution of beta Kari offline or
leave about four hundred five hundred
milligrams a day in divided doses and I
realized after two months without a
single episode of arrhythmia that there
might be something going on because I
found one preclinical research on triple
negative breast cancer cells that had
beta-2 adrenergic receptors on them and
they claimed it was an inverse agonist
and I just thought I'd toss that out
there's a softball because we're talking
about the entourage effect if there's a
beta blocker effect with the most common
turkeying beta carry off way maybe we
can start to elucidate this I mean it
doesn't distinctly have the anti-cancer
aspect though there is some of that in
cancer research it's more about just
kind of clarifying this when it's a
molecule we're seeing an uptick in use
you have any knowledge on the beta carry
opportunities in beta blocking yeah I
think I will answer that generally first
of all I I didn't I didn't work
specifically with better kirvline like I
never separated from the others and in
general I think what we will see in the
next few years that there were few
indication will will disappear and few
things that will appear and I think hard
diseases and affecting on heart and
other things like that
would be major because the heart is full
of endocannabinoids and I know it's been
affected by cannabis and by terpenes and
by the flavonoids flubbing will be a and
B being shown to affect them so I'm
quite sure it's will be a big I was just
curious because they distinctly
confirmed in the preclinical research
about the beta-2 adrenergic receptor it
was an inverse agonist and that's the
only note so I just thought I think yeah
I much for all your work thank you
hey Danny hey Murr just play boys okay
you know it's me just for my boys right
quick quick question is the standard
available for the 3 3 1 1 8 B 4
ain't no well when are you gonna make it
available so that we can all test for it
I'm working on that literally I send my
you know two of my workers last week to
the states to examine which best
equipment to buy for that in order to
start to purify it in a better way
because now I'm pure fighting then using
it to my research but it takes a lot of
time and a lot of efforts I need to do
more efficiently I hope to have it and
you know I'll be waiting and we're
creating notice to give it away ok we'll
be ready okay hey I'm dr. Prendergast
primary care physician from Jamaica we
have lots of cannabis there as you know
but we have very little puree purified
[Music]
product that we can use I have found in
my practice that the best one that I can
use is a three to one ratio which is
three cvd to one THC which is the most
useful however being limited to only a
few
right now legislatively is do what would
you say
CBD alone for I use it for inflammatory
conditions I use the CBD CBN which is
also available
those are the only two that are
available legally and so broad-spectrum
what do you think about a three-to-one
CBD to THC so first of all I think you
need to understand that I'm not a
physician and I don't know what is good
for patient or not I know to look for
mechanism to answer a big question to
look on the wide the aspects I don't
know to treat patient unfortunately and
I don't know the answer but basically I
would say in the cannabis field to say I
found three to one is the best ratio and
will ask to make me sleepy o to make me
awake
what do you mean the best one the best
one for what to every indication on
every disease no it's different like
inflam inflammatory conditions
autoimmune conditions I found that to be
C is CBD three CVD to one THC on
activated of course and I found that to
work very well with the limited scope so
we like the broad spectrum so so you're
taking a specific strain and it's worked
for you three two one and I learned from
cooking what is work for you don't
change but but we work on multiple
sclerosis multiple clones it's kind of
inflammation
I have strained that causing the disease
to be so severe that they might not
survive and I have strange that the
mines are almost curing from the disease
with the same ratio of CBD and THC so I
don't know to answer and save identity
you asking the wrong person I believe
that it's much more much more
complicated than working with ability T
it's known that CBD and then the Rafa
showed in the morning in the GTHA
patient CBD alone can reduce the
activity of the immune system right but
in the ratio between delta T CI
okay thanks thanks for your talk there
highlights every year I see patients and
recommend to patients and when I started
after coming to one of these conferences
I I give my patients recommendation I
say get a whole plant extract in this
approximate ratio and what came back to
me is there's no such thing in the
dispensaries as a whole plant extract
its combinations of different
cannabinoids and different ratios so now
I'm doing micro dosing with one to one
and I'm just curious and changing the
ratios and so forth
I'm just curious do you see any value to
using a whole plant and having the
patient make their own extract from a
whole plant in order to get more
likelihood of the enter entourage effect
where do I stick with oils and micro
dose sublingually which is kind of what
I do because I take care of a lot of
elderly patients and I can't and none of
them were interested in inhalational
therapy so in general again I don't know
I'm not a physician are asking about
patients just asking yeah I don't know I
think you know it's a lottery you're
taking a very complicated can activate
once can help not can not help and I
understand that outside in the field
with the patient we need to take a
decision and and I admire the physician
that doing that and I think they're
doing very right and in order to to help
the patient with what we have but I will
say something else that might be the
audience here won't like I don't believe
in that the patient need to take a
decision for himself and make the de
medicine for himself I never saw a
person getting to emergency room said to
the doctor leave it I know what to do
you know and and and I didn't see any
patient
lying down with no way things to his
veins and decide what to put inside I
don't believe in in self curing I
believe in physicians that learn a lot
of years and no better to take decision
not always right not always good a lot
of mistakes but better than the day that
the patient will take for his self
decision so I believe that even though
you might lose pupil matters it's still
need to be in your hands but it's
totally my opinion here and not you know
I can't see if there is me I got it I
got um the blue me again the
endocannabinoid system is it taught in
Israeli medical schools because it's not
taught in most medical schools here so
it's a complicate an sir we have in
Israel already courses for physicians
nurses pharmacists there is more than I
think eight courses part of them is part
of the Ministry of Health out of them is
they through the universities itself in
the main courses for medical school I'm
not sure we have I think you'll see
where you have started right so your
system which will speak here later from
a University of Jerusalem started
of course like that in for the medical
student there it's coming more and more
so in my university in a in the Technion
we are talking about to start from next
year in the jerusalem universities they
started already so it's there but we
have Ravi McCollum it's not fair you
know
it's not fair no nobody can argue with
us it is important we have the gold foil
thank you very much
[Applause]