[Music]
welcome to the camed Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I am the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and proud member of
the team that puts on the camed
conference all right just a few
reminders before I introduced this
episode's guest if you are listening to
this episode on the day it's released
then I'd like to remind you that the
abstract submission deadline for K 24 is
November
18th so if you have any new or novel
research related to cannabis science
medicine cultivation or safety testing
we want to hear from you I put a link in
the show description where you can can
learn more about the abstract submission
process and submit your abstract good
luck also our early bird deadline for
Kim at 24 ticket packages is December
1st which is a little more than 2 weeks
away if you are planning to join us in
Marco Island this may then now is the
best time to register you will save
$300 on our full Summit package which
includes access to the medical practicum
industry workshops oral presentations
poster presentations networking events
meals and a three night stay at the GW
Marriot Marco Island resort with all the
associated amenities so head over to CET
events.com now to register and I hope to
see you in Florida this
may Our Guest this episode is Dr llo
mechler Dr mechler is the chief medical
officer at the dent neurologic Institute
the largest outpatient NeuroScience
Center in the United States Dr metcher
is the director of the dent cannabis
Clinic which has more than 15,000
patients certified through the NYS MMJ
program and continues to grow each
day Dr metula has published some of the
first major retrospective research
trials on medical marijuana and
headaches and other neurologic disorders
and lectures both nationally and
internationally and is a recognized
leader in the fields of neuroimaging
headache medicine
neurooncology and medical cannabis Dr
metch is also a member of the CED 24
Advisory
Board during our conversation we discuss
how the dent Institute is uniquely
positioned to study medical cannabis for
a variety of conditions results from
recent studies conducted at the dent
cannabis Clinic the challenges of
studying medical cannabis and how a
proposed rescheduling could help and the
ongoing struggle to convince fellow
clinicians and medical associations that
medical cannabis is legitimate before we
get to my conversation with Dr mler I'd
like to thank this episode sponsor the
dent
Institute with more than 300,000 patient
visits per year the dent neurologic
Institute ranks amongst the largest
Neuroscience centers in North America
its 24 subsp specialty clinics often
treat the most challenging neurologic
conditions including but not limited to
migraine chronic pain ALS Ms Parkinson's
dementia and
neurooncology with their mission of
advancing Neuroscience the dent
Institute established a cannabis clinic
in 2016 to Aid in the treatment of these
conditions seen throughout the Institute
to learn more visit Dent institute.com
all right and without any further Ado
please enjoy my conversation with Dr llo
[Music]
mechler good morning Dr Dr mechler
thanks so much for joining us on the
podcast
my pleasure it's good to be here
excellent and first off I want to thank
you for joining us on the cmed 24
Advisory board for this year we were
very fortunate to have you as a
presenter at CED 23 and folks can check
out the video um in our caned archive I
think I might be referencing it a few
times throughout the conversation uh we
were fortunate to have you there and
have Dent the dent Institute as a
sponsor for the medical practicum I
thought it was a great addition to the
event and we're excited to have you guys
is involved again for for next year in a
bigger way yeah it was a real pleasure
being there and meeting uh colleagues
and uh specialists in this field that
was really eye openening for me in many
ways so I really um honored and it's
going to be a great pleasure to be there
uh for the next meeting so thank you
again for the invitation absolutely and
I'm excited to catch up with you today
about all the the research and clinical
studies that you and the team are doing
at the dent Institute because it's
substantial um I think and it's
important because those who are hesitant
or maybe oppose some of the legitimacy
of cannabis medicine will typically
point to a lack of evidence so it's
vital that institutions like yours are
are doing the work as they say so that
might be a good place to start and if
you would kind of tell the audience a
bit about the dent Institute and and
your role there so the dent Institute
was founded in 1960s so before you ask
it wasn't founded by me because that
would make me too old but I've been here
close to 38 years I'm the chief medical
officer or medical director of The
Institute we are the largest private
Neuroscience Institute in the United
States by far just to give you a feel we
see about 1300 patients every day in the
field of Neurology uh we're a private
Institute uh but we
uh work with pharmacological or
pharmaceutical companies we have close
to a 100 studies looking at different uh
drugs in the field of Neurology uh
everything from Alzheimer's Ms headache
uh stroke uh movement disorders um so
we're very active in our research
component and the pharmaceutical world
knows about us seeing that we're the
largest Neuroscience Institute uh you
know I like to say that in today's world
research is done in academic centers and
people think that the private sector uh
doesn't do academic work we're just the
opposite we're in the private sector so
we're a private Institute run by
physicians but we do a tremendous amount
of research and the farmer world knows
that so that's one of the reasons uh it
was a little bit complicated when I got
got into uh cannabis and you used a word
called uh
legitimate my whole thing is legitimacy
I'm a full professor at the University
and the chief
of of
neuron at a at a cancer hospital called
Roswell Park and the den Institute is
our private Neurological Institute where
uh in every year we see over 310,000
patients and uh and uh we uh educate in
fact in my in my room right now I have
uh four or five students from all parts
of the world listening uh so we very uh
focused on Research education and taking
care of a lot of people with high
quality care that's what we're about
excellent now when did the dent
Institute get involved in cannabis and
was that sort of a logical fit for you
guys illogical it was not logical in any
way shape or form um only reason we got
into it because we take care of so many
people so when cannabis was was made
legal in New York State uh about six
seven years ago um we were getting phone
calls 500 a day I said no I have no idea
about cannabis I've you know I'm not a
smoker I'm not a user I'm not I don't
even use alcohol which makes me
tremendously boring so the the point is
the next day was another 500 phone calls
the third day another 500 phone calls
now if you were on the business you can
imagine how much money and energy that
takes to answer those phone calls so has
said look let's get into cannabis let's
make a clinic let's start learning about
it so because we're you we're um our
business model is so private and not
institutional we're able to set up a
cannabis clinic and for the next six
seven years it took that amount of time
to understand the use of cannabis in
patients with neurological symptoms
including pain and you know you're
self-taught I mean where are you going
to go medical school they don't teach it
where so so the only good places to
learn is at these conferences and so I
was honored to be you know at these
conferences everywhere from Tel Aviv to
uh Malta Europe and the United States so
I've been part of this and I've been
learning as we go and now I feel I have
an expertise because how do Physicians
understand medicine they have to see
patients so right now in the clinic we
have over 13,000 patients on cannabis
for medical reasons
so I don't deal with recreational and I
need to emphasize that I'm purely on the
medical side I'm purely there to
legitimize this whole
process excellent so was there a was
there a light bulb moment or was there a
specific um piece of evidence that you
saw that you know kind of clicked in
your head that you know there's
something to this cannabis well as
you're seeing
patients as they come up to you and they
throw their arms around you and hug you
that's the changing moment that you
found something where patients said you
changed my life you got me off
opioids my quality of life has improved
and With Tears in their eyes they're
hugging you and saying thank you that's
the moment that every physician wants in
their life and I got that in cannabis
interesting enough uh you know I deal
with bad diseases I deal with uh you
know brain cancer it's one of my
specialties and it's it's you know you
never get that moment so yeah it changed
the way I practice uh I still do you
know brain tumor research and treatment
I do uh other things in neurology but
cannabis has been an eye openening
moment where you can change the quality
of life of individuals by understanding
how cannabis works on human
beings great and so now how did the
studies work at the dent Institute how
do patients become enrolled and how how
does that process sort of start so I I
don't have to teach the audience how
difficult it is to do research in
cannabis so in the same time I you know
we have every pharmaceutical company
come in here we do phase one phase two
phase three studies I have a whole
research team uh uh looking and putting
patients on board for you know these
drugs that we are using for example in
migraines um so cannabis is a whole
different story where do you get the
support who pays for that research what
company so I realized very fast if I
want to do research in cannabis it has
to be self-funded init initially we have
to do our own research so it that
perspective of being federal legal being
a schedule one drug made it very
difficult to do prospective research so
I'm I'm sitting and I say well let's get
a um schedule one license then I
realized back then if I do get a
schedule one one license who could um
who could tell me that the Cannabis that
I'm using is of high quality uh which is
as we all know initially came from
Mississippi so so uh I decided initially
not to get the schedule one license I
decided to uh uh do the following uh I
said the initial studies of the
literature were small studies 25
patients 30 patients and the criticism
from the medical community that these
are small studies and studies that that
uh are not academically
worthwhile so I said well that's
interesting um uh how about if we do
retrospective large population studies
and that may open up the eyes for
clinicians and academic physicians in
that okay we're not talking about 25
patients we're talk about hundreds of
patients and look at them
retrospectively so this so it's popular
populationbased research but larger
numbers than what we've had in the past
and so I've had the opportunity to do
that in multiple uh Subs Specialties of
Neurology everything from Ms Parkin
headaches for example uh and dementia uh
we are looking also at other diseases
like autism periphal neuropathy trial
neuralgia so I'm going down the list of
neurological disorders and then getting
large populations and looking at uh
efficacy and side effect profile which
is very important ratios and dos mage of
what I'm using and uh I put that all in
a data bank that I have of now you know
13,000 patients so so it's been very
interesting to do do this type of
research and as you know hopefully if
this becomes a schedule three drug maybe
things will change for clinicians like
myself yeah no I and I definitely want
to to touch on that but before we do so
when you say retrospectively so is that
you're putting patients on uh you know
a course of cannabis medicine and then
sort of checking in with them after a
defined period of time and saying you
know how has it helped you yes exactly
so how do you treat somebody so I'm I'm
looking at patients are not gonna get do
not want to get high the 75 year old
female with rheumatoid arthritis who
doesn't smoke doesn't drink doesn't do
marijuana uh does not want to get high
this is where I have a problem with the
Cannabis world because a lot of uh uh
people think oh all patients just want
to get high that's not true yeah I look
at a different population these patients
want to be uh cautious they do not want
to get high with their grandchildren um
uh they want to be cognitively sharp but
they want pain relief they want symptom
relief uh so so as I'm seeing these
patients I'm realizing which ratios may
work in which age group uh and I have to
be also very knowled ible about what
medications they're taking I mean many
of these patients are at 75 years old
they're on 15 different drugs so you
just and they may have asthma so you
don't want to give them a vape if they
have asthma and on anti-coagulation so
there's things you need to know so
that's why I think it's important that
in medical cannabis programs you have a
physician or a physician extender who is
very knowledgeable in how to use these
medications treat these patients uh
because and then very important come
back in a relatively short period of
time so you can adjust the dosage you
can adjust the titration schedule you
can adjust the ratio depending on the
side effects and symptoms and efficacy
rates so you have to keep an eye on
these patients you know in in medical
marijuana programs a lot of people are
seeing that I'll see you back in one
year I mean patients don't want that
they want to be nurtured through their
through this experience see somebody
who's knowledgeable and then they can
see him follow up regularly and when
they get stable then you can see them
later in six months or 12 months right
and so where do you Source the medicine
are you just sort of giving
recommendations and then they have to go
to the dispensary and sort of get the
medicine themselves yeah in New York
state strict rules so if as a physician
I can't be involved in the business of
cannabis so I don't have a dispensary
here for medical marijuana um you know
there are CBD products that I got
involved with because that's a whole
different world uh you know CBD products
less than .3% THC but in medical
marijana uh we're an Institute so we we
didn't have a dispensary in The
Institute in my area we have three of
them and the good news is that after
some initial hurdles initial
difficulties uh they realized that
whatever I want I want my patients to
get that they can't change it at the
dispensary example would be initially a
patient went there uh I gave a tincture
uh it was switched to a vape the patient
ended up in the emergency room because
the the butt tender or whoever worked at
dispensary did not know that the patient
had asthma and so these are just one
example but I work very well with the
dispensaries they they respect my
knowledge and and and and they
understand that I'm adamant if I uh uh
certify somebody for a ratio or dosage
that's what they're going to get get MH
great
um so you mentioned before that when the
medical marijuana program came on there
was a ton of interest and you were
getting a lot of phone calls how has
that interest changed uh over the years
is it is it more than ever now so yeah
New York State's a big state right we
have over 20 million people at in the
New York State program I myself see 10%
of all patients in New York state and
let's include you know New York City
Long Island and so on so we see a lot of
patients and most of them in regionally
some are long distance but they have to
be within New York State they can't come
from Florida because you need a New York
state license uh so so uh the program is
a little bit rigid it's very expensive
but the rigidity of the program meaning
everything has to be tested has helped
me because I know what my patients are
getting uh
it's important me to understand because
when you buy things off the street you
have no idea and you know the literature
has shown that cannabis off the streets
has a high incidence of contaminants
everything from heavy metals everything
from bacteria fungus uh pesticides
insecticides so it's good to know my
patients are getting something that is
uh tested
often hence the expense is higher which
is an issue in most medical marijuana
programs so uh uh I'm not sure if I
answered your question I went on a
monologue which I do some sometimes but
uh you know the good thing about the uh
program is that I like to fact that it's
strict um but oh you I thank you you
asked a question about drop off uh so as
you know New York State went for medical
now it's recreational uh has there been
a drop off
uh I would say
yes uh I think people feel there's a
it's complicated because in New York
state we have a lot of reservations in
Western New York and under reservation
being Sovereign land they actually have
their own cannabis and sell
it unfortunately uh what I've seen is
that what they're getting is not always
what was uh advertised uh and it's a lot
of contaminants and some of those
contaminants I've had positive
LSD with people on cannabis who have
side effects and hallucinator and
paranoid
reactions so it is changing I I've asked
New York state to protect the medical
marijuana program but as you may know uh
Ben when recreational marijuana comes
into a state yeah usually it affects the
medical marijuana program so I think my
numbers are down but let's be fair now
I'm seeing patients who really really
are interested in medical marijuana and
don't want it for recreational reasons
right yeah and do you think it's a case
that some people think that they can
sort of self-medicate you know just go
through the the recreational program
rather than kind of get a physician
involved yeah I think that's true I
think the younger patients think that
yeah I think the younger you are the
more likely that you don't you don't go
to a doctor but you know we have a very
strong um uh presence as an Institute
and as a physician I've been in this
community for over 35 years and so they
kind of know your reputation as a
cannabis doctor and so so I think a lot
of patients uh come to me uh and are uh
comfortable with the knowledge set I
will also say one thing that I'm very
different to anybody else so when I
started a program I said I'm not I'm
going to legitimize this and I said how
do I legitimize a program where people
are making a business out of it let's be
fair a lot of doctors got involved for
the sake of seeing a lot of patients in
a short period of time and billing them
$250 cash sometimes 350 not including a
urine test which is another additional
money some people were paying
$800 on an office visit so I said what
if I don't accept their cash and that's
unheard of what do you mean you don't
accept people's cash who doesn't accept
cash cash well if you accept cash that
to me is is not a legitimate process in
medicine so I said I'm not going to
accept any cash from any patient who
comes to me for cannabis so I talked to
the CEOs of hosp of insurance companies
health insurance some companies uh you
know I talked to them I said look I'm
gon to see your patient but I want to be
the patient's doctor not just giving him
certifying for cannabis because they got
back pain so I became the treating
physician which means that I I dictated
a three-page note for example if they
had multiple sclerosis and they have not
had an MRI in 10 years then maybe I'll
do an MRI or if they have back pain I
like to know why they have back pain so
I wanted to go to the ideology of the
symptom um if they had trial neuralgia
which is pain in the face uh I like to
know what medications you're on maybe I
can adjust it so I want to become the
treating physician for that reason I
build the insurance company and all of
them said yes and I've not had a problem
in six years so when a patient comes to
me they'll have to pay cash at the
dispensary but they don't pay cash with
me I'll accept what whatever their
insurance pays and I think you may
understand a lot of these individuals
don't have good insurance because
they've been disabled they're not
working because of low back pain or
chronic pain so a lot of what insurance
pays is not a lot but it really doesn't
matter at the end of the day I serve
13,000 patients I think we have a very
strong reputation and to me this is
legitimizing the whole process yeah I
would say so it's let me just if
somebody accepts cash as a physician I'm
not critical of that uh if they do a
good job and not just certify the
patient and Say Goodbye if they really
keep an eye on them then yeah I don't
have a problem with somebody accepting
cash but at my Institute uh I said no to
that yeah no I think you're right I
think there definitely was a cottage
industry that that popped up of just you
know writing writing recommendations and
being done with it so yeah I know of
people flying in from a different state
and going to a strip mall renting a
office for one day and flying back the
same
day I've heard stories too of of doctors
setting up booths at conferences and you
know you just you just walk up and
they'll write the recommendation for you
and just keep keep the line moving and
then initially I know sure if it's still
being done initially then then these 1
1800 numbers these phone numbers that
you don't even have to see the doctor
all you have to do is call phone number
get certified now I don't I don't
understand that's such a money money
Focus way to take care of human beings
um you know I I really feel strongly
that and maybe that's because I I you
know I'm a professor of Neurology
oncology at a a cancer hospital and here
at the Institute
that I really think that if we take care
of people uh we should do it in a
ethical way with empathy uh I don't mind
if there's money at the tail end of this
for Physicians or institutes but I think
we can't lose the fact that patients
want to be taken care of uh again in
medical marijuana programs not
recreational so I I don't believe in
calling a number and getting certified
and then see you one year and I I and I
accept $250 from you to me that's not
taking care of human beings that's a
business yeah no and I think part of the
problem too is is something that you
touched on earlier is that most medical
professionals are not educated on
cannabis so you know a lot of these
patients who who want access to cannabis
can't really go to their primary care
doctor and have a an intelligent
conversation about it because you know
they're just not they're not educated
and you I was one of those six seven
years ago I I'll admit I'm the first one
to admit that this was a process this is
a road that I had to go down and
understand and go to conferences and
read books and uh and and it really has
opened up my eyes and understanding why
we're in the situation we are today
because then comes the politics of
cannabis the social impact on cannabis
and and uh you know the and and to
understand where why we are here today
you need to go back historically
understand the history of Catabus not
the one about 2,000 years ago or a
thousand years ago or oi in Kolkata
India in the 19th century I'm talking
about the 20th century history and how
we are here today everything from uh
from uh Nixon and the why we are in the
situation we are today you need to
understand that and then you get a B
comfort with cannabis yeah absolutely
all right so let's transition to some of
the research that that uh your team is
doing I know that um you might have some
newly published research uh into a
couple different conditions yes so so
there's two type of research what is the
retrospective retrospective large
population studies in specific
neurological disorders I think what we
published recently was that migraine uh
thisan chronic migraines and headaches
which is really I think very impactful
uh in that treatment of that population
we have done a lot of uh recent phenetic
studies interesting uh looking at CBD
products and how uh what the Pharma
kinetics are of different CBD products
uh in healthy individuals that that's
what I would call Pharma kinetic studies
um and and we've done several of those
recently um what has recently published
is two publication I think one has been
accepted I think the other one has just
been accepted one is multiple sceris
well without you know educating people
on Ms we have one of the highest MS
populations in the United States if not
the world in Western New York so Ms is
you know we have thousands of Ms
patients so we see we saw a population
of Ms so we did publish an article of
multiple sclerosis and use of cannabis
which is relatively interesting because
uh uh quoting from the results that
about 72% of patients pain was
alleviated or improved statistically
significantly then they have spasticity
that improved and the opo use was
decreased by a significant amount of
patients either completely or partially
but statistically different so we have
that article and I have a very strong uh
neuropharmacological division of the
dent run by excellent uh uh Farm
doctors such as Dr Ranka Dr aladine and
really uh we're very fortunate to have
that team work with us hand in hand the
other article that we recently published
is medical treatment of Parkinson's
disease which we all see Parkinson's
disease in that group 56% of patients
either stopped their opioids or
decreased it significantly in that case
we saw about 69 patients about 87% of
patients said their quality of life has
improved on cannabis now I can quote so
that that article is called medical
cannabis in the treatment of Parkinson's
disease the lead author is uh is Tracy
abdine who is our one of our farm uh
pharmaceutical doctors uh and um and
that's an interesting article to read so
here we have retrospective looking at
studies looking at quality of life side
effect profile for example in the MS
study the main side effect was fatigue
11% now let me tell one of the main
symptoms of MS is fatigue right so it's
hard to say that the 11% side effect was
actually from the drug or not because as
I mentioned it's a common side effect so
so these are out in the literature um we
have a lot of abstracts we present at
the American Academy of Neurology in
fact uh for the first time ever I ran a
course uh on cannabis and I'm proud to
say not a hundred people showed up sever
several hundred people showed up for the
Symposium at the American Academy
neurology which is probably one of the
more
conservative uh medical Societies in the
United States I always say
that in the business of cannabis you
don't have to win over patients you've
won them over you don't have to win over
most of the politicians because most of
the politicians you won them over it's
the medical society you have won over
you've won the doctors over the doctors
individually believe in it most of them
but the medical societies that control
the behavior of doctors you haven't won
them over have you you go to their
websites and they say yeah we think
there may be something there but we
don't want you to use it we should we
want more research that's what you hear
across the board yep so how do you win
the medical society's over well I ran a
symposium uh at the American Academy
neurology which is very well received I
often will lecture there and give U
abstracts uh even at the American
Headache Society or other s neurological
societies so uh and I go to Europe quite
often to lecture at the European
societies which was
surprisingly is probably a little bit
more rigid than the American Societies
in many ways so you ask me what ongoing
studies well we looking at ALS ALS most
people know the term lugaric disease uh
we're looking at retrospective study I
can tell you some preliminary findings
so far we see about 79% Improvement in
quality of life uh then we looked at
dementia which is you huge why we're an
aging population dementia is going to be
a major issue for us as the as our
lifespan increases as we get older uh
it's a major issue uh so we looked at
dementia we saw a 65% Improvement in
quality of life I'm not going to get
into the specifics because it hasn't
been published but we're very op open uh
optimistic about that study we have a
study looking epilepsy we know that a
CBD product epd Olo has been approved by
the FDA via GW Pharmaceuticals uh for
the treatment of lenx Gat and Draves and
even tubers so these are three rare
types of seizures and epidox has been
approved uh we looked at our population
when we added cannabis we saw a 70% 71%
reduction in seizure control again
retrospective not perspective not
something that would be accepted as a
FDA approved uh drug we also looked at
anxiety and insomnia uh we saw a 50%
reduction in insomnia and 45% reduction
in anxiety and we also looking at autism
with one of my colleagues Dr mcvg who's
a pediatric neur
neologist so we yeah we're very much
interested in putting the research in uh
that's what we're doing now uh and and
and and educating Physicians educating
the population educating the business
world yeah and now you and you mentioned
that sort of the the medical
associations are the the ones you need
to win over H how is that fight
going um it's like fighting Mike Tyson
yeah um not doing well um you know I
always say that if you can't change him
from the outside change him from the
inside right join them I did and I it's
very difficult because a they always
back off and say where is the research
where is the prospective randomized
research and we don't have it is it our
fault that a schedule one drug and FDA
legal no it
isn't so I understand academically what
they say but there's a lot of drugs we
use if you look at them these old
drugs there weren't randomized studies
and we still use them but understanding
and being respectful for they're coming
from yes we have to do the randomize
studies yes uh uh the Cannabis doctors
have to be legitimate they have to come
with uh with um some legitimacy in their
credentials and understand that you're
fting an uphill battle that you will win
one day
uh we you know this is going to be
one and maybe descheduling it to
schedule three is the first step to do
randomized studies then you can change
the perspective of the academic medical
Societies in this
country around the world not just United
States but United States when it takes a
lead on anything then most of the other
countries will step up and and and uh
Contin and continue what the American
results are so I'm hopefully getting
these studies done here
um I'm looking for sponsors which is
very difficult who's going to sponsor my
study uh cannabis business is not hot
anymore you know the the stocks are down
there there's a shortage of money uh and
who's going to throw millions of dollars
but it's not thousands millions of
dollars for a randomized study looking
at uh Placebo versus different ratios of
cannabis and migraine for example
beautiful study it's going to work but
who's going to sponsor that will the
government sponsor that I can't get
Federal money on a federally legally
company I can't get it from the NIH uh
it has to be done state within the state
and it has to be done by a company that
will support that uh you know in many
ways we should uh join forces everybody
who works with cannabis every business
puts in into a uh a bank and from that
bank have a committee looking at good
scientific research and then sponsoring
it from that uh uh bank and then then
physician groups can then publish these
things perspectively I think that's a
possibility in the future something we
can talk about at our meetings yeah I
know and because I was going to bring
that up that you know these cannabis
companies they're not going to fund the
research partially because they're not
going to have like a proprietary drug
either right I mean it's it's a natural
medicine so if you publish that research
then you're actually kind of emboldening
your competitors as well and not just
you that's right so you have to look at
the big picture and can't look at your
own interest which is very difficult
today because uh because the fact that
companies are not doing well and they're
looking at the bottom lines so to
support research that's going to be if
it's positive if it's good it's going to
be good for everybody so you got to look
at the big picture uh and hopefully one
day we'll see that so you mentioned
rescheduling and I think that's
something that we're all sort of
watching and hopeful for that there
we'll see some movement there but so say
um it does get rescheduled I think what
schedule three is one of is what's on
the table here how would things change
for you if if that were to
happen
well it's gonna change a lot of things
um so schedule three is like
cabine um and I think T Cod number three
is in schedule three also so first of
all still going to be federally legal
illegal but locally I could do a
prospective study looking at cannabis in
the treatment of I'm going to give you
an example I do have a protocol which I
wrote for this for chronic migraine
migraines defined by morning than 15
headaches a month uh and I can look at a
uh Placebo or a 20 to1 1:1 ratio and 5
10 15 20 milligrams that's a perspective
respective study there'll be several
arms I could do that you can ask me
who's going to fund that I'm going to
say right now nobody who's gonna fund it
we're gonna fund it uh I have a
benevolent um uh uh family Dent family
Dent was a uh philanthropist back in the
60s who by the way had Parkinson's dis
he started Institute in
1963 and and there is a family
non-for-profit Family Foundation that
supports research within the Institute
and they by the way for the
last six seven years have unequivocally
supported my research in cannabis and
that and that's and that has given me
the opportunity to publish to put us on
the map they still support but we're not
talk about Millions we're talk about
significant amount but they do support
us so yeah I'm going to get some seed
money from them to
support a study if if I can do that if
it becomes a schedule three drug and
then I can publish that article
prospectively randomized
study part of the money from seed money
from the dent Family Foundation part of
the money through the dent cannabis
Clinic we you know we'll readjust money
to put it in research uh so instead of
putting it in our pockets we'll put it
in research self-funded if you want to
use the term and then we can publish
that once we publish that I could show
it to the insurance companies I can show
it to the medical societies and and then
let them critique it and you know one of
the things is one of the problems I
think you may understand is cannabis
medical marijuana or medical cannabis
programs are too expensive for patients
yeah now I did it a way about I did a
way you don't have to pay me cash that's
a positive for the patient right but
they have to pay in cash and some of
these patients are paying $800 a month
they can't afford it and let me be
honest with you in the medical marijuana
program most of the people can't afford
it and because they can't afford it and
the insurance companies throw their arms
up and say you know we're sympathetic we
know that if you put somebody on medical
marijuana they'll tell take less opioids
they'll take less Xanax they'll take
less sleeping pills they'll take less uh
anti-inflammatories so it's good for the
insurance company
but they fall back on the fact no
research yeah so if I have a prospective
study the first thing I'm going to do is
present it to every CEO of every
insurance companies because let's pay
for this because a I save you money I
keep patients out of emergency rooms
they have less testing because their
quality of life have improved and
they're L using less drug so that's the
first thing I'll do so that may change
something uh at that level then the
medical societies will look at it
critique it
uh it'll be published in uh in
peerreview journals which is very
important and maybe we start moving at
the medical society level uh so I'm
optimistic that for me it's going to be
fine it's going to be a step in the
right direction I'm not sure if it's
going to help the business of cannabis
because that's still federally legal
there's still taxation
issues um um banking issues as you all
know and I don't get involved in that I
just read what I read so but in my
perspective I think it's a positive
move yeah so will insurance companies
they will well I mean there's a lot that
goes into it but be it being a schedule
three drug would not you know preclude
them from from covering
it it could be a schedule three drug but
it'll but anything you use it for it's
off label because it's off label because
it's not not been approved in that
disease for example uh what disease say
migraine that's makes it easy 36 million
migr in this country 36 or 700,000
patients in the United States with FS
yeah that's a lot of
patience will they approve it they won't
because show me the research right right
right how can I prove a drug off label
that there's no science that shows it
works then you go testimonials well I
have patients who can't live without it
that doesn't count it doesn't
testimonials don't
count randomized phase two phase three
studies do count yeah so that's what
we'll have to do and we'll do it yeah
and then would it come down to that they
would approve a
certain uh formulation or a certain
product or could it be as as broad as
cannabis so so that's that's a that's
another problem you yeah Ben you open up
a can of worms because that's the
criticism of a plant it's it can't can't
patent it and it what that what we're
dealing with is never sativa or Inda
they're all hybrids right yeah and when
you do a study how rigid and strict is
the use of Catabus and what are you
using actually well that's one of the
advantages of New York State because our
patients know exactly what's in it I
know what's in it I know what the ratio
is so I'm so you can't do it with
recreational it has to be regulated
cannabis coming from probably one
facility that's tested regularly each
batch and look at that it won't be easy
it won't be
easy but it's as but it'll be a step in
the right direction absolutely
absolutely yeah I think we're all we're
all hopeful that that's um that's what's
going to happen but um remains to be
seen um and sure go ahead no I was
saying one of the problem is that a lot
of smart doctors a lot of smart
researchers are working at the best
places in the country academic centers
that are FDA funded by research so there
have a fear of doing cannabis research
by having their other research being
pulled so look there's a lot smarter
people around the country at Duke and
John's Hopkins at Mass General who I
know
personally uh who could do the research
uh but
one of my advantages that that Institute
that's behind me is a private
Institute and I don't have a CEO of a
hospital I don't have a dean of a
university saying yes or no if we think
it could work we'll do it in in a
legitimate process but we can do the
research uh and but in the United States
most of the high quality research is
done at academic centers that
unfortunately some times they're they're
they're unable to do it because of uh
fear and political reasons yeah yeah
absolutely all right Dr Mel I definitely
want to be mindful of your time um and
you're you're kind enough to come on
here um but before I let you go I want
to give you an opportunity to share with
the audience any additional resources or
research I know that you you mentioned
some studies some papers and I'll
definitely put those links in the show
description so people can uh read more
and learn more so if there's other
resources sort of like that that I could
include uh please let me know and also
um any other other plugs for the dent
Institute and yourself um now is the
time yeah we're very happy to see all
patients for all neurological disorders
including cannabis you have a lot of
good people in this country doing
excellent research uh I always quote
Ethan Russo I think he has done
extremely work I recently I had Dustin
surle coming into my office oh great and
he he G he was kind enough to give me
his book which I've been reading which I
think is excellent reading so if you
like to read Dustin cac's book I think
it's on cannabis it is really a
phenomenal book and he's called the
Healer and I understand why meeting him
so we have a lot of good people in this
field I think what you need to do is is
just bring him together uh uh brainstorm
what's our next steps at that level uh
so so I will continue my you know uh
large population retrospective studies I
think uh I have 800 patients on cannabis
who have a neuropathy and people in the
audience many of them have neuropathies
so I think that's a very interesting
study I'm putting together um I like to
see the results of that but my
preliminary results are quite positive
uh so yeah so uh there's a lot of uh you
know um good books out there uh come to
the these meetings I think these
meetings are phenomenal talk to
individuals uh I just want the business
of cannabis to support the science of
cannabis because if we uh have a Schism
if we depart from each other then it
will never be accepted in the medical
community and that's what we have to do
we have to accept it at medical schools
where they teach it to the medical
students we have to look at residency
programs where patients are able to
bring their cannabis to the hospital and
not told you can't bring it in we have
to look at it at the attending level and
at the University levels also so we have
to win them over but it's it'll take
time but it's gonna happen right it's
gonna happen because once you're in the
Cannabis you realize the
results uh and and it's not a Panacea
meaning it's not doesn't cure everything
and we have to watch out because as soon
as you tell a doctor that I'm gonna
treat your cancer with only medical
marijuana their eyes will roll and they
think you're a nutcase that's what we
have to watch out for you can say that
there's scientific proof that in in
tissue uh examples that in animal models
that Canabis has decreased the size of
tumors but you can't take it to the next
level where that's the treatment because
I see patients coming to my office who
have breast cancer which is a treatable
disease of today who said no I don't
want radiation I don't want chemo I just
just give me cannabis I won't treat
those patients I'll give them cannabis
because it improves their quality of
life but they have to go through
mainstream treatment so we have to be
very cautious and we have to emphasize
to our colleagues that too yeah
absolutely um and I think it's great you
mentioned Ethan and and Dustin sulac who
are our fellow Advisory board members uh
with yourself good to know for c24 and
they will be participating in the
medical practicum again uh for at 24 so
there's any Physicians out there that
want to get a worldclass education on
cannabis medicine that's the place to be
I agree Ben all right Dr mchy thank you
again for the time and can't wait to see
you down in
Florida I'm looking forward to it not
that Buffalo has bad weather but Buffalo
has bad weather
yeah all right good talk to you Ben all
right we'll see you
soon
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Dr mechler check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor the dent Institute
our next episode drops November 29th
that's 2 weeks from today in the
meantime please go to Ken Med event .c
now to register for our canmed 24
Innovation and investment Summit you can
claim your ticket now at the early bird
rate but the deadline is December
1st you can also submit your abstract
for consideration for oral and poster
presentations at the summit right now
the deadline for that is November
18th go to camet events.com to learn
more about the process and good luck
also I invite you to follow us on social
media we are on Instagram Twitter
Facebook and Linkedin just search for
camate events and lastly don't forget to
rate review And subscribe on whichever
platform you use to listen to or watch
us all right that's it from us until
next time stay safe stay healthy and be
sure to join us for the next CED Coffee
Talk
[Music]