hi everyone thank you for the people
that are not on the beach now
the few of us
um I've been in an argument in my
faculty months ago if it's closing
remarks or just the last one that
non-bandy wants really to hear so I will
call it closing remarks
my
own
you know self-esteem so thank you very
much to to the people that stay with me
here
[Music]
um
let me see how this work like that okay
so my name is Daddy Mayuri I'm a
professor of the technique on the
technology Institute of Israel as a
disclaimer also owner of Kennesaw which
is a company they're doing analytics but
also a lot in the r d and part of the
results that I will show you here been
done also in cancel
cannabis
I think it's stupid to show this
figure here in the last session of the
days and also to say that is a unique
plan that harboring unique molecule
called cannabinoids it's affecting the
endocannabinoid system in our body but
I'm saying that
to people that maybe not admire how
complicated the endocannabinoid system
or how complicated cannabis is
the endocannabinoid system is a system
in our body that every cell in our body
harboring the endocannabinoid system and
being affected by endocannabinoids so
there is
220 some different types of cells in our
body whether there is a neuron whether
are these are a skin cells or liver
cells they're all harboring receptors
for the endocannabinoid system can
produce endocannabinoids
in the blood samples today we can
analyze more than 120 different ligands
endocannabinoids and there are more than
30 receptors that we are looking on them
actually the endocannabinoid system it's
a communication between two cells one
cells send the signal to another cell
increase appetite reduce pain increase
heart beating modulating of glucose
modulation or glucose
intake and immune cells they're all
being controlled by the endocannabinoid
system we didn't say any word till now
about cannabis it's
system in our body that control and
balance
doing kind of a homeostasis on almost
all the cells in our body cannabis was
just totally unlucky to produce similar
molecules
to the molecules that our body producing
more than 10 000 years ago people
started to breed this plant and to
increase the amount of these molecules
and create kind of a puppy kind of a
poodle plant it's not a natural plant
okay I know that there is people from
Morocco here that told me you need to
come in to see the original Plants guys
ten thousand years ago people walk with
that breed it there is no Regional it's
all been produced by humans the Cannabis
shouldn't produce more than 0.1 0.2
percent of fetal cannabinoids who is
here published few years ago about 60
some plants producing phytocannabinoids
the difference between them to cannabis
is the amount of phytocannabinoids
cannabis was breathing and Britain
Britain and we create a plant that
Harbor a lot of
of these molecules in high percentage
people from the 60s can tell you that in
Woodstock it was six percent THC and not
36 percent THC why
we didn't do the breeding right that's
all okay
so
cannabis
it's not the one plant it's a lot of
I will call the chemovars different
variation that harboring different
combination of these molecules
and in my lab we identified 11 different
families that we can analyze around 166
phytocannabinoids and the big question
in these Arena
and this is similar to what I talked
last year but I will take it for a
different angle soon the big question is
how you match the right flower to the
right indication how you match the right
flower to the right bread right if
cannabis or the endocannabins can
influence pain sleep appetite immune
glucose
so which combination of molecule which
plant can affect the appetite which one
affecting immune or which one of them
reducing pain
so how we are doing that and I show
these results enough time in Canada so I
will go fast to reach the point that I
want to talk about it
so how we can do that we can screen
on on Cell culture we can take data from
patient we can do many things to Define
which cannabis is affecting which
indication so if we're screening we can
grow cells on the plate like that we can
grow cells on the plate that have many
Wells we can have equipment that's
screening it very fast in the lower
plate you can see 96 well played that
have 96 well you can put different types
of cannabis different dosing and there
is equipment that's screening very fast
I won't go on that it's not important
and these are results from my lab most
of you already saw that result I'm
showing that in the last three years so
I'm going fast on them this is how
cannabis influence leukemia we know that
cannabis affecting the immune cells so
how it's affecting the cancer of the
immune cells so alibaster PhD in my lab
take a tll which is a specific types of
leukemia screen of them different
chemother of cannabis you see every
color it's a different came over and you
see when the line is lower the mean that
it kill more cells so you see that in
two microgram per ml most of the
Cannabis didn't affect the leukemia but
there was one excerpt that was very
efficient killing the leukemia because
leukemia is a given name to many
different diseases we tested different
types of leukemias and we saw that in 50
of them these types of cannabis kill the
leukemia very efficiently in 50 percent
of them it didn't affect actually the
opposite what I showed 50 did an effect
and 50 is killed very efficiently
so we screen this 10 through camera we
did the genomic screening and we find
that every time that there is a specific
mutation called Notch one this specific
cannabis killing the cells when every
time that there is no mutation it's not
affecting the cells what I'm trying to
show you it's how specific it is
cannabis can kill cancer Rick Simpson
Oil no
one type of cannabis from 200 and some
different chemothers that we test was
the only ones that affect this leukemia
from that it's not all the leukemias
it's just leukemia that harboring
specific mutation and this Notch one is
a protein sitting on the membrane field
the other cells nearing what we call
contact contact inhibition doesn't
important we take we take this specific
leukemia we create mice model for
leukemia you can see a city of a mice
with a cancer in his back
we're treating these mice with cannabis
with this specific extract you can see
the black line on the left it's two more
of with mice that didn't treat with the
Cannabis how the tumor are growing
exponentially while the gray line is
mice that Harbor tumors that treated
with this specific cannabis which the
the tumors didn't grow on the right side
you can see the tumors before and after
three weeks treatment because this is
Leukemia we did the bone marrow into
implantation with primary cells from
patients we show that we are doubling
the lifespan of of the mice we did five
different mice model and we showed it
now we're asking which molecules from
the Cannabis doing this effect these are
all the molecules that these
specific extract is harboring we're
taking this extract we fractionated with
taking pieces we said there is 100
molecules that take 25 25 25 and 25
we're going back to the cells on the
mice and you see that the first line the
vehicle didn't kill the cells the whole
extract extract number tell was very
efficient killing gases and then four
fraction and just fraction number two
mimic the all extracts so we're already
eliminating 75 of the molecules that we
don't need and we're going back and
forth and what's important here is that
in the end we succeed to analyze three
molecules just three that if you take
them synthetic or purified from the
plant and take the three of them you get
exactly the same action as the whole
extract
if you take any one of them and this is
the boss in the left low every one of
them a combination of two of them it's
not working as good as the three of them
together okay and we did a lot of Cell
Biology and biochemistry and this paper
actually published last week we did a
lot of work in the end
we Define exactly the mechanism of
action these three molecules CBD cbdv
and a new cannabinoids we call the 3318
binding two different receptors CB2 and
trp1 and doing a full action of many
proteins and with I won't get into that
now that actually blocking in the Golgi
the ability of the mutant protein to
reach the membrane a lot of biology with
most of you are not scientists and not
Physicians which is not important to you
what I want to say we understand why we
need free molecules and we understand
what they are doing the cells and why
there is mutation it's killing the cells
and when there is no mutations not
killing the cells
we Bridging the Gap between herbal
medicine between saying this is a plane
that affecting
to real modern science and modern
medicine showing these are the molecules
this is the Affinity this is the ability
this is what they are doing this why you
need the three of them but pay attention
we need three of them
most of the drugs that have been
approved by the FDA it's single molecule
to single Target why because we're
afraid from drug drug interaction and
more things
this is kind of Next Level I can show
with different work that sometimes we
can isolate single molecules from
Cannabis in that in that slide we see
from breast cancer different types of
cancer we isolate different type of
molecule we call it 3337315b
similar a little bit to CBG but you can
say that there is three oxygen there and
this molecule reduce the activity of the
estrogen receptor and for that reason in
estrogen receptor in breast cancer a a
dependent estrogen receptors it can
affect the cells okay
again not important the breast cancer
and the results the idea in this case
it's one molecule it's not THC not CBD
not CBG you can call it minor
cannabinoids it won't be minor if it's
if your breast cancer patient okay it's
a molecule that reduce the estrogen
and for that it can affect
estrogen but this is now it's one
molecule
so I showed you that cannabis can affect
cancer in different way different cancer
different cannabis is it always good
so this is a different question on drug
drug interaction what are these
molecules we've known we know nothing
about this molecule we don't know if
it's safe if it's not safe
but we asked few years ago we know that
cannabis modulate the immune system we
know that it's good for inflammatory
bowel disease we know that for
autoimmune disease patient Israel being
treated with cannabis
and I showed you that's affecting T
cells in in leukemia
one of the best treatment today in
cancer or the most
Innovative treatment is in immunotherapy
immunotherapy is when we are telling or
teaching the immune cells to attack the
cancer cells the cancer doing two things
and I will show a slide in a moment he
changing the micro environment near him
and actually changed the immune system
to bring
cells that are not attacking him
actually quite supporting him he's doing
two tricks first of all he presenting
protein said hey himself I'm one of the
cells from the body don't attack me
secondly produce specific proteins that
exhausting the immune cells to attacking
him make the immune cells weaker okay
how can this is the fact that if
cannabis reducing so we're giving a
treatment that actually activating the
immune system
but cannabis reduce the immune system
activity in inflammatory bowel disease
in autoimmune disease I showed you in
the leukemia
so if you look on the literature
okay if you look on the literature there
are few Publications that show that
patient these are clinical trials
patients that getting immunotherapy and
cannabis it's actually improve the
activity of the immune therapy this is
beautiful but if you look there are
other papers that showing
that if you again clinical trials that
if you give cannabis together with
immunotherapy it's reduce the activity
of the immunotherapy my problem with
this publication that the same idiot
published all of them
okay
if you
if you sitting far of course I wouldn't
say idiot if it wasn't me okay
we did four clinical trials
with different results but this is fit
to what I believe cannabis is not one
plant
there is many varieties and part of the
varieties can do something and part of
the varieties can do something else
so we ask ourselves okay let's build a a
model for that okay let's take mice
normal mice and let's take mice without
immune system every scientists know that
we are using mice with no immune system
we call them nude mice because they
don't have a hair at all okay
so we're taking normal mice and nude
mice and we're treating them we can we
create them tumors in these mice and
we're treating the normal mice with
cannabis and we're looking for strain
that reducing the size of the tumor
the same one that succeeded here with
treating with mice with no immune system
and now we want to see which extract
reduce the sign in normal mice but don't
affecting the size of this tumor
without immune system
and that will tell us that it happened
through the immune system we succeed to
isolate specific extract we learn the
mechanism of action what is doing we
succeed to isolate specific molecules
that doing this effect we Define that
it's reducing secretion for for the
cancer cell of specific cytokines I
don't I don't want to go deeper to the
result but we saw that these molecules
affecting the immune activity of the
cells we Target and we mimic it what we
did with this full excerpt and we see
that the single molecule doing the same
effect as the whole extract
then we we know that what the cancer
cell and I explained that few minutes
ago what the cancer cell doing is doing
two things first of all he presenting
potent cell himself this is me don't
attack me second he produce specific
protein that affecting the immune cells
to be weaker actually this spotting
breaking down a amino acid that is
essential for the T cells to attack him
we have very good treatments today what
we call the immunotherapy is it blocking
ntpdl1 controller whatever you call them
that blocking the ability of the cell to
say I'm self on this one what we find
out that the Cannabis blocking this part
so now if you're giving cannabis
specific cannabis with this specific
molecule together with immunotherapy
you get a way better action that the
immunotherapy alone on the Cannabis
alone
but what is the message here
we need to know
it's not enough to say to a cancer
patient that getting immunotherapy take
cannabis
which type of cannabis what molecules
what is the effect it can be on that
side or it can be on that side
cannabis is a complicated plant
but all the plants are complicated
okay I used to say in one of my my talk
previous like seven years ago cannabis
is not like a tobacco that have nicotine
there is a lot of molecules then I met a
guy from Philip Morris that tell me oh
you know cannabis is a simple tobacco
there is more than 1 500 active
compounds so stop saying that anymore
okay
all the plants are complicated when
we're going to the grocery store and buy
apples we know that the green man called
Smith they are very sour the red one
called Macintosh they are sweeter and so
on and so on we know that apples are
different
Israelis have something very unique to
us we have
superpower when we knock on watermelon
we know if it's sweet or no okay every
Israeli when you're buying a watermelon
if you if you travel in Israel you see
this phenomena I'm serious we're
knocking on the watermelon to know if
it's sweet or not right I have like
three Israelis here that can approve me
so every Israeli know that every
watermelon is different
but when we're going to herbal medicine
we flatten that it doesn't matter if
it's cannabis it's whatever
good for the immune system what do you
mean
Ginkgo good for that what do you mean
like all of them the same doesn't matter
where it's growing we have the same
molecules because it's the same story
as cannabis when we're talking about the
today on cytosobic mushroom magic
mushrooms all of them are the same there
are more than 20 families hundreds of
species many active compounds called
tryptamine the same story
and this leading me
to what we called the Entourage effect
is mainly saying in cannabis or other
plants you know there are many compounds
they're doing something complicated
but I think in cannabis it's Unique
there are three layers of the Enterprise
effect so first of all let's start what
is the Entourage effect Ravi mishulam
and and Professor Ben Shabbat published
in 1998 a paper
I'm not sure if you rather or not no so
published a paper called an Entourage
effect
after these three words try to read it
it will be difficult to all of you okay
inactive endogenous fantasy glycerol
ester enhanced to a hedonic glycerol
cannabinoid activity
none of you remember that you remember
the Entourage effect actually it wasn't
about cannabis it was about
endocannabinoids and it showed the two
endocannabis two linole glycino two
parliamentary glycine which not binding
CB1 enhancing
other endocrine beans to AG to bind The
receptors it called it the Entourage
effect it wasn't about cannabis I think
it turned even the one that that took it
no
okay so so Ethan here saying that the
next year they send another paper that
saying that it's also applying for the
plan but the first one was this one okay
so what is the Entourage effect
so first of all I showed you
for examples in the leukemia that you
need three molecules what the meaning of
this three molecule when three molecules
activate on the same
cell different receptors we actually
call it polypham ecology it's when
you're treating a disease by modulation
more than one target you have
activity which is more complicated I
showed that in the leukemia example how
three molecules binding different
receptors opening calcium channels I
didn't show the mechanism of action but
they're doing something synergistic in
the plant
in in the cell but they are affecting
the same plane
the same cell and if you think about it
plant are harboring poly pharmacology
Within
because if you think about a physician
10 000 years ago five thousand years ago
if you come with a kind of inflammation
you will take a route from your flown
from here
you know a stem from here combine them
together and kind of creating
polyphammacology
and and I think poly pharmacology will
go and be bigger and bigger
in in treatment and also I think the FDA
will start to approve more and more this
is my opinion because we're changing in
the last 20 years our analytical ability
to analyze these molecules but more than
that to use computers to understand
networking and Pathways so if you look
about Network or three molecules five
molecules if in the past it was
complicated to understand that today
with computer analysis it's going to
understand and to see what is the drug
drug interaction and modeling and things
that will open that gate but this is for
me the first layer of the Entourage
effect few molecules that affecting one
cell
second layer of the Entourage effect is
that we have molecules that affecting
different cells so I will take for
example IBD inflammatory bowel disease
and flamboyant ball disease consists
mainly two types of cells it's the colon
cells
that being
sometimes somehow harm
mainly probably well bacteria or micro
environment whatever but they have been
harmed they secreting specific molecules
so-called cytokines calling other types
of cell the immune cells to come
and to help them but actually we
creating chronic inflammation
that cause this disease okay but it's
two types of cells to system the colon
cells and the immune cells so in two
different studies two different PhD
students in my lab one of them work on
the common sense and define specific
combination of cannabinoids actually two
that reduce the ability of the colon
cells to secrete these cytokines to call
the immune cells
but in the same extract different
student different PhD work work on the
immune cells and show the different
molecules from the same extract actually
blocking the ability of the immune cells
to migrate towards the colon different
compound different results okay the
first one if if people are here our
physician or defenseman reducing
specific protein called stat 3 which is
creating the inflammation or the the
release of cytokines the second one
reducing protein called cxco4 which
actually it's kind of the antenna the
this the colon cells secreting the
molecules the twitching the the the
immune cells binding them and then
binding a specific more important called
cxcfo which feel now where it's bind if
it's bind here here and here and started
to migrate towards
so the Cannabis from one hand
one molecule from this extract reducing
the colon cells to secrete these
molecules different molecules blocking
the ability of them the cells to feel it
and to migrate and you're getting
Entourage effect you're getting
synergies and you're getting powerful
reaction that if you take just with
molecules that affecting the colony just
these molecules affecting the immune
system you won't get it
and this is a different layer more
complicated for me for the FDA or
something like that it will be two
treatment that we need to combine or we
need to use the plane but this is a
different layer of the Entourage effect
the third layer of the Entourage effect
on third Entourage it's when we are not
talking about single indication but we
are talking about the quality of life of
the patient we're talking about the
whole patient
so if we take pain patient we did the
clinical trial 3800 pay patient and we
measure many parameters of the patient
even though the patient 50 of the
patients said the Cannabis is really
help them change their life did a lot
when we measured the pain we saw that it
didn't reduce much of the pain less than
30 percent reduced to point in the the
in the pain of the patients but when you
started to to check why this patient
they said that it really helped them we
saw that it's really also reducing
anxiety reduce depression improve sleep
improve appetite and when you measure
quality of life action what we call
catastrophism how the patient conceived
his is disease then we saw a huge
Improvement actually the Cannabis
improved the quality of life of the
patient but if you think about that few
molecules
affect the pain few molecules affect
appetite few molecules affect anxiety a
few molecules affect sleep and all
together
the patient improves its quality of life
and this is cannabis because it's
affecting so many systems
in all of them is doing moderate to
action a little bit on the pain a little
bit on the sleep a little bit on the
appetite you're getting something as a
whole treatment which is better and you
wouldn't get it from single molecules
single treatment you need to give peel
for Sleep peel for pain pill for
appetite and so on cannabis give
something more holistic so if we think
about it
cannabis is kind of an orchestra of
molecules
that working on a system called the
endocannabinoid system
mimicking things in our body we can
narrow it down
so I I didn't prepare my talk until two
hours ago
and I prepared because things that I
heard
during this conference there are kind of
division here people that coming from
Pharma and looking for let's take single
molecules or they and and purify then go
with that and people that believe more
in the plant and looking about the
Entourage effect
but actually what I'm trying to show
that nobody is wrong here
in few indication if you're looking very
specific you want to treat something
very specific
you can isolate a molecule and go farmer
out and there is indication that it
might work
if you want to be more complicated more
risky on the business side you can say
okay I will take these two molecules
that affecting the the colon these two
molecules that affecting the immune
cells that will try to combine them to
botanic treatment or to be very very a
brave and to try to go with this to the
FDA congratulations to you okay
but it's still I believe in that okay
and the third one is to say when you
want to treat quality of life of the
patient which is the most it's the
majority of our patient
you can't run away from the plane you
want one you might want a consistently a
product something safe something that
you know what you get but you won't get
away from the plan because it's too
complicated and it's doing too many
things I think the future
will consist
part of these things I think we will see
more and more drugs FDA approved single
molecules you know three three one five
that Daddy write a patent and somebody
license it and go with it to reduce a
estrogen okay we will see drugs like
that
we will see
the whole plant is the medicines for
many years I don't think we can run away
from that it's already there countries
like Israel 150 000
prescription in months for patient one
of the most prescribed medicine in
Israel but this is the whole plan
and I do believe that we will see a new
route A New Path of more complicate
drugs that trying to affect not one
mechanism not one system but more of
them and I think it's you know you need
to break a wall you need to be
Innovative you need to do that but I do
believe that there are diseases like ALS
Alzheimer's types of cancer that we hit
our head to the wall many years and
don't succeed to solve them with a
simplified activity and when we will
understand the complexity and we try to
do complicated things we might
bring a cure to these ones by that I
want to say thanks a lot to the amazing
team that working we shrinked that was
before the corona we shrinked a lot from
them but these are my students and my
work workers are doing the amazing work
that I showed thank you very much
thank you very much Daddy for this
wonderful presentation but I have to say
that you left me a little bit confused
what what do you think what what does
the future hold for cannabis do you see
cannabis being developed to do it from
it to be a pharmaceutical drug or rather
it might just uh or not just but it
might stay as a herbal a herbal extract
or product what do you think
so I think it's it's depends of the
indication in my opinion and my father
taught me that if I'm arguing with
somebody I'm 50 wrong okay
actually we'll say in if you argue with
your mother it's 100 wrong so don't
argue that was his what he used to say
so it's my opinion and and just my
opinion I believe that in specific
indication
and mainly save lives indication it will
be more precise more Farm around these
molecules for leukemia or whatever I
think in in indication which is more
related to Quality of Life much more
wide will stay with the with the plant
for two reasons first of all it's a
cheap medicine
and and there is a there is a reason uh
why you know in the global world I just
came from India yesterday I actually fly
from India here I learned that Miami is
not on the way from India right or
Israel it's actually between
um
there are countries like India that
cheap medicine is extremely important
and think there is cannabis is a cheap
medicine and it stay like that and I
think in the complicated thing in the uh
you know quality of life things that
you're treating many it will stay with
the plant I think we need to precise it
I need to to know which extract which
plane to use to what but I think it will
stay with the plant
thank you thank you I would just like to
to comment that if it might there might
be some difficulties in this approach
since once you define the certain
substance certain molecule is a drug
then it comes to be under regulation
which might not support public use for
different purposes so just you know so
so again you know the Cannabis is very
unique because there is regulation each
country looks in a different way but I I
just came from India that they have
regulations for plants they have
plants is a medicine okay I forgot how
they call it every day or Avida you know
isn't
I
Veda okay it's specific regulation for
plant which we don't have
in the you know in the state or or in in
Israel so it's very depend on the
regulation I agree with you there is
problems
one
Daddy thank you that overview is so
important a question about the so-called
minor cannabinoids that you've been
testing are they much more potent than
the major cannabinoids you need to
amplify their concentration or dose that
you're giving in these models or do you
give them in relatively tiny doses like
they occur in the plant
so it's the answer is specific for each
minor cannabinoids that we Define okay
there are minor cannabinoids that we
found which are extremely potent and
more like 3318 in in the leukemia is
very similar to CBD when you increase
its amount it's more potent to this from
the CBD so even if you tried it on
epilepsy it's working even better than
the CBD okay and very similar action to
the CBD but something else there there
are other Fido cannabinoids that I I
think their potency is lower but they
are potent like the minor can you know
there are many minor cannabinoids the
minor cannabinoids that we found that
active they were very potent the other
one that I showed there were estrogen
because you have three
oxygens on on the outside its viable
ability is way higher than the regular
phytocannabin then that might be wise
more potent I don't know the result but
yeah they are potent thank you
Bonnie hi Daddy uh thank you for a great
lecture as usual
um I have a question going back to the
slide where you showed the cancer cell
having two actions one saying I'm self
don't kill me and that you're saying
that that's the when the anti uh pd1
comes in that is not is is this new
information that you're sharing that
with you said a new paper
um that's not where cannabis is causing
an issue it's causing an issue more on
the immune system
in the micro environment yeah the
Cannabis is what we found okay the
Cannabis these cannabinoid is affecting
the cancer cell first of all is reducing
the secretion of specific cytokines
called csf1 and csf1
changing the the cancer cell secrecy is
a fund to change the profile of the
macrophages arriving the micro
environment M2 instead of M1 so actually
there are macrophages that coming and
deactivating the T cells changing the
profile of that changing the activity of
the T cell that one thing the second
it's reducing the the activity of two
enzymes ionos and arginas which break
down Arginine which that the way to do
what we call immunosuppressive blocking
that blocking the ability of the cancer
cell to immunosuppress the T cells
activity
and and so so if we take two months and
we did that you take tumors from
patients you grow them in a plate you
treat them with the Cannabis okay and
then you taking the supernatant like
they're like you know the what they
secreted and put on T cells you see that
if you're not doing that it's inhibiting
the T cells activity but if you treat
with cannabis it's one to inhibit the T
cell activity this is like classic
method to test it
okay so I have a follow-up question and
it's okay if you don't want to answer me
just today I got a text message from the
mother of a boy I've already emailed you
about once I don't know if you remember
as a 10 year old with metastatic
osteosarcoma his second cancer is
treated for leukemia as a young child
and has a subsequent secondary cancer
he was on cannabis in chemotherapy
his Physicians decided to switch him to
novoma lab
and I discontinued the Cannabis and she
texted me today to say is there any way
we can add it back he has the most
horrific side effects
and so I wrote back I don't know if
there's anything safe but I'll see Dr
Mary and ask him so I I know I'm putting
you on the spot to translate to a cancer
patient so it's always difficult for me
to answer that the clinical trial that
we showed that was reduced the activity
of the immune or the immunotherapy was
on Death Drive specific drug and we saw
that in general the success rate reduced
from 40 few percent to 25 so it's really
affecting that but this was high T8 high
THC strained Classic this trend that we
used here in this study is high CBG
strain so it's totally different profile
totally different than
I
you know I in Israel I'm working with
the uncle all the head of the oncology
department in in the main hospitals and
and we had a panel of the old the head
of the oncologist and and me about that
and the answer was you know there is
risk you know we won't take it so in in
the in the frame that they gave
immunotherapy that's stopping the
cannabis
I do think
according to our results that the high
CBG strength today that are available
outside
are safe enough and I don't see this
reaction from the patient and from the
the pre-clinicals that we get we get but
I'm not sure that these strains are
effective on the side effects so I don't
know if the high CBG strain are really
reducing nausea or pain or that I don't
know the effect on the side effects so
it's it's complicated
but but in there is risk to to give
cannabis with immunotherapy if it's just
just cannabis
again it depends on the cannabinoids so
right and that's and that's a nice
helpful answer because if they're if
he's terribly desperate and he's not
finding any relief I would probably feel
a little more comfortable we can try CBG
so so again the the cannabinoids that
they showed in the immunotherapy work
was CBG it's not the minor kind of
business I I don't called my CBG minor
so okay thank you very much just a
comment Barney it's it's such a tough
question but then you have to weigh the
other side is that can this kid complete
the course of therapy without the help
of cannabis or are they going to have to
throw in the tell on immunotherapy
thank you sir I I just wanted to comment
on on a couple things from your previous
slide regarding the approach moving
forward as far as investigating this
further uh groupers versus Splitters
those that tend to want to treat it
holistically versus those that want to
pinpoint specific parts of the plant uh
I wonder if there's a middle ground uh
regarding this and considering that
there are different strains just like
your Apple slide could it not be more a
way of approaching it in understanding
that our categories neuromuscular
neurological GI pain inflammation as
specific areas to address rather than
getting specific conditions or illnesses
rather grouping them in in certain
generalities that we can pinpoint and
direct treatment plans for patients do
you feel that rather than again
segregating the plan and cutting it up
in smaller pieces why not just develop
certain specific medical strains towards
that grouping and see and investigate
that very question of Entourage and how
mental health affects all that and how
the mental health if improved can
improve the physical condition
so I will answer that in two ways first
of all it's you know some that the truth
is not the nice there I'm a cell
biologist that's what I'm doing so I'm
interested in what the molecule doing in
the cell in the end that's why okay I'm
not the Cannabis you know
regulator or something like that but to
answer that the technology is there like
we can analyze the compounds we can say
this is the profile this is the groups
that doing for that and that the
technology are for there but the
knowledge is not for there not there yet
so we don't have the knowledge to say in
in all the indication not even in minor
indications to say this is the profile
that you need for that so this is the
prophet and uh to group that we just
don't have the knowledge yet so you know
I showed few things that we have results
but in most of the things we don't know
and you know I'm responsible for for
courses in Israel for physician or for
nurses and and for and and people said
yeah education is very important we need
to teach them what I know to teach them
I don't know what to teach them but I'm
I'm showing the Entourage that I think
the endocannabinoid system there but I
don't know to tell them what to
prescribe which one is really good for
that or for that I'm starting to have a
knowledge
so we don't have this profile a day the
technology is there I must say that
very few scientists in the world I'm not
talking about companies out there I'm
talking about even scientists taking the
approach to really go deep and to look
on the minor cannabinoids and the
combination you know and I need to
sitting here and and other a a
scientists doing that but these are I
can count them on one hand so we don't
have this that we just don't have this
data okay
um and that's reality we don't have the
data to to push it there
thank you very much and have a good