well welcome to La the cannabis capital
of the world thank you all for being
here and my name is Michael Shermer
Titus I am the CEO of advanced nutrients
Big Mike's blends and the locked earnest
labs which is a cannabinoid research
incubator being built right here it's a
20 million dollar lab my name is Danny
Keith I'm the CEO of cannabis club TV
work with Tommy Chong is one of our main
influencers and what we really strive to
do is tell the story and educate the
customer short and sweet guys
I am Evan Brittain I'm a former NFL
player I played six years in the league
with the Jaguars and the Bears as an
offensive lineman I got into the
cannabis space and a cannabis advocacy
activism if you will you know through my
career I suffered a laundry list of
injuries how that's dealt with in the
NFL is lots of prescription pills had a
handful of concussions and through that
cannabis was really my preferred source
of pain management
you know when the pills opiates in
particular made me feel insane irritable
made it difficult to sleep and recover
you know I could constantly come back to
cannabis and it was the one thing that
helped me recover it helped me heal from
you know long day of grind three hours
of full padded practice smashing into
other 300-pound individuals hundreds of
times a day you know that does a lot of
damage to your skeletal system to your
brain in particular and you know coming
out of that experience feeling like I
had for the most part my body and my
mind intact you know learning about the
neuro protectant antioxidant qualities
of cannabinoids in the brain following
brain trauma and concussions I do a lot
to push the NFL to remove cannabis from
its banned substance list as it looks to
be the number one
remedy to their biggest issue which are
concussions and CTE which is affecting
just about every guy that plays football
whether it's from high school to the NFL
87 percent of football players tested
positive for CTE that's from high school
to the NFL 99.9% of NFL brains tested
positive for CTE in a Boston University
study that came out probably about a
year ago now so I created an
organization called athletes for care
which is a resource and education
platform for athletes in their
transition out of their careers as pro
athletes as well as you know educating
them on the medicinal benefits of
cannabis as opposed to prescription
pills and so it's great to be here thank
you guys for having me so the panel is
about to be about medical cannabis but
in the scenario the NFL I always
imagined it would be better for the
players to actually be preventative
medicine right that there should be
probably neuroprotective in their
bloodstream during the game what is this
term medical seems very reactionary what
are your thoughts on this I think that
you know right now the NFL unfortunately
continues to run from their issues I
think it's funny that you can watch a
football game now and they have PSA is
talking about new helmet technology
which does nothing as we know they're
talking about coaches are really
concerned about the well-being of their
players and you know it's it's [ __ ]
and frankly you know cannabis is
something that you know our federal
government has a patent on cannabinoids
as a neuro protectants an anti
students the NFL has a major issue with
concussions these are guys you know CTE
the wreckage that it causes is you know
you're a 40 year old man and you're
already being diagnosed with stage 2
dementia you know I have friends guys
who have played in the league who are in
you know real dire need of anything to
get them out of it and so you know the
NFL seems to be very slow to take on
this conversation I think they're
starting to approach it a little bit
other leagues have been more proactive
you know really comes down to the owners
relationship with the players you know
it's since you're a rookie coming into
the league it's about protect the shield
you know everything you do as a player
is about maintaining the integrity of
the league rather than putting that
before yourself and the NFL owners have
a long history of turning their backs on
players look at Colin Kaepernick right
now they've totally demonized him and
ruined his career essentially and power
to him for taking them to to court for
it
you know so I had conversations with NBA
owners who are very you know excited to
support their players in any way they
can you know you see with guys like Al
Harrington cliff Robinson these guys are
really making strides David Stern former
Commissioner of the NBA saying that guys
should have access to cannabis you've
got Steve Kerr talking about it with the
Warriors you know so they are much more
proactive and actually do care about
players well-being you know this isn't
like a boo boo thing for the NFL players
you know it's really on the NFL players
at this point to make a stand for
themselves you know don't go out and
play that Thursday night game stay in
stay in the locker room until you start
getting your demands met because at this
point you know the PA is really just a
front for the NFL now it's all funded by
the league and when you walk in there
even me as a former player they don't
care about
former players and you know from aside
from that they're not really looking to
go up against the league in anything
that matters you know I think at this
point with everything that's happened
all the conversations that have been
going on the opiate abuse in the league
NFL players are four times as likely to
abuse opioids in the average American
and so you know they have a number of
issues that cannabis can solve I think
it'll be a bargaining chip for them on
the table coming into this new
collective bargaining agreement you know
but what it's going to be is you guys
play two more games maybe will allow you
to use cannabis or at least in the
states where it's legal you can access
it but I think that's still a long
stretch for the league at this point are
you seeing traction in other sports like
an NHL obviously plays across borders
with Canada and is this can we leverage
the other athletic associations to try
and make change for sure I think that
you know the NFL will make a change you
know the very last minute that they can
you're totally right on the NHL is much
more interested in the cannabis
conversation allowing their players to
use it a guy that is a co-founder with
me at athletes for Kerr Riley Cote has
made some tremendous strides in getting
the NHL Players Association to start
having these conversations about
cannabis at least for their former
players and then you know who knows
maybe you did it removed from the banned
substance list but you know the NFL is
in a unique position because they have
so much influence you know they could
really uh you know I I challenge the NFL
over and over again maybe one of these
times I say it they'll they'll read it
but you know they could really be the
ones spearheading this new era of
medicine you know they could be
spearheading this idea that
these cannabinoids can be used to treat
traumatic brain injuries as well as you
know they've got a great opportunity for
you know the best case study for
cannabis as a preventive medicine you
know in in their players and
and every team in the league what's your
perspective on this what on which what
precisely are you asking you've got a
lab started now you've been making
nutrients sure for many years you've
here's a deal every one of you who are
sitting here in the audience is an
influencer that will positively show
cannabis in the way that it must be
showing I am so glad Netflix got rid of
the show disjointed I'm sick of seeing
the typical stoner stuff and them making
fun of us and laughing at us think about
this for the last 40 to 50 years the
general public has been indoctrinated
falsely given false information and been
brainwashed and it's gonna take a while
to unravel it it's gonna take all of us
in this room whether it's the state
level the local level you got to get
busy and start either writing articles
Evan here he's a creative writer he did
something very smart he learned how to
write write white papers inform the
public get rid of the stigma and let's
enter into the new age of what cannabis
really is about and what it can do for
people I don't care if it's recreational
nutraceutical or pharmaceutical
everybody deserves to have great
delivery systems safe and standardized
products and everyone sitting in this
room can have a hand in it if you choose
to and I'm asking you to do it go back
to your your cities where you came from
start writing articles getting on TV
anyone who will listen to you and do not
allow them to stigmatize cannabis in a
negative way because we don't deserve it
and we've worked too hard and too long
and this plant is an amazing plant that
has so many properties to heal people
so many levels I don't care if you're a
recreational user or pharmaceutical user
to me you're all patients you're
medicating for a reason and we all
deserve safe standardized products yes I
[Applause]
offer you to a discussion I also think
the whole recreational medical thing is
is a bit of a misnomer it's like it's
some sort of forced dichotomy that
doesn't really exist if you don't have
enough of the former or the recreation
you're gonna find out needing that you
need the medical so you obviously yeah
well the same experience how about you
David what's your feeling this well I
mean that's exactly why you know we got
into the business and started doing the
in dispensary broadcast network is
because of the stigma I mean being in
the NBA we had players that were using
CBDs and and using marijuana you know in
fact that the teams would prefer it
versus them going out and drinking and
getting in trouble so it's to me I had a
like kind of an entourage effect with
you know we had just finished the 2015
season things were going good
all of a sudden Tommy got rectal cancer
and my wife got a brain tumor my dad
passed away from opiates and at that
particular moment I left the team and I
went full bore into cannabis club TV and
I agree with with Mike on the sense that
we you know even though Tommy's our
influencer you know he's an amazing
activist and you know the campy side of
cannabis is not always well received and
it's what it's our biggest weapon used
against us and I think for us we try to
really focus on bringing educational
content whether it be how to grow how to
cook with cannabis
you know topics of discussion new
financial information you know it's
about the education and to Mike's point
like you you know we live in an era
where every single one of you guys can
be an influencer and you can help spread
the word and it's really about you know
having that discussion with people
asking them what their point of view on
it is a lot of its just fear and I think
the the benefit of having the science
you know platform and having that
relationship with cannabis and learning
words I've never heard before
you know is is how we're gonna be able
to reach a lot of these patients and so
you know we'd need to make people feel
as comfortable to go that they go buy a
bottle of whiskey that they're able to
feel it's just as comfortable to buy the
cannabis to treat their nausea for some
reason yeah indeed indeed and we're
seeing that now we're seeing a massive
migration of the alcohol industry into
cannabis and it's my belief that that's
gonna echo itself with the
pharmaceutical industry we're gonna see
tylenol go away we're gonna see
ibuprofen go away we're gonna see
aspirin go away because we have safer
alternatives I mean for those at the tie
and all am four or four right this is an
endo can have annoyed my medic that is
made when you deliver digest Tylenol and
it makes a toxic byproduct in the
process that sometimes been attributed
to to in utero autism events all types
of other overdose related issues you can
have with your liver but we have all
these cannabinoids now that are gonna
march in and at some point I think farm
is gonna stop lobbying and start buying
and investing in these other cannabis
companies and so I think that next wave
is coming and what we're seeing right
now go on in Canada is just the start
much more to come here's an interesting
statistic new patients new medical
marijuana patients who are coming in for
the first time into dispensary are 56
years of age they also spend three times
more than the REC recreational client
well as well interesting so management's
gonna be huge demographics I said at a
time I think medical is gonna be bigger
than rank I just we haven't recognized
it yet hmm yeah on that point big Mike
my my wife's family is a very
straight-laced or column Pasadena's god
bless him love him today but you know
since being on this this path of really
cannabis advocacy just being outspoken
about it educating at just about every
family function party I go to talking
about do you know we have an
endocannabinoid system in our bodies
and you know since then I've really you
know it's been first my wife's uncle
then her parents you know and they're
coming to me and they're like AB you
know I can't sleep
only well I got something for you you
know and immediately they're they're
converted into believers you know from
people who were really affected by the
stigma you know growing up in the 60s
and 70s you know having this idea that
you know it's the devil's weed there's
no place for it in a family setting in a
family atmosphere and they're like wow
this stuff really works you know it
takes me from waking up you know every
couple hours throughout the night not
being able to get a good night's sleep
to waking up feeling refreshed and
recovered and I think that you know as
it as it comes to influence like Big
Mike was talking about you know getting
into just at your local level I mean
your influence you can have a positive
influence on this thing you know just
starting at your family functions you
know have a conversation at the dinner
table then you never know you might
affect your gonna change you know one or
two minds and then the ripple effect of
that and how many people continue out of
that that you positively influence about
the power of this plan because the truth
is you know it's non-toxic it's a
thousand you know ten thousand year old
remedy probably older you know it comes
from the earth there are no side effects
it's never killed anyone helps you sleep
we produce these same chemical compounds
in our body it's amazing you know and
continuing to inform people about these
things I think it really it makes a
difference you make an impact I had a
really interesting conversation with dr.
Bonnie Goldstein just just a minute ago
about this you know it's it's kind of
crazy you know how you can affect you
know even she was telling me about her
parents how she's got them using
cannabis dangers
so did the ovens point the general I
talked to a lot of doctors not in
obviously in in this conference they
have no idea that we have an
endocannabinoid system they have no idea
we have cb1 cb2 receptors so when you
educate things that you take for granted
that well everybody knows that let me
tell you the general public has no idea
they don't know leaders between cannabis
indica sativa or a hybrid so start with
the basics and educate up I think it's a
great point because we went through a
very similar thing this year with her
father
and we were educating folks at
dana-farber right so we get in there and
it's a typical PSA test they do some
scans and everything else and the
treatment is kind of a protocol and we
say well hold on let's sequence this
thing and we discover he has this
mutation that's known as a b-raf k6 o 1e
variant okay for those in the cancer
space they're really familiar with this
variant because there's a neighboring
amino acid called v600e that is heavily
studied in Roche has drugs that targeted
but nothing for one of me to acid over
look crazy right Foundation medicine
then gives you this report that says
well these are all the experimental
drugs that might work for it they're in
phase 2b trials good luck but you want a
KT inhibitors and of course having read
about a KT and m2 we're now in cool
cannabinoids or potent a KT inhibitors
why aren't we using those bringing all
the papers show them and they're they're
like go for it we support you no
problems with that at all here
which I was quite surprised by cuz we
had other experiences where when he got
hospitalized due to other other
scenarios they would end up in a
hospital that was like you can't have it
on premise get out of here
they almost threatened to send him the
thirty thousand dollar bill for having
used it on-site and so there is there's
different education that needs to go on
in different hospitals I think the
cancer centers are aware of this they
see that people are using this with
success for nausea and for pain but many
of the other ER doctors that might
handle patients getting rushed in due to
an adverse event in cancer are oblivious
to it and they're held down to certain
rules and regulations that don't allow
any of this stuff on-site and they're
the ones
to get a work on I'm fully convinced
that if my dad was able to use a veteran
so he was unable to take cannabis if he
got tested positive when they did test
for it but they had no problem giving
him 900 1/2 milligram pills of or 5
milligram pills of oxycontin so and
literally killed him I'm certain if we
were able to get it and there's a lot of
you know businesses that are popping up
and going into the the the old folks
homes if you will and like talking to
the patient's I mean my 74 year old
mother-in-law Japanese very strict no
way to smoke weed or cannabis sorry is
now using CBD so it's like in and it
came from actually her doctor referring
it to her like hey this is going to be
the best for you we really got to ask
our doctors to to kind of look into that
what's your doctor's position on
cannabis how are they willing to look
into that I'm living in Santa Cruz I've
got a beneficial bubble basically
everybody embraces cannabis there but
it's a pretty small bubble when you get
out of it look the United States has to
lead the way to educate the world I was
just reading today if you're a citizen
of South Korea and you come to medical
marijuana state and you use medical
marijuana that's perfectly legal in that
state it's the same thing as breaking
the law in South Korea and you're liable
to get five years in jail in Abu Dhabi
if you go there and they take your blood
and they find cannabinoids in your blood
it is exactly the same as possession be
careful where you travel but here's the
real point United States and Canada must
educate the rest of the world and
society because if we are to your point
we're living in a bubble here once you
step outside of this bubble it's
extremely different I traveled all over
the world and I get in a lot of
conversations about cannabis and a lot
of governments are still very negative
they don't understand it's it's
everywhere this medical journey that we
went through with her father was just i
opening as to how the amount of
ignorance that's out there on this
and suppression that's going on by the
way all these people who are against it
as soon as one of their family members
gets ill and dries cannabis and is
successful with it it changes
immediately
I've seen this so it happens so many
times well right after my wife's surgery
we managed to mitigate pain and nausea
from a full craniotomy you know peach
sized tumor with indicas and CBDs and
her neurologist is like you're healing
really well you're not refilling your
prescription what are you doing and we
told her and she's from Stanford like
keep doing it you know just keep doing
what you're doing that's what triggered
my mother-in-law and my father-in-law
who's a 25-year master sergeant in the
Marines
it just takes somebody you know having
that personal experience to then
transfer out and then they're the
biggest they're like the best advocate
they tell everybody that she's telling
all her you know Martin fans like when
she goes and plays cards like hey when
using CBD I catch it because I hear CBD
but the rest is Japanese you know a lot
of times I've been I got a few surgeries
and they always prescribed me these
opiates and I said I'm not gonna take
them they go what are you gonna do I'm
gonna take CBD and THC and they watch me
do it and every one of them when I'm
done with the surgery and of heal that
go tell me more about what I can do and
how can I get some of this to give to my
patients every one of them well we had
one other story I'll share which was
I've father had to get a pacemaker put
in throughout this whole cancer
treatment because some of the cancer
drugs were triggering his afib and going
into v-tach so it was one complication
after another so he ends up going in for
the pacemaker in Manchester hospital and
we figure I we don't know what type of
anesthesia they're gonna give them
what's it's wean them off wean him down
for a couple days bring him in all the
nausea comes screaming back they get the
pacemaker in but there isn't a single
drug in that hospital that will get rid
of the nausea and so we ask okay where's
where's the Marinol can we you have dry
little insight and they're like now that
one is locked away we don't have easy
access to that thing and so we're like
well can we just give them some CBD like
not on site after about
day of this they realized he's getting
dehydrated it's not under control
bless the nurses involved in this field
because they just said you know go get
it and we're gonna lock the door and and
do what you got to do 30 minutes later
he stood up and walked out of there and
they look like they saw a ghost every
one of them was interested in CBD and
that is something we need to do more of
and I also throw it to the vets out
there I'm finding a lot of people who
have who have pets that have have cancer
or have other types of pain and the vets
are on it like no problem
CBD you got it let's get it order it
online and we'll give it to them and
it's not the exact percentage who cares
it's you know these dogs are facing some
some some grim circumstances no doubt I
give my dog CBD a little THC every day
he's got bad hips he's an English
Bulldog she's got you know bad hip
dysplasia and he's gonna turn ten and I
mean since giving him the you know a
little tank sure else put it on his food
I mean he's like a puppy again it's
pretty amazing
it's funny how with animals were
preventative most of time but humans
were more reparative I give I have a
little chihuahua no teeth same age ten
and she's you know jumps up and down too
much frail give her some CBD and it's
like boom just takes off you know and
they want it like you they know when
you're bringing it out to the show here
it comes
yeah so just we gotta get in the same
mindset as animals yeah they're much
simpler yeah I think the way to change
hearts is through their family members
and and we see this and as the
population is aging we are gonna have a
demographic shift on the elderly needing
access to this and and it's very true
we're finding many of the people of our
age have parents now that are starting
to who were probably vehemently against
it when they were when we were kids for
all the scare mongering reasons we know
about are now wide awake and open to it
and I think it's a very good thing and
we can't we need to keep our intention
on that generation because I think
they're good very high medical care
expenses happen there and that's where
the system is gonna break so we're gonna
figure impact there
cannabinoids no dough yeah so tell us
more about Tommy Chong's experience I
understand he started off really strong
recreational advocate and of course
ended up with prostate cancer himself
and and and curing it with CBD yeah yeah
yeah - cancer scares actually first was
the prostate cancer
first and foremost Tommy you know he's
pretty much as you see him is how he is
but he is such a believer of the plant I
mean in all space I mean I'm
anytime I run across a new CBD cream or
anything he's willing to be like the guy
that tries that out and see how it works
you know he's a great test pilot but
when it comes down to like treating his
cancer you know it was a pretty big
scare the prostate cancer initially was
like okay this was gonna be a tough one
and he did really good with that and
then when it you know we beat that and
then within a year it returned you know
as rectal cancer and now those one that
one usually takes you out you know you
don't really pull off the rectal cancer
but he he was like diligent about it he
watched his diet he you know was doing a
fair dose so he tried to stay away from
the chemo but a lot of CBD a lot of CBD
suppositories to really kind of get
there and do it and you know I remember
Tommy going through that and we were in
Vegas when he made the announcement and
you could see it in him and it was like
okay is this gonna you know he's just
turned 80 years old but he never gave up
you know you always believed the plant
could heal and me always you know
everybody was a doubter as doctors were
a doubter
and he ended up pulling it you know he
had to have the you know he has a
colostomy bag now but he's alive and
he's looking really good and he's still
doing bunch of shows you know with
Cheech and and when we go do dispensary
visits that's the one thing I really
like working with Tommy is he gets out
and talks to the to the actual patients
and shares their stories with them and
you know people are coming up you know I
used cannabis for my epilepsy or I have
you know shaky like that we have a guy
that works at our work he has an extra
chromosome it's like helps settle down
his chromosome if you take CBD and you
know so he's always wanting to learn and
then to that point we educate people as
they're coming through the line to get
his autograph for whatever he'll have
intimate conversations with them and as
an influencer I think that's really
important because you have the ability
to change someone's
now these people are usually already
consuming cannabis but then those people
go back to their family and again it's
at daisy chain reaction so you know
while tommy is a campy guy at times he's
really you know his mission I feel he's
he feels like he's made his mark and
he's paid his dues and I think he's very
pleased with the state of cannabis right
now but I think he sees that we have a
long way to go still and you know he's
willing to do the hard work and get
boots on the ground well to Mike's point
I found that when you give lab tours you
you start to win people over these
people are afraid of this and they see
all this technology's mass affects these
sequencers all tearing apart this plant
and they realize what wait a minute this
isn't just about bongs and they see that
there's regimented science behind it so
if you own a lab please give tours local
politicians and anyone who seems to be
concerned about this because I think
that is one thing that really turns
people over when they see that there is
a tremendous amount of scientific
horsepower being applied to this plan
and in many ways the testing regulations
for cannabis you'll you won't get any of
the food in the grocery store to get
through this stuff right this is this is
above and beyond what we have for most
of the produce in the field and no one
knows that and I think it's important to
show them that we've also been doing
some work with even high school students
we've been touring around that we also
have some interns here as well where
we're trying to get that younger
generation and this is tough in high
school because if you like what are you
talking about you're gonna send your
students around through a cannabis
testing laboratory their parents are
gonna kill us but it works out and you
then get them very intrigued at a young
age to want to march into this field and
go into college thinking about alright I
want to get involved in botany or
genetics or something else so I think
this is the influencing side of this is
really important and we have to take our
times do it I know just to add Tommy has
always been a big proponent of testing I
mean even before regulations were put
into place he was very adamant about
making sure that we know we visited the
labs I'll be visiting a lot next week
another new one I mean the other thing
is that these labs are still kind of
dialing in these these devices and it's
a it's moving pretty fast people don't
realize the investments that these labs
are having to make to actually stay up
to regulation on time with Bureau and
then you got the the influx I mean it's
just crazy demand and flow
of cannabis non-tested we tested
cannabis do you have it is it packaged
properly I mean there's been a lot of
crazy regulations that have come down
the pipe and I think the biggest piece
as consumers that you should always try
to make sure you remember is that you
you really vote with your dollar so make
sure you're paying attention to the
brands that you're purchasing and you're
supporting the ones that are trying to
do the best work and not just the ones
that have the highest THC or the ones
that you know you think gonna get the
most results out of try to focus on you
know who the players are and what
they're doing it right the reasons why
they're doing it yeah I mean I see the
testing space not just as keeping people
honest but it's discovery engine we saw
today people are bumping into CBG plants
which we haven't had much access to so
if we're not doing this testing we're
not gonna be discovering those things
how have you seen the is the NFL against
just THC do they care about CBD do they
even know what CVG is you know I don't
THC is what they have listed on the
banned substance list okay you know I've
had some debates they claimed even
taking a CBD isolate product you would
test positive on an NFL drug test and
the way the drug testing works in the
NFL is there's an annual street drugs
test which cannabis is on and so you
have but you you know you have a general
idea of when that test is going to
happen it's going to happen sometime
between the first day you get to the
facility in April to about the first
week in training camp so you know you
have all of spring and then basically
some if you're not tested some time in
there then you know you're definitely
getting at that first week in training
camp and then you're free to consume
cannabis as you need it if you're one of
those guys I was one of those guys and
you know thank God I was I wouldn't be
in the shape I am now if it wasn't for
cannabis
and you know that's the truth I I don't
see it any other way I've seen guys who
coming out of the league and they've got
bottles of pills trailing behind them
you know and when you get cut and you
have a box of stuff from your locker
those pill bottles are in there and
you're really dependent on those you
know to deal with the nagging injuries
you're leaving the team with whatever
surgeries you've had you know that are
still that are you know you're still
having pain from and that now there's no
one to help you you know figure out
organize your healing regimen you know
and so you're going home and these guys
are diving into you know opiate
addiction whatever pills they have
available to them and they're losing
their minds you know and meanwhile
there's this thing that's non-toxic that
could really save them and their
families a great deal of pain so you
know the NFL really I've sat across the
desk from the director of player
wellness at the NFLPA and having a
conversation when are we gonna start
looking at cannabis you know why aren't
you doing that and really she didn't
want to hear any of it you know she
didn't she was really scared to have
that talk with me and that was
unfortunate you know you have this
doctor who you know can't even really
begin to have a conversation about
something that actually will help so you
know I think it's uh it's a bit of a
fiasco with the NFL frankly as far as
player wellness and player health goes
but I think that you know even them
having the conversation Roger Goodell
making statements about it there's been
a handful of players in the league now
who have come out and had positive
comments about cannabis as a defensive
end for the Cowboys most recently I
think David Irving
he said you know I know what these pills
do to me I don't want to put him in my
body and there's this plant that I can
use and it helps me helps me feel better
you know and it's really as simple as
that but you know the NFL wants to twist
it into that guy's an individual he is
destructive to the league and you know
he's not NFL caliber so you know I think
that continuing to push the science and
understanding that and also as well as
you know of having a really positive
effect on the NFL's bottom line having
healthier players leave the league
spending less money on pills etc you
know I think that they could make you
know get a benefit from it and the
myriad ways let's include the audience a
little bit do you have any feel free to
jump up to the microphone do you have
any other compelling stories or cases
that have helped like turn people what
are methods that can help become very
potent influencers hi thank you for
doing this
I just want to share that I've been
doing education for about a decade now
and down in San Diego County which was
one of the toughest counties in
California and the average age of the
people I work with is 67 this revelation
in the media that oh the new user of
cannabis is the boomer is I don't buy it
because I've been helping these people
and the the difference is they're afraid
to admit that they use it
my husband 64 he just came out of the
cannabis closet three years ago where
he'll will only say this is what I do to
help with my situation and we believe
that he's alive today because of
cannabis you know Evan not to the degree
that you are but for various health
reasons so I see I've seen thousands of
people over the last ten years really
good success I'm glad to be part of
today I'd like to invite you all to come
and see our Center in Oceanside
California and see what we're doing
thank you what's the name of your second
two
all right this is about connections I
think I have won it we mention hi my
name is Amanda Crawford I'm with my
chain I'm so a couple of things plus a
question would be you know one the the
main question that I've seen really cut
through to people is are you in pain do
you know someone in pain is your mom in
pain what's going on and just being able
to start the conversation from that
point and also at what we're doing with
my Jane is meeting meeting women where
they're at which is they want to stay in
the cannabis closet and they want to be
educated while they're still in the
closet two and a half minutes okay so
you know we're approaching education
kind of from that where we bring it into
people's homes what do you guys see on
the horizon of for education platforms
you know of the future you know I know I
know with um with the media channel that
you have you know do you have any
insights into you know kind of what's
going on you know green flower media is
a great resource but what else are you
guys seeing out there so I you know I
think the the way that new customers or
patients can get educated is somewhat
fractured and people that are in the
closet if you will are probably not
going to pick up a high x they're
probably not going to do much research
online or follow anybody on social media
or go to a cup so I think you know it's
it's one of those things where again we
have to create this normalization in
society and you have to be willing to
share so if somebody isn't out of the
cannabis closet my recommendation is
share with them articles share with them
you know a social media channel that
they want to follow maybe you know they
don't want to follow the gnarliest you
know cannabis heads out there but they
there are tons and tons of social media
channels and videos and articles that
can be shared I try to keep a few going
out to people that I think it can help I
mean you don't want to always you don't
want to be that pushy person because I
think you know when you're in cannabis
and everybody automatically I don't want
to smoke I'm not looking to smoke it I'm
just asking some questions and you're
like I'm not gonna try to smoke with you
right now you're asking me questions I'm
trying to answer them so I think that's
you know compiled some education that
you feel is really helpful
the in-home thing is a beautiful idea I
mean I think I'd love to talk more with
that about with that about you you know
so we can see how we can maybe help with
that that would be amazing
I'll catch you after this I've been
taking acid cannabinoids for about seven
years and I think about sometimes
different types of sports if I were to
compete against people who wasn't taking
it - the fact would I be doping but I
thought well maybe there should be a
team called the th CAS nice and you're
talking raw cannabinoid acids right not
acid and cannabinoids like 9ca
right proper distinction called canna
Club Ivan has spoken to us you're
awesome
thank you I think reaching out to
students college students is a huge huge
thing right now it's I guess moving
forward with the youth even with just
their interest but also with how curious
they are on an academic level so I
really really want not just y'all but
everyone in the room to kind of reach
out to students and teach them we want
to learn about all this and we want to
be part of all this and there are age
demographics to focus on like the older
consumer but students also want to be a
part of that and help older people kind
of get situated with cannabis as well as
us learning simultaneously but I wanted
to thank you Evan for coming and
speaking to us students I really hope
some of you cannabis industry leaders
and professionals take the chance and
educate even the youth and let them know
what this is all about it's not just a
drug it could help their parents it
could help them streamline their
streamline their career and to help
others and yeah I really want to see
more effort with kids college kids and
the college market and see what we could
do as a youth in cannabis excellent you
guys should definitely if you get a
chance go speak at the can of club these
guys are doing great work I mean I think
there's something really to that you
know there should be cannabis 101 at
universities across America I agree you
should be able to take a class and learn
yeah hell yeah our own cannabis 101
curriculum it was organized and designed
by students for students because
administration isn't going to you know
instill a new academic cannabis program
so we started it dr. Chen it took a lot
of time but you know we had the support
of other industry leaders and we had
your support even to even speak to us
and speak to other student athletes but
know we've started a curriculum we have
it every two weeks Kat Packer will be
talking on November 14th speaking about
the current LA atmosphere and stuff on
cannabis but know we've already started
a curriculum and I really hope it gets
to the administration we're doing our
best us students but we also need the
support of I guess the industry leaders
and the people who've been in the game
for longer than we have
so ya know thank you alright this is
great Ben good to see you again good to
see you my name is Michael Masterman
Smith and I'm the cancer biologist here
and I'll be presenting tomorrow on
aspects of Connect Thank You cancer yeah
well I think what you guys are doing
that's sort of my you know scientific
but political contribution because
there's a lot of you know you get when
you reach people on a real level of just
like you know like Kevin says it's like
you know we got some banged up players
they need to be taken care of and my
question is - really I'm I'm trying to
understand this concept
how do we in a political environment
we're supposed to be you know we have to
be advocates for what we're doing but at
the same time where do we decide forget
trying to convince the people that
aren't going to be convinced and how do
we build our relationships anew each
person has an individual is like you
work with dana-farber maybe talk about
what was that like to deal with the
doctors and talk to the doctors
and what was what was that what were
they responsive to and maybe evan answer
this question is is that who was
responsive who were the folks that will
be a part of this a part of this
movement that we can talk to because we
know we're gonna be you know it's it's
almost like let's should we be in denial
of the guys that don't want to do enter
just have some opposition to it and just
focused on who's receptive or maybe what
percentage do we put up the fight to the
ones who don't want to listen and versus
the percentage of folks who are hey
listen we're gonna get all these other
folks on board and let's focus on their
you know give me that give me that
perspective I'll give you that
perspective those are the people who
don't want to learn just don't waste
your time on them because go after the
people who want to learn who want to be
educated because those are the ones that
you're gonna turn into advocates and and
zealots and the future of cannabis the
people who are staunch like sonshi
against it you're gonna waste a lot of
time with those folks get get the large
part of the herd and let them convince
the other guys later on that's what I
that's how I mark it I I would agree
with that and I'll weigh in on the
dana-farber experiences that we found it
was best to be able to speak in their
language you know we we walked in there
with the DNA sequence of the tumor which
Dana Farber loves to sequence tumors you
know and we're like look we have this
yeah and they've worked with Stan Nelson
whose great work in this field it's
sequence for the first glioblastoma
genomes right and so you walk in with
that saying this is pointing to a KT
inhibitors and here's ten papers on
cannabinoids being potent ones
everything else you're offering his face
to be these aren't these aren't you know
they're non-toxic and he was just let's
do it
and so I think it helped going in there
with speaking their language I think if
we didn't have those that sequencing
data and we didn't
those papers he just would have been
like you know if you want to do it for
pain that's fine it's off our books we
don't want to know about it but we're
not giving to get in your way it that
that conversation changed to being okay
let's do the sequencing in his
bloodstream every quarter if we can that
way we can monitor the the mutation that
we found in this blood stream because
the PSA numbers gone we can't trust that
anymore after you went through
immunotherapy it dis wrecked it so that
that really is what I think brought them
in and so I'm glad that you're here
because you're doing this type of work
as well and I think there's more will
convince more oncologists if we are on
that that table with them yeah well I'm
gonna tell you I wouldn't be here if it
wasn't for the audience that would be
interested this is these are things that
is in the cancer community we we were
always a part of it we always knew it
but unless we had a unless you had a
movement behind us we were not really
going to be able to come up here do and
be vocal about it so I'm like that
leading edge and I'm gonna keep on going
and you know you can you can tell all
your friends that yes cannabinoids can
be used to treat cancer we're getting
there and so maybe that's some of the
things that I that folks like me entered
to the conversation but support the
physicians support the folks that are
trying to do the medical aspects of it I
think that's going to be a great
potential but media guy what are you
gonna do when you're in your talks and
in your in your podcast we party last
night I forget you guys are the coolest
you know for us it really is our desire
to become the platform where people feel
comfortable learning about cannabis
whether it's through a podcast whether
it's through watching one of our
broadcasts whether it's through
listening to us on you know or following
us on social media I think you know I
agree with Big Mike about not
necessarily the pursuing people that
don't have a have an inclination to to
embrace cannabis but I think at the same
time it is a round like you do it around
everybody and eventually that one last
person gets split and I think that's
going to take some time you know so for
us it's really about you know trying to
not hype things
you know like this everything is
different for every customer so just
really helping people understand what
they did what edibles will do to you and
what micro dosing means and you know
kind of some of the basics around
consumption is really where we try to
focus because that's where we have them
right at the point-of-sale there that's
they're watching a TV right before
they're about to walk in or it's in the
flower room so we try to have the brands
give have a good call to action and
really try to provide an answer and you
know at least create questions for them
to ask the budtender
when they're you know about to make a
purchase all right thank you very much
gentleman keep up the good work
excellent well we've got one we'll go
one more question because I think some
folks by yury swear food's gonna be
enough happened some announcements
they're cool um so we have a youtube
show a little youtube show that we do on
Sunday afternoons from our little
apartment house in Mount Washington
where we talk about the cannabis news
across the country every week and that's
how we contribute to normalizing
cannabis and it's called DC 420 LA on
YouTube
Sunday's live at 4:20 um and we wrote a
movie about Alice hi Murs and cannabis
to again help normalize it and share
that information to a wider audience and
I mean your mama loves you it's the best
yoga teacher in all of Los Angeles I
love that I love that my mom has I have
so many people come up to me I just
randomly thank you
she hey she helped me get to the NFL
doing yoga at 13
you