good morning everyone thank you for
being here so early and thank you to can
Med for inviting me and to all the
sponsors this is the best Cannabis
Conference that I've been to in a long
time and more and more it's feeling like
a family of people working together in a
common mission
and and it's just beautiful so I'm I'm
so thankful this morning
last night I was talking with my friend
Nicole who thanked me for always making
her feel like she doesn't know anything
after my presentations
and my response was well actually I have
a whole presentation about that tomorrow
but I've never actually designed my
presentations to do that before but
apparently that's the intention today
so I want to show you something that
I've been thinking a lot about over the
last 13 years of clinical practice based
on the observations I've had in my
patients and things that I've found in
the primary literature and how we can
tie that all together to have a better
and deeper understanding of the
potential of cannabis we know that there
is a huge untapped potential in this
plant
and we just don't know exactly where to
look so I'm going to point you in a
certain direction and to do that we
might need to zoom in a little bit we
have a beautiful flower from my backyard
this first picture
and then as we zoom in it starts to look
a little different a little like a
fantasy world and as we get even closer
it starts to look a little bit like an
alien landscape and this is where I want
to take you today suddenly we went from
Cannabis land to mushroom land but um
but when you when you zoom in like this
and you get a deeper understanding of
what's happening in one small part of
the Cannabis world then I think we can
zoom out again with a better
appreciation for the whole so whenever
we zoom in during this presentation
today let's stick with the hole as well
we're going to talk about some cannabis
dosing Trends hormesis and its role in
medicine might be a new term for some of
you
pre-clinical evidence for low and ultra
low dosing
we'll talk about some of the potential
mechanisms of action and then I'll bring
the rubber to the road for some
recommendations for researchers
producers and patients
a lot of you have heard this phrase the
dose makes the poison which is a
paraphrase of a quote from paracelsus
who lived in the 14 and 1500s all things
are poison and nothing is without poison
only the dose allows something to not be
poison
and for the um AV guys in the back thank
you for doing such a good job could you
make my next slide a little bigger I
don't have notes on the PowerPoint so I
don't need that big thing there
so when we overdose on THC we tend to
see paradoxical effects you look at the
list of symptoms that can occur with an
overdose you'll see almost everything
that cannabis could cure or treat at an
appropriate dose nausea vomiting
diarrhea all these GI complaints anxiety
and paranoia it can cause headache
myoclonus hyperkinesis like needing to
move around and twitching and and
confusion and even psychosis now this
most commonly occurs when somebody eats
a delicious looking treat that has an
appetite stimulant in it that makes them
want to eat more or when the poor
patient receives a tube of dark stuff
from one of their friends
uh that really wants to help and tells
them to start with a half grain of rice
and they wake up in the middle of the
night in a acute psychosis not not fun
and and sorry guys in the back I don't
know if I
um you know misspoke but now I've got
the same thing on both sides I'd love to
have one of what I'm talking about and
one of what's coming next if you can
swing that so if you look in my clinical
practice at the oral dosing range that's
been effective and this includes some
outliers we could go all the way down to
.01 milligrams of cannabinoids per
kilogram of body weight of the patient
per day all the way up to 100 milligrams
per kilogram so here we have like a 10
000 fold dosing range which is quite
unusual and like I said there's some
outliers but you I've seen people I'd
start them at one milligram of uh maybe
THC before bed and they sleep well and
they never have to titrate after that
and then we published a case last year
of a woman that was taking around 7 000
milligrams of total cannabinoids daily
with breast cancer and she did really
well with that even these huge doses are
far from the top toxic doses in primates
monkeys were treated with 9 000
milligrams per kilogram of THC and they
survive that even though I'm sure they
did not enjoy that
laughs and now within this huge broad
dosing range we have non-linear dose
response effects which means as you
start at a low dose and titrate up
people will start getting better and
better results until you go past some
threshold and beyond that the patient
starts building tolerance and losing
efficacy so these are non-linear dose
response effects and they show up all
over the pre-clinical literature of
cannabis here's an example of locomotor
activity in rats and as you can see
let's see if I can get my um
my laser to work here
is it up there it's a little dim but as
you can see if you go at a low dose 0.2
milligrams per kilogram of THC locomotor
activity decreases so these rats aren't
running around as much as you increase
the dose of THC the locomotor activity
increases above the Baseline and then as
you increase it even more it goes back
down again
This Is Not Unusual with um with
cannabinoids Not Unusual when
interfacing with a homeostatic
regulatory system and it shows up all
over the place not just in rats but also
in humans and not just with THC but also
with CBD here's an example of a study in
humans that was looking at purified CBD
for treating anxiety and they tested
that with a public speaking Challenge
and you can see here that 300 milligrams
of CBD reduced anxiety 100 did not and
900 did not
there's a sweet spot in there and what
about all the doses that they didn't
test in this study what else are we
missing that's what I want you to keep
asking where are my blind spots and what
else am I missing the 300 milligrams of
CBD could outperform clonazepam and 900
do nothing now throughout the years of
my clinical practice we've had
experience with this I've met a lot of
people that were down here in the red
circle and I taught them how to get back
up here to their optimal dose a dose at
which people do not have tolerance they
maintain efficacy for years or decades
and they have less side effects and
better efficacy
so we have had this experience of
reducing the dose of cannabis and
getting better results
what might be going on down here that we
don't know about
so this is something that's been
interesting me
and there's a there's a concept in
biology that the term was coined in 1943
it's called hormesis and it's derived
from the Greek term to excite it
describes a dose dose response
phenomenon in which a low dose will
stimulate and a high dose can inhibit
and it was discovered using the
fungicidal extract of the red cedar tree
and the researchers
mentioned on this page they they looked
at concentrations of this anti-fungal
and tested it against numerous fungal
species and they notice that at higher
concentrations it was an anti-fungal it
killed the fungus but if you diluted it
enough it would make the fungus grow
faster
why would an anti-fungal at a low
concentration increase the rate of
growth anybody got an idea
I'm I mean it put your hand up if you've
got an idea
sure nobody
all right oh yeah Mike
exactly so he said we have mechanisms
that are designed to detoxify and when
you use those well so how I would frame
this is that when we challenge the cell
with an a toxin at a concentration
that's not high enough to kill it but is
high enough to turn on those Cellular
Defense and repair mechanisms then we
get a net benefit right we we nudge the
health of that cell just enough that
it's upregulated and I think that a lot
of you are familiar with this concept
right the best example in your lives
hopefully is exercise if you exercise
too much you're going to hurt yourself
but if you exercise the right amount
you're providing a stress to your system
that allows it to get stronger so this
is like the what doesn't kill me makes
me stronger and one way in which we
respond to exercises through the
endocannabinoid system here you can see
more than a doubling of anonymide levels
after 30 minutes of running on a
treadmill singers get this from singing
as well
so looking at some of the other things
in our lives you a lot of you may have
heard about Resveratrol this is a
compound in foods that is believed to
have helped the French prevent heart
disease by drinking wine I'm not sure it
works like that this is an antioxidant
and if you look at the potential
benefits you'll see that it kind of
looks like cannabis anti-cancer
anti-aging neuroprotection anti-diabetic
cardio protective and so forth here's a
molecule that does all these different
things and even though it's an
antioxidant the quantities of
Resveratrol that we consume aren't going
to provide orac values that have all of
those effects in our body so what's
Resveratrol doing it's actually up
regulating our endogenous antioxidant
and repair mechanisms so you could think
of it almost like a toxin that's making
us stronger Resveratrol like cannabis
has a lot of hormetic effects and as you
can see on the right this is a rodent
study of a model of heart attack at low
doses of Resveratrol the damage and
apoptosis to the heart is decreased but
if you go too high on the dose of
Resveratrol you actually increase the
damage to the heart you see that so it's
a healthy thing at a low dose but it can
be toxic at a higher dose however let's
look at another model of Resveratrol
here are breast cancer cells and you can
see that at low concentrations it's
accelerating the growth of these cells
but at high concentrations it's
inhibiting how do you get it right
how do we know and how do we use
hormesis in medicine well it's actually
used a lot in medicine here's one
example that some of you may be familiar
with it's called preconditioning
hormesis so if you remember the movie
The Princess Bride the pirate was going
through this battle of wits with the the
clever villain and there was poison that
could be placed in one Goblet of wine or
the other but the pirate put it in both
because he had spent years before this
battle of wits taking tiny doses of the
same Poison every day and gradually
increasing his dose so that if he ever
had this opportunity he would win the
battle
um that's preconditioning hormesis he
took tiny doses of a toxin to upregulate
his endogenous healing mechanisms so
that when he had a big challenge he
could handle it it's not exactly the
same as the idea of probably the old
definition of vaccines who knows what's
happened to the new one but not exactly
the same as that but kind of similar
right expose yourself to a non-lethal
dose of something that could prepare you
for something bigger in the future so
that's preconditioning hormesis and then
there's also post-conditioning hormesis
oops what happened we went back
post-conditioning hormesis which is
probably most well known in Homeopathy
but what a lot of you probably don't
know is that cannabis has been in the
world of Homeopathy since 1841 and you
give tiny tiny tiny doses of cannabis to
people that exhibit the symptoms of
having too much cannabis they haven't
had too much cannabis but those are
their symptoms so you're giving
something similar that could produce
those in a big dose but you're giving it
such a small dose that the body will
correct it'll again upregulate these
corrective mechanisms in our physiology
so how does cannabis work well I think a
lot of us are focused on the way in
which it mimics and supports our innate
stress response Pathways but could it
also act as a hormetic stressor and I'm
going to show you some evidence that it
certainly can and I want to orient you
to this ultra low dose now it's
impossible to convert a dose that's
injected into a rodent into an oral dose
for humans but I do my best here so um a
lot of these studies I'm about to show
you use
.002 milligrams of THC per kilogram of
body weight of the rodent
intraperitoneal injection is about five
times better absorbed than oral there's
this kind of allometric scaling law from
rodents to people and so what we might
end up with is somebody my size uh
having or a little a little smaller than
me having like a 20th of a milligram of
THC orally this is the kind of dosing
range that I'm about to show you
something between like a hundred and a
half of milligram of THC let's just give
it a range okay so we're actually going
to start out just a little bit lower
here's a study from 2007 in which a
single injection of .001 milligrams per
kilogram had a significant negative
impact on the performance of the mice
three weeks later and their their
performance was in a stressful memory
test called The Morris water maze test
okay one teeny injection measure them
three weeks later compared to vehicle
and the ones that got the small dose of
THC did worse
also interestingly when you give a high
dose of THC to rodents they get
hypothermia analgesia and decreased
Locomotion also catalepsi but they
didn't do that in this study give this
tiny dose of THC to the rodents and they
get the opposite they get warmer they
get sensitive to pain and they and they
run around more what the heck is going
on here we saw these paradoxical effects
with an overdose now we're seeing
paradoxical effects with an underdose or
maybe the 10 Megs per kig is the
overdose it's hard to say so then a
subsequent study looked at .002
milligrams per kilogram a single
injection which was able to induce
measurable cognitive deficits in normal
mice five months later give them a
single shot of .002 measure them five
months later compared to the vehicle and
and you can determine that they're
impaired and and you can measure
different Pathways have been up
regulated in the cerebellum five months
later in mice after a single injection
now what's strange about these mice
they're normal
that's the strangest thing about them
something that I can't claim about any
of you out there or about myself
because who who Among Us is a wild type
with no other toxins or challenges in
their life right so what happens when we
treat mice that maybe have a challenge
in their life so this is a
toxin called
penciling tetrazole and it was injected
at a high dose 60 milligrams per
kilogram it's known to produce
neurotoxicity and in this study the
researchers administered that same
single dose of THC but either before the
toxic challenge or after so
preconditioning or post-conditioning
like we talked about one three or seven
days before or one or three days after
the behavioral tests evaluated different
aspects of memory and learning three to
seven weeks later and what these
researchers found was that both the
preconditioning and the
post-conditioning administration of
ultra low-dose THC completely
obliterated the damage from the toxic
Challenge and demonstrated reduced
phosphorylated erk activity
so we have evidence of ultra low-dose
pre and post conditioning and a toxic
challenge this is the difference between
using cannabis and isolated environment
where it could actually reduce the
function because you're giving it maybe
a tiny bit of a toxin versus using it to
up regulate the healing now it doesn't
just do that in the brain it does that
in the heart here's a single low dose
administered two hours before a
myocardial infarction look at the size
of the infarct difference in that bar
graph and that was the best result but
if you administered it 48 hours before a
heart attack you still got measurable
statistically significant cardio
protection if you gave the same load
dose every day for three weeks in Step
24 hours before the heart attack still
got cardio protection what could these
ultra low doses be doing it's not just
in the brain not just in the heart it's
also in the liver here's liver enzyme
measurements when the ultra low dose of
THC was administered two hours before an
ischemia reperfusion injury in rodents
and you can see much lower levels of alt
and AST on the right on the left it's
the Sham group that just got the surgery
but not the liver injury
so so that's all just purified THC and
an ultra low dose just a little sample
of what's out there and then here we
have
um a lower dose but not ultra low dose
three milligrams per kilogram per day
given to mice that had uh cognitive
decline so these are old mice they're
exhibiting signs of dementia give them
this low dose of THC for a month and it
restored the gene transcription patterns
so that the expression of these THC
treated 12-month-old mice was almost
identical to the two-month-old mice
literally like turned the gene
expression in their mind around in their
brain around here's here's a map just to
remind you that we're dealing with a lot
of complexity here these are all the
genes that had a change from uh compared
to vehicle all of these different genes
were upregulated in pink and some were
down regulated and the pathways are
interrelated we are living in such a
complex this diagram makes me think of
like trying to use our equipment to
understand something that's much more
intelligent than us right and and we're
getting there but we're definitely not
there I'm sure this is also just the tip
of the iceberg
so now we're back to ultra low dose 24
month old mice injected with the .002
milligrams per kilogram performs
significantly better than those that did
not get that injection or not get the
THC and perform similarly to mice age
two months so the last study was low
dose every day for 28 days this was a
single ultra low dose injection restored
24 month old mice to the behavior levels
of two month and that effect lasted for
seven weeks
what the heck is going on here in this
ultra low dose range and the pathways by
which this worked some of them were
elucidated sir two and one is a pathway
that's gaining a lot of attention kind
of in the biohacking world and oh yeah
and then the MRI just demonstrated
larger volume and higher tissue density
in various regions of the brain and the
mice that receive the THC it actually
changed the volume of their brain a
single ultra low dose measurable
differences for seven weeks and then the
last rodent model I'll show you this is
a familial Alzheimer's disease model
mice that were either six or twelve
months were given a single low-dose
injection ultra low dose injection and a
lot of cognitive tests what's
interesting here is on the left that's
the water Morris maze the higher levels
oh okay so dark is vehicle light is
ultra low dose WT means the wild type
the healthy mice and the TG means
transgenic the Alzheimer's mice and if
you just look at Alzheimer's mice you
can see getting that ultra low dose of
THC really improve their performance on
this water maze test it also improved
the performance a little bit of the wild
type mice if you look at the novel
location recognition in the middle you
can see the wild type was a trend
towards decreased performance and same
in the Y maze so again we have the same
thing that might be gently hurting wild
type mice helping mice that have a
disease that's an important point and
then yesterday we heard about the trick
B1 receptor pathway for bdnf well these
transgenic Alzheimer's mice they express
a truncated trip B receptor that's not
functional it's like a broken receptor
and the ratio of that broken receptor to
the fully functional receptor determines
our capacity to respond to bdnf and grow
new neurons and new synapses and heal
the brain and you can see here also the
ultra low dose of THC significantly
reduce the expression of that truncated
receptor meaning their bdnf pathway
pathway was work looking better
so these what are the mechanisms we
talked about hormesis but I want to go
beyond hormesis into pharmacodynamic and
pharmacokinetic Synergy that means how
they're working together or how they're
absorbed and metabolized because so far
we've only talked about THC but let's
look at cbda for example now the scale
here is micrograms per kilogram not
milligrams per kilogram and you can see
here that half or one microgram per
kilogram of cbda reduces nausea and
rodents which is very different from CBD
you can see the effectiveness of CBD is
here at 5 or 10 milligrams per kilogram
not half of a microgram per kilogram so
much higher potency not you know what
else you see with the CBD picture is the
um
there we go so you can see that um at
very high doses of CBD even without the
lithium chloride challenge even just
with saline you get some nausea and at
the 20 and 40 milligrams per kilogram
you get an exacerbation of the effects
of the lithium chloride which is what
causes the nausea so we're back to this
biphasic dose response model right
there's a sweet spot in there so um so
what about combinations here's a study
that looked at Ultra low-dose thca and
cbda in combination for nausea these are
tiny tiny doses
.0001 milligrams per kilogram of cbda
another very low dose of thca these two
doses on their own are not effective put
them together and you see that they are
effective with the bar graph that goes
down in the middle and then if you block
the P power Alpha receptor you
ameliorate that benefit and if you block
the serotonin receptor it goes away as
well
similar things happen with cbda and pain
here you see 10 micrograms per kilogram
of cbda reducing hyperalgesia but a
thousand micrograms per kilogram meaning
one milligram per kilogram not reducing
hyperalgesia there's another sweet spot
here do you need the tiniest little bit
of cbda maybe it's it's hard to know
this is a model of inflammatory pain
and the cbda was only effective when
given before the inflammatory Challenge
and that was given via injection however
if you give it orally and you give it
with a teeny bit of THC a bit of THC on
its own that does nothing so now we're
at 100 micrograms per kilogram but when
you give them together orally it works
that's what we're seeing here and it
even works when you give it after the
inflammatory insult so it works even
better than than the cbda on its own at
the precise dose when it's injected
what's going on with cbda here's an
example of pharmacokinetic interactions
this was a beautiful study from Jonathan
Arnold's group in Australia they tested
a whole plant compound which you see on
the left it's got just about everything
in it you know acidics and neutrals and
then they tested the exact same doses of
those isolated substances for oral
bioavailability in rodents and this is
what you would expect to find when you
administer lipophilic compounds together
they can compete with absorption and so
you would expect to see better
absorption from purified CBD than the
same dose of CBD given in the context of
this extract
so that's a normal finding this was the
unexpected finding cbda when
administered in the context of the full
plant extract was much much better
absorbed 14 times better absorbed than
the same dose given on its own
why is cbda absorbed so much better when
it's given in the full plant extract
well these researchers determined that
there's an e-flex pump called the bcrp
that kicks these cannabinoids back into
the Lumen of the intestine as they're
being absorbed but if you have a little
bit of CBG or a little bit of THC in
there it blocks the function of this
efflux pump in relation to cbda and it
makes you absorb much more cbda so 14
times the absorption when there's a tiny
bit of THC or CVG we haven't proven this
in humans but we do have some human data
that shows that cbda is much much better
absorbed than CBD again in in these
studies it was between 5 and 11 times
better absorbed thca is 32 to 51 times
better absorbed than THC just remarkable
so we're going to bring it home right
now and I just want to remind you that
there's a lot of cannabinoids in the
plant
and we're exposed to them at ultra low
doses all the time
what is going on here we don't know but
we can have a direct relationship with
the plant to help us find out I'm going
to skip through one example of clinical
data because I want to get to my
recommendations and maybe a question or
two so for researchers I encourage you
to take what you've learned today and
design studies that include a range of
doses or concentrations that can reveal
non-linear dose response effects and
please don't don't forget to go down a
microgram per kilogram rodent studies if
you have the opportunity to do so
because you probably find some very
interesting things down there
test trace cannabinoids and other
phytoconstituents alone and in
combinations we have Hina needs and
daddy that have been doing this and
that's really exciting that's where this
research needs to go
for producers I encourage you to test a
broad to include a broad range of
compounds try to get as much from that
flower into the bottle as you can avoid
complete decarboxylation because even
tiny bits of these acidic cannabinoids
go a long way as you could see they
might actually go a longer way than
higher Doses and please make your labels
and certificates of analysis easy to
understand I just uh that's a big
problem in this industry I don't think
it's been mentioned much it should be
easy for a patient to know how much
they're getting per drop or per serving
here's an example of a part of the COA
from a Healer product called balance
which includes 19 chemovars six of them
are CBD dominant type 3 and the rest are
type one we blend as many together as we
can it's half decarboxylated it's got
equal proportions of CBD cbda THC thca
this is like a shotgun product I hope
that eventually we know here's the
specific chemother for this specific
problem and this specific person with
their current functional status and
their genetics we're far from that right
now so until I can get my laser pointer
and a sniper rifle we're going to go
with the shotgun right the balance for
clinicians and patients I encourage you
to explore this oral dosing range in
your patients don't start too high this
means starting as low as half a
milligram or maybe one milligram for the
average adult and if you do that and you
take your time and wait they might not
get great results the next morning and
be like oh my God that was amazing my
life has changed you gave me my life
back I know it feels really good to hear
that but if they stay consistent with
low doses for a little while they'll get
some impressive results you'll be
surprised
and that's especially with acidic
cannabinoids and whole plant
preparations and titrate slowly if
possible
use cannabis to improve resilience to
stress don't always think about it for
treating a disease think about what
could it do to up regulate your natural
healing mechanisms turning on these
intrinsic mechanisms May provide better
results than just ameliorating symptoms
because you're getting healthier you're
getting stronger you're getting more fit
for your environment your homeostatic
physiology is functioning more
efficiently and that's not only going to
make you feel better but prevent future
disease instead of just covering up a
symptom without addressing the
underlying vulnerability so watch for
gradual changes healing versus symptom
relief and secondary outcomes and side
benefits
and know yourself
cannabis is very complex but so are you
and you have a direct relationship with
this plant or at least the capacity to
do so so the Cannabis State of
Consciousness can be extremely
empowering for self-awareness and body
awareness one can use a little bit of
THC and actually go inside and feel and
get extremely accurate messages about
what's happening inside of them so allow
the Consciousness shifting aspect of
cannabis from time to time to help you
get better in touch with yourself with
all our healer products we include these
guides so people can check in with
themselves do the inner inventory write
it down on the worksheet and so forth
and then my last recommendation page if
you're a patient and you're not using
acidic cannabinoids I highly encourage
you to do so easiest way is take a
little bud and throw it in your morning
tea or coffee you'll steep it you'll get
a little bit out of that and I can tell
you more about that if you need to avoid
tolerance in most cases so check out
that sensitization protocol if you feel
like you're over you using you'll have a
much healthier and more fruitful
relationship with cannabis if you
reverse tolerance and then be aware of
the subtle benefits try a variety of
chemovirus and blends of chemovirus and
and the cannabis tea is just a great
thing for a lot of people thank you so
much
foreign
for your great talk and your great work
I wanted to ask you a what do you think
how low would you go
would you
touch that
um humans
humans
uh what what is the line between going
low and
party yeah so I think that um well
because I've seen results in adults at
half a milligram of an active
constituent today that's how low I go
right now I don't like to waste a lot of
people's time and that might still be a
time waster I skipped over a study in
fibromyalgia of women with fibromyalgia
where they started at one about one
milligram of THC per day and were
titrated only every 10 days and they had
fabulous results with with that type of
titration they went from one to two you
know every 10 days so something low and
slow to me sounds like that half a
milligram to one milligram
good morning Dustin thank you so much
and for your spirit here
um question so titrating to find that
optimal dosage how about for tolerance
breaks do you is it cold turkey titrate
down what's your recommendation for that
so the way I've framed the sensitization
protocol on healer.com involves 48 Hours
of abstinence from Cannabis but it's
very intentional and I have all sorts of
videos to hold your hand through that
and give you exercises bright breathing
meditations things to to get you through
that there's a lot that you can do to
get go through that 48 hours but a lot
of there's one fmri study in men at
least that were heavy cannabis smokers
that showed after just 48 Hours of
abstinence their CB1 receptors in the
brain return to normal levels so I think
that's one beautiful thing about
cannabis is we don't need super long
tolerance breaks 48 hours can do it but
then we continue with three days that
the key to the sensitization protocol
isn't just the tolerance break it's what
you do afterwards it's how you change
your relationship with the plant to
listen to its effects on your body body
so that you don't get into a tolerance
problem again in the future so that's
what's happening over the next three
days very careful titration and you can
get that all it's all complementary on
healer.com I'm out of time thank you so
much it's great to be here with you