[Music]
great I think we we touched on how
people acquire it what the difference
stages are we briefly touched about
different treatments now is that a
rabbit hole that we can go down it's a
bit of a rabbit hole what what I would
suggest when people get if people get
Lyme disease and the initial treatment
isn't
enough then a great thing to do is um
there's a few resources one is to look
up um your local Li many especially if
you're in a major urban area or in a
largely populated state there's going to
be Lyme disease support groups he
contact them he say I'm really sick my
initial treatment is not working I'm
looking for names of doctors who
specialize in treating L because it
really is a specialty it's called Lim
literate um is a is a term to use I'm
looking for a lime literate physician
there's another organization called
ilads it's called International lme and
Associated disease Society they they
really have established a protocol for
this and that's where uh your lime
literate Physicians get their training
from you can go to their website and do
a search for doctors trained in your
area um and find somebody to talk to
most of the time these people will not
be accepting insurance and
so uh good rule of thumb is to get a get
a good quality rule out if you're sick
sick and and you want to know if you
truly have Lyme disease or not you
probably expect to spend somewhere
around $1,000 oh wow yeah just to find
out if you have really yeah what if
you're talking about spending a doctor
$200 an hour for their time and then the
testing is generally out of
pocket and the testing would be from
those lime literate Physicians and not
um well they would they would draw the
last but there's there's a few Labs that
really because I told you the testing so
bad the standardized test there's yeah
Labs that are fully credited in good
Labs but they they they're not uh
insurance coverage uh generally because
they do their own assays um and so
they're that's uh but they do a good job
and that's usually where these um
doctors will send the
tests okay yeah and I have to imagine
too I mean at least from my own
experience with with finding the deer
tick it's tiny I mean I think they
describe it's like the size of a sesame
seed yeah the nips can be that small yep
so I imagine that you know like perhaps
in your case too where you have some of
that that summer flu or something or
that you know that sickness that you
just can't kick and you know attributed
to oh it's a virus or something but it
really could have been yeah my you
sometimes people don't know they're a
bit my dad almost died last year uh he
was in the emergency room in and out for
for three days they didn't know what was
wrong with him and he kept getting
fevers and and his organs were
failing and I showed up and I said have
you tested for ticks and they went what
do you do for living never you mind and
I was right and then they gave him my ab
biotics and he bounced right back wow
yeah yeah and so that didn't develop
into some sort of persistent condition
no because it was it was a it was that
was a that was a rare kind of case where
it hit him hard and fast and it was
anaplasmosis that was really um tanking
him um and that and that happens
sometimes I me he's old say 80 and and
yeah sometimes that happens
[Music]
a