[Music]
when we started working on cannabinoids
which was many many many years ago in
the 60s we isolated quite a large number
of compounds in in hashish which is the
resin of cannabis and of course there
was a cannabidiol the major compound we
looked in collaboration with many
friends that the activity of some of
these compounds but we still don't know
much about them for example there is a
compound which we called canopy Jarrow
we know very little about it it seems to
have anti-cancer properties but it has
to be looked into in much more an
underbite has never been given to a
human so we don't know what it does
when administered to a human which is
again a strange situation we know that
it's not toxic we know that it it is
formed in the body when needed and
immediately broken down nobody has seen
any major side effects in animals and
yet it has never been administered to a
human although it was discovered by us
in 1990 to compare this to what happened
with insulin when insulin was discovered
in the body in the 20s in Canada within
six months it became a drug it was given
to a few patients after they found it is
not toxic given to a few patients
insulin was found to lower diabetes and
it became a drug excellent red still
widely used we synthesized new compounds
which are much more active than
cannabidiol so we are developing them
and hopefully they can become the new
drugs the moment we have more practical
things looking at endogenous
cannabinoids like compounds which seem
to be of major importance basically what
I'm doing at the moment is collaborate
with a huge number of people and we do
the chemistry so there is
think that we can start initiate we do
the chemistry my collaborators do the
biology in different fields and together
we come up with a with something that
hopefully contributes we do a lot of
research and it involves investment in
in the people that they do the work in
my lab I have a small group with two or
three people working part-time you have
to find money to support the lab and
support the people that work in the lab
there's two basic things that have to be
learned
strangely enough still after so many
years we don't know enough about the
compounds the activity of the compounds
in the plant itself very strange but
that's where we are we know a lot about
THC we know a lot of CBD but we know
very little about some of the other
compounds
[Music]
you