[Music]
welcome to the CED Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I'm the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and proud member of
the team who puts on the C Med
conference a few housekeeping items
before we introduce this episode's guest
check out cam at events.com for all the
latest information about the camed 24
Innovation and investment Summit
happening this may in Marco Island
Florida camed 24 is an all-inclusive
event featuring worldclass content
fourstar accommodations ample networking
opportunities and meals and drinks
included be sure to sign up for email
Emil alerts at cam events.com so you
don't miss any announcements leading up
to this year's event if you plan to join
us in Florida I encourage you to buy
your tickets now space is limited this
year and rooms are filling up and if you
can't join us this year you can still
stay connected with the camed Community
by following us on social media we're on
Instagram Facebook X and Linkedin just
search for camet events you can also
enjoy free access to all the podcast
archive episodes as well as videos of
all the past canmed presentations in our
canmed video archive at canmed
events.com our guest this episode is Dr
Kimberly Gwyn Kim is a professor of
Entomology and Plant Pathology at the
University of Tennessee her lab
currently investigates natural products
that are produced by plants and microbes
and their use as medicines and as
biopesticides at C 24 she will present
hemp processing byproducts as
biopesticides which describes her team's
work using tpine Rich Industrial Hemp
byproducts to control plant diseases and
pests we discuss why tpin are effective
biopesticides which pathogens imp pest
tpine Rich biopesticides can fight what
are nanoions and why are they important
to this application how this technology
can open up a new Revenue stream for
Growers the regulatory lift for getting
biopesticides approved and more before
we get to my conversation with Kim I'd
like to thank this episode sponsor Rare
Earth
genomics Rare Earth genomics is a
dynamic partnership formed with Texas
A&amp;M agralife one of the world's leading
research institutions to accelerate hemp
research and create tools for Farmers
their mission is to increase the
likelihood of a successful Harvest for
Farmers through genetic analysis and
rigorous Environmental Testing of
vigorous cultivars learn more at
rareearth
genomics. okay and without any further
Ado please enjoy my conversation with Dr
Kimberly Gwyn
[Music]
good morning Kim thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast good morning
it is delightful to be here all right I
am excited to talk with you today about
a novel technology that you and your
team have developed to use hemp derived
tpin as
biopesticides of course you will be
presenting this work at camed 24 this
may in Marco Island um but I think a
good place to start with this
conversation would be for you to explain
how your team came up with this idea and
why you started investigating it uh I
have been very interested in uh
biopesticides for a number of years I
think that they are uh a good way for we
that we can do be more environmentally
uh friendly in
agriculture um one of the problems with
biopesticides is where do we get our
materials and so I have been looking in
several different areas for agricultural
byproducts
and those byproducts uh can bring more
uh Revenue to Growers so that that was
kind of my uh take on it my colleague Dr
Tony Wong is a food scientist and she's
uh been very involved in developing
these Nano emulsions uh for different
reasons and so we've teamed together to
develop this
biopesticide excellent so what kind of
LED you down the path of using tpin from
uh as the hemp
byproducts yeah Tarpin are great tpin
are like one of these things that we can
use for a number of different things you
think about Tarpin you think about their
smell right they're volatile so they can
be used to prevent things from happening
like an insect Landing they can also be
used to encourage an insect to land so
you've got to be very careful uh they uh
will also affect how a fungus can grow
so uh and they are they are part of the
plant's natural defense system so what
we are doing is taking the H the hemp
we're we're not we're just using hemp in
this in this work uh we take the hemp
and we use its natural defense chemicals
and we use those turn those around and
bottle them and turn them into an
emotion and then uh use them as
biopesticide so when you talk about you
know byproducts so is this hemp being
grown particularly for CBD or
cannabinoids and then so you're sort of
using the the castoff tpes to to create
this biopesticide correct correct we are
we are only looking at what is coming
from the CBD uh because that is where a
lot of thines are being uh discarded
when they're just when they go for the
cannabinoids then the Turpin are left
behind and that's what we are interested
in
great
so do Growers need to sort of modify how
they're already getting the cannabinoids
to be able to sort of access these tpin
how does that
work um I think you know the product at
least in hemp is is the CBD and is the
cannabinoid so they the uh manufacturers
the extractors want to maximize that um
and leaving behind the Tarpin is not
part of their uh their business plan
they don't really care about the turpins
uh except you know whenever you're
looking at the whole product then you do
care about the turpins because that's
what allows you to have particular types
of smells and
tastes
great so you mentioned before that
you've been investigating biocontrol
agents for quite some time so what are
some other solutions that are available
to Growers and how how do they differ
from this approach
um if you look at the epa's list of uh
pesticides that are approved for hemp
production uh you will find B pretty
much only biopesticides I think there's
one conventional and it's a herbicide um
most of them are uh from the name plant
and also some microorganisms so some
microorganisms are very very helpful in
uh controlling the natural environment
on the plant so plants are just like us
they have a microbiome so part of their
microbiome is actually effectively bites
off the pathogens so what we do with a
biocontrol agent is we we put that on
the plant and help the plant stimulate
its natural defenses and also some of
those actually actively fight against
pathogens so so you mentioned hemp
specific spefically so that was going to
be one of my questions was is this
biocontrol agent specific to whether it
be hemp or cannabis or could this
potentially be used on other crops as
well we've expanded to other crops we've
we've been testing some cucurbits uh
this past year uh both in the greenhouse
and in the field excellent and now what
are the pathogens that you're sort of
targeting with this approach you
mentioned insects um is it also I know
there's there's fungi there's bacteria
there's weeds is it sort of all of the
above or there specific ones that you're
looking for um one of the things that
you have to be careful about when you
develop a natural biopesticide is it's
that it is not phytotoxic so it in it's
very very uh most concentrated form that
we could possibly make it could be used
as an herbicide but that's probably not
going to be where we go with it right uh
it's been we've uh actually been able to
control uh powdery mildew on on him with
this and it's worked as well as any of
the commercial
products better than some of them too oh
wow yeah and that's I know powdery Milo
that's one of the the big ones what
other sort of targets are you looking
for uh I've just recently switched my
interest to uh fusarium pathogens and so
we've been screening uh different
fusarium pathogens this hasn't been done
on the plant but it's been done in the
lab
and uh we have very effective growth
control on the on the
fusarium excellent um so you mentioned
Nano Emulsion um for those listeners and
hosts who might not be familiar with
what exactly that is could you sort of
explain well let's go back to the very
Basics on it the very Basics are what is
an Emulsion so you can think about an
Emulsion is very very simple as making
salad dressing you take your oil and
your vinegar and you shake it and you
get something that looks very different
than oil and vineger that's an Emulsion
well that's going to be a very very weak
Emulsion it's going to separate out in
some cases before you can even get it
out of the bottle onto your salad but
what we do with a nanoemulsion is we
make those kind those uh little oil
droplets very very very small Nano means
like 10 to the 9th when you're talking
about things
uh and so we we make these very small
and we suspend the Tarpin in these uh
compounds in these little oil bubbles
essentially and they uh will stay in
solution we've been able to keep them on
the lab bench at room temperature uh for
over two years W and so it's in
water it's in water and we use a natural
um soap it's called Uh
tween uh and basically uh we are going
for things that are extremely safe so we
use only use products in what we're
doing that are considered to be grass
and grass is
gas and it's an FDA category that's
gener generally regarded as safe so the
bottom line is this is a pesticide that
you could probably eat no I wouldn't
advise it you could probably you could
probably eat it it smells very strong uh
but it's um but it we are trying to make
it as safe as
possible excellent no I'm glad you
brought that up because obviously yeah
tpin they they smell and so if you're
adding these to the plant is it going to
affect I mean if it's if it's cannabis
it's one thing but um if you're if
you're looking to put this on other
crops is it going to affect the smell
Taste of those crops
um I think that we would have a limit of
how late we can spray this on on some
crops for example you wouldn't want to
dunk your Apple in it and keep that as a
post Harvest uh but if you spray uh like
the C cbits uh we didn't affect the the
quality of those um by doing early earli
earlier sprays we did not spray the
fruit themselves so in you know in most
cases we're not looking for the plant as
the uh product we're looking at you know
a fruit so you just have to be careful
when you can spray those and also
remember that that Tarpin are ephemeral
even ours will eventually uh go away but
I have a feeling that we won't be using
them on post Harvest because I think it
will affect consumer
taste great and now there are a number
of different tpin that the plant
produces as well are there specific ones
that you're interested in um we have we
have not focused on any specific one and
the reason is we want to be able to use
uh these uh
byproducts and so we have used uh by
we've done this technology for a couple
of different uh
extractions and uh we we seem to get the
same effects so uh I think when an
extractor goes in they you know they
have all kinds of different plant types
and cultivars that they're using uh so
we really can't control that if we're
using it as a waste product so we just
we do we do have this analyzed and we
know what the the Tarpin are we know
what you know residual CBD is there uh
and it's um but we are trying our best
not to really pay that much attention to
that look at look at it as a whole
product but um the ones that are are the
ones that we we when we test them in the
lab are anti-fungal and uh anti-insect
com okay so is this not limited to just
tpin or I mean I know I just I just
spoke with a gentleman who published
this whole paper about other um
compounds that produce Aromas there's
Esters and all these other uh names that
I'm not I can't recall um so are those
coming along for the ride too or are you
kind of specifically sticking to tping
we've focused on tpin because that's
really what is the dominant smell in
there we know those those will provide
the uh compound the the activities that
we are interested in um
yeah cannabis SAA is like the miracle
plant as far as metabolism goes it
produces so many different compounds uh
I think there's a there's a paper out
there from several years ago that calls
it the plants of thousands of
molecules and um it's you know we don't
know what's coming along for the ride we
do know that CBD we have a you know a
small percentage of uh the CBD uh is in
there as well and some of the
CBG and so is the extraction technique
that's used does that play a role here
too are there certain ones that are
better for this than others we've been
looking primarily at ones that have had
an ethanol extraction we um I don't I
don't know that the same type of U
material is evolved when you use super
critical great and now so what is the
goal here
um is it that eventually Growers will be
able to sort of formulate their own
biopesticides or um is that something
that sort of a a specific company that
needs to do yeah I think you're probably
going to have to have that done by
somebody because our our equipment is
very expensive
uh it's uh so it is uh it's a high
sonication you can make it but it's not
going to be as good as ours it's not
going to stay in solution you can make
it with a with a sonicator uh but this
is a high speed sonicator and we've
spent a lot of time getting the
conditions that we do we produce it just
right I mean but if you have that
material you can certainly replicate it
we've publ
our
methods so but could it be something
that you know Growers sort of um I mean
it be an extra Revenue stream for them
that they could be providing that um
that waste material to to your company
or whoever whoever is going to develop
this um and turn that into that's the
dream yeah the dream is to get extra
revenue for Growers get a safe
biopesticide uh for
producers and uh you know expand this
because you know if you have something
that is uh naturally broken down by what
whatever is in the environment on the
plant in the soil and that type of thing
that's these natural products are broken
down easily more easily than
synthetics uh and then you so you have
something that's environmentally
friendly you have something that Growers
get an extra Revenue stream from um and
that you know and works so if you have
all of those three things you've got the
kind of the pillars of developing a a
biopesticide great and so where are we
at in terms of sort of evaluating
whether it works or actually getting to
Market so kind of where are you at there
well I'm I'm hoping that the interest
from cmed will bring people around that
that want to invest in it to be honest
with you uh we would love to see this go
into a uh a company and uh develop
this technology so that it could be
available to
everyone yeah and so what is sort of
the how how do you get something like
this approved um what are the sort of
agencies that that dictate that it's uh
it's EPA and the uh there are there are
rules for biopesticides for uh
developing those that are less stringent
than um those for synthetics because
most of the those things are natural uh
so we would go through the EPA uh we
would we would then you know we would
tell them everything that's in ours uh
and how it is used and how it's
formulated and then we would uh show
them the efficacy because they don't
approve it unless it's going to it's
going to work uh and uh they will do
that but they have approved other
essential oils like garlic oil uh
rosemary oil those types of things are
already approved as biopesticides and
some of the same tpin are in those as
well yeah that was going to be one of my
questions too because I know that you
know cannabis hemp that's not the only
plant that produces tpin so are there
other other products out there that
utilize tpin yes and then that
essentially when you hear the word
essential oil that's probably a tping
mix um we've looked at in the past I've
looked at tping from a uh genus of
called menarda which is B bomb and it's
got the most amazing different types of
turpins based on cultivar we actually
were able to chemotype them by their um
by their turpine chemistry so you had
mentioned other biocontrol agents before
and that sometimes they use actually
microbes whether it be bacteria or
things like that and I know that those
can actually contribute to some of these
total count tests um that Growers need
to pass in order to get the products to
Market whether it's total yeast and mold
or total bacteria so I would imagine
that this would be helpful for for those
Growers because uh it's not using those
microbes right and that that's one of
those things as we talked about the you
know when the when you harvest uh you
know this might be helpful in uh
reducing the those counts um but we
we've tested it against fusarium which
is one of the pathogens that affects the
inflorescence but we haven't done any
other testing so for right now that's
sort of conjecture on my part but it's
something that we definitely want to
look into yeah that's sounds definitely
promising I know that you know Growers
are struggling a lot with aspergilus um
being one of them and um imp pythium as
well so um I'm sure those are already on
your radar asilis is definitely on our
radar because asilis can cause problems
in humans
it can colonize the lungs and cause a
syndrome called
asilios and um that has been connected
with cannabis use but in but in immune
compromised people yeah exactly yeah
it's rare um but something we definitely
uh we like to test for all right Kim
well winding down here I want to give
you the opportunity to share any other
links uh that or mention any other
resources that folks might be interested
to read more about sort of the work that
you're doing um and also any websites
social media any ways that folks can
kind of get in touch with you or learn
more about the work you're
doing um I'm sort of an old school
scientist so I don't have a lot of
social media presence um but uh we are
working right now on some of the
fusarium pathogens looking at how to
control those in the inflorescence and
looking at the potential that they have
for uh
producing mot toxins so we're looking at
that as that's where my a lot of my
future work will be
focused um and hopefully we I can
combine these two and we can use this to
control uh fusarium uh in the INF
fluorescences because I think that it's
probably more of a problem than we think
lots of fusarium disease out there in
Greenhouse production as well as field
production yeah absolutely I mean we are
kind of just launched a new fusarium
assay uh for Growers which has been uh
very popular and um I know that there's
one scientist that's going to be at
caned um Dr zamir punja who's done a lot
of research into that so hopefully you
guys can uh can connect him Marco Island
yeah zamir and I have published together
and we actually right we're at the same
institution at one point so we're very
familiar with each other all right well
then you guys will get to catch up yeah
excellent well thanks again Kim for the
time um and I look forward to meeting
you in person at K at24 all right thank
you and I will uh I'll see you there
great
[Music]
bye I hope you enjoyed my conversation
with Kimberly Gwyn check out the links
in the show description to learn more
about the topics we discussed and thanks
to this episode sponsor Rare Earth
genomics our next episode drops May 1st
that's 2 weeks from today in the
meantime go to camat events.com to check
out all the details related to canmed 24
speakers poster presenters networking
events panels workshops meals and more
all the information is there while
you're at camet events.com sign up for
email alerts so you don't miss any
announcements before the event if you
are planning to join us in Florida this
may register for your ticket package now
space is limited and tickets are going
fast I also invite you to follow us on
social media we are on LinkedIn
Instagram X and Facebook just search for
cam at events and lastly please rate
review And subscribe so you don't miss
an
episode all right that's it from us stay
safe stay healthy and be sure to join us
for the next CAG Coffee Talk
[Music]