hello everyone thank you very much
um
so
making cbd a drug
that's what i was going to talk about in
2020 and i'm really sorry to do the bait
and switch on you we were really looking
forward to do that project but um
a few things came up
and uh this is what we're going to be
talking about today
so
uh
yeah 2022.
thank
goodness um
so
first about who we are um we're
deliclabs um we're a contract research
organization
we
prize collaboration with everyone we can
we we want to try and bring as much of
the scientific method as possible to
counters we want to try and make
information more widely available
we do a lot of collaboration with the
university of british columbia we're
actually based
on campus-ish
so we've got access to a lot of
instrumentation that a regular lab just
simply cannot afford
through our industry collaborations
but we also like to do a lot of
collaborations with other people in the
cannabis space
moniker and linda two examples of that
so our research topics are
chemistry we're we're a bunch of
chemistry nerds who who that's
that's what makes us happy that's what
we do
um
i'm the
uh
my background is computational medicinal
chemistry so drug design and molecular
modeling
and i'm sort of on board as data and
that that side of things
the rest of them are very interested in
organic synthetic chemistry analytical
chemistry
uh and those sorts of things
um
what we work on is anything that is a
biomolecule and is regulated that's
that's what gets us off
so
we're lucky enough in canada that we
have what's called a section
45 54. oh god my dyslexia is kicking in
i think it's section 54
which is an exemption to do psychedelic
research so we can work with a whole
range of interesting biomolecules we're
doing some dmt stuff some psilocybins
some solution
and those sorts of things
but today i'm going to talk about a
client project we did
our client
unfortunately i can't talk as much about
this as i would like to
i can say our client was a multinational
we were trying to develop an enhanced
cbd vape
and what they engaged us to do was a
virtual ligand screening so we're
screening
potential molecules
in computer simulations
to try and reduce their in silica sorry
they're in vitro and they're in vivo
load
so
again i really wish i could talk more
about this but i really
can't
all i can say is that we were looking
for terpenes
that are expressed in cannabis and we're
looking for agonism at the gabarae
receptor
and we're looking for cns gaba
so the medics can probably have a little
bit of a guess
what we might be trying to do there
so first i want to talk about virtual
screening so
this is the process that you would go
through to determine how you're going to
do your virtual screens so the first
question is what do you know about the
protein of interest do you have any
structural information do you just have
a sequence
in our case we actually had some protein
structural information there are crystal
structures of the gaba receptor
so that means we can
go along and do some docking which is
just in silico placing ligands on the
protein and seeing where they interact
um and then from there that may even
answer some of your questions
and there are
other routes you can go after that which
i'll take you through as we go
so
what was the plan well the first step
was to have a look at the existing
crystal structures um
see where the current molecules were
interacting seeing how we could um
see see if we can find out how a terpene
might bind in those same pockets
compare any of the ligands and to those
native crystal structures and then let's
just see if we can jam some ligands in
there and see if they're happy
i should point out
ligands in this case really just means
small molecule
it's a throwback to inorganic chemistry
where you're chelating to a to a metal
um the inorganic chemists hate us
molecular models using this but
at least we don't call them like ants
so a little bit about gaba
um the receptor the iron channel um the
endogenous ligand is gaba amino butyric
acid it's a really common um
neuro
signal
um it's found throughout the body um
there are multiple subtypes um
each comprised uh each of the subunits
have different types and then the the
subtypes are comprised of different
different versions
i'll give you a little idea it's quite a
complex
protein structure so there are these
five protein subunits
that are all come together to make a
transmembrane pore
it's
it's an ion channel so what it does is
it depolarizes synapses
which is an inhibitory mechanism it
calms you down a little bit
the important thing is this picture down
the bottom uh what you see here is that
there are two gaba sites and there is
another one there that is labeled the
benzodiazepine site so that was the site
that we were targeting that's where we
wanted to interact um and it's been
shown that it sort of acts as an
allosteric modulator so it doesn't
make the channel turn on um by
stimulating that side at all but it does
potentiate um gaba's effect
on that receptor
and the other thing to note is that all
of these sites are at the interface of
the two proteins so you really need to
be studying the complex as a whole you
can't just look at one of the sub units
right so now
i went on and did some literature
research before i jumped into the
project um and what we found is that
there is limited evidence of terpenes
interacting with gaba and having an
agonist effect which is pretty cool so
there's some good news at the beginning
and there's a whole lot of
pharmaceuticals that are well known to
interact with gaba so great awesome
there's some crystal structures out
there
what i found very quickly is that the
quality of those crystal structures
varies hugely um because gaba is such a
complicated protein
and it's membrane bound
the only way you can really get it to
crystallize well is by using some pretty
unrepresentative physiological
conditions you end up throwing a lot of
detergent in there to get it to actually
crystallize and what that means is the
conformations get distorted
and you end up with a structure that's
not particularly representative um
classically it's down in the
transmembrane domain that they they
actually collapse on the core and you
get some rotations and some twists
um
that turned out to be a little bit of a
problem
i'll get to that later
but the gist is that it's thought that
cbd does activate gaba and we were
interested in looking at cbd at cabra as
well but it's thought that gaba doesn't
actually sorry cbd doesn't actually bind
at the benzodiazepine site it binds down
in the transmembrane domain
on a cleft on those those proteins down
there
and
since that area is heavily distorted in
the crystal structures it makes it much
harder to model
so up here we're looking at the
benzodiazepine site here so
so we've got the two different crystal
structures here we have 6 huo and
6d t5 i believe
in
green you can see the 6d
6d65 structure and where i've got that
red arrow i'm showing that the two
structures are quite distorted
in comparison the the white ribbon
basically means it's forming a beta
sheet that's the sort of structure
you're expecting the green wiggly lines
represent loop structures which are
normal in a protein you do expect to see
loops
you just don't expect to see them there
so what that's showing is that in the
process of crystallizing that structure
has been distorted
right so
on to the in vitro data
so
like i said you know people use
benzodiazepines they know they work
that's awesome great
yay
um however most of those were developed
a long long long time ago and what they
did is they just stuck them in humans
until they saw it working and they went
great it's the dose
there's not easy to
find out how strongly a compound binds
to gaba alone you can't really
just isolate gaba stick a molecule on it
find out what concentration it is
actually binding at
most of these assays are done through
patch clamps which is where you express
the
receptor in i believe it's a frog ovary
and then you run a voltage across it
and then you're looking for the calcium
transmission so what you're actually
doing is a functional assay you're not
really doing a binding assay you're not
really seeing because you can't do a
classic washout assay here
um so i draw the literature and i found
a whole range of different various
values i didn't find any binding data at
all i found some ic50 data which was
confusing because it's not inhibitory so
i don't know why it was labeled
ic50
i found some ec50 which is what i was
expecting however the numbers i'm
showing here are averages and they
differed by orders of magnitude
so
that was a problem
but uh you know we're brave we're going
to push on anyway
because they're paying us so we're going
to do it
so um i thought right well the first
thing to do is we know lindelof works so
let's dock linalool
and um sure enough that's actually the
gaba site and linoleum in green lies
beautifully on top of gaba it just sits
there and it was like great okay
so it binds to gaba and then it bound to
the benzodiazepine site and it bound to
about 15 different other sites so it's
like oh docking right so i can stick
i can select anywhere on the protein and
i can dock a little to it i was like oh
dear so this isn't going to be selective
so
how do we actually indicate what's
working and what's not
so we thought right
what we really need is some binding
energy calculations so this is a way of
calculating how strongly it's docking to
a particular spot like does it actually
want to be there
um and the basic gist is that there is a
state function between
freely floating ligands
and the protein and then they go through
a transition state and then they
collapse down into their bound
conformations they both adapt their
conformations a little bit their lower
energies change
and if you have a favorable binding
you'll have a total drop in energy
so this is molecular mechanics and
generalized born surface area
approximations
that's not particularly important all
i'm here is to say is that there is a
way of calculating this you can you can
do it with a computational simulation
um
it does neglect entropy which is an
important part of that equation i showed
you earlier
the justification is that usually you
use a cogeneric set of ligands so a
whole ligands that look like each other
they've just got small variations in
functional groups
and you can assume that they all have
similar entropies so you can cancel that
term out across a series
i was testing a broad range of terpenes
which are not cogeneric
so that assumption was a little
questionable
um so we did the work anyway because
you've got to see how it's working and
these are just the control compounds so
these are just the pharmaceutical
compounds that we have some estimates of
their binding energy predictions
and what you can see in the molecular
dynamics is i actually have a negative
trend
so i have negative correlation to the
binding energies which is not a great
sign
the docking energies are so varied that
while i do have a positive correlation
it's not great
in fact if you look at the r values
they're basically random so that's not
much use
right what's next
the the i can still remember my my
chemistry lecture explaining this one to
me and and yeah all of those assumptions
were just garbage
so we needed to find
a new way of tackling this problem
um
docking scores docking scores are used
to
uh
weight the confirmations that the
molecules are
adapting and and see which ones are
favored it's a really good way of
showing what the most probable
confirmation is
if you know the binding site
but they're not very good for comparing
between molecules usually they're
additive
so if a molecule has more atoms it will
get a higher score
but there are ways you can gain that
system
ensemble docking is one of those ways
and that's where if
i think it's the next slide okay it's
the next next slide
but the general gist is that you dock to
a whole lot of different protein
confirmations you doctor the same site
and what you're looking for is
how does the binding score change as you
change the protein conformation
what you'd really be hoping for is that
a ligand has the ability to adopt adopt
different confirmations to adapt to the
change in the binding site so
one of the problems that we always have
is we get presented with these beautiful
crystal structures which is this lovely
static model but the reality is they're
under brownie emotion they're all
vibrating they're all moving a little
bit so that conformation is adapting so
if you have a molecule that is
incredibly rigid
then it needs to have a massive energy
bonus to really stabilize that
conformation
there are times when you maybe you want
an actually a flexible ligand so it can
adapt to a whole range of protein
conformations
but what you're really looking for there
is that you get a nice constant score so
that even though the ligand is changing
confirmation that the docking score
stays consistent you don't want to see a
wide range in docking scores
for different protein confirmations
so here are three example um protein
conformations so these are taken from a
molecular dynamics simulation which is
where you you're allowing
newtonian forces to act on the protein
and it's vibrating away you raise it to
a normal temperature you give it
natural motion
and what you do is you take a series of
snapshots through that trajectory and
you get different protein confirmations
then you dock back into them so what
i've highlighted here is three areas
where that protein which is close to the
leg and the ligand is in the
the the thicker
um
sticks and
what you're seeing there is the amino
acid residues in in the finer sticks
in in green you have the cartoon
representation which is sort of the the
secondary structure of the protein and
what i'm highlighting here is the
changes that we are seeing in that
secondary structure which is derived
from the changes in the confirmation of
of those residues
and how that has changed through those
snapshots so what i ended up using was
uh 10 snapshots from different
simulations which were
the lowest binding energy of the ligand
in that simulation
um
and i used it for all of the the
pharmaceutical compounds all of the
benzodiazepine simulations that i'd run
so i ended up docking into 40 different
protein confirmations
which
i'm going to show you here
so
what we managed to do was from a panel
of 200 odd terpenes that are known to be
expressed in cannabis and found in
cannabis um
we found
some compounds that were better in
silico
than lineal
this project is still undergoing work by
our partner
they have completed the in vitro testing
and i believe the in vivo testing was
scheduled to start
at the end of last year so
it is quite possible that this
product will be on the market soon
with
unfortunately again
i can't say
which terpenes i'm very sorry about that
um
i'd like to thank the team um this this
is uh our founders um and the rest of
the team who helped throughout the rest
of this project
um i'd like to thank you all very much
for your attention and um
have a great day
any any any questions
to where
oh it's going to be in a vape so it's
going to be inhalation so it'll go
straight into the bloodstream i have no
concerns about the
bioavailability of them
um
i
[Music]
[Applause]
i don't think any of them are going to
be
drugs of their own right i don't think
they're that potent
i don't think we're looking at
benzodiazepine replacements for instance
um but i do think
there is some value in giving
gaba a little bit of a nudge while
you're also delivering cbd i think that
happens naturally um
with some of the other terpenes that are
you know naturally expressed
but what i would say is that some of
those terpenes identified in the 35 are
very very minor terpenes in um
cannabis and what i expect is that there
will be an artificially high level of
these terpenes delivered in this cbd
product
so we're enhancing what you could call i
suppose the entourage effect i
i'm
not a huge
fan of that i think it is a
i don't think you need to put
the 800 900 compounds found in cannabis
all into one particular formulation but
i think there are definitely
minor components that you could amp up
the concentration of and make a really
wonderful product from
thank you
[Applause]