[Music]
welcome to the caned Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I'm the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on the canmed
summit well our canmed Advisory Board is
hard at work reviewing all the great
abstract submissions that we received
for caned 25 our goal is to have all of
our oral presenters selected by the end
of the year and to announce them in
January so stay tuned for those
announcements we are also working on a
number of great workshops that we will
be announcing very soon so if you have
not already sign up for email alerts at
canmen events.com so you don't miss any
of those and other
announcements also if you are planning
to join us at CED 25 next June in Puerto
Rico be sure to purchase your ticket
package today and take advantage of our
discounted early bird rate find more
details at camed events.com
our guests today are Ed lir and David
mckillop Ed and David have teamed up to
create high science a new TV series
premiering on YouTube today November
27th and that features medicinal
genomics and
canmed David is an Emmy award-winning
producer with an impressive background
in creating hit shows like Duck Dynasty
and Pawn Stars he brings his
storytelling expertise to the Cannabis
space teaming up with Ed to launch a
show that is as entertaining as it is in
formative High science promises to take
viewers on a journey through the world
of cannabis focusing on its therapeutic
potential the people who grow it and the
science that drives It
Forward during our conversation we
discuss Ed's personal health journey and
how it inspired the show's creation the
show's goal of making the medical
science of cannabis more accessible to
the public and reducing cannabis stigma
the challenges that cannabis
entrepreneur ERS face in the form of
strict regulations Financial challenges
and the thriving Black
Market how the series uses personal
storytelling to balance education and
entertainment Why YouTube was chosen for
its Global reach and creative freedom
compared to traditional networks and a
glimpse into future Seasons which may
explore other plant medicines such as
mushrooms before we get to my
conversation with Ed and David I'd like
to thank this episode sponsor High
science TV High science TV shares the
Lively exploits of colorful characters
around the world trailblazing all things
cannabis and pursuit of the modern-day
Gold Rush fatherson host Rich battenberg
Jr and Richard Rick battenberg iiii
explore legendary seed gurus Relentless
cultivators expansive Growers pioneering
product makers and imaginative
dispensary owners as they break the
barriers of this new
frontier the storytelling unmasks the
mystical powers of the ancient cannabis
plant and its innumerable uses through
Dynamic
entertainment High science premieres on
YouTube November 27th at
youtube.com at high
sciencv okay and without any further Ado
please enjoy my conversation with Ed
Lair and David Mulla
[Music]
good morning Ed and David thank you so
much for joining me on the podcast good
morning good morning all right well I'm
excited to talk with both of you today
about high science a new TV series
premiering on YouTube today November
27th um and it features medicinal
genomics and canmed the series takes
viewers on a journey through the world
of cannabis focusing on its therapeutic
potential the people who grow it and the
science that drives it forward an
ambitious project to say the
least so with that said Ed what inspired
you to create high science specifically
about cannabis and why
now you know uh back in 2018 I had
acoustic neuroma surgery and if anybody
knows what that is that's a a tumor in
the brain uh that's connected to uh your
basically everything and after surgery I
spent 33 days and ICU and had some
issues uh and the medicine I was on I
did not like uh I also believed when
they did the the surgery was I don't
know 10 12 12 hours whatever it was uh
they said it was easier to remove it was
more cystlike uh than the tumor uh and I
believe that when I found out I had this
this uh problem I just smoked a lot of
weed because I heard uh it was great for
cancer and tumors and blah blah blah the
list goes on so I smoked a lot of weed
and uh I believe that's what made it uh
easier to remove the doctor doesn't
think so but that's
medical versus a cannabis guy and uh I
had this idea for a show and because I
wanted other people to understand what
cannabis was all about uh and managed to
through a friend meet uh the infamous
David mckellop uh who's now my partner
and I don't know what I would do without
him uh I think we make a great team uh
and he asked me do you really think uh
we could do this and I said I do David
and he goes who's going to own the IP
and I said you and I uh we're not going
to sell it to a network uh we're going
to do everything ourself and he said
let's go uh he comes from the television
world and uh we set out on a road to
find the most
incredible
OG entrepreneurs in the Cannabis
industry from Medical geonoma being the
top lead scientists in the country and
around the world uh to the little guy
that produces seeds uh we wanted to
really
showcase these incredible entrepreneurs
and the incredible work that they're
doing with this plant and I gave all
these puzzle pieces to
David and here we are getting ready to
launched the show today the
27th uh eight weeks David took this and
built one hell of a beautiful puzzle
this show is going to be great not only
informative educational entertaining
it's all right there excellent yeah and
David tell us a little bit about your
background and what got you involved in
the project you know I'm a I've spent
most of my life as a television
programmer I've headed up uh programming
departments at the National Geographic
Discovery Channel uh history A&amp;E I ran
A&amp;E as the general manager um so I've
spent most of my life producing programs
um everything from uh Deadliest Catch at
Discovery to Storage Wars Pawn Stars and
uh Duck Dynasty at history and A&amp;E um so
I you know i' I've been doing this most
of my life um when I met Ed you know I
had I kind of left the network you know
you you you can't program you have
there's a certain limit to which you can
do in terms of your age and everything
so it's time to let the other people
come in and program but I had a great
run and loved what I was doing um and
you know I was looking for my next thing
so when Ed approached me I was skeptical
to be quite honest with you you know to
me it was like oh [ __ ] you know am I
allowed to say that um is that
um that um
I'm not going to just sit here and do
some kind of Stoner show you know that's
just not what I smoked the I smoked some
weed when I was a kid in fact we when I
was growing up we actually smoked weed
we didn't really drink I never even
drank until after college um but anyway
I started to meet some of the people Ed
had rounded up in this group and I
started to do some research and I
suddenly realized
wow um people's perception of the C
Canabis industry is still squarely in
this idea of a of a recreational drug
and the government and big
pharmaceutical companies all would love
to have you think that but what we soon
discovered where Ed had shown some light
and I did some discoveries is that quite
the opposite I mean up prior to to the
to World War II cannabis was the goto
treatment for up to a hundred different
alements it was also the main treatment
for pain before aspirin so we began to
discover that the relationship of human
evolution and cannabis evolution is
tightly bound and it's somehow gotten
lost uh you know I have my theories on
why a lot of it probably is people don't
have patents on it and can try to make a
lot of money off of it but anyway so I
thought you know what I'll take this
I'll take this on you know we didn't
have a lot of
money uh but but we had a lot of passion
and someone like Ed and we met some of
the people and the characters in the
show and we worked hard and we all
chipped in we didn't weren't you know we
weren't
paid this was kind of a uh it became a
passion for me and um because I know how
many people can benefit from it and the
most important thing is is that people
there have been lots of stories about
people overdoing it or going into mer
rooms and that's because there there's
no information there's no one there's no
trusted source of information the
government doesn't want to tell you
anything pharmaceutical companies don't
want to tell you anything so people are
basically finding out for themselves how
many gummies it takes and that's a
disaster you know an
uneducated population is not going to
really be able to fully Embrace what
cannabis can do for the human body and
since no one else is going to do it Ed
and I decided that we're going to do it
and the first step in this was to create
the high science TV show which is going
to be an anthology Series so this first
series is we're following up a family of
investors but our second third uh we
could be doing something totally
different but the goal here is to
educate people at the same time and have
a and have a lot of fun so that's how I
kind of got involved in it excellent no
and and your story is not unique to to
enter the the industry or the topic
skeptical but then dig into the the the
actual information and be made a
Believer we hear it all the time on the
podcast we hear it at the conferences
all the time um so I think it's great
that you're bringing this to more more
people so we can have more Believers out
there and get more great information
into the hands of folks and I think
people are going to see it's trusted
information you know I mean there's so
much you know what is real anymore and
so um or what what what can what can you
trust to be real information or truth um
and so what we've relied on is rather
than lecturing people about what we
think it is is we've just followed the
stories of individuals people tell their
own stories uh from you know veterans
who um were were in very dark places who
stumbled across literally stumbled
across
cannabis uh that that that was changing
their lives people aren't going to lie
about
that um so our show is really
testimonials wrapped up in a wonderful
narrative um and so it's not preachy
we're not here creating a documentary
with a voice of God that's that's
telling people they have to know about
this stuff it's actually you're
experiencing the journeys of a lot of
individuals uh as they come to the
realization of what cannabis can do
responsible use of cannabis can do sure
now and you've said said that it's the
blending of educational content with
entertainment were there challenges in
Making Science and cannabis accessible
to a broader
audience yeah I mean look well there
there's certain limitations in terms of
broadcast uh it's it's you know what we
were doing you know 10 years ago would
have put us in put us in the federal
penitentiary um but um look storytelling
is human is our way of that that's the
secret to
Humanity um you'll never change
anybody's Mind by throwing facts at them
but you will convince people by telling
him a good story the most obvious
example OJ's trial right I mean the
defense had every single fact it was an
open and shut case and all they did was
they presented the facts OJ's attorneys
turned around and just gave a better
story and the jury went with that so
this idea that we tell as human beings
we we we Thrive the most in terms of
learning and educating it during play
and
storytelling um so how do we find the
narrative and the arc that's kind of the
that's what took Ed and I so long but
once we found the narrative then it just
fell into place um you know it's
probably never going to be able to air
on a table Channel because they just too
many standards and practices issues it's
still illegal on the federal level
advertisers have certain um has lots of
reservations but in some ways I think
that's a that's a mark of
uh courage and I think people like to
see that especially
Americans um we're we're leading the
charge kind of pioneers you know you
know and and and and the beauty is when
you look at our cast members uh they're
being supported and backed up with
Incredible people like uh Kevin mckernan
uh one of you you know one of the owners
of of medicinal geonomics uh Dei Mir who
I think uh I I I just couldn't get
enough of Dei when I was interviewing
him uh he said some things that just
blew me away uh Ethan Russo uh again we
were all at caned and uh uh that's
that's the place you really need to go
uh and you guys have really supported
what our cast members in the show are
doing and it just hit the nail on the
head when he put all these pieces
together it's not it's it's really look
the information is there you all these
all you guys you guys have done the most
amazing work in the research and um the
I mean there's there lots of simple
Concepts that we don't that the average
person doesn't know or understand um and
something as simple as that um you know
when you inhale
cannabis there's only a like I think
it's 40% 30% or even less is is is is
actually metabolized into your body but
when you eat something it can be upwards
of highs of 90% um which is you know why
eating too much and it takes longer so
what's the difference between you know
indoor grows and outdoor grows what is
the um what is the benefit of of of a
rainbow effect of uh cannaboids and
Tarpin you know um so once you start to
learn all that stuff you begin to sense
wow there's something here I mean it
actually goes back to challenge the the
way that the medical system works now
where they use a very sharp focus of one
one very specific drug for one very
specific symptom cannabis they're
beginning to understand as you know and
this is what these stories we're going
to be telling is it is a it's it's a um
it's a fabric of of of U medic uses that
attack it as a group so we're going from
a a single shot to a shotgun approach
and that's very very that has that has
an enormous promise in terms of Medical
Treatments I mean I'm preaching to the
choir you know all that stuff but what
I'm getting at I get excited about it
that then my job is to make the audience
get excited about it because if they get
excited about it they can then you know
they can go back and educate their
doctors you know because we're not going
to see you know the here's an
interesting statistic 70% of the income
for broadcasting cable television comes
from the pharmaceutical
industry wow that's where their ad
revenues that that's where their
revenues coming and so that's when you
if you have who does I don't know who
watches the news anymore but if you do
watch CBS or ABC News try it one night
broadcast every single commercial is a
drug there are only two countries in the
entire world that allow
the um drug companies to advertise
that's the United States and New Zealand
every other country in the world it is
banished the drug companies spend more
money advertising than they do on R&amp;D W
so you know so we're up against a
monster
here and and so it's a no pun intended
it's really this is where Ed convinced
me it's a Grassroots Duty here to get
people to educated on the potential of
cannabis now cannabis isn't the Cure All
it's not going to change the entire
world but it is certainly a safe and
organic uh alternative to a lot of the
uh kind
of uh what's the word um well
traditional ways now that medicine is is
being practiced and our job is to
educate people and then let them make
their own decision we're not pushers no
pun in it again um we're educators um
and as you know this there's a lot of
potential and also the other thing is we
don't we only know we only know what was
it Ed how many how many canono are there
in in a in a plant something like 48 or
something or 100 I forget what the
number was it's he would know better
than us because yeah but we don't I
don't even think we I don't even think
we fully know we don't know and we only
know
about a fraction of those isn't it like
200 we only know about so far but like
yeah so there's more to learn yeah and
then in terms of how many are actually
tested for too it's even a a smaller
portion of that yeah so there's a
there's a
vast body of knowledge that still needs
to be discovered and so getting people
excited about that will help them you
know encourage others and encourage
their doctors and uh uh and and and
lawmakers to
to not just run away from this kind of
uh misrepresentation of of a very
powerful drug one of our main characters
or one of our characters is a guy named
John piai I don't know if you know John
he's a he's a he's a grower up in
Massachusetts uh I I refer to him as
kind of Mr Natural meets Thomas
Jefferson uh he is just uh he's a genius
but um he's also just an amazing man and
has incredible knowledge
and his whole piece is that he believes
that the cannabis plant really has a
co-evolution with humanity and in the
same way that the dog became the one
mammal that co-evolved with humans he
firmly believes that the cannabis plant
which can be traced back to the earliest
known uh human interactions actually
evolved in a similar way with with
humans um and so that that there's a
tremendous
amount of power in that
potentially no I think you're absolutely
I I saw rambling I'm sorry Ed got me all
excited about this and now I I can't
stop talking about
it no it's great your passion definitely
definitely comes through and I think you
touched on a lot of great points there
and one of them being that I mean for a
lot of us in the industry we take a lot
of this information for granted and
assume that it's common knowledge but it
really isn't so having a show like this
that's more accessible to the general
public so that they can start
understanding what we already know um is
very
powerful you know I ran up against that
one at the History Channel you know when
when we first took over history it was
there was a lot of criticism that we
were showing shows that weren't really
about history and I thought well you
know everything we do is about history
but what we did find was that
it it inow television is a wonderful
means of expressing emotion it is a a
terrible means of giving
information um but if you tell as I say
if you have it's a great emotional
that's like you know you see a cotton
commercial and you cry right I mean it's
uh so it has a it triggers people um and
the one the most successful thing we did
at history was that it wasn't so much
that we were just reciting like a
historical encyclopedia we just got
people excited about history and as they
got excited about history we went from
the number 30 for Network up to number
three um and people knew where they you
know you get them excited about American
history they go on to the internet and
they learn about it here if we get
people excited about cannabis they'll
start doing their research they'll come
back to you and they'll find
you um rather than having to go to the
conference they'll be doing their own
research because of their impassion and
then they'll find you Excell you know
the other thing the other Beauty about
the show uh a lot of people think that
these entrepreneurs are just sitting
back making boatloads of money yeah uh
not true they're fighting for their
lives uh you know uh the millions and
millions of dollars that it takes to
build a grow an indoor grow the the the
amount of money that it takes to open a
dispensary the not only the the
regulations you got you know federal
state county Parish you know depending
Where You Are which is changing daily
and stick around it'll change in the
next 20 minutes uh it's it's like you
know banks close you down because for no
reason because we don't have safe
banking in the industry you know they
because you work in a cannabis industry
you can't go buy a car you can't buy a
house uh because you're using federally
illegal money well it's the same damn
money that's in my pocket uh that's in
yours I I mean the list goes on of what
these poor guys men and women in this
industry are fighting uh and we touch on
on all of it in the show uh to show
people that hey it's not all you know
champagne and pop and corks these guys
are actually busting their butt because
they believe so much in this plant
they're willing to do this and that's
what high science is all about is
showing all of it oh no well said I mean
there are a lot of a lot of things up
against folks in the industry not just
the regulations but you have the black
market that they're competing with and
now um with the farm bill and have all
these loophole stores that are popping
up with our hemp derived canabo there's
there's a lot of things a lot of
challenges facing the industry and uh I
think it's great that you guys are
highlighting that and obviously those
are topics we try to dive into as well
at the conference at can helping people
kind of try to navigate this because it
is a difficult industry the one thing
that I found that when I tell people
what we've been up to and this is at
dinner parties or friends houses and all
is every single person has said you know
I just don't know much about it and the
other story is I I find a lot of older
people I was at a like a neighborhood uh
picnic the other day or couple months
ago and this couple said they were in
their I don't know late 50s and they
said that they had heard about you know
gummies and so they decided they were
going to take a gummy so they took some
gummies nothing happened they took
another one the woman said that three
days later she was still thinking about
going to the emergency room um and you
know the the the the thing here is that
if they had only known that's what they
said they just didn't know anything
about it and um so educating people not
only is it good for them in terms of you
know empowering their their Wellness but
it's also a very important protection
against irresponsible use and there's no
place to go you know there's no cons
there's no consistency it's not like you
go and pick up a bottle of Tylenol and
know exactly what to do right right um
so that's why it's so important to get
the show on the air and to start
generating interest is that it's there
to educate people and an educated
population on this stuff is going to be
good for wellness and it's going to be
good for the Cannabis
business well said so let's talk a bit
about you know how is the show what can
people expect when they're watching the
show you mentioned that um you kind of
have some characters that um tie all
these different stories together what
does that look
like well you have to have a thread you
know you have to have a thread and and
and and a story you know and I've always
been very successful with uh father son
relationships whether it's Pawn Stars Or
Duck Dynasty you know multiple
Generations tend to uh people tend to be
able to relate to that um so in this
particular ep season you know we we're
following a a group of a family of um
venture capitalist
entrepreneurs um as they um look to
expand their business in in the Cannabis
world and in doing so they we created
their
interactions with everybody from ogs to
Suits to scientists and there's a bunch
of H Jinks that UE you know in terms of
family Dynamics
uh uh situational comedy that kind of
stuff but that's all tied into the to
the the the entertainment pieces it but
it's really just a skeleton and when you
hang on that skeleton all of these other
individuals including John piai we've
got this couple uh uh Megan Eric up in
the birk Shear who are you know who have
been experimenting in in in retail to to
customers we have um we have Mo in
Arizona who you know he's kind of this
uh he was his mother was suffering and
so he invented a a type of cannabis
that's used for your skin so we and and
we've tied all of these individuals into
a storyline around this family that's
out in search of of increasing their
knowledge and investments in in the
Cannabis world that's kind of how we did
it um so as I say it's not a lecture
it's not a it's
not it's kind of a reality Series right
but I think you know the reality is
series are kind of misunderstood these
days but um but what it is is it's it's
very entertaining it's watchable it's
easy on the eyes um but it's also really
informative uh in fact it's like you're
getting that information on a on a
secondary and tertiary level you don't
even know you're getting it because
you're enjoying watching the
show right so Ed you were originally
conceived of the idea how does the
finished product compare to your origin
Vision you know when we were looking to
go well he fired me the first
time I'm not the first person to get you
fired no I've been fired a lot the the
the the the thing is when we were
looking to put this on cable uh nwork
the show was so different from what I
envisioned uh in the very beginning uh
because when you go on cable uh uh you
know you can't show this you can't show
that you're showing too many products
you're going to dispensary oh my God you
got to block all those names out you
can't show smoking you can't show
somebody taking a gummy it's like it's
like all of a sudden you're doing a
Seinfeld show a show about nothing so
when we cut the
cord and David really got
into
uh the characters and how they all
intertwin together he goes I got it I
got it and the show is exactly as I
Envision uh David has had 100% creative
control uh you know I I sit back and I
really treasure his thoughts and ideas
and uh I just I I'm super super excited
about it uh and uh I I just can't wait
for everybody to see it hon in fact most
of the people working on the series
refer to edai as The Odd
Couple a good thing H it's a good thing
you know uh they they kind of we walk
into a room and you know I'm I'm usually
got a suit jacket on and a button- down
shirt and and uh and they look at they
kind of look at it go whoa what is
[Laughter]
this but uh but we work together really
well so um and I think it's because we
share the same passion um which is you
know to get people to understand the
benefits of cannabis it's a you know
this is a it's an important story to
tell and that's what we want to tell it
excellent and now you've mentioned
future seasons and maybe you know
working with with different characters
are there any you know people on your on
your wish list or dream collaborations
or experts that you'd be interested in
featuring and future Seasons yeah we
have I mean look we could some of the
people that we've met along the way in
in this season we could spin off and do
separate Seasons um I think what it's
going to become is an anthology series
meaning that high science will come back
season after season and they'll have
returning characters that from different
but there'll be maybe a totally
different story being told there is so
much out there honestly there's so much
potential uh and
um some spin-offs there's some spin-offs
one that we could spinoffs and and do
their own series I think they're strong
enough to handle their own series uh and
as we spend them off we can add newans
into uh new cast members into season two
of high science uh and it's just it's
exciting to see this all come together
and you know we're you know we're we're
gonna we made a conscious decision to go
out on
YouTube I personally think YouTube is
the future of uh you know
YouTube today is what cable was 25 years
ago it's where you go to learn about
cooking shows that aren't competition
shows and all the rest of it so um
YouTube is a has a powerful reach into
the to the everyday common person in
America um and now you know it's you
don't have the marketing Machinery
behind which you would have at a network
but honestly I think through social
media and Word of Mouth build it they
will come and I think YouTube is really
the perfect place for this you know we
got a lot of push back from some of the
uh characters in the show because oh
they said this is going to be a TV show
and it's G to be on you know Netflix or
some other thing like that and
um but I remind them that uh right now
YouTube is probably the has the largest
potential audience um and if we can if
we can manipulate social media to act as
our marketing
I think it's the perfect um it's the
perfect spot for
it yeah no I mean if my if my kids are
any
indication um YouTube is where it's at
that's all they want to watch is YouTube
you know when you when you sit back and
you think it's
worldwide uh it's uh 78% of the people
uh that stream they stream by their
handheld uh so you know most people have
cut the cord on the television uh the
beauty is not only can I watch uh
YouTube on my handheld but I also have
the app on my television and I can watch
it on my my TV as well y so or on your
your your iPad whatever it might be so
so I I think it's the perfect Avenue for
us uh now that's not to say we're not
going to go out and sell the show or
license a show in other countries and
and uh doing other things with it since
we own the IP we have that that ability
to do that uh and that's exactly what
we're going to do but we're starting
with YouTube and we could not be more
excited about it and the people are
really embracing it uh that we're
telling uh our cat some of our cast
members kind of scratched their head and
some of them goes oh you guys are
geniuses this is
perfect excellent so yeah let's remind
people where where can they find the
series and um yeah where can they find
it you can go to YouTube not YouTube TV
YouTube and uh in the search column uh
go up and type in high science
TV go to our Channel subscribe boom
watch the show
4:20 afternoon on the 27th which is
today in just a little short time we're
going to be popping champagne bottles
because the show's coming on excent now
is it going to be all all eight episodes
uh right from the start or are you going
to kind of drip them out no uh the first
two episodes are going to be on the 27
so you're going to have episode episode
one and two then every Wednesday after
that at 4:20 in the afternoon is another
episode for eight
weeks excellent we might take a couple
weeks off David am I right on that might
take a couple weeks off for the
Christmas holidays uh and kind of play
some Christmas music or whatever we want
to do show some you know the Jolly Old
St Nick taking a break break sitting
down in a rocking chair smoking a joint
relaxing as he got some Christmas music
in the background but whatever but I got
the long white hair so I can be jolly St
Nick uh sitting there but uh we're going
to do something uh and then the show
will pick back up and we're we're
starting to put together season two so
uh we're really excited about
it excellent so I mean winding down here
um I guess make one last pitch for for
the folks that are watching to to watch
the show and um how else can they
connect with with you guys and any other
projects that you're working
on uh you can go to High science.com and
sign up uh if you sign up for the high
science club uh which doesn't cost you
anything uh you get a we'll mail you a
free pin uh so you got a high science
official pin that show that you're part
of the high science Community uh we've
started High science 420 mobile uh with
some of the major mobile carriers uh
we're getting ready to launch High
science uh travel Club to tell you all
the really exciting and
420 open places that you can go to and
vacation at uh so it's all right there
and and the I guess the thing that I'm
more passionate about than anything not
only the show but we started the high
science charity
foundation and a percentage of all the
merchandise a percentage of our online
store uh as well as 420 mobile uh a
percentage goes to our charity
Foundation which is helping veterans
with PTSD and mental health uh David
says it best David what's your line for
the uh the the charity Foundation I'm
not sure I for God i' I always come up
with so many lines I haven't I haven't
had I haven't had my six martinis put
them on the
slide but uh we we've started a bunch of
different ways everything's at high
science.com you can find out all about
about us you can find out about all our
cast members you can read their bios you
can read David's bio and find out that
this man right here is a Emy
award-winning producer uh he uses him to
hold his doors open at his house uh it's
uh it's it's just exciting the amount of
people and you're going to meet Kelly
mofo MOS uh Johnny greenfingers uh Meg
and Eric Kevin MCC Carnell and Brendan
uh the list goes on of all these cast
members and the incredible work they're
doing in the Cannabis industry and I
could not be more excited to be sitting
on a side of David watching our episodes
as we we go live and you know when we
realiz these things take time too so you
know we we've managed our expectations
that's the other thing about YouTube
it's not like we're launching after a
multi-million dollar ad campaign and
buses ads on buses in New York City and
billboards in La uh but I do believe
it's like a diesel engine you know it
takes a while to get those guys up to
speed but once you hit your your your
once you hit your RPMs they're almost
impossible to stop and so we'll be we'll
be we're going to be uh manage our
expectations but we are 100% behind this
and everybody that we have been working
with is 100% behind this everybody who I
have to say shout out to all of us none
of no one is no one has been paid for
this that's the other thing um people
have are doing this out of the out of
the their their passion to get this
information across um and I think that
when you do something like that and you
have that type of passion and personal
commitment success may take time but
it's going to
happen absolutely you know one thing I
want to I want to say uh DD Mir I keep
going back to him uh incredible
scientists work with
mulam uh the father of of cannabis and
Israel uh the list goes on uh I asked
Dei I said Dei could you tell me the
difference uh because season one we're
in cannabis season two we might go into
mushrooms I don't know where we're going
to go uh but we need to explore and he
goes Ed Ed Ed Ed Ed sit back I said
what's that de he goes Ed cannabis is
the little
village he goes but mushrooms is the
kingdom he goes I'm telling you just
wait and see so we're going to no
telling where season two is going to
take us but we're going to be exploring
this plant
medicine uh it's got a lot to be said
for what what Mother Nature has put on
this Earth and I'm hoping also that
people will see the show and then
contact us because you know I I think
it's just the tip of the iceberg of who
we've you there's been a lot of
serendipity in terms of who we've been
able to to rope in and meet but I'm
hoping that the series will bring all
kinds of interesting people out of the
woodwork and and and so it start to grow
exponentially um and that's gonna that's
what's really going to be exciting and I
think it's also excited for the for the
people we are showcasing in the series
too I mean I think um it's great uh
it puts a face to a lot of uh a lot of
these products and and it actually puts
a human face to the science and that's
kind of the basis of the series is we're
putting a human face with a human story
on some really exciting and complex
science absolutely I hope we can help
just one person through education in a
show I hope we can shed some light to
our politicians that something needs to
be done with Federal legalization I hope
we can be instrumental and helping
through the show with safe banking uh to
really help these guys out uh in the
industry uh so keeping my fingers
crossed I got everything crossed uh
everybody loves the show and uh we can
bring some education and entertainment
in people's lives with high
science all right well very exciting
we're very excited on our end for to see
the premiere later today I'll have links
to all the resources that we talked
about in the show description so people
can easily find the show and find the
website and everything that we talked
about and um yeah we're big supporters
of the show we're we're definitely we're
definitely a part of it and we'll
continue to promote it um in the coming
weeks try to get as many eyeballs on it
as possible well thank you for being a a
really fantastic partner as we made this
series um and uh look forward to many
more uh opportunities as we move forward
absolutely I think we have a shared
vision and uh Village we definitely do y
Grassroots
Grassroots all right thanks again guys
and
congratulations thank you so much
[Music]