foreign
[Music]
Coffee Talk podcast where we talk with
the leading Minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I am your host Ben amaralt I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the cam Med conference
so if you have signed up for email
alerts at cammedevents.com or if you
follow us on social media then you saw
that the can Med 24 Innovation and
investment Summit will return to the JW
Marriott Resort in Marco Island Florida
May 12th through 15th
kmad 23 was our first year on Marco
Island and the feedback was
overwhelmingly positive the beach the
food the amenities the networking
opportunities and of course the content
presented were all exceptional and
kmed24 is shaping up to be even better
registration will be opening up soon and
tickets are limited so if you haven't
yet sign up for email alerts at cammed
events.com so you are among the first to
know when tickets go on sale
all right so this episode we brought
back Dr zamir punja to talk about total
yeast and mold
zamir is a professor of plant
biotechnology at Simon Frazier
University in Canada
his research interests include the
etiology and management of plant
diseases on vegetable and Horticultural
crops
and the application of plant
biotechnology for disease management
since 2018 his work has shifted on
Research in cannabis and his group has
described a range of previously
unreported pathogens affecting the crop
and has evaluated various methods for
disease management
his team just published the results of a
three-year study that identified several
factors that have a direct effect on
yeast and mold levels
they include factors related to Growing
drying and trimming cannabis
specifically
this is important because when Growers
fail for microbial testing yeast in mold
is often the reason
so if you are a grower that has
struggled with total yeast and mold
perhaps these findings in the paper and
on this podcast can help you get back on
track
I've put a link to the paper in the show
description and if you're watching on
YouTube I've added several figures and
images from the paper throughout the
conversation
we cover the different species of yeast
and mold that are commonly found on
cannabis and which are potentially
harmful to humans
the value of total yeast in mold testing
as an indicator of product safety and
quality
what is a reasonable threshold for total
yeast and mold
how cannabis genotype affects totally
stumbled levels
why Leaf litter drives up tym levels why
hang drying is a better method than wet
trimming
the drawbacks of a radiation and more
before we get to my conversation with
Samir I want to thank this episode
sponsor Agilent Technologies
whether you manufacture or test cannabis
you face the challenge of delivering
high quality products increasing sample
volume and meeting emerging regulations
Agilent offers best-in-class cannabis
and hemp analysis Solutions featuring
robust instruments software services and
consumables
their team of experts can develop
Implement and optimize methods to get
you up and running quickly
learn more at agilent.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr zamir Puja
[Music]
good morning zamir thanks again for
joining us on the podcast
hi Ben good to see you again yeah I know
we had to get you back in we had to get
you back in quick too because I know
that you and your team you recently
published um a great paper
um about total yeast and mold in
cannabis and uh that's one of our
favorite topics here on the podcast and
at medicinal genomics as you know uh
total yeast in mold seems to be one of
those tests that Growers really struggle
with and more often than not if if a
batch is failing for microbial it's
either for total yeast and mold or maybe
more specifically aspergillus which is a
fungi and would be kind of included in
that category so always good to to
explore that topic and I know that your
paper it includes some factors that
you've identified for causing high tym
levels so hopefully we can get some good
best practices or recommendations for
Growers that they can enact so that uh
they have fewer failures but before we
get into that
I wanted to ask you why you and your
team
um were interested in investigating tym
and cannabis
right so you know t t who I am in
cannabis is certainly
um one of the most common things that
that Growers will encounter
um it's it's everywhere in the sense
that yeast and mode is not specific to
cannabis
um apples blueberries raspberries
strawberries you name it uh peanuts any
product that's grown out either in the
field or even indoors will always
capture a certain proportion of Eastern
mold because these these organisms feed
off of plant material so any exudates
any nutrients anything coming out of a
flower or or a potato or a pod will
attract some level of yeast and mold
for the most part these yeasts and molds
aren't necessarily harmful to people
when you consume an apple that's got
some yeast in mold the Tendencies for
the body to break it all down and digest
it all in it and it's basically gone
cannabis of course because of the
various ways it's used whether it's
inhaled or Vaped or extracted from
yeast and mold apparently has raised
greater concern in in cannabis than it
has potentially on other food crops and
so of course the Regulatory Agencies
have established the criteria for
testing for yeast in mold and
established levels that will cause a
product to fail
so the reason it's hard to manage and
the reason we were interested in it is
because you know it is everywhere and we
wanted to find out are there certain
things that Growers may be doing or not
doing that may increase or decrease the
levels of yeast and mold in their
product
so we didn't actually manipulate the
yeast and moles that were naturally
occurring but what we did was we tried
to understand if you if you planted a
certain genotype if you had a certain
type of air circulation if you were
leaving a lot of leaf litter on the on
the floor would those things increase or
decrease the levels of yeast and mold
and um up until now nobody's actually
looked at that you know we've looked at
yeast and mold after a product is
harvested so for example if you
irradiated what happens if you heat it
up to a certain temperature what happens
if you analyze it in the lab using
different methods what happens we wanted
to find out from a grower perspective
what could they be doing to try to
reduce those those levels in flour
yeah excellent and
so what did you find I mean more
specifically um you know I know that
you've identified like certain types of
species
um that you found in more abundance than
others I don't know if that might be a
good thing to explore
right so um so we we sort of analyzed
all the types of Eastern mold you know
we found a total and and we actually
went a step further and identified all
the different species using molecular
methods and um penicillium penicillium
was the one that seemed to be the most
prevalent on on cannabis flower now
again penicillium is everywhere you you
can find it indoors if you've got a home
that has you know slightly damp
conditions you'll find it in your
basement you'll find it in your rug
you'll find it sometimes in your clothes
I mean it's there you know and it it
obviously most of us can can deal with
it you know in our bodies because we're
used to it we may be inhaling it it's
not so much of an issue but in cannabis
um and we don't know enough about
penicillin actually it may or may not be
of concern so that was the first the
most prevalent one we've known and then
we found a bunch of others that normally
occur in the air things like Alton area
and another fungus called cladysporium
which which is quite common in the air
aspergillus wasn't that high you know
the overall levels of aspergillus we
found
wasn't high now this is under Greenhouse
cultivation right so you know we don't
have a lot of plant material laying
around it we're not next to a wooded
area or a forest where you may have a
lot of aspergillus flying in you know
blowing in through the air
so that wasn't a big concern in terms of
the sampling we did in the greenhouse we
found primarily the the penicillions and
then some Alton area and um titusporium
species present
yeah I know I'm glad you mentioned
aspergillus
um and were you looking specifically at
the species level too like where is it
um sort of the pathogenic strains of of
aspergillus your flavus fumigatus Niger
terrius yeah so we the primers we use
should have been able to to separate
those out because then we also looked at
sequences
we didn't find a lot of fumigatas we
didn't find a lot of the the pathogenic
strains the one we found was it was
called aspergillus or gracious or
gracious and it's it's actually a yellow
aspergillus you know sometimes you can
on a petri dish when you grow these
moles like we do for for a long time one
you know one of them is black another
one's green another one's gray ours is
yellow and and it's a species that is
not on the current list
of regulated aspergillus species now
that's not to say it's not important
it's just for some reason it's never
made it onto that list and maybe it's
not pathogenic right it's it hasn't been
uh flagged as being a pathogenic species
but because it's aspergillus they're
pretty much everywhere they're on
decaying plant material they're in the
air
it just so happens that in the
greenhouse we picked up more of this
yellow aspergillus species they want the
second one we found was aspergillus
Niger which is a black aspergillus and
again that's not one of the the really
uh species of concern the ones like the
fumigators and the other ones we didn't
see a lot of in in the greenhouses that
we were working with yeah no Niger
actually is on the list for for many
states as one of the the big four
pathogenics okay so we did we found a
few of those yeah interesting
interesting yeah
um any of the others that you've
mentioned um are they known to be
pathogenic or even benign to people like
what's what are we looking at there so
you know the the biggest concern I would
say with a lot of these Eastern moles is
is the the toxins and when I say toxin I
don't mean something really scary just
they produce these chemical byproducts
as they grow if you if you're growing up
in in the lab as these cultures grow as
they get a little bit older they produce
these chemical structures that are
referred to as mycotoxins both
penicillium and aspergillus will produce
some of these mycotoxins which again
it's on the radar for testing uh
OTA for example okra toxin is a
microtoxin produced by both aspergillus
and penicillin species and it can cause
some issues if it's ingested in a very
high concentration
so for example you know penicillium you
see that on moldy cheese
cheese that turns blue has penicillium
on it if you ate a lot of that you'd
probably end up with some issues in your
tummy because you know there's secondary
metabolites or or toxins produced we
don't know how much or if any toxins are
produced by the penicillium species in
in cannabis that's something that
perhaps will end up on the radar uh
eventually how much of these toxins are
produced fusarium on the other hand
which is known to infect wheat and
barley and other agricultural crops does
produce a lot of very dangerous
mycotoxins
one of them is called vomitoxin which
when it's ingested when The Barley or
wheat is ingested by by animals like
like cows or cattle they'll vomit like
they'll throw up because there's so much
of it in the green we probably as humans
wouldn't be exposed to as much but there
are cases where poisoning has occurred
by fusarium mycotoxins but again we know
nothing about what they may be doing or
if they're even present in in cannabis
the whole Focus has been primarily on
aspergillus so Better or For Worse I
mean that's what the Regulatory Agencies
decided was a priority
yeah I mean and I know that we've uh
We've written about it before it's been
I mean it's one of the tests that we
that we sell to of course
um but it is one of the few if not the
only you know contaminants on cannabis
that has been shown to uh be actually
fatal
um so maybe for a good reason that that
we're there we're testing for
aspergillus yeah that's the one that's
definitely the most well known you know
it causes the aspergillosis in in lungs
of humans Farmers it's sometimes
referred as Farmers lung disease because
when Farmers work with a lot of hay with
a lot of barley wheat over years they
develop a sensitivity to the aspergillus
spores uh and certainly people that are
are immunocompromised or have you know
health conditions uh sometimes diabetes
or even have had organ transplants they
will be more susceptible to problems
with aspergillus but for the most part
you know healthy individuals and I would
consider myself healthy and you look
pretty healthy to me I doubt either one
of us would suffer from aspergillosis
unless we were smoking you know 12 14
joints a day that that had aspergillus
in it on a regular basis we probably
wouldn't suffer from this unless you
know we had some underlying conditions
but as you said it can cause problems in
humans and so if there's any doubt any
concern in its flight and so aspergillus
is like
right and now when you were talking
about you know different species and
everything
two that kind of stood out to me that
maybe you didn't mention or maybe you
didn't even find powdery mildew and
botrytus
um yeah did you find that so poverty
mildew uh is there and uh you know
you've seen it on buds I've seen it on
buds it has you know white white sort of
a moldy appearance because we were
growing these unconscious media plates
in the lab that one doesn't actually
grow on on the plate and so
um it is actually fortunate or
unfortunate not on the radar for total
yeast and mold testing because you can't
you can't test it you can't grow it
so you may see a mole a bud that's
almost white covered in powdery mildew
it may pass
um because it it you know it doesn't it
doesn't grow well tradus was an
interesting one
um we can't we don't see a lot of it
growing on yeast and more plates
we know it's there I mean you can see
the treaders mold but uh for some reason
it's it's overgrown by some of these
other
um other fungi which in some ways sort
of leads to me to question some of these
decent model testing accesses that are
done uh from a cultural perspective how
do you know when you do a yeast and mold
test that you're you're culturing
everything that's important for from a
disease perspective you may be missing
or you meaning the person doing the test
may be missing certain species of fungi
and I think botritis is one that's being
missed for some reason it doesn't seem
to want to grow as much
now this botritis cause problems in
humans
um we don't know for sure it does
produce some of these metabolites these
mycotoxins that I referred to earlier
but again it's not on the radar for for
uh for testing from a regulatory
perspective so it it skips it's passed
unless it's super moldy as you know I
mean if it's that bad you don't want to
sell that product anywhere
sort of the The Moldy strawberry analogy
that we always talk about you know even
if you're if you're in the grocery store
and you see strawberries that are
covered in mold you're not going to say
it well I guess at past testing so I'm
going to buy it you're just you're going
to go on to a different package and it's
interesting that the biggest mold on
strawberry is bertritus interesting yeah
that's the one that tends to cause
stories to go bad if you haven't eaten
them in a couple of days
um is detritis so we've been we've
probably been swelling but trying to
spores for for a very long period of
time
wow and that I mean and maybe that's a
good thing to bring up too in terms of
like a total yeast and mold test is it
is it really kind of to protect the
consumer from potentially getting sick
or is it more of just like a check on
just good sanitation or hygienic
processes that are going on in the grow
yeah so I think it's both
um the reason it's it's flagged from a
regulatory or health perspective is
because of the fact that there are these
reports from the 70s and 80s of uh
aspergillosis occurring or aspergillus
infections sometimes in patients that
have us have smoked cannabis so there's
been a correlation there now how often
is it I don't know is it one in a
hundred thousand is it one in ten
thousand we don't have those numbers to
say that out of all the population of
cannabis uh consumers a certain
proportion will get aspergillus
infections but I guess if one person
gets it that's enough to to raise a flag
a radar the other yeasts and moles that
are in there that you are you and I are
consuming every day in our diet whether
it's uh strawberry or or blueberry or
some other fresh fruit our bodies deal
with it and break it down and it's it's
not an issue
in cannabis we really don't know when we
do these yeast and mole tests and
somebody comes to me and says I got 20
000 or I got 40 000.
I don't know what that means from a
health perspective and I don't think the
health practitioners know what that
means either
certainly the more it is you know the
more the chances of getting a problem
but if you told me that twenty thousand
is twice as bad as ten thousand I
wouldn't believe you because there is no
data to support that now if it's a
hundred thousand I would say boy that's
a lot like you shouldn't have a hundred
thousand cfus in a gram when we put that
on a picture there's that petri dish is
is covered you can't see the pikriatives
it's just got so much mold on it to me
that's not a great product itself
but if you told me it's forty thousand
versus ten I have no idea what that
means now in Canada we've set the limit
at 50 and and so 50 seems to be a doable
number it's a reasonable number in that
uh if you're below 50 you're you
probably have a product that's that's
other than the aspergillus species a
product that that's doable in a sense
the body can deal with that level of
mold
um if it's less than that so much the
better because it's getting closer and
closer to being almost almost clean
so different states have set up
different numbers I think Massachusetts
is probably up around 100 000 other
others maybe less uh countries like
Israel uh where if you're using cannabis
for medical purposes it's zero like the
product has to be essentially irradiated
to make sure it's totally clean
so we don't have data on what these
numbers actually mean in terms of a
health perspective
yeah no and I think that's interesting
that in Canada it's set at 50 because
like you mentioned here in the states I
mean it ranges Iowa I believe if you
look on the map that we have on our
website Iowa has it set at 10. literally
10 cfu which seems almost impossible
um and then you have Florida and I
believe Michigan and maybe Connecticut
too they're up to a hundred thousand and
everywhere in between but it's all
orders of 10.
um so it's funny that Canada is like
well 50. so it's well we've always been
known as a country that sort of tries to
balance things out and you know make
sure that we're we're approaching things
from a reasonable perspective I have
never seen I have never seen a cannabis
flower uh come in at zero yeah and I've
never I would never have seen a flower
come in at 10. so that's unreasonable to
me uh to to have something that will uh
walking down the park to your car you've
already inhaled more than 10 quality
forming units of mold because of the
mold in the trees and in the flowers and
everything else around you so there has
to be a reasonable number that says you
know I'm not saying 50 is reasonable but
there has to be a number that says okay
we can deal with that from a grower
perspective you know when when we see 50
000 on on flower
it's usually a product that has been
grown under very high humidity or it's
during the peak of Summer where there's
a lot of heat or it's a flower that's
had some damage done to it because 50 is
still a very high number uh to to to
meet in other words most things should
pass 50 000. I've seen maybe two to
three percent of product get rejected
because it's been over 50 000. so that
that's a good number to say that okay
you know what below 50 things are
probably going to be okay so 10 or 50 or
100 cfus to me is is very low
I mean it's impossible really because
everything out there has mold on it
right
and really I mean so I kind of go back
to what we were saying before it's not
so much
how much mold although that can be an
indicator but it's what type is on there
too right because I mean yes so say you
you've set the limit at 50 like you're
having Canada
um if you had 40 000 cfus of say
aspergillus that's much more concerning
than if if it were you know one of these
other
non-pathogenic species yes I agree I
agree and so in my in my opinion there
are maybe three uh three groups of fungi
that should be tested for let's say we
decided we don't want to do total sea of
fuse anymore
and we abandoned that approach and said
all right we're just going to Target
certain fungi that we know historically
have had an importance for humans
uh and could potentially cause problems
if they're present in flower or on
product one would definitely be
aspergillus again because of the
historical significance of aspergillus I
don't think anybody would argue that we
we should just exclude it that would be
turning a blind eye to to reports of
aspergillus causing disease the other is
fusarium we know there's fusarium on
cannabis and hemp uh we know fusarium
causes major problems on cereal and
other crops because of the toxins and
then the third is penicillium now
penicillium is a tough one because
there's so much of it and not all of it
is bad like I mentioned the cheese right
you've got you know penicillin on your
cheese if you eat a little bit of moldy
cheese you're going to be fine
so but if we are are going to Target
three organisms those would be the three
the rest of it just ignore it like it's
we're seeing those every day in our
diets it hasn't caused a problem
everywhere
um I can find
30 to 40 different species of Eastern
mold on any given cannabis flower
out of which maybe two is aspergillus
and one might be fusarium so really out
of that list of 40 I would only be
concerned with three those three I think
we should just test for those three
and let the others be as they may
um because a lot of times Growers use
beneficial products like trichoderma and
I and gliocladium and other fungi that
are registered they're allowed to be
used on cannabis they can cause yeast
yeast and mole numbers
so high that the product fails
so you're coming to me now and saying
I've treated this product with
trichoderma I haven't used any
pesticides this product is clean but
it's failing because it's got huge
numbers of spores of trichoderma which
is has been found to be okay for people
to to have
and so that's a dilemma if we're testing
just total use the vote if we're testing
for aspergillus 3 0 of the penicillium
the trichodoma one is going to pass yeah
and now now I know in the case of
aspergillus product is more familiar
with it that you know it it likely the
regulation wouldn't be just any form of
aspergillus because there's all sorts of
different species it would be those four
pathogenic ones that we had mentioned
before is it the same case
um with penicillium and fusarium
I would say yes I would I would say
there's there's like penicillin citronum
is one species that's very very common
that produces a number of these
mycotoxins and certainly in fusarium
there's a couple of three uh species
gremliner is definitely one of them and
pseudogram linear sport tracheoids I'm
just throwing these names out because
these are names that we know about so
yes for sure you wouldn't necessarily
want to go after every single cesarean
that may be there right um it would be
targeted towards the ones that we know
so really you're looking at about oh
three and three six maybe eight
eight or nine uh specific fungi that are
known to be harmful to humans that have
produced toxins and we should monitor
for those and um the others obviously
and then maybe set a limit of let's say
50 000 total cfus if if they were going
to use that yeah um and anything below
that don't worry about it but then uh
test for these seven or eight like we do
salmonella and E coli and so on we don't
test for Every bacteria that's present
well
in some states they do in some states
they do that's right they have the total
bacterial loads as well yeah right yeah
but luckily like you said those
thresholds are usually set pretty high
and that isn't one that uh Growers seem
to struggle with but total Easter mold
is and we did say that we were going to
talk about some of the factors that your
your team identified so let's get into
that and I think one of the major ones
um that you identified that was in this
paper was that the plant genetics
themselves
uh play a huge role in the tym levels
um I wonder if you could speak a bit to
that and is it specifically like the
physical structure of the plant and the
in the flowers that leads to that or is
there something else going on like does
it have something to do with immunity
yeah yeah so that that was a bit of a
surprise to us as well and I'm sort of
glad we really included like seven or
eight different types of genetics or
genotypes right in the study
um obviously we were grabbing whatever
whatever we could whatever was being
grown at the time so it wasn't a planned
experiment but we did find definite
differences between the the types of of
cannabis that were being grown primarily
it's to do with the morphology and the
size of the flower structure so the
larger the the flowers you know the
bigger the the mass if you wish or
volume the higher the yeast and mold in
general plants that produce very small
buds smaller buds many of them but
smaller in size not as dense seem to
have less over over East and low so
there was definitely this physical
um correlation in some cases I do think
there were chemical products chemicals
produced in the flower that would be
would be inhibiting yeast and moon I I
say that because
some some of these flowers were the
Eastern mold was so low
that it was almost impossible to explain
just from the fact that the flowers were
small I think they were secreting some
kind of a chemical product a natural
chemical product that was it was
preventing these Eastern walls from
growing if we knew what those were boy
maybe we'd be off to a really good start
from a research perspective I mean
definitely that's something that needs
to be looked at I don't think it's
something like terpenes or or some of
these other volatiles that we know it's
definitely not THC or CBD because all of
these were producing THC CBD something
else that that perhaps isn't on the
radar yet something that other
researchers or breeders may want to look
at but certainly flower structure flower
size and the reason though the larger
flowers seem to have more yeast and mold
is the humidity the moisture in those
flowers is higher by three to four
percent in terms of relative humidity
than the outside air and their
temperature builds up in the flower it's
almost a mini it's a mini Greenhouse
sitting on a flower on a plant because
it traps the solar radiation and it
warms up the buds warm up two three
degrees higher than the environment so
that humidity and moisture the
temperature creates this little
Greenhouse that allows these yeasts and
molds to build up so one thing we asked
ourselves well if you if you circulate
the air you know you turn a fan on close
to the plants and let this air here to
infiltrate through the flowers what
would happen and boy the easternmost
dropped by 90 a while now you can't go
out and put a fan next to every plant
but certainly you increase your your
airflow your air movement the humidity
drops the temperature drops and your
flowers have way less yeast and mode
and it's not impractical it's some
greenhouses you can set up 8 or 10 fans
blowing in a certain direction and that
will really reduce the yeast in milk
yeah and you know I'm I and I imagine
Growers too would be encouraged to to
hear you say that there could be
something more than just the morphology
of the buds that that's contributing to
it
um because I mean because if you think
about it Growers want big dense flowers
and to have that be associated with
higher tym well that's that's not good
news at all no no certainly and so the
chemicals are discovered which they will
be eventually uh that will be very very
useful because that's a natural way for
the plant to you know to protect itself
now plants don't have a an immune system
but they do secrete many many chemicals
and many of these chemicals are known to
inhibit the growth of mold and bacteria
and so on and so finding that um strain
or strains would be very useful yeah or
even you know putting that into a spray
of some kind or
um yeah
and one other thing that I saw in the
paper too is that you know in addition
to the density and the size of the buds
it was the number of leaves in the
actual flower too contributed to that as
well correct yeah so so this is the
first time I've actually taken an entire
flower apart using a pair of forceps and
scalpels sort of like a surgeon would
you know I took the flower and cut it up
into its various components and All
Growers will know that we've got these
bracks which are the sort of the
fluorescence leaves that surround the
the center of that of that female flower
and really the more the more
inflorescence these you have generally
speaking the higher your THC and CBD
because the trichomes are found in these
little breaks surrounding the the
pistols so I went through it and
literally cut them all out and started
counting them and the larger buttons had
more of these inflorescence leaves of
Brax again because it provides
protection against the flower and it
increases the humidity in there
so like you said the bigger flowers more
more total THC more CBD but also more of
these inflorescence leaves are building
up in there so visualize a flower
structure that's more open
where Eric can sort of filter through
it's got fewer leaves on the outside
lower yield definitely lower yield but
less tea it's less of yeast and milk so
it's sort of a trade-off right well you
don't want two small flowers you got no
yeast in law but then you've got no THC
or CBD so to speak yeah somewhere
there's a happy medium
yeah so I mean I guess in terms of so
for giving practical advice to Growers
who are trying to lower their tym
um in terms of plant genetics what
should they be thinking should they be
trying to select strains that you know
have certain morphology that are going
to be more favorable for lower levels
should they be increasing their airflow
what do you kind of advise yeah so I
think the breeding part is still a ways
off I mean I I'm sure there are Growers
that have made correlations with certain
strains are known to have higher yeast
and mold a lot of the strains
incidentally that have high yeast and
mold are also very sensitive to botritis
so Growers know which strains they grow
that have more botritis Bud rot they can
stay away from those because those are
the ones that are also going to build up
highest and mold go with your botritis
tolerance strains they would have a
tendency to have lower yeast and mold
because the flower structure is much
smaller more less dense
obviously keep the airflow happening
lower low our humidity is always good
for for both botritis and yeast in mold
don't leave a lot of leaf litter on the
floor right there's a Tendencies to just
cut leaves and drop them when the leaves
get dried out there's a ton of yeast and
mold that naturally start to grow on
that and anything that disturbs that
leaf litter on the on the bottom will
create some of these spores uh you know
flying up to the top of the flower now
you know flowers are sticky right
they're producing resin and we've shown
that if you have a lot of yeast in mold
in the air they'll actually land on the
flower and stick
they'll stick onto that resin and
they're they're not killed they're not
inactivated so those flowers when
they're taken into the lab and test it
for yeast and mold they actually have
higher levels because of the fact that
spores in the air were sticking to the
surface of that resin so that's
something else to obviously be aware of
during Harvest don't create a lot of
activity around the plants in terms of
too much shaking or too much jiggling
because that'll just create a Spore dust
if you wish that that will land and
stick to the to the flowers
yeah
sure sorry go ahead so as far as spray
sometimes people say well can I spray
zero tall or can I spray some chem some
product that's registered
I don't think it's a good idea because
you you're increasing the humidity uh
moisture level in that flower
particularly when it's closer to harvest
um so really there's not much you can do
from a treatment perspective to bring
those levels down
no and I and I understand too that a a
lot of it isn't so much what happens
during the growing of the plant but it's
in the post-harvest activities uh the
drying the curing and the trimming
um I wonder if you could speak a bit
about what you found around that sort of
uh activity yeah yeah so that that's a
that's another aspect that's super
important so let's leave the grower
aside you know you've you've picked up a
whole batch of
harvested flour and now you're deciding
how am I going to trim this do I want to
do you know the standard wet trim where
you push all the flowers through into uh
into a trimmer and then dry the
individual the buds or do you want to
hang dry where everything is left intact
and then you know the moisture is taken
out and then you can trim off your your
leaves we found a pretty uh big
difference between hang dry and and wet
shrimp the wet trim creates some damage
obviously to the to the leaves and
releases chemicals or or nutrients that
a lot of moles that might be present
particularly penicillium start to feed
on it and grow
so even on during the drying process
you're seeing buildup of these molds in
a flower that's been trimmed wet on the
other hand when you dry this thing first
uh you're not allowing these these wound
sites or broken off leaves as a source
for mold and yeast to get in the entire
flower structure is dried you've you've
eliminated 90 percent of your yeast in
mold and then when you start trimming it
as a dry trim we found the the eastern
wall levels were way lower
so that's one thing that definitely will
make a difference a lot of Growers are
using the handguard system they'll
probably find they don't have as many as
much issues with yeast and mold
we didn't look at anything beyond that
in other words you know the curing
process or the packaging and storing
process I think All Growers know that
when you store inappropriate humidity or
temperatures you're gonna get build up
of Eastern mold and they know that if
you cure them too long or under high
moisture you're going to get yeast and
mold so we didn't really look at that
aspect we kind of stopped right at the
point where the flowers had been trimmed
whether it's wet or dry and then
collected data from that
no that's interesting so do you have any
idea like in terms of percentage what
Growers are typically doing is it more
common for them to be doing wet trimming
versus dry they're shifting a lot
towards dry trim because it's less work
in a sense you know you can bring the
flowers into the dryer rooms hang them
and then and then deal with them later
the drying process itself is very
detrimental to easternmost which is
obviously a good thing you know when you
have dry herbs and dry products dried
figs and they tend to last a lot longer
because the moisture is taken out of
them similarly with dried flour the
problem is that you never get down to
zero I've never seen a dried flower get
down to zero more yeast and more there's
always a fraction that still hangs
around and that that population can
always build up later on if if the
storage conditions aren't right
but if you're coming in with a very high
Eastern mold load then nothing you do
after harvest it's going to bring all of
it down to zero so there's two two
components try to reduce the Eastern
mold while you're growing and then after
you harvest and bring it in try to do
things that will reduce the yeast amount
even further in that in that product
that you're handling
yeah and I have to imagine that leaf
litter too would be a big consideration
during the trimming process
yes and even having too many leaves on
there can't create problems for not
enough moisture drying and so on so hang
drying has to be done carefully because
that you've got way more plant material
and you want to make sure that all of it
gets down to I don't know 12 to 14
moisture so that you're not leaving
remnants of yeast and mold even in the
hang dry samples
um I would say over over the year of
study like we looked at maybe
I don't know two to three thousand
samples if everything is done right
samples are are not too much yeast and
mold in the beginning
um they're a hang dried and carefully
handled
in the entire batch of 2000 samples I
would say the average yeast and mold was
around 2000. so 2000 would be sort of
the average that you would expect
everything was done right you know you
brought things in properly they were
hand-dried and trimmed and so on and so
forth 2000 is doable in Most states and
definitely doable in most most countries
but never will it ever go down to zero
yeah I know and I was going to ask you
too about the you were mentioning the
hang drying and they're being kind of
leaves and kind of creating the maybe
the moisture environment that's similar
to what you were talking about during
growing so with that in mind important
to have good air circulation when you're
doing the hang drying as well totally
totally and in fact we actually see an
explosion of Eastern Rome when the
plants first enter the driver the drying
room because there's so much on there
that they just start moving around so
you're right get the airflow happening
make sure it's a it's a long process
seven days five to seven days uh get the
moisture out measure the moisture in
there to make sure it's low enough
before we take it out and start trimming
it for for final product
there are pockets of Eastern mold in
there I have seen in some in some of the
flowers for some reason there's little
pockets where you're looking at 10 15
000 cfus per gram but if it's fried
properly uh it should go down to between
two to five
I would say is a good number that
anybody would be happy with yeah no
absolutely and as you said you're never
going to get down to zero unless you
maybe do some irradiation
um I don't know what kind of experience
you have with that or if you have
thoughts on that I know it's sort of a
touchy subject in in the yeah so so
that's allowed in Canada we're allowed
to irradiate with e-beam radiation I
have looked at samples before and after
from the perspective of Eastern mold uh
it's pretty much zero after it's been
irradiated what does it do to the final
product uh people that have used it
would say that it doesn't really alter
too much of the the cannabinoid profiles
it may perhaps impact some of the
terpenes but overall they they're
finding not a significant difference
between irradiated and not from a from
an organoleptic perspective the problem
is the cost
it's really expensive to go through and
treat all the product unless you
absolutely have to for example if you're
exporting and it's a requirement for
zero zero mode that you you would have
to do that but it's it's expensive
um there's there's other ways and I
think the article we published was
trying to address what are these other
ways that could minimize your yeast and
mold levels without having to resort to
things like
irradiation afterwards
yeah and which I know there's different
types of irradiation which ones were you
looking at is it ozone or no we looked
at uh Electron Beam radiation even
radiation I haven't looked at ozone
people have talked about ozone there's
also plasma cold plasma treatments
um the Israelis the Israeli researchers
have done a good good studies on that
they've published a couple of papers on
different forms of radiation that that
are effective and most of them do very
similar results to to e-beam radiation
that we've looked at but there is a cost
factor that is there's also the handling
Vector right you gotta then take your
products move them over to the site
that's being uh created and then bring
them back for for packaging and so on
yeah yeah absolutely all right but it
does seem like There's Hope here that
you know if if best practices are
followed then you should be able to
hopefully get underneath the the
threshold as as long as your state has
set a realistic one I think so now we
haven't talked about outside growth oh
yeah that's that's another story
altogether because you have so little
control over the weather if you get
rained on if it's a you know a series of
Hot 100 degree weather with high
humidity uh it's almost impossible to
manage Eastern world that's really
unfortunate and I don't have any
suggestions or recommendations there
because I haven't worked with outdoor
growing cannabis uh in terms of yeast
and mold uh it would be definitely more
challenging uh to to manage those those
plants
yeah I can tell you as someone who has
grown in the Northeast and had plants
that finish in October it can be very
tough to to manage mold yeah and you
know something just occurred to me maybe
there should be a criteria for
um regulations indoor cannabis versus
outdoor where there's more leniency on
the on the indoor because you know that
the the eastern wall pressure overall is
going to be lower indoors if
everything's done the way it should be
outdoors maybe that's a different
scenario so I don't know if the
Regulatory Agencies consider a method of
production or not uh there could be some
way to discriminate uh indoor or
differentiate I should say differentiate
indoor grown versus outdoors in terms of
potentially having lower
um cfus
yeah no that's a great Point all right
Samir uh do you want to be very mindful
of your time and um I already know that
I'm going to be putting a link to the
paper in the show description for people
to check out because there's a ton more
information in there that we didn't get
a chance to get to
um but in addition to that if you have
any other resources or
um or research that you'd like to share
with the folks and that I could put
links to uh please let me know and then
of course any ways that people can maybe
get in touch with you or follow the work
that you're doing please plug away
sure I appreciate that and again it's an
exciting field to be in because there's
there's so much to learn and um the idea
of exchanging information to me is is
very important uh the the fact that
we're talking today is because I want
the information to get out there I want
it to be used uh you you guys have a
good way of disseminating it and the
more we share the more we know the more
we understand and the more we can manage
these these problems these problems are
not new they've been around for
centuries uh since the day cannabis was
first Grown I suspect the yeast and mold
tolerance was much higher back then
um than it is now but we need to we need
to know we need to study and we need to
share
absolutely no and we appreciate you
coming on again zamir and I'm sure I'm
sure you'll be back you'll be back again
and uh if we don't see you before can
Med I can't wait to see you down in
Marco Island thanks a lot appreciate it
all right thanks man
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Dr punja check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode's sponsor Agilent
Technologies
in the meantime please like comment and
subscribe on whichever platform you use
to listen to us
also please check out cammedevents.com
to sign up for email alerts and learn
all about our annual Innovation and
investment Summit
you can also view videos of all the past
kanmed presentations in the can Med
archive at canmanevents.com
I invite you to join our cammed
community group on Facebook to interact
with other cannabis professionals and
please do follow us on social media
we're on Instagram LinkedIn Twitter and
Facebook just search for Kim at events
all right that's it from us stay safe
stay healthy and be sure to join us for
the next Kim and Coffee Talk
[Music]
foreign