foreign
[Music]
Coffee Talk podcast where we talk with
the leading Minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I am your host Ben amaralt I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the can Med conference
speaking of the cam Med conference can
Med 24 Returns the JW Marriott Resort in
Marco Island Florida May 12th through
15th and registration opens October 6th
don't miss this opportunity to learn
from and network with the industry's top
researchers and innovators in one of the
most beautiful settings possible
we have a lot of exciting new additions
to the summit format that we will be
announcing soon but really there's no
reason to wait to register for the can
Med 24 Innovation and investment Summit
you want to make sure you secure your
spot soon because capacity is limited at
the venue and we are expecting to sell
out so act now and take advantage of our
early bird pricing go to cammed
events.com to learn more
my guest today is Mitchell Westmoreland
Mitch is a PhD candidate working for Dr
Bruce bugbee in the crop physiology
laboratory at Utah State University
his PhD research focuses on whole plant
physiology and cultivation of medicinal
cannabis in controlled environments
he has published his research on
photobiology and plant nutrition and
high impact peer-reviewed scientific
journals
I spoke with Mitch about the various
environmental factors that contribute to
cannabis yield specifically light
temperature humidity and CO2
Mitch does a great job explaining the
energy Cascade which is a way of
describing the underlying mechanisms
that plants use to convert photons to
energy and ultimately biomass
Mitch also explains how these factors
can be manipulated to not only increase
yield but also make better use of
resources
I really enjoyed this conversation and I
expect we will see Mitchell on the can
Med stage very soon
before we get to my conversation with
Mitch I would like to thank this episode
sponsor Advanced Nutrients
founded in 1999 Advanced Nutrients was
the first to develop a complete nutrient
system that unlocks the true genetic
potential of the cannabis plant
since its Inception the brand has
introduced more than 50 Innovations to
the cultivation community and continues
to revolutionize the space through
proprietary scientific discoveries learn
more and advancenutrients.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Mitchell
Westmoreland
[Music]
good morning Mitch welcome to the
podcast fun sprung happy to be on her
all right so today we are going to
explore the different factors that
contribute to cannabis yield
um and I know you are a good person to
talk to because you've done a lot of
research into these factors and you
recently presented some of your work at
the Cannabis Conference out in Nevada
which is what got you on my radar so I
expect we'll have a good conversation
about these factors and how they
contribute but before we do that I think
it might be wise to establish what we
mean by yield because I think sometimes
and at least in my mind the term gets
used interchangeably when talking about
biomass or the amount of flour the plant
produces and cannabinoid concentration
so maybe when you're talking about yield
which of those are you're talking about
if not both
yeah I mean with any crop plant when we
talk about yield we're talking about the
harvestable part of the plant right so
for tomatoes it's the tomatoes for wheat
it's the seeds and so for cannabis
medical cannabis it's the flowers
um now that sort of you know depends
there's a lot of it depends in the
Cannabis world if you're going for
extraction you might be using all that
biomass but generally when we talk about
yield we're talking about the mass of
flowers and in my mind one of the bigger
issues is all of the different metrics
that are used in the Cannabis industry
so you'll hear things like yield per
plant or yield per light yield per
fixture things like that
and if you've got sort of a standardized
plant size or a light source then that
can be useful useful but for the most
part those don't really tell you a whole
lot is it a big plant small plant high
pressure sodium light versus LED lights
and so we can take it you know one step
further and say yield per area right so
grams per square foot ounce per square
foot and that gets us a little bit
closer to being able to compare and see
how a different facilities are
functioning But ultimately
um
you know even with that yield per area
did it take you eight weeks to get that
yield but it could be 10 weeks so
there's time component in there too and
so one thing that we're really trying to
push is this uh concept of photon
conversion efficiency so we're talking
about how efficiently a crop of cannabis
takes the light that it's given and
converts it into flowers
right
um that's kind of what I want to get in
today and we can break up that Photon
conversion efficiency into smaller
components to try and untangle you know
some of these environmental effects
um and then when we're talking about
cannabinoid concentration that's
typically what we would call Quality and
both of those things are important
yields for Quality sometimes you're
willing to sacrifice a little bit of
yield if you can get your cannabinoid
concentration a little bit higher
but that's sort of the distinction for
me yield is flower Mass
quality is the cannabinoid concentration
or the terpene concentration
yeah and you make a good point in that
it it sort of the term is dependent on
what your goals are right because in
some cases if you're if you're looking
to extract the cannabinoids then
I guess the yield would be the amount of
cannabinoids contained in the flower
exactly yeah the cannabinoid yield and
so yeah as with everything and I'm a
scientist so I'm really hesitant to
speak in absolute but it it always
depends you know what is what is your
growth goal what capabilities do you
have what are your limitations and
ultimately what are you striving for
there's a lot of Depends in there for
sure
yeah okay and so now you made reference
to sort of this idea of how well the
plant converts the photons into actual
flowering and that there's a number of
different
mechanisms that contribute to that so so
let's dive in let's let's talk about
those yeah so
you know
cannabis is just recently been
started to be studied right it's been
illegal for so long but now research
institutions are starting to get on
board
and you know all what you'll hear all
the time is we don't know anything about
this plant because we haven't been able
to study it and to some extent that's
true but at the same time it's it's just
a plant right and so we know based on
Decades of research and other crops
what the basic nutritional needs are how
they respond to CO2 irrigation water
stress things like that and so
optimizing all of those things isn't
necessarily difficult
once you get all of the environmental
factors optimized nutrition CO2 watering
light becomes the limiting fact of the
growth and what's remarkable about
cannabis and we'll get into this a
little bit more it can harm a lot of
light it really likes exceptionally High
light
um
but with that sort of perspective
nothing else is limiting other than
photons
how do we efficiently convert those
photons into flowers which is ultimately
what we're going to harvest right
and so the very first thing that that
needs to happen and again at this point
we're considering a canopy a big
community of cannabis plants rather than
a single leaf or a single plant
the very first thing that canopy has to
do is absorb those photons right you've
got a small plant that's not taking up
the entire ground area there's photons
that are just hitting the floor and
those aren't driving in growth right so
the very first step is capture those
photons and we'll talk a little bit
about how the environment can influence
that here in a little bit but once we've
captured those photons
some of them are going to be absorbed by
non-photosynthetic pigments like
anthocyanins things like that some of
them get reflected right we see the
plants they're green
and so the next step is how efficiently
do we take those photons and use them to
drive photosynthesis to fix CO2 from the
atmosphere so step two is photosynthetic
efficiency
now the next one is you know sometimes
I'll mention this in talks and sometimes
I won't uh but the next one is carbon
use efficiency this isn't a very
well-known metric but once the plants
fix that carbon through CO2 some of it's
going to be respired again as CO2 right
they've got to make DNA they've got to
make proteins uh
so the carbon use efficiency this one's
really hard to change with the
environment it's it's remarkably
consistent across species and
environmental conditions the plants will
respire in proportion to how much CO2
they fix through photosynthesis
the last one is one that can be heavily
influenced by the environment and this
is sort of the last component that gets
us to yield and that's carbon
partitioning efficiency or harvest index
so how much of that carbon that's fixed
and stored in biomass is put into the
flowers that's ultimately what we're
what we're interested in
so what's what's great about these four
components and we call it the energy
Cascade model because we're following
the energy from the photons all the way
down into the flowers these are all
efficiencies so it's an input over an
output or an output over an input right
and then you know with a little bit of
behind the scenes math and some units
conversions we can multiply all of these
values together and get that Photon
conversion efficiency
and that has units of grams of flour per
mole or photons you know everybody
measures their ppfd and micro multimeter
squared per second and I think most
people are familiar with the concept of
Daily Light integral which is the total
amount of light that's received
um
over the course of a day and
that's ultimately how we how we arrive
at that value and what's great about
this is it doesn't matter how long you
brew the crap crop it doesn't matter if
it was 10 000 square feet or a hundred
thousand square feet
this sort of normalizes all of that and
we could start to compare across
facilities and how efficiently they're
using the light to make the flowers
so if I understand correctly
what you're really driving at is to be
able to say okay if your input of light
is X you would expect at the end to get
an output of Y correct exactly exactly
and you know what's that's a
great point because when we arrive at
this Photon conversion efficiency grams
per mole we can take you know whatever
DLI we print at input and multiply it by
that value to get the expected yield for
theoretical yield so we can start to
sort of put numbers to these now they
you know I know that proton conversion
efficiency isn't a very well-known
metric but I'll just to give you some
perspective for cannabis we typically
see something between 0.2 and 0.3 grams
per mole and then again with some with
some math and some units conversions you
can take a DLI input and predict what
your yield should be in grams per square
meter or Brands per square foot
right and so then if if by the end your
output isn't what you expected you could
sort of Trace things back and kind of
see where you're kind of leakage was
exactly you can go back to those four
components you know and say was my
Photon capture low was the
photosynthetic proficiency low
um
or was there something else limiting
like water or nutrients or CO2 something
like that
but it's it's a it's a really elegant
model
um mostly for its Simplicity you know
it's kind of hard to talk about I wish I
had a whiteboard so I could go through
it and show the units
um
but it's it's a very simple way for us
to start to understand how the
environment influences yield and
ultimately if there is an effect of the
environment on yield it has to come back
to one of those four components was it
Photon capture photosynthetic efficiency
and so once you have that once you have
a good understanding of that you can
sort of get away from all of the snake
oil claims that you know this product is
going to boost your yield by 40 you know
on and on
and you can ask yourself okay well which
of these four components is this product
actually affect them
now
I have to imagine that genetics play a
big role in this too right with all the
different strains they're going to sort
of have different uh
different roles to play big time and
with the with the genetics
you know the the two components that
it's most likely to influence is the
photon capture efficiency right is it a
blank that sort of spreads out
horizontally to capture more light or is
it more of a tall slender growth habit
does it have thick leaves or thin leaves
um that can have big effects on how
efficiently that crop is absorbing that
light and then the other one is carbon
partitioning efficiency you know some
varieties just put more of that
uh carbon that they fix into flowers
some of them don't make a whole lot of
leads and stems on the other hand some
of them make a whole lot of leaves and
stems and that's not what we necessarily
interested in when we're talking about
high value Medical phone numbers
interesting okay
go ahead but the other two were really
fundamentally
um limited by physiology and they're
well understood at the basic biology
level
um genetics aren't going to have a huge
impact on those
interesting okay so so let's talk about
environment how is the environment
affecting sort of these different
underlying mechanisms and I mean I know
that's sort of broad so maybe you know
you could you could start with you know
light or or whichever one you think
yeah let's let's start with light
um
and when we're thinking about light and
you sort of uh hinted at this earlier
there's sort of three characteristics
that we're interested in the quality or
the Spectrum the color of the lights and
the quantity of the light or the
intensity and then there's also the
duration or the photo period
and
you know I'll just kind of pick out some
of the the highlights let's start with
light quality so the colors of Lights
um
Photon capture uh spectral quality can
have a big effect on photon capture and
I think people are starting to to get a
lot more of this but especially far red
light has received a lot of attention
over the over the last few years but
it's well known to cause Leaf expansion
and increase Photon capture
unfortunately you also get a lot of stem
elongation along with it so for cannabis
it's not often used for this purpose but
for things like lettuce it's extremely
valuable to give them some Far red light
so they expand and capture that light
faster
um green light is an interesting one
that's also starting to get some more
recognition you know people typically
think that green light isn't used by
plants we see that they're green so they
don't absorb any of it which is not in
fact true they do absorb and use green
light for photosynthesis and one of the
valuable things
about green light is it can penetrate
deeper into the canopy whereas red and
blue light tends to get absorbed on the
outside and you have a whole bunch of
stuff in the middle that's not getting
uh that's not capturing any light and so
those green photons can penetrate deeper
and increase that Photon capture a
little bit
those are sort of the big ones with
light quality you know in terms of
photosynthetic efficiency there's some
small effects for the most part you've
ever heard of the McCree curve it's
often cited as you know the relative
photosynthetic proficiency of different
colors
um
but under high light intensity that
tends to be a pretty minor minor effect
and then going on to quantity uh this
one's this one's an interesting one and
it's kind of counterintuitive when we
start to think about proton inversion
efficiency
so if we if we think about the
photosynthetic efficiency so how much of
those absorbed photons are the plants
putting into
photosynthesis to fix carbon and you
know if I were to say to you you know
if I give my plant more light what's
going to happen to you the obvious
answer is the yield is going to go up
right but when we think about the
efficiency with which they're converting
that light it actually goes down with
increase in life intensity and the
analogy that I like to use is imagine
you're drinking from a faucet right
you're going to get most of the water
that's coming out of that faucet ready
to get the Melt right on it now imagine
you got a fire hose up to your mouth the
quantity is way larger and you might be
getting more on an absolute basis but
you're also wasting a whole lot right so
the efficiency with which you're
ingesting that water goes down so that's
the same or photosynthetic deficiency
you just dump and light on the plants
this will be efficiency goes down
so there's a sweet spot there you want
to be giving it enough to to generate
big flowers but you don't want to be
wasteful
well it again it comes down to what is
your goal do you want to maximize your
yield per square foot or your yield per
area dump the light on there because
that's going to keep going up and up and
up
um if you're interested in maximizing
the efficiency if you've got to pay for
those photons for example or other
electric lights you might try and find a
sweet spot where uh you're not wasting
too much but you're still getting high
enough yield per square foot to to reach
your goals so again it depends
and then the photo periods you know this
is something that's starting to be
increasingly studied in cannabis for
right now
um most people still do the the 1212
although there's been some nice papers
that have been coming out
um that is sort of starting to challenge
that concept but really this this has
the biggest effect on carbon
partitioning right once we give those
plants a short day whether it's 12 12 13
11 they're going to start shifting that
carbon into flowers maybe if we go less
than 12 hours we might be shifting more
of that carbon in the flowers right
right
and then saving on those photons too
yeah exactly exactly you know and
a circle back kind of to light quantity
really quick you know ultimately what's
driving growth is the Daily Light
integral the total amount of photons
that are falling every single day you
know we're out here in Utah in the
Western United States we don't get a lot
of rain
um but when we do we're not interested
in how many raindrops are falling every
single second we want to know how much
we got over the course of the day over
the week or over the entire year and so
if you've got a variety that will still
flower under a longer photo period you
can give the plants a lower light
intensity a lower ppfd for a longer
period of time and get the same DLI
but the photosynthetic efficiency is
going to be higher because they're under
a lower
light intensity that's looking for my
faucet rather than a fiber hose so I
think there's a lot of potential to
start breeding for and selecting
varieties that flower under a longer
photo Boot and we've got the you know
the autoflowers and things like that but
I think there's a lot of potential there
to to optimize both yield per area as
well as the efficiency the yield
efficiency
so those are kind of the big ones with
light light is kind of the sexiest of
all the environmental factors right now
like nutrition
but you know generally what we say is if
you want to get high yields
give them highlight and at that point
respectful quality as a as a really
small effect on especially yield but
also inhabinoids and quality
no and you make a good point that light
is you know one of the more more popular
more well-known uh of these factors but
with that said are there sort of
misconceptions or sort of maybe false
narratives that are out there in terms
of light
uh I think most of those come down to to
Quality to cannabinoid concentration
um you know the one that's sort of
persisted since the 1980s is this idea
of UV
um and we published a paper earlier this
year and there's there's been some other
papers that have come out of uh
University of Guelph that have really
not shown not been able to repeat the
initial results that found that you be
increased when appenoids
um and so I think I think people are
starting to get on board with that and
sort of to ditch the idea that that UB
is the Magic Bullet to give your plants
you know like cannabinoids
oh
that's that's sort of the biggest one I
I just think generally speaking spectral
quality it's too much focus and light
intensity doesn't you know what we
always recommend is
get a light source that is if you're
growing under electric lights get a
light source that's super efficient
gives you a lot of photons but not a lot
of energy and a light source of the high
output a high protein output don't worry
about the spectral quality so much
you should really be focused on
electrical efficiency and that Photon
conversion efficiency
yeah and it's interesting you say that
too I mean I've I've dabbled with kind
of home cultivation a little bit and
I've definitely walked the floors of
different trade shows and everything and
when you look at the light uh the
different light manufacturers it seems
like they really focus in on this sort
of spectral quality they have the graphs
and everything like that but you're
saying that's not as important as just
the amount of photons that they're
getting yep and I think I think some of
these lighting companies are starting to
to see that but with the way the
Cannabis industry is going you know
prices are falling people have got to
start doing this more efficiently more
cost effectively if they want to stay in
business if you're growing under
electric lights that the only way that
you're going to do that efficiently is
by sourcing an efficient light source in
your high profile output you know after
that it can maybe be some some small
effects on anabinoids you know I sort of
use the analogy of the microscope if
you've ever been inside science class
you've got a course Focus knob and I get
you kind of up and down and close to
where you need to be and you've got to
find Focus knob to kind of dial it in
not find Focus knob as sort of the the
spectral quality that can maybe have a
small effect but really
that efficiency in the proton output is
dispute
interesting yeah good analogy
um so with light too and something that
you mentioned earlier was this idea of
broader Leafs or plants that sort of
spread out and can absorb more light
could theoretically you know convert
more of that into flour so what about
the practice of pruning or lollipopping
plants to kind of increase flowers that
seems to be kind of counterintuitive
yeah
um you know this is another thing that's
that's really a Hot Topic in cannabis
people love to prune their plants and I
get it I mean I love to be Hands-On with
my plants too
um
I think oftentimes the the daily thing
is overdone you know if you can look
underneath your crop of cannabis and you
can see light coming through it that
means you're wasting photons right
but at the same time if you can kind of
pinch and manipulate your plants to
encourage them to grow out while still
keeping that that sea of green as they
call it
um you know you can
sort of force the plants to capture more
of those photons which you'll end up
with with a higher yield right the other
way you can do that is with planting
density you know you see all the time
people start out with really small
plants that are super uh super spaced so
you've got a lot of light there early on
that's just falling on the ground so you
can give your plants a shorter veg pack
them in there
prune them and pinch them to keep them
short and to sort of fill that canopy
automatically start out with a higher
Photon capture uh more of that light is
being absorbed more that's going in the
flowers so these cultural techniques are
another way to sort of influence these
these four components but again it comes
down to one of those four components for
the most part it's Photon capture
yeah and the way it was always explained
to me was that you know you want to get
rid of those big fan leaves to get more
light to the actual bud sites to grow
those does that make sense or does the
plant really care or is it just going to
kind of convert whatever energy it
absorbs from those leaves to to all the
flowers
yeah I mean
there's emerging evidence that
flowers that are lower in the canopy
that have been shaded the entire time
and have a lower cannabinoid
concentration we've seen it in our lab
and I know that other people have seen
it too so I think there is something to
delivering light to those flowers in
order to maximize the cannabinoids
but
the the thing to keep in mind is that
you can you can make sure that you have
all of your flowers at the top of the
canopy absorbing the light without
sacrificing Photon capture and so one of
the things that we do and a lot of
people are starting to do is
a relatively short veg period and then
multiple pinches even after you know 10
to 14 days of short days and again what
that does is spread the canopy out and
it promotes fewer but smaller or more
numerous but smaller flower buds at the
top of the canopy that are absorbing the
light you know a single leaf can absorb
like 95 of the protons that hit it so
when you've got flowers that are down
low in that canopy even if the ppfd is
you know a thousand at the top of a
canopy those plants might only be seen
50 micro moles at most and that's just
not enough for them to dissustain
themselves
so yes there is something to it
um but I still think the focus should be
on maximizing that proton capture not
removing too many of those fan leads and
just promoting more numerous smaller
flower buds at the top
right that are more spread out so you
know instead of going you know
three-dimensional vertically try to keep
it all kind of one level spread out
exactly right yeah and I think a lot of
people do that right now with the with
the netting and things like that right
and that's that's a fine way to do it
but again the goal is maximizing that
Photon capture
excellent excellent okay so I guess
moving on from light how about
temperature it's yeah temperature is a
big one uh so this is this is sort of
the focus of my
um dissertation and this is one of those
things in cannabis that just hasn't been
studied
um and part of the reason for that it's
really hard to do in order to do
temperature studies you've got to have
separate Chambers separate rooms
separate aerial environments right and
so we're fortunate in our lab to have
some really good facilities some great
growth Chambers to sort of do these
temperature studies
and so the first you know we go back to
our core components uh Photon capture I
think this one's sort of intuitive you
know as you increase the temperature the
plants grow faster they absorb more
light
um early on so high temperature early on
is great to increase that Photon capture
and
you know I'll get through these and then
we'll talk about this idea of changing
environmental conditions throughout the
life cycle which you sort of hinted at
earlier
but if you
light temperature early on is great to
help increase that Photon capture
now
high temperatures
forest plants to just move super fast
and what that does is sort of
I don't want to say damage but it just
makes the Machinery tired so at the end
of the life cycle if you keep that
temperature hot the photosynthetic
efficiency starts to go down
pretty dramatically the plants are just
tired and they're pushing them too hard
so low temperature late in the life
cycle
has the potential to keep that
photosynthetic efficiency High the
plants are still fixing carbon still
putting it into the flowers
and so you know typically what I
recommend is high temperatures early on
what that means is kind of going to
depend on what you can do and the
varieties that you have
but high temperature until that canopy
closes the plants are absorbing all of
the light and then bring that
temperature down to preserve that
photosynthetic efficiency
but one of the things that I've seen in
in my studies is that
in addition to high temperature increase
in photon capture it helps to promote
carbon partitioning to the flowers so
the plants need some
base temperature early on in order to
set those flowers to start developing
those those valuable
inflorescence so
the high temperature early on both
increases Photon capture and carbon
partitioning
and then
you know one of the other things that
I've seen and I don't think people think
about a whole lot is
those flower buds at the top of the
canopy are just big dense clusters of
mass they don't have a lot of
evaporative cooling like Elite does and
so it can get really really hot
six seven eight degrees Fahrenheit
warmer than the air temperature
and of all of the environmental factors
that I've studied
temperature has the biggest effect on an
ethnoid concentration so we've seen at
high temperatures that the cannabinoids
just go through the floor and part of
the reason for that is the flower buds
are always warmer than air temperature
gender HPS that would be 10 degrees
Fahrenheit warmer than the air so even
if you've got a nice you know 70 72 air
temperature the flowers are 82 something
like that
so the other thing that the low
temperature latent life cycle does is
help to keep that flower temperature low
and and preserve the photosynthetic
machinery and the Machinery needed to
synthesize those cannabinoids
yeah and that sort of aligns with sort
of the the lore or at least what I've
heard in terms of of growing is that you
want to have low temperatures during
flour and that's going to give you more
Frosty buds so that would be the
cannabinoids yep and you get the nice
purple color at the end if you go low
enough right so there's a lot of there's
a lot of potential to use temperature
and manipulate it throughout the life
cycle to achieve whatever goal you
wanted
achieve
but in terms of yield again it comes
back to those those four components
according to capture them the biggest
one
so when you talk about high temperature
low temperature I mean what are we
talking about in terms of you know the
ranges there yeah and this is where
people usually get frustrated with me
and I get frustrated too because the
answer is it depends yeah okay you know
I've talked to enough scientists
yeah
temperature is not only the the thing
that I've seen have a biggest effect on
cannabinoids it's also the thing that
I've seen most variable among varieties
so there are some cultivars where the
cannabinoids start to plummet at an air
temperature of
72 74 something like that so not
terribly hot
um and then there are others that can go
up into the 80s and they're they're just
fine
so it really depends but generally what
I say especially if you're interested in
maximizing the cannabinoids is air on
the cold side rather than the hot side
because if you go one degree too warm
you might be screwed you go one degree
too cool you might not be that big of a
deal
especially during the flowering part I
assume right yeah especially once those
flower buds start to form they're at the
top of the canopy they're absorbing a
lot of energy a lot of heat and they
just get hot
yeah okay
all right so we talked about heat what
about humidity
you know this is
I've seen a lot of people talking about
you know crop steering with BPD and with
humidity
and this is another one of those things
that in my mind is is sort of
overly focused on in cannabis
um
the biggest thing that humidity
has an effect on is disease pressure you
know once you start to get really crazy
and you've got you know 20 humidity and
80 degrees Fahrenheit then things might
start to get a little bit
um
stressful for the plant but for the most
part humidity has a small effect on
growth
now it can have some pretty big indirect
effects and the biggest one is on
temperature
so plants cool themselves by evaporating
water just like we cool ourselves by
evaporating sweat in a humid environment
you know the plants can't transpire as
much they can't cool themselves as much
and so when you've got a high humidity
or a low vapor pressure deficit those
flower buds can get
even warmer so the biggest effects of
humidity are really an indirect effect
of
temperature
we sort of try and look at all of these
different environmental factors piece by
piece but in reality they're all
interact with each other right it's it's
not a very simple straightforward thing
there's a lot of back and forth
um and that the back and forth between
humidity and temperature I think
should be focused on more and less on
you know you got to get a BPD of 1.2 for
week one and then 1.25 for week three
and so on
um
just sort of understanding what affects
humidity to have is going to get you a
lot further than trying to dial it in
yeah no and that makes sense that
humidity might not have a direct effect
on on yield which is the topic of the
conversation but I know from from our
perspective too medicinal genomics we
deal a lot with microbials and plant
pathogens
um and I know that humidity can play a
big role in you know particularly mold
yep which I wish I would imagine if the
plant's infected with mold it's it's
going to compromise your yield your deal
yeah you can't you can't stop that right
so that's and that's that's the biggest
humidity does so the best way to deal
with that and ensure that you know
you're not throwing those molds is to
make sure that you've got good air flow
through that canopy to blow out any
humid air and prevent those sort of
microclimates been forming around the
flower buds and the leaves
right excellent all right and what about
CO2 I know that you know a lot of
Growers kind of supplement their CO2 yep
yep and CO2 you know this kind of comes
down again to basic plant physiology the
fundamental processes of photosynthesis
you know Carbon gets fixed a little bit
of water and goes to Sugar
um so obviously CO2
enrichment helps to increase yield right
and we you know this is another thing
that's not well studied in cannabis
right now for the same reason as
temperature you've got to have separate
Chambers separate rooms
we've done a couple of preliminary
studies on co2 going you know all the
way up to 1500 PPM something like that
and really once you get up to about
our ppfe of a thousand excuse me CO2
concentration of a thousand PPM you
don't really get any more increasing
yield and going from ambient to a
thousand you might increase yield by
about 30 which is actually consistent
with most other crop species that have
been studied in response to CO2
um but the main component that that's
affecting is the photosynthetic
proficiency there's just more CO2
available for the plants to fix
now
since we were just talking about
interactions and temperature CO2 is very
much like humidity in that it can have
indirect effects on temperature so when
the plants are in a high CO2 environment
they close their stomachs the little
pores on the leaves where CO2 goes in
and water comes out they don't need to
have them quite as open because there's
a whole bunch of CO2 outside and what
that does is reduce the evaporative
cooling at the leak surface and so your
canopy and your flower temperature gets
bottom right so again something you know
I think it's great to enrich with CO2 we
always do enrich with CO2 it you know
reduces water use there's a whole bunch
of benefits to it
um but you've got to think about it in
the context of all of your and other all
of your other environmental factors to
make sure that your co-optimizing all of
them
excellent excellent all right Mitch well
I definitely want to be uh respectful of
your time we've already spent a lot of
time talking about this but before I let
you go
um so I mean we've mentioned that
there's a lot of these different
environmental factors and some of them
haven't been as well studied what is it
that you're working on now what can what
can we uh anticipate
yeah so I'm I'm in my fourth year of my
PhD so I'm hoping to get out of here
soon and I've got a lot of data on
temperature that bits I think is going
to be extremely valuable for the
industry that I'm really looking forward
to to getting out
um the other thing that that we've done
a lot of in our lab that's very unique
is measurements of canopy photosynthesis
so we can watch Plants fix carbon and
respire carbon
uh continuously throughout the life
cycle and what that allows us to do is
separate some of these four components
and say was this an effect on photon
capture is this a direct effect on
photosynthetic efficiency so we can
start to really take apart these these
environmental factors
um but but in my opinion I think the
biggest thing that's going to come out
is all of this this temperature data you
know I talked anecdotally to Growers and
they'll say yeah we had a you know a
string of hot days in the greenhouse or
cannabinoids went through the floor but
there's just no no data on it yet and so
I think that's going to be that's going
to be valuable the other thing that
we're doing is you know I talked about
how this plant just loves light it'll
hog light all day long or you know we're
trying to
figure out where that upper limit is we
just did a study like going up to a DLI
of like 100 moles per day and I think
there have been some
commercial companies and lighting
companies that have done similar stuff
but
we've got data that the yield continues
to go up up to 70 80 moles a day which
is like 30 percent higher than anything
we would ever see in the field
practically you may not ever want to do
that in your facility it's expensive to
get to 100 miles a day but
physiologically that there's a lot of
interesting things that we can learn
about uh cannabis and use it sort of as
a model prop
to understand the limits of plant
physiology
excellent well that is that is exciting
and hopefully
um hopefully you'll have some data out
and you'll submit an abstract and we'll
see you present some of that at can Med
um
so before I let you go I want to give
you an opportunity to share with the
with the audience any ways to maybe get
in touch with you or read more about
some of the work that you've done please
plug away
yeah um we've got my email address I
don't know if you can link this with the
podcast uh it's
mitchell.westmoreland usu.edu
um you know our lab for the past two or
three years has been putting on an
online cannabis class that's available
to the public you don't need to be a
registered USU student uh we're just
getting ready to start the Third Edition
of this course we're still working out
some of the details uh but if you're
interested in that I go to
cannabis.usu.edu and that'll have all
the information
registration details and things like
that coming soon
um and then if
uh if possible I can link some of our
our papers we've looked at phosphorus
nutrition uh blue light and then I
mentioned the the UV light paper that we
can link here if if anybody's interested
in that
um
but I'm happy to answer any emails any
questions that anybody has please feel
free to reach out
excellent yeah and we will definitely
link to those resources that's great you
guys have that uh that free course
that's that's fantastic yeah all right
Mitch well thanks again for joining us
and uh yeah hope to see you down in
Canada next may all right thanks Ben I
appreciate you having me on
[Music]
hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Mitchell Westmoreland
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed thanks again to this
episode's sponsor Advanced Nutrients our
next episode drops October 18th that's
two weeks from today
in the meantime please like comment and
subscribe on whichever platform you use
to listen to or watch us also please
check out cammedevents.com to sign up
for email alerts to learn all about our
annual Innovation and investment Summit
and purchase your ticket to cammed24
you can also view videos of all our past
cam Med presentations in the cam Med
archive at canmedevents.com I invite you
to join our can Med community group on
Facebook to interact with other cannabis
professionals and of course follow us on
social media we're on Instagram LinkedIn
X and Facebook just search for cam at
events
alright and that's it from us stay safe
stay healthy and be sure to join us on
the next can't make coffee talk
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]