great so good it's good afternoon
everyone so the title of my presentation
is does marijuana smoking increase the
risk of pneumonia when considering
treatment with any therapeutic agent one
must always benefit whatever it's always
benefit one must always balance benefit
against risk and regarding marijuana its
smoke contains most of the same
ingredients found in tobacco smoke many
of which are known to be toxic to lung
tissue and we know that marijuana that's
tobacco is the major risk factor by
virtue of exposure of the lung to these
toxic components within the smoke to
chronic obstructive pulmonary disease
and lung cancer both of which account
for considerable morbidity and mortality
worldwide so for some time there has
been concern that marijuana because it
shares the most of the ingredients the
toxic ingredients contained within
tobacco smoke might actually pose
similar respiratory risks however the
weight of evidence thus far does not
support a significant association
between marijuana smoking even heavy
marijuana smoking and these two
respiratory complications of of tobacco
on the other hand there is another
tobacco related respiratory risk namely
community acquired pneumonia 25% of the
cases of which can be attributed to
tobacco smoke there are 1.4 million
deaths due to pneumonia a worldwide and
unfortunately there is little
information concerning the possibility
that myrrh
smoking might also predispose to
pneumonia and so that was the objective
of a study that we conducted that I'm
going to results of which I'm going to
be presenting today so I'd like to begin
with a brief discussion of the biologic
plausibility of there being at risk of
marijuana for for pneumonia so we
performed bronchoscopy on a large number
of smokers of marijuana there were
regular generally heavy smokers of
marijuana alone were with tobacco
tobacco smokers alone and non-smokers
and we obtained biopsies at various
sites in the lower respiratory tract and
found that in contrast to the normal
bronchial mucosa and here we see the
nice ciliated columnar epithelial cells
that line the the larger airways these
were largely destroyed and replaced by
mucous secreting surface epithelial
cells so-called goblet cells as well as
other cells and this then results in an
increased production of mucus from these
cells with the limited capacity of the
lung to clear the mucus out of the lung
because of the Associated ciliary loss
so that this excess accumulated mucus
mucus could serve as a culture medium
for pathogenic bacteria and predisposed
to pneumonia and as a matter of fact
there are observational studies
carefully conducted observational
studies that do show an association
between increased butan production and
marijuana use now alveolar macrophages
are the primary immune effector cells
that reside in the lung and they serve a
very important function to protect the
lung against infection when they are
stimulated by bacteria or other
microbes then they release toxic
products including reactive oxygen
species nitric oxide etc that kill the
bacteria we wanted to look at the
function of alveolar macrophages
harvested from the lungs of marijuana
smokers and so we used the technique of
Bronco ireally lavage who the bronchus
go to rinse the the the cells out of the
lung so that we could examine their
function and we compared macrophages
obtained from marijuana smokers with
those obtained from tobacco only smokers
combine smokers of marijuana tobacco and
non-smokers and what we found these were
this is the old studies but they're
still valid that the macrophages from
the marijuana smokers relative to those
from tobacco smokers were impaired in
their ability to release the reactive
oxygen species when stimulated they were
also impaired in their ability to
produce pro-inflammatory cytokines the
TNF l46 gm-csf
that play a very important role in up
regulating inducible nitric oxide
synthase which is the enzyme that
converts arginine to nitric oxide and as
I mentioned before nitric oxide is one
of the effector molecules that are
important in killing bacteria so we
culture the macrophages that came from
the marijuana smokers with pathogenic
bacterium staph aureus feels that
similar stays with fungi and and then
looked at the waited awhile and looked
at the ability these macrophages to kill
the bacteria on the the upper curve here
represents the occur from the
macrophages obtained from marijuana
smokers this is bacteria remaining so
the shallower the curve the less the
killing so we haven't see an impaired
ability of macrophages from marijuana
smokers to kill bacteria
compared to macrophages
nonsmokers and also from tobacco smokers
and this is a little complex light so go
through a little slowly the white
circles represent nitric represent a
bacterial killing and the white bars
represent nitric oxide production ignore
the black circles and bars and we here
we see again that the bacterial killing
by the macrophages and the marijuana
smokers is impaired in parallel with an
impairment in nitric oxide production
when we added a cytokine gm-csf
exogenously we restored nitric oxide
production and at the same time restored
the bacterial killing capacity of these
macrophages so what is the clinical
evidence that marijuana use might be a
risk factor predisposing to pneumonia
there are older case series of fungal
pneumonia in marijuana smokers
immunocompromised by AIDS and other
conditions we know that hiv-positive
individuals are particularly high risk
for developing pneumonia including
opportunistic infection such as Loomis's
karidian pneumonia and there are a few
older epidemiological studies that
showed a significant association between
marijuana smoking these were studies
included hiv-positive individuals and
and pneumonia
although conflicting findings have been
reported so is our objective to
reexamine the question whether marijuana
smoking does or does not increase the
risk for pneumonia and we use data from
the Modi Center AIDS cohort study which
is an ongoing prospective observational
study of gay men regarding the natural
history of HIV infection so the study
was initiated in 1983 as I mentioned
it's still ongoing
we analyzed data from subjects who were
either
persistently HIV negative or HIV
positive we excluded those who converted
because we have possible conversion
confounding by serial conversion and the
subjects returned to the clinic every
six months and it was at these visits
that we then determine whether or not by
self-report whether or not the patients
had had experienced pneumonia in the
interval and divided the pneumonias into
community acquired pneumonia and
Pneumocystis Carini and pneumonia the
most common district pneumonia in in
hiv-positive individuals and in most
cases the pneumonia was confirmed by
chest x-ray we censored the data
whenever a pneumonia was first diagnosed
when AIDS was developed and and when the
subjects reached the end of the study
which was the end of the 2013 so at
these six monthly visits we also
obtained a lot of information about
marijuana use during the interval since
the the Wobble first of all about
pneumonia but also during the interval
prior the six-month interval prior to
the development of know as well as
baseline information on marijuana on
exposure to other risk factors including
tobacco potential risk factors alcohol
other recreational drugs and we also
looked at dose response relationships
obtain information on how often the
marijuana was used over the previous six
months and actually from the beginning
of the study as well and we performed
Cox proportional hazards to estimate the
risk for pneumonia either not a
community acquired pneumonia or PCP by
marijuana use and adjusted for the
covariates own in this slide
age race ethnicity socioeconomic status
the prophylaxis against Pneumocystis
pneumonia the sulfamethoxazole sorry our
method method sorry oh man and that's
that's um I think I have the beginnings
Alzheimer's but bactrim or septa so
noumic and of course numerous
vaccination against pneumococcal
pneumonia and adjusted also for tobacco
smoking of course use of other illicit
substances either by smoking or by
injection antiretroviral therapy and in
those who are seedy who were HIV
positive viral load cd4 count and
hepatitis C infection and these were the
results so in the motive area analysis
in the persistently HIV negative group
there was no association between
marijuana use and the development of of
pneumonia community acquired pneumonia
and the positive the control was tobacco
and they always do see a significant
effect of tobacco on pneumonia risk for
the hiv-positive group again marijuana
smoking was not associated with an
increased risk for pneumonia
whereas tobacco was and of course a low
cd4 count that was as well and in with
regard to the risk of Pneumocystis
Carini pneumonia in the hiv-positive
group again marijuana smoking was not
associated with any increased risk of
pneumonia cd4 counts were a
paradoxically tobacco in this analysis
was not we cannot explain this this the
finding there may be some residual
confounding that we couldn't adjust for
we're not sure when we looked at dose
response relationships we failed to find
any association between marijuana and
the risk of pneumonia whether or not the
irrespective of how frequently than
among the marijuana was used monthly
weekly or daily in either the HIV
negative or hiv-positive populations for
either community acquired pneumonia or
for PCP pneumonia
so in summary regular marijuana smoking
does increase the risk of chronic
bronchitis it does impair bacterial and
fungal killing by alveolar macrophages
obtained from marijuana smokers but is
does not appear to increase the risk of
pneumonia even in individuals immuno
suppressed due to HIV infection and I
these are like to acknowledge actually
Josh Quint received his PhD recently in
epidemiology from UCLA Roger needles is
an epidemiologist used to be the Dean of
the School Public Health at UCLA and we
are grateful to the max executive
committee for releasing the the data for
us to analyze although it was rather
painful processes took two years to get
a hold of the of the data and I am
finished all time
[Applause]
and be happy to answer any questions if
I could possibly see you with your hair
I'm on your left Donald yeah over here
on your left my left straight ahead okay
yeah Ethan Rousseau here
thank you for elegant presentation as
usual Donald I wondered whether you
examine any patients doing vaporization
in your cohort that's a good question
obviously if you vaporize the THC you're
not going to expose the lungs to a lot
of the particulate material there's
within within the smoke my guess is if
you studied individuals who vaporized
the THC you might find that there was no
no association with chronic bronchitis
which probably has to do with exposure
to the mostly the particulates and
possibly some of the the toxic volatile
material within the smoke as well no
what we did we did not study vapors
nonetheless very helpful thank you thank
you okay yes yes so I was interested in
the nitric oxide evidence that you have
for you know correlations with I guess
macrophage processes so do you see that
there's any correlation between the
cannabinoid it's signalling off of the
macrophages and suppressing nitric oxide
synthase activation so it's not
necessarily that nitric oxide is not
being able to be expressed it's that you
have cannabinoids interacting with your
macrophage production since there's some
correlation between those two yes I
think so
i cb2 receptors probably exists on
macrophages the alveolar macrophages
that haven't yet been identified on but
they most likely do and so the binding
to THC to those receptors then
essentially deactivates the macrophages
impairs their ability to produce
pro-inflammatory cytokines it's the
cytokines that are needed to up regulate
it inducible nitric oxide synthase that
then leads to the conversion of arginine
within the cell into nitric oxide which
is then released thank you one minute
okay I don't see any other hands but
thank you very much