thank you for inviting me here to speak
my name is David Mary I'm not a
physician I'm a scientist I have a
laboratory in the Technion which is
similar to the MIT it's a Technology
Institute of Israel I wish it was
similar to the MIT it's a little bit
smaller and my background is biology and
my Master's is in biochemistry I did a
PhD in plant biology and by kind of a
mistake I did my postdoc in Toronto in
cancer biology when I came back to
Israel and got my own lab I got a
laboratory for cancer research my
presentation sorry yeah let's not get
somewhere
okay I will keep without my presentation
so when I got my rabbit her and I
started one of the papers that I I saw
that quote one of my work in mypos dog
show that treating breast cancer with
cannabis can block the ability of these
cells to migrate to create metastasis
and this is what something that I did in
my postdoc and look very interesting to
me and I want to keep going with it so
this is the papers and I will go on and
when I started to read about cannabis
and cancer I saw that there are few
papers that showing the treating cancer
with cannabis can create apoptosis to
these cells and apoptosis is like when
cells committing suicide every cell in
our body have a machinery that we check
itself all the time there is checkpoint
and something is wrong he is committing
suicide and cancer cancer and it's a
given name to hundreds of different
diseases but we put them in all the same
box and we said every time that we see
all this phenomena we will call it
cancer and the first phenomena is that
the cell can avoid apoptosis that it
avoid this committing suicide and then
they are standing there and become more
involvement so as a scientist as a
researcher for cancer you want to have
the ability to bring back these
phenomena this killing that they will
kill themselves and that would why so so
the first question when we approach this
question with this work we asked which
type of cancer so we saw that in breast
cancer there is publication we thought
that in glioblastoma death publication
but what about other cancer there are
hundreds of different types of cancer
and second what the hell is cannabis so
so cannabis it's a plant and as I said I
in plant biologist I know that if you
grow a plant if you pick a plant in
different time of the day have Sun of
Agriculture if you pick strawberries in
the morning or afternoon they have a
different taste okay they're sweeter in
the afternoon I will tell you a secret
okay
but because they're doing photosynthesis
and whatever but it's the same thing for
cannabis what is cannabis so we know
that there is at Eva indica I would
realize we know types of cannabis it's
the different soils that you grow them
that will be different in Israel we have
91 different strains that the care is
that the patient can face and every
strain it's like a different medicine so
which kind of cannabis what I what we
should do so how we approach it
we're taking cell so I went to one of my
students I told her okay let's try to
see where are we standing let's try to
repeat the experiment that these guys
did and see where are we where what is
the point we want to start so we took
six different types of cannabis
different types of plants and we make
six different types of extract and we
choose eight different types of cancer
that where they we have in our lab okay
so we are growing in the cell and the
cells growing on the plate like that
it's it's they're going like confluent
on the cells the cells look like that if
you're taking a picture if you look in
the microscope cells look like that this
is one cell and we're growing the cells
and now we are treating with cannabis so
if we look on on colon cancer you see
the structure now it's a lower
magnification you just see like a
structure of the cells growing on the
plate nicely weird extract number one
all the cell died we add next extract
number two all the cell died we add
extract number three nothing happened to
the cells so first I see distinguish I
see I see differences between different
types of cannabis which was quite
exciting and another thing we Pia we put
really low amount of extract so we put
one microgram per ml so if you taking
rose marine and you extract the oil from
rosemary and you put on cancer cells
then we die but if you're doing
extrapolation how much you need to eat
you need to eat 20 kilogram per day okay
not interesting okay but if you look if
you're doing extrapolation of what you
need
to take versus cannabis you reaching one
gram which never just show you this it's
one joint so it's fine when we are in
the good scale and if you compare it to
those that when we put chemotherapy like
tax or vincristine vinblastine it's the
same thing because the active compound
here are nano gram so this was very
exciting this is a very important
material so we look on the breast cancer
and we see the exam results extras
number one and to kill the cells and the
extra Nami d3 did nothing we look on
trusted cancer and now we see different
that extract number one did nothing to
the cell extract number two did nothing
to the cells extract number four sorry
extract number three kill all the cells
so we see specificity between types of
cannabis to a type of Ken of of cancer
which was very surprising and amazing
when we use it on normal cells there is
no normal cells that going growing on a
plate but these cells are without cancer
mutation then it's much less effective
okay which was another surprising result
so I was very excited and said okay
extract from strain number one
scooby-doo and from Mickey Mouse what
what the hell what I am holding in my
end okay what are the materials it's the
real names what are the materials that
really killed the sense that binding the
receptor affecting the cells okay and I
looked around I realized that there is a
laboratory in Israel that can read this
I send them the materials and they came
back with five cannabinoids these are
the cannabinoid these are the percentage
when I looked on the extract extract
number two and extract number three was
exactly the same the same can I been
doing the same time cannabinoids that I
get a read I got the same percentage so
this is not good okay I am lucky I am in
Haifa in the north of Israel but I have
my shulam in the center of Israel which
is 45 minutes right in Israel so I got
iPhone III called Rafi I told him hi
this is David from from the Technion
and he call he said come over I came
Ruffy start to explain everything and
unfortunately I realized that we are
knowing more than 100 cannabinoids today
we recognize over than 144 different
cannabinoids so in my extract I don't
have CBD indeed see that what I'm
looking on there is a lot of others and
if to be very disappointed if Raffi want
to kill me also told me a little bit of
temper Turpin's ok over two hundred two
points so actually Lumiere honish
published a review a four months ago
which showed that there is over 500
different compound in the extract so as
a scientist where can I start so first I
realized that we see just the tip of the
iceberg we look on TD CBD it's not the
story at least not with myself ok second
in a half the year I went to Colorado I
looked in Israel I went to scientists
and in half a year
I hid my hand in the wall because unless
I know what I'm holding or giving to the
cell I can't repeat the experiment I
can't identify what is the effect I
can't stop to work so for half a year I
struggle with this question I really
want to do cannabis research ok but I
couldn't so coming back after this half
a year to my laboratory I decided if
we're not doing everything nobody will
help us ok and I will skip on on these
slides because the time is short but
usually people using HPLC unit standard
to see we have today twelve or thirteen
standards for cannabinoid from the 144
this is not helping us in the if I will
skip a year and a half forward and we
develop a whole method with LC LC msg
CMS and other equipment this is the
method I won't go into it I'm just going
to the point today my laboratory have
the ability to see all the cannabinoids
and all the tear pins so
in the end I will show this the
miserable Students Club forehand okay
not me so what I'm showing here is a
heat map okay and what we see in the
line it's different names of
cannabinoids you can recognize it it's
in CBD there but other cannabinoids
going down it's just a print screen of
of this heat map okay and on the row you
can see different extract different
strains that been given in Israel to
patient and this is a heat map when you
see a dark square the meaning that this
can be highly expressed there is numbers
behind everything but it's more visual
like that okay and when why it's low
Express and what I want to show you on
this image that every strain that the
patient get in Israel it's a different
medicine look how different they are
from each other there is no two strains
that look similar so if we have ninety
one strength in Israel I actually have
91 different medicine for the patient
and this without starting to say that in
the winter they are growing differently
in the summer batches and I will show a
little bit of of the results okay so
just to showing you on the blue side
okay you see the mark in blue this is
too high CBD strains low TC 20 to 1 and
these are the two strains that were
extract to an extract 3 and see how
different they are so it's true that the
CBD is very similar but all other
compounds are different this is the
reason those 1 cell 1
X are killing the cell and the other is
not killing the cell ok so having we did
the same thing with 2 pens and also it's
all around a lot of result so having
this ability to see all the compounds
actually did something to my lab that I
didn't expect it's open the world to my
lab because now every girl every startup
every physician they're doing clinical
trial coming to my lab and said hey I
want to know what I'm
to the patient if it's extract if I'm I
have a perfect test train I saw a guy
outside that's saying that his train is
better than others okay he's coming to
my lab said okay I want to prove it read
all the canape Linda they have I want to
see if there is different cannabinoids
so my lab in the last year you grew in
in unexpected way and we're doing today
a lot of things not just cancer so I've
actually four groups in my lab one group
is doing all the chemist analysis so
we're asking what are the difference
between ethanol extraction Boonton
extraction co2 extraction there is a
huge difference if you taking one strain
and doing Boonton extraction versus co2
extraction or ethanol exactly you get a
different medicine it's a different
compounds that you get in the end fine
heating and CBD are there but you're
losing cannabinoids you're gaining other
terpenes you changing the portfolio
totally okay so what are the
bioavailability when you smoke when
you're taking a pill what is reaching to
the blood okay all this question we have
the ability to answer while we knowing
to see this compound okay so this is a
group that doing chemist analysis have a
group they're doing in neurobiology
mainly epilepsy brain development and
sleep and I won't touch it at all in
this talk I have a group that doing
database that were collecting that on
the patient versus they cannabinoid that
they are taking and I speak about it for
two minutes if I will have the time but
I want to show you few results from the
cancer group that still it's the main
group in my lab and in the cancer as I
told you we can grow the cells in the
plate but we can also grow them in a
plate that have many wells the long one
called 96-well every scientist of the
physician know this plate okay so you
can take glioblastoma or pancreatic
cancer and the same one grow in this
plate so you actually can do in one
plate 96 different experiments you can
do 96 dosages 96 different the strain
whatever you want and I have in my lab
this machine which is known as a
high-throughput screening so this is
incubator connected to co2 and to oxygen
and
I think the cells need to grow live and
there is a camera there is a microscope
on top of it that know how to move
between the wells and take images it can
take over them 1,000 images an hour if
they have fluorescence so you can put
markers so in the end you get these
images today to the computer and you can
analyze it images so make the story
short you get in the end like a table
with Jerry tell you in which well it was
most effective okay in well c4 you can
100% of the cells through apoptosis
while insane well a d7 nothing happened
so in that way we can screen a lot of
different dosages or a lot of different
extract find the one that is most potent
and start to work with it for a specific
type of cancer okay so when I'm finding
something specific with one strain that
killed specific is a cancer with a
specific mutation and put a PhD student
and the miserable guy need to work on
this for years okay but that the way I
did it before and you know I'm kidding
but but when we find something like that
we put a student and and this is like
his goal so I want to show you few
results that showing how much complex
this area and how much it's not if we
can't say that cannabis is good for
cancer or something like that so what
you say on top is them it's the images
that you we get from this machine you
see that in the left corner you see the
control and then we put a mic a it's a
name of face of strain it's killing all
the cells and RN doing nothing but I
want to focus on the on the graph here
with the color so every color it's a
different strain extract from a
different strength and what we see on
this graph is the percentage of the
cells a dime okay will end on the extra
you see a dosages to my program for my
program six microgram eight microgram
okay so you can see if we focus on four
microgram per ml that there are strains
doing nothing
a 375 it's melanoma cancer okay you see
that in for my program there are
strangely doing nothing to this self by
while there are strains at killing fifty
percent of the cells and there are
strains at killing most of the cells so
what I want to show you it you can see
cannabis is killing the cells you need
to need to know which cannabis will kill
these cells okay and if you look here
you will see that a day the gray one is
melanoma the black one is lung cancer
and you can see that there are strains
that are very good to kill the melanoma
but doing nothing to the lung cancer as
I show you before and if I will take it
to the next step if we look on these
cells and we choose one strain Mike a
okay which kill 70% of the cells with
for my programs and now we're taking
this strain and we've purified the teeth
then the CBD from this strain we have
now 100% 98% pure T 80 from this train
it's the same THC right it's not
synthetic whatever I'm not going to
these politics questions okay and with
you purified in and give now to the
cells you see that even in eight
microgram of purity T which is twenty
times more than we give the extract look
on the green one which is the a 375 it's
doing nothing to the cells okay
so it's not that easy we did it also
with the CBD it's not the CBD it's
something more I will show another
example so this is if you taking this
pure and add it to the extract again is
doing nothing it's not the tea it's in
the CBD in these types of cell of cells
okay if we I will give another example
on prostate cancer so we see in the left
side fix extract and you see that now
it's the opposite it's the variability
how much the cell survive so when you
see a lower bar it's better it's giving
more cells so it's is that extract
number one is very useful by killing the
cell while while other extract is not
useful so I will tell you I I know
exactly what the difference to treat
cells in Mysore in the plate versus a
person there is a huge gap so don't
learn from this that this is what you
need to treat people that you know okay
but I want to do an extrapolation let's
do a mind thinking okay if you own a
patient now and you're going to pick
strains that will help you for prostate
cancer what is the possibility that you
pick the right one it's very low now I
want to be a the bad guy a little bit
more okay so I will tell you that
extract number one and extract number
six are the exact same extract we
extract from one strain from from the
girl we separated it to one we activated
it okay there was a question here we
activate the we heat it to be activated
to decarboxylate okay and the other not
straight number one extract number one
is without the heating and strength
number six is after heating okay so now
here if you're patient and you're very
lucky and you pick the right strain but
you're smoking it it won't help you
according to these results okay so now
you said okay David say tell us that not
that they make dhikr books the day the
acid form is better to put to cancer so
look on the other side in glioblastoma
it's not the story after heating it it's
much better so what I'm trying to say it
still so complex and still we know so
little that we need to be very careful
to say what is good and not good what is
working and not working okay I want to
skip everything because I'm red okay and
I want to show two things very very
shortly how can I go back okay I want to
show two things very shortly one it's
something that we got last month there
is a clinical trials that need to run
they asked they need to prepare a lot of
materials they grew the same strain the
same
genetic planting in the same day but
because they need a lot of material
they're planting in five different
greenhouse okay four different
greenhouse we got this sample look how
different the it's the same genetic of
the plant just growing in different
greenhouse okay so this is a problem
that we're facing every time we're
getting different materials okay that's
first of all second I want to show to
say very very shortly that the for group
in my lab doing cannabis database and
the database that we are doing having
the knowledge that we are the
laboratories that know exactly what the
patient getting from bottom to top we
can follow up on this patient so we did
we are doing this database well first
aim we create a cannabis strain database
every cannabis every plane to extract
that patient can get in Israel
everything that the patient can get is
coming from first to our laboratory and
we're doing all the amplification so if
you ant is getting a Mickey Mouse in
December I know what she got okay
the same are the second arm we're doing
follow-up on all the patient in Israel
we're getting all the data from them we
build a questionnaire and I won't go
into it because of the time but the idea
is to say okay this 75 strains increase
appetite in eighty percent of the
patient what are the materials in in
this in these 75 strains that are common
that increase appetite that are not
existing the standard don't increase
appetite and this to take to clinical
trials and to model and mice model to
make it evidence-based just and I'm
finished here show you one example with
the strength of it we are tweeting in
Israel 70 kids with autism severe autism
and the result of phenomenon and one
gate which would you say anxiety reduce
the violence there are more concentrated
more variable okay everything is perfect
Mickey a door mention it everything was
perfect a month ago a month and a half
ago
one day seven kids flipped out crazy one
the kid 17 years old bTW the [ __ ] of his
mother other like crazy day we got phone
calls from the physician what's going
wrong we don't know I'm Lou I'm going to
the head of my database project tally
and I tell they're Italian these are the
numbers of the kids check and she's
coming back said that is all these kids
are from the same world so in Israel we
have eight authorized girls we watching
all of them all these kids got the
extract from the same girl
I'm calling the girl and said hey what's
it been changed today we have got every
or every kid that get materials from you
from autism is getting crazy
nothing daddy everything is the same
we're using the same extract is 22 one
CBD to teach him I'm calling the
physician said send send me sample we're
checking this sample and we see that
actually the worst changes strain okay
so he didn't lie about the day CBD in
tici tici state 20 to 1 okay but other
materials in the strain are totally
different you can see CB TV here a CBG
a.m. several dogs see CBD all there
change and this is what I'm looking
because now I have 8 cannabinoids that I
suspect that are important to reduce
enjoy anxiety thank you very much
just to say thank you to my student that
doing the work while I'm giving
[Applause]
you