[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben emerald i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
speaking of the canmed conference have
you gotten your tickets yet for
canmed2022
if yes then i can't wait to see you out
in pasadena this may for another
fantastic event
and if not what are you waiting for head
over to canmedevents.com now to get your
tickets
at cam ed 2022 you will learn from the
leading minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
and if you want proof of that look no
further than our keynote presenters
representing our science focus area we
have dr ethan rousseau presenting about
cannabis and psychiatry
representing our cultivation focus area
we have dr seth crawford talking about
innovations in hemp breeding
grace bandong our safety keynote
presenter will talk about building a
comprehensive analytical testing program
and finally dr bonnie goldstein will
discuss cannabis medicine for children
as our medical keynote
those presentations alone are worth the
price of admission but please go to kim
at events dot com to see the full
schedule
and if you want a preview of what you
can expect at kmed 2022 check out our
camed archive which is a searchable
video library of all the past canmed
presentations and panels find that at
cammannevents.com
at this year's event we are also
offering a full day pre-conference
medical practicum taking place on may
3rd
the medical practicum is led by dr
bonnie goldstein dr dustin sulak dr
kevin spellman and eloise
thiessen each of them will share the
latest medical cannabis research
including information on dosing drug
interactions and different product types
they will also share their clinical
experience they have acquired treating
patients with medical cannabis this
really is a must attend event for any
health care professionals who are
interested in recommending medical
cannabis but it's not limited to those
folks
anyone who is interested in learning
more about medical cannabis can and
should join us for this event head over
to kim at events dot com slash practicum
to learn more
of course if you can't make it to canmed
2022 we have a number of resources to
help you stay engaged with our community
and enjoy some world-class educational
content
you are already off to a good start
listening to the canmed coffee talk
podcast be sure to hit that subscribe
button so new episodes download to your
device automatically
second we have the canmed archive that i
mentioned earlier it's a searchable
video library of all the past kmed
presentations and panels that you can
find at kmedevents.com
while you're at canmedevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts that's the
best way to make sure you are up to date
on all the latest canmed news and
special offers
fourth we have our canmed community
facebook group which is a great place to
share and discuss news and topics
related to cannabis science the link to
that group is in the show description
and finally you can follow us on social
media we're on instagram facebook
twitter and linkedin just search for cam
at events
this episode we are talking all about
heavy metal testing with robert thomas
robert is the principal of scientific
solutions a consulting company that
serves the training application
marketing and writing needs of the trace
element user community
he has worked in the field of atomic and
mass spectrometry for more than 45 years
including 25 years for a manufacturer of
atomic spectroscopic instrumentation
in recent years rob has become a
prolific writer on the topic with more
than 100 technical publications to his
name
in fact he literally wrote the book on
icpms the technology labs used to detect
trace elements and in his latest book
titled measuring heavy metal
contaminants in cannabis and hemp he
applies his knowledge to the nascent
cannabis and hemp testing space
in our conversation we discuss what
brought rob to the cannabis and hemp
industry
how heavy metal testing in the cannabis
and hemp industry differs from the
pharmaceutical industry
why cannabis and hemp are particularly
susceptible to heavy metal contamination
the multiple sources of contamination
throughout the cultivation and
processing process
steps growers and producers can take to
limit heavy metal contamination and the
current and future regulatory
requirements for heavy metal testing
before we get to my conversation with
rob i'd like to thank this episode's
sponsor pigment tracker
the pigment tracker is a fluorescence
spectrophotometer designed to allow
cannabis processors and operators a way
to quickly accurately and cheaply record
the pigments in an extract or flower
sample
record keeping allows for more
repeatable processing which lowers the
likelihood that batches will be rejected
by clients or final consumers
for more information check out pigment
tracker's instagram account we've
provided a link in the show description
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with robert thomas
[Music]
good afternoon rob thanks for joining us
on the podcast
you're welcome i'm glad i could make it
okay so you have decades of experience
with heavy metal testing that you are
now applying or you're lending your
expertise to the cannabis industry so
maybe a great place to start would be
tell us a bit about your background and
what attracted you or got you started in
the cannabis industry
sure yeah
i think to put it all into context i
think it's good to understand that i'm
not from this industry but i found the
industry about three years ago
i've been work 25 years for the
perkinelma corporation as an analytical
chemist in the field of atomic and mass
spectroscopy
i took one of the retirement packages a
few years ago and i ventured into the
field of science writing i always like
to write i think i was reasonably good
at doing it
so i started looking around for
opportunities fortunately i had made a
lot of good editorial contacts
and i started getting requests to write
about trace element analysis um probably
the
one thing that put me on the map with
regard to trace element analysis
publications was i did a 15 part series
on icp ms
for the journal spectroscopy in the mid
2000s
that gave me a lot of visibility and a
lot of exposure it eventually led to a
textbook
on icpms
in the mid 2000s and all of a sudden
i was getting visibility um
in a global sense because my book was
sold all over the world it was english
of course but i was fortunate enough to
get it translated into mandarin and into
spanish so that gave me additional
visibility
at that time i was asked to serve on the
american chemical society
committee for reagent chemicals i was
asked to lead the heavy metals task
force so i came on
on board right about that time
and
i was fortunate enough to be involved
with helping united states pharmacopoeia
update their heavy metal testing
procedure
which eventually came out in chapters
232 and 233 the acs was an interested
stakeholder
with the usp
and
we had both used a heavy metal test for
almost 100 years which was a
colorimetric sulfide precipitation test
which was very crude and did not work
correctly and
it was impacted by the experience of the
analysis it was totally inappropriate
and it was only for a small group of
metals lead in particular
so
usp
um were
were involved with changing that method
because the pharmaceutical industry
for so many years did not have an
accurate test
to actually quantify elemental
impurities in pharmaceutical products so
with the fda behind them
usp were tasked with coming out with
brand new plasma spectrochemistry test
methods to come out with a
an accurate and precise test for
replacing that sulfide precipitation
test and at the acs
we were also doing that because our book
of companion standards is a book that's
recommended by usp
in their usp nfl book and we found that
if we were going to change our method
and usp were changing their method
it would be good to align them so in
fact i was on
many meetings with the usp which
discussed how would we change the method
what was important and how we would go
about the process of changing it
usp
worked very slowly acs does to a certain
extent but we managed to change our
methodology
from the sulfide precipitation test to
icp oes and icpms in a few years
yet usp took
in excess of 15 years to do that it was
frustrating but we understood that at
that time because they were trying to
align the method
with europe and the rest of the world
and particularly to align it with ich q
3d directives so they took a long time
but in january 2018 they come out with a
standardized method for both icp oes and
icpms together
with elemental impurities for 24
heavy metals based on the method of
delivery
so they came out in 2018
i had worked with them over over a
number of years up to that point being
the heavy metals
leader of the task force at the acs so i
saw an opportunity
to really leverage that information
which i've learned
and i was still going ahead with my
writing and i just felt that based on
that i presented to my publisher
an opportunity for another book which
was elemental impurities and
pharmaceuticals
if you know
if you know textbook publishers it takes
a whole lot of proposals and
justifications to get something approved
so it took a while but eventually they
agreed
for me to go ahead and do that so i gave
them an outline
took me um i used a lot of the material
that i put together for my rcpms book
so it didn't take as long
to actually put together a book on
elemental impurities in pharmaceuticals
it took me another 12 months
but
it helped having done a book
so
in march of 2018 to coincide with the
approval of usp chapters 232 and 233 i
came out with my book
which was great for me because it put me
on the map in the pharmaceutical
industry so that again gave me a lot of
opportunities and a lot of more
writing possibilities
however at that time i got to know the
usp folks very well they suggested that
i should take a look at the
cannabis industry because they felt that
they were in need of help and they did
not have a good understanding
of heavy metal contaminants in the
entire manufacturing process from
cultivation
to processing to extraction to
production to packaging to delivery so
i'm a little hesitant i just finished a
book and as a writer of books
it consumes you for the time you're
writing it you really don't have time to
do anything else so i just finished my
pharma book so i was hesitant to
really get involved but i did i started
talking to some contact names they gave
me
and i started realizing wow um this is
an industry that's exciting
it's fractured it's chaotic but what an
opportunity what an opportunity to make
a difference so i said i said i've got
to do this so i went to my publisher
again i said
i would like you to consider another
book i at that time i had no outline for
a book but i just felt
that the industry was primed for putting
together an educational resource to help
the industry
understand this topic of heavy metal
contaminants
so again i had to write another proposal
justification they agreed to it
that was about two years ago it took me
another year to put it together again i
use components from my farmer book and
components from my icpms book
and i just laid in
a cannabis piece of the of the book and
i found that very interesting because i
got a lot of input from the folks i just
met in the cannabis industry of folks
that i'd connected with because that
first year i was just learning how the
industry worked
and that's and that's all i did was to
talk their jargon to fully understand
how it was working and how the dynamics
between cultivators and processes and
regulators
and all the things that all the things
that go with you know with the industry
so anyway um
i did i sat down and um i wrote a
proposal wrote an outline and eventually
came out with a book heavy metal
contaminants in cannabis and hemp in
december 2020 so that was over a year
ago
but that kind of got me the visibility
and installed all of a sudden i was
getting so many requests for writing
publishing and speaking engagements and
that started my journey which
i'm still on the train i still can't get
off it's very difficult to
the demand for my time is pretty crazy
but
you know i relish that i welcome it and
when i got a request to speak at tanmed
i said i've got to do that
unfortunately uh i had to find funding
for it it took me two days to get
funding for my travel so but i did so um
i'm all signed up to talk at canmed so
and with with that you got involved and
uh dad put me in contact with you and
this is where we are and here we are
and we're happy to have you uh as you
know you know analytical testing or
safety testing it's one of our key focus
areas for
for canmed so to have someone like you
to to
give us information or or share your
knowledge around heavy metal testing
it's um it's invaluable for sure
and
so i wanted to ask you so once you've
shifted from you know pharmaceuticals to
cannabis um in terms of heavy metal
testing what were some of the
differences that you found whether it's
you know in what heavy metals they're
actually looking for or techniques that
they're using or just sophistication of
equipment
what were some of the things that you
you noticed
well um i think the first thing i
noticed was that
the pharmaceutical industry
took 15 plus years to come out with
comprehensive elemental impurities so
they had to go the whole process of
carrying out
a comprehensive risk assessment study of
the industry
based on the toxicity of the metals that
are likely to be found somewhere in the
manufacturing process and doing a
complete understanding of where those
elemental impurities might occur and at
what levels
and documenting them in something that
the pharmaceutical industry could read
and understand and that is fully
documented in ich q3d directives and um
it it goes through exactly how the how
the pharmaceutical industry approached
this when i came into the cannabis
industry i started asking people have
you done a risk risk assessment of heavy
metals in your products and there was
this blank stare or black
it was like what is a risk assessment
study so i you know i had to come to
grips with that but clearly the cannabis
industry
were not flying by the seat of their
pants but they did not have a good
understanding from cultivation
to extraction to i mean everything
everything
involved there are so many contact
points and i began to uncover those as i
started as i started getting information
as i started doing research of my own
but sometimes
i was getting evasive answers from many
people the thing about the cannabis
energy some folks are not eager to share
with someone who is just coming in
trying to understand what's going on
that's unfortunate um
but you know i got some responses but i
did a lot of research on my own
and i found out there was no
understanding of risk assessment with
regard to heavy metals
and it was something that i felt
strongly about
and
one of the things i realized was when i
was kind of on my own i was a someone
coming into the industry with a lot of
experience and knowledge and trace sound
analysis
but no no no one really knew me in the
cannabis industry so i thought how can i
get credibility
so what so actually so what i did was i
started working with organizations where
i'd work with not so much in the past
but organizations i knew would have an
impact on the cannabis industry like
aoac astm
nist
so i started and i'd had good contacts
at these organizations so i went to them
and volunteered my time obviously and
astm were eager to bring me in because
they didn't really have
any heavy metal expertise
within the committees or subcommittees
people who are knowledgeable but no one
if you like with as much expertise as i
had so that was nice that they that they
welcomed me in one of the first things
that i recommended was i wanted to get
together a workshop or a symposia which
highlighted this which brought this out
into the public domain because to me it
wasn't in the public domain it was in
cannabis cultivators processors
regulators there was a little component
of this
um
you know lots of people had but it
wasn't out there in the public domain so
i asked them if they would support me in
a heavy metal workshop this was this is
a year ago now and we talked about it
again i had to write a proposal but i
was used to writing proposals and
justifications so we eventually put
together a workshop last summer
three-day workshop um i was the chair
but supported by astm
and we got abstract we got something
like
22 abstracts and then 22 papers in
just specifically on heavy metals and
whole aspects of heavy metals from
instrument vendors uh from from
cultivators from i mean from the whole
industry from from academia and that
really brought it to the surface so
if you like i think that's where the
industry started
started saying okay so we need to do
something but things started moving very
slowly but that was the major difference
between working in pharma and working in
cannabis with farmer you had a highly
regulated industry
and in cannabis you have a highly
unregulated industry if you can call the
state's regulators they are but there's
only so much they can do and they don't
have the knowledge and expertise uh to
really regulate the industry in a
meaningful way yeah
no and i think that's a that's a symptom
of the industry in general right is that
you know a lot of us
regulators cultivators everyone was sort
of asked to run
directly after legalization and you know
yeah and you know
industries like the pharmaceutical
industry have had decades of experience
and
you know well-regulated
processes and everything that they've
built upon uh where we are just sort of
making not making up as we go we're
doing the best that we can but um
there's certainly more work to be done
there so i want to take this i want to
take a step back a bit and just talk
about heavy metals in general like what
elements are we talking about here um
what is their potential damage or uh
effects that they could have on humans
consuming them and why in particular
um
are cannabis and hemp sort of
susceptible to contamination
okay
um
well
we know the cannabis and hemp are really
excellent
phytoaccumulators they will they will
accumulate any male or any okay not so
much heavy metals but any elements
that are in the soil or in the growing
medium um
they will attract it and absorb it and
it does not affect their health and it
does not affect their rate of growth so
for decades they've been used as phyto
remediators to clean up toxic waste
sites you know chernobyl being one
example of cleaning up heavy metals
you know radionuclides and they've done
a really good job of doing that but
there are other other plans for doing
that um
the whole science of fighter remediation
is is uh is it is a fascinating topic
and there are many plants that can do
that but fortunately or unfortunately
cannabis and hemp are one of the best
fighter remediators so they are used for
that purpose
on the downside a plant is used for
cannabinoids and other
you know the the production of other
things that we consume
it really means that you have to be
careful where you plant cannabis in them
now in the early days the majority of
the plants were grown indoors whether
hydroponically or in greenhouses indoors
where the growing conditions are far
more
far more stable
it's a it's an environment which can be
controlled so you don't have the impact
of weather you don't have the impact of
soil or you don't have the impact of any
contaminants that might be in an
external growing medium so that's the
first point to emphasize so if it's in
the growing medium it will be absorbed
into the plant it will get absorbed
through the roots and stay in the leaves
the shoots the stalks um the leaves and
eventually end up in the flowers and
there's a number of studies out there
which show the ratio of how it's
deposited in these different components
of the plant and that in itself is a
is a fascinating um you know a
fascinating way to look at it um
but the thing is that um
some of the most toxic heavy metals
which we have which we have as humans
caused anthropogenically we have
contaminated much of the soil and much
of the contamination
that we have given to our soil is based
on using metals like lead
mercury cadmium arsenic which uh
if you like the repercussions of an
industrial world where we're continually
putting
heavy metal contaminants out
into the environment whether it's from
lead pipes from water supplies whether
there's leaded gasoline whether it's
from
lead in paint so lead in particular but
mercury mercury is another element that
we've done very well
or contaminated the environment
you know power plants spew out 100 tons
of mercury every year and it goes on
plants into the soil and into the
aquatic systems and unfortunately once
it gets in the aquatic systems um it
gets converted to methylmercury
by the bottom feeders and then it goes
up the food chain and that's why you've
got to be careful when you eat
fish like uh
like tuna or
swordfish which are predator fish which
will consume all the smaller fish and it
goes up the food chain so as a result of
that the big four lead cabbie mastic and
mercury are by far the most toxic and by
far the most of environmental concern
but it's not only those that are other
what are called
heavy metals although heavy metals is
not a
group in the periodic table so when
people say heavy metals i ask them what
they mean because it could mean
different elements to different people
but obviously classically the big four
lead cabinet mastering of mercury but
elements like chromium manganese
copper nickel iron zinc i mean there are
so many which can be quote unquote heavy
metals so we have to be aware of that if
they're in the soil they will end up in
the plant and ultimately when they will
end up in the flower and if they end up
in the flower or anywhere in the biomass
and that biomass you extract the
cannabinoid whatever the cannabinoid is
um it will it will end up to some degree
and then as you process that through the
system depending on what process is used
you get concentration you get
purification and you get additional
elements brought
into
into the equation because
it will absorb whatever it's in contact
with
you know metal-wise stainless steel
brass um
anything and i'm sure we'll get into
this but there's the whole thing about
vaping devices which has nothing to do
with the production of categories but
it's the way they're delivered and
unfortunately we have what are called
vaping devices which uh
unfortunately they are little devices
which uh
which contain lots of metal components
and when you vape with elevated
temperatures never mind if there's
nothing
in the cbd extract or whatever the
liquid is
you have the high potential of actually
corroding the internal metal components
and producing nanoparticles of that
metal
which the consumer or the vapor will
take into their lens that's a totally
different subject but
you know it has to be brought into the
equation but the thing is that uh it's
very difficult to eliminate
any kind of metal from a plant that you
grow outdoors so you have to deal with
that how do you deal with it how can you
mitigate it can you mitigate it if you
can't mitigate it how do you reduce the
impact
so yeah
excellent and now if i understand
correctly
is this less of a concern with other
crops because they're not as efficient
as
cannabis and hemp are in terms of
accumulating these metals
um
yeah i think uh
it's a fact of life that hemp and
cannabis are really good fighter
mediators they're really good at hyper
accumulating what's in the soil but no
it's not it's not um
there's other plants which
which will will absorb heavy metals and
some of those plants we consume there's
been a number of reports out and i've
i've reported on them and i can
certainly send you the information but
um
arsenic in rice arsenic is a big problem
with rice because it's predominantly
grown in flooded fields and
unfortunately arsenic is a big component
in soil there's lots of bastard console
so if it's if
rice is being grown in flooded fields
the arsenal gets into the water and the
water and it gets extracted it gets
absorbed by the rice and there's a study
put out recently on arsenic in infant
cereal right and of course infant cereal
contains a lot of rice and um actually
congress got hold of this report and
they um
they went to the fda and say hey what's
going on this is not acceptable because
the fda does not do a good job of
regulating
food in general for heavy metals yet
alone infant cereals so yeah
there was a port recently of high levels
of cadmium and chocolate
um
it gets into cocoa beans um
yeah it's it's yeah it isn't only
cannabis and hemp
it's a problem as humans we have
contaminated the environment
and we have contaminated on a global
scale i read a report recently that
up to one-third of arable land in the
world is contaminated some to some
degree with heavy metals or some kind of
metal contaminant that's pretty scary
when you consider if that translates to
the us
so one field in three is contaminated
so the this is what we have to deal with
and um the industry is not doing a good
job of understanding
and dealing with that and this is this
is this is the whole this is the area
that i'm trying to bring
trying to bring exposure visibility to
the industry but it's serious and you're
okay at the moment because the industry
is moving so fast so rapid and it's
growing so quickly
um
with very little serious regulations at
some point in time the federal
government we're going to have oversight
and based on what's going on in the
pharmaceutical industry um
i think there could be some serious
decisions to be made
right
you know you briefly touched on
maybe some ways to kind of prevent
getting heavy metals into your cannabis
whether it's making sure that the soil
is free of heavy metals or that if
you're using you know hydroponics making
sure that you have good water source but
i'm curious
if you know that you have cannabis
material that is contaminated with heavy
metals is there any opportunity for
remediation or removing them or it can
is it something that you can extract out
what can you do yeah it can be extracted
out but it's extremely expensive i i
talked to someone fairly recently about
that someone who would
who would just um
who had just grown a large batch of hemp
i actually i can't remember where it was
i think it was in colorado but i can't
remember and they
they contacted me and asked me what what
what are the opportunities to mitigate
or reduce the heavy metal
level in this plant and there are there
are ways of doing it um
you know extraction for example but they
are
extremely expensive so i said
you know there's a chance i don't know
um
but there's a chance that you might have
to destroy that crop which they didn't
want to hear
um
but it's i i hear of this all the time
and even though i can tell you
that the industry is concerned about it
there are ways that they could reduce
heavy metals by using
higher purity nutrients
clean fertilizers water that's water
that's been tested trust me
if you if you were growing hemp in say
an area
where they know where you know they use
leaded pipes and using that supply of
water guaranteed there would be lead in
the water supply and guaranteed it would
end up in the plant so it's stuff like
this you you've got to be you've got to
pay attention to what you're doing and
you've got to pay attention to how you
can mitigate or reduce the level of
heavy metals in the planet eventually
the flower so there are ways of doing it
but uh um
i've um i actually give a talk at a
analytical cannabis workshop the past
couple of days wednesday and thursday
and someone else who gave a talk before
me was from penn state and he gave a
talk
actually on that problem of how do you
reduce or how do you mitigate the
transfer of heavy metals from the soil
into the cannabis and hemp plant it was
a fascinating talk
and um
i hope there were people listening to
that because this is where
this is where we can have the biggest
impact of getting clean cannabis and
hemp is that is at the cultivation stage
excellent
yeah and
you know kind of before we went on that
you were talking about regulations and i
did want to ask you about that so i know
that heavy metal testing it's well first
of all regulation is out is very state
dependent as we know so
to your knowledge you know what states
are requiring heavy metal testing and
as we know at least on our side from
medicinal genomics that
um you know the state to state
requirements can can vary vastly where
some can be sort of overly inclusive
with too many things and others can be
drastically
under
under inclusive so in your opinion you
know which states are getting it right
or what do you think are the most
important heavy metals that folks should
be testing for well um you know to start
with um
when
when states started regulating cannabis
and they came up with a list of four
heavy metals
that was predominantly they looked to
the dietary supplements industry and
they looked to the american herbal
pharmacopoeia who were only
who were only only had the big four
heavy metals on a list of heavy metals
to monitor
for for dietary supplements
and herbal products so i can understand
where they came from however what has
happened
as the industry
and different states have come on board
they have been a little more proactive
in trying to understand well what other
heavy metals could be of concern and a
number of the states have
increased that panel new york for
example has nine on the list the big
four
plus chromium nickel
um
barium zinc selenium and i think one
other kind of zinc yeah but anyway so
okay so they have nine maryland had um
selenium silver barium and chromium but
they've recently
uh dialed back on selenium
silver and barium i don't know why so
they have chromium in it sort of the big
four um michigan has the big four plus
um
copper nickel
chromium and inorganic arsenic now
michigan are an anomaly i don't
understand because no other state has
inorganic arsenic so i'm trying to find
out
why michigan decided to
specify inorganic assets there doesn't
be any any apparent reason why they do
that because i've talked to a state
testing lab and they report total assets
so i just think that maybe state
regulators don't understand the
difference i don't know i'm not being
unkind to them but
there's no reason why they should have
done that um
so i think some states are being
proactive and um
i've i've got involved with a number of
states idea oregon
who had no heavy metals limits put out
for public comment their new regulations
and i sent um i sent my comments in
together with a few of my publications
to suggest that you should be monitoring
maybe up to 15
i don't know whether they will do that
but uh at least uh i put it out
you know i put it i put it to them in
public comment and connecticut also had
um were revising the heavy metals
regulations and wanted public comment on
that so i sent those in as well um but
you know what i tell statewide because i
know what i i know a lot of state
regulators they they kind of understand
what i'm doing i'm very sympathetic but
i think they they they understand that
they they don't want to be the first to
expand the panel to say 15. so i think
they're waiting for other states but i
keep reminding them nist have recently
come out with a toxic metal certified
reference material which contains up to
13 elements so so i said look the nest
they believe that this should be
regulated more like tobacco
than it should be um you know as it's
being regulated at the moment
i serve on the astm committee d37 and
i'm on a number of subcommittees one of
them is the laboratory subcommittee and
we have just written a method
for up to 21 elements
in cannabis related materials by icpms
we're currently going through the review
process now
um so hopefully that will come out in
the next month or so so really excited
that astm are supporting me on this so
they only have the 21 elements in that
method
and also which is which is brand new um
usp have put out for public comment um
they posted
a draft monograph for cbd to be used as
an api so this would be
cbd to be used in a pharmacist or a drug
formulation so you're talking about
um you know epidialex or maybe other
drugs that are going through fda
approval which contain cbd
and in that draft proposal
they say
that it must meet requirements of
chapter 232 for elemental impurities
well that that's telling me
that if they have that cbd monograph
in their book of compendium standards
to make cbd uh that's that's of the
quality required for
an fda-based drug you're gonna have to
be monitoring up to 24 elemental
impurities
so
this is telling me this is the way the
industry's going and i'm trying to get
the cannabis industry on board
to really think about this because you
know you'd only be in a position where
when you're two years down the road fda
comes in
and says well um
what's your list of elemental impurities
how many are you monitoring what you
know what's going on here i i mean it
obviously won't be as simple as that but
i'm telling you based on my research all
the signs are
that the elemental panel is going to be
expanded
so
yeah wow and so you mentioned all the
different elements that folks should be
monitoring so i'm curious
what is like an acceptable limit for
these elements does it differ for for
each elements are some sort of like pass
fail where you don't want a trace of
anything or in others there's sort of a
limit that's acceptable
well what the states are using is the
pde limits that were generated
for drug compounds drug substances um
and this is
this is described in ich q3d directives
where they spent 15 years to
understand toxicity based on
well-established animal models so that's
that information
for pharmaceuticals is documented and
it's good it's it's good data based on
pharmaceutical delivery but you've got
to understand that pharmaceuticals are
delivered basically four different ways
orally inhalation intravenously and
transdermal so there are four different
categories of pharmaceuticals as you can
imagine an inhalation has much lower pde
limits than say a normal delivered drug
but also remember that these are limits
per day
so the way they define them in chapter
232 and i see hq 3d directives is is
maximum limits per day
and they give you an example if a
pharmaceutical compound has a maximum
has a maximum
delivery maximum of 10 gram per day you
divide these daily maximum limits by 10
and you can come out with an
approximation of what you need to have
in your product
well that's great because the
pharmaceutical industry
you know is well used to defining you
know delivery amounts and mode of
administration the cannabis industry is
not so if you define 10 gram per day
what does that mean someone who's
inhaling cannabis someone who's eating a
brownie someone was putting it on there
on their arthritic finger i mean there
are so many ways
that cannabinoids are being delivered to
consumers nowadays and you can't say for
certain
that someone is only consuming x grams
per day and if you're basing your
if you're basing your maximum allowable
limits on a pharmaceutical guideline
which is based on the maximum dosage per
day you have to define a maximum dosage
in your cannabis product and they don't
do that they do not do that and you i
mean
you know that's my critique of the way
the regulations go
is that um
there's no
there's no logic to the way
they define the okay the regulations but
for example many states
even though um
they you know they lump every
cannabinoid or every cannabis product
into one mode of delivery they'll say
that it has to meet the inhalation pdes
will work out there's no rhyme or reason
why that should be the case but because
of the lowest they feel that if they can
put the lowest levels of the max lowest
maximum levels
in their specifications for those
product
if it's if it's under those levels the
product has to be safe well that's a
that's a that's that it's one of a
better word that's a dumb way of
regulating you know cannabis products so
that's my other critique pharmaceutical
pdes are based on well-established
animal models they're based on delivery
methods and the dates based on maximum
dosages
okay cannabis you know regulations they
don't take any of that into
consideration
so we talked a little bit about sort of
the different sources of contamination
that can introduce heavy metals into
cannabis you know we talked about from
you know from just growing the plant
whether it's accumulating it from the
soil or the water but i wanted to get
into maybe after post-harvest what are
some other other ways that you know
heavy metals could
contaminate the plant
okay um
well we know based on the extraction
process that different amounts of heavy
metal will be extracted into whatever
you're making broad spectrum full
spectrum isolates and based on the
extraction method whether it's co2
whether it's alcohol whether it's butane
i mean there are there's so many of them
out there um
there's definite and
there's there's information on the
public domain
which talks about
you have to balance
efficiency of the extraction method for
producing cannabinoids and i understand
that
um and extracting the minimum amount of
heavy metals so
most extractors will obviously look for
efficiency and not not not be survived
so much but are you extracting
contaminants but i always point to
gw pharmaceuticals who have their
extraction patent in the public domain
if you look at that
and um it's complicated but it explains
it very nicely that they balanced up the
contaminants
with efficiency of cbd that ultimately
they're making cbd to make uh drugs like
epidialox right they they actually have
another one going through the fda
pipeline which is coming out soon
so they go for
okay less efficiency
but
extracting less of the contaminants the
reason they can do that
is their growing process is all indoors
all the cannabis that dw farmer grows to
make epidiolex is grown indoors so
they're controlling the environments
very very strictly growing
controlling the watering controlling the
nutrient the fertilizer and everything
um
clearly many extractors in the u.s don't
grow it indoors so
they're not looking at that extraction
efficiency with regard to contaminants
so we know
that there's probably more heavy metal
contaminants coming through the
extraction process which could
further down the the either processing
chain could be purified could be
concentrated so you're always going to
be dealing with that so then you take it
through the next step and depending on
what you're making um you know that's
going to be in contact with
things like stainless steel mixing
vessels maybe grinding equipment or
whatever i mean there's so many
different options here of what the
product could be in contact with but we
know based on based on researchers out
there and you know what i've uncovered
that for example um it'll pick up
chromium for from a from a stainless
steel cutting scissors which is used to
snip the buds yeah
can you believe that yeah that's true
and um now you know that surprised me
but certainly in mixing vessels i mean
you know chromium nickel and iron are
big components of stainless steel
obviously
and if you use
if you use a lot of stainless steel
somewhere in the manufacturing process
your product will pick up
one or more of those metals
and
in addition to that
that's going to be i mean that's going
to be difficult though i mean
of course us coming from the microbial
side right i mean one of the advantages
of stainless steel is that it's pretty
sterile it's not going to be harboring
um microbial life as well right but yeah
now you have something else you need to
consider
yeah you know again i could point you to
publications which uh which you know
which have shown that and
you know i think it's important to
understand
that um
you you know many times in the
processing
in the chain of things you're doing
in you know in processing the
i mean whatever you're making it's not
in contact with services for long
periods of time but if it's stored in
something and this is a this is a whole
science of its own is that liquids
picking up impurities from storage
vessels and when i say storage vessels i
mean things like glass things like
plastic
we know for example that borosilicate
glass
which is used a lot in the industry is
notorious for having high levels
okay not so much heavy metals but
transition metals and some of those are
heavy metals so
what as a analytical chemist who uses
glass
in the process of analyzing
uh anything for heavy metals you learn
you can never use borosilicate glass you
have to use either high
predictor glass or quartz glass because
that's the purest because you know if
you store any acids any calibration
standards in border silicate glass
you'll get metals that were
that are actually being leached out of
the surface of the glass so you tend to
use high purity plastics but not all
plastics are high purity so you've got
to be careful the type of polymer or
plastic that you use
there's an example recently where
um
a
a testing lab in florida
was finding
over time that cbd and graduated little
dropper bottles
was increasing in lead level from the
from the time that the product was made
to
two to three months on the shelf and
what happened was that the graduated
marks were made from lead-based ink
so what was happening was the lead was
leaching out
of the ink into the extract and i'm not
too sure what the extract was but this
testing lab was finding over
extended periods of time of testing it
went from round about the regulated
level which was half a ppm and in some
cases
they were getting up to 50 times higher
in the extract
so the stuff like this that the industry
do they realize i think some folks do
when they do anything about it not many
but there are so many points along the
way
um where this could be happening and
then you get in
into delivery of the of the cannabinoid
which you know when you get into the
to the vaping devices which are becoming
the delivery method of choice nowadays
and um
again uh it's scary it's scary to think
what is happening and the industry is
not doing a good job of trying to
understand that because the process of
knowing what's in the aerosol is very
different to knowing what's in the
liquid in the tank
because the liquid in the tank is at
room temperature you start heating it up
elevating the temperature
and then
vaping it
because that in itself will draw out the
heavy metals which are being corroded
and the vapor or the consumer will end
up vaping small little particles of
those heavy metals not just the
regulated big four but we know based on
a few studies out there there's not many
that um
there are iron particles that are
chromium particles that are lead
particles that are nickel particles and
that's because of the components inside
these vaping devices including
lead-based solder you would think that
wouldn't be a problem but now the
industry is moving away from lead-based
solder because initially it was a huge
huge problem so whatever you're using
whether it's stainless steel brass uh
nichrome cantal there's so many
different designs out there um when you
increase when you start vaping at two to
three hundred degrees fahrenheit
you start coding the inside of the
components and then it's anyone's guess
how many you're getting through to the
consumer
wow so
i mean i guess given that maybe not so
much that last example that you provided
though but the fact that
this contamination can happen kind of
throughout the supply chain here is it
important that testing labs be testing
sort of the final product for for these
impurities because i know that that's
also very state dependent like for
example california that is a requirement
you have to yeah you have to do that so
absolutely yeah you know um
i'm going to talk about this to many
regulators because i
i'm trying to convince the the regulated
community and there is a national
association of regulators i forgot what
they're called but uh
um the state regularly or one of the
state regulators from maryland is is the
chair of that group and she talked at an
aoac meeting last week
um
and
you know we talked about that it was one
of the questions i asked her i said i
need to get right i need to get the
regulators to make them understand
that this is something
that they that they should be looking at
seriously and being proactive in maybe
trying to increase the number of
elements in your state because
the elements that are not being measured
and not being scrutinized
and we know and i've told again
two to many people about this that
you know cultivators are using things
like nickel based salts
um they are
they are flower they
they produce larger flowers silicon
basils which make the shoot much
sturdier so there's stuff going on like
that
but these elements are escaping the
scrutiny of state regulators they're not
being regulated
so
and i i'm not picking nickel and
silicon out
um
you know for any other reason but i know
that these are used
by cultivators but you can argue that
most of the nutrients and fertilizers
that have been used are not high quality
and most of them have been made from
phosphate based fertilizers phosphate
based fertilizers are notorious for
having high levels of heavy metals so
you know it's anyone's guess where what
metals are being delivered from from the
nutrient and the fertilizer
into into the cannabis plant so yeah i i
you know again um trying to get the
attention of the industry and you know
regulators are one component i've
offered to give a talk to this
um
are you familiar with this national
association of regulators
uh yeah yeah yeah okay yeah um so um i
followed up with an email to the person
i
do you know laurie
uh the name does sound familiar okay
yeah yeah so um
i said um well okay so i asked her a
question which was a little bit unfair
because she couldn't really answer it
that well but i said i would love to
talk to your to your group about how
maybe
you know you know to be aware of the
problem to be aware that that a lot of
elements are not getting scrutinized and
i think that's impacting
the safety you know consumer safety i
mean i've got to be careful what i say
here because
i you know i don't want to alarm the
industry then all of a sudden
that the the industry is producing
unsafe products but i'm i'm just trying
to make them aware of research that i've
that i've done over the past two to
three years which has covered a lot in
my book but i followed up with
publications and
public speaking engagements
i just think the industry should should
be more aware of this that's all
well
then it's a great thing that you're
coming to to canmed this year because
we're attracting folks from all over the
industry and you'll you'll definitely
have a platform to yeah that's
information
but yeah i think i mean that's why i
wanted to accept the invitation i
you know it's a probably three or four
day trip for me but
um you know again you have to justify
your time and your expenses but i think
it's well worth it definitely
excellent all right before i let you go
rob i do want to give you a chance to
share any additional resources with the
audience that they can learn more about
your work
or the topic in general if you let me
know i can put the links into the show
description so that that they can learn
more
yeah i mean would i would you mind if i
give you a link to my book for example
absolutely okay yeah and you know let me
give you links to a couple
of my sort of more recent publications
and that will give the audience i think
a better understanding of
where we are at the moment
excellent and i encourage any
any listeners to come out to canmed as
well and listen to rob stark of course
of course yeah please you can talk to me
personally then
excellent
all right thanks again rob and i can't
wait to see you out in pasadena for cam
ed yeah great thanks a lot appreciate it
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
robert thomas check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
our sponsor pigment tracker our next
episode will drop april 13th that's two
weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out the
canmed archive and join the canmed
community facebook group to stay
connected with us
of course you can also stay in touch
with us on social media on facebook
instagram linkedin and twitter just
search for kim at events
sign up for email alerts on cam at
events.com to stay up to date with all
the latest news and please be sure to
rate review and subscribe on your
favorite podcast app doing so helps us
reach more listeners
i do sincerely hope to see all of you
out in pasadena this spring but until
then stay safe stay healthy and please
join us for the next canbed coffee talk
[Music]
you