hello thanks for being here I'm from
teakettle own farm and
and I'd like to go through a couple of
things about tikkun olam first how I got
involved in tikkun olam and secondly
what tikkun olam is up to now one of our
studies which I think will have
important implications for the cannabis
community and basically what other
research were doing I was working as a
hedge fund analyst portfolio manager and
someone called me up and said you know
what you interested in in doing a
cannabis company and running a kind of
his company and I said no then you smoke
pot you see you feel better what am I
gonna do to really show any benefit and
said they said well you got to go to
Israel and speak to dr. Michelle I'm
Ruth khalili and Tim Naftali and so I
went and this is what she showed me in
in our in one of her ulcerative colitis
studies after eight weeks of cannabis
treatment and you don't have to be a big
radiologist to sort of see this that one
of the patients had a clean colon
I said that's interesting but not all
the patients had it and what else do you
have and then she showed me one of the
chrome study she did and she had an
eighty five point seven percent
significant improvement and this was
just 30 patients but these thirty
patients as dr. door said went through
the standard of care and after using the
cannabis eighty five point seven percent
felt a significant improvement and
that's something you know that doesn't
mean don't see those kind of numbers
every day and they're not coincidental
and the final thing that kind of got me
he got me interested was the
corticosteroids now we had 30 patients
and 26 of them we're taking
corticosteroids and after the canada's
treatment only four now that may be like
something you're not interested in or a
nice number but if you look at the side
effects of oral corticosteroids use long
term you know you have vulnerability to
infection diabetes hypertension the fact
that we can get the patients off oral
corticosteroids in the long term i think
was in that kind of seal that there's
something going on here and there's
something worth pursuing
the history of tikkun olam so i decided
obviously to do it the history of tikkun
olam was in 2002 was started as a
non-profit company basically for
holocaust survivors and veterans for
more for PTSD 2005 we got a licen the
first license from the government of
israel and in 2012 they started
producing cannabis for medical use and
dispensing even today one out of every
three patients get their cannabis from
Tekin along in israel um
now in the u.s. it's a total different
story
no doctor michelin isolated discovered
THC in 1964 and it took till 1981 to get
a drug on the market with had some
cannabis usage and then four years later
a Marinol to rabinaw and sessom that
other two drugs that are on the market
for for use in nausea and vomiting see
inv and you know before I started doing
this I was thinking you know I'm an
analyst and you have two drugs on the
market and everybody's saying this is a
billion dollar industry yet these two
drugs haven't really done that well or
really haven't been used and it was
further research I realized that these
are synthetic THC s it's probably less
than 10% absorbed with Marinol and
actually the market is is a lot bigger
once we get to the botanical products
2010 yet sativex by GW which was only
approved in Europe for spasticity due to
multiple sclerosis it's a 50/50 product
50 THC 50 CBD and before we heard
explanation why it's not in the US but I
know they're working on for for pain and
probably they will be filing at some
point earlier this year a liquid form of
Marinol was approved and it was approved
at schedule two and the other Marinol is
Schedule three and you're trying to
figure out why why is this being
approved that's scheduled to more severe
and the answer is that did they do
likability studies and
apparently they were able to abuse this
more like dumping cigarettes in whatever
was so and basically that's the approval
and finally we get to happy dialects
which is a major victory for this
industry as having a botanical product
approved by the FDA and the bigger
provement is that a schedule five which
is the least the least severe of all the
of all the different schedules and
schedule five means you could use it
off-label and you could probably get
insurance reimbursement that remains to
be seen and this is just a quick chart
of the DEA scheduling of drugs you know
yeah just like I spoke before cannabis
the THC is still scheduled one for Noah
with heroin LSD and MD MD at tikkun olam
since we essentially long since we
launched the medical since we trust the
medical dispensary we decided to
actually follow the patients and give
them questionnaires to figure out what
these patients are taking what diseases
they're they're taking them for and how
it's working we've got a database of
close to 20,000 patients now and
obviously growing every day as we
dispense more cannabis and if you look
94 percent of the patients so
improvement in their condition and 62
reduced medications which I'll come to a
little bit later which i think is one of
the most important things of cannabis is
that we can reduce toxic medications
this is a study we released early in the
year to prospect this study on
on cancer patients their usage and the
efficacy of medical cannabis it's with
the lihi bar LAIV who Schindler who's
our medical director in Israel Victor
Novak who is our clinical director and
if you need a paper rough dr. michele
has to be on the paper so we have all
the guys on this paper so this is the
indications that we found for useful
middle cannabis 60
none of the patients are from cancer
symptoms 24 pain and as we move down we
see you know others there for other
diseases the the we screen 3:30 845
patients and 209 20 923 responded to the
questionnaire this is their you know the
severity of this is in in six months a
quarter of the patients died so our debt
that what we're working on is probably
close to 2,000 patients and these are
the malignancies they had that breast
most had breast cancer lung cancer
pancreatic all the cancers that are
typically found but the majority with
breast and lung the symptoms it's an 8
on the pain scale 8 is a very is 8 out
of 10 it's a very severe amount of pain
that these patients had they had sleep
problems you know their digestive
problems all the anxiety depression
nausea vomiting of course all the
typical symptoms that you would see with
cancer patients and if you see the
global assessment they after six months
it's pretty amazing that 50.8% felt they
had a significant improvement there it's
34 and 10 in terms of slide and moderate
so we had a 9 to 5 point 5 percent
improvement in patients however they
they felt it was but I think it's very
important that that's that's a big
number and I think we should really keep
that in mind going forward the quality
of life before and after you see as
things moved along the this after six
months we had 611 felt there probably of
life was good and 199 very good and if
you've been around cancer patients these
are very significant numbers and so this
is these are the symptoms and the change
after six months and you could see the
sleep problems 16% disappeared an
improvement was 70.8 I think sleep
has a lot to do with getting better I
think at peace people are sleeping
better they have a much better chance of
improvement you see anxiety and
depression you know a lot of people like
seventy five percent felt improvement
digestive problems and and nausea and
vomiting of course which is the old then
the tried and true reason for cannabis
here's the adverse event you can see
it's pretty pretty good only eight
percent has some dizziness dry mouth
increased appetite so it's kind of
consistent of what we'd expect with
cannabis and in terms of treating cancer
pain it's probably better than any drug
that's out there so so this is I think
if if you want to do the important slide
in my presentation is this slide and if
you could take away because this is what
I think will lead to for us to do more
studies and other people out there doing
more studies if you look at the first
line you have people who stopped taking
opioids we have 36% and we're talking
about a pain of eight which is very
significant 38 36 percent stopped taking
their opioids and nine point nine
percent and decrease their dosage this
is something that's about 50% of
patients were off the opioids and that I
have to tell you what's going on today
with opioids in terms of addiction and
I'll come back to it a little later but
I think this in itself propels us to
start doing some studies in terms of
replacing opioids with with cannabis if
you look at Anzio lytx the you know sort
of like the volumes of the world 23.8%
stopped taking them corticosteroids
twenty thirty one percent stop taking
corticosteroids and obviously
antiemetics and nausea 67.3% so these
are and laxatives because obviously if
people stop taking opioids they they
don't need to laxatives because opioids
you know can cause
tremendous issues with so I think but
but I think what we should be
concentrating is on the opioids and how
these patients stop taking the opioids
and I think you'll be hearing from us in
the near future in terms of doing
Studies a quick discussion of the the
study just so you don't think we're
everything was great
well the treatment was effective
heterogeneity we had I used a
heterogeneous population from a few
months to 99 years old 18.8 patients
discontinued treatment so some people
kind of just didn't help and the other
issue was self-reported and what we need
to do obviously is to establish a
national and international clinical
investment program an investigational
program to prove these results back to
the opioids currently the CDC statistics
115 15 American's die every day from
opiate overdose forty percent of the
patients involved prescription opioids
and from a financial burden on the on
the country seventy eight point five
billion a year is caused because of the
people of using opioids at ticking along
we're gonna go further and do many more
studies these are the studies that are
scheduled to be done the Krone study as
dr. door mentioned we just released some
data in Europe on Crohn's we had
remission we had quality of life we're
going to do the other data in terms of
internal colonoscopy we did have
decreased in colonoscopy in in patients
taking cannabis we also had a little bit
of decrease in placebo so we're gonna
have to work our way through that in
terms to understand what why that was
the case it was eight weeks I I suspect
if we take it longer to six months we
probably will see a differentiation
between between the Crohn's patients and
the placebo
we're doing an acute migraine headache
study we started we're doing agitation
and Alzheimer's we were more than
halfway through that study and the
results are looking pretty good we're
going to start an autism study very soon
Tourette syndrome we're doing an orphan
drug and the most important we have to
prospective study papers coming out
probably before the end of the year
one is an autism in a hundred and eighty
eight patients where we these patients
were taking cannabis obviously the data
will be good otherwise I wouldn't be
mentioning it and I think you guys
should keep an eye when it's the most
patients that have ever been reported
upon in the autism and we will be doing
a fibromyalgia we have a fibromyalgia
paper with 367 patients so that's in the
near term I think you it would be very
helpful to kind of keep an eye on that I
think all of us are in the in trying to
make these studies and increase the
clinical data because only that's the
only way things will change I think if
we increase the clinical data mainstream
physicians will start using crowd will
start using cannabis I think ultimately
the political people will pick up on
that and I think that will be the
beginning of a turnaround for the use of
cannabis in sick patients thank you
[Applause]
hi thank you very much for that
presentation going back to the opiate
reduction use I saw a column that said
new medications what are the new
medications that they they took after
reducing their opiate use I don't
remember that it basically was simply we
stayed on opioids there was no new
medication the new medication may have
been the opiate the cannabis but these
patients were taking Canada specifically
and they stopped their opioids there
were no other medications at all I see
thanks awesome hi thank you so much for
your presentation okay the question is
in the scientist dr. Michelle um talks
about the possibility of cannabis for
type 1 diabetes and I was wondering if
that's on your list also um it's I've
seen some animal data out of Hadassah
they showed it to me I don't think we're
ready for that now but I'm sure down the
road either we'll be doing it someone
else will be doing it but they have what
I've seen that's to be very good animal
data thank you can you speak to any
randomized control trials being done
with Parkinson's disease we've done some
preliminary studies in Parkinson's they
they found it to be safe it's been
effective but we're not at right now
doing any kind of large-scale studies
but I know there are other companies
doing it and it would make sense that
Parkinson would be since it's a
neurological disease it would make sense
that at some point someone would be
doing some studies on the two minutes hi
are there any studies being done
comparing delivery methods of
cannabinoids for things like Crohn's
disease such as inhaling it versus
putting it in the gut
either in a capsule or suppository I
mean the we're thinking of that and I'm
sure other the thing about right now
we're using sublingual we found out to
be we've done PK studies and we found
that to be the best route of administer
bypassing liver in terms of oral you
have to get some specialized some
specialized drug delivery to avoid
metabolism by the liver I'm sure there
are people working on that right now
we're very happy with the sublingual use
but at some point I think we'd have to
get a little more sophisticated and but
right now is for Crohn's and others
we're doing the sublingual drops thank
you for your presentation
the 18.8% that dropped out first I don't
recall if you gave a dose of THC and CBD
and secondly do you think they dropped
out because the treatment was not
effective as opposed to adverse effects
I think they dropped out because the
treatment was not effective and I'm sort
of happy when I see things like that ice
when I see side-effects when I see
people dropping out because ultimately
our goal is to get to get the THC or the
CBD to be a drug and if you looking you
know any kind of PDR anything every drug
has side effects and it doesn't work in
everybody so I'm quite happy to see it
not working in certain people thank you
I don't recall did you listen no we
didn't list of this I said thank you are
there any studies being done for mental
health conditions to avoid the heavy
duty drugs that are being we're not in
doing those studies but I think
ultimately you know if we're doing
Alzheimer's agitation in terms of
reducing agitation I think it to be
quite possible in autism where you're
kind of reducing aggressiveness I think
there's a place for that study but we're
not we're not doing it round of applause
please for Sid tubman field