my name is Sarah Jane ward an assistant
professor at the Louis Katz School of
Medicine at Temple University I'm in the
center for substance abuse research also
in the department of pharmacology my
research that I do at Temple is using
animal models to study the safety and
efficacy of molecules from the cannabis
plant for many of the therapeutic
targets that we investigate in the
laboratory there are not very many
treatment options available and for some
of the disorders that were investigating
in the laboratory such as chemotherapy
induced neuropathic pain for example
there are currently no FDA approved
treatments for for this disease we think
it's really important to do some good
basic science research to see if this is
a viable treatment option that can be
approved at the 2017 can med conference
I plan to share some of the research
that I've been conducting over the last
several years at Temple in my own
laboratory in collaboration with many
other scientists here specifically
investigating the therapeutic potential
of different components of the plant for
the treatment of various CNS disorders
that specifically have an inflammatory
component to them some of the topics
that I'll be talking about are our
results in animal models of chronic pain
as well as animal models of spinal cord
injury traumatic brain injury and stroke
one of the reasons to attend conferences
like the Ken med conference are to
really get an appreciation for how much
research is going on in the area of
medical cannabis one thing I'm surprised
about when I talk to people who are
outside of the basic science field
they're unaware that there is so much
research going on both at the basic
science and clinical level to
understand the safety concerns
associated with medical cannabis as well
as the potential therapeutic efficacy
that we're discovering in our research
as a substance abuse researcher I had my
own concerns about the abuse liability
of marijuana or different therapeutics
based off of marijuana and through
attending many scientific conferences
talking to colleagues reading scientific
articles
it's definitely shifted my opinions and
really I think almost every time I talk
to people other scientists other people
in the general population when when
people are exposed to the kind of
research that is going on and the kind
of results that are being obtained think
by and large people's attitudes are
shift or certainly their their minds are
opened
[Music]