my name is Bonnie Goldstein and I'm a
licensed physician in the state of
California and I have a medical practice
called Kenna centers and what we do is
educate and help patients use medical
cannabis for their serious and chronic
medical conditions my talk at kin med is
going to be about my medical practice in
terms of what I'm seeing with patients
so overall what I'm seeing with chronic
pain patients what I'm seeing with
cancer patients what I'm seeing in the
pediatric epilepsy population that I'm
taken care of sharing those stories and
talking about how patients are using
this to improve the quality of their
lives can med is a really important
conference and one is because it really
does target the science so they get the
best scientists they get doctors they
get researchers they get people who are
maybe in other fields who now have
crossed over and that's important
everybody's passionate and everybody's
sharing ideas and it's all with the same
goal is to help our fellow mankind many
of the parents that come to see me are
really nervous
and once they start using it they say oh
well wow this is really working and you
know they have a lot of anxiety because
they've been through so many different
things already and so many of them
aren't trusting and they're afraid to
hope and all they need to do is to see
that there is something there and then
they they just say okay now I need to
tell everybody about this because why
should anybody else be suffering there's
a little girl that kind of comes to mind
who came to see me who has numerous
medical issues and including seizures
and she tried multiple different
medications and although some of them
work to reduce the seizures all of them
had terrible side effects so we started
her on cannabis oil and she was able to
wean off those medications and she came
to see me when she was about seven or
eight years old and she wasn't able to
read or write
and by 10:00 she was reading and writing
and having much less seizures and I just
feel really lucky as a doctor to
actually be able to help people truly
feel better if this were to go away
people would use it off the black market
and it would be unregulated I know that
there are people in states where they
don't have medical cannabis they're
using it because their child is sick and
their child is better on it who wouldn't
do that for their child I have met
people at conferences who came because
they're curious but they're still
doubtful and then they start to listen
and they hear a doctor from a
prestigious university speak about their
research and then they hear a someone
from another country who's allowed to do
research for instance dr. Michelle him
from Israel came to speak about his
experience last year and then they hear
from me about my patient experiences and
they say well there is something to this
and that starts them on the journey
[Music]