there was a comment made that I couldn't
get rid of is that in the United States
research is apparently in the private
sector at in Canada it's University
there's exceptions to the rule
I agree that Buffalo is on the border of
Canada the United States but still the
USA so I'm going to present my research
uh that we I have done now my background
is I have five board certifications uh
professor of Neurology oncology
neurology headache medicine
and neuroimaging and uh so I went
through the academic world and the last
time I gave this talk was that the
American Academy of Neurology
where there was 400 people in the room
and they had to get an overflow room
to tell you the interest at the
neurological level in academic medicine
so there's a tremendous interest and I
would love to see more Physicians come
down for this meeting because I think
it's well worthwhile to network with
that Physician Group
so I'm going to as you can tell I I
presently run about
110 research studies with Pharma so I'm
I'm in bed with Pharma big time and in
fact when I talk about migraines the
last eight drugs that have been FDA
approved
which is worth what billions for each
company eight different companies uh I
was uh I did I was part of the research
team that did that at our Institute
this is the Institute and I think the
most important part of it is is the 13
000 cannabis patients that we actively
see so you understand that this
NeuroScience Center sees about
uh 1 300 patients on a daily basis
so although it was 250 are migranters or
headache patients so that we have a huge
volume and the reason I chose migraines
being the director of the migraine and
the canvas Clinic it was so easy to do I
also I'm a chief of neuroncology so I
was very much interested in the
glioblastoma uh literature in cannabis
which is very new uh probably more
advanced in England and Spain but also I
I run a center in Europe uh called The
Mind clinic and that's in Budapest
Hungary it's a NeuroScience Center
so this is a breakdown of our cannabis
clinic so we have thirteen thousand and
seven that's pretty up to date this is
in the New York State uh medical
marijuana program or cannabis program as
I like to call it is is
um is quite regulated quite expensive
but you know it's it's we I'm about 10
or 11 of the whole state seeing patients
so we see a significant amount as you
can tell chronic pain is 70 and you go
down the list of cancer neuropathies
many of the chronic pain patients by the
way have cancer and other disorders so I
I uh you know I did I did one thing I
told the patients I won't accept a
dollar from you in cash but then you
have to fill out all this data and
that's your sacrifice and they trust me
they agreed to that so we have a huge
amount of data intake we don't send
patients away for a year we bring them
back depending on the disease state but
no longer than two to three months so
this way I'm gathering the data and I
agree
as somebody who runs around to my
studies I'm going to talk to you about
large population retrospective studies
the criticism of cannabis research over
the years has been obviously that this
numbers have been relatively small
so I talked about legitimacy only
because uh uh my fight is not with the
Cannabis uh users or the business my
fight is to uh uh talk to the
academicians the presidents of societies
uh and change their attitudes to
cannabis and I know a lot of people in
the audience uh Bonnie Ethan
Dustin have also had this fight for many
years some longer than others but it's a
long-term fight and I didn't understand
that fight until I got into cannabis
about seven years ago which is when New
York State uh uh
legalized it now one of the other
reasons is that as a migraine specialist
who runs a large probably the largest
migraine Center in the country
many of my predecessors the people I
looked up to uh were actually gowers
from England who was a neurologist a
father of Neurology osley a father of
modern medicine from Canada who
developed Johns Hopkins these
individuals in their books at the 200th
Century the previous Century wrote about
use of cannabis in in the treatment of
headaches and migraines so in fact that
was probably one of the most common
cause and O'Shaughnessy in Calcutta did
the first scientific studies of pain
endometriosis went back to England to
treat the queen at that time and this is
something you all know uh is that
cannabis or marijuana extracts with the
first second and third most prescribed
meds between 1842 and 1890. if you don't
know the history of what happened and I
presumed this audience does
look it up review it because it's really
it opens your eyes how politics business
influence medicine so this is two
studies that I quoting you so I firmly
believe that people people ask me do I
smoke I said I don't
but I don't even drink and I don't I
don't smoke tobacco but many of these
so-called uh alcohol is being used for
medical reasons we all know that many
alcoholics become alcoholics because of
under underlining anxiety depression uh
PTSD so the bottom line is that that in
my opinion more people use medical
marijuana recreationally I'm a medically
than Recreation then we are understand I
went to Colorado at the beginning of my
search for this knowledge and I asked I
went to a bartender in a you know in
Colorado and asked him then what CBD
products do you have he said we don't
have many CBD products that go so
everything we have is THC I said why is
that because everybody wants to get high
and so how about my grandmother who's
got rheumatoid right arthritis at age 78
I need some kind of cannabinoid and the
reply was the same she wants to get high
and that's not the fact because in my
thirteen thousand patient I the question
I asked routinely it's it's on the data
do you get high from the cannabinoids
I'm giving you and the answer is in 99
no
so so there is this population out there
and I'm talking about medical marijuana
not recreational some people get drink
alcohol to get drunk some people use
alcohol on a daily basis to maintain
their quality of life whatever that may
be
I'm not going to review that but the
endogenous cannabinoids which have well
be discussed uh and and uh and
phytocannabinoid noise we all know these
types and some of the you know these
researchers are in the audience uh we I
also uh don't believe in sativa and
indica and strains I usually use the
type 1 type 2 type 3 cannabis uh
chemovars which I noted above here and
the clinical endocannary deficiency
something I'm I'm really interested in
because as a neurologist I treat a lot
of people Parkinson's disease and
Parkinson's disease is a lack of
dopamine
Alzheimer's a lack of acetylcholine
depression a lack of Serotonin and
norepinephrine so we have these
deficiency states in the diseases that I
treat on a routine basis uh and the
endocannide deficiency syndrome and by
the way the endocannabinoid system is
not taught in medical schools except for
about eight percent so there's this
obvious ignorance and I use the term
ignorance Loosely that Physicians don't
understand it and because they don't
understand it a physician will then
build those walls around them and say
not for my patients so we have to
educate at the medical school level
about the endocannibal deficiency yet I
have to commend Ethan Russo because he's
one of the strong voices in this
community that really tries to make
Physicians understand and I say try
because sometimes it doesn't work out
and he's already laughing because he
knows I'm going to show that slide to
have to get to you because it's very
important to understand that the
endocannibal deficiency may be occurring
in disorders uh Beyond migraine and if
you know the definition of comorbidity
comorbidity means that you have one
disease and another disease happens in
that one individual that's statistically
higher than by incidents for example
migraners have a high your incidents of
fibromyalgia or idiopathic bowel
syndrome
post-traumatic stress disorder bio
bipolar disorder anxiety and so on so
these these circles Envision a subset of
a population which is rather significant
because if you look at migraine uh the
the the incidence of migraine is 12
uh which is the prevalence rate is 12
around the world in women it's about 18
percent and in women between the age of
20 and 40 it's close to 40 percent
so 40 percent of women in here are
migrators if they know it or maybe they
don't know it but I promise you that
migraine is a disorder that is
tremendously easy to do research on
because we have a strict criteria what a
migraine is based on the international
Headache Society classification so these
disorders are natural to be treated in
our clinic this is in Pasadena I think
recently last time I think uh uh Dr
Michelle came to the United States and I
had an opportunity to talk to him about
his
um about his theories about the use of
cannabinoids and headaches and so on and
and obviously he's a Pioneer and I don't
know if we call it grandfather or
Godfather of research and cannabinoids
so we know about all this I'm not going
to go through this because this but this
is the picture I want to show you the
individual way on the left is uh uh is
uh is is the president of the American
Headache Society this is at the American
Headache Society Dr Silverstein then as
myself and the one who's got the
microphone is Ethan Russo oh and the one
next to him is the next president of the
American Headache Society and he and and
and coming from London England
originally from Australia
which maybe I I'll leave his name out
for now but the bottom line is as Ethan
is appropriately answering a question in
an audience much bigger than this
he got up and said this is [ __ ] and
left the panel now you don't see that in
academic medicine I think you don't see
it in many places uh I I hope Dustin
doesn't come up here and say this is
[ __ ] and pushes me off this after
because he has that potential I saw him
dance yesterday he's got a potential for
a lot so the bottom line is this is
really this just tells you the internal
resistance from academic medicine toward
individuals who have really uh put their
academic career and their life for a
cause as advocacy and with science so
this is just tells me about headaches
now migraines I won't get into but I
will tell you there the migraines is one
of the most common disorders in fact
according to the World Health
Organization who
chronic migraines is the second most
disabling disease in the world
first one is low back pain
and and so if you're a microner you can
see how much one suffers that's episodic
migraine which is the on the left you
know 40 to 72 hours unilow location
pulsating moderate to severe aggravated
by causing physical activity
you have migraines with aura but that's
only about 15 to 20 percent of all
migraines so people say oh I don't have
an aura so I don't have a migraine not
true
chronic migraine 40 of my clinic is
chronic migraine by definition more than
15 disabling headaches uh a month of
which eight have to be migrants lasted
more than four hours a day so this is
the definition of international Headache
Society definition of migraine this is a
migraine there's a pro drone which could
last 24 to 36 hours
where you have mood changes cravings for
example everybody thinks well I eat
chocolate and now I got a migraine and
chocolate caused a migraine when in fact
maybe the craving a hypothalamic
phenomena is the cause of you craving
for chocolate and it's part of the
migraine itself the aura occurs in 15 to
20 headache phase postro
all right so the the numbers are huge so
if you want to try or study a disorder
in medicine then migraine is ideal
because these patients are are
quite frequently in our in our practice
and and quite easy to treat because
micronares tend to have a higher
medical knowledge than non-migranters
and that's been shown I'm not going to
go through the pathophysiology but it's
interesting that the cortical spreading
depression is electrical phenomena uh
that was outlined by Leo from Brazil and
then it goes to the migraine generators
in the brain stem the rafae nuclei the
locus cerelius uh and then through the
trigeminal vasculature we have cgrp
being a new uh entity now cgrp I listed
one two three four cgrps but it says
three other ones called uh uh also so we
I studied seven cgrps all seven were
approved by the FDA so yes I'm a
superstar in headache medicine because
the the pharmaceutical companies love us
because we we did this study and it was
not just at my Institute it was a
multi-center study the other g-pan
answer called yeah the ones listed at
properties the ones on TV you bravi
neurotech and so on trip dance uh came
out in 1992 we thought that's going to
change headache medicine it did somewhat
ergot it means we don't use any more
came out in 1920s and but Botox which is
neurotoxin is still approved for chronic
migraine we also do research in
neurostimulators and then I add cannabis
at the end the thing about chronic
migraine ners people with chronic
migraine by the IHS definition they have
low anatomide levels so this is somebody
asked about can you do spinal taps on
these patients well this is a study
looking at spinal taps on patients with
migraines and looking at anandamide
levels or endocannibals and by the way
in chronic migraine they're low I truly
believe that when I see a patient and I
see a lot of patients is that some
patients will respond to cannabis
wonderfully and they're they say you've
changed my life some people don't and I
truly believe that this is part of of
the endocannabinoid deficiency syndrome
where phytocannabinoids supplement
endocannabinoids in individuals who have
low cannabinoid levels so so anandamide
levels have been shown low in chronic
migraine so this is some of the
re-studies we've done so we did see
initially we did 263 patients obviously
we have more than that but when we have
to go back 88.9
reported Improvement in migraine 83
percent of patients reported Improvement
of their headaches besides migraine and
51 on Ops were able to reduce their
consumption completely or significantly
so this is a chronic migraine study
so the efficacy of medical cannabinoids
seems to be dependent on the ratio of
THC and CBD what we use because we know
the ratios the one criticism on New York
State Canada cannabinoid program is it's
expensive the the positive is that it's
regulated relatively rigidly and
strictly appearance of a distinct group
of receptors type 1 type 2 I'm going to
show you the and what's interesting
about this cannabis and chronic migraine
is I did that in parallel to cgrp
monoclonal antibodies these are these
are shots given once a month or an IV
once every three months if you're
familiar with these drugs those drugs
have been approved by the efda and the
cost of that drug is about eight
thousand dollars a year
now insurance companies uh have accepted
the research and are now paying for
these drugs 8 000 a year they won't pay
for cannabinoids but they'll pay eight
thousand dollars Botox is about six
thousand five to six thousand dollars a
year uh for chronic migraines but the
results of the studies albeit my study
was retrospective but parallel to the
other studies I did with Pharma uh and
you could see the results in
171 patients there was a 25.7 percent
of patients had a 75 Improvement on
headaches on cannabinoids
that number is remarkable by the way if
you deal with headache medicine I think
we have neurologists in the audience but
you look at 63.2 percent had a 50
Improvement of chronic migraines which
the who has stated is the second most
disabling disorder in the world
so fifty percent Improvement of this
population which is the worst of the
worst by the way many of these have
sleep disturbance comorbidities of
depression anxiety fibromyalgia go down
the list irritable bowel syndrome so
this is a population that now even 80
said there was a 30 Improvement on
cannabinoids and so this is these
numbers are actually if you look
parallel to the cgrp monoclone
antibodies that were approved by the FDA
are very similar numbers except one's
retrospective and the other one's is
randomized studies and I agree with
academic medicine that random my Studies
have to be done but that's you know
that's the next question who will pay
for that so uh and then this one here 63
percent responded very similar to all
the cgrp monoclonal bodies and this is a
cannabis and chronic migraine in this
population at 41.8 percent decrease in
headache monthly headache days per month
and then average decrease in monthly
headache days uh was significant so
cannabis can work in chronic migraine by
improving the uh depressive levels
anxieties analgesia and to influence
there's many reasons why and I'm I'm
purpose did not get into the uh
pathophysiology of how cannabis affects
the central nervous system because a lot
of this information was given to you so
this is the cannaboids I use so I first
question I ask are you naive or not
naive it's a simple question
um so most of my patients are in the you
know 60 and above so most of them are
quite naive so I'll use this titration
schedule in patients who are naive I
start lower patients are not naive I
start higher and I may give a higher THC
comma if they're smoking it and I want
to switch over because people are
realizing that as much as we love our
cannabis there's got to be a way that we
can find better than smoking it
or or vaping it now vaping it has shown
to be less toxic to the lung than than
smoking and the literature has not come
out with cannabis smoking is associated
with a higher incidence of lung cancer
like it is with tobacco so so uh
probably because most people are not
smoking as much although you're inhaling
it deeper so I'm not sure that
literature is going to stand for a long
time we'll be we'll find out but you
remember I'm an oncologist too so I have
to respect that so cost Berry is the
major issue for me when I treat patients
uh I I I bring them back if they don't
come back I'll give them a call my staff
does and says why did you not come back
why didn't you go to the I stop I looked
at the istop which is that regulatory uh
state-run system that I know when they
pick up the opioids the benzodiazepines
or the Cannabis and they didn't go pick
it up and I asked him why didn't you do
it so the numbers are straightforward
then I looked at zip codes
I looked at all the people who could who
went and said I can't afford it I looked
at zip codes and do I have to tell you
what the ZIP code showed in my part of
the world Western New York the zip codes
were downtown Buffalo it was a it was
totally on income and race
which is why we put these systems
together
it's not working and I know that and I'm
in yeah I have a lot of meetings with
politicians to say look you put a system
together and it's just not working for
the population that we need to be more
cognizant of so the barrier says so this
is the article I recently wrote came out
in two years ago or now uh two and a
half yeah two years ago and it's
cannabis and migraine it's complicated
that would be I urge you to review that
so my conclusion is cannabis work
because they're anti-convulsive and the
reason I migraine is not a seizure but
migraine has ion channels uh as has
epilepsy so there may be a correlation
analgesic anti-matic anti-inflammatory
it's a it's a promising compound yes we
do need rad to my study uh I have a few
things here of
post-concussive headaches and chronic
pain and all I can tell you in this
study we've done the 80 showed
subjective Improvement on
post-concussive and chronic pain 80
percent of improvement with sleep
sending Improvement and and the
treatment I use usually is a 20 to 1
oral tincture which I titrate slowly and
then
and then this is this is something in
the in the in the uh opioid uh epidemic
uh we have right now which is a real
serious problem uh that has to be
addressed uh is that if you look at
opiate consumption
look at the different diseases TN is
trigeminal neuralgia uh these are the
decreased in amount of opioids they use
based on the different disease States
but across the board you'll see
especially fibromyalgia at 63 percent
come off opioids this is important
reduction of opiate consumption and
should be studied to the hilt especially
now in in the study now this was
interesting trigeminal neuralgia another
pain syndrome lancetting pain and this
the results are really unbelievable 81
reported significant subjective
improvements so I'm going to go by
fibromyalgia anxiety I'm gonna go that
wherever the art of medicine is love
there's a lot of humanity Hippocrates
and I thank you very much
and I think my team also so thank you
very much