[Music]
my next question is you know which one
of these indications is sort of the
furthest along or closest to actually
doing clinical trials and it sounds like
it's um this ALS motor neuron um
application M dis I I think so right
excent over the last year we've learned
a lot about ALS motor disease we've
learned a lot about how the cannabis
plant has helped people suffering from
neurological ailments um um since the
beginning of time in a variety of
different cultures and again leaning on
the experience of Dr Ethan Russo our
senior medical
adviser and what the work that they did
formerly at GW Pharma we know that
cannabis can help in severe neurological
diseases neurod degenerative diseases
and ALS MTO neuron disease is an area
where these patients they need help a
lot of them use cannabis right now to
help manage their symptoms but they
don't have something standardized and
the practitioner doesn't always know
what the patient is using even though
they can come into the clinic and say
hey we're using cannabis we feel better
we're eating more so on and so forth so
our goal is to be able to leverage all
the work previously done along with some
of the new work that we're doing right
now to be able to move this forward into
the clinic and really help a patient
population that's looking for answers
that's looking for um help that's
looking for a better quality of life and
really deserves to have it excellent and
now
um the therapeutic that you're sort of
evaluating is that a like a single
molecule um therapeutic or is it sort of
a combination of of different compounds
what does that look like so generally
speaking when we evaluate um our Assets
in any indication we put a series of
different candidates in there so we will
put like um highly purified single can
canlab and can we'll put can a extract
and then we could put combination
extract in there and see what performs
best um based on the mixture the
cocktail mixture the almost Entourage or
synergistic approach right now based on
the work previously done and based on
again being a student of Dr re so we
know that in the clinic for humans it's
probably not going to be a single
mixture a single ingredient that has the
best opportunity to help these patients
it's going to be a cocktail mixture or
cocktail approach not dissimilar to how
these patients are getting treated right
now but we can talk about that a little
bit later um as I was saying we put
together a series of um different
molecules found in the plant at various
concentrations at safe concentrations
that we believe can be delivered to
patients chronically on an everyday
basis that can help them manage their
symptoms that can improve their quality
of life and might also be
neuroprotective as well um and help them
with survival so we think that we have
something that can be disease modifying
now we just have to continue to go out
improve it great and so and so where are
we at now and I mean maybe let's how
about a little preview I don't want you
give way too much because we want people
to come out to the event but um what
what are you looking to present at at
canmed so at canmed I we have a series
of again previous literature that's been
done but also some unique exper
experiments that we've recently done to
validate that our combination actually
does work how we think it's going to
work so I'm really excited to share some
of this information share again the
process that we went through from
looking at all the things previously
done to adding our unique twists on it
and then showing uh what the result is
and how we got it to work in our favor
[Music]
excellent