I believe that once we should know that
there is a complete there should be a
complete separation between recreational
cannabis and medicinal cannabis and the
reason is that in medicinal cannabis or
people that take cannabis as a drug for
people that do research and medicinal
cannabis have to know that it has to
follow medical regulations a patient
should have to know the exact amount of
material is getting you should know how
to get it and you should be in constant
contact with with a physician
recreational cannabis is a social issue
decisions and recreational cannabis have
to be made by society not necessarily or
not even at all on medical grounds the
reason is that they're two different
things so we should not mix them
together we should try to move the
medical cannabis as much as possible
towards the medical reasons for using a
drug and that's what happening in Israel
we're changing it we're not there yet -
we're changing it I hope that we shall
be there within the next few months so
patient who who is allowed to get
cannabis for his specific disease not
for any disease for his specific disease
whether it's pain with gastrointestinal
problem like Crohn's the weather is
anything else that's approved like
epilepsy for example the person or his
parents her parents should know exactly
what mixture he is getting because
cannabis medical cannabis is a mixture
it's a mixture not just of THC and CBD
but also a lot of other compounds
including some therapies so a person
should know as much as possible on what
is the drug that he's taking we started
about the recreational use and
men often I am asking the Parliament
meetings about our opinion about
recreational use of cannabis in my
either answer is the same
I mean we are physicians we do not deal
with social decisions so the current
elevation on use is a social decision
which should be made by the Parliament
the government not by us by physicians
at present we are working for example on
brain trauma we found many years ago
together with dr. with Professor st
shock army that cannabinoids help in
brain trauma in mice it's a little bit
difficult to do brain trauma more
experiments in humans so it has been
done in mice and it helps specific
compounds whether they are the natural
ones the one that we make the endogenous
cannabinoids whether THC or
cannabidiol from the plant or these up
in different ways there are also
additional compound surprisingly which
are found in our body which resembled
structurally at least some of the other
compounds I mentioned and these
compounds also help with brain trauma so
is there no drugs in helping with brain
trauma at the moment I assume that we
can help in this particular field forty
percent of our patients today oncology
patients suffering from pain from the
test awfully for the robot II resulted
from the treatment with excellent
results sometimes I'm a little bit a
confusion I have to present this and
then when I presented the results in
Department some of the dominant members
there were somewhere minute
it's me as a representative and why
don't you allow treat
two families for everyone ecology
patient in Israel it closes cannabis and
I have to call the realtor I'm not sure
if you but I'm sure it's x-ray CT
symptomatic later on when we see the
results of the new researches I hope
even more from the disease which is a
IBD inflammatory bowel disease and I was
diagnosed for four or five years ago and
I'm currently treated with medical
Mirada
with some other drugs and so my personal
experience as a user I can't really say
for a hundred percent percent that I'm
better because of the medical cannabis
but I can say that I'm very well
balanced overall and before I started
using medical cannabis it wasn't so it's
not an scientific proof but that's the
fact regarding what my grandfather said
in medical school we now learn more
about cannabis especially in the field
of pain and comparing to other pain
drugs such as opiates and stuff and I'm
I'm confident that our colossal doctors
to be will know more about cannabis and
will be more involved in this industry
which is the biggest problem with the
physician service medical cannabis when
they prescribe medical cannabis to a
patient you can get something something
that has 25
% HC and novel CBD or the opposite or in
the boot or in between and this is even
before he started talking about the
other compounds which are still in
research
when you say medical cannabis what do
you mean what what do you mean we said
that's exactly the problem
that is this is exactly the the problem
that I'm facing I need to know before is
double-blind for everything else I need
to know that I'm prescribing something
to a patient that he will get the same
thing every time which is not currently
not exactly the situation you cannot
give a patient just something it's there
it's medical cannabis medical cannabis
is not a medical term it's just a
general that we should know exactly why
we stand and we should try to push those
that prepare the drugs the growth of
those that prepare the drugs to have an
every single type of preparation whether
it's an oil whether it's a smoking
whatever the exact amount of a piece of
this at this point of THC and CBD maybe
later
other things but at least these two
because otherwise where we are not there
we are not in medicine this is not the
way to do it
[Music]