thank you so much for coming to can med
2019 and spending your day here with us
thank you for I mean even just showing
up to this panel it is not easy to show
up anywhere at 2:00 p.m. on a Tuesday
usually you know you've got work driving
your kids around to soccer practice
picking them up from school or you know
maybe you have to go to school and
you're here instead which is actually a
very very special thing the fact that
you are deciding to educate yourself
about the power of the plant which is
pretty phenomenal if I mean if these
people definitely are proof of that
you know educating educating about the
plant is the only way we're going to
tackle this industry tackle this space
and do it right education is the only
way before we go any further I'm gonna
introduce myself my name is Mary carrion
and I am a journalist and I've been
covering the cannabis beat for about
five years and I'm currently the editor
at Mary Jane where we cover everything
from culture and science news everything
in the candidate space if you don't know
us you should look us up you can find us
at Mary Jane comm so as I was saying
education is the reason why we're here
today and we are at a pivotal moment in
history where education is going to
change everything so like I said you
guys are here today to become educated
and we are here to talk about how
cannabis is going to be incorporated
into the education system and that is
historic we are everyone who is here
today is also making history and you
know the fact that we're able to sit
here in this kind of ballroom experience
is a very unique thing we wouldn't be
able to do this 20 years ago or even
less than that not too long ago we were
not able to do this so this is a very
very big deal being here today is proof
of how powerful lifting the chains of
prohibition is even if it's only a
little bit look how much we're able to
do look how much we're able to do with
just a little bit of leeway and imagine
how that's gonna be in 10 15 20 years
it's gonna be it's going to be a great
thing
another thing us being here today is
proof that the government isn't always
right
and the fact not that we need any more
examples of how the government isn't
right
but you know it's proof that there's a
need for it's a proof that there's a
need for education it's a proof that
there's a need to know about the plant
and move forward to progress into what
this whole industry is going to become
and I feel lucky to bring this kind of
education through a stacked group of
rock star panelists and I would like to
give them a round of applause
[Applause]
like I said they could be doing anything
today and they're here they're here with
us so that's a really great thing and
thank you all for showing up today this
is a really great experience you guys
are just as much of rock stars for
showing up and showing your love for the
plant so thanks for that and before we
get into our discussion I'm going to
briefly go over a PowerPoint just so
everybody is on the same page and we
know what we're discussing and yeah so
let's get into that all right so who is
on this panel we have well we originally
had some people on this panel but do we
have new people on the panel we have
Caroline McCallum who is here tell us a
little bit about yourself Caroline Allen
nope can you hear me okay sorry bit
closer okay hi everyone I'm Caroline and
I'm a physician I have done my specialty
training in internal medicine and I
focus on complex pain and I do addiction
and complex disease I formerly in my
training worked as a pharmacist and so I
bring a combination of skills and I'm
working out of Vancouver BC in Canada
and obviously we've got some some things
that are a little bit different up there
in terms of cannabis regulation so I'm
hoping today I'll be able to draw on a
lot of those experiences and perhaps we
can have a discussion about what
opportunities may be possible in the US
in the future yeah so having Caroline on
our panel with us is a phenomenal thing
because she's going to be able to
provide some differences in terms of
where the United States is currently
and where the United States can be later
using Canada as a mirror in terms of
education and the freedom that they have
up there in terms of cannabis and we
also have dr. David Berman in a minute
okay
that inauspicious beginning I'm a
physician I been practicing medicine for
over 50 years
part of that has been doing addiction
medicine I've been doing cannabis
medicine for 20 years as well as pain
management I in addition to being a
clinician about half my career has been
in his administrator at all levels of
government I am an author push in my new
book cannabis medicine I think a big
great text book it was written in
combination with the nurse specifically
with the idea of it being a textbook I
also have other books in the history of
drug laws and the way drugs have been
used in society and one of the things
that's disturbing to me is how little
physicians know about the
endocannabinoid system it's arguably the
largest neurotransmitter system in the
human brain central homeostasis
modulation speed of neural transmission
important in the functioning of the
immune system and it touches on an
enormous spectrum of illnesses and it is
frankly criminal that so few medical
schools actually discussed the
endocannabinoid system let alone talk
about the medical utility of cannabis
and that's very very true and now we
also have a doctor Tom foulin who is
joining us today and we're really
grateful he's here
thanks Mary yeah absolutely everyone
ComEd I'm excited to be here this is my
first year presenting on a panel you
will have the opportunity to hear me
talk later about cannabis hyperemesis
syndrome
the five o'clock panel and I was asked
in last minute to fill in for Daniel P
Emily who couldn't be here a little
about myself
I'm a neuroradiologist by training I
graduated medical school in 2007 and
through a personal story one of my
siblings became quite ill with northern
mewn disease and ultimately cannabis
proved instrumental in his
rehabilitation and continues to you
until this day as part of my second act
in medicine in addition to being a
neuroradiologist I maintaining clinical
practice in cannabis / cannabinoid
medicine my focus is on Leo blastoma
patients given my neuro Radiological
training and interest in all things
neurological but I'm also educating
myself and taking on clients with
anything from autism to low-level
anxiety to medication reconciliation in
seniors all things cannabis an
endocannabinoid system and just echo
what dr. yerman
and dr. McCallum were saying it is
absolutely cruel that we have physicians
graduating medical schools as I did in
2007 not learning a single thing about
one of the largest systems in our body
absolutely and that brings us pretty
much to our next point here is you know
the fact that the endocannabinoid system
is the large is one of the largest
systems in our body and in our brains
and the fact that no doctors are being
taught about this I mean that needs to
change given how many people are using
cannabis and some startling statistics
are the fact that only 13% of only 13%
of medical schools even mention the
endocannabinoid system according to a
survey by dr. David Allen and only 9%
report teaching only 9% of universities
report teaching about medical marijuana
according to Washington University's
School of Medicine and ultimately only
out of 172 medical schools in North
America of which 101 replied to a
specific survey 66% were 66% were
reported that they were not equipped to
prescribe
or even answer questions about medical
marijuana so 90% of doctors aren't
learning anything about the medical
about medical marijuana in school and
that's very alarming yeah I mean we
that's a problem that's a problem it
needs to get fixed and that's why we're
here today so that's that's really
wonderful and so we'll go through this
very quickly you guys but what is the
endocannabinoid system just to get
everybody up to speed is basically a
biological system composed of
endocannabinoids in the body which are
neuro transmitters that bind to
cannabinoid receptors through our
vertebrae yeah through our vertebrae and
through the nervous system they bind to
cb1 and cb2 receptors and yeah it's
again it controls homeostasis it impacts
that help a healthy operating immune
system and impacts our sleep health so
it really impacts a lot of things and
yeah okay so I'll just leave this on the
board for you guys for now but these are
the schools that are currently offering
courses on cannabis and these are not
all of them but these are some of them
and they are pretty major universities
but still not enough so now we're going
to get into some of these questions that
I have and for the first question I will
ask is for our wonderful panelists how
do the current federal how does the
current federal status of cannabis
impact the various forms of education
that you are allowed to pursue please
Caroline okay I'll start
so coming from the Canadian experience
from this angle I I was joking to Mary
when we were just chatting earlier I was
like what do you mean like how does this
impact basically it hasn't affected my
practice of cannabis over the past five
years because we've recognized at a
federal level a medical cannabis system
it has gone through multiple changes
over the years and now it's a lot easier
for patients to get medical cannabis
than it used to be the axis has has
evolved dramatically and we now have
over 170 companies growing met
Cannabis sorry they've been licensed but
in various stages of growing and so for
me it's been really easy honestly
however with legalization for
recreational purposes at a federal level
which occurred last fall in 2018 now
we're seeing even greater need for
education so I don't really feel like
I've had red tape in terms of my ability
to educate but just the need is just so
much greater and I think one of the the
big issues that I'm facing or just the
difficulties I'm having is with
redundancy so unfortunately we're not
speaking to one another at the various
levels so there are federal groups or
sorry like federal programs different
provincial or state programs different
associations and stakeholders and
universities all creating very similar
things and it's really unfortunate
because I just think we could combine
and be stronger and get more experts
involved instead of trying to do our own
version kind of on our own instead of an
a-team so I wouldn't really say there's
any barriers to to creating educational
opportunities in Canada but it's just
been that we're not really working
together as well as we could yeah and
you guys have the definitely a level of
freedom that we don't have here and that
freedom it I mean I'm sure that's
extremely overwhelming today it's more
than the federal government
it's the 70 year history of stigma
that's been attached to cannabis most
people are unaware that in 1937 the AMA
testified vigorously against the
marihuana Tax Act and in that testimony
said the AMA knows that no dangers from
the medical use of cannabis in terms of
medical schools most of them won't touch
talking about cannabis with a ten-foot
pole because many of them are reliant on
federal funding and they have no idea
what the federal government will do so
as the reason to hub up over whatever it
was that Trump did do or didn't do we
can see that there's a lot of subtlety
in terms of
encouraging or discouraging people do
certain things and medical schools are
discouraged from even doing research
about cannabis doctor Donald Abrams who
is an oncologist at UC San Francisco for
about eight or nine years submitted a
proposal to NIDA to demonstrate whether
or not cannabis was beneficial in
treating the pain and their neuropathic
pain from AIDS and finally the director
of NIDA said Don you have to submit a
proposal showing the dangers of cannabis
not the benefits because we're the
National Institute of drug abuse not the
National Institute of drug use so in
listening to researchers talk about the
difficulties that they've had they've
been enormous and it's very difficult to
even do research with whole cannabis
much of the research that's been done is
with isolates or with Marinol or with
CBD alone and as folks in nimbin which
has the longest drug war protest of all
second longest after Seattle they had a
sign there saying the plant the whole
plant and nothing but the plant and I
think that there's a great problem in
the medical schools utilizing the plant
the whole plant and nothing but the
plant and talking about the plant
they're much more likely to talk about
the pharmaceutical ization of this plant
and I think that also represents a very
in addition to the stigma and the money
that the federal government wheels so on
that note what do you thin of medical
education dr. fallin so I'll take this
as Mary pointed out earlier at 2017
study at have seen this University in
Washington found that mine percent of US
medical schools out of the 101 that
responded we're actually teaching
anything about the endocannabinoid
system and I believe another statistic
there was 85% of students didn't feel
comfortable I just
saying cannabis with their patients so
we have this really weird situation
where we have 33 states which have
legalized in the District of Columbia
and in many cases I would say most
everyone in this room knows more about
their local doctor does about cannabis
which is just an unacceptable and an
untenable situation and as dr. Berman
points out a large part of this has
nothing to do with the fact that there's
nothing to teach about cannabis or that
you know the endocannabinoid system is
not implicated in autism in fibromyalgia
in migraines it has to do with the
stigma that cannabis is a drug and just
like how we all are aware that NIDA will
not Commission a study or approve it
unless it is focused on the harms of
cannabis and we all heard from dr. Sulak
earlier today talking about a crutch
versus a tonic and you know these really
important key concepts for cannabis and
it just becomes increasingly obvious
every year that the status quo is
unacceptable but what does portend hope
and give us room for hope is as we see
on the screen here
all of these colleges that you know ten
years ago would not have been teaching
about cannabis or taking it seriously
the writing's on the wall so I certainly
think that nine percent number is going
to continue to increase and one of the
issues that has talked about with
incorporating this into the medical
school curriculum is well they say where
we're going to find the 10 to 20 hours
of coursework and no joke this is an
actual thing that's being discussed
even with pharmacy schools who are also
looking to incorporate cannabis
education what are they going to give up
so you know that's just where the the
the conversation is that but certainly
as we said given our increasing
recognition of the ECS it's plio
capacity the many different targets CB 1
CB 2 GP r 5 v t RP v all of these
receptors again there's just no way
we're going backwards on this so forward
momentum
so carolina tonight say one more thing
which is that the doctors out there
recognize that they don't know i've had
more than a hundred doctors in southern
Santa Barbara County refer patients to
me because they feel uncomfortable not
because just because of their lack of
knowledge but because
of the stigma that's associated with
this and I've tried to do see me and we
have done we've got an organization
called the American Academy of
cannabinoid Medicine if anybody wants to
collaborate with us from Canada we need
to have more of these kinds of
conferences and we need to integrate
this into like pain management
conferences and they have seen some
gradual improvement so I think that
there we are making progress but I'd
like to see it be a lot more rapid
because there's no excuse for the status
quo
absolutely and Caroline what is your
involvement in the education system in
the university system in Canada and how
is it there how is it how does it differ
from what we're doing here so I do
educate on a number of different levels
and with different groups of people yeah
I'm I'm really close is this on sorry
okay
okay I'm really close sorry
so at the University currently I teach a
couple of lectures for the School of
Pharmacy so particularly I'm working
with the they've got a pain curriculum
so I do a lecture there I also lecture
in there with some fibromyalgia and
other complex diseases in their in their
curriculum and in the medical school
actually not at the undergraduate level
but at the post get at the postgraduate
level I actually take the fellows in my
clinic so I frequently get geriatric
fellows pain medicine fellows I've had
an orthopaedic fellow also palliative
care so these areas are obviously areas
where we use quite a bit of medical
cannabis but I'm actually getting
interest from pediatric fellows so these
are residents and their final years of
training which is really great and so
they come to the clinic sometimes
they'll spend a few days maybe up to a
month with us and really learning a lot
about the plant and so I think that
that's been a really big win for us that
at the clinic where I work is actually
considered a clinical teaching site by
the University were recognised I'm
surprised that it didn't take quite as
much work as I
suspected they were pretty open to it
because especially in Vancouver where I
am there's just so much cannabis use
that's really what we focus on is that
your patients are doing this anyway
so let's try to equip the physicians
with the right information so I would
say those are largely the two areas I'm
educating but we really need to get it
into the formal curriculum so this would
be the undergraduate program like dr.
fallin has already mentioned but I am
teaching some academic cough days as
well so that's a three hour lecture
block that I get for those specialties
that I've mentioned so certainly we are
seeing some changes and that's been I
think really beneficial to show that
this is or certainly seeing greater need
and actually the fellows are going to
their program and demanding it so I
think that that's how it's gotta go I
can't just tell them what they need also
having the students recognize it as well
um one of the things you know we're
talking about professional training here
but there's no reason why this shouldn't
be taught in high school and in junior
colleges me what why should we wait
until people get to medical school or or
nursing school I mean we're talking
about a very amazing substance that has
this incredible broad array of
applications as evidenced by you're
talking about the different specialties
that come and see you and people doctors
are hungry for this kind of information
I had three physicians from Ohio that
spent several days with me I had doctor
from London that spent some time with me
and we need to set up more fellowships
and more opportunity not only for
students to learn by the what's your
method by by working with the doctors
that are that are in the field one of
the things that I might mention his
years ago I started a speaker's bureau
on sex education at the University of
Washington and the faculty OBGYN faculty
and psychiatry faculty said look the
amount
students are meeting once a month for
three hours to talk about human
sexuality don't you think we can have a
few more hours in the curriculum so I
think that organizing the medical
students to demand this or even to self
educate themselves by inviting people
like the people on the podium here dr. P
Melanie or what have you is one way to
help move things forward you also have
to have people on the inside like dr.
ple and like Bob Solomon who can lobby
for having more time in the curriculum
and has been pointed out here there is a
lot of competition for face time with
medical students on that note yeah
absolutely
what what do you think we can do to get
medical schools and universities to
teach about cannabis like what is there
anything that we can do either either
students or as professors or doctors so
I'll comment on that I think it's
already occurring right here in
California UC Irvine UCSD in UCLA
medical student associations focused on
cannabis cannabis as medicine there's
the canvas initiatives famously
occurring at UCLA with Shiva Cooper and
so this is generating excitement and
also by virtue of you know can Medicare
and all of these canvas conferences
people are actually approaching us now I
get many emails that and phone calls
texts like doc following we think what
you're doing is very exciting
you know I'm currently working at the
State University of New York I'm in
discussions with them about potentially
talking to their medical students about
cannabis so really just by virtue of
being an advocate for you know the
status quo for the fact that patients
are using this substance anyway
and really kind of just shaming the
medical establishment into understanding
that look there's two ways about this
your patients why are they going to use
cannabis and you're going to know
nothing about it or your patients going
to use cannabis and you're going to know
about it and you'd be you know with that
tact we actually are achieving progress
where we're all around the country I
believe just recently this month and
Florida one of the osteopathic schools
they're just incorporated the teaching
of medical cannabis for the first time
into their curriculum
I know Miami Dade Community College just
started incorporating some classes so
the change is occurring but it's
incumbent upon all of us to continue
pushing for this change to continue
talking about that you know as again dr.
Sulak mentioned today how cannabis you
know it changed my life and the amount
of times we hear this from patients is
just overwhelming in fact you almost
believe like it's a can report one of
you mentioned patients and I think that
that's an important focus you know in in
California we're the Wild West and a lot
of physicians that are making
recommendations for cannabis aren't
really practicing medicine
they're just minting money they're
spending 10 minutes or 15 minutes with
the patient and not fairly often some of
these patients come and see me and spend
another hour with me it because they
don't understand how it works
patients want to know how cannabis works
they want to know why it works they want
to know what it treats they want to know
what dose they should take they want to
know what to do if they get high these
are all things that people like those of
us up here that have worked with
patients over time have come to learn
and come to understand through hard work
through listening to the patients and
there should be a more solid foundation
for us to do this rather than having to
spend years of experience or digging
into dusty books to find the answers
that were that we're looking for we
really need to directly assault the
stigma remember that the marihuana Tax
Act was passed for economic reasons
because DuPont and the petrochemical
industry was concerned about competition
from him it had nothing to do with
marijuana just I think I'd be remiss not
to mention you know law schools as well
and so we're gonna start to see even
pharmacy schools and nursing schools and
and so forth them psychology and and and
the works but just to mention I weave
we're both recently talking about
medical legal cases and certainly the
need for physicians who are
knowledgeable in cannabis for a medical
purpose re for medical legal purposes so
certainly testifying and I almost get a
request every week for something of that
nature which is a huge amount of work to
do especially because you really do have
to be able to go through all the
evidence and and to be able to support
the case so I have also been asked to
speak for a lot of law societies just as
a as a as an evening event but I think
we're gonna start to see that in their
curriculum as well for sure so how
important do you think it is then that
medical schools and law schools and you
know the various forms of schools how
important it is for them to work
together well I suppose that the law
schools that they already are trained in
terms of dealing with substance issues
there's a standard textbook that was
written by the former dean in the law
school a bit Santa Clara Journal Dolman
and the you know just as McCallum
McCallum Calum I get a straight here
just like dr. McCallum said there are I
have spoken to legal groups usually the
groups of defense attorneys and the
interesting thing in regards to the
cases that I've been involved in there's
a couple of interesting things one is is
that you get exposed to things that you
wouldn't get exposed to in the clinical
practice of medicine you can ask some
unusual questions but the other thing is
how often the defendant is obviously not
guilty of the offense and I I've written
my reports in the hope of educating the
district attorney to get them to either
you know I have a more reasonable plea
deal or to drop the charges and
generally speaking I haven't been that
effective at educating the district
attorneys through my reports but there I
think it's critical for particularly
prosecutors and and law enforcement
personnel to be familiar with this the
other problem is is that we are stuck in
medicine with a lot of people who hold
themselves out to be experts and are not
and I know the California Highway Patrol
had such an expert I won't mention the
band's name but he created his own
research which wasn't very well done and
that was then integrated into standard
police policy he he was the guy who said
if you smoke marijuana you get a green
tongue can I have a show of hands of how
many people had seen green tongue okay
can I just add one more point on to that
because I think we could go all day you
just prompted me on a couple of other
things so I think what's really
important when you ask you know the
medical schools in the law schools and
and how that could happen
is that what I notice especially doing
the three cases I did one on impairment
one on anxiety and one on pain
specifically was that I really couldn't
give them an answer until I explained
the science of the plant like I they
just want a one-pager and it doesn't
work that way so in actual fact I was
really in Clutton for punishment because
the first case I wrote 60 pages and I
included a dictionary of terms
I had the ten clinical pearls that you
need to understand understand what I'm
even talking about and then all three
cases I was actually doing a rebuttal of
other physicians opinions which were
completely wrong they were psych
psychiatrists and so therefore the
person had anxiety so cannabis must be
inducing the anxiety not that she's
using cannabis to treat the anxiety so
really for law for them to be able to we
each have to help each other because
they don't even know the science yeah
absolutely
absolutely it goes back to also what you
were saying about there is no
communication happening between between
the various groups of people who are
either governing cannabis or teaching
about cannabis and there's
redundancy as a result yeah I just want
to piggy tell one point on that which is
that a lot of the there's a lot of work
going on like now with this
toxicologists called Ryan Moreno where
every day on Twitter he debunks these
news stories where police report that
police went to a site and he picked up
some fence Melanie passed out and he
overdosed and we're even seeing these
stories coming out of a defense Nilla
laced cannabis believe it or not where
was talked about and so it is incumbent
and especially important for those of us
within the medical community with
knowledge of cannabis to be active on
these forums and talking about the
ridiculousness and you know non
possibility of these things and also
just to add on as well they think the
current state I practice in New York
currently and in New York if you
recommend medical cannabis there's four
hours of required seeing me so in
addition to the medical schools and
teaching there we also want to be
teaching at the state levels but if you
have a state cannabis program
how are those physicians getting
educated at that point so in California
there is no such requirement and in
Canada there's no requirements at all
either to to authorize cannabis which is
very different when you look at programs
like suboxone programs or methadone when
you must have you know ten hours or
whatever number and so really this issue
of competencies and having standardized
programs that actually meet the needs
for the prescribers I think are very
important so yeah Tom that's a great
point just to caroline point in the u.s.
we can't call ourself prescribers
because it's utterly illegal to
prescribe we are merely the recommenders
that cannabis may you know may be
beneficial for you so yeah the reason
that we could recommend is that
fortunately the Constitution does not
say when you get your MD degree you lose
your First Amendment right to free
speech so if somebody asks you what do
you think about cannabis as a medicine
you can say I think it's great I think
it's awful I have no idea but the
government cannot put a gag
over you over your mouth forget what the
heck I was going to say we were talking
about prescribing and actually in Canada
it's called authorizing I Islip there
and I wasn't sure what how you guys word
it but basically because cannabis
doesn't have a DIN number so a drug
identification number which
prescriptions do you can't prescribe it
so it's not a typical prescription pad
you're using it's called an
authorization and so again speaking to
doctor Sulak this morning that like you
know these single molecules this is what
add in an infirm is really going towards
us making a single chemical entity
designed to work in a certain way on a
certain receptor which you know does
obviously work for a number of
conditions but for a number of the
conditions were seeing you do need a bit
of a shotgun approach and we don't fully
understand how the plant works but
that's okay because my patients have you
know ten to twenty symptoms I'm managing
and you know using 10 to 20 medications
just doesn't make sense and they've
already tried them and they're not
working so you know this idea of a drug
and prescribing even this kind of
nomenclature we're speaking cannabis is
just in such a different category it's a
different medicine it's really hard to
relate to it as you know how we've been
doing with other prescriptions because
the we have marginalized all plant based
medicine and I call that the cult of
modernism which came about in the 1920s
as we begin to marginalize plant based
medicine and rely more on single
entities one other historical note is
cannabis was in the United States
pharmacopoeia from 1854 until 1942 and
it was available in every drugstore in
the country matter of fact at the turn
of the 19th the 20th century cannabis
was the third most common ingredient in
patent medicines and prescriptions after
opium and alcohol so we and in the 1920s
American doctors wrote two to three
million prescriptions a year that
contain cannabis in fact my father was a
assist and he was at the University of
Minnesota School of Pharmacy in 1928 and
one of their assignments was to make
tincture cannabis and he said and we had
to be very careful because the alcohol
was illegal
[Laughter]
Wow Wow
so so there's a lot of Education that
happens between doctors and their
patients and there's yeah do you guys
mind going into that a little bit so
something I think is really important is
this idea of knowledge translation so we
can speak about the evidence here and
about studies and and high-level
discussions but patients don't
necessarily understand that language and
so it's how do we move this information
you know from from that area into the
general public and I think something
that I'm becoming a bit better versed in
is opinion editorials so I've been
fortunate enough in Canada to get a
couple published and so really trying to
tackle an area of controversy so I've
done one on psychosis in cannabis as
well as Pediatrics in cannabis so really
going for for the big areas of concern
and saying you know I recognize that
there's there's issues but hang on like
let's actually talk about this in a
logical fashion and bringing some of the
evidence into play that you know I can
make it such that they understand and
not focusing on all the nitty gritties
so I think that patients when they hear
it from that kind of lens that it lands
a bit better but certainly in our clinic
we spend 45 minutes with patients our
counsellors spent an incredible amount
of time and it's really challenging
because you know clinics you've just
mentioned a lot of them you know they do
it in a different way than we do it and
patients suffer when they don't get
adequate information and then they
actually end up coming to us because
they've taken too much cannabis because
they weren't taught how to use it and so
then their their gut reaction is I'm
never going to do that again and it's
really unfortunate because with some
education they could have a very
different experience so the patient
education is just so key and this even
brings into play what Dustin was
speaking about earlier lower dosing and
you know you don't need to be
and all those kind of controversy will
not really controversy but patience
concerns there the first thing they say
when they come in our clinic and we
really can't address them adequately
with with education I'll just I
completely agree I mean you know we're
learning you mean this is a can med
conference but just even to look at
psilocybin and what we're learning
they're equally important as the use of
psilocybin and something dustman again
pointed out to a set and setting and you
know the other key concept in campus low
and slow all these things were famously
we remember Maureen Dowd going to
Colorado back and whenever she went and
consuming a hundred milligrams of THC
and you know feeling like she was dying
and we don't recommend that okay we're
much on the order of one milligram
two milligrams if you're going to be
starting with an edible and then waiting
an hour and as Caroline pointed out we
do our initial intake with patients at
solace MD which is my cannabis company
we spend an hour just giving them the
lay of the land in terms of in terms of
what are your receptors what's your ECS
explaining the concept of bespoke
medicine explaining the concept that
cannabis is not one thing it's much more
than the THC and CBD you may have heard
about in CBD that's everywhere of
questionable quality and all these other
concepts but again in in the same way
that satin setting are essential to
psilocybin and therapeutic use the same
is true of cannabis and using with
intent and using the smallest amount
possible to achieve your desired outcome
one of the things I want to mention is
that probably the most effective thing
in getting physicians to recognize the
medical value of cannabis is their
patients asking them about it and I
think that one of the things that we
need to do is healthcare professionals
is to ask our professional schools why
they're not teaching about the
endocannabinoid system and about the
medicinal use of cannabis you know the I
remember scene in a cover article in
High Times in 1975
had a list of medical conditions that
they said that cannabis was useful in
treating and to tell you the truth I
thought well that's interesting that's a
nice tactic in terms of legalizing the
recreational use and then shortly after
that I looked at these things more
closely and the more I looked at it the
more I realized that yes all of those
conditions and more respond to the use
of cannabis and we are saddled with this
stigma because the laws have been used
to marginalize discriminated against
groups and that's not unique for
cannabis I mean it goes back thousands
of years to trying to marginalize the
pagans or trying to marginalize the
midwives that were known to the Pope as
witches
so dealing with the stigma is important
and what's really important is to do
what doctors up here have done and that
is to stand up and speak out you don't
have to be obnoxious you don't have to
be abrasive what you need to do is extra
lover choose of science and we are in an
anti-science era where 98% of scientists
say there is global warming and yet the
president United States is selling
plastic straws for $15 a piece that you
know leads me to a whole other question
and point is uh what responsibilities do
institutions have to help shape an
equitable future in cannabis I I'm an
idealist so I would say they have a
great responsibility you know one of the
things that's being discussed which of
course may be a little controversial is
the whitewashing of the cannabis
industry and the fact that we have so
many predominantly people of color and
Latinos in prison for maybe selling a
dime bag and yet we have other
enterprises that are predominantly male
predominantly white doing very well in
the nascent cannabis and
so certainly I think there's a role that
we don't whitewash or forget the history
as dr. Bierman has talked about that had
nothing to do with the health of people
are the safety of people are the welfare
of people and so I've again I've
encouraged as I'm sure all of us are to
go against the grain to continue asking
the questions to continue spreading
unpopular truths to get involved and
yeah I don't give the institutions and
in slack as we're learning but MIT
recently that accepted money from a
known pedophile
we certainly to be keeping an eye on
institutions and questioning where their
money is coming from and questioning
what their narratives are look let me
say also that one of the problems that I
think we need to fight in with cannabis
is the pharmaceutical ization of
cannabis you know doctor McCallum talked
about the difficulty in treating the
plant as though or a single molecule
medication while it's not and we've only
had single molecule medication since
1897 and people we have had some
breakthroughs these pre 1897 plant-based
medicines were effective for for many
things and I think part of the problem
and I hope I'm not stepping on too many
toes here is we have people who have got
their priorities reversed where they're
looking at making the money first in
helping the people later and frankly I
think you can do better for society and
actually better for your bottom line if
you put the patient first and that's
really what education of the medical
schools and nursing schools is important
so that we can put the patient first
yeah absolutely so what do interested
professor up professors and institutions
need to know before adding cannabis as
an option for degrees or courses
well one of the things that we should do
is to lobby state legislators in
medical-legal States for them to pay for
research about the endocannabinoid
system this will have people in the
medical school you know that have a
horse in the race
we also as dr. McAllen pointed out
should require physicians who are making
more than say a handful of
recommendations to have 8 to 12 hours of
continuing medical education and one of
the questions that we talked about in
preparing for one of the most important
things we need to do in order to get
cannabis taught in medical schools the
medical schools are very concerned about
how their students do in the national
boards so we need to lobby the National
boards to have a couple of questions on
the endocannabinoid system on the
national boards and one other thing I
want to say before I forget it is one of
the questions is what can we do and what
can you do and it seems to me that one
of the persons that has been hurt by the
stigmatization is dr. Massoud and I
think that what we need to do is lobby
for dr. McCollum to receive the Nobel
Prize for science so just another point
kind of on the same topic is also
considering other institutions so at
everybody give a round of applause to
Professor Robert Solomon who is at the
UCI Center for the Study of cannabis who
made it today and it's our big deal that
he's here who's not walking in late by
the way no nope uh-uh
absolutely not wonderful it is great to
have you here thank you thank you um
yeah so now that we have a leak a
clinical attorney present we can open
the discussion to the elements of law
that play into incorporating cannabis
into the education system okay I hope
heard the question right so it's in my
position
it's very different than when we talk
about education of cannabis at a any
different level because I'm at a
professional school and we care in very
rough terms about how to learn to be a
lawyer passing the bar exam and getting
a job and so I don't see cannabis law as
being any different than say sports law
or entertainment law it's a specialized
field where we have specialized
knowledge and I said to the Dean a few
years ago after attending a conference
we really need a course in cannabis law
because there are jobs out there and it
is a specialized field to which the Dean
said great you're right find someone to
teach it and so thus I offer the first
cannabis law course in the country at a
law school so why is it important well
for one thing this is a highly regulated
field and highly regulated fields mean
among other things full employment for
lawyers it is very hard to negotiate not
that that's a good thing but it is very
hard to negotiate this field without a
without a lawyer it's also true that we
have very specialized tax law affecting
you sought to pay taxes if you have a
sale of illegal federally illegal drugs
and there's very complicated law by the
way cannabis businesses paid 5.2 billion
dollars in taxes to the federal
government last two years ago probably
and most of that was guess what in cash
imagine going to IRS with bags of cash
we also have highly complicated internet
law which of which applies to cannabis
we have all kinds of rules affecting
investors that are not in other areas we
have incredible problems of local
control so the the cannabis board has
held that although localities can
prevent
distribution and growing they cannot
prevent deliveries in two municipalities
guess what happened 24 municipalities
are currently in litigation against the
state so local control is a major major
issue there's the whole question of
federal preemption and what it means law
students learn this right away then
there's the problem of driving under the
influence and what we mean by that and
how we will measure that and I have a
whole list somewhere on a slide I've got
it for you there's more and you know I
could I could teach two courses on this
frankly but large law firms are now
getting into the cannabis business and a
lot of it is similar to real estate law
except there are particular wrinkles
based on local local law and local
control so it's a complicated area it is
a specialty it's going to grow it's
inevitable absolutely thank you for that
so professor Solomon works with dr. paya
Mele at UCI Center for the Study of
cannabis which is very exciting and
together they are tackling the cannabis
space in a multidisciplinary fashion
with the law school the neuroscience
program and everything and it's they're
doing incredible work in fact their
school that they are putting together
might be you know a model that other
schools look to to figure out just how
to make it all happen so that's also
very very exciting and it's happening at
UC Irvine Irvine in Orange County that's
crazy it's a sign of the times oh my god
can I just say one quick yeah I gave a
talk at the Exploratorium in San
Francisco and as I was leaving the
subway the BART I could smell not the
subway I am from New York area you can
tell I could smell cannabis in the air
and hear the Grateful Dead and my first
thought was we're not in Orange County
anymore
[Laughter]
yeah that's great I was talking to mr.
Solomon on the phone and started to get
into some of the science and you
suggested I'm taking a risk here because
I'm going to
say that I'm not sure that I agree that
you felt that that defending or dealing
with cannabis was similar to dealing
with other drugs and I think that the
attorneys do need to understand the
endocannabinoid system need to
understand that THC is fat soluble in
order to do their job well and maybe you
have the same feeling and I
misinterpreted what what you said but I
think that some special additional
education is would be helpful to
attorneys in defending cases involving
Canada yeah we don't disagree and in
fact in my course daniele p.m. le
presents two sessions on the science and
our plan is next fall to to really
divide the course equally so the science
is critical my point was that the skills
are the same and trying a driving under
the influence of alcohol as drying
driving under the influence of any
chemical and the police aren't
particularly concerned with what the
chemical is we've had several sessions
with law enforcement and what they are
really concerned about is the field
sobriety test and the field sobriety
test is you know you've all seen this on
TV can you walk the straight line you
know there there is something funny that
they say there in fact it is somewhat
true a joke I used to tell that I would
rather have someone stop at a green
light and drive through a red light and
the police said that there actually is
some truth to that one of the tests that
they give is turn your head back close
your eyes and tell me when thirty
seconds has elapsed and people who are
under the influence of alcohol will
often go okay and it's like five seconds
and people who are under the influence
of cannabis or you know something else
suppressing their system will you know
be back there and after a minute the the
officer will say how long has it been
and they go oh gee only 15 seconds I
thought you know so so are the the
problem however according to tests and I
do want to say to credit police too
surprise they're very sophisticated
about this here incredibly sophisticated
really obviously getting good training
on the met on the medical side but they
don't care that much but the real you
well I'm talking to LA please so it's LA
and and Orange County but to them the
difficult part is changing lanes
changing lanes involves a lot of
executive functions and if you're under
the influence of almost anything that's
where the problems occur yeah I just
like to make a comment on that and and
while I agree with with the general
concept you're mentioning under the
influence it doesn't really matter what
the substance is however what my concern
is is if they start to do random checks
so somebody's driving appropriately
there's known signs of impairment and
then they're gonna start looking for
cannabis it's like well if you're going
do that then why don't you also check
for morphine and for anti histamines and
anti nausea and other medications that
we absolutely know could cause
impairment theoretically but you also
have to understand that a medical
patient who uses that medicine every day
has a very different situation going on
and this gets us into tolerance this
gets us into what's actually crossing
the blood-brain barrier and how their
executive function is so they really
need to be pulling over the right people
and not just okay we're gonna check
everybody for cannabis because it's
Thanksgiving weekend or something like
that I am going to take issue now
regarding the training of the Los
Angeles Sheriff's Department there is an
expert witness named Nick Moreau who was
a retired LA County narcotics officer
and he helped put together the drug
recognition exam and said that it has no
scientific basis there's also a lot of
criticism of the field sobriety test now
there is a new test coming out that
seems to have some merit and it's a
nickname druid Dr UID and it's the the
thing about the police out there is they
have a very low
are to go over they it's not the same as
being in court and this is what the
Chief of Police of Ojai said at a panel
that I was out we we don't have to prove
that the person was driving in the
influence beyond a reasonable doubt we
just need to have a suspicion I don't
know how strong the suspicion is and
that's a very very low bar and then you
start looking at the police report at
the driving in some instances there is
no description of the person's driving
all you have is that the person failed a
field sobriety test or in the case I'm
working on now they actually passed the
field sobriety test and they take a
toxicology screen and of course the DA
didn't go to medical school he doesn't
know how to interpret the toxicology
screen he bunny doesn't know that the
cabinets are fat-soluable and you end up
with the problem and this is not a
problem just with cannabis but when you
the to a hammer everything is a nail to
a police officer everything is a crime
so if you have a stroke if you have a
hypoglycemic episode if you previously
had a traumatic brain injury and now the
police officer stops you they are likely
to think that you're under the influence
of a truck and if you're a regular user
of cannabis which you might well be
they're going to draw your your blood
now I think one of the best defenses is
to ask for serial draws of your blood so
that you can see that the THC is coming
from the adipose tissue and not from the
result of having recently smoked a joint
Wow that's very interesting yeah that's
a great point I was gonna mention the
same thing like being fatigued you know
there's rules for how long you can't you
can't drive well you can only drive for
so many hours it's it's no different
there are medical conditions that can
cause impairment and actually my pain
patients say that they are better
drivers when they use some amount of
cannabis I'm not saying use cannabis and
drive but I think you need to look at
the full picture and really understand
what's going on and not have people in
court acting as scientists and and doing
all this yeah they can really make Mis
leading cause and effect and
associations and draw these conclusions
that that may not be their thang so I
have to wrap up here very quickly but
one issue that I have to ask in terms of
Education education across law education
across medical and in the United States
and in Canada how do you go about
educating about pesticides and
pesticides in products and pesticide use
among growing and also you know because
patients consume them well I don't think
until the US has federal you know
legalization you're gonna be able to get
anywhere with these these issues that
are very much all across the board
applies to all states it's not just you
know able to have an individual state
rules on these sorts of things then you
need to have mandatory lab testing more
than just pesticides now with with fate
you know vitamin E esters or acid eats
and all these different derivatives that
that can also potentially have long-term
outcomes we don't know
so needing to get funding for levels for
research so from we have cihr in in
Canada and you don't have to study abuse
you can study other other parts of
cannabis which is really important not
to just be focusing on harm moving into
looking at CBD looking at other things
and not just recreational use looking at
medical so I think that yeah it's gonna
it's gonna be difficult unless you're
United on on these issues in terms of
how you're gonna go about getting
answers yeah I'm in complete agreement
with Carolina and in fact if any of you
who follow me on Twitter will you know
have noted that I was recently arguing
with the Surgeon General about this very
point so where he was saying oh you know
these kids are dying from vaping the
marijuana cigarettes and the whole thing
and we're like well actually you're just
making the argument for federal tea
scheduling for research and for
regulating these products so that we're
not producing 5,000 of these vape
cartridges per week as was occuring in
the state of Wisconsin which wouldn't
you know what they don't have medical
cannabis so it turns out people are
resorting to these illicit products
because they don't have
says to tested regulated products and
it's way beyond pesticides we have
bioaccumulation potentially from
solvents you taint hash oil so that's
fine you use a vape in or whatever a
product with vho one time it's no
problem what if you're using that
product everyday for years at a time and
you have this bioaccumulation occurring
so really the way forward is D
scheduling research regulation and
testing when you take a look at the
newspaper articles the they are there to
sell newspapers they are not there to
educate people and they often don't read
the research they may read the press
release about the research and there
tends to be sensationalization people
have been vaporizing cannabis for
thousands of years I mean they found
things were was used in religious
services as an incense and so we've got
we've had the historic Bickle volcano
that's been around for 25 30 40 years
that uses the whole cannabis and they
are part of our problem in this country
is we really don't regulate it
industrial production of just about
anything that's dangerous as strongly as
it should be I mean one of the things
that I tell people who are questionable
about canvas they said it's too bad that
we don't have these same questions about
all of the other pharmaceuticals that
are on the market I'd like to see those
questions with the same intensity that
we had cannabis because I would feel a
lot safer as a patient we buy best
estimates we grow in California about
three billion dollars a year worth of
cannabis we sell legally about 1 billion
dollars a year in cannabis I was in
Berkeley this weekend and talking to
someone and he was telling me about his
cousin has a great business where he he
grows and he delivers to someone who
drives to Connecticut and I said that's
you realize that's not a legal business
and he said oh I know I didn't
like that he was a legal grower well you
know our other 2 billion dollars is
going somewhere and to make it worse
within the state we have created all
kinds of incentives to get license to
sell and all kinds of disincentives to
get a license to grow so there really
are incentives starting with tax where
there is a reason as long as you can
market your product to not market it
legally
and since the law requires a seed to
sale being able to track it it's only
the legal sales that are that are being
tracked that way so you know we are in a
transitional period we are everything
I've said is not not me giving a radical
opinion everyone knows this is the case
and so we need to start working this out
and we're still early in transitional
systems but somehow we're going to have
to figure out how to have a more
equalized distribution center system and
that is going to be based on a having a
federal policy that in legal terms
doesn't entirely suck because the
current policy is totally insane it
makes absolutely no sense it's based on
racism it's based on trying to suppress
groups of people it's based on putting
people in jail and it's based on the
just saying no policy well once you say
just say no you're saying abstinence is
the only thing that makes sense and that
makes about as little sense in cannabis
control as it does in birth control Wow
one of the things I'd like to mention
that that reminded me of is the stigma
extends to the highest levels you may
recall that former Vice President
Biden's son died cancer and they did not
use cannabis to try to treat his cancer
and he set up this program to take a
look at options and so I sent him a
letter and said you know you might want
to take a look at cannabis it wasn't a
you know outrageous or anything and I
didn't even get the courtesy of a
response
you really have to wonder here's a man
who lost his son to cancer and refuses
to even respond or have a staff respond
to a suggestion that they look into
something that we have known since 1974
can kill cancer cells and as dawn Abrams
has said there's more than enough basic
science research and anecdotal reports
to justify doing double-blind studies
and it seems to me we're thinking about
talking about teaching medical students
and nursing students pharmacy students
about the endocannabinoid system one of
the hooks to hang our hat on is the fact
that we know we can say for a fact that
cannabis will cure your Mouse's cancer
but we can't say whether it'll cure your
cancer as a human being because the
double-blind studies have not been done
except for one in England a glioblastoma
which was had some optimistic findings
that's about all the time we have for
today we could talk about this forever
thank you guys so much for showing up
thank you for being here