all right thank you very much
uh so uh i'm gonna speak about
metagenomics and capability response and
it's a big reach right now but hopefully
by the end of this i'll i'll convince
you that they're actually connected
uh so uh over a decade ago we started
sequencing the human genome across the
river a few people in this room were
involved in building
a uh a robotic field to basically
uh construct two football fields worth
of robotics it was in east cambridge
because the real estate was cheap and
that's an important point um
now that took us several years to build
the robots but in 10 months those robots
finished sequencing 40 million e coli
clones and we spent painstaking efforts
to make sure there wasn't any microbial
contamination in the human genome
reference
and that was important so that after the
human genome was complete we could then
study the effect of microbiomes on human
health and we needed human reference to
screen that stuff out
well everyone's probably familiar with
the mice transplantation experiments
where you can actually transplant
obesity from one mice to its twin by
moving the microbiome over
so it's very clear that this has a
profound impact on human health and we
need to understand these genes
there are more microbial genes on your
body than your own
but they're different genes they don't
have a lot of exon intron splicing going
on
so they don't argue we don't produce as
many proteins but they're still
nevertheless more cells that are
microbial in your body than human
so we want to pay attention to uh to the
microbiome now
fast forward to 2000 and oh i think i've
missed a particular
slide there but if you fast forward to
actually 2010 to look at cannabis
genetics i'm just going to step in here
and see if i can
resurrect that you'll see something that
doesn't look
as if it is that modern let me see if
this will
surgery will prevail here well
it won't so uh anyway what we see today
uh if you saw the picture behind this it
was actually two people in a hotel room
purifying dna in holland
because in 2010 we didn't need a
football field full of robotics you
could actually purify dna from from a
species in a hotel room
and get and get it to get to its genome
just by moving that dna to a sequencer
now in the process of doing that a few
years later we've been able to
actually throw some of these robotics at
the problem and ryan lynch is going to
be showing where these uh where these
robotics actually lead to
i think i've got it going right there
some of you saw the tour yesterday so
this thing is
basically running around sequencing
dozens of cannabis genomes to get us a
better phylogenetic tree
and there's a good reason for this uh
but a lot of this
effort is actually to drive it and
understand the genetics that drive
cannabinoid expression and terpene
expression
and perhaps a lot of other traits
perhaps flowering rates and oil and
how quickly these plants might grow we
can perhaps tag those things to genetic
variants and track them
um and we've particularly excited about
the changes that have happened since
2000 uh
even the year 2000 the human genome
closed the cannabis genome is not nearly
in as good shape as the human genome we
have the human genome probably down to
only 100 gaps right now and
the cannabis genome is far harder to
sequence it's probably the hardest
genome we've ever sequenced it's about a
billion bases in size
it's 65 80 which is a nightmare to
sequence just from a chemistry
standpoint
and on top of that it differs by about
100 bases whereas humans differ about
one in a thousand so
this is the equivalent of having chimps
being able to mate with humans and still
have
productive offspring so this is a real
challenge to sequence and only recently
have new
sequencing tools emerge to help us on
this now one thing we did learn from the
first time we sequenced this genome was
that the thc
synthase region of the genome was at 8x
higher coverage than the rest of the
genome
that stood out to us as perhaps being a
gene replication event that was
responsible
for secondary metabolite expression and
maybe was also responsible for
bringing us more thc synthase throughout
the selection and prohibition
all right but at the time we actually
couldn't properly sequence this because
we only had 700 base pair reads and the
gene was about sixteen hundred bases
long
and we needed to know the perfect phase
of this gene which meant we needed to
know which variants were resting on the
maternal chromosome and which were on
the paternal chromosome there's two
copies
of every chromosome in this plant and if
you don't know that and the gene happens
to have lots of variation in it it can
be very difficult to call the amino acid
sequence that's resulting from these
genes
so we knew there was gene expansions we
didn't know what they coded for and
there was naturally a question did these
other genes code for these other
cannabinoids
because we really only see two genes in
the genome that can code for
cannabinoids cbd synthase and thc
synthase
fast forward to today and we now have
these single molecule sequencers which
can luckily sequence 40 000 bases at a
time it's a real breakthrough
the challenge is they only have 85
accuracy so to
uh to get the accuracy to a place where
we want it to be uh we can play some
tricks with 40 000 base pair
read lengths is we can actually clone
this dna with some hair pins
and they call them smart bells and this
thing can then
run around like a hamster on a wheel and
sequence this thing around and around
and around like a circle
and give us a error corrected sequence
this is what we call a
circular consensus sequence and it does
this with these zero mode waveguides if
those of you familiar with microwaves
you may
see a screen in front of that microwave
that is to basically make sure the
radiation which has a larger wavelength
than the
diameter of the whole of that screen
doesn't emanate through it but what it
does do is it leaves a little finite
zeptolita volume of a radiation of that
wavelength at a pin point in the hole
and that pinpoint is so small that a
single polymerase can fit there
and we can watch that single polymerase
incorporate dna signals in real time
now just due to the nature of loading
these things about a third of them only
get loaded with a polymerase
i can read but nevertheless there's
millions of these holes we can read
basically the the thc synthase sequence
of dozens of cultivars to go
and as long as we run it around 20 or so
times we get the accuracy up to a point
where
it is acceptable to to understand the
amino acid sequence of all these things
so when we've done this on a many drug
type cultivars what we find is there's
actually
a lot of copies of thc synthase and now
we know the amino acid sequence of them
and we can determine which ones are
active and inactive and which ones are
still question marks
there are a lot of inactive copies that
are getting replicated these have frame
shift mutations and they probably don't
code for anything
there's a handful of other ones that
have single amino acid changes that
might have a different efficiency of
folding
the precursors or they may actually have
other side products that might
result in these other cannabinoids folks
have seen but lo and behold we still
only see two major dna or i'm sorry
synthase like compounds and some of
their relatives which
we could argue maybe can account for
about 10 of the cannabinoids and their
derivatives
but we can't explain where all the other
ones are coming from with just this
alone
unless the side product thing is real
now the other literature that's out
there are that that microbiomes
potentially transform these things by
hydroxylating different parts of the
side chain and maybe even
dr machulan was recommending that they
might hydroxylate some parts of the
terpene precursors
that would change the way that these
things fold albeit most of these papers
suggest it's at very very low rates and
yields that this occurs and that they
can't get enough of the material
to do any type of clinical study with it
nevertheless this is very different than
what we see in the terpene synthase
pathway the terpene synthase pathway in
plants looks a lot like a plant or
vertebrate gene it has lots of introns
and exons and we get all types of
alternate splicing
and it's perhaps this alternate splicing
that might in fact be governing
the diversity that we see in terpene
expression
so where did thc synthase come from this
is a very important
question there's a berberine bridge
domain in this in this gene
that we see in poppy which folds opiates
and we also see it up and down the
angiosperm line then there's some very
weak homology to bacteria and fungi as
well
and it kind of looks like a microbial
gene it has a start and stop and it's a
single exon
which is very interesting to us
considering some of the work that dr
mitchell has published on quorum sensing
with these compounds and that they in
fact might be antimicrobial
so these compounds look as if they are
communication vehicles to the microbiome
that might sit on the plant and that
could be very important to us
when we're trying to understand this
level of complexity of terpene
expression that can occur with these
multi-exon genes
i think we can understand a few genes
could do this if they had all types of
alternate spicing it's harder for us to
imagine 100 cannabinoids coming from
just two genes
with the diversity that's in there but
maybe that's what's in fact happening
so we need to know the the microbiome
then
of these plants and we set out to do is
design a test that could be used in many
of the states that are doing
uh mold testing and bacteria testing
we're mandating mold and bacteria
testing in almost every state that
cannabis gets legalized in
however the techniques that we're using
to measure this stuff do not really
identify what bugs they are they just
count colonies and it's about 100 year
old technology known as a petri dish
now culture is a very interesting thing
getting things to culture has maybe only
70 percent or less
of the microbes are culturable some
argue it's maybe even
lower than that and on top of that it's
not very specific carbon sources don't
give you the type of information that
dna does so
we designed a test that actually
operates off of the its region of the
genomes this is the part of the genomes
that put you on the tree of life so
they're highly conserved regions in the
ribosomal dna operons that you can land
primers on to specifically amplify
one of these one of these genre and
in doing so there's information inside
of here that if you were to sequence it
would give you
high specificity in exactly what genre
and species you're dealing with
so we designed pcr assays that target
this region and give us quantitative
information as to how much microbial
content is present on the plant
and once we have that if there's any
questions of one that happens to be very
high in signal
we can then go and acquire what it is
and we do that by sequencing these pcr
products and it gives us a little
microbiome
idea of what's going on in these plants
so now we have a nice picture
of all the bugs that might be on
cannabis plants and we can go through
and itemize them
and ask okay we see some aspergillus we
see some
some fusarium and some botrytis but you
know here's one girl scout cookie that
has a tremendous diversity and a long
tail of different microbes
and the other ones that are these ones
are a little bit older samples and they
they seem to not be dominated by just a
couple
a couple microbes a couple of them stood
out however because these ones we were
not finding on anyone's radar in terms
of being a problem
in healthcare or on the plants these are
penicillium species
and they don't grow very well in
traditional culture systems they need
different temperatures and longer time
for these things to emerge
lo and behold when we look at these
compounds and
i'm sorry these microbes and we try to
grow them we have a very difficult time
growing them in just a couple days these
are 3m
petri films that didn't grow them these
are biolumix cartridges didn't grow them
and these are used in mold things from
some plate that didn't grow them
we can readily see the dna this
naturally evokes questions whether the
bugs are alive or dead so we had to go
and confirm that we could in fact grow
these in the right conditions
and that if you ran the sequencing
before and after growth you could
actually see a shift in how these things
were growing over time
so that they are live we do know that
and they happen to produce these
interesting compounds
now whenever you do ita sequencing it's
standard to go back and confirm that
with a secondary assay that that it's
really species specific and you've got
the bug that you're thinking about
and so we targeted the paxilene gene
that actually makes paxolene in the
cytrinium gene that makes it
a whole genome sequence those genes
after we amplify them and prove that
they're in fact there
now what we don't know is how much
they're expressing but an important
point is these all look very lipophilic
and they will probably co-extract with
cbd
they also happen to be this one in
particular is a nanomolar drug
so a small percentage contaminant of
this can actually have a bigger impact
than cbd
alone because it's a potassium channel
blocker and it's been published to have
contraindications with cbd in mice
we have another one here citrinium or
this one actually is known for disease
called rye grass staggers and farms so
some cattle can eat rye and have some of
this penicillium on it and they'll
stagger around with some type of ataxia
this one is more of a nephrotoxic agent
that's actually involved
in a pathway that we know about from
roger pertue's lab in duncan ryan's
paper suggesting cbd actually targets
this region and the vdec 1 receptor in
the mitochondria
and so trinum seems to be playing some
role in there we don't really know
what role it is though so this set us on
a mission
with digipath to try to see if we could
detect whether the compounds are
actually there it's one thing to show
the genes there you've got to show that
it's actually expressing the compound
this can be very difficult in the
cannabis background so we started with
paxolene from sigma
and started spiking that into cannabis
matrixes to see if we can pick it up
and at first sight what we can see is
that we lose about five to ten fold
signal in trying to detect this
if we use the oulig method that was
described using an lcms
ms spectrum of this when we spike this
in we lose about five to 10x signals so
we're still working on how to do this
with the samples that we detected a
in a few slides prior but we now have an
assay thanks to
thanks to sydney's group that can detect
this we just have to make sure we have
the sensitivity to pick up stuff that
might be uh
nanomolar in concern so just to
summarize some of this microbiome work
what we have here is we've seen that the
culture-based systems are
basically screening things on any number
of colonies now this is not a very
accurate system
and we're quite concerned about this
because we don't know what microbes are
in fact
there as as we mentioned before 99 of
the microbes in your body are commensal
symbiotic
and harmless and we don't want to screen
those out we really need to get specific
about the ones that are a problem
and target the ones that are actually
human health risk and not just
start screening out microbes that might
the plant might need
our fear in screening out microbes the
plant might need is very analogous
if you had to live on antibiotics you
might screen out microbiomes that you
need to survive and we may create an
enormous genetic
selection against certain genetics in
the plant that can't make it through
this very grotesque screen
so what we want to do is dial in and get
much more specific with the dna
and hopefully fail less material and
only point out the ones that have health
risks
now what we've seen to date is we can
already tell that most of the yeast and
mold assays out there
when we see colonies on them we grab
those we sequence them and what we tend
to find are bacterias
bacteria that are native to humans and
are not harmful we see staph we see
pseudomonas
we see acne propion bacteria now there
are some pseudomonas we need to worry
about originosis and we have seen that
on occasion
on on some cannabis samples but
generally it's a ubiquitous form of
pseudomonas it's not a concern
likewise with with the acne samples so
we need to be aware of this there's the
flip side of this coin is that a lot of
bugs do not culture at all and we've had
samples that are
totally loaded with mold that you can
see with your own eyes and they don't
grow at all
dna certainly uh picks these things
right up okay so
this was published and thanks to some
people in the audience john
mcpartlin really deserves to be an
author on this paper because he gave us
such an incredibly constructive review
and i really like this mechanism of
publication because of that because the
reviewers really
actually do strengthen the paper but
this is a
paper where you can review a lot of this
work and see what we did to compare this
to
a variety of different culture systems
so i'm going to flip this over to human
genetics which is five and a half
percent of the human population are
going to develop a genetic disease at
some time in their life
and this is uh it could go as high as 60
over time
and so we want to understand those
genetics because if we're going to be
applying cannabinoids and perhaps some
mitochondrial transformed cannabinoids
onto humans we want to understand
the genetic diversity in the patients uh
that this might apply to
um so in doing this we primarily been
focusing on mitochondrial dysfunction
and we did this for a reason
it does have some inroads into the ecs
and the reason uh this is a very
productive place to start sequencing in
the human genome
is that most of healthcare is very
skeuomorphic in that it is designed
according to anatomy we have cardiology
we have nephrology we have neurology
these are all organ systems that we've
built healthcare silos around and
and when you're dealing with a
disfunction in the krebs cycle it is
very agnostic to which organ it is in
it can bounce between any of these and
that creates an enormous expense in the
healthcare system that likes to
specialize based on organs
so patients that have this type of
dysfunction can sometimes take six years
to get a diagnosis and an enormous
number of bills and of course this this
leads into
seizures because your brain is two
percent of your body weight but twenty
percent of your energy consumption so if
you have a mitochondrial dysfunction
it actually can find its way into pain
into gi issues into
seizure disorders and into asd and
developmental delay
so we've developed a lot of these panels
to target these different regions
they're going to be spoken on a little
bit later
but i think the the really exciting work
that we're seeing and this is published
by bernard
a few years ago is that we are seeing a
lot of cb1 localization to the
mitochondria
in neural neural cells about 15 percent
of the cb1 receptors sit there so
there's definitely connections
and there's something going on there now
why do we want to know this genetic
information
we want to know this genetic information
because we're finding a continuing
growing list of genetic
contraindications or indications
particular genetic variants
okay so the sodium channel one mutation
is probably the most well-known in this
audience because this is one that that
signifies dravet syndrome
and although people in the past used to
avoid sodium channel blockers this might
be a signature to actually
move on or go directly to epidiolex or
cbd because this is these patients are
responding the best in those studies
we also love glucose transporter
variants that are indicative of a 90
response rate with a ketogenic diet so
if you have that variance you might as
well drive go right to a diet change and
that may
it may help with the patient there's
these polymerase gamma variants that you
want to avoid with vulpric acid if you
have this variant and you're given
depakote you can destroy your liver and
you end up with a 500
000 liver transplant all right this is a
very important thing to find out
and and you want to know about it before
you jump on to depakote
um there's other other indications with
gaba receptors and steripental and
calcium channels changing this but i
think the one that probably resonates
the most you may hear later is that
there's a vitamin
b6 form of epilepsy that if you have a
mutation in this gene you can treat the
patient with vitamin b6 and you get a
very good response right
and this is a form of epilepsy that if
you treated it with cbd you might
actually just mask the problem for six
months and
honeymoon out of it and realize you
should have had b6 six months ago
uh so that's one that's that's that's
that's it's on our radar quite a bit
so how do we go about doing this some of
you wanted the tour yesterday won't
spend much time on this uh we basically
have been sequencing panels and exomes
predominantly panels first in pediatrics
just due to the fact that when you
sequence whole exomes
you can uncover a great deal of
information about people that never
consented to being sequenced in other
words their relatives
when you find apoe variants or bracket
variants in these pediatric patients
that implies some other family members
may have some risk as well and so
acmg prefers that you you dial this into
panels first and expand
exomes later but the most important part
of the technique that we're running up
there
outside of the analysis that goes on is
in the laboratory it's a very condensed
laboratory because every patient that we
sequence
we hydroxy methylate their dna in the
active amplification so that dna is a
femoral and gets just self-destroyed in
the process of sequencing
and that's needed so that we never
contaminate someone else's dna with
another and it makes the lab footprint a
half the size
and it's been published in nature
biotechnology it has some implications
for it for um
uh gene patents as well um as i
mentioned earlier uh
this is uh the progression we tend to we
tend to start with is maybe 500 to a
thousand genes that will sequence we try
to dial this into just the genes that
are in the literature that we know are
connected to the particular phenotype
and uh if we don't find anything there
there's a possibility of expanding to
exomes and the difference between panels
and exomes
it's just besides the box that you order
these days
these things put out 250 gig in a shot
and these do about 10 gig in a shot
now inside this panel there happens to
be 39 uh different genes that we know
are really
tied into the ecs we have many of the
sodium channels
we have the v deck one uh receptor in
here you can see cenar one senior two
pha
maggle daggle mtor and a lot of these
other ones uh particularly the p450s
that are of importance
this is not all of them we think the
list is probably about 175
long but we're not sequencing those
other genes right now because it's tough
to find any clinical correlation with a
variant in those genes to it to an
actual human patient
i think in time that will change um so
when we do this
i want to touch just briefly i think i
have time on the p450 system here
um it is well known now that uh that cbd
is uh effectively like a grapefruit
juice warning on a drug
okay so it is a potent inhibitor of sip
3a4 and 2c19
which means if you have drugs that have
grapefruit juice warnings on them
grapefruit juice has bergamot in it and
that actually goes through except three
four and inhibits it
um cbd will slow down the metabolism of
other drugs
uh clobazam or onfi is one that was uh
seen in in the epidialex trial that this
can actually
escalate that in the blood and this is a
pro drug so when you when you change the
metabolism of a pro drug you're you're
slowing down the conversion of the drug
into the active form
and it can it can lead to some
complications same is true with cars
carbamezapine both of these drugs i
would caution just
to make sure that you have your hla 1502
variant sequence because they're both
known to actually trigger
stevens-johnson syndrome which can have
30 mortality rate if you're not careful
not very frequent in our population very
frequent in asian and in the pak rim
populations
uh so so p450s are important because to
know this
helps you understand how all of these
drugs are going to bounce around with
one another and most
patients with epilepsy are on three
drugs if not more
so what we do is we provide these tables
of drug drug interactions that if you're
on cbd what are the other drugs are
going to go up and down in the blood
according to the known literature
and of course which variants are
involved in the metabolism of these
whether they're fast metabolizers or
slow metabolizers
and this may help guide treatment
optimization uh of course we also
sequence the entire gene
and that's important not just nailing
these snips but when you sequence the
entire gene you might find frame shift
mutations in that gene
that are going to basically reverse the
if this is a fast metabolizer genotype
it's not a fast metabolizer if there's
actually a frame shift next to these
snips and so that can be important
information to capture with whole genome
sequencing
and we do see that stuff on on the
panels okay so i'm just going to wrap up
with what you can do when you
get to a pace of doing about a thousand
patients a month like we're doing up in
woburn
is that serendipity will have it that
you'll sequence some patients that are
actually
in current clinical trials and so we
tried to organize this a little bit
better than serendipitous serendipity
and we called up warren davinski and we
called up eric marsh and a few others
and said hey can we sequence the
patients in your study
hopefully to get to a common
polymorphism that might predict response
there's been great success with
epidialics out there
but there is a small subset of patients
that get worse
and when they get worse in epilepsy they
can be intubated you can end up in the
er
you can end up with status epilepticus
this can be very expensive and so we
want to see if we can dial that in
and what we have found to date is only
55 patients have been sequenced to date
and with those 55 patients we're
starting to see some signals although i
will caution you and david goldstein
would chime in here saying anything
to 10 to the minus 4th could be a
synthetic association and you need more
patience
but nevertheless the the snips that are
coming out of this
are implicating a handful of genes that
may have
a predictive value on the response to
cbd
now what's interesting is the ones in
yellow up here have some published links
to anandamide and that is actually
enriched next to any everything else
that's in the panel
that we that the genes that are falling
in as the top values here
actually have published links so that's
very interesting but we need to do more
and we just uh started on this doing
more with
um mgh we have an irb study approved to
sequence 55 more patients and mgh
interested in elizabeth thiel and david
friedman down at nyu
have been doing some work showing this
endes metal club exam escalation with
cbd
is real and traceable in the blood we
don't yet know if it's
if it's correlated with those genotypes
and that's what we're going to get at by
sequencing these other 55 patients
there's also another 50 patients that
we're bringing into the irb from
university of alabama birmingham i
believe some of them are here in the
audience
thank you for for joining us uh and we
have an irb that's also grant approved
uh now from chop they just received
another grant to sequence 50 more
patients so in the end we'll have
another 155 patients
hopefully that will be enough patients
to decide whether this is real or
synthetic
and we may have a marker that can help
predict cannabinoid response and maybe
teach us a little bit about
what's going on with with the esoteric
nature of cbd
now to do this correctly you need a team
of genetic counselors and there's
something on the x chromosome about
genetic counselors
um i don't know what it is yet that's
going to require a bit
a bigger study um but all of the without
these people we would never get any of
this done
it's a tremendous team up there that has
a real
interest in personalized medicine and
there's a lot of external people as well
they've been helping us on this
including internal people
uh i want to have um some call-outs to
digipath and cindy orsner she developed
that lcm sms technique
um now there's going to be some
presentations a little bit later from
ryan lynch
talking about the work we're doing with
the list exchange and genotyping a lot
of these plants to get a better
understanding of the drift and the
plants
and of course uh i want to call out doug
smith who's been doing a lot of the work
on the gw
study with oran eric marsh and and
russell senato uh
peter doherty with uh with roberto who's
been doing work on getting this to the
market
uh jessica avon and wendell and lay
they're all here doing work on various
aspects of exome sequencing and
microbial genetics
christina and adrian adrian did a lot of
work on cbd synthase and single molecule
sequencing with us over the summer
christina's been helping on exomes as
well
uh ben john and viscio as well have all
chipped in and likewise some of our
friends at
sc labs have helped us getting very
interesting genetics to sequence so with
that i will leave it for
questions
[Music]
we have time for just a couple questions
and we'll break for coffee but if
we could take a couple questions for
kevin if there any please
let's go ahead he will be available at
the coffee break as well to answer
uh and answer any questions you might
have
any questions john sir over here that
was a great presentation kevin
um speaking to the mic a little bit more
i will speak into the microphone
there we go okay so thank you michael so
with the interaction of the microbiome
and its potential
pathogenic nature in some cases
do you anticipate remediation or
sculpting or remodeling of a microbiome
for a particular cultivar
so that's a very good question um it's
early days and and we're hoping it may
help in just uh
perhaps bio moniting in in growth rooms
and to understand if anyone has
particular infections or blights that
this will be a helpful tool just to
understand
um understand that domain there is
definitely literature on using
bacillus to knock out botrytis and
bacillus is harmless
and uh and that's um that's interesting
to us i mean i think it's an important
point because when you look at food
we take these tests and we go into the
supermarket and start testing cheese
yeah you get a lot of cfu's some cheese
but it's not it's not harmful to you you
know
it's basically one big ball of microbes
um and so
uh i think we have to be rethinking the
the colony forming system because it's
not giving us information with any
specificity about what to do
if you have high cfus but i think it's
still early
as to doing what you suggest i'm hopeful
we can figure that out
one more question sure hi fred
vogelstein at wired what's it cost
to have your genetic test so the genetic
testing costs can vary depending on
whether you're just doing the microbial
sequencing up into whole exome
sequencing but i would say the gamut can
spread from
some tests that are 500 up to like 15
000 depending on how many genes you're
sequencing these are insurance
reimbursed
usually uh and so you know with that
there's some limits on how much
i can never get back to the patient due
to out-of-pocket expenses
thank you okay thank you
you