hello everyone thanks for coming and
seeing my talk here appreciate it hope
everybody had a good lunch
so microbial inoculation of clonally
propagated plant starts so you know I
consider this more of a white paper just
so I think everybody in the room needs
to be informed you know we're non
scholar you know really honored to be
here in you know this facility with this
crowd and you know this audience we
really have a passion for cannabis and
the scholarly side of it is something
that we really just have enjoyed as a
fan base and really using those as tools
to advance our learning so appreciate
everybody in this room in this community
a lot I'm Daniel Hendricks I'm the
co-founder and CEO of Hendricks farm
we're a cannabis clone nursery so we're
located in Humboldt County we have four
operating partners all of the founders
were born in Humboldt County we are
commercial nursery so what we do is we
create clonal starts for other
businesses in specifically Humboldt
County but all around California we have
our annual license right now there in
the beautiful redwood rain forests of
Humboldt County and people have rather
enjoyed our services and we're really
grateful for that it's our community and
that's kind of how we discovered this
opportunity to do some research into how
we can maybe contribute to a better
product and just a more environmentally
sound cannabis industry so in Humboldt
County it's the redwood rain forest
mycelium connects all of these trees
they're able to talk and communicate
with each other what they do is the
signal to each other you know pathogens
nutrient exchange a lot of really
amazing stuff so underneath our feet is
this web of really intelligent
you know bacterial bio technical
applications and I don't know how
trained everybody is I'm sure everybody
has
a really strong understanding of some of
the stuff but I'm gonna go over it
anyways just give some general terms so
raizo bacteria are root colonizing
bacteria that form symbiotic
relationships with many plants so in
other industries this is a really common
application plant growth promoting raizo
bacteria PGP ours have been reported to
support plant growth suppress plant
diseases and increase the yield
productivity of many crop producing
plants so in all other agricultural
industries this is really common
they inoculate their crops they see
different kind of agricultural results
and you know the term plant growth
pronating right so bacteria is just an
attractive you know acronym we want to
see our plants perform better and maybe
this is a good opportunity for us to
discover how so like I said non Scholar
the the way I was introduced to these
kind of concepts you know was from Jeff
Lowen fells and Elaine Ingraham you know
I worked in the cannabis industry as a
pot grower you know for over 20 years
and it was around 2014 I started to get
my curiosity going about what other
types of applications whether other
industries could help influence the
cannabis industry because I believes
legalization was gonna have a major
impact and the cannabis was going to be
a big part of our economic success in
California in the country in our
community and humble so the concept of
the soil food web is to me common sense
you know the big things eat the smaller
things and specifically right there at
that bacterial point you know the
bacteria are able to digest and make
more available all of these amazing you
know phosphates all kinds of nutrients
supply that's already there in your soil
so the bacteria is able to break that
down and deliver it to your rhizosphere
to your roots of your plant now that is
amazingly interesting ok so
I get introduced to this concept and
here we are I'm working at Daisy supply
in Humboldt County we're sourcing
nutrients for other farmers on the
emergence of legalization and with that
came a lot of companies wanting to
introduce their new products
everybody had a new product a new
solution that was going to recreate
cannabis and one of the most interesting
that I encountered back then was this
bacteria roto Pseudomonas palustris so
roto Pseudomonas palustris is a
gram-negative non sulfur purple
rod-shaped bacterium found both in
aerobic and anaerobic environments so
that means it can survive without oxygen
that alone is a pretty exceptional
testament to this bacterial strength and
how to use it in cannabis well we wanted
to find out you know the evidence so
there was this product that was being
used in the agricultural industry and
our customers started to attract to it
they wanted to use this bacterial
inoculant and they were claiming these
amazing results this bacteria has
potential for bio remediation it breaks
down waste in polluted environments
that's been proven it can produce
hydrogen as a result of nitrogen
fixation nitrogen fixation is pretty
incredible it can fix nitrogen and
create that nitrogen to make it
available to your plant it produces ATP
which the plant uses as energy and it
has the capacity and the capability to
fix carbon dioxide as a biomass through
photosynthesis so that was really struck
me as amazing this bacteria you know is
able to absorb parts of the light
spectrum that the plant can't your plant
really only needs is they only able to
absorb that central portion of the light
spectrum right there in the visible
light spectrum but bacteria they're able
to convert infrared or ultraviolet light
and use it as an energy or a food source
so roto Sena Moniz palustris was able to
use that energy infrared and ultraviolet
to food their feed their food source and
fix carbon out of carbon dioxide out of
the atmosphere and so your plant doesn't
have to expend energy to fix carbon wind
roto Pseudomonas palustris is doing it
for you so your plant may use that
energy to produce biomass produce
cannabinoids we don't really know so
this struck me is really interesting
right and as most AG products enter the
market there's not a lot of testing so
this AG product this company saw an
opportunity in cannabis and they made a
cannabis specific product which was a
diluted roto Pseudomonas palustris and
they had a consortium of bacillus other
things and they suggested a dramatic
increase in the usage of the product and
that was one of those moments where I
froze I said I don't see any evidence
why we should be increasing the usage of
this bacteria so drastically just for
cannabis I felt like that was kind of a
ploy to use the product more so I wanted
to see some studies being done so in
2014 I took a break from the product but
I continued to take an interest in what
advancements were being made in cannabis
that might help justify use of these
products so one of the papers written
that I really enjoyed by max Winston and
a number of other authors they published
in Chicago but the studies were done
here in California understanding
cultivar specificity and soil
determinants of the cannabis microbiome
so the rise of fear what max and his
colleagues were able to establish is
that rhizosphere bacteria will colonize
root tissue okay that's a that's a great
start
we know that cannabis in the rhizosphere
bacteria will actually colonize in the
area and also move into the plant tissue
he did a study with Sour Diesel
kukuku sh Burmese cultivars Maui Wowi
and white widow
and the objective was to understand how
that soil bacterial presence was going
to be distributed into the plant if
there was a synergy or capability there
and what effect that might have on
potency so what he discovered was that
the competent composition of the soil
and the cultivar specificity determined
the microbiome so what cultivar or clone
you might use is going to determine what
bacteria the plant allows to come out of
the soil and become part of the actual
colonize the actual vascular root tissue
he discovered that cannabinoid
concentration in composition was
significantly correlated with the
structure of the under eye so community
so what he found is certain bacterial
presence in the soil were also
associated with certain cannabinoid
concentrations really interesting stuff
right
ok the bacteria in the soil are going to
help us determine what our potencies
might be what other terpene or
cannabinoid profiles might be present so
the composition of the and erisa
communities also suggested root decay so
in one of his studies he wasn't able to
get to the end erisa root tissue until
eight weeks later weren't sure if how
that overall affected some of his
results but a really great paper open
source really helpful for years later
Mary Ann Scott published in the Canadian
Journal of microbiology along with a
number of other of her colleagues at
McGill University published this paper
endophytes of industrial hemp cannabis
sativa cultivars identification of
cultural bacteria and fungi in leaves
petioles and seeds
so with these hemp cultivars Yvonne
crs-1 unka they took the plant tissue
from the leaves petioles and seed
embryos and did an analysis they wanted
to see what was there and what was
present naturally in this hemp cultivars
natural biker biome
and what they discovered it was really
interesting and also caught my eye
thinking about this roto Pseudomonas
palustris so 44% of the natural
microbiome in the leaves were
Pseudomonas and 16% were bacillus in the
petioles 39% were Pseudomonas as well as
a presence of bacillus bacillus made up
18% of the seeds and we actually didn't
see as much Pseudomonas within the seed
embryos so for me you know I I like I
said I'm not a scholar I look at this
and I say well there's a tremendous
opportunity you know if naturally the
microbiome already is made up this
Pseudomonas taxa then we probably have a
good opportunity that to see that it
might uh adhere and be able to colonize
the cannabis root tissue the highest
abundance of bacterial strains isolated
from leaves where isolates of
Pseudomonas and bacillus respectively
that's a quote from Maryanne Scott's
paper and there's a phyllo tree I know
you can't see anything but that does
show you know all the different species
and strains that are present there the
most frequently isolated endophytes
belonging to the gram-negative genre
Pseudomonas 35% in Penta way a 17
percent and the gram-positive genres
stefa locus 16 percent and bacillus 9
percent so again I read this and I'm
getting excited I know of a product that
you know needs more research done on it
and really we want to see this kind of
synergy at our facility so looking at
this you know table here we have several
bacteria these are the back some of the
bacteria Genesis that were present in
this study and these different
biochemical applications cellulose
phosphatase ACN sodaro for production
organic acid production we see that
Pseudomonas I can get this to work
has a presence of all of these different
biochemical applications so
it has a positive association there
vassilis like i went to the next screen
vassilis was able to be really you know
efficient here at this phosphorus
conversion so that was one of the most
like powerful clues for me that hey this
might have an effect down stream with
you know flower development and flower
potency efficiency so in this paper she
establishes there's an immense abundance
of Pseudomonas and bacillus in the
natural microbiome that makes me feel
like this is maybe a good opportunity to
try these different inoculants and also
ethically it feels like i'm not
introducing anything to foreign this is
something that it's already common with
in cannabis her study also used only
hemp cultivars so as a THC cannabis
clone producer i was curious
does this work with THC or is this only
a CBD you know hemp cultivar application
there was another study done in 2018
that is not open access so i didn't
share a lot from it there but it also
further established that finola hemp was
highly receptive to PGP ours in seedling
form so in their study they inoculated
seedlings found that those bacteria were
easily able to colonize colonize the
vascular root tissue and establish a
presence within the plant the other
thing that they were able to establish
it was that there is a significant
cannabinoid increase that the plants
that were inoculated with the bacteria
had a cannabinoid increase Wow I think
that is really powerful stuff so our big
concept PGP RS can increase the yield
and secondary metabolites of other crops
is this same true for medical cannabis
cultivars so this was our moment to say
okay how can we contribute and how can
we make our product better for our
farmers down to down the line so we took
one of our clones and we introduced a
cannabis root inoculant
we went back and we had the opportunity
now to test this product that so many
years ago hadn't been tested and let's
see let's see if the results can match
the potential so naturally like I said
we saw a tremendous justification for
using Pseudomonas and bacillus roto
Pseudomonas palustris has been
inoculated in grain and demonstrated a
9% yield increase now that could be
something that would be really
beneficial to our farmers a 9% yield
increase affects your bottom line and
that's really powerful bacillus subtilis
bacillus mega terraeum and bacillus lay
conformists they're all able to promote
plant Ruth health and stimulate root
hairs cells increase nutrient
acquisition so in our experiment we took
the products m3 otic plus it was a
product that I said had been built
specifically for the cannabis industry
and we wanted to see if any of these
claims of the productivity and other
crops could be applied to cannabis so we
made three inoculum we had a control
with no treatment at all we had a one
ounce per gallon which was the minimum
suggestion on the bottle and then we had
a one quarter ounce per gallon
suggestion as well in the finola
experiment we also saw that there was a
max point that you can use to much of an
inoculant in which case their results
demonstrated that yield and potency
actually might go down if it's used in
excess so there we are at ramblin rose
farm as another licensed producer in
Humboldt County I don't know why oh it's
up here on this screen you guys can see
the Humboldt County outline that oh
that's where we're located in Humboldt
County Northern California ramblin rose
as well as the producers of this
bacteria that's CC with Simba's we're
all sitting there pondering the
potential of these results all three of
us were blind to the study we only had
one person at our facility that knew
which batch was inoculated so we had no
clue which
which batch contained the inoculant
which ones were the control there's us
taking some of the sampling this was
actually not the official sampling we
did some early sampling tests as well
just to compare the lower and the top of
the plant see different kind of potency
results as well so the results were
really amazing
we saw positive results across the board
and just to demonstrate right here lower
twin X got the highest total harvest had
the highest trim weight as well as the
highest flower weights lower twinsie we
had the lowest total harvest weights and
lower twin or lerton y and lower twins
II was second with 500,000 375 grams
over here is the potency lower twin x
overall combined potency THC and THC a
was seventeen point nine seven lower
twin y fifteen point two seven and lower
twinsie fourteen point six and so we
would hope that this would help us clue
in that maybe lower twin x was the one
that contained the inoculant so this is
the overall weight that combines trim
and flower and this is a bar graph of
the potency and so yes we find that
seventeen point nine seven this highest
potency was lower twin x this received
the highest inoculum floor twin y
fifteen point two seven that received
the 1/4 ounce inoculum so the minimum
strength inoculant and then this was the
control so really nice cascading graph
there that was really pleasing
especially to the farmer who got an
eighteen point seven five increase in
THC and THC a combined versus his
control and found an overall harvest
yield increase demonstrated significant
nine point nine percent so you can
imagine these kind of results scaled the
cross and
tire acre you know if we should get so
lucky is to be able to repeat something
like this that might be really powerful
so some of the other things that you
know come up in this discussion we still
we found an increased yield and we found
an increased potency in our test trial
and we don't anticipate that this is
gonna be uniform we we're gonna need
lots of other studies to verify this but
there's so many other potentials we
found that in the tobacco industry
they've been dissing roto Pseudomonas to
test its validity as an inoculant
to prevent tmv tobacco mosaic virus
right after our paper was published and
testing and terpene magazine another
paper was printed in 2019 further
exemplifying that we need more research
on specifically these two bacteria so
dong my Lu excuse me for mispronouncing
his name if I did that he wrote this
paper along with his colleagues plant
growth promoting rise up bacteria for
cannabis production yield cannabinoid
profile and disease resistance and that
just immediately left off the table I
read it worried that he'd beat me to all
of my research but he was actually just
helping us justify further that research
needs to be done specifically on these
two so the potential role of PGP ARS
focused on two genre Pseudomonas and
bacillus in his paper and he predicted
that it will achieve higher yields have
more desirable cannabinoid profiles as
well as disease resistance plant growth
front is the same paper so biological
control in deeds disease resistance
associated with PGP ours
powdery mildew in blight control well
these things are virtually unexplored in
cannabis production you know these
bacterial inoculants may have very
powerful defense mechanisms against crop
crop damage that everyone in this
industry is experiencing so you know we
see this as just further justification
that the small bit of research that we
do we've done needs to go a lot further
and it could potentially you know affect
more than just our yield and harvest
quality it may have affect the overall
health and disease control within the
industry as a whole
so it has capabilities that potential
you know as a plant pathogen defense
roto Pseudomonas palustris has been
researched as a plant defense and bio
control induction of plant resistance of
tobacco music mosaic virus infection so
it would be really powerful knowing that
this tobacco mosaic virus right now is
causing problems within the cannabis
industry be great to see some defense
mechanisms against it it could have a
huge environmental impact so similar
crops inoculated have demonstrated
higher yield with less water and less
fertilizer usage roto Pseudomonas it has
the potential to retain moisture so
during those drought periods crops tend
to have a lot less stress and a lot less
stress effects based on the fact that
the bacteria are able to retain the
moisture within their own body and as
they die they release that moisture back
to the plant so it helps mitigate stress
and then of course quality and yield you
know Pseudomonas and bacillus inoculate
has potential as an affordable and
environmentally friendly application so
you know all we had to do in order to
see these results in the field was make
a very very small maybe two gallon batch
of this inoculant and just submerge the
plants and the root tissue in it we
never went out and inoculated in the
field we never did anything different
with any of those crops all we had was
the single stage so the farmer didn't
have to do anything different and what
an amazing you know potential result
thank you we really appreciate you guys
coming today this is some gelato grown
by
ramblin rose farm they did a wonderful
and beautiful job and if you have any
questions you'd like to get ahold of me
there's my information thank you
[Applause]
if anybody has any questions I know in
California you don't have to test for
total aerobic bacteria but have you
tested to see if this increase in
microbials will artificially inflate
total testing no I have it and that's a
really good question I've been asking
some of the testing companies if they're
able to identify between you know plant
growth promoting bacteria and you know
potential harmful pathogens and that's
not really something that they're doing
right now so that that is a really good
question and definitely something that
we all need take a look at yeah her
point yeah a lot of the testing labs are
doing plating at least where I come from
in Massachusetts and plating is
notorious because I can't tell the
difference not only between bacterial
strains but even live and dead bacteria
mm-hmm so it's caused a big issue so I
think it would behoove you to have
really a ready answer for whether
possibly this bacteria could in fact
cause a failure and a test to take place
because it's an important question but
my question is really when you're
applying this inoculant do you have any
notion of the degradation period of the
bacteria in other words like how long
after exposure is is the bacteria going
to be soluble it's and without being
decorated right yeah I I'm not sure it's
a really good question you know I know
that the product that we use is
guarantees a shelf stability for 18
months before you open the bottle and
then once you open the lid it guarantees
another six months where before the
bacteria starts to degrade so this in
this case they stabilize it in a liquid
and so by having in a liquid they're
able to actually have the community feed
and continue to grow
it's on the shelf but I think that
ultimately we have to take a much more
scientific approach to answer some of
those questions all those bacterias need
to be individually studied in different
combinations of those consortiums need
to be analyzed so we can actually try
and determine what bacteria are even
contributing and I and I would love to
work with you know any of the
intelligent minds in this room and at
this facility to help answer those
questions Thanks
yeah thank you let me say I thought it
was an excellent bit of research my
question for you is do you have research
plans continuing forward yeah I don't
think we've framed those plans yet you
know we kind of put this together as a
white paper I didn't even really
necessarily think that it was gonna be
something that we've even developed into
this you know kind of a publication or
this kind of an opportunity and I think
that you know we like I said being non
scholars we really want to look to the
community to see well what what
weaknesses you know are we presenting
here in our approach and and how can we
make it better so we're open to
suggestion okay
I'm dr. Roger Kern I am a plant
scientist and microbiologist originally
out of UC Davis I'd love to sit down and
just talk with you about where you see
things going yeah we really appreciate
that thank you
look forward to that hi Daniel
can you talk to root exudates as far as
a mechanism for stimulating the ribosome
to be more productive for the release of
nutrients back into the root system I am
not qualified I you know I I definitely
enjoy you know all the literature but I
wouldn't say that I'm qualified to
actually answer that question
thank you yeah thanks thank you
everybody really appreciate it
[Applause]