my name is George Fernandez and I'm the
founder and CEO of modern Canada
Laboratories modern Canada's reputation
speaks for itself and we've built that
reputation over the years not just
through fast turnaround times and good
service but also by providing reliable
data that our clients can count on when
samples comes to the laboratory it is
our responsibility to ensure that they
are safe for human consumption it's
about accuracy it's about
reproducibility and reliability modern
Canada was founded in 2014 we were the
first lab involved in rural development
we're the first lab to test medical
marijuana in the State of Florida
something else that we take great pride
in our clients know that our data is
legally defensible and that it's
reproducible this is an industry that's
changing it's constantly evolving so you
have to be nimble you have to be able to
Pivot quickly adjust to new rules and
regulations in 2019 we found out that
the state was planning to require a
variety of microbial analyzes and so
when that happened we really needed to
start looking more into what provider we
were going to use what vendor we were
going to go with what technology we were
going to go with at that time we were
doing plating and we were having a lot
of inconsistency with reproducibility of
data contamination and so we started
looking at microarray versus qpcr and
medicinal genomics had done the work to
understand and know these assays that's
not something that every vendor could
provide and that was when we decided
medicinal genomics was going to be our
partner we used medicinal genomics
products to test for microbial
contaminants in our extraction process
we're isolating the DNA from there we
then tested for aspergillus species
salmonella shingotoxin E coli and yeast
and mold besides those we also test for
viruses and gender testing through
medicinal genomics the important part of
isolating cannabis DNA in the process is
that it serves as an internal standard
and allows us to ensure that our process
worked so if there's no microbes present
that we can confidently say there was no
microbes present this is a big benefit
over something like plating where you're
not able to have that internal control
you can plate a sample and something
won't grow and you may think it's safe
however if that plating didn't work you
really don't know if the product is safe
for human consumption one of our
favorite features of medicinal genomics
is our fast extraction process when we
have busy days in 80 to 100 samples
there's a lot of work in micro being
able to streamline our process is
extremely helpful using medicinal
genomics in their qpcr platforms really
allows us to have that confidence in the
data we're reporting it allows us to
know for sure that that sample is clean
and no one is going to be harmed when
they consume it I do a lot of
troubleshooting across the lab with
various instruments and different
chemical processes for the different
tests that we do within the laboratory
medicinal genomics has been a fantastic
partner providing technical support do
very good difficult to do my job without
having them in place the future of
Cannabis Testing is here to stay
third-party testing is going to continue
existing so that people can work out the
Kinks and figure out the regulations and
the standardization when it goes
recreational the market is going to be
booming and if Labs don't have the
support and the standardization that
they need they're not going to be able
to handle the sample volume of such a
booming Market we want to be number one
and I think that with a partner like
medicinal genomics we can do that