hi everyone and welcome my name is Jenny
Glaros and I am the CSO at modern can
labs which is a third-party testing
laboratory located here in Florida today
I want to talk to you about a topic that
I am very passionate about from the lab
testing side of things because I think
it is very important for what we do in
the industry and also very important for
cultivators to be able to understand
moisture content so if you're a
cultivator you're a grower um you're a
lab a lot of labs are reporting anywhere
from 12 to 15% moisture in flour and a
study we have conducted has proved that
this may not be a true representation of
water content in
cannabis so let's Dive Right In what is
moisture so the FDA usfs no OAA if and
EPA all Define moisture as the water
content that is present in a sample so
looking solely at Water how much water
is there cannabis creates some
difficulty because it is volatile has
lots of volatile and semivolatile
compounds so we have cannabinoids we
have Turpin we have flavonoids we have a
lot of other compounds present that may
or may not be factored into those
moisture calculations depending on how
you're analyzing for moisture
moisture so this is kind of where our
study originated from so aoac is an
organization that's a standard
organization and they are in the process
of creating a cannabis PT and with this
cannabis PT and hemp PT it's a real life
sample so a lot of the pts on the market
you have to do manipulation of them you
have to change them you don't follow
your standard protocol this is different
because it is a real life sample coming
in and you process it as you would a
normal sample so with the AC pilot data
we saw that Labs reported moisture is
anywhere from 6% to 16% that is a pretty
drastic range and even the like average
rain looking at that three sigma data
ranges from about 9% to almost 14%
that's still a really big range for
something that should be the same sample
so the question is why and how is that
happening before we talk about the
different techniques for analyzing for
moisture I want to paint a picture for
why it's important to understand water
content and what the impact is of
varying moisture results so here I have
a table that's going to show you various
analytes and the impact that moisture
and dry weight correction has on those
results so when we look at something
like total THC we see we have an asre
received value of 20% that's what the
lab tested it as if they dry weight
correct that to 5% that number goes up
to 21 then to 7% that number number goes
up to 21.5 and then if they go to 15%
that number is suddenly
23.5 so as a cultivator or producer you
of course want that 15% moisture because
you're going to get a higher THC however
is this an accurate representation we
see the same thing happening with tpin
where an as received tarpine value may
be 1.5% and by time you dry weight
correct that to 15% you're now seeing
1.76% moisture we we also have some
contaminants listed here and
contaminants kind of are the
double-edged sword of moisture
Corrections right so if we're looking at
arsenic um in Florida the regulatory
limit for arsenic is 200 ppb so in this
sample lab received and had an as
received value of 180 ppb so when they
dry weight correct that to 15% moisture
that value is now 212 so now a producer
is failing so we really need to
understand an accurate moisture content
in order to get an accurate reported
value for producers Growers on what
their sample actually would be we also
have a pesticide example here seeing the
same thing that regulatory limit is
3,000 ppb so we see that if that as
received sample came in at 2700 it's
failing if the lab is reporting a 15%
moisture so how can you analyze for
moisture well there's a variety of
techniques in the industry and I've
included five of the main techniques
here so first we have Carl Fisher then
we have vacuum oven vacuum desiccation
loss on drying at high temperature and
loss on drying at low temperature in the
next few slides we're going to cover all
of these and give you a little bit of a
deeper explanation of how each of them
are done first up we have Carl Fisher
titration and this is the gold standard
of Botanicals and agricultural agents
but it's difficult to do so what labs
are doing is they're performing a
titration on the sample in order to
determine the amount of water that's
present based on a reaction that occurs
what's really nice about Carl Fisher is
because you're looking only at water
molecules and the reaction of water
molecules it prevents any of those
volatile and semivolatile compounds from
being factored into the moisture
calculation however one of the big
downsides is it can be very expensive
for Laboratories to utilize a caral
Fisher instrument can cost anywhere from
about $50,000 to $775,000 and then you
have consumables that go with that so
Laboratories who are trying to make
money chances are this is not a
technique that they're going to be able
to use and still make money and profits
on their samples we then have vacuum
oven and this is where uh this is
actually from the European pharmacopia
and basically the sample is placed in an
oven at a low temperature in this
instance 40° C under vacuum for an
extended time period to slowly evaporate
all of the water from the sample and
with this we limit the loss of volatile
and semivolatile compounds because we're
not heating it to a high temperature
however some of the negatives of this
are that the method does need to run for
24 hours which can decrease the lab's
throughput depending on the size of the
vacuum oven that they're utilizing if
they can only fit so many samples and
they have reruns it can affect their
turnaround times then we have vacuum
desiccation so this is similar to the
vacuum oven except for the fact that
we're keeping things at room temperature
and we're utilizing desicant to help dry
it out so a vacuum pump and a desicator
with absorbent desin in the bottom you
then place your sample in there and you
suck off all of the water um this is
great because it prevents all of the
loss of those volatile and semivolatile
compounds by keeping it at room
temperature or theoretically should help
limit it the most um however since that
sample is not heated there is a chance
that some of this water that's trapped
is not going to be fully removed so we
need to take that into consideration as
well then we have loss drying at high
temperature and this is pretty much the
universal standard of what Laboratories
are using most Laboratories in the
industry are using a loss on drying at
high temperature and what they're doing
here is they're heating a sample to a
high temperature normally above 103° C
to remove the water granted you see Labs
that heat anywhere from 103 to 150 and
that can impact those results the higher
the temperature the more the volatiles
you cook off so we need to understand
that impact and this is an effective way
to do moisture because you're ensuring
all of the water is being removed water
boils at 100° C and it's a quick process
however this temperature utilized is
drastically impacting those semivolatile
and volatile compounds that we know are
so prevalent in
cannabis then we have loss on drying at
low temperature and what this does is
it's very similar to that loss on drying
at high temperature except we're
limiting the temperature at what we're
heating the sample and in this instance
80° C and the reason for that is that we
know cannaboids start to decarbox at
about 85° once they've sat for a certain
period of time so we can prevent that
decarbox of canabo by doing this it is a
quick process so that's nice for
Laboratories and most of the water
should be evaporated at ADC however this
temperature does lead to some loss of
volatile and semivolatile compounds
because those tpin if you smell them in
the air it's because they're
volatilizing so at 80° you're definitely
going to start volatilizing those so
what did we want to do to compare all of
these methods and ultimately we wanted
to design an experiment that was able to
assess all of these Methods at once on
the same samples at the same time this
has been a really big complaint for the
industry is that when you're doing this
oh well you analyze Carl fiser on day
one but you analyzed loss on drying at
day five the moisture changes from day
to day so how is this comparative and
that's ultimately what we wanted to
eliminate we wanted a true comparative
study of samples the same day the same
time analyzed across all five of these
methods so the goal was to analyze at
least 100 samples we ended up with 120
samples total for this experiment and we
analyzed them via all five of those
moisture techniques so Carl Fisher which
was the oven was at 100° vacuum oven the
oven was at 40 degrees vacuum desig at
room temperature so 22 degrees Celsius
loss on drying at high temperature at
103° C and loss on drying at low
temperature 80° C we also wanted to run
each of the methods nine times in order
to get a comparison to measure the
reproducibility and variance from method
to Method one of the complaints we've
heard in the industry is that some of
these methods you run them and your
results change drastically from run to
run across the same sample so we wanted
to see are there any concerns for that
and finally the really big part of this
study was that we wanted to process a
subset of the samples for cannabinoids
and tpes pre and postanalysis to
understand what is happening to the
product when you're drying it in these
manners what decarbox silation is
occurring what turpine loss is occurring
and that's really the big overarching
goal was to truly understand what was
happening to the chemical makeup of
these
samples so first up I'm just going to
show some brief moisture comparisons
these are just uh we're going to have
three slides of these I chose 45 of the
120 samples and whenever you're looking
at this you can see that those three
bars that are about the same are going
to be the loss on drying at low
temperature the vacuum oven and the
caral Fisher and for these across all
120 samples we saw an average moisture
for and these are all dried cured
cannabis it should all be fairly similar
um so when these arrived we saw a
average moisture content across all
120 with the loss on drying at low
temperature of 7.4% moisture the vacuum
oven we saw 7.7% moisture and the Carl
Fisher we saw 7.3% moisture so that's
pretty impactful because across all
threes of these methods we're seeing
very similar moistures well within a
percent of each other however when we're
looking at the other types of testing so
the vacuum desiccation is yielding an
average overall moisture of about 4% and
the loss on drying at High tempure is
yielding an overall average moisture of
about
12.5% so this is a pretty big variance
so what is happening and why is this
happening before we look at a sample
through the entire process comparing
decarbox silation and Turpin I wanted to
do a quick review of the reproducibility
here so you can see the reproducibility
study yielded that all of these methods
really are reproducible within
themselves Labs if they're running them
should be able to get reproducible
results we have standard deviations well
within the expect expected range of what
a lab should be
validating so what are our initial
takeaways our initial takeaways from
this are that the vacuum oven the caral
Fisher and the loss on drying at low
temperature methods all yielded results
that are similar the vacuum desiccation
results appeared to be skewed slightly
low about 2 to 3% compared to the other
three methods that were uniform with one
another and then loss on dry at high
temperature results appeared to be
skewed High about 4 to 5% compared to
those three methods yielding the similar
data there was also no specific pattern
uh amongst those three similar methods
of which resulted in a higher or a lower
moisture so we weren't seeing a trend
where Carl Fisher was always the lowest
or vacuum desiccate or vacuum oven was
always the highest so it did fluctuate
and I think that that is going to be
very well explained in the next several
slides when we talk about decarb
oxolation and tarpine loss and then at
the end of course all of those methods
produce data that is reproducible
against itself which indicates that a
laboratory should be able to get
consistent results internally if using
any of these methods so there shouldn't
be this conversation of oh I used loss
on drying at high temp and one of my
samples was 10% and one of my samples
was 15% that's not what we should be
seeing if people are processing these
methods
correctly so let's do this full
comparison for an individual samples so
we are about to go very data heavy um so
just bear with me here
so first up we have the cannabinoid
decarbox silation so what I have in this
image is a zoomed in image looking at
Delta 9 and thca and I have an overlay
of all of these methods and I've
attempted to color code them so
hopefully you can tell the difference in
the colors here but what we can see in
the table below as well is we have the
OG which is going to be our as received
so that's a sample as it came in
analyzed it didn't manipulate it in any
manner and we saw that the thca was
20.5% and the Delta 9 was about 4% so
then we ran all of our different methods
and we looked at what those percentages
would be of the thca and the Delta 9 and
you can see here that that vacuum
desiccation sample really didn't change
much we still have
20.3% uh thca and about 0.5% um Delta 9
the loss on drying sample though that's
a little concerning that's at pink Peak
so when we're loss on drying that sample
at a high temperature of 103 we are
almost completely decarboxylating it so
you can see there that we now only have
about
27%
thca and now we have
17.4% Delta 9 UM loss on drying at low
temperature had minimal um degradation
and decarbox silation of the
cannabinoids similar to the vacuum oven
interestingly enough Carl fiser did see
more decarbox silation however what we
know about Carl Fischer is that it's
only looking at water molecules so
theoretically even though this decarbox
silation is occurring it should
shouldn't be factored into that moisture
calculation and that is why we're seeing
a similar result between that loss on
drying at low temperature the vacuum
oven and the caral Fisher because that
decarbox silation is not being factored
in on the next several slides we're
going to review the total percent
decarbox silation and so in order to
calculate that we looked at the actual
decarbox silation divided by the
theoretical decarbox silation multiplied
by 100 and that theoretical decarbox
silation was calculated based on what
that as received sample would be if it
fully
decarbox so you can see here the vacuum
desiccation sample this is a
chromatogram at what we refer to as a 1x
so our standard prep so do not be
alarmed of how big that thca Peak is we
are definitely not quantifying off of
that we run a second dilution but I
wanted you to be able to see the big
picture and also be able to see those
minor cannabinoids and how they're
impacted so what we're looking at is a
pretty similar chromatogram between the
as received in the vacuum desiccation
we're not really seeing much of a change
here we are seeing that THC Peak drop a
little bit and the Delta 9 Peak increase
a little bit but overall these
chromatograms are very similar we then
go to the loss on drwing at high
temperature we're not looking at a
similar chromatogram this chromatogram
is now very very different in addition
to having the thca PE Peak be almost
non-existent and the Delta 9 Peak being
huge we also have CBN being formed so we
know that Delta 9 as it breaks down it
forms CBN so we also have other decarbox
silation products occur occurring the
cbga in this sample also decarbox into
CBG loss on drying at low temperature
very similar to what we were seeing um
with the L on dry or the vacuum
desiccation sample where we're not
seeing too much decarbox silation but
some I also have those total decarbox
silation percentages on the bottom of
each of these
slides the ased um versus the vacuum
oven again very similar to what we're
seeing so we can tell from these methods
that we're seeing limited decarbox
silation across those three methods so
the vacuum desiccation the vacuum oven
and the loss on drying at low
temperature we get to the Carl Fisher
and we see a little bit more decarbox
silation occurring so this one we saw
about 37% decarbox silation um so not
anywhere near what we were seeing on
that loss on drying at high temperature
but some the sample is being manipulated
in some ways there is being a chemical
change
occurring so next we wanted to look at
tpine loss and wanted to understand what
that impact may be on the samples as
well so we analyzed for Tarpin again the
very similar procedure where we looked
at the you know original ased tpine
content and then we measured the tpine
content after analyzing via each of
these methods and what we can see here
is that we started out in this sample
specifically with about 1.6% tpin the
vacuum desiccation sample resulted in uh
having a remaining turbines of about 87
the loss on drying at high temperature
had absolutely no tpes left the loss on
drying at low temperature had about. 5%
the vacuum oven about 3% and the Carl
Fisher about 0.5% as well and similar to
what we did with the decarbox silation
we also want to look at the percent
tpine loss so how many Tarpin were lost
overall so that total tarpine lossi
divided by the total Tarpin as received
times 100 on each of these next slides
so here's the zoomed in chromatogram of
each of these and we're going to start
with the as received versus the vacuum
desiccation and what you can see here is
the really big peak that looks the same
in each of these as our internal
standards so that is good that should be
there um but the rest of these analytes
we can see that a lot of these tpin are
starting to drop and starting to
disappear however one important thing to
notice is that the tpin in front of the
internal standard drop off more than the
turpins behind the internal standard and
that's based on the heaviness of those
tpin and the volid volatility of those
tpin so the higher the boiling point the
less they're boiling off in these
methods or the less they're coming off
in volatilizing and this one this is at
room temperature so it's all just
volatilizing based on that vacuum you
being
utilized whereas those lighter ones we
are seeing quite a bit of degradation
still we then looked at that loss on
drying sample at a high temperature
there's absolutely nothing remaining
there may be a little itty bitty baby uh
alphab Biz Biz aolo Peak but um
definitely below our detection limit for
quantifying so those results ended up
indicating ating that that was
Zero then we looked at the loss on
drying um at low temperature compared to
that as received and we saw something
similar to what we saw at the vacuum
desiccation but because we're adding
heat a lot of those early looting tpin
are almost completely gone which is what
you would expect you're adding heat at
80° in this and so those Tarpin are
saying bye we don't stay here anymore
and no longer in that
sample then we have the vacuum uh oven
sample and so this one's heated to 40°
and so we did surprisingly see more loss
in this than we did at that loss on
drying at low temperature and I think
that this can be explained by the amount
of time that it takes so the loss on
drying at low temperature that sample
only takes about 14 to 15 minutes to
analyze however this loss on drying
because you're doing or this vacuum oven
sample because you're doing 40° C you
have to leave it under vacuum for much
longer so those Tarpin are being pulled
off of the sample then we had the Fisher
sample which again it is experiencing
that loss to you are heating the sample
to 100° C however what we know about
Carl Fisher is that those values are not
going to be factored in unless water
molecules are being formed and I think
that's an additional part of this
investigation right is what water
molecules could be formed in any of
these caral Fisher extractions and could
that be impacting
things so as kind of a summary of this I
wanted to paint a picture for
understanding the total weight loss via
each of these methods so here we have
the moisture obtained by each method
along with the weight lost by decarbox
silation the weight loss by turbines and
the total weight loss this is exactly
how much what percentage of the weight
is lost via each of these methods so you
can see when you're running that vacuum
desiccation method you obtain a moisture
of about five close to 5% and we're
experiencing a total weight loss of
about 0.9%
um we then moved to that loss on drying
at high temperature yes we're getting a
moisture of 133% but the total weight
loss contributed to the decarboxylation
in tpin is over 4% so if you think about
samples where you have high tarpine
content and high THC content that number
could be even higher when we're talking
about that total weight loss we then
have the loss on drying at low
temperature sample we got 88.3% as our
moisture obtained and then we saw about
1.2% loss the vacuum oven we got 7% and
saw about 1.3% loss and then the Carl
Fisher we got 7.72 and saw about 2% loss
so interestingly the caral Fisher did
yield the second amount most amount of
loss yet its results still line up
really well with that loss on drying at
low temperature and the vacuum oven
which further indicates that the caral
Fisher is not factoring in anything but
those water
molecules so what are some of the
conclusions we were able to establish
from this study first is going to be
that there is significant decarbox
silation and loss of Tarpin with the
loss on drying at high temperature
method and so overall what we saw in
average across all of the samples that
we looked at for cannabinoids which
ended up being about 30 samples um we
saw that the loss on drying had an
average decarbox silation of
87% and had an average turpine loss of
93% so that is very impactful uh for
understanding those results then we had
the Carl Fisher and it did exhibit the
next largest amount of decarbox and
tarpine loss and so for that sample we
saw 37% decarbox silation on average
along with 69% turpine loss however
those results were not drastically
impacted by that which lends to the
understanding that the Caro Fisher is a
gold standard kind of method when
looking at something with a lot of
volatile compounds the vacuum dation
samples did experience the least amount
of decarbox silation and tarpine loss so
on average the decarbox ation was only
1.7% and the turpine loss was about
55% however there are concerns that
those samples are not being brought to
complete dryness because of some of that
water may be very well Bound in the
Cannabis and we're doing some additional
experiments with that where we're taking
the samples analyzing them using the
vacuum desiccation and then putting them
on the caral Fisher to see what it
indicates as far as what moisture may be
remaining in those samples and then
those that finally that loss on dry at
low temperature the caral Fisher and the
vacuum oven results are on average
within 1% of one another and I think
that this is really impactful for the
Cannabis industry um not only because
we're limiting the decarbox silation
we're limiting the turpine loss but it
also gives us a way to make method
recommendations for what people should
be utilizing in the industry and so
ultimately the final takeaways are that
Laboratories should be using something
like Carl Fisher the vacuum oven or the
loss on drying at low temperature when
looking at moisture content and based on
this study we are you know hypothesizing
that most cannabis flow is actually
around 7% moisture once it's finally
dried and cured versus the 12 to 15%
that most people are obtaining in
addition to this we have also done a
relationship study between uh water
activity and moisture to help understand
that and that correlation and I would
love to talk with you all about that
after if you have any additional
questions I'd love to share some of that
data and with that I would like to thank
a couple of people metrome um being one
of them metrome you gave us a Carl
Fisher to be able to utilize for this
study which was very very helpful as
well as aqualab by ADM they provided us
with a RW one which is a moisture
balance that does low temperature so 80°
and allows us to analyze nine samples at
a time which really helped us be able to
process all 120 samples and with that I
will take questions
[Applause]
thanks uh Jenny so it it it appears the
the drying technique here can alter the
canabo profile and um not necessarily
reflect what the patient's going to be
consuming um is there any motion toward
moving to sort of aerosolizing smoke and
measuring the actual inhalation products
because all of this stuff's going to get
decarbox anyway when someone decides to
you know light up a flower so uh it
seems like we're uh it seem we got a bit
of a struggle here where we've got raw
canabo content then you get rid of the
water content and if you overd dry it
some of the canabo change but at the end
of the day the patients never going to
see any of that they're going to see
pyrolytic uh canabo right so I think the
difference here is this is focusing a
lot on the moisture techniques that
Laboratories are utilizing so the with
this you know the Growers and the
cultivators are drying their flower in
much different ways they're not using
any of these techniques it's more of the
laboratory and how they are providing
data to the producers and Growers to
know how wet or how dry their flower is
when we talk about uh aerosol testing it
that's a whole another monster um that I
think still has a lot of Kinks to work
out before we see any labs doing it
successfully and doing it at a high
scale thank you for the presentation
have you ever considered freeze drying
so we did uh talk about freeze drying in
this um and thinking about how that may
impact it however for a laboratory
whenever we're analyzing it most of them
don't have freeze dry capabilities so
when we were thinking about this study
we wanted to really focus on what most
Laboratories could potentially use and
then of course what that gold standard
the Carl Fisher is
[Applause]