[Applause]
thanks brian
thanks everybody so yeah i'm ryan lynch
i'm uh
certainly not a medical doctor or
any type of expert in health care but
what i do have a background in is
non-human
non-animal genomics genetics and
biodiversity assays
and so as we've heard throughout all the
amazing talks today
it's clear that there's the need to
really understand the source of all
these different
therapeutic compounds and combinations
of different compounds
that seem to be so compelling
so i don't have any type of strong
personal story that got that got me
involved with this
it was more of an uh
scientifically and just sort of a
general curiosity and
an identification of of just a clear
lack of study of the system
and so what i've observed and i think
what we've all seen anybody that's
that's
worked with the plants is that there's
this tremendous phenotypic diversity
and whether that's the you know the
branching structure the leaf morphology
the smell the bouquet the aroma that
comes through from the terpenoid
compounds you know the perceived effects
when you consume it or the therapeutic
outcomes that we're
hopefully going to be able to nail down
with some more uh
carefully controlled clinical trials
there's clearly a lot of different
types or varieties of cannabis out there
and so given my background i'd yeah i
decided that
dna sequencing and analysis would be
one of the best ways to approach some of
these questions so
a little outline of i think some of the
the best applications
for cannabis dna analysis
i i like to think of it as uh you know
there are ways to look
into uh the past
you know the history of the plants it's
at least six thousand years
of domestication and transport around
the planet
there's certainly a lot of debate about
uh you know the different
species name systems nomenclatures
varieties you know there's also the
operational
functional names that people associate
with
the indica and the sativa
words although those date back to the
1700s from
linnaeus and lamarck
but i think for me the most interesting
thing and it was
really highlighted listening to all the
the wonderful talks today
was uh more the functional side of it i
think that we can
debate the taxonomy and what you should
call what uh endlessly and it probably
won't be
resolved anytime soon in my opinion
there's probably
you know we should be just calling it
one species at this point but it is an
open question but more importantly
you know we can leverage different
layers of information to start
understand
uh you know some of the uh underlying
causes
of these different chemo profiles that
mark just uh
very carefully described so that's
that's going to take a lot of academic
discourse and modeling and so forth
and the more immediate present we can go
through
and just clean up uh some of the issues
that we have with
the names that you're seeing in the the
various state markets
and that's important because uh patients
and
consumers you know they they they have
expectations and
they uh they associate different effects
with these different names and so that's
something that
we can immediately start to draw lines
in the sand
and begin to set some standards
and as a side effect of that you can
also
start
[Music]
helping to establish
proof of ownership at a certain point in
time through the sequencing data
so the other thing i'll touch on at the
end i won't really have time to go on
this but
going big scaling up developing new
strains automation
full agricultural genomics combined with
modern breeding techniques
so an important caveat i think that uh
it's important i have to remind myself
this sometimes is uh
you know the dna is is the code of life
it's it's the instruction manual
the issue right now and it's incredible
the technological
uh revolutions that uh have led us to be
able to now you know access
every letter in that instruction manual
many times over
for you know hundreds or just thousands
of dollars
for human and and plant plant genomes
and so
in the case of the cannabis genome
that's 800 million
or a little bit more base pairs so you
have all the information but we're still
we're still at the at the uh you know
this isn't jurassic park or anything so
it's not like
it's important to keep in mind that
we're not going to be able to take that
digitalized information
and go in and recreate some type of
unique strain
and in some cases we don't even know you
know we can't even interpret what it
would become
so there's there's uh it's still really
a
developing field in that sense and it's
uh important to keep that in mind
so to address some of those questions
it's uh
it's been an interesting process you
know i started at the university of
colorado
and uh you know just towards the end of
last year
um you know transitioned into uh the
medicinal genomics and it's it's uh
this this issue has continued get
getting samples out of different grows
has always been a unique challenge it's
uh not something where we can just pick
up a flower sample at your local
dispensary and then take it onto campus
legally so it's been some some
interesting stories there
driving around with a trunk full of
centrifuges and pipette tips and
training training people that have been
growing their whole lives to do these
dna extractions and then
dealing with bar coding and sample
labeling issues so
it's it hasn't been easy but um you know
this is
just a a small array of just one grow
a medical dispensary in colorado and
just some of the the interesting
shapes and leaflet blade morphologies
and colors that
that they had in stock at the time
so just a really quick overview on the
the sequencing technology i found this
the other night it's a nice white paper
by
fluorogenix so if you're interested in
the details i think this is a
a really nice schematic and so what it
does is it
it represents the genome as that that
dark blue line at the top
and then it goes through all the
different
steps that it takes to do the sequencing
and so
i i think the best to just look look at
the bottom down there and compare versus
whole genome shotgun sequencing which is
what uh
i started out doing it it fragments the
the original genome uh into random
little segments and then you sequence
all that and then you realign it back to
a reference and so as you can see uh
that create that that does cover the
entire genome but it takes
more uh more sequencing runs to
get that information compared to the rad
seek restriction
site associated techniques that we're
using now so if you counted the stacks
the number of sequences and the rad
stacks it would be fewer
than the shotgun sequencing and so the
important point there is that it's
uh these techniques have allowed us to
sequence more samples and gain enough
information to do the analyses we're
interested in
while keeping costs down
so to answer some of the relatedness
questions that i find really interesting
and i think have some direct
applications to
most people involved in the industry
i've i've relied on a series of
different
uh uh methods to infer relatedness and
um
behind you know there's a number of
different models and algorithms and so
forth but
i just wanted to point out some of the
the uh the nomenclature
that we use to uh interpret the
visualizations
and so the obvious ones are the toxon
those are the
the samples the strain or the variety
and then there's the uh
the branch which is really important and
so if you wanted to compare the
relatedness between for example
species d and e you would add up those
uh those branch lengths
on the x-axis and what's important to
keep in mind is a little bit misleading
about these renderings is that
the distance on the y-axis isn't
actually included
in that calculation so the other point
is rooted versus unrooted that's just a
way
of adding an extra orientation to the
order in which you think
different taxa have diverged and so with
cannabis
we don't have well we know that the
nearest
plant relative is hops cumulus but we
don't have the molecular
reference tools to really use that so
all the
phylogenetic trees i'll show are are
unrooted
so the other thing to keep in mind i
pulled this off of uh
icymag.com a few days ago is that uh
you know cannabis i mean it has a very
convoluted history i mean people have
been
doing this in their basement for decades
in terms of
prohibition era breeding and you know
moving these things around the world in
very small batches
and then there's the issue of course on
the production side where
you really typically do not want a lot
of pollen in your facility so
we've had a bottleneck in terms of male
genetics and so
this schematic that was just put
together through somebody's
recollection so i don't know how
accurate that might be but
you know it really looks more like a web
than a bifurcating tree
and so a compromise we came up with was
a tool that allow it's sort of a hybrid
that allows
inference of both network-like structure
relatedness and
tree structure and so this is from a
paper that
i did with nolan and the rest of the the
kane lab
and uh finally got it out in a review so
it was a quite a battle
with the editors and uh the point here
there are
of course sample names on all those i
think it's about uh it's just under 200
samples and
there's a full 4 mb high resolution
version if you want to check it out on
the pre-print server but after a number
of different
clustering and structural analysis
models
we were able to recover significant
evidence for
three broad types of cannabis diversity
and we borrowed nomenclature from
rob clark and mark merlin and so we
called those the broad leaflet drug type
and if you were to zoom in on those
you'd be able to see a lot of names that
have cush in them
and actually some samples that we have
pretty good confidence were actually
brought over from afghanistan so these
are
shorter stockier um biotypes that uh
we believe originate from the north side
of the hindu kush mountains
so then you have that big spray kind of
from 11 o'clock all the way down to
uh you know about five o'clock there and
that's that's just a whole mess of other
different varieties that uh we're
lumping in as the
narrow leaflet drug types and then uh
the most distinct one of course are the
european hemp groups that
those are seed and oil fiber types that
do not typically get used in drug type
reading so
if you're interested in any of the names
in there i mean some of them are
actually
you know we've been able to recover
clones from different states that are
totally identical but
some of these are not so consistent and
i'll go into some more examples with the
more recent data we've done at medicinal
genomics but i thought that was a good
example an old famous name jacqueriae
i mean it's just it's just all over the
place and
maybe there's a little cluster almost
a hope for some type of consensus down
there at six o'clock but uh it's
certainly uh
it's certainly uh not the same thing and
from
every source
so we don't have uh any of the the
resolution that
mark just showed but we were able to uh
in a way
confirm some of the validity behind
those genetic groups
through looking at the average
cannabinoid and terpene levels and
between those those three groups that we
recovered we found some significant
differences that are
noted with the brackets and the
different levels of significance and the
astra season
so maybe not not uh not huge magnitude
of differences in the thc and the cbd
but
you do find some very interesting hints
at
different genetic backgrounds may
correlate to
some of these different terpenoid
compounds the
the linole and the mercy in particularly
so now at medicinal i mean we've you
know we're really looking to ramp this
up and go from
dozens or hundreds of samples to
thousands and um go from just you know
what we could scrape together in
colorado and maybe stuff people wanted
to send us in california to
uh you know the the all the states where
there's access
and of course uh beyond
and so this is uh really just at the
onset of our launch for this but
we've been able to uh to already make
some great progress
and we're doing a rollout in colorado
and california with us
and we've really upgraded our our
version of the rad seek protocol so
we're getting a very large chunk of data
from the genome
it's a it's actually 10 times more than
i used in
in my paper and so that that's going to
be a great robust platform that can be
developed into a number of different
types of analysis down the road
and so i have a um actually as of this
wednesday
uh in the uh the colorado estate
tracking system there's going to be
over 100 000 uh products that came from
plants
that we certified and tracked through uh
all the way from
uh clone or seed to to harvest and
product whether that's flour or mips and
so that's
something like i have some other updates
here just came through
700 pounds of flour and that's uh
just just just at 41 strains so we have
the capacity to do
um hundreds if not if not thousands of
samples per week
at the the quarter gen medicinal
genomics facility so
um i'm really excited to see what kind
of
new patterns and stories emerge from
that
so something kevin touched upon uh i
think it was last night at dinner
so it was uh you know
trying to tap into to just this global
community
and uh so we've set up a website where
we're going to have different layers of
uh information from our genetic
sequencing efforts
and also our partner labs that are going
to provide chemical
analytics and then also a more
distributed open source section where we
can get reviews and
different types of feedback and comments
from everybody in the community so
that's we'll be rolling out um step by
step through april and may
so just a little uh a little a couple
little um stories from the
latest data hopefully this works
that resolution got downgraded
one thing that popped out to me was we
do have some good some good chemical
data from
sc labs actually generated this for us
and
uh what we can see is that uh you know a
lot of the strains that
are coming through with the higher
elevated cbd
to thc ratios are are clearly
quite quite closely related and so it
suggests that
there's certainly room for improvement
in terms of
introducing that trait with you know
some of the other varieties out there
that have different terpenoid compounds
or you know
other traits of interest that might be
useful whether it's disease resistance
or yield
another thing i thought was interesting
were the this cluster of green samples
you can't see the names there but
they're
they're all different and uh the genetic
distances to me suggest that we've
picked up
a breeder who's been using one male for
a variety of different females and so
um you know it's not uh it's not like
that makes those
those varieties useless or anything but
uh it's
uh it's it's it's interesting and it
shows uh some of the limitations of the
the current uh breeding techniques that
have been used
hopefully you guys can read that yeah so
there's an example of just a total
strain naming consistency so we have a
snoops dream sample that was picked up
from a dispensary in washington state
and that was that ended up being
genetically identical to
another variety that came out of
colorado medical dispensary
called blue dreams so i don't know which
one's which
or what was the original we can't say
that from those data point but
i looked it up on lethally snoop's dream
is supposed to be a hybrid between a
master kush and a blue dream
but so maybe it's the blue dream that's
mislabeled here in this case but
that's going to be the thing as we get
more and more samples we'll be able to
build
case studies on on some of these
inconsistencies and
go back and and hopefully
and hopefully clean up some of these
issues
and there's just another little uh
cluster issue there
so we have uh we have catatonic butane
uh bhutan and the catatonic ac dc
variety
those are all genetically identical
three different names
they all came uh two were from
california one where one was from
massachusetts
so i'm not sure what the original was
there either but well just
i'll just leave you guys with this
little uh you know dream big here
so so this is something from pioneer
genetics and so what what this machine
is is the corn chipper and so they'll do
crosses this is a way to accelerate
breeding
improve strains novel traits
intragressed you can do crosses
dump the seeds in somewhere at the top
it's kind of cut out of the picture
labels each one rotates it around
takes a little cutting off of the embryo
the seed's still viable stores the seed
dna sequencing off of that little piece
that was removed
search for markers decide which ones
you're actually going to grow and do
field trials on
all automated you know genomic selection
marker selection so it's it's uh
obviously a work in progress but uh put
that on the
the wish list for your next grow
so just a quick summary there and
probably over the timeline here
so i think uh there's there's um you
know there's a lot of information you
can get out of dna sequencing and some
of it isn't interpretable but
some of it you can't really get
otherwise so it's important that
we consider these data but it's also
important that we don't
that we that we work together and we
blend these data and we layer them
so the genetic data without the chemical
data is
uh it's a little bit thin and together
they can make some really powerful tools
and so as we've uh we've heard in some
of these talks and some of the papers
that have come out recently there's
this number changes but i'm quoting a
113 different
phytocannabinoids have been identified
and at least 120
uh terpenoid compounds and so the caveat
there is
okay yeah it's found on the plant the
plant may not necessarily actually
synthesize all those as kevin brought up
there's
certainly the potential for some of the
alterations and the chemical structures
coming from
the microbiome but it's intriguing
nonetheless and
i think there's a lot of room for
improvement
thanks for listening