well I've already called a bunch of
friends and I said you have to be there
next year because this is high level
networking
I mean you're getting to talk to the
people that are innovating that are
making a huge difference in this
industry and pushing it forward with a
lot of Integrity there is no substitute
for the face-to-face
opportunities that we've had this week I
can't go to a coffee station without
meeting somebody else who has a
fantastic story who would be very
important to what I do or that I'm able
to help myself it's such a great group
of individuals here and you keep seeing
the same familiar faces time and time
again and it's so intimate that you can
have a conversation with anybody just by
walking across the room and saying hi
but I have made you know over a dozen
new connections that I think are
meaningful that are bringing
possibilities to either teaming
agreements or collaborations on future
research and development and business
workings
like one of the most authentic genuine
conferences I've ever attended and I've
been to many because I've been in the
pharmaceutical industry for over 25
years this just felt so unique and it
felt like people weren't trying to
impress each other but actually learn
from each other and so
for me that was a it was it was it was
so inspiring
it's refreshing to come here and see
like-minded people who understand the
future of cannabis we've heard today
information that has not been published
from the people who are doing that work
and they go into great detail when you
get them one-on-one
into what they're doing later and the
strategy behind it and so it's like
being able to see Over the Horizon and
know where things are going to be not in
weeks and months but a year or two from
now and this is the only place that's
going to happen
so
um
appointed by the by the conversation
sessions by the op the awesome dinners
and networking it's been a fantastic
experience and I'm so happy that it came
[Music]