[Music]
you know so between 204 in the present
there wasn't a lot of explanation of
what CHS was from now there had been
again studies that showed that a marked
upregulation of the hypo thalamic P
pituitary um system um so basically
stress responses now you bet if you're
in pain and you're nauseated and
vomiting you got stress but I mean this
is really serious stress um this isn't
you know simple situation of of vomiting
a couple of times because of a virus um
people lose weight um they get merked
abnormalities uh sometimes of
electrolytes you know the mineral
balance in the blood and there've
actually been two deaths attributed to
this because of how bad the vomiting was
from
CHS um so you know there are certain
markers but until um recently we didn't
have an explanation for this why does
one person get it and another one
doesn't so this is the reason
we wanted to examine it with the
hypothesis that perhaps certain people
have a genetic susceptibility to this so
that's what we wanted to test um so uh
with endocan health uh we put together a
study uh starting with a survey again of
over 500 people and um we for entry as a
CHS patient we had very strict criteria
we didn't want there to be mistakes so
first thing was they had to carry a
diagnosis of CHS in other words somebody
had seen them and said that this wasn't
what it
was um then additionally they had to
have active symptoms we didn't want
people in that may have been
misdiagnosed as having CHS but we're
okay now in other words they didn't
really have it um so that whittel things
down
um we um we got it down to uh something
like 200 candidates and um they were
offered
um genetic testing which is done with a
swab in the mouth um to look at the
DNA unfortunately there was a lot of
attrition between step two and step
three uh because only 28 CHS confirmed
CHS patients returned the kit after
after all of them and said that they
wanted
it the reason for that was we had a
great deal of push back from the CHS
online community there were people that
questioned our motives um thought we
were in this for the money um didn't
like our methodology for one reason or
another and so there was an active
movement to uh tell people not to
participate um so that wasn't helpful um
and then we needed to compare them to to
somebody so there were some people who
took the survey that were high uh volume
cannabis users um interestingly about
the same four grams a day who didn't
have CHS symptoms and didn't have a
diagnosis so th those were the
comparison
groups um what we found was a little
surprising so the first hypothesis was
well there's got to be a problem with
the CB1 Gene the gene that codes for the
CB1 receptor um we didn't see that as
mentioned previously you do see that in
uh cyclic vomiting syndrome so instantly
we had uh uh difference between the two
syndromes we also hypothesized two other
things that it could be a problem with
the metabolism of THC how it's broken
down we did get confirmation of that
because
there was a statistically significant
difference in a mutation in a um cyp 2c9
Gene between the CHS patients and the
heavy usage of cannabis that didn't have
symptoms so
cyp2c9 is the um enzyme in the liver
that breaks down
THC so you might understand if there
were a mutation there perhaps that it
wasn't as efficient breaking down THC
that levels would be higher and this
could produce this funny
reaction um the third um hypothesis that
we had was that there would be an issue
with the trpv1 trip V1 Gene we thought
of that because one of the interesting
things about CHS is that hot water
exposure seems to help and
interestingly something else that's hot
application of capsus anointment on the
skin the active ingredient in Chili
Peppers also temporarily relieve
symptoms uh that turned out to be the
case too again we saw statistically
significant difference uh in the number
of mutation seen in the CHS patients in
the trip V1 Gene is compared to the high
volume cannabis users without CHS
um so uh then there were a couple of
things we hadn't uh
hypothesized there were two genes
related to dopamine metabolism with
abnormalities uh one was uh for the gene
that codes the dopamine type 2 uh
receptor um this is an interesting uh
receptor in that it's the target for
antipsychotic drugs um
and um when people have a mutation there
as we saw in the CHS patients they're at
risk for a whole bunch of things um
addiction to other
substances um also uh risk for psychosis
and other psychiatric issues to a strong
degree U whether it be um depression
anxiety
Etc there was also a mutation in What's
called the CT catacol omey transferase
Gene this is the gene that breaks down
dopamine um and again if uh there were a
problem there um you might get a buildup
of dopamine that would um provoke
addictive uh Behavior or that kind of
thing right and then there was one that
made sense though because all of what
we've mentioned so
far um sort of
it informs the symptomatology and
phenomenology of CHS meaning that it
helps explain some of the symptoms um
you know
trpv1 among other things has to do with
propulsion in the gut if things aren't
moving you will tend to vomit um it also
is in the brain and is associated with
anxiety and pain um so things begin to
make a lot more sense but the fifth
mutation that we saw was something we
had not expected um this is a gene
called
abca1 it has to do with cholesterol
metabolism and this one's a little
ominous because people who have
mutations on this Gene may be
susceptible to a number of problems
later in life specifically coronary
artery disease type 2 diabetes
metis um and Alzheimer disease so we do
not know yet um because this hasn't been
around yet our folks with CHS that have
this mutation at greater risk for these
disorders the answer is quite possibly
yes so this takes on another dimension
of Public Health uh relevance that we
really need to be
examining
[Music]
a