I'm certainly a cannabinoid fan probably
more well known for my interest in
terpenes
um I think you know fully wholeheartedly
embracing the Entourage and Ensemble
effects I think all of them are
important more of them together are
probably more efficacious than one by
itself
but today I'm going to talk a little bit
more about what we're seeing in the
cannabinoid space predominantly in the
hemp derived cannabinoid space and as we
know there are many different
cannabinoids certainly won't try and
cover all of them and there's the major
actors and some of the you know more
emerging ones like Ethan was just
highlighting
and some of the more common minor ones
like he had mentioned CBG cbga CBN and
thcv
but what we're starting to see in the
marketplace which I will highlight is a
highly unregulated Marketplace I will
definitely Echo Ethan's frustrations and
concerns with legislators lawmakers and
Regulators science moves at a much more
rapid Pace than any of them seem to be
able to do so
despite our yelling at them screaming at
them trying to converse with them and
really adamantly talking to them
just time and time again about problems
that we may see coming as Science and
Technology advances much more rapidly
than the law and regulation
and what we're seeing today are more of
these hemp derived cannabinoids so the
2018 Farm Bill put the lovely word
derivative in the language and as a
chemist we also started to light up
saying how might we derivatize some of
these molecules
um what might this open or entail and
what we're seeing today are some of the
ones listed on the bottom of the slide
I'll try to not have to pronounce every
single one of them
but there certainly is a large plethora
of them and the lettering and the
numbering and naming start to get rather
dizzying even for a chemist such as
myself so I can appreciate you know the
lawmaker in regulator position when they
say I don't understand chemistry I
failed Math and Science in in high
school and didn't even take much of it
in college so what am I supposed to do
about trying to write legislation or
regulation around these things we try to
comfort them and say here's some copy
paste language it sometimes goes over
well sometimes does not not but they
hear from everyone in the industry and
unfortunately there are some folks with
very strong lobbying efforts very large
amounts of financial resources that can
keep getting the conversations time and
time again and they are saying there's
no problems don't worry everything's
fine
um please let things persist as is and I
think in the absence of Regulation we
have seen that in the Cannabis industry
we know that there are Purity problems
there are mislabeling problems there are
all sorts of issues that arise that are
not to the benefit of a consumer and
especially not to the benefit of
patients so we can't continue to operate
in a space with no laws that are clear
and no regulations that are really
helping to Define how these products
should be produced and managed and
introduced to the public
um so there are you know a small problem
here as a chemist there was an old
numbering system and this shows the
numbering systems I'll just highlight
the the three and the four
um because the numbering system around
the ring changes
um into what we see today so this is the
more monitoring numbering system based
on some technical chemistry positions
and we're familiar with what's up here
is shown as Delta 9 THC
and so you'll see around the ring
structure here
there are many isomers this is where you
get Delta eight when you go and move the
double bond from nine to ten to eight to
nine there are many other derivatives
you can pretty much walk that double
bond all the way around the ring and see
one of those is probably out there in
some fashion some of them are more
thermodynamically favorable to form or
produce than others so some might be
much more easily accessible than others
certain derivatives are probably more
plentiful because of that that's just
the physical nature of chemistry
we are also seeing derivatization on the
phenolic Oh by acetylation so forming
acetates things like that so we have
that as another functional point in the
molecule that we can see derivatization
and the other aspects of some of these
compounds that are out here are
aliphatic chain lengths so you just
heard about thcv that's when the chain
length is shorter there are also some
other ones out there in the marketplace
now where the chain length is longer and
I'm going to try and describe a little
bit of each of these
so when you look around the ring up here
you'll see the isomers such as Delta 8
Delta 10 Delta 7 Delta 11 and this is
where it's the little funny part Delta
three or Delta 4 which would be the 10A
or 6A positions and the number is where
the double bond starts
um just for the nomenclature
so you can make Delta a THC from Delta 9
THC you can also make pretty much any of
these from CBD so hemp Farmers
overproduced there was a lot more hype
and interest in cultivating CBD it is
very easy to manufacture and isolate CBD
isolate in high Purity so CBD is a solid
that's very friendly from a
manufacturing standpoint to isolate with
high purities I can recrystallize it I
can get it to come out and filter it THC
Delta 9 THC by itself is a highly
viscous sticky oil so I don't have the
ability to recrystallize it or make it a
high Purity solid I'm trying to distill
it and often there are a few other
either minor cannabinoids or other
components that go with it you can see
you know typical THC purities in the
marketplace in the 90s 85 to 90 percent
sometimes a little over 90 percent but
you can't see the same Purity as you can
with CBD so I can get CBD at 99 plus
percent
um it's readily available it's extremely
cost effective as a chemical synthon so
now that that's out there the current
estimates that we're hearing are about
75 of the CBD in the marketplace is
being derivatized to Delta 8 or even
Delta 9 THC
depending upon how you try and control
the chemistry you can get the
cyclization happen and you can land at
Delta 9 or Delta 8 THC so poor Farmers
had to get rid of their compounds in
some fashion they had overproduced and
we see this rise in Delta 8 THC types of
products
I don't think it's the molecules
sometimes that we should think you know
could be demonized I think Delta 9
obviously we know much about Delta eight
I think has wonderful physiological
properties I think there's great
potential for that it's a little bit
akin to a hybrid between Delta 9 THC and
CBD
slightly lower psychoactivity potentials
it could be very beneficial for some and
some folks are saying it's their
medicine of choice so I think we know a
little bit more about that one than some
of these other derivatives from
Medicinal Chemistry studies or other
types of you know pharmacophoric
perspectives that the pharmaceutical
industry has performed over many years
it's not quite as studied as Delta 9 but
I'm a little bit more of a fan of Delta
8 and some of the other derivatives
because we know a little bit more about
it today
the question becomes what have I used to
make it and what might be left with it
so what's the end purity of the product
and are there any other you know
cannabinoid or cannabinoid-like
impurities or are there any of the
reagents that were used in this type of
transformation that might be present as
well
um and it was funny to kind of look back
from my perspective at UCLA in 2018
in can Med I presented this exact slide
it was the last slide in my slide set
and we talked about Delta eight we
penned a white paper on Delta 8 THC in
2018 when we saw the the farm bill
language we knew that this might be
coming
um it didn't quite expect it would be
coming as much as I've seen today
um but you know our concern then was
what you see here what else is going
with it so I'll call it a Delta a
product or someone will call it a Delta
a product but what else was there and
what we saw in a one sample in Oregon is
highlighted in Orange where you've got
other things that are obviously
cannabinoid like molecules
um a much better representation is the
blue line where you have a little bit of
CBN and I'll caution this is diode array
detection CBN lights up a lot greater
than the other cannabinoids because of
the wavelength that you're using when
you do detection so it's not a
quantitative picture but the unknowns
are obviously much more present in the
orange sample than in the blue one
and this was the concern what else is
going with it what else was made in the
manufacturing process today in Oregon
the regulator has tried to stop the
introduction of Delta 8 and other
synthetic cannabinoids in their
regulated supply chain they had found
most Delta 8 on their Marketplace was
between 70 to 85 percent impurity and it
just begs the question what's the other
15 to 30 percent is it an unknown
cannabinoid is it some other impurity is
it something that could be highly toxic
is it something that may even be better
for us simply because we don't know we
really shouldn't permit those in the
marketplace or in the product streams
they've tried to set up a system where
we might be able to introduce Regulators
approving a process I think that's more
of a sensible approach if this molecule
seems to be okay and we're okay with
that being in the marketplace then how
has it been made and how do we monitor
that process and know the impurities
that go with it and that's a major
reason the FDA exists so in the absence
of federal regulations doing these types
of things which they do for
pharmaceutical apis and you know all the
time we're going to require State
Regulators to try and grapple with this
problem or send folks into the field to
identify processes now Oregon has said
if you've got a new dietary ingredient
process if you've got a molecule under
grass status or self-affirmed grass then
you might be able to say that process
has been approved in a federal sense and
that would be acceptable to introduce
into the Oregon regulated Supply stream
they specifically carved out CBN as well
for some other reasons but there was a
lot of CBN already in the marketplace
and they think that that one might have
been a little bit more acceptable as a
synthetic chemist I don't know if that's
necessarily true the manufacturing
methods to CBN depending how you try and
get there could actually create a large
number of impurities
foreign
so these are kind of the two that I'm
maybe a little more worried about um
there's some others I'm much more
worried about but the hhc the fully
hydrogenated version where there's no
um double bonds left and CBN so these
come from Delta eight or Delta 9 and
hydrogenation to perform hydrogenation
and and quickly my background is a
synthetic chemist so I'm pretty well
versed in these manufacturing methods I
performed hydrogenation methods myself
in graduate school
you require a catalyst it's typically
Palladium or platinum sometimes it can
be some other exotic metals that are
used but those are really concerning as
to what levels of those are being left
in the products no Cannabis Testing Lab
that I am aware of is testing for a
trace Palladium Platinum runny you know
catalytic process reagents that may be
used in a hydrogenation process
so the FDA very tightly scrutinizes
hydrogenation methods it's a very common
last step in a lot of apis it is
something that can be managed and is
watched but you have to be very careful
that your Palladium Catalyst has not
stuck to your product it's not leaching
into your end product and no one here
that I am aware of is currently watching
that today that's a great concern so
understanding the process and how we get
there what of those reagents might be
left in the product is really of great
concern
I put the asterisks up there because
hydrogenation happens from the top or
the bottom of the molecule and you'll
create a chiral Center here so you'll
have a right hand left hand type of
problem you definitely have different
physiological activities sometimes you
can have catastrophic types of
physiological activities such as the
case of thalidomide so understanding
your enantiomers may be very important
as well when you leave the double bond
in Delta 9 and Delta 8 you don't have
that rasamate problem when it starts
walking around the ring you start to
generate the problem as well so now we
have complex mixtures of problems we're
going to need much more Advanced
Analytical methodologies to discern what
is this mixture over that mixture some
of them may have better medical efficacy
than others some of them may generate
unwanted toxicities we really don't know
and I think it's really more incumbent
upon us to say let's slow the train down
a little bit and start to understand at
least from a toxicological perspective
what are we introducing into this Grand
human experiment that we're running the
you know the scientific train and
Manufacturing abilities are greatly
ahead of legislation and regulation
this is the structure of CBN
um I think we're probably far less
concerned about its physiological
activity because it doesn't cause
potential psychoactivities
um I think it's you know potentially
okay from a metabolic standpoint I worry
about hhc's metabolic abilities so most
of the metabolisms are allylic
oxidations you need the double bond
present to facilitate oxidation and then
eventual clearance from the body I'm not
aware of the metabolic fates of hhc I
don't know if they've been fully studied
and it starts to you know make you
question will this build up to toxic
levels in the body might it become a
problem if I chronically use it over
time certainly at larger and larger
doses how much of an issue might it be
we're aware of you know complications
with CBD and liver potential toxicities
we're aware cannabinoids have to go
through the cytochromes to you know be
metabolized and excreted what happens to
ones that really May potentially lock
that system up or be you know very proud
problematic I think those are still
somewhat unknown questions as well
um the acetates I'm also not a
significant fan of we have some big
problems with that in a couple of
different ways and I apologize it
shouldn't be acetylized I think the
industry and my toddlers keeping me up
too late at night got into me it's
acetylate
um a set of Lies is not a word so I
apologize for the error on the slide
this is a simple chemical transformation
I just have to take the phenol boil it
in acetic anhydride and I can make an
acetate
um there are probably even other
acetates that I might be able to make
and that starts to beg the question how
many of those might be okay or not it's
akin to the manufacturing method of
taking morphine to heroin so we know
that there are huge differences in that
they now cross the blood-brain barrier
in very different ways and there are
great concerns about these types of
things being in you know in the body I
think the bigger problem with this is we
now know phenolic acetate such as
Vitamin E acetate cause the cases of a
valley so when you heat these up to
certain temperatures they'll degrade
into a molecule called ketine which is
highly reactive and that caused a
significant lung um you know abrasions
and problems so these products inside of
an inhalation product could be
catastrophic I'm not a fan of allowing
any of these I don't think they're not
naturally occurring they're not found in
the cannabis plant they really don't
make much sense they're completely new
molecular entities probably don't have
great place inside of our regulated
Supply stream right now we have plenty
of other good cannabinoids to deal with
that we're not tapping into let's stick
to the Natural ones
the aliphatic variants the reason these
are starting to show up is because they
improve their potency at CB1 and they
start to become much much more
psychoactive and at least are touted as
being 30 times stronger than THC itself
or thcp
so as you get longer in the chain you
can start to see that increase there is
a length limit it starts to decrease as
well but this is why you'll start to see
six seven and eight carbon lengths
greater than the THC one that has five
doing some of the math if you have some
of these present at 0.1 percent in hemp
it might take you ten thousand dollars
worth of raw material to produce a kilo
of extract and that's before you go
about doing the manufacturing methods or
isolations to go ahead and bring these
products to Market so when they're
selling for eight nine ten thousand
dollars a kilo
doesn't make me think that they're being
derived from him I'm not aware of any
hemp cultivars that are actually present
with
um you know appreciable amounts of these
molecules either so while they may have
been found in Trace Amounts we have not
used them in larger amounts we're not
putting 80 percent of those in
concentrates we're starting to venture
into a realm where these are not really
understood or well known and again I
believe these are probably more than
likely being synthetically derived and
not being extracted from hem although
all the web pages will tell you
differently
so what do you see in the marketplace
today it's frightening if you just start
putting in you know THC H THC JD thcl
like just start looking up some of these
websites and you'll see some of these
products are throwing everything and
anything in between
um to try and say my products more
potent my products differentiated and
you can buy them online there's no age
gating systems or kind of they're hoping
you have a credit card
um there is fancy packaging things that
may be attractive to children and it's
starting to blow back on the rest of the
industry so the poor licensed operators
that have been operating within the
states desperately trying to follow
hundreds of pages of regulations and
complex laws are being you know forced
to combat folks that don't pay the same
taxes don't have the same regulatory
scrutiny can't lose their license and
don't even have to care what's on their
packaging I think that's exceptionally
unfair it's not rewarding to those that
have been carving this difficult path
for patients and other consumers and to
see products like this available at what
could be a gas station or a grocery
store or anywhere you know I mentioned I
have toddlers I have you know kids
around me all the time it is a grave
concern to me and to many others like
myself what are these things why are
they available and why can't we do
something to stop it
um so how do we regulate it
I don't know this is like a good shot at
maybe a good guess to start with
um you know Delta nine THC which we know
is ranked as number six you can't
compare directly
um Ki values or inhibitory constant
values at CB1 because they're not always
done in the same models they're not
always done in all these molecules so I
tried to take that and with some help
from chatgpt who doesn't know science
very well either
um you know I just kept trying to think
it through think it through and think it
through and came up with you know
somewhat of a picture from a lot of
anecdotal insights a lot of what folks
will tell you or Post online and some of
what we know from General pharmacophoric
structures and some of what we
understand from actual use within the
Cannabis industry so this is a guess
this is not etched in stone is supposed
to start conversation and I think this
is what The Regulators may need to say
how do we start somewhere so we can't
say no to all of them we definitely want
some of them naturally occurring ones
that's seems okay unless they seem to be
too potent or not actually being
isolated from the plant the approved
column is saying the regulator should
approve the process because the molecule
might be okay but how did you get there
is a more concern and I really think
that there's a lot to be had in a
complex slide like this a lot of
questions that are you know arising but
lawmakers and Regulators especially in
California today are trying to figure
out how do I grapple with this problem
what should I allow or not allow and I'm
sure the federal regulators and
lawmakers are thinking about it with
rewriting the farm bill this year as
well this again is not etched in stone
it's for conversation there are some
question marks here some of those are
naturally occurring I think the
cannabinoid acids don't have the potency
problem but if you say all cannabinoid
acids are allowed we'll start to make
the acids and then they'll decarboxylate
them at home in inhalation devices and
you might have the same problem so it's
a very sticky Wicked and challenging
problem with a lot of molecular are in
technical complexities but it's one I
think that is present upon us today and
one that we have to take upon ourselves
to really work together and say how can
we best regulate these to allow the
molecules that are beneficial to
patients good for consumers but at the
right Purity and potencies and labeled
properly so that we aren't harming
anybody inadvertently because when they
see they're tested they think they're
tested for everything and we just have
to be conscious of that
thank you for your time
sure yeah I'll take a question for sure
thank you what a wonderful talk and so
eye-opening as a clinician I you know I
know when the a valley thing happened it
was like we're not testing for the
Vitamin E acetate so we didn't know but
I'm curious
do you think there's going to be any
work this year with the farm bill since
it we're coming up on the five-year
anniversary do you think some you know
because what I'm seeing now is in the
marketplace THC at five to ten
milligrams of temp Drive THC which in
some ways is a clinician I appreciate
because it's easily accessible for
patients you know in in states that
don't have it but you know then I see
this talk and I'm you know scared so do
you think there's any any talks right
now about the hemp build do you have any
insights around that and changes thank
you yeah there are a lot of folks
talking about the farm bill I think
there's an effort towards aiming to
regulate
um THC amounts so the farm bill says
0.38 THC that was meant for biomass not
for manufactured products because if I
make you know a granola bar or brownie
or chocolate bar and I say it's 0.38 THC
I can have potencies and products that
are much stronger than what's allowed in
the regulated market it's just a simple
math game I'll just make the product
bigger and also I've got 30 or 300
milligrams in one unit I don't want
anyone getting that at a gas station
that's ridiculous and that was not the
intent I think of the law they just
didn't know what they were writing and
in the absence of regulations
everybody's points to point three weight
percent which is why they think there's
some legal precedent to allow them
um to have those products the DEA is
like we don't think that was the case
we've kind of they've kind of said you
know HHS has said hey you guys need to
regulate this or take some sort of look
at it so I think everyone's aware of
their problem and they hopefully will
come out with a total milligram
allowance in hemp regulated products
something that you can analytically test
for something that you could Monitor and
label properly and something that
doesn't hurt all the legal State
operators on the Delta 19 she said
I hope I can't promise and you won't
know until like the last second when
someone finally says okay the Bill's
going to pass
sure hi uh from one organic chemist or
the other um how do they make THC p and
the other lymphatic chain length
derivatives
are done with the levitolic acid and um
you just stick it together so take a
levitol but it's a derivative of a live
at all and that's the longer chain and
then you just stick it to the duranal
group okay so you're just resourcing all
uh stuff yeah okay yeah so it's a simple
synthetic process it's not too
complicated but no derivativeization of
CBDs but fully synthetic correct okay
thank you Jeff um can you hear me sure
um thank you and always thank you for
answering my many texts and emails and
learning from you always
so my question is
um about what you think and I don't mean
to put you on the spot but there were
two cases that were published in
literature in December 22 of a 20 year
old and I think a 35 year old that were
both in separate cases but presented to
the same hospital with psychosis
suicidal ideation and what they called
refractory depression after using Delta
eight products and I believe it was in
Colorado my question to you is do we
have any idea which compound in this mix
might be causing those or is it more
than one compound I don't think it's the
Delta eight
I'm with you in that I don't think it's
the Delta 8 itself I mean it may be
right we can't rule that out but I can't
find analytical data on the products
that they've had they don't allow anyone
to really scrutinize that for every
other minor cannabinoid or impurity
that's there but it does beg the
question was it the impurities or
something else in those manufacturing
processes that cause that
um you know much like spice and K2 we
know if you lock up the endocannabinoid
system you can have huge problems I
think that's the concern with thcp and
some of the other ones when they're so
strongly binding you can lock the system
up and have catastrophic issues are some
of these metabolic or some of these
synthetic impurities causing the same
problem they're cannabinoid like so they
could do so but in the absence of great
analytical understanding of those
products and that I mean I kind of doubt
those were the only two people to take
that product so you know you're seeing
probably out of a population there's you
know never 100 you know perfection in
some of those but it does beg the
question it's most likely not to eight
it's probably one of the other synthetic
impurities on how they got there
but we don't know
maybe time for one more sure
um
are the cannabinoids hemp derived and
marijuana derived the same
it's all cannabis to me
sorry as a scientist right it's Cannabis
sativa L we call it hemp or marijuana
for legal and tax definitions
um so you know which is horrific from a
scientific standpoint and probably to
everyone in this room
um hemp derived as saying I came from a
cultivar that was high in CBD and low in
THC marijuana would be one that has
higher than 0.38 THC it may also have
some CBD and other ones as a chemist all
the molecules are here it may be more
advantageous to go from one that is
higher in one cannabinoid and expressed
in a large amount so if I have 20 CBD
isolating that CBD is much easier from
that but legally I'm trying to call it
hemp derived so I can skirt the state
laws and I can just go out there and
sell it online
chemist point of view
a business point of view it's an
economic Factor yeah oh yeah it's a huge
economic piece yeah
Jeffrey could I get one more
uh sure
um I'm going to be meeting in Sacramento
with some of the state legislators for
uh bills they've actually been really
good I've had some very good
conversations with them I think some of
them want to hear some of them are just
like I have no idea please help me
um others are like I don't know
um it's a crap shoot uh what I was going
to ask was like what is your short and
sweet uh or when I meet him because
we've usually got about like 15 minutes
uh and I'll visit several offices but I
get to talk to the chair people uh the
Committees that are seeing those bills
through
try to listen to the diverse array of
Industry not just one Industry Group see
if they are coalesced around a topic
protect those that have state licenses
because they've been working so hard to
do so and the question is should we
allow hemp ingredients into California's
regulated Supply stream that's where
they're being tested and labeled that's
where the rules apply I think pushing
everything into a cannabinoid centers of
excellence we might eventually call
these dispensaries makes more sense
because people should be more informed
about cannabinoid cannabinoid therapies
and that's where I'm kind of going to
expect I'll have these things and I
wouldn't find something you know at a
smoke shop or a gas station with someone
that just said go buy it because it's
supposed to be the strongest thing out
here I think putting it in a dispensary
makes much much more sense just from a
sociological standpoint good yeah that's
what they were looking at uh thank you
you're welcome thank you everyone