[Music]
hi I'm Kevin mckernon I'm the chief
scientific officer of medicinal genomics
and this year at can med we have some
exciting stuff to talk about we have
been funded by a cryptocurrency named -
who is also sponsoring a conference but
they also were very interested in
entering the cannabis market as a
solution to many of the banking problems
in the field whether that be raising
money for for new companies or whether
it be solving point-of-sale banking and
they recognize that the seed to sell
tracking system is also a little bit
disjointed and can probably benefit from
a blockchain so we proposed to them to
sequence a cannabis genome to the best
extent that's ever been done before and
they liked that idea because it forms a
nice foundation for seed to sell
tracking and also a good scientific sort
of donation to the field to get their
name well established and and we've now
done that they funded us two months ago
and we've been through and we've done
about 90 fold coverage of cannabis
genome known as Jamaican lion we picked
this strain for a very important reason
it dates back to 2007 and then what
cannabis cup in 2011 and it is a type 2
cannabis plant which makes both CBD and
THC and those are a little bit
controversial right now based on some
recent patents that have issued and so
by sequencing this we hope to make a
reference genome for the whole world to
use we're gonna put a public and this is
going to help people design better tools
in the cannabis field because the
current references we have while they
were beneficial for the last few years
the technology today can make them far
far better so we'll be presenting on
some of that work and all the sequencing
we've done with single molecule
sequencing and piecing together this
genome into work right now the
assemblies we have are better than the
human genome project was when we
assembled it for the White House back in
2001 when we had a party at the White
House over the human
project completion the size of the
context of the human genome we're about
500,000 letters long the average number
of a that's what they call the m50
number so half of the genome rests in
pieces that are larger than 500,000
letters of time we now have cannabis
genomes that are better than that and we
think the deserve some celebration as
well and we're going to celebrate those
at Kent met and and show you what those
genomes look like what tools we use to
build those genome references and what
they enable because once you have better
references like this we think it
actually hosts it it opens up the door
for all types of epigenetic studies we
can now see that THC and CBD synthase
are actually on the same stretch of
sequence and the third they may be
interacting in some way so that's that's
a really interesting find and it'll
probably also help for people who are
trying to think about RNA interference
if you want to do RNA interference to
maybe throw it off pests and other types
of things playing in cannabis plant you
really have to know your targets the
same thing is true for any CRISPR cast 9
type of work we suspect the RNA
interference stuff will come first
because it's less of a GMO event it's
more of a way of applying foliar sprays
to modify the expression of the plants
or the pathogens but to do those things
you really have to have good cannabis
references and we like having them
public as much as they can be so that we
can keep this and open you know an open
form of science for the rest of the
community so we're gonna be showcasing a
lot of that can med and we encourage
everyone to come thank you
[Music]
you