[Music]
this study has been uh submitted and
approved through their IRB um we are
looking specifically for just really
simply uh two criteria basically are you
an adult we need 18 or older um there's
just too much uh complexity in trying to
get this info from kids hopefully can
start to uncover more about Pediatrics
later so we need you to be an adult who
either has been diagnosed with CHS or is
believes they're suffering with CHS
right we don't need you to be diagnosed
by a doctor but we we need you to kind
of think like this is this is what I'm
pretty sure what's going on um and we're
going to we got a Litany of questions
right it's two parts each part's going
to take about 25 minutes it's a long
time I do recognize but to make it more
valuable for you you will be entered
when you complete the survey into a
raffle for $100 gift card um we're
leaning towards Amazon but not the brand
drop uh but we're gonna we're still
figuring out where where that's going to
come from um but yeah it's we're really
excited to drop this two-part survey to
understand both the symptoms and use
patterns and then also the burden how
much health care you know how how hard
has this been on you and your family and
the truth is it's going to be what
organs did you have removed that's
literally a thing right did someone cut
out your appendix during the process of
trying to discover that all of this
inflammation was because your endocrine
ammonoid system was out of balance
because you've been smoking uh too much
cannabis or marijuana as they say
[Music]