good morning everybody thanks for
rushing out of the breaking coffee to
come spend a little bit of time with me
my name is Deborah kimless and I'm
really excited to share with you some
really interesting research that we're
doing through PG Pharma and some water
solubilized CBD and pea in addition to
me Consulting with PG Pharma and doing
exciting things I represent a bunch of
other companies as well I want to do a
shout out to Dr Mike from Entourage I
think he's talking tomorrow and a shout
out to the the sponsors here for
medicinal genomics RS by Therapeutics so
I'll go stop by their booth and talk to
them about some really cool stuff that
they're doing I also want to thank the
mckernan family
and Doug Kennedy for always welcoming me
to participate in this conference and to
create a safe space for everybody to
share their knowledge and really get to
understand things either within their
scope or outside of their scope in 2016
I was so proud I was there at Harvard
presenting a poster on using low-dose
cannabis oil to reduce or replace
opiates
in 2017 I shared some case reports using
low-dose cannabis oil for prostate
cancer and brain cancer and so why am I
taking this trip down memory lane when
we're really supposed to be talking
about diabetic neuropathic pain because
it's at this conference where Dr Raphael
michalum was sitting in front saying you
know there's a bunch of other molecules
out there cannabinoid like molecules I'm
not really sure why anybody doesn't look
at those and it hit me first the answer
was because you know they're not cool
they don't come from Cannabis and second
is because I'm not cool so I decided
that I would sort of explore what he was
suggesting so one of those was called
pea palmito ethanolamide and I did a
little bit of research played around
with it and then did what all scientists
do try it on themselves and then try it
on their friends and family and in 2018
I was able to present a little study it
was very lightweight in its robustness
as far as studies go but it really lends
some information and Credence to the
power of the combination of low-dose CBD
Pea in a sublingual tablet for the
treatment of mild to moderate pain and
we saw that it seemed to have worked or
my friends and family didn't want to
hurt my feelings
the folks at PG pharmace Steve goldner a
Visionary decided to take it to the FDA
and we all know that we need randomized
control you know trials that are blinded
and they have placebos and that was a
little bit scary for me so I said Steve
before we go ahead and jump into this
space let's figure out some dose
arranging studies and let's look at
whether or not there's some efficacy
so we did a single arm open trial
and so we looked at sublingual
cbda pea combination for the treatment
of painful diabetic neuropathic pain of
the feet why so specific because when
you go to the FDA they want an
indication specifically and after we had
our pre-ind meeting this is what we left
with
and so we looked at diabetics as a scope
for business because pure research is
great but does this make sense there's
over 37 million people in the US alone
with diabetes about a quarter 25 percent
of them or a quarter of them will end up
with painful diabetic neuropathic pain
of the feet
and it ends up being
a four plus billion dollar cost to
health care costs direct costs a year
so it seems to be something very
interesting to pursue there are already
some DEA FDA approved
medicines
is there a secret to this there it goes
and some are off label use some are FDA
use they all have variable consistencies
whether or efficacy as to whether
they're working or not there's a ton of
side effects from something mild to
nausea and insomnia to confusion to
suicidal ideation so we figured there's
got to be a better way
so we looked at CBD and pea they're both
uh you know very interesting lipids
Palmetto phenomide is endogenous to
humans and many plants sadly not the
cannabis plant as pointed out to me
again by my cousin Ethan Russo
um and CBD is of course a molecule of
Interest
especially since the passing of the farm
bill there were some studies looking at
these two molecules individually in
Mouse models for diabetic neuropathic
pain and you know multimodal cause
mechanisms of action but it seemed to
work and these are two Publications
supporting that so we we had a little
bit of proof and so they took steps they
meaning the formulators of PG Pharma
took steps in trying to improve the
bioavailability because these are fat
molecules so if CBD was complex with
cyclodextrin pea uh was Ultra micronized
and administered through sublingual
tablet
so again we did an open label study this
was dose controlled and was prospective
our endpoints were safety and efficacy
of course pain relief and then we wanted
to see what would happen with sleep and
anxiety
um
because those seem to be common side
effects when you have chronic pain so we
onboarded 31 participants 13 male 18
female they had to have an average seven
day NPR score so a Pain Scale score of
five or greater due to the their foot
pain we dosed them at 20 milligrams of
CBD plus 100 milligrams of pea three
times a day and we did this for three
weeks
and they were permitted to stay on their
pain meds as long as their Pain Scale
score before they were on boarded was
five or greater
and so interesting the pain responses so
if you look at the orange bars that's
the ones where the patients who continue
their medicines
for pain relief and the yellow ones are
the ones that never took it they just
sort of were sucking up their pain they
both had a very very similar starting
point for their Average mprs pain score
not statistically significantly
different from the two and then after
the trial
both of them reduced about the same
greater than three and a half points
it's pretty incredible
we also looked at their highest pain
scores again not statistically
significant difference although the
people on FDA and off-label use
medications at a higher average paying
scale score than those that did not take
any Medicaid pharmaceutical medication
and again they had a statistically
significant reduction in pain
so I find this incredibly exciting
especially for the next couple slides
too we did a hammy the Hamilton anxiety
score the higher the number the higher
the anxiety the lower the number the
better
again not a statistical significant
difference between those ahmeds and
those not all medications and again a
statistically significant reduction in
their Pain Scale score
same thing with sleep response we did
the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index the
higher the number in this case the
better the sleep
so and again no difference really
statistically between the difference of
the people on medicines and those that
were not taking any and again
an improvement
but the coolest thing was no adverse
effects now granted nf31 it's small but
it really did inform us as to whether or
not we should pursue this and whether or
not you know we should this dosing is
correct
so we did the scariest of all
the longest you know eight months of my
life randomized double-blind
placebo-controlled trial
using
the sublingual tablets
or endpoints for similar pain anxiety
sleep and then patients Global
impression of change it's how they
perceive they responded to the treatment
so we onboarded 54 people that were
randomized either active or placebo
we did get them off all of their
medication which was crazy
um the average
um duration for people for suffering
with this pdpn was greater than seven
years so they've been dealing with this
for a very long time
and all of these these studies were done
during covid so all this was
decentralized remote on web-based
platforms
so they had to do a washout period if
they were on any medication including
cannabinoids they were allowed to take
rescue Medicine of their choice either
acetaminophen or Ibuprofen
and the treatment again was for 28 days
so the interesting thing pre-treatment
the average mprs score for both both
arms was 7.3 the CBD group The CBD
randomized group was 3.6
um I'm sorry um 7.19
the placebo group was 744 so no
statistical difference and then after
four weeks
post-treatment dropped to 3.63 and the
placebo grew plateaued at about 5.7 so
they were statistically significant
reduction in pain in the treatment arm
same thing with the highest the highest
average was uh 8.74 for the CBD group
8.72 in the in the placebo group again
not a statistical difference in either
one of these groups pre-treatment and
then post-treatment a statistical
significant reduction in pain
4.93 in the CBD group and it plateaued
at 7.02 in the placebo arm
so I think this is incredibly exciting
but what I think is even more exciting
is what I like to say doesn't meet the
SOA test the SOA test means great you
have statistical significance but is it
meaningful to the to the patient so is
it clinically important
so it has a tremendous impact right for
us clinicians who are treating patients
we want to know great statistics what do
patient say
so the
mcid for pdpn of the fee believe in her
author is one using an NPR score is a
reduction in two so if you have a pain
scale score of eight and it goes down to
six patients actually recognize this
so the average change in this study in
this in this cohort the CBD group had a
reduction of minus 3.56 in their NPR
score versus the placebo placebo group
of only 1.74 so not only did it meet
statistical significance it meets the
SOA test
I should get extra minutes for this
clicker not working
interestingly the anxiety showed an
improvement in mcid but not was not a
statistical significance again I don't
know if r or this was not an anxious
Bunch this group had only mild to
moderate elevation and anxiety I think
our end might have been small or as what
you know Ethan Russo says small amounts
of CBD may not do anything for anxiety
so could be that reason as well
and sleep scale score same thing that
met the mcid requirement but was not
statistically significant I'd be
interested in seeing what a larger n
would look like with this treatment over
time
and the patient's Global impression of
change it's very interesting it's two
questions they look at you know activity
ability symptoms emotions overall
quality of life they look and say is it
better is it worse since treatment or it
really didn't matter and the people in
the treatment arm said yes they reported
a significant Improvement in all of
those scores
while on this on the medicine
and safety because at the end of the day
as a physician Do no harm right or try
to at least reduce it
in the safe in the CBD pea group there
were zero reported Adverse Events and
there is one case of abdominal distress
which led abdominal distress to me
because it was a placebo group and it
were blinded and I didn't know it until
I had a
check it at the end
so in summary for this
this is an incredible opportunity we've
been listening to exciting important
information and if you went to the uh to
the other group yesterday where they
were talking about we need more we need
more trials we need more research so
that people can get funding
these are the trials in research that
are important in that what people are
asking for so if there are any investors
out there or anybody who's interested in
Pharma development you know I put a
challenge to you to either you know
continue to invest in research like I'm
doing or come up to any of the companies
that are out there today you know if
this isn't exciting to you there's lots
of other cool stuff going on that this
is some of the things that you should be
looking for I mean I think at least in
this small group of people we've
demonstrated some efficacy with this
combination
but like as a nerd my favorite group The
Carpenters have said We've Only Just
Begun
and we then decided Well we you know PG
Pharma group that repackages this up in
a nice neat way
we think there should be smooth sailing
going to the FDA for for doing this
this is my backyard by the way
but there are always surprises when you
least expect it especially when dealing
with the FDA and so yes we are dealing
with lots of surprises we're answering
those questions a lot of the questions
require a lot of money so if anyone's
out there and excited about this and
want to participate this is our team of
robust uh smart scientists and chemists
and I thank you and if anybody has any
questions I'm willing hi Ethan
thanks for sharing
um my question has to do with the
reception you've had at FDA so combining
CBD or phytocannabinoid with pea and
endogenous and synthetic agent they must
consider this a combination medicine so
what are the problems what what are the
steps that they've made to go through uh
along the path towards uh acceptance so
excellent question
I wish you asked me that four years ago
when we went and had our pre-ind meeting
they did not mention anything
about that which was insane exactly but
when we submitted to openrind that was
the first question they asked and they
want to see a combination uh talk study
which is what our next steps have to be
in order to pull this through which is
not cheap
which is a shame
thank you so much for your work I'm
curious did I hear you correctly say
that you got them all off their
medications before starting this study
we we did we got them off of all of
their treatment for the pdpn not all of
their medicine so if they had issues
with diabetes or or right or wrong issue
or whatever they stayed on those meds so
you got them off like their Gaba the
gabapentinoids and the duloxetines and
amitriptylines and those types of things
you know how many of them went back to
that after this study I'm curious to
know
I don't know I didn't follow up with
that with that question that's
interesting I don't know congratulations
getting them off those meds thank you
as a fun fact our our protocol for the
FDA keeps patients on their on their
current medications as long as their NPR
score is five or greater
and that was a request to the FDA
any other questions
nope thank you for your time I
appreciate it