all right good afternoon and thank you
for joining us here today
i want to take a moment though to thank
canmed
for and their entire team for putting
this
conference on and also
the time for our panelists that they're
spending with us today
i'm the moderator today my name is
michael stromaitis
my friends call me big mike and uh
i'm the ceo and founder of advanced
nutrients we manufacture
a complete cannabis
growing system consisting of fertilizers
and additives
that optimize every stage of the plants
growth from seed to some essence
all right
so today's panel is going to be about
the role that nutrients play in yield
cannabinoid output and plant vigor
now before we get started i'd like the
panelists to introduce themselves
so i'm cal ravi i'm a phd in molecular
biology and i worked on plant nutrition
for more than 15 years specifically
focusing on ira metal nutrition iron on
copper specifically
my name is inia fear
i am the chief science officer at
canadasave been in the cannabis industry
since about 2013
or so
i've been a while i've been instrumental
in setting up a couple labs across the
state um currently at canasave uh
pretty much
was a growth leader in the space in
california
so we've been able to do that
successfully also co-owner of a
consulting company
but i'll stop there
hello i am allison justice and i am a
plant scientist
you'll probably hear it my accent but
i'm from south carolina
after graduation at clemson university i
went out to san diego
first time i've been back in quite a
while
in socal that is
but i worked for a
vertically integrated company
in san diego where we grew indoors
outdoors greenhouse
but currently
and for the last four years i am back in
south carolina where i have a hemp
company that's vertically integrated and
also a
a research company that we can get into
more later hope mentioned earlier
i really want to talk about the research
company um
so in the meantime hope jones
i got my phd at the university of
arizona plant sciences was my minor for
my phd was my major as an undergraduate
my phd work was actually in molecular
cellular biology and i was
doing cancer research and
i also worked at nasa researching how to
grow plants in space
and so and then i took a period of time
off from the hard sciences for a while
until the cannabis industry came calling
and then now i'm back full circle
actually which is very very cool um
because i
this is where i'm the happiest is where
i actually get to work with people and
work with plants so i get both of my
my two favorites but it's really about
um
to me i see it as as a as a playground
for us
and i cannot do it without the knowledge
of the people like you big mike and
other like my partners i work with
because i did not come from the industry
from the black market days and there's
so much to understand about this plant
that
um it's one of the reasons actually why
i come to conferences all the time is is
to help me be better at what i do by
learning about the
about these strains and these genetics i
mean it's just
it's been a long road for you guys
been a long road for a lot of us
uh the first question i got for for the
for the
panelists are what are some of the
commonly held misconceptions
that you found out about cannabis in
your research this is this is a a great
topic so what misconceptions about
cannabis and your research that you
found
so i mean
i don't know if it's a misconception but
it's at least a mislabeling when we talk
about micronutrients usually people
think they're not essential or you know
not as essential as nitrate phosphate
and in fact they're as essential as any
of the neutrinos they're characterized
as micronutrients because they
accumulate only at a certain level a few
ppm in the plant tissue
but they are more than essential and if
if i can take iron as an example because
i worked a lot on this nutrient
you know iron is utilized in directly or
indirectly any reaction in the plant the
two main reactions involving iron that
are critical are respiration on
photosynthesis
these two processes
are just the energy plant in a in a cell
and without this basically there is no
development
and just to capture one molecule of
light one quantum of light and to
transform it into
molecules that is useful for the plant
the photosystem which is a complex that
capture this light and transform it in
chemical energy require more than 20
atoms of iron
and any missing iron atom in this
complex will completely disrupt the
light energy
capture
for the respiration the same if you if
the plant doesn't have enough iron the
respiration will be compromised and the
plant development will be
dramatically affected so
i think one of the misconception is that
micronutrients are not as important as
macronutrients but micronutrients have a
macro function and actually iron is a
very example for that because life could
not have evolved without iron iron is
utilizing all the organisms nature
doesn't have any
hasn't found any ways to supplement iron
there are a few tiny examples where
copper or other metals could replace
iron in one protein
but life
is sustained
based on iron biochemistry so it's it's
more than a critical nutrient
that's great
you know i'm really here on the
analytical side you know you have this
great wealth of knowledge experts that
are sitting here more in um
growth but one of the ones that i've
heard is the correlation between
uh
your cultivar or your your strain color
with the potency and i don't think this
really comes from the seasoned growers i
think this is more of a layman's uh
general public i think in perhaps you
know when you get those vibrant purples
hues all those colors that generally
it's higher potency and of course being
in the analytical lab i get to you know
usually prove them wrong all the time
as a matter of fact i've been seeing the
reverse
um
i have a couple hypotheses about that
but i've sort of been talking to some
folks and really
why
what's the case around you know certain
colors uh when you have your
your harvested plant having certain
colors and having lower potency
initially my hypothesis was that it has
to do with sort of uh the ability to
you're driving uh your potency while
you're driving the plant to produce more
anthocyanins usually responsible for the
colors you know there's some other
things that could be responsible for
that flavonoids and whatnot um but
chances are you're pushing the plant to
focus on another part of its uh its
energy and something else rather than
making high potency uh thc or increasing
trichome size or whatnot
so i get to hear this a lot and
generally when we get that in the lab
you see that the lower
potency ones are also colorful
and i think allison here will be able to
tell you a little bit more later about
you know why that may be the case but
it's just an interesting misconception
that i hear out there
okay so i i would say my biggest
surprise uh being in the cannabis
industry is the application of
phosphorus
and so you know going back to to grad
school reading by the book yes
phosphorus is needed for flower
production
uh but if you're thinking of other crops
that
um other plants you know of course they
need phosphorus it's one of the
essential nutrients but
you know thinking back in grad school we
applied
eight ten percent with uh i'm sorry
parts per million
with 20 parts per million being kind of
that that top leveled out you know
that's the extreme
well when i got to san diego 2016 um you
know the the company i was working with
they already had a a cannabis nutrient
company that they were using
not not yours
um
we'll change that
[Laughter]
and so
you know the the the label seemed vague
and
me being used to actually taking
individual salts and making my own
fertilizers i i thought okay well i have
to figure out what's in here see what
see what's very different
and they were applying
100 you know up to 200 parts per million
phosphorus and flour which is just
mind-boggling um
because you know if you think of field
crops what's our biggest pollutant well
it's phosphorus
um and so even though you know the
mindset and cannabis is be be efficient
be uh sustainable um there's actually a
lot of pollution happening um you know
that extra phosphorus that you're
applying is going right down the drain
brian whipker at nc state has done some
great work and nutrition is for him but
you know i've got to play on both sides
and it's all the same
but he's got some excellent papers out
there showing you know well if you get
over 15 parts per million phosphorus
you're not doing any good you know
you're not getting more yield you're not
getting more potency
you're just wasting money and polluting
the planet
so you know i guess my takeaway is you
know a lot of the the misconceptions of
well yes phosphorus is needed for
flowering let's pump the phosphorus in
there that's it's kind of backwards
because as you know there's lockout
there's all sorts of other problems you
start applying more phosphorous well
you're going to block the uptake of
certain things specifically zinc and
what is that causing as a problem down
the road
so
know your nutrients yeah
yeah for me as far as misconception i
was shocked
one of the first presentations i gave
about six years ago i was talking about
virus and i showed a picture
because i walked into it at the grow
that
i was running and i was walking down and
so when i'm giving this talk the thing
that shocked me was
nobody believed that cannabis could get
virus
and so um
and still to this day i might hear that
occasionally but it shocked me
and and what was actually even more
concerning was with our own staff um
when i found it walking down the row of
in this particular facility the moms
were in the middle it was one large bay
in a greenhouse and so the moms were in
the middle
the clones were on each side of the mom
and then the veg plants and the teens
and early veg were over off to the side
and i'm walking down the rows and i just
was stopped
and i said to to the guys i said well
what do you think is happening here
and they said cow mag
and i get that answer a lot oh it's a
cal mag problem and you know what it
could be like it could be but then
that's when we engaged some of our
troubleshooting mental checklist okay so
if it's cal mag um the other answer i
got from the other uh
kid that was there and he was in charge
of watering he's like oh it's a ph issue
and i said it it could be
but do you measure your inputs and
outputs mental troubleshooting checklist
question number one
do you
if it's if it is a certain nutrient
deficiency or toxicity or
cation competition
and all the plants in this row were in
this room are being watered and fed the
same would you expect only to see it
randomly in these three plants and
different rows
but they're close together
those kinds of misconceptions and
everybody goes right to the nutrients in
their responses
when it came to disease that i think
that's one of the reasons
again this is my two cents in theory
that the disease status is so bad
because we're so good as an industry at
sharing everything or wanting to have
everything that is just killer and
killing it at the cups but we don't
quite understand our nutrients and then
the troubleshooting behind that that
things get away from us
and then now it's a problem that
we have to deal with at a national or
international level from a disease
status
you know
perhaps
oh i was just going to add to that
that's a great point real life
experience is uh we had a client
bring his plan to the lab you know it
was sick and they thought it was
nutrients so obviously we run hlvd and
and some other beat curly top viral
viroid on it
sort of having a little experience
around that and um sure enough it was
you know hiv did i was infecting his
plants i mean it was
pretty bad
even on the dried cured flower generally
which you don't test for we did and it
was evident that it was there and it
really wasn't a nutrient situation so
go right to the newts and also uh
hope did a really great paper for us on
hlv and you can find it at
advancednutrients.com forward slash
hlv carl i have a follow-up question for
you about iron what forms of iron
uh
can translocate and which forms of iron
cannot in the plant
okay yes iron exists in two forms the
ferric iron which is oxidized iron fa
three plus
and in a radius form which is called
ferrous iron two two plus
and i think
this is basically the source of its use
in biology
because once you have a protein that
bind iron this protein now have the
capacity to take an electron
from another molecule and to transfer it
to another molecule by changing its
balance between iron two and iron three
so iron lose an electron to give it to a
molecule and this is how all the
oxidation
reaction works in in living organisms
that's why it's so important in fact
and uh
so it also exists in the soil in these
two forms iron two and iron free much
more as iron free because iron is easily
oxidized
by oxygen so
there is plenty of iron on on the earth
crust it's very very abundant but
unfortunately it's all oxidized because
of oxygen from here so it's like
basically rust and this is this is very
unavailable to plants
the plants like cannabis because there
are different type of strategies
depending on the plant but plants like
cannabis used to take it up as iron 2.
so it has to be in its reduced form
which is basically very poorly available
in soil there is a very low amount of
ferrous iron so the plant have developed
some system in order to acidify
the root area in order to basically
transform this ion free into iron two
making it soluble and then a very
specific transporter
a kind of channel on the root cells can
take up specifically this iron too
now cannabis is also a secondary system
that can take up iron free but iron
three needs to be chelated to different
molecules organic molecules and as a
complex iron free plus organic molecules
these can be taken up by the roots by a
different transporter
and then in one it gets inside the plant
iron is so reactive by changing
electron of taking electrons from other
molecules it's actually a very dangerous
element to deal with so it has always to
be chelated into the cells in order to
be less reactive
so it is true it is basically
transforming across the plant and
translocated to the chute
in the form of iron-free
citrate iron-free iron-free
nicosagonamine which are all organic
compounds that allow to transport the
iron-free into a soluble
form
to the different parts of the plant and
to prevent its reactivity it's
uncontrolled reactivity with other
molecules
and when it gets to the chute if this
iron needs to get to the chute to work
in photosynthesis
once it's it's in place in the protein
then it's more it's safer and it will
work on in that context and it's not as
reactive but transporting iron from the
roots to the sync part is a very very
challenging
trip for hyrum and for the cells
right also i'd like to add about
phosphorus phosphorus carries a lot of
heavy metals so not only are you
polluting the planet throwing your money
away you're also
you know not thinking about the best
interest of your patients
what are some of the differences that
you found in the different cultivars
that you've worked with
you know i can go as far as analytically
really the differences have been uh
their affinity speaking of metals their
affinity for metals um we found that
depending on your cultivar
you can feed a whole you know grow with
different cultivars the same nutrients
over time same environment but at the
end end up with different residues of
those levels uh residues of those
compounds
in the finished product um
took a while to sort of figure out why
this is but really it's simple it is
cultivar dependent as we know this plant
is a you know everybody knows to buy
accumulator right so generally holds on
to these things however
i guess a rate at which they also
release is different and due to the just
general vascular nature of the plan and
and whatnot i'm sure you guys are aware
we found that um
even through flushing
you cannot get rid of them at the same
rate through your different cultivars
you know we've seen in situations
something like cadmium for instance a
certain
grower
feeds the same nutrients everything's
equal generally
and then somehow one particular cultivar
ends up failing all the time for cadmium
and you know scratching our head why is
that why is that
you know there's really no clear reason
apart from the fact that it just holds
on to that a little bit differently i'm
sure there's much more that can be done
to find that out but that's what uh i've
really noticed that has anyone tissue
cultured it to see
yeah i think they're getting that done
now after we've gone through exactly why
that really is you know at the lab we
can only offer so much analytical help
and yeah we'll help you figure that out
but you're gonna have to go through
tissue culture yeah get more information
i look forward to that data
actually it's very interesting because
cadmium usually accumulates when iron is
deprived in the media right because when
when the plant feels
a lack of iron
the plant the genetic programming of a
plant is changing in order to sanitize
much more of a transporter to get this
iron you know so the roots are expanding
and then there are a lot of transporters
to be able to capture any atom of iron
available
but if there is no iron you know the
roots are still seeking for it making a
lot of transporters and unfortunately
the transporter is not specific enough
so when you have a lot of iron
transporter in the root system but no
iron to be captured it will take up
cameo so one of the main effects of iron
deficiency is often a cambium toxicity
because the system is sucking calmium so
if you have cadmium contaminant in your
soil in your substrate then obviously if
you have imbalance of iron you will have
canyon
loading into the plant so
this is something to investigate because
perhaps it's related to that yeah i'm
happy to get that yeah
so even we're learning up here
i
i guess for me the the most evident uh
nutrient deficiencies i've been able to
see between cultivars
you know
very evident
very quantifiable is
nitrogen and magnesium
you know we have hundreds of different
phenotypes in our greenhouses and you
know we we feed them uh one recipe you
know it works for
the majority of them
but there's a couple varieties that you
know
it will very evidently show it's still
hungry
and it's got the classic signs of course
of nitrogen
and others with magnesium and so you
know for us
to make life easy because we want life
easy as growers you know we'll take
those specific varieties and just do a
top dress
so it gives it that little bit extra
boost but as far as the whole greenhouse
you know we're able to just have you
know our certain stock tanks of um just
a very easy one fade
you have a
with your work on calcium could you talk
about that foliar feeding the different
types of calcium and when to apply it
absolutely so
calcium is one that that we feed every
single week
you know the amount that we feed it
seems
crazy
seems like it could be toxic
but a lot of that work comes back from
research that
my old major professor has done on
certain things like petunias and
geraniums
and what he's been able to show is you
know with a certain
uh foliar application of calcium you
know what we're doing is building cells
building a plant that's tough and so
whether that's um
you know the infection of fungi whether
that's
insects
you know what we're doing is building
those cell walls and so you know calcium
in many forms if applied foliarly thank
goodness it's not toxic
and so what we've shown in petunias and
and what we're seeing now in cannabis is
that you can apply rates every single
week of 500 parts per million which is a
lot
if you think of what you might apply uh
through the roots you know it's
50. uh so significantly less
you're not going to get toxicity you're
just going to get uptake and really
build that plant's natural
defenses but the one thing that is
extremely important to understand is
that calcium is not just calcium it's
attached to something else
and so
the common forms are calcium nitrate and
so nitrate
nitrogen and calcium chloride
basically what you put down when it's
snowing to to make you not slip
um
but you know it's getting more and more
popular for people to talk about crop
steering you know it's it's a huge thing
that people have known for forever and
tomatoes you know certain nutrients
certain things will make a plant steer
more vegetative and certain ones will
make them steer reproductive and so
you know i guess the takeaway here is if
you're growing a vegetative plant and
whether this is in propagation or
as mother stock
you know you you want to apply calcium
nitrate
this encourages that vegetative growth
this applies nitrogen that maybe you're
lacking
from bottom feeding
but that is the form you want to apply
if we think about when switching to
flour if you continue with that calcium
nitrate for their application your buds
will be funky
they'll they'll stretch out the plants
thinking i i'm trying to flower but you
know this nutrition regime is making me
think that
i'm wanting to stay in the vegetative
state so
the takeaway here is you know go from
calcium nitrate into flowering where
you're at calcium chloride same thing
you know up to 500 parts per million
calcium
and
so far it works very well
i have a question about that so when
it's going in a flower and you see those
colas starting to stretch is that a
similar
to the monkey tailing which we know is
more of a light stress signal so how how
how different is this from that that's
pretty cool
so
i've always called it foxtail stealing
that
i like monkey though
in my experience what i've seen with
that is it's it's kind of just the the
tip of the flower that's making this you
know weird curl and elongation
whereas when we see when we apply
calcium nitrate the whole flower is just
kind of exciting i got you yeah yeah and
uh even though
in our research we see a higher yield
that's great if you're just going for
extraction but if you're going for
aesthetic
you're not going to sell that it's very
ugly
so i think it's a little bit different
but
same concept which is a whole other
rabbit whole week it jumped down
specifically the crc is cannabis
research coalition is going through um
lighting work and you know what we're
seeing
everybody knows the two-week stretch you
flip to short days and there's a stretch
what we're seeing is that that stretch
is based off of
um
cultivar dependent but also based off of
how many hours is your short day
if you have if you switched
directly from you know 18 or 24 into
eight hours it doesn't expand as much it
doesn't stretch as much if you go
straight to 12 hours
um
you know you're you're going an extra
third of the plant
so
you know still tons to figure out but
that's that's kind of what we're seeing
on that that's dramatic like from a
yield perspective too wouldn't it
absolutely absolutely
all right one of the things a common
theme i've heard here i've hear
growers say fertilizer is fertilizer
and actually it's not the inputs and the
forms of those inputs edta dbta or eddha
let's say for iron matters how the plant
is going to uptake it and use it calcium
nitrate versus calcium chloride and
flowering so would you agree with that
yeah
something interesting is now with the
knowledge we have about regarding you
know our genes are used in these
different nutritional status you know we
know for instance during iron deficiency
what genes
are on
in order to sanitize protein to take
more iron so i think with all these
transcriptomic analyses we can have a
diagnostic basically on the nutrient
status of our plants for calcium for
iron for any for nitrate for any
nutrients so now we have the access not
only to look at the plant or look
at the final yield we can basically in
real time pretty much a couple of hours
know exactly what the status is in
different developmental stage in order
to optimize basically the whole
nutrient program during the world
development of a plant so i think now we
have very powerful tools to improve our
formulations and
you're talking about looking at the
molecular level yeah right
all right next question so what
in research or anything that's developed
in cannabis get you guys really excited
uh
i i'm excited about the capabilities
that we have
today to
to transfer some known mutations that
could potentially make a cultivar much
more nutrient efficient
just by taking mutations that are known
in different plants or in a specific
cultivar that you don't have access to
or
you you like this attribute but you
don't like all the other attributes so
to be able to take that specific gene
variant and to copy it in your in your
own cultivar of interest that you want
to improve and using genome editing
which is a brand new technique to make
some
genetic modification without being
called a gmo
is a very powerful technique that is
opening a lot of avenues in order to
develop
elite varieties that will use
nutrients in a much more efficient way
that's great
um analytically
i'm really excited to move away from thc
um and then
thank you
um yeah don't take that the wrong way
but the focus on thc is a huge issue
right the plant provides so much i mean
a viewer in the medical practicum or any
of these talks you keep hearing about
whole plant medicine and how all these
other components of the plant help
whether in just um
passage into the bloodstream and whatnot
but i'm excited to
refocus
i'm really actually right now i'm
focusing on flavonoids um i mean there's
much more to be learned about flavonoids
but in the nature circle industry
flavonoids have been known i mean you
can buy vitamins that are strictly
flavonoids um they're anti-inflammatory
responses
or activity and whatnot
there's so much more and there's plenty
of them in the cannabis plants including
you know cannabis specific ones like
canned flavon um so that's something i'm
really doing a lot of work on currently
to
learn more and we know that nutrients
and environments have an effect on those
compounds as well so
as much as you know nutrients have a
huge impact on your thc output
and the rest of the environment
so along with the other components that
are medically useful as well
and i think we really overlooked that
what i've found is that those flavonoids
actually differ quite a bit from
cultivar to cultivar so
from seeing canned flavon at high
residues in in in some high thc
components uh separation between the a
and b form and you know 17 other
flavonoids that i've seen so far
is really interesting and i'm excited
for the industry to at some point
hopefully in the near future start to
refocus on the whole plant medicine
rather than just um you know high thc
so for me it's uh it's photoperiodic
response
um and so you know now being in south
carolina i'm outdoors
and it's not as easy as 18 hours 12
hours i have to understand at my
latitude
when will these flower when will these
plants initiate flower when will they
finish when do i have to get my
regulatory tests where i don't get
charged for a federal
crime for one percent thc
um you know i have to understand this
backwards and forwards
and so
you know what i'm seeing with with the
varieties i i deal with is that
you know maybe not all autoflowers are
actually truly
um
not photosensitive
you know what i'm seeing is well if you
take that autoflower and you put it at
18 19 20 hours
it's gonna stay vegetative and so that
means it's not truly an autoflower
well with a plant like that
it's special and if we understand the
photo period and we understand how to
work that plant it's special
so just for example say you know you
have a plant you take clones from it
you keep it vegetative you plant
you plant it in your greenhouse you
can't afford light depth you don't want
to pull black cloth because it's
terribly annoying and you raise the
humidity and all sorts of other problems
well instead you grow a
i'm coining this term i don't know
semi-auto
um
where it is
it it is photoperiodic but very
different than than what you know
we're used to
um so instead you know you're able to
take clones from this plant because you
kept the mom at 18 hours
you plant a greenhouse full of it all
you have to do is put up
you know very inexpensive led string
lights
all year round because nowhere in the us
gets over 18 hours of light
you keep those plants vegetative you get
them as big as you want you turn those
plants off and they flower year round
back to back to back
and so it's just you know understanding
how
light affects those different varieties
i think we can really take advantage of
that really save you know for the grower
save time save effort
and do what we need to do but easier
it's hard to follow
so for me i think one of the pleasures
has been seeing more and more scientists
enter
this industry and working with
the people who provided this industry to
us right so we're all here
because of everybody before us and
there's nothing more amusing to me
to see
somebody who's been in the industry
growing for 30 years start talking
already like talking like a scientist
but not getting the credit starting to
get more credit and and still talk in
the talk and then more scientists
talking like bros
it's actually been
it's been wild because i it's this
merging of these worlds that should have
always been together
that we now are able to start doing the
research that we have
should have been doing for decades and
decades and we can start understanding
regional differences
in in our genetics which is something
that has been very hard
i know with doing hemp production and
selling clones or seeds nationwide
how is any one company going to have all
that data to be able to speak to you in
washington versus somebody or even
really truly understand the genetics
and have the confidence behind the
genetics to talk about that so those are
the things that actually has been nice
to see
well what gets me excited about the
future of cannabis
is mirroring three technologies together
and and that is number one genetics
then the growing environment and the
fertigation program
there is technologies out there with
crop steering uh that are
more and more coming out all the time
that will actually give the grower
god-like control in an indoor
environment over the plant and that
keeps me up at night and gets me excited
uh because once you put those three
together you can truly optimize that
plant to its true genetic potential
okay
yeah sure i want to add one more that i
just
because justin and i were talking about
this earlier before our panel and
i think probably what motivates us as a
business and i am kind of speaking for
you here but you said it too so i'm
making sure to dish out the credit but
it's something that has always been a
part of my model
and do currently with everybody but we
don't talk about it enough and that's
actually working with breeders so as as
a tissue culture company
yes we can get into the idea of doing
that biotech kind of breeding and the
hybridization and stuff
okay i'm gonna
we'll do that but why would i not
why would i
waste all my time only doing that and
not actually working with these breeders
that have these amazing strains and why
would you want to work with us
and so
you know my argument for that is because
when you put your brand out it needs to
be represent
your brand and that plant or that
cultivar and its best
possibilities its full genetic potential
and right now when people are buying
clones from nurseries and their disease
does that representing your brand well i
mean why not work with groups like us
where we can actually it's your brand
it's just we're producing those clean
stock plants for your brand through your
brand and we do everything through
licensing royalties mtas everything
should be on the table and and be an
option
and and that to me is going to be the
most exciting next two years for me
personally going into a new lab in in
arizona being able to do that because
no one group is going to have all the
flavors of the rainbow
you know there's so many
so many good
strains out there and breeders who are
not getting recognized because they may
not be the big you know
10 seed packet going for a grand but dan
well should be um and so we can get more
of that vegetative material out with
working like with our groups i agree
there's there's kind of a conflict
between let's call the legacy growers
and what's happening now in the
marketplace and a lot of them aren't
coming out of the woodwork and they
absolutely should they have absolutely
just killer strains some of these things
giving 42 thc who knows what minor
cannabinoids they could have in there
and you're right there should be
licensing deals between companies and
and growers and they shouldn't be
weary and afraid of as they call them
the suits
yeah i do think that there's not been
any favors done by previous you know
mistakes out in the industry and so the
best that we can do is just say look
this is something that we can do we can
do it right we can be transparent we can
do things
but damn get out there get your brand in
the market and let's let's represent it
in the best possible way and it's a
win-win for everybody
yeah and it's it's doing you justice to
your work it's not trying to be stolen
from you so thank you for pointing that
out absolutely
so
what grower specific advice do you have
for the audience
grower specific advice for the audience
i mean i would i mean if we talk about
nutrition on
the nutrient formulation you are using
either you are using a commercial
formulation and you just have to follow
the label if you start playing with
nutrient it's very difficult i would
warn you that you know as soon as you
change one
one nutrient quantity perhaps in order
to find the optimal dosage for high run
let's say in one with one basic
formulation you identify
you know android micromolar to be the
optimal concentration of iron if you
start then to change nitrate and
phosphate in the original
formulation it will now the optimal
amount of iron will be completely
different because all the nutrients or
most of the nutrients are interacting
together and we don't actually today
understand exactly how they interact
together so trying to trick you know
formulation on your own is a very
careful approach and i would definitely
advise you to not do that or just
to do it scientifically with
the proper approach but not just you
know gamble on your crop by just
changing one nutrient because you know
just 1.5
i more iron as you should you kill your
plants so
trying to optimize nutrient formulation
is a professional job i would say and
you have to have the capability
and many experiments
if you do it in your basement then
obviously you might have backed your
prices so
this would be my advice don't play with
nutrients as you
you wish yeah going off of that it's
really great in the laboratory we
generally have growers who want analysis
of their nutrients
either
what they've pre-mixed or what
the soil around the plant
or the runoff and and a lot of times we
end up missing sort of the whole picture
so
you want to do sort of a mass balance
right you want to okay what was your
input what's left around the plant
what's in the vascular powder plant
maybe you take a root and we analyze
that and then
what's being flushed out take a sample
of that and analyze that and sort of see
that mass balance i mean um also making
sure that your lab is even testing for
the right analyze like you say you know
the iron the various iron oxides and
what not making sure you're testing for
the right analyte you can't just test
iron it's like which iron
and then you need all that information
in order to make an informed decision
as he was saying to change a certain
nutrient right if you don't have the
full picture you go ahead and change
something that perhaps could be very
detrimental to your plan you know
it helps you especially when flushing as
well right whether you're using a
pre-mix or you're doing your own
ratios you need to know and get that
whole
picture so make sure that when you do
ask your lab for nutrient analysis that
you're taking it from several different
areas to get a whole picture and do like
a mass balance that way you can make a
better informed decision
i'd say i i appreciate these guys
so 2016 which is and is not a long time
ago
you know i
i'm growing plants legally
and
i want to take tissue analysis
you know i spend days and hours on the
phone trying to find someone to take it
and give me data and no cannabis is
legal no cannabis is illegal
and so what do i do well i dry it and i
grind it up and i send it off and say
that it's tomato
that's all i could do
and so they send me results back and i'm
like all right this is great well
you know usually when you get a report
back they compare it to something
um and so they can compare it to tomato
well
sure it's it's a great starting point
but
there are some differences i mean
they're going to need something a little
different
and so you know for for years all i had
to go off of well is this plant looks
good
what does that mean
um
i want my nutrients to match this well
then you get into well there's a million
different varieties and
so it's tough
but i guess my point is
you know i'm very grateful for
him being involved has done a lot you
know there's universities getting
involved that are testing thousands of
plants
and they're able to give you that bell
curve of well this is deficient this is
toxic this is the range you want to be
in it might not be perfect for your
variety but it's at least a range we can
work with
and so not to brag on him again but
brian whipker at nc state
i think just a month or two ago has put
out new standards of of what we should
you know at least a rough range where we
should attempt to be in and so you know
having analytical testing you know all
over the place now is amazing and so i
guess my advice would be use it use it
hey so i'm i'm in the same boat um
and and having previously been cso for
analytical lab
you know first of all and i'm going to
explain why but dump your ipa stop using
ipa within your cultivation facility and
i'll explain why in a second
and then second of all get to know your
lab
get to know your lab i mean i had this
guy francis call every morning and he's
a chef over in arizona and he literally
has turned himself into an analytical
chemist and because at 10 a.m aaron who
was running the lab you'd be like that's
francis
and he would stop and he would take the
phone because francis would ask
questions nobody's gonna this stuff
isn't intuitive for anybody and
especially when you're trying to dial in
you want to be able to make
a phone call and talk with your lab and
so now that we can be open in the out in
the open about what we are testing um i
think it's important to know your lab
and one of the things that i learned by
knowing my lab
is the substrates i've been having
trouble with substrates soilless peat
core and um you know it's it's a
variation and if it's going to be that
what the starter charge is going to be
which i mean the whole thing is really
important especially for a tissue
culture company because i use a diluted
nutrient solution
on my um hardening plants and so if i am
you know
subculture or transplanting my cultures
into a substrate that has
terrible quality control or
has
aspergillus is the biggest problem that
i have seen um aspergillus is that
organism that emit um that has the af
that produces the aflatoxins that we
have to test for from a compliant
perspective
so my advice is to test your substrates
know your substrates know your labs i
would have never known that the
companies were having problems until i
spent like 20 minutes in the lab when i
was dropping samples off
and i happened to mention in passing and
they said we've been noticing the same
thing our farmers and the growers over
in yuma are saying the same thing so
they actually called up the vendor and
or some of their vendors and was asking
and it was the cannabis industry that's
putting
you know at the time this was probably
about four years ago was putting a
stress on the supply chain and they were
having the source from different areas
and they didn't have time to keep up
with everything i would have never known
some of that behind the curtain aspect
if i wouldn't have known my lab and
talked with my lab so then does
aspergillus will ipa kill aspergillus
well um
will ipa kill virus when you're in your
grow
no it does not
it does not
so by putting your tools into
ipa you're doing nothing to mitigate the
spread of your
viral
loads much less you're doing very little
to kill really what's
plaguing and and aspergillus is a
problem because i would i would
pasteurize my substrates then i went
straight on to sterilization of my
substrates well the reason why i totally
understand now
in a different way than i did before the
reason why we test for aflatoxins most
of the states is because aspergillus can
survive high heat
it can survive a lot of chemicals if
you're not actually breaking that
cellular wall you're not killing that
microorganism and it will survive
sterilization so when it survives
sterilization and then it you moisten it
and in my lab i put it in a bend with
with a lid over it well now there's no
competition
oh aspergillus is i mean you could see
it through the bends so test your
substrate snow your labs
you're seeing that in cocoa and peat yep
both okay yeah yeah it's
it's terrible
so
if you're failing consistently for
aflotoxin look at your substrates
so
i want to make growers aware that there
is a shift between macro
micro and secondary nutrients between
the growth and the flowering phase and
it's quite dramatic and it will affect
your yields if you do not get it correct
what else
all right let's uh open it up for
questions
we're doing a q a we have a few minutes
left are there any questions good timing
yeah the thank you to uh to the
panelists for a really fascinating
discussion
so question to the panel
what approaches are you seeing
if any that use beneficial bacteria or
fungi
to influence plant nutrient uptake and
bioavailability
and that's to the panel and to you as
well mike
you understand the question
just where i heard you right uh what
what bios are used to help with nutrient
uptake so anything using uh
bacteria or fungi to affect how the
plant takes up nutrients or
so in my experience um you know we do a
bit of contract research for you know
large-scale hemp production
and and help you know the prices are so
we have to be very careful about what
our inputs are um and so uh two specific
companies uh new leaf which is a
bacteria and uh pro-mix which is a
mycorrhizae uh what we did with them
this past season was you know it you
couldn't
you cannot take these products and apply
them to 20 acres at a time
you know you every week it's impossible
you would make no money
um but what
does make sense is taking your clones
and doing a significant drench prior to
planting
um and so it's a one-time application
and you know we we went through the
steps you know elemental analysis
yield potency
um and so what we saw with these two
specific products you know there's many
others out there but with these two
and it was consistent with the two
is that it did not increase potency it
did not increase yield
but being in the southeast where it's
hot and crazy humid
um and it doesn't get cold enough to
kill most of the
pathogens off in the native soil you
know we have terrible pathogen problem
pressure and so but what it did do
is it significantly reduced disease
pressure
and so for us that was a huge win it
wasn't just well you took up nutrients x
amount more
it was
you basically saved the life of this
plant
so that was kind of the takeaway we
learned in actuality it did increase a
few minor nutrients but that didn't
equate to
what the farmer wants being money you
know yield potency
thank you
if i may add one more thing to that just
as you use that be certain depending on
your state or your regulations that it
may lead to a microbial failure if
they're looking for total aerobic
organisms and whatnot in california it
wouldn't because they're looking
specifically for pathogens
such as aspergillus and e.coli so just
be aware that it doesn't get onto your
final end product
uh thank you
i i want to commend you for
acknowledging the role of legacy
breeders and the importance of
integrating them into the
into the industry and to that end since
we have a fairly big audience here i
just want to announce that tomorrow
last thing in the small room right
before you go off and party for cinco de
mayo
the impacts of legalization on the
cannabis legacy and the need for
solutions to create a healthier industry
so i hope
some people will attend that
it's really important and i just want
also put in a shameless plug for
my company breeders best i work with
ethan russo and rob clark and we're
doing exactly what you talked about
bringing in genetics from legacy
breeders that have been doing this for
decades and trying to find markets for
them so
look us up give us a call we want to put
some genetics out there
good pledge man
so is there a preferred ph to the foliar
application that you were talking about
with the uh
cal mag
you know i
i would imagine there are extremes that
would be detrimental to that
but in my experience
in the in the broad range of
acceptable
there's been no difference
i'm going to rely on you on that
question at the extremes of
foliar nutrition and ph and ph
yeah obviously i will confirm that the
two extremes are bad then after
obviously for metals you prefer rather
acidic quite acidic which is not good
for over micronutrients like nitrate i
guess
so it's a thin balance between you know
having a good equilibrium for uptake of
all the nutrients
rather than optimizing
you know for one but basically you will
deprive your plant of nitrate if you
optimize only for metal so
so i think plants have evolved you know
to grow in the kind of soil ph's and
obviously very some genetic diversity
depending on the type of soil plants
have been able to evolve within a narrow
window but i think obviously in the
extreme you know below four higher than
hey perhaps it's more difficult for
cannabis to to grow
and with the
with the observation of the semi-autos
would this be a symptom of the ruderalis
autoflower blending in with photoperiod
plants reducing the effect of the actual
production of the hormone based on
overshadowing or is this technically a
attribute that is coming out as its
individual statement
it's a hard one
um
you know the varieties i've worked with
you know it wasn't an intentional cross
of ruder alice and a photoperiodic
variety
that's a genetics question
that's not necessarily my
speciality so i'm not sure i would
imagine so but um
i'm unsure in our personal garden we've
actually been able to extend um based on
light intensity with autoflowers uh
after a conversation realizing that the
root oralist started out as an under
crop so basically as its competitors
grew taller the overshadowing would
hormonally trigger blooming and that's
just one of the reasons i was asking if
it's a cross between the two and
attributes because i know a lot of us in
the breeding culture
have taken the original land races that
breed and elongated sectional timings
such as the indica is going 10 to 15
weeks
and sativa is going 15 to 21 weeks or 25
in some regions and basically shortening
those by breeding in root oralist plants
i'm just interested to basically see if
that's a linkage in the instability
we're seeing with hermaphroditic
tendencies laid in bloom or if that's
something that's just promoting based on
our current practices and being away
from nature
so i didn't hear every word it was a
little bit hard it's a little bit hard
to hear
basically oh i'm sorry basically what
i'm asking is are we creating
instability by breeding in these two far
reaches
uh and are we seeing that as an
attribute to the hermaphroditic
tendencies in some plants that occur
late in bloom
uh i i have not been able to correlate
hermaphrodism with
i guess photoperiodic response
um
you know i think we're hybridizing just
about everything whether it's
photoperiodic response purple color
you know what whatever it may be
um and i think it's gonna it it really
goes back to um you know homogenizing
your your genetic line
um because sure one one cross of very
extremes you're gonna get a lot of
different types of children um but
picking that one you like and then um
you know
breeding to to support those
genetic traits you're looking for i
think that's what's gonna you know
stabilize it
um until then it's gonna
kind of be a up in the air of of what
you're getting
does that answer it i appreciate it
thank you
hi guys
my name is ali i'm with cannabis talk
101. this question is primarily for mike
and uh any but i'd love to hear from all
of you
how important is standardizing nutrients
to getting standardized medicine and do
you think there'll ever be a day that we
will be able to get such consistency
that we're almost at par with
pharmaceuticals
yes
we've tested
directly every competitor out there
we've looked at the cannabinoid profiles
and you can manipulate cannabinoids by
macros secondaries and micro
micronutrients and i talked earlier
about marrying genetics and crop
steering and fertigation that will give
you what you're looking for as well as
you know lighting and environmental
controls and all the sensors will be
involved you'll be able to steer that
plant in many different directions and
there's quite a bit of research that has
to be done we're just cracking the tip
of the iceberg
when we think about canvas and all of
the different effects that would be the
possibilities when you look at the
cannabinoid profiles
yeah it's really important you know i
was once in a production environment
um somebody was pressing rosin
and um
there were a bunch of new techs there
that he had to teach how to you know
press the rosin out and and do that
whole process and
he was really good at what he did but he
said that he couldn't really teach that
because
you know the temperature you have to
feel it you have to feel the pressure
that you press at you had to it's like
okay i understand that but that's not
how it should be it has to be
standardized you have to be able to set
a certain temperature you have to be
able to set a certain psi of pressure um
you know these are what sops are
necessary for
i think as we get uh
legalization or federally regulated
things have to be a lot more
standardized you couldn't just i get it
with the master growers they've been
doing it for years and they know what
they're doing but now the great
challenge is to get that written down in
a strict direct manner i mean that's
essentially what i do so when i'm
you know
creating a lab or setting up a lab i
couldn't just
put everything there and expect to do it
all myself otherwise why hire people i'd
have to run all the essays i couldn't
even sit here right i have to create
sops for people to follow and it has to
be standardized so that has to be the
same thing that we have to head towards
in this industry
if you're willing to or if you're going
to be able to produce
consistent medicine with consistent thc
levels uh other constituents flavonoids
whatever it that growing process has to
be standardized now i get it there's
always situations where there's disease
and whatnot um that could throw a wrench
into things but think about you know
shoot the
corn we eat right it's a very
standardized process of growing that
they're not just shooting at the hip
about it so it's going to be very
important i i agree it's going to be
really important one of the things that
i think saves our ass when it comes to
competing with the pharmaceutical
industry is the entourage effect
and so if we're going to do something
that is plant-based
and we want to mimic anything like what
we have within those trichomes you can't
do it by
only synthetics right and so there's so
much more research to do so
we do stand a chance in the industry in
my mind to be able to compete with
anybody if we're willing to put the
investment and training behind
proper facilities and hvac is one of
them it's the biggest mistake that i've
seen in almost every facility that i go
in is just
a crappy job of hvac or dealing with
what they have
then it comes down to tracking the data
and we need a baseline of genetics
so one of the problems that i see with
so much of even the current literature
that we're dealing with is until until
we have markers and we know a strain is
what it says it is
we have no
baseline as an industry now we have
years of anecdotal evidence when you
work with your plants regardless of what
its name is you know its growing habit
how do you replicate that on a
commercial scale and then to be a
commercial scale every commercial scale
industry deals with
new genetics coming in on a regular
basis we are so tied to our genetics i
have clients that will not
will not get rid of a diseased plant
because it's the last one that they have
and it's irreplaceable
that is terrible way to go about
business we but we care about our
genetics like they're our children and
our pets
and that's okay but then we need to
learn to maintain them so we have
healthy plants and children right so
there's nothing wrong with our way we
just need to meld some of additional
ways and finances into how to do that on
a commercial scale we can compete with
everybody
all right good question all right
well we've come to the end i want to
thank our panelists today and our
audience as well
thank you very much
[Music]