good morning uh third day I'm tired
um
first time for me in Florida
it's hot it's flat
but I came prepared I read up on the
Florida man
so that was my guiding impression for
this uh visit
but today
as the talk might indicate maybe we talk
about sex education
but I only have 20 minutes so I probably
get it through before DeSantis signs the
law Banning this topic
um
actually no we're talking math
um so the first question I have to you
and you can write down the answer
yourself and then at the end I tell you
you're wrong
uh in one of the later slides okay so
Mary Jane goes to a store and buys an
eighth of lemon OG The Strain has 23.3
total THC she rolls a half gram joined
she takes three puffs
so how much THC has she inhaled
anyone
I mean like all the other talks over the
last few days was all about consumption
of cannabis
and how much you should take there was a
low-dose talk like can anyone answer
your
no you're wrong and I and I actually
show you the data at the end
okay okay this is a hard one so let's go
for an easier one
um so if you want to buy Bubba Kush with
20.2 THC for 4.420
uh or lemon OG was 23 uh for 710 and yes
these prices are made up because the
numbers are funny
um which one gives you more bang for
your buck
because right now that is what a
cannabis consumer buys for and and the
ma the industry is trying to sell to the
consumer it's all about the total THC
number
okay so
um the less potent THC is actually the
better for the bank of the buck so
actually they shouldn't have bought the
higher one they should have bought the
lower one if they just wanted more THC
for the same amount of dollars
so this is weird right
um I find this
curious why the industry is doing this
and so the whole talk will be about why
are you doing this why this is wrong and
how can we do it better it's an idea so
here's a summary of what we're going to
talk about
I will
tell you how cannabis support today why
it's wrong
how could we do this better and I will
fight you for it like the Florida men
who got convicted for a sword with a
deadly rifle by throwing an alligator
through a drive-through window
but actually that's not efficient and
I'm all about efficiency so I wouldn't
use the alligator I'm German I'm kind of
a stereotype I have a PhD in chemistry
I'm German and I'm all about efficiency
and so my lab does all process
optimization analytical development and
all the other fun stuff of chemistry
um but I don't do this alone we do this
in collaboration with other research
institutions and researchers
um Verdian science
presented yesterday Mike Tagan and I'm a
good friend with his colleague Linda
clumpas but also at this slide I just
noticed that all the speakers from the
US they have private companies that
presented their work and then all the
Canadian speakers so I'm German but I
live in Canada my lab is there they all
are from universities the university did
this research and so on so same here we
work with UBC
um because that is federally legal we
have the licenses and we're allowed to
do this work
okay
um luckily for you I'm actually not
going through all the hard experiments
that we've been doing so we can skip all
the queue metrics and the kinetic
studies uh and it's more of a
theoretical or conceptual talk also um
as I see a picture a camera back there
you don't actually have to take pictures
of this this is being filmed I upload
this to SlideShare it will be on my
website at some point and the last slide
has all the references so take a picture
of the last slide
um oh yeah and in Canada we are licensed
to do mushroom and psychedelic research
so I have those compounds in my safe as
well
but for another day
so
how do we buy cannabis today
if you go in a store
it's it's all about the total THC number
how much THC by weight percentage is in
the flower in the joint in The Vape
cartridge and that seems to be the
number that everyone wants and everyone
seems to be complaining about it
because the producer needs to get the
higher number
but the testing lab is not giving it so
the producer tries other things or the
testing lab will artificially inflate
these numbers just to get their the
business
and there have been enough articles uh
in the recent memory that showed that
the labor claim is incorrect that
Laboratories are cheating and getting
caught for it that producers are
cheating and getting caught for it and
all that just because you need this High
number
but does this number actually make any
sense or do we even need this because if
we think of other Industries do they do
that
so in Pharma
do they sell by weight
not really so actually turns out two of
these packages actually three or all
three packages half the milligram of the
active substance in on their packaging
but that's not the one you look at
right
maybe the melatonin with the 20
milligram write down the label but the
others you don't really care about the
number you just know that
you need that compound or that drug
not how much
and then the other one so I like to ask
questions and participation by the
audience
which is the best wine to buy
I took this picture from a website the
10 most expensive wines in the world
so here um I think four of them are red
and there's one white which one is the
best wine
and all of you are wrong because it's
the Vodka it has the most alcohol
if we go by the logic of the Cannabis
industry that is the best product to go
to buy when you go on a wine store
and so you already see why I want to get
to if you sell by THC weight
you can't sell the right product you
can't really advertise your product you
can't distinguish your product
okay and then the other point is the
total THC numbers actually
mathematically incorrect
and it's easiest exemplified by pure
Crystal of thca
uh you might know the total THC number
is the THC percentage plus the THC asset
percentage with a weight correction
because THC acid gets lighter when it
decarboxylates so a pure a pure THC acid
Crystal has 87.7 total THC
does that make sense can a pure
substance be 88 pure
can't right because
you didn't listen in middle school
chemistry and in middle school math you
have to correct for the weight loss of
the sample
if you substrate weight on the nominator
you also have to do that on the
denominator
so this formula actually is corrected
and now it works
very esoteric very geeky why do we care
because you're underselling your
cannabis
all your cannabis would be bumped up in
total THC number if you do the correct
math
and here we meet again our laminar G and
Baba Kush
they bump up by nearly a percent point
if you have the higher potency higher
potency I'll get to that later
um cultivas okay
maybe to wake you up or why do we care
if we sell cannabis by percentage point
of THC and that defines the value which
we did we scraped websites online stores
of cannabis companies to find out if
there's a correlation between the sales
price and the THC percentage and there
is it's about 33 cents per percent point
of THC that your price sales price
increases so the industry is losing 400
million dollars a year
by not correctly calculating and yes
economists would May would agree that
then the prices would adjust but anyway
so right now 400 million so think of
that number because you didn't listen in
school and didn't get your math right
all the banned books that here in Canada
in in Florida with them that they ban
all the mass books wasn't really helpful
okay
um but there's a bad side to everything
because your hemp is hot
um and it gets even worse so I showed
you that we work with the university so
we get a lot of Co-op students so these
are undergrad students that have to work
four or eight months in a company to get
work experience and that counts as
credits so yes I have students that work
in cannabis and get uh get a degree for
that they love it
and they're super cheap because I pay
them a good wage but I get half the wage
back from the Canadian government so the
Canadian government sponsors a lot of
our research it's amazing like just
think of that that blows your mind as an
American
okay so cannabis you buy flour you buy
it by percentage weight of THC
uh you buy a cart Vape cartridge and
that is either in percentage rate THC or
it is in milligrams per gram
uh if you buy a brownie it's a milligram
per unit
and if it's a tincture it's a milligrams
per milliliter
like it's all over the place like you
need an advanced degree to just keep
track of this
and we had talks this morning and
yesterday
of how much cannabis to take and like
how do you how do you square that how do
you have an idea how one correlates to
the other
like a brownie five milligrams per unit
or a tincture both ingested
milligram per milliliter like
that's a different unit type right it's
really difficult to keep track of
so
here are some ideas
for new approaches and I'm not saying
I'm right I'm just saying you are wrong
and we have to change this
so my first idea is sell the bus
don't sell that weight
so yesterday evening and for some of you
all through the day
uh you enjoyed some alcohol
and everyone or you should be aware of
the idea or the concept of a standard
drink
and you know
intuitively you can drink a larger
volume of beer then you can drink
vodka or scotch
because the standard drink is a constant
unit of alcohol
so that a large glass of beer and a
small shot of whiskey have the same
amount of alcohol
so you just correct for the ingredient
and you vary the weight or the volume of
the product
and so if we take that concept and now
call it the standard dank
you could package cannabis by a
consistent amount of THC
so now you don't sell an eighth of flour
but you sell
a fixed amount of THC
and so your unit packaging might go from
three grams to four grams it just varies
and you don't actually care about the
THC percentage anymore the consumer
won't feel cheated because they get the
same amount of Buzz every time or the
same amount of THC and you can now start
labeling other things
request unit is standardized
and so here as an example your edible
would be one unit of of standard tank
and then a joint with 20 flour has 200
unit 40 units and it goes up for then
big cartridges and tinctures
so that would be one idea that is firmly
a new recreational world we just sell
you the THC
um
but we also have a lot of medical
presentations so
is there more of medical approach to to
labeling cannabis
and I think there is because you already
try you call it a potency
but it's not a potency like 20 percent
weight percent THC flour is not less
potent than 25 THC flour like you all
talk about the Entourage reflect and all
the other compounds it's it's not
potency it's just concentration what
you're labeling right now so can we
actually label it by potency
and for that let's just quickly take a
step back and think about so who of you
took the vitamins this morning
some of you yes how much vitamin C did
you take
no idea a thousand IU what does IU mean
no one has an idea so IU means
International unit and an international
unit is a measure of effect
has nothing to do with weight has
nothing to do with concentration uh
nothing to do with moles it is purely
based on the effect and it is also that
you can compare different application
forms Administration forms that always
give you the same effect so a pill or a
tincture would give you the same
international units of or the same
effect of of vitamin C so the weight
between the two products might actually
change
but you always get the same effect
so could we use that in cannabis
so if we call that as intoxication unit
we standardize it and just say that a
dose effect is 100 IUS
and
if we just think an IU is you get bust
and five milligrams of an edible make
you buzzed
how much
is that in a joint
it's maybe a puff
and I'm guessing here because I don't
actually consume cannabis so but I
assume that like a brownie or like piece
of piece of gummy and and a puff on the
joint is about the same Buzz rightly so
we just Define that as a hundred IUS
between the two products
so now
we would sell our products in multiples
of these intoxication units
and now it allows a consumer to go from
a joint to a tincture to an edible and
knows that they always get the same
effect
right that's all we're talking about for
the last few years to like standardize
the effect
so we could do that with an intoxication
units
and for CBD we ramp up the number
because uh the clinical doses for CBD
are way higher so you just hide that
underneath it because right now the
consumer has to remember that they
should take five milligrams of THC but
probably weigh over 100 milligrams of
CBD
so you can just all hide that under I
use
but that's difficult right
so maybe we should do the work like if
we want to be medical or pharmaceutical
we should put some effort in and it can
be done because back to our initial
question on the smoking side I have a
robot that smokes joints and I promise
you it's not my colleagues
we smoked cannabis both high THC and
high CBD
flour and looked at how the particle
size so the mill size of the flower that
we put in the joint affects the delivery
of THC or CBD to the to the consumer and
the particle size affects the inhalation
massively we can double the THC
delivered per puff by just Milling it
finer
so our initial question what does Mary
Jane get can't be answered because we
didn't mention in that math question the
particle size of the flower
and with that I don't care if your joint
is 20 THC or 25 or 30 THC the
architecture is as important for the
delivery as the flower ingredient
also the recoveries are really bad so we
are and that cap is consistent with
other literature
about 30 to maybe 50 percent of the THC
that's in the flower actually ends up in
your mouth the rest is just combusted
and goes off to other places
so
you're wasting a lot a CBD and I do not
understand why CBD is way more efficient
in inhalation like more CBD gets
transported and the recovery is like
quantitative and I have no clue why that
is but we have a lab and we will get to
that in the future
um and we can also do that for tinctures
yeah this is a peer-reviewed study we
did on a randomized triple blind
comparatively parallel studies like all
the buzzwords in there we actually
checked how different uh formulations of
CBD in liquid lead to blood plasma
numbers of CBD so yes you can do the
work
so parting thoughts
I'm not the only one who says that
there are also people from the emerald
cup Alex Dixon from from SC lab says
that over and over again you might sell
the first product on the THC number but
you're returning customers are coming on
other factors like terpenes like flavors
it's not the THC number
so stop advertising it or using that as
your Prime real estate on your Packaging
uh also right now the
consumer
that has been using for decades they
know the THC number new consumers don't
and they're way more new consumers than
the old consumers so we can't go with
the argument oh we can't change it
because that's the way it always has
been or it also has always been illegal
and we managed to change that and we
have way more potential customers coming
our way than than the old ones so maybe
we should put an effort in and change it
um
yeah don't sell weight and percentage
gsv sell convenient
and just a summary
standard tank is the mass of
cannabinoids and intoxication units
would be the resulting effects
and with that I think my call founder
Professor Glenn Summers and the whole
research team that
helped me in these experiments and kept
quizzing me why cannabis is done this
way
and with that this is the one for the
picture with the references
and I made it exactly on time thank you
very much
foreign