I'm also going to thank the organizers
which sounds very weird considering my
relationship here but it's true in that
anyone who knows me knows I'm not this
organized so many hats off to Doug
Kennedy in the cordon team here we are
going to be speaking a little bit about
decentralization and what the cannabis
industry is going through because when
you look at this from historical context
and you look at other industries when
this happens use do see real Renaissance
a curb we're not all the way there yet
as you've seen from many of the speakers
today there still is centralized control
over the cannabis industry and it leads
to one-size-fits-all thinking which can
be detrimental to watch the marketplace
but we're half way there were partially
decentralized with the laboratory of
democracy here where many different
states and countries are experimenting
and this experimentation is incredibly
healthy we hopefully will eventually get
to complete permissionless innovation
which will happen if it's a fully
decentralized environment but I don't
think we're there I think we still need
some tools to accelerate this we need
catalysts to get us there and when you
look at other industries have gone
through this those catalysts sometimes
actually require some order from chaos
as my brother just brought up so let's
take some historical examples that are
perhaps overused and a little bit trite
you look there's no technology
presentation you can do without talking
about the printing press so here we are
Gutenberg's printing press it wasn't
really the first book that presented off
it that mattered it was the fact that
anybody could print it and we've seen
this also with the internet we have a
very vibrant debate now over what's fake
news and what's real news and I actually
think that's fantastic because now
people are actually looking for
references and we actually have science
omit the scientific method inside of the
news agencies hopefully and it gets
people to think for their own this is
this is very very helpful we're seeing
it in the financial industries with
Bitcoin this is a centralized banking
crisis that we have that's all over the
globe right now and now there's
cryptography and peer-to-peer networks
that can do this a different way we have
a 30 billion dollar economy that's
booming out of this thing and it's gonna
play a role in all types of informatics
databases in the future and of course
now we are in a world where we can
sequence genomes out of things that fit
in our pocket I was actually afraid to
tell you about this and fear that this
whole audience would clear out of here
and go look at it but a Vaughn has just
set up a DNA sequence they're out there
in the hallway and it's sequencing a
cannabis genome
as we speak so go have a look at that
when this is over but this is gonna mean
that you can decentralize sequencing you
no longer need million dollar
laboratories with licenses to sequence
we're gonna see people do it in Africa
we're gonna see people do it in
Afghanistan and that's gonna change
fundamentally how we approach science
because many more questions can be asked
about the code of life as opposed to
having somebody to manage it to you what
it is by some written book this is
what's gonna happen in the next few
years it's already happening we have
million-dollar sequencers you may have
seen up with the Couture's accordion
they're turning into these things in the
next few years we have PCR equipment
that's probably 20,000 dollars to get
your hands on and it's turning into USB
based pcr devices you can see out on the
tables out there so when this happens
much more innovation is going to come to
the table because many more minds can
access this and many more minds means
much more innovation so to make this
innovation happen we do need a little
bit of a nomenclature system if you look
at the internet it runs off of tcp/ip if
you look at Bitcoin it actually has
everybody agreeing on a consensus and
everybody running the same code and
Gutenberg probably had a font size that
mattered these things help us
communicate when we want to decentralize
so I'm going to go through a couple
examples of this here we sequence things
of variety of different ways at ed
medicinal genomics and quarter gin
there's whole genome sequencing when you
sequence the whole 800 mega base genome
we put a couple thousand of those public
we have some strain seek version one
which we did many years ago we were
sequencing 3 million bases out of the
plant and you get about a hundred
thousand variants from that strain state
version two is what we're doing mostly
today there's eight hundred and fifty
thousand bases sequenced for that and
that gives us a nice ten thousand
variants or so we've put it four hundred
and twenty of those public just this
week many of them have been partially
public through canopy dia we got them a
little bit more organized recently and
I'm gonna touch on one that's a little
bit smaller than this a $450,000 or 450
thousand base pair panel that we use to
try and build a rosetta stone for all
the public data that's out there so we
can look at data in the same way and
then there are sniped genotyping tools
we're gonna touch on as well where you
can just genotype a couple snips to
really understand what's going on with
your plant so this is a phylogenetic
tree now that's up on canopy dia it's
actually an interactive one I don't
think I have time to bounce to it on the
on the website here but if you scroll
around in this these
apples will light up based on their
proximity to each other when I say
proximity I mean their genomic proximity
so there is a scale on there that's a
ROYGBIV scale red orange yellow blue
green that tries to designate if
something's within a clone distance of
one another a sibling distance of one
another or a distant cousin and so on
and so you can see from maps like this
you can quickly select a set that are
closely related and we also happen to
have hundreds of these things terpene
and chemo type assess so we can ask do
the ones that are very genetically
similar does it predict the chemo type
of the plant in the case of these ACDC
can athon declines they do we see very
consistent mersin signatures out of
these pining and busy bolo
we've also see this in a Terp inyline
class of samples that are quite
frequently found with the jack herer
class and the st. Jack's
and they come out with beta-carotene and
turpentine so the genetics are beginning
to give us a prediction tool for which
terpenes might in fact be expressed and
this can be very important if you want
to understand nomenclature and labeling
right so we didn't run around in
sequence about fifteen or twenty blue
dreams from all over the country to
figure out what is this thing and you'll
see that lots of them actually cluster
right up here in red but there are some
over here and some over there and some
of there and we see some people have
renamed them to snoop stream and there
are absolute clones of something else
and maybe they sell better we don't know
but that does go on and the question is
can you split this with something more
than sequencing 450,000 bases because
that can be expensive and we're gonna
we're gonna touch on that in a bit
the other thing that's going on in this
data set it's not yet public but we're
working to move it there is that we are
sequencing the microbiomes of these
we've done about 400 microbiomes of the
cannabis flowers occasionally on the
roots and about 10% of those have
actually been on samples that have been
terpene profile and the reason for this
is we know the microbes are playing a
role in terpene metabolism we know
they're playing a role in terpene
expression if you look at this wonderful
paper that went about using antibiotics
to fumigate the plants they see the
terpene expression changes if you
actually fumigate them with antibiotics
now this wasn't done in cannabis but you
can see the terpenes that are up there
imply that it'll probably happen in
cannabis these were very similar
terpenes little ol piney Mersin so
we're expecting a similar thing to occur
so we can't ignore the microbiome the
genetics are of course predictive but
it's the hand that you're dealt not
necessarily how you play it and so we're
keeping an eye on that now switching
gears a little bit here when you have
this much sequence density if you
sequence two you know 450,000 bases or
850,000 bases inside of a inside of a
cannabis plant you get it enough markers
throughout the genome to do what's known
as genome-wide Association studies and
you're just simply tracking the variants
to see if they correlate with a
particular trait a quantitative trait
loci they call it and when you do this
you start to get some signatures coming
out you need about 200 samples done done
that are profiled with your trait and
and you have perhaps they're altering
profile and not tripping profile and
when you do this we're already starting
to see some signature for snips that
might predict terpene expression now we
need to expand this with more strands
because we didn't have a whole lot of
terbutaline rich strains in this data
set but it's promising because this is
what we did with the human genome
project it worked very well so this
leads us to a rosetta stone panel that
we just recently caught and we have a
couple hundred samples deep into this
this is meant to triangulate all the
public data that's now public we have
many people contributing to cannabis
genomics now which is fantastic we've
got a data set from knowing Keynes lab
he's gonna speak about this we've got
John page here who's gonna speak about
all the data they've done we have
Philo's out Oregon who's doing a lot of
great work they've put 845 samples
public as well but the problem is we're
all sequencing different regions of the
genome so it's very difficult to take
our data and compare to theirs and
vice-versa and so we can't really build
a nomenclature system until we can start
to triangulate these things so we
decided to build a panel that would
sequence hundreds of snips from
everybody's data so that we can then
triangulate any one sample to everyone
else and while we're at it we figured we
all sequence the genes that everyone
cares about which are these cannabinoid
inter peen genes that that the VAM
Baykal paper described back in 2011 so
we have this panel running now and we're
beginning to sequence these to refine
some of these maps but I think what's
gonna distill from this is the capacity
to take all of the snips that have the
most discriminatory power in and distill
them into a barcode if you will and the
reason we want this is that these terms
indica and sativa anyone who's done
genomics will tell you they're
meaningless and people are putting these
on labels and giving them to patients so
we have to change this we don't mind
those historical terms but
thrown around but we should bring in
something that has a little bit more
digital signature to actually the
fingerprints of these strains and that
may also tie to the chemo type by
sequencing some of some of those genes
so what we want to do is sort these
snips that are quite potently
informative into an array that can then
get distilled into a barcode label and
when we ask that question we're
beginning to zero in and around 30 snips
29 snips maybe 27 there's some debate as
to how many exactly we need but it's
looking like it's a very small number
that we can use to distill any one of
those strains on that large map and if
that's the case it changes the way you
think about the technology and how
decentralize you can get so here's a
list of blue dream and what you're gonna
see appear on vertically are every blue
dream sample and the different snips
they have at the particular scaffold
locations in the genome and of course
you can see that all those red ones that
are clones have very similar snip
patterns and some of the ones that are
sitting off in the other areas of the
chart like at 8 o'clock and 6:15 and
10:30 they're the ones that are way out
here so we can readily discern between
clones siblings and things that are just
mislabeled with just 29 snips and we
think that's gonna hold true throughout
the rest of the tree which brings us to
the second part of this talk which is
how do we make this go to the grow
because there are state lines we have to
honor we can't move material we can move
DNA around we can't move leaf matter
around and we want to get the the grows
to be actually be able to do this on
site so there's a lot of people that
helped on this the reason I have to have
this Henry Ford thing up here is that
this would not have happened without the
help from New England Biolabs it would
not have helped and help or happen
without the help from Ike and chemical
in Japan it would not have happened
without amplia sand mini PCR there's one
of those devices out there I recommend
people see and we did play around with
some nano pores in the process as well
and we have one of those running on the
desk out there so what do we do well
let's use these six hundred and fifty
dollar USB drives that can do PCR these
are now available they're no longer
twenty thousand dollars they do not have
a detector head on them which is one
reason why they're very cheap they're
light enough you can get them up to the
space station they're sending one up in
the next mission I've heard it may
already be there
and you can't get them to the TSA I've
done that
they didn't have any issues with it I
didn't have to pour it out so it does
it's very portable very light but with
this it does eight wells of PCR you can
bet you can gang up two of them under
one laptop the asset costs are still a
little bit unknown it's around 750 it
should be cheaper than anything you put
the mail and the ambiguity here is that
we don't know the kit sizes people want
yeah we're collecting a lot of feedback
on that it could they could be big they
could be small and you'll see why that
matters momentarily and the other detail
here is that it works off a hole punch
one hole punch from a leaf and you can
get genomic information off of it with a
very quick prep that we have that can be
showcased outside and you get answers in
ninety minutes so this is much faster
than shipping in the mail and waiting a
day or two and the more important thing
that our lawyers really addressed on
this is that the reason we did this and
the impetus we did this was that we had
lawyers review whether we could put
leaves in the mail or put kaledin
stamped onto paper in the mail and all
of them said no they said you can put
the DNA in the mail and you can put the
hemp stalk in the mail if it's been
sterilized but you can't put anything as
photosynthetic onto paper and ship it in
the mail I don't make these rules they
do seem a little silly but the fact is
we would rather move the problem to the
grow then move the problem to our
database where it will become a
collection of people who have violated
the CSA privacy is in fact an issue for
many people there are cannabis patents
emerging and a lot of them speak to
genetics so this keeps it in your hands
so this little device can then run tests
like for the B D allele we did a lot of
single molecule sequencing to figure out
what snips are driving the BD allele and
some folks in this audience Adrian who
actually helped champion this stuff at
medicinal genomics and many others
medicinal genomics this tells you
whether your plant is going to be a type
2 or type 3 they cannot discern between
the homozygous or heterozygous aid of a
functional CBD allele but it can tell
you that your plants got the potential
to make CBD and usually it's gonna be a
50/50 or a tall CBD strain if you're if
this thing turns yellow on you so if it
doesn't turn yellow
you are THC rich strain and you'll be
pink and oh look that's the blue dream
in the ak-47 you can see up there the
other thing we can tell is male versus
female from this we have assays that
target the white chromosome so you can
get a color change if something's
male or female and there's a few other
tests that we're working on a touch on
momentarily if you want to scale this up
we're working toward cheap ways
that will get this in 96-well format as
well these there are some thermal some
hot plates from from thermo that are
around for new bucks a piece that can
get you going on this but they don't
have automatic timers on them so they're
not as you have to kind of control those
yourself so we did bring this out to the
field to several beta trials and we're
very thankful I think many of them are
here Connecticut pharmaceuticals the
Slater Center in Colorado seeds helped
us in this and every one of those sites
we learn something and change the
primers accordingly and I would just
give you what on the most recent one
that occurred we went out says Colorado
seeds very recently and ran 47 known
males and 47 known females we could
visually confirm they were male and
female and we were able to get a hundred
percent accuracy off of that that trial
we've expanded this since then and that
accuracy is probably more like 95% from
what we're seeing when we go out to
numbers of 250 and it's very strange
specific there is another version of
trying to sex Sam seeds where you look
at the size of the seed and some folks
think that they can determine sex from
the size in the shape of the seed we
have a high discordance rate with that
we don't know what the answer is for
those those plants are still not mature
but if we look at our concordance
compared to what we did with knowns we
think the seed sizing probably is still
a bit of a coin toss now we also did
this in the BD allele we went and looked
for the BD allele which is the CBD
producing gene all over the country we
did many samples that Sonoma Labs helped
us capture out of the Emerald cup we
went to Colorado and looked at a hemp
farm out there and we all detect all of
those and we also looked at the ones in
Massachusetts we've not seen a fail yet
on CBD these are all the samples we've
tested to date with it so if your if
your genome is in there this test likely
works for it we're always open to scan
more there's possibility that there is
an unknown marker out there we've missed
now this can obviously extend to other
regulatory concerns we can go about and
test any presence/absence test that's a
concern with the plants so if you're
thinking about Aspergillus if you're
thinking about a coli or salmonella a
lot of the lot of the regulated labs
have to test for these things we're now
in the process of converting those into
yes/no color metric assays these can be
done both and third-party labs and done
locally which is probably how the
industry should mature eventually the
manufacturers will begin testing before
they ship two to two labs it's just the
right thing to do we have a grant from
NIDA as well to fund this to try and dry
some of this technology into picking up
the
Oh toxins that's gonna require some
immuno PCR and there's a bit more to be
spoken about that and next year so
genomic scales very well that's the one
thing I want to touch on there's plenty
of time for it if anyone's been
following this human genome curve that's
Moore's law that's looking really flat
and slow there well the the genomics
race has actually gone way past Moore's
law on this and this is going to apply
to what we're doing in this space with
this colorimetric assay can we scale
this down such that these 25 micro liter
wells can quickly move into 96-well
plates but we've already done that we've
already moved him into ten market leader
wells into three to four bolt plates so
you can see these cost curves are very
elastic and we're playing around with
the system that does 1536 wells and
these 1536 wells are 2 and 1/2
microliters this is not hard stuff this
is just repeating history we did this
before in 1996 these can go even down to
6 nano liter wells if you really want to
get micro fluidics involved I don't
think we need that because when you
think about the problem we're trying to
address if it's just 30 snips we just
need a log scale of reduction so that we
can get an entire genotype of a plant
point of grow in one of these assays so
you can imagine all you need is your
camera to just take a picture of this
and you can hit canopy do you know what
it is and while you're at it you should
throw an Aspergillus powdery mildew and
a handful of other markers that you
might want to get out of your grow which
brings us to powdery mildew this is not
what we thought it was we went through
the literature trying to make assays for
everything in the literature that might
be on the plants and so you'll see in
the literature alt Orca pee MACUL
heiress and Golovin mi sees we thought
it was at we made assays for it they all
failed it turns out it's a novel species
that exists on cannabis it's been
painstaking to get the genome sequence
of this has required a lot of special
care to make sure we don't get other
into fights and epiphytes in the process
of sequencing but the thing to know is
that this pest which is probably the
largest pest in the cannabis field when
it hits you it hits you at the worst
possible time at the end of your light
cycle when you spend all that time
growing the plants and it can it can
whack out 50% of your grow this thing's
vascularized in the plant and so it can
be there when you can't see it and the
DNA picks it up and so we decided to
make a hole-punch assay that would
actually target this genome so that we
can then see if we can eradicate this
from grows before become
a problem so we managed to scrape off
some of that white those spores off of
the leaves and shotgun sequence those
and then get ourselves a reference now
we've only done this in New England
samples there's a possibility that
there's another species out there out
west that we need to consider this is in
fact the case with wheat wheat has two
different bloom areas that exist on it
but cannabis so far this is the only
data we have right now is pointing to
this one strain and so far the numbers
on doing this look pretty good when we
run around with all the kilometers we've
had and look for the samples that are
clean and look for the samples that
aren't clean of it we get different
signals the clean samples stay pink and
the ones that have powdery mildew turn
yellow we've tried a few samples that
were in question and went through and
acts absolutely mutilated the samples to
see if we just under sampled the clean
ones and it was still there
it turns out the hyper sampling didn't
show us a new results so needless to say
we're still learning how frequently we
have to sample this to pick this up
because it is vascularized and we don't
know if we'll get it one hole punch but
at the moment right now it seems like we
are getting it with one hole punch the
question is are we going to capture it
when it's a clone are we gonna capture
it at 10 weeks or somewhere in the
middle we don't know yet we're hoping to
work with a lot of people in the field
to do that so finally we did begin
looking at other ways to genotype which
is using these portable sequencers and
this is still a work in progress but
STRs are becoming quite popular in the
field to use STRs to fingerprint some of
these strains and the reason people want
to do STRs is that they run a capillary
electrophoresis and they're really cheap
to run they can be under $1 to run per
STR but Capital Area lector Freese's is
a $50,000 instrument that's not field
portable so we want to take that
technology and move it to these field
portable sequencers so because one day
these field portable sequencers are
projecting to be as small as a little
chip that goes into an iPhone it's not
here yet but if it happens that could be
a very handy STR tool for field based
genotyping and we would want to
integrate that into the canopy dia
database if we have to the preliminary
data on this looks like there is still a
little bit of work to be done but it's
going to work these are STRs done out of
cannabis on nanopores and what you're
seeing in a lot of these is let me go
back to that I missed it
laser what you're seeing here that there
is is the SCR which is a it's a tandem
repeat and you'll see the tandem repeats
they're diff
because they're supposed to be these are
in fact the the variations were looking
for the other thing you'll notice is a
couple of the bases have error rates and
that's not actually unknown or not
uncommon with these nanopore sequencing
there's still at about ninety percent
accuracy a lot of depth of coverage
might correct a lot of that they're
getting better so I would say the the
verdict on this is still out stay tuned
but these are probably going to play a
role in doing pathogen detection or
other types of fingerprinting in the
future
so to summarize I am on red we think
under 30 stamps can actually genotype
samples we believe we're gonna be able
to put this point of bro we're out
looking for funding to expand this
genotyping technology so we can build
the right microfluidic chips that we
have to do this very cheaply on site and
we can hopefully include a variety of
other markers that would be of interest
and you see that marker list is growing
that marker list we have male female we
have CBD we have powdery mildew we're
looking into terpene markers and we're
in likewise all the microbial risks but
we really want to open it up to the
community as to what do you want to look
for because the capacity to do
genome-wide Association studies means we
could do with probably two or three
hundred samples we may be able to find
markers for powdery mildew resistance or
drought resistance or name your QTL your
phenotype several hundred samples
sequenced in one condition or the other
we can hopefully distill a snip that can
make it to a point of growth system that
you'll be measuring on your phone so
with that I want to thank everyone who
made this happen which was a very large
group of people including people outside
of courtesan and missile genomics it was
a quite a fun era I'm the lucky
recipient to brag about it up here but
it's really not my work it's others
thank you
you