[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed conference
all right we've gotten a lot of great
feedback from the announcement of our
canmed23 innovation and investment
summit
if you haven't already heard canmed23 is
going to be bigger and better than any
of our previous events in a few very
important ways
first as you've noticed the name is a
little different it's now the canmed23
innovation and investment summit which
highlights both the nature of
breakthroughs being presented at the
event and the inclusion of principles to
fund those efforts
second cam ed 23 will be held at the
marriott resort at marco island florida
this will give attendees like you
the chance to fit in a little r r at one
of the most beautiful vacation venues in
the world with amenities like world
class golf
tennis yoga massages on the beach and
more
third the summit will feature immersive
workshops to bring you up to speed on
the latest in capital markets medical
training and deep dives into cultivation
and laboratory technology although kmed
23 will be different in these ways some
things will remain the same
we will still feature world-class oral
presentations in the areas of cannabis
science medicine cultivation and safety
testing curated by our canmed advisory
board for impact and importance
in fact our call for abstracts is open
now and you can submit your abstract for
consideration for a camed 23
presentation just use the link in the
show description
we will also continue to share our
knowledge with the cannabis community
through our canmed archive social media
platforms and of course the canme coffee
talk podcast so even if you can't join
us in marco island you can still be part
of the kanmed community however if you
do want to join us at cammed 23 you can
request your invitation now at
cammanevents.com
our guest today is dr dale hunt
dale is a plant scientist a cannabis
lawyer and a registered u.s patent
attorney with over 20 years of
experience protecting plant varieties in
the united states and throughout the
world
dale is the founder of plant and planet
law firm an intellectual property law
practice where he provides guidance and
expertise on patents and i.p matters and
aids clients in establishing i.p
protection for their legal cannabis
cultivars products and businesses
at kmed 2022 dale participated in a
panel discussion titled the impacts of
legalization on the cannabis legacy and
the need for solutions to create a
healthier industry where he provided his
expertise with regards to how legacy
breeders can protect their ip
during our discussion we cover the
different types of patents that can be
used to protect cannabis and hemp plants
what plant patents cover as well as
specific exemptions
how plant patents can be challenged or
invalidated
the panic then ensued after the biotech
institute began patenting cannabis
plants in 2017 and how it affected the
industry
the biggest hurdles that prevent
breeders from protecting their plants
and how breeders can determine which
plants are worth patenting
before we get to my conversation with
dale i want to thank this episode
sponsor breeders best
breeders best is the first company to
specialize in licensing patent-protected
cannabis genetics and the only company
in the cannabis space to exclusively
serve independent cannabis breeders
born from the desire to help independent
cannabis breeders become and or remain
economically viable and not be left
behind in this rapidly changing industry
breeders best exists to bridge the gap
between independent cannabis breeders
and the marketplace using a licensing
model proven in horticultural industries
to learn more visit breedersbest.com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with dale hunt
[Music]
good morning dale thanks for joining us
on the on the podcast
good morning i appreciate the invitation
all right yeah no i'm excited to talk
with you about uh about this topic we're
talking all about intellectual property
patents licensing trademarks all that
good stuff
now
patents and ipv protection can apply to
really any aspect of the cannabis
industry from genetics to manufacturing
processes to the final product so could
you explain which part of the industry
you specialize in and why you chose that
to be your focus
yeah thanks uh that's that's really fun
to talk about so um i came to
intellectual property as a plant
scientist i studied botany and plant
genetics and molecular and cellular
biology before i went to law school
and
in my career as a big law firm attorney
i had an opportunity to work on all
kinds of patents biotech clean energy
sustainable technologies medicine
all kinds of things and i still do to
some extent but as the cannabis industry
really emerged and
people started realizing that patents
were obtainable for
cannabis genetics that really seemed to
be a sweet spot for me
i gave a few talks and a few breeders i
guess found out that this is what i do
and they came to me and asked me if i
could help them protect their cannabis
genetics and that has become
a really large part more than half of my
practice so it's um it's it's very
exciting to see the growth um
uh the industry has its ups and downs
like all industries do but it's um it's
fun to participate in it
excellent now
can you explain the different types of
patents that can be applied to protect a
breeder's ip
yes
um
let's we can talk about patents and then
we'll i'll talk about a patent
equivalent so i hope i don't forget to
talk about that because that's a very
important thing in the us and and abroad
first starting to it in talking about
patents the the one that people always
think of is something called a plant
patent and plant patents are really for
any kind of plant that is asexually
propagated so in in cannabis we refer to
that as cloning but you know if you
think about grapevines and cherry trees
and all those kinds of things those are
all asexually propagated organisms and
the plant patent statute was really
created to
fill a gap in the kind of available
coverage
for
creative work when
the plant breeding industry as an
industry really started to take off and
that was back in the 1930s
so
one of the options with cannabis is to
get a plant patent
the interesting thing about plant
patents is they are only infringed by
asexual propagation
so let's suppose you've got a strain
that or a cultivar there's some
difference of opinion about the the best
term to use
i am pretty agnostic about that because
i think it's more about just
communicating with where people are but
let's suppose you've got a cultivar that
um
that is so
that this not easy to breed with and not
very stable but it's really special in
its clinical form
and so the real value is all about
clonal propagation and that's really all
the only thing anybody would ever want
to do with that plant in that case a
plant patent would fit because
it
it would provide the adequate coverage
to for something that's only really
clonally propagated
the thing that's interesting about the
cannabis
plant though is as you know it can be
propagated
on in scale
either clonally or by seeds and one of
the things people might want to do with
a special cultivar is use it to breed
some other things
and what's important about a plant
patent is it's not infringed by breeding
and it's not infringed by making seeds
and so if you've got something that that
has value for breeding or for for
producing seeds a plant patent really
wouldn't be enough and then you'd have
to
pursue a utility patent
and utility patent is the kind of the
common kind of patent that people use on
jet engines and and telecommunication
devices and pharmaceuticals
but there's a way to make a utility
patent really fit a plant variety and
make it not as
complicated or difficult to obtain as a
typical utility patent and that is by
defining
the claims to finding the invention with
reference to a specific biological
deposit they say this is our example of
this organism it's on deposit we're not
trying to get anything that's broader
than this organism or that's different
let's say different from this organism
but we are trying to get some breadth
around it so we want to we're going to
make this deposit and then we're going
to say
we claim seeds that correspond to seeds
on this on deposit we also claim using
plants grown from these seeds or progeny
of those plants grown from these seeds
for breeding or for
making products etc so you can get a lot
broader protection than from a plant
patent so why would anybody ever choose
a plant patent well it's faster and it's
cheaper than a utility patent but of the
utility patent that involves making a
deposit which in my firm we refer to
that as a variety specific utility
patent
those cost about twice as much as a
plant patent and take a little longer
usually to get but they are it's it's
still
very consistently predictable that you
can obtain those you're not going to run
into a whole lot of barriers if you
really did breed that and if it really
is new and distinguishable from other
things that are out there
excellent
so
back to the plant patent and it's it's
interesting that that asexual
propagation is such an important piece
so
here's a hypothetical so say i i
purchase a patented cultivar yes and i
self it
and you know create feminized seeds and
then from that i do my own final hunt
and then
um find a cultivar that's actually
pretty similar to the first one that i
purchased am i in the clear there
if it's only protected by a plant patent
and so how do you know well you call me
or
you can look it up if you if if it's
marked with with a patent notice which
patented goods are supposed to be marked
with then it will have a patent number
and it will either be
a um let's see uh an eight-digit number
um so it would look like something yeah
it would look like 10 comma you know
three digits three digits that would be
a utility patent if it has a number that
starts with two p's it's p p and then
usually five digits that's a plant
pattern
um and if so if it really is just a
plant patent and what you're doing is
you're breeding with it and then you're
doing a phenol hunt those things those
activities would not infringe a plant
patent and that's why even though
it's rare that we recommend plant
patents even though i've done tons of
plant patents in other with fruits and
flowers
it's rare that that's adequate
protection for really special cultivar
but like i say sometimes a cultivar
isn't very stable you're never going to
make good seeds from it it's not easy to
breed with for whatever reason but you
just really love that exact clonal form
and that in which case plant patent
would be a perfect fit
excellent and now you did mention patent
equivalence and you didn't want to
forget to talk about that too yes thank
you for remembering i saw you taking
notes there
in addition the u.s is really unusual in
having three different ways of
protecting a plant cultivar you can
certainly as we've discussed you can
protect it with a plant patent you can
protect it with a utility patent that
involves a deposit you can also protect
it with something provided through the
usda called the plant variety protection
certificate and so that's it's a form of
intellectual property and it has a
similar scope of
it's an exclusionary right meaning when
you have the right to or when you have
that that grant of intellectual property
it gives you the right to make other
people
stop doing something in court or stop
and go to court to make them stop doing
something or it gives you a right to
authorize them with a license and
correct and collect royalties but a
plant variety protection certificate is
um it's it's a it's different from a
patent
it is part of an international
convention called upof it's the us
implementation of upof and upon was
created really as a patent alternative
because a lot of countries don't want to
have living organisms within their
patentable subject matter scope they
don't they don't there are their patent
offices don't like working with living
organisms or have some other public
policy reason not to
but recognizing the
tremendous importance of plant breeding
and plant varieties throughout the world
there was this international convention
created that established its own form of
intellectual property protection for
plant varieties and so
there are about 75 countries that are
members of upof including the u.s but so
when the u.s joined upof we did it by
plastic passing the plant variety
protection act and making the usda the
administrator of that the administrative
agency for that
act so
what are the differences the main
difference is that well there are a few
differences for one right now at least
the since the usda requires a seed
deposit for a pvp application
the only
and they receive the seed deposit
themselves or some
government agency proxy does uh they
will only accept applications that
qualify under federal under the farm
bill as him
so it's got to be 0.3 thc or less than
the flower um if it's more than that and
you have to describe things like you
know the thc levels in the flower as
part of the overall disclosure so and if
it if it doesn't qualify as hemp they
won't accept the seed deposit and so
they don't have
a real per se ban on accepting marijuana
applications or considering marijuana
applications there's just no mechanism
to handle the seed deposit requirement
so
we we believe that this this will change
it changed really fast when the farm
bill was passed the usda very quickly
adopted it started accepting
applications for hemp genetics and we
believe that they'll do the very same
thing for marijuana as soon as that is
federally legal but and and then the
other important thing about pvp
protection is that it has a couple of
kind of public policy carve-outs it is
not an infringement of a pvp certificate
for someone to breed with that variety
it's it's in it's built into the statute
that that's okay to do
um so again if you want to if you want
to have breeding be prohibited you've by
with your intellectual property rights
you've got to do that with the utility
patent because the pvp certificate and
the plant
patent will not
that will not prevent breeding and then
the other carve out the other kind of
public policy right is that someone who
obtains legitimately
seeds of a of a pvp protected variety
has a right to bulk out the to make the
same number of seeds for the next uh the
next planting that's called the farmer's
exemption and so you buy the seeds once
but then you can make your own seeds
after that now you can't make them to
sell to third parties but you can make
them to replant the same area the same
acreage
so
you know
there are scenarios under which a pvp
certificate would make a lot of sense
and would be the right thing but first
of all it's got to be hemp secondly
you've got to be you've got to recognize
the farmer's exemption and the reader's
exemption and be okay with those now the
one other little nuance to that which is
that in the u.s and i think in most upof
countries if you don't like those
exemptions you can only license you can
just have a policy that well we don't
license this to anyone and we don't give
access to these seeds to anyone who
isn't willing to sign an agreement that
they will not breed or that they will
not re they'll buy new seed from us
every season and so
in most countries it's okay to contract
out of those exemptions
and to fill those gaps with a contract
but some countries are so committed to
that as a matter of public policy that
they won't they'll say any contract that
attempts to take away these exemptions
is invalid
so
that's country by country and it changes
sometimes so
you'd want to get a lawyer that knows
this and works with it to check the
countries of interest and see if you can
contract out of that but that's some
that's that's the ip well it's an ip
it's a form of intellectual property
it's a patent equivalent but not really
a patent and really plant variety
protection throughout all the rest of
the world is done through up rather than
through patent offices with a couple of
really minor exceptions
great and so which type of
uh ip protection do you think is or do
you see as the most commonly used to
protect cannabis cultivars
well you know what's interesting is
if you watched the patent issuances over
the last few years you saw a lot of
plant patents issuing um and i think
it's for two reasons one is they do
issue faster than other patents
um they're cheaper and so people who
just want to have a patent for you know
portfolio building purposes or bragging
rights or something might choose one
like that
and i think also a lot of people didn't
realize the weaknesses of a plant patent
and how plant patent doesn't work very
well for
well doesn't provide really full
coverage for a plant-like cannabis that
can be propagated both ways
so i think it was a combination of all
those reasons you you are seeing more of
these variety specific utility patents
um issuing now
we've got a lot more than i could count
off the top of my head we've got a lot
that are pending we have a few plant
patents that are pending and somebody
who has
for whom protection
quick and thorough protection is a
higher priority than saving money they
can they can certainly pursue both and
so you could start with a plant patent
get that issued quickly
have your clonal propagation protected
and then follow it um with it with a
vsup a variety specific utility patent
that ties back to the plant patent
filing and then you can have both kinds
of coverage but now you're paying you
know something like 3x the cost of the
plant patent instead of
one of the other 1x or 2x if that makes
sense
yeah yeah yeah
no and then you sort of mentioned
monitoring the different patents that
have issued over the years and you know
it's funny about five years ago
when groups like biotech institute began
registering patents on cannabis plants
there was a lot of panic in the industry
from people who thought that
you know they would maybe be sued for
growing weed in their own backyard so
what has become of those early patents
and have they been enforced or had any
real impact on the industry
i think they've had a big impact on the
industry but maybe not the intended
impact
so
the whole way i got into the industry i
was minding my business in my office in
san francisco and i got an email from
somebody who was organizing something
called the open cannabis project and
they were all in a flutter over those
biotech institute patents they thought
this is the beginning of the end of this
emerging industry it's going to be
dominated by
overbroad patents and it's going to put
a chilling effect on every all the home
growers and all the home breeders and
people are going to freak out and they
did kind of freak out
um
so they called me because they said well
we not we want somebody who really knows
plant ip we found you and would you be
willing to to
advise us and so that's actually how i
got into the cannabis industry in the
first place
um and so you know
i'm glad that happened it's been a it's
been a really interesting um
uh evolution step in my in my career
personally but
i think everybody did did believe that
there would be this really overbearing
um
oppressive
uh approach to patenting and patent
enforcement in the industry and there
are a few things that i think limit that
practically practically or or perhaps
legally and i'll try to go into all that
but before i forget when i started when
i got in involved in this and became so
involved in the industry and going to
meetings and talking to people and
giving talks and things i realized that
there were a lot of questions and not as
many answers and so i started a blog
called it's at plantlaw.com
it answers a lot of the really common
questions in fact one of the posts i i
is titled because it was a question i
got a million times at uh at a meeting
was can monsanto make me stop growing
monsanto or anybody else make me stop
growing my own plants
and um so i had i i started answering
these questions in the blog i don't blog
as much anymore i need to get back to it
but i'd say um the posts that are there
answer a lot of the most common
questions but yeah there was so much
anxiety about that so what has happened
since then and why
did it not go the way the people who
spent
tons of money on those patents maybe
thought it would um and i i'm not i
can't read their mind i don't know what
their motive was but
these early patents just to give some
context for people who haven't seen them
made the attempt to protect um to to
carve out some nip position not based
upon a specific genetics
like
seeds on deposit or like one cultivar
and its clonal progeny but it defined
the patent scope the patent right more
in terms of a chemotype
so it was really any cannabis plant that
has that checks these boxes you know a
certain
thc to cbd ratio a certain uh
ter really general terpene profile that
really would cover a lot of things
so why did that patent ever get allowed
well the way a patent examination
process works is the examiner
they're supposed to find reasons to
reject a patent claim
but how do they find their reasons they
do a search of the literature and so
they look at prior patents
and they look at prior academic
publications and anything they can get
from say
um
you know from the internet trade trade
journals or anything else
so
what's what is unique absolutely unique
about the cannabis industry in
comparison with other
high value industries is that
um there was a lot of prior commercial
activity and a lot of prior inventive
activity but it was the opposite of
published it was hidden
and so if an examiner needs to find a
way to reject a patent claim that is
very broad
he or she has to go look at prior
patents and there weren't a lot
prior academic publications not a lot
prior commercial activity or evidence of
prior commercial activity which was all
hidden
and so the examiner may have had may
have done a great job examining this but
did not have the tools to reject it so
of course now that the community sees
these claims and say hey that that's
jamaican lion and jamaican lion's been
around for a lot longer than this patent
than when this patent was filed and the
the community takes starts to take its
collective memory
and creates another kind of what you
could call prior art and that that's the
term that
they use for those things that the
examiner finds in a search
you could say this is prior art it's
just not
published prior art but it is something
that factually is out there and that
people could verify this is at least the
line of reasoning i haven't
independently verified this stuff but um
so they say all right in our community
collective memory or in the the evidence
that individual people could bring
forward
this chemotype existed a long time
before this patent was filed and so what
does that do well it explains why the
patent was at grant in the first place
the examiner didn't know as much as was
actually out there
they're not omniscient and they can only
do what they can do with searching so
that the the thing that would have
killed that patent application perhaps
was uh something that was factual but
not not knowable by an examiner but once
you start enforcing a patent you know
you you take you you
identify a defendant and you sue them
and you tell them you've got to either
pay me some money or stop using
my patented
technology or both
that's when
that's when it gets real right and um
and somebody's highly motivated to dig
deeper
and dig deeper than an examiner had time
to do
and use more resources now of course
that process is tremendously expensive
so one of the things i was advocating
early on
um in my blogging was to form some kind
of a community coalition that would a
little bit like nato or something we'd
all stan we'd all agree to defend
whoever is the one that gets uh that
gets poked by this first and we you know
we'd pull our resources and pull our
community knowledge to
overcome an overbought patent now what's
cool about this is
uh to my knowledge those patents have
never been asserted um they uh
they were maybe but they really
galvanized the community in a way that
i'm
i'm grateful for them and um and there
may be some real i'm not saying that the
patents don't have any value or don't
have any great business purpose they may
um that's that's um knowledge that i
don't have i don't have any inside
information on that company um and of
course that company is not the only one
there it's kind of a patent attorney's
job to try to get the broadest claims
they can
but when i'm counseling a client i i
tell them we want to get the broadest
valid claims you can get we don't want
you to have a patent that's not going to
be valid and so
just to close the loop on that when if
someone does assert a patent against me
and i do have evidence that the patent
never should have been granted one of my
defenses i might say yeah well i'm not
saying i don't that what i'm doing
doesn't fall within these claims which
would constitute infringement what i'm
saying is these claims never should have
been granted this is an invalid patent
and
my defense is not my own activities it's
that this pat the the patent office
didn't
granted a patent that never should have
been granted and and what's interesting
about that is if a patent is invalidated
in litigation
because the defendant can produce
evidence like that it's gone forever
yeah so you lose once and you and
on a validity challenge and and you're
done you know that and that assumes that
you've exhausted all of your appeals and
everything but uh so you know it's it
that might be another reason that these
patents haven't been asserted yet is
that there's a risk of having them um
exposed as being invalid
and i want to hasten to say i'm not
providing legal advice or legal analysis
on those patents but what i am doing is
talking about um
what the community has informed me of
and
combined with some general principles of
patent law so um no no legal advice or
opinions here but just a summary of
what's happened over the last few years
it's a good disclaimer
so
so you mentioned that you help breeders
sort of apply for and acquire patents on
their genetics do you ever represent
growers on the other side where maybe
there is
um
they are being sued for potentially
using patented
material and your as you described maybe
defending or invalidating that patent
yeah you know um what i do is something
that comes a little bit before that
patent litigation is so tremendously
expensive that there's a lot of
kind of paper shuffling and and foot
stomping and maybe saber rattling that
happens before a lawsuit is filed in in
many cases so somebody will get a letter
and they'll say and the letter will say
something like maybe you're not aware
but we have a patent that
that has this scope and you might be
operating within that patent and we'd
like you to take a look at that and
we're open to license discussions so and
that's that's a really gentle
kind of
uh nod towards a cease and desist letter
and the reason those are usually so
gentle is if you come on really strong
and say you're infringing our patent and
we're going to sue you
that can create something called
declaratory judgment jurisdiction which
will let the party that just got that
nasty letter sue you first and they'll
they could if they've got the money to
do this they can say oh we got this
letter we're taking you to court um for
a declaratory judgment that your patent
is invalid or that we don't infringe and
that shifts the balance of power so
there's there's some really good reason
not to write
overly aggressive overly explicit
initial letters like that so you usually
just try to
make someone aware that they've got a
risk without creating declaratory
judgment jurisdiction so when a client
gets a letter like that whether it's and
it's usually not about plant genetics
it's usually
about you know some manufacturing
technique or some composition or
something and i work with all of those
different subject matters in in cannabis
and across a lot of other industries
they get a letter like that and they
come to me and they say
um let's take a look at this and see
well
they say help me and then i say let's
take a look at that patent let's talk
about what you're actually doing let's
see let's interpret these patent claims
in view of not just what they say but in
view of the supporting
application that was filed and view the
arguments that they made to the patent
office to get to get it allowed in the
first place
and this whole analysis is called a
freedom to operate analysis and i do a
lot of that and i'm actually writing a
series of blog posts about fto that i'm
hoping to drop later this year so
when that happens you know the first
thing you do is you look at the patent
claims themselves and and you look at
and the claims are the part of the
patent that defines the legal right
defines the invention and you compare
that with what the
accused party is doing and if you can
find even one thing that that claim
requires
that your client or your you know
whoever is not doing
then that's that's what what you people
refer to that in a short hand called the
missing element rule
if there's something that the claim
requires that you're clearly not doing
then you just don't infringe and it's
not always black and white sometimes
it's pretty hard to figure that out but
and and let's say that right now
you do infringe every you you have every
one of the elements of that claim but
there's a design change that you could
make in one little feature that would
make it so that you there there's now a
missing element then you just you make a
design modification you write back and
say
uh you know our current uh our current
product doesn't seem to have everything
this patent requires so respectfully um
see you later uh
there and there's a lot of that and then
sometimes the client will just come to
me with knowing that one of their
competitors is doing a lot of patenting
and they'll say hey can we keep an eye
on these guys keep an eye on the claims
that they're issuing and
let's do a checkup every once in a while
and make sure that we're not stepping on
their toes so that we're not facing any
risks you know boards of directors and
inventor investors love it when you're
that careful as long as it's not too
expensive to be that careful so there's
there's a really good balance between
um you know kind of keeping your nose
clean as a company and making sure that
you're not infringing patents and that
you're aware of the ones that you need
to be watching out for um
and uh occasionally you know altering
your activities to redesigning your your
products or your methods
but to circle back to um the question
really about plant genetics
usually the because as i've as i've said
these kinds of patents like a plant
patent only infringed by actual cloning
of the exact same variety a variety
specific utility patent only infringed
by really starting with the same
genetics and doing something with it
that's within the scope of those claims
it's really rare to accidentally
infringe something like that and not
even know that you did maybe you
received something from someone else and
you're working with it and then you find
out late in the process that it was
covered by a patent and you didn't know
it and so maybe you did in good faith
infringe that well then smartest thing
to do is stop doing it and move on to
something else um
but uh it's it's really rare that these
things have to be litigated because if
someone isn't using the same genetics
it's pretty straightforward dna test and
you guys certainly know that those
things uh medicinal genomics um it's
pretty straightforward dna test to do a
comparison and say well you know these
might look superficially similar
phenotypically but they're not the same
genotypically they've got all these
differences and then anybody who who has
that pat would be crazy to continue to
pursue the case they'd just be throwing
money away down a hole because
the evidence would end up demonstrating
that it's not an infringement um on the
other hand if there is a a great match
either an identical match or a match
that shows that this these two this this
this accused plant definitely descended
from this this
patented plant then depending exactly on
on the scope of that patent right
it may be a clear infringement and the
reason these things don't get litigated
is because the evidence is usually so
clear one way or the other that there's
going to be a settlement way earlier in
the process without spending all the
money on discovery and a trial
excellent yeah no and you brought up
genotype which was great because i was
over genotyping i should say which is
great because i was going to ask you
about that now
i imagine that's probably not a
requirement for a patent application but
i imagine it's pretty valuable
especially if you're having a plant
patent and it's going to be asexually
propagated because then like you said
you would that is some great evidence to
show that it's exactly the same yeah the
what's interesting is the plant patent
statute says that you have to just you
have to disclose as much about the
variety as you can
um
it doesn't require you to do a dna test
i always tell people if you've got dna
information even just a few markers or
if you've got a whole genotype or
whatever
go for it let's include that but it's
not required i've gotten
lots and lots of plant patents and
variety specific utility patents without
submitting dna information but if you
again if you've got it and a lot of
things originate from it you know you do
a dna test and you say oh this looks
pretty interesting
and then you end up deciding this might
be interesting enough that i should
patent it so and by then you've already
got the dna information in your pocket
you should include it in the application
um
but it's not required and so i always
tell people look if you if you've got it
use it if you're curious and you can
afford the test go for it do it it's
great information if you um
don't have the dna test right now well
you'll certainly want to get it if
there's an infringement or if you're
accused of infringing but the cool thing
about dna is it doesn't really change if
you've got a clonely propagated organism
it's going to be there and you can use
it when the evidence is you can go get
the test when the evidence is needed
excellent
so what would you say are the most
common hurdles
preventing
breeders or growers from protecting
their ip
i love that question um
and one of the early blog posts i did
was
the question was how can i know if my
plant is unique or different enough for
patenting
and the answer is if you've read it
and selected it and you can identify how
it's different from its parents
it's already unique enough for patenting
or new enough for patenting the that's
really not the challenge the challenge
is deciding which things are worth
patenting you know if you commit to
patenting um a cultivar
you're going to be spending five figures
um it's you're going to spend
at least 10 to 15 to get a plant patent
and you know probably 25 to 30 to get a
variety specific utility pad and that
can vary a little bit but it's not going
to vary a lot um
and so you're making a pretty big
commitment there let's say that you've
got something that's going to be the
flavor of the month a couple years from
now and then it'll fade away um not
worth patenting probably
on the other hand you got something that
might be licensed worldwide that's the
next
you know the next huge thing that
everybody wants to grow
then
it'd be foolish not to spend 30 50 100
whatever it took to protect that that
would just be a rounding error on all of
the value that that thing creates and so
um
but the problem is you've got to you
there's certain deadlines that you
within which you need to file a patent
application and it's usually before you
know if you've got a major home run or
the flavor of the month and so um i just
the way i the way i talk to clients
about this is i say do you think that
this is going to be
um increasing in value and demand in
five years or will it have already kind
of run its course
and
that's not an easily knowable question
but they'll know it better than i would
and if they believe that it's um that
it's going to be increasing in demand in
five years and 10 years then patenting
is really kind of a no-brainer
if they think that it will already be
kind of passe or less interesting in in
um
in three or four years then by the time
they got a patent nobody would be
infringing it so you know it just it
usually it turns into a business
decision more than a um a legal decision
if that makes sense legal or technical
question
yeah no it does and you mentioned
deadlines and
this might be a basic question but
are you only able to apply for a patent
before you've actually sold it or
commercialized it
it's a great question in the u.s there
you can you can apply up to a year after
the first
public disclosure
now what's interesting about that is
and this might seem quite surprising it
was kind of surprising to me um
is that let's say you want a plant
patent then what constitutes a public
disclosure is public availability of
that exact genotype in clone form
so a lot of people have had some really
special genetics that they've been
propagating and
growing themselves and selling flour but
they've never sold any clones if you've
never sold any clones you don't have a
deadline yet for plant patenting even if
you've been selling flour for a long
time i ran this
uh scenario past one of the senior
examiners at the patent office and i
said let's suppose somebody's had a
they've been clonally propagating and
selling flour for 30 years but nobody's
ever
nobody at them has ever had access to a
clone he said yeah that's still
patentable as a plant patent because the
thing that you are saying is new
is that living plant in clonal form
so if that still hasn't been out there
even though the flower has been now
let's suppose you want a vsup a variety
specific utility patent then anything
that has been out there to the public
for more than a year is not not eligible
so let's say seeds have never been out
there
public hasn't been able to breed with it
the um the clone form hasn't been out
there but flour has been out there flour
and extracts then you just have to be
careful not to claim flour
or extracts you could still claim the
seeds you could still claim the breeding
you can claim anything that hasn't been
publicly available but
prior sale of flour or extracts may make
it that um that that's not part of what
you could claim at that point
and then just to
there are no short answers when when you
ask me a question but um
when you go to the pvp system the pvp
and upof system the deadlines are quite
different they're defined based on
um
exploitation exploitation of a variety
and that even that that term has a
slightly different definition in a lot
of different countries so first of all
you have to dig in and ask yourself
what what is the level of activity that
creates that constitutes exploitation of
the variety in this country
and when did that start
um
so and then
that's further complicated by the fact
that for cannabis under upof
you'd have two deadlines you have
one deadline would be you have to file
within a year of local exploitation and
within four years of the first
exploitation anywhere
so let's say i start selling flour
um which would i think would almost
certainly be considered commercial
exploitation i start selling flour this
year i've got a hard four year deadline
for anywhere in the world to get my upof
application filed and i have a hard
one-year deadline for for the country
where i've been selling when i've been
doing anything commercial with that plan
so you know sometimes just licensing a
plant into a country and authorizing
someone to start cultivating it may or
may not cross the threshold of
commercial exploitation so you've really
got to dig down and understand the rules
in the countries where you're interested
in protection but uh we're expecting as
that four-year deadline approaches we're
expecting to be filing a lot more
applications in foreign countries uh
under that uh that kind of deadline
regime
great great all right so so winding down
here a bit
um
do you feel like there's an aversion to
patents and ip protection in the
cannabis breeder community um in general
because again going back to when those
first ones issued there's a lot of
people on social media or sort of
grandstanding that you know this is a
community plan we shouldn't be patenting
it at all has that sort of
has that changed people more agreeable
to it you know there's a lot there's a
widely varying opinion about that and i
respect that you know this is really a
values thing for a lot of people it's
it's community standards and values and
principles and i would never want to
talk anybody out of their values or
their their deeply held principles but i
would like to give them opportunities to
think differently just in case they're
interested in examining the question
from another point of view and one of
the posts that i wrote on my blog
is it's titled something like
lessons for from terrific from tom
terrific on good fences and this
actually makes reference to uh
some controversy that happened with tom
brady and trademarking the term tom
terrific
and um
uh
and that's a little bit i if i go into
too much detail it will take too long
but basically look at that blog and
you'll see that it's really about
whether it's it whether it's it goes to
questions of whether it's right to own
land
whether it is ever right to um to have
any any like ownership rights on
something as
natural and sacred as a cannabis plant
and the point that i make is
um you may think it's not but let's
suppose that um
well if when you get an intellectual
property you're still allowed to let
other people use your ip
but you have the choice of keeping some
people out it's like building a fence
around your property you can let people
through if you want but you also have
the right to keep people off your
property if you want to
and
and so that that's
that's one angle on it the other angle i
sometimes i talk about the ethics of
patent and cannabis
and
um
here's the angle on this one
if you are a plant breeder your life
your life's work is a creative work and
you've been creating something special
that people benefit from and that
somebody might make a lot of money on
um
but unlike somebody who writes a song or
writes a book or makes a movie you don't
have any automatic protection
in the us and almost the entire world
there's automatic copyright protection
for those kinds of creatives works like
songs and books and movies as soon as
it's created you don't even have to
register anything you can get stronger
rights by registration but you've got
automatic copyright from the moment it's
created
unfortunately that doesn't exist for
plant varieties so you've got these
other creative people these plant
breeders who very much like an author or
a photographer or
or whatever they have this great
creative work that has tremendous value
but if they don't protect it
they don't get paid the same way
somebody can
who just creates different kinds of work
that has copyright protection so
if you if you look at it that way you
might say all right um
maybe i wish patents weren't the way to
do this and maybe i don't really like
patents especially the ones that can be
abused but as a way for somebody to
protect their life's work and to get
some value out of their life's work and
have it be their living instead of just
a hobby you know who's rich enough to i
don't know very many people in the
cannabis industry that are independently
wealthy and can just breed for fun
most of them need to find a way to pay
their bills from their work
and so
patenting
or other kinds of intellectual property
protection just kind of level the
playing field with copyrights and other
kinds of creative work and i think that
plant breeders are every bit as worthy
of getting paid as authors and um
sculptors and and fine artists and and
so on and so i to me the intellectual
property protection just helps them get
paid for their work
excellent no that's a great place to
stop but before i let you go i want to
give you a chance to plug any social
media or resources i know you mentioned
the blog a lot i'll definitely put a
link to that in the show description but
anything else that people can um can
look at to learn more or maybe get in
touch with you well i appreciate that my
law firm is called plant and planet law
firm
um it's plant and planet.com
uh easy to find and um i also have a
company that i started to help readers
protect and license their special
cultivars is called breeders best
and that's at breedersbest.com
so um we're excited about being able to
help people in this space and we love
helping people and so if anybody has um
questions or
or can think of some way we could help
them with any invention in the life
sciences area whether it's cannabis or
something else we'd love to hear from
them
all right dale thanks again for taking
the time to be on the podcast um and
hope to see you out at a k-med event
thanks a lot i'll be there
cheers
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dale hunt check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode's sponsor breeders
breedersbest
our next episode will drop august 31st
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out the
new and improved canmenevents.com
the team really did an exceptional job
updating the website with all the
information about our canmed23 event
and of course you can still find videos
of all the previous canmed presentations
and panels in the canmed archive you can
also find all the previous episodes of
the podcast as well and while you're
there make sure you sign up for email
alerts to get all the notifications
around this innovative industry-leading
event i also invite you to engage with
us on all our social media platforms
we're on instagram facebook twitter and
linkedin just search for candid events
and lastly please leave us a review on
apple podcasts doing so really helps us
improve our rankings and reach more
listeners
alright that's it from us
stay safe stay healthy and be sure to
join us on the next candid coffee talk
[Music]
you