thank you very much
um it's an honor quite an honor to be
here
i'll try to speak loud enough that the
mic catches it as i'm a bit above it
um i tend to be that sometimes
uh again it's an honor to be here my
name is kyle turley
uh a kid from southern california
son of a truck driver decided to play
football one year in
uh high school and was that good at it
that they
decided to give me a scholarship to go
to college
i had no intention of doing so so that
required me to spend the rest of my
senior year while everyone was on half
day making up all the classes that i
needed
to qualify for college and earn this
scholarship
so along that way
had some amazing things happen some
unbelievable things
met some amazing people did some things
that very few people in the world
had the opportunity to do
along the same time had some severe
consequences from it
this is life this is
why we're here in my opinion we're here
to
live this life to take on these
challenges
to look at these mountains as
only obstacles and accomplish great
things
the many things that were talked about
earlier in this
discussion today so far by dr mushulam
who has been an
unbelievable asset to this discussion
and conversation
for many many years to have brought us
here today
at harvard what an amazing opportunity
thank you again dr mashulam for your
excellence and your perseverance
one of the most amazing parts in meeting
this man
to sit and talk with him and see after
so long
his continued perseverance uh and
persistence to tell this story
uh for obvious reasons that we don't
know
that some people do know they are uh
intent on keeping this from us
uh and to have individuals like uh dr
muschilam to to tell that story
when he could easily be doing so many
other things with his life
um is uh very inspiring
again i've had the opportunity to meet a
number of people in this world
through my fame and playing in the
national football league
but when people ask me those you know
moments and who did you meet and all
these cool things that you got to do
uh you know this tops it this is
unbelievable
opportunity and an honor uh for me to be
present personally
in this moment at this time
in our existence as humans
this is speaking about a medicine that
will save many people
um that it's taken us this long to
redirect ourselves because
as we know cannabis was not illegal in
this country even
until the 1970s when they went on their
tiraden rampage against it
at the same time of the birth of the
pharmaceutical industry
and that is why i'm here today
sometimes in life we have to examine and
contemplate what it is we're here to do
and for some reason i have been put here
to be a part of this discussion
so it's a very
emotional roller coaster to be on
and to be standing here again a kid from
san diego state university uh
wasn't supposed to make it to college
wasn't supposed to go to make it through
college
wasn't supposed to be a first-round
draft pick you know drafted higher than
all the
guys in the sec in my position you know
this kid coming out of san diego state
and it was always because i searched for
the answers within myself within
the energy that surrounds us as we
understand it and many of the scientific
minds in here
understand that our energy uh force
resonates uh
far outside of our physical structure
and so i tend to try to tap into that
and that ultimately brought me to where
i am today and having the experience
that i've had with cannabis
to tell my story that came along
from a 20-year addiction to
pharmaceutical medications because of
trying to climb a mountain
along that climb uh having these amazing
experiences
i had the opportunity to have intimate
knowledge
of the pharmaceutical industry and what
it does for
injury and illness
and i can honestly say through prolonged
use
uh of pharmaceuticals uh these man-made
concoctions that
in you know all fairness have been fully
intended to help
uh i think we've realized the
consequence of that in our country as we
see it daily playing out on
our televisions uh with the devastation
that is
uh not just plaguing our athlete
community but plaguing uh
our respective communities in our
hometowns where we grew up
major metropolis cities and not just
anymore the excuse of you're from the
ghetto
cannabis has been a savior to me
in that at my lowest point in life of
despair and and loss of of
who i was because of
the inherencies in playing the sport of
football
the damage done by the game but more
importantly
the damage done on top of that damage
from these chemicals i was putting into
my body
i knew i had to make a decision i was as
i was sitting on my couch
one day
just returned from the crosby center
down in san diego where i was receiving
some care
going through therapy sessions for over
seven years i went to neurologists
neuropsychologists
psychologists counselors
therapy groups to try and understand
what was happening to me
as a a young man when everybody
says you look amazing
to know that inside i felt far from it
uh was a very difficult thing to deal
with
and that is the consequence of playing
the game of football
we obviously have severe damage to our
bodies when we get into
car accidents or any other severe cases
of
trauma where our bodies are injured
but we do this on a repetitive basis day
in day out
an average practice will be 60 to 80
plays and at certain positions
that is in 60 to 80 collisions
equivalent to
a massive car accident and
that was the position i informedly chose
to play
because of what this game has
in store um which is why i'm here
i'm here for athletes uh i started a
campaign
called athletes can because i believe
athletes can change
this conversation take it away from
this singular notion of well it could
help these people
we have individuals that we expect
to achieve and accomplish great things
in our country
it's not only spans for athletes but uh
through our military
um where these are not as it is
appearing
certain powers uh are trying to position
these
uh choices for our children these were
not always ghetto choices these were
choices in
the highest learning institutions to
achieve these high honors playing
football at harvard
was no different than playing football
at any sec school
your ultimate goal is to make it to the
national football league
and i have many good friends that
attended this school that have done so
and we have discussions about what is
going on in our community
harvard itself has a study right now
that is taking place with the national
football league and the players
association
to analyze players lives
to hopefully help for future generations
of playing this sport
defeat against all of these things that
are coming at us from every angle
as it is in a football game these
efforts have
come to an extent
a crossroads of how are we going to
accept the inherencies in this sport
and continue to encourage our children
to play these sports
and encourage their dreams to accomplish
these amazing achievements
when we know that inherently within
these sports lies
nine to ten times rate reception of
alzheimer's dementia als
parkinson's disease and
10 to 20 kids die every year in youth
football
and it's a guarantee due to the lack of
attention given to certain injuries
that are inherent in the sport
you cannot have unfortunately with the
human body
injury not occur while putting it in uh
precarious situations of collision
uh and these sports these contact sports
or as we're experiencing
even into other sports uh as we've
experienced recently
in the extreme sports community a number
of
bmx riders
are starting to kill themselves so
we look at it myself my friends
my colleagues and we try to understand
how is this happening
why is this happening and we only need
to look at ourselves
which is a very fortunate position to be
in and that
i can sit to talk and tell my story and
it is something that
is very detailed to anyone even in
the world of science because i
understand these things
that are happening to me the resolutions
i've
found in certain medicines through trial
and personal error
of taking these medicines and that uh
is is not just in in in
me and in my court this is a uh
relative uh ability for
my teammates to speak to this as well
post football career i went into music i
enjoy playing music
i play guitar and drums and i sing and
so i went to nashville
of course to try and climb another
mountain had the other
opportunity to tour the country playing
my music coast to coast and
pretty much in every state for over four
to five years and
uh had the opportunity to play with some
amazing artists uh
around uh this this great country and
every opportunity
i had to connect with the next teammate
i did so
and across the board every one of us is
suffering
uh in ways that
people wouldn't believe it's hard to
i know understand this because you're
sitting there looking at me like ah this
guy's
got it together and he's been able to
speak about this and talk about this
articulate this and
the only reason i'm here today and being
able to do this
is because of cannabis there is thank
you
through my trial and error uh in taking
medicine um i realized that
there are certain things that i have an
injury
that medicine is good for as far as
common medicine western medicine but in
the long-term use
of being addicted to these medications
since 1996
until exactly a year ago this month
when i decided uh at an a position of
desperation to take a chance
because my daily living was
my hands shaking so severe i couldn't
stop it
to where i had suicidal thoughts
constantly
homicidal thoughts constantly
rage to no end and it was ruining my
life my family's life and everyone
around me
um i knew there had to be a something
better there there must be
something better i knew along the way of
using cannabis for the first time when i
was in my second year in the national
football league
because i was always concerned about
passing drug tests
and you know not ever having that be
associated with me
as i saw many of my friends being
suspended lose scholarships in college
because of their use of cannabis i
refrained
and then in my second year in the
national football league was going
through some very trying times
i had a teammate after a practice one
day suggested to me as i was
losing sleep couldn't sleep a lot of
pressure in the national football league
a young player
going through trying to create a normal
life
with a wife and trying to start a family
etc very frustrated very
very stressful to try and
coordinate all those things and make all
those things happen without
having a lot of
confusion disruption for anyone and then
on top of that
trying to associate all these things
to being normal in and very unnormal
world
the transition from going from the real
world to
an nfl practice facility to an nfl
game day is you have to have the switch
and you need to have to you have to be
able to turn it on and turn it off
unfortunately the off switch was
neglected many times it is
something that through what we
understand now about the brain
has created the disruption that we have
in our community
that is causing suicide at an
unprecedented rate
we can no longer stand for this we can
no longer
allow a medicine that has been proven to
protect
our brains to be kept from us any longer
the things that
you heard from dr mashulim and mckernan
are unbelievable in
their science but more unbelievable in
the neglect
of this information that has gone on for
too long
can we change this conversation i think
we can i think that it's happening i
know it's happening
our veteran community is crying for this
and that spans across our military and
all of our veterans of these great
achievements and mountains that we
expect our children to continue to climb
that have consequence it is important
for us to understand that
these things you don't just wake up one
day and become a professional football
player
or an elite force military service
member
these are incredible accomplishments
that come with incredible cost
and it is imperative if we want to
continue to raise our
children in this great country and
expect them to achieve these amazing
accomplishments
that we find a medicine to help it
there's no doubt about it that cannabis
can be that medicine
it has saved my life personally one year
ago today
i was a very different person and could
not stand here in front of these lights
with this pressure to speak uh
to be around uh these amazing people
uh and stand here and tell my story it's
important that
my story can add to this conversation uh
as i speak for athletes across our
world who at young ages are being
stricken to
severe addictive drugs like oxycontin
and vicodin and percocet and laura tab
and darvaset and tor doll
and everything else that i can go on
with all the slides and everything that
have been given
these things do not help recover injury
especially neurocognitive injury and no
person in my opinion with a brain injury
should ever be given
anything but cannabis as cannabis has
saved
my life period but has proven to me
to resolve neurocognitive issues that
psych meds like well well butrin
depakote and zoloft which i was
on for six years uh were only merely
trying to do
i appreciate the opportunity to be here
but i
more importantly urge you to continue
this conversation outside of this room
outside of these hallways and take this
conversation
to the mainstream as that's where it has
to be these uh
studies and all these things to many
people are only going to occur
with full legalization of cannabis and
that has to happen
there's no possible way for us to defeat
the big machine
with this medicine unless we have full
legalization and that is
at your hands that is at my hand
i implore every one of you vote for
cannabis
every chance you get vote to legalize
vote for medical cannabis
wherever it is at on a ballot and change
this world because cannabis will there's
no doubt about that
and athletes can save this conversation
of suicide as we add our stories
if you're an athlete even just a weekend
joe please visit
athletescan.org start to add your story
i started one organization the gridiron
cannabis coalition
and it became a football issue this is a
much bigger issue
whether you're a weekend joe that likes
to
go out and ride your mountain bike when
you fall you're going to have an injury
when you go to talk to your doctor
they're going to give you a medicine
they're going to give it to you
freely and willingly in large doses and
those medicines
unfortunately are not going to look like
that which is something that grows from
the ground
this is a plant we need to understand it
we need to explore we need to research
and develop this as a medicine but we
need to immediately allow
access as we understand the incredible
fight that is against this
information coming out thank you for
your time i appreciate being here
you