[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed conference
all right big news
just last week we announced details
about canmed23 and if you signed up for
email alerts at cammanevents.com
then you were among the first to be
notified if you haven't signed up yet be
sure to do that now because there will
be a lot more announcements between now
and next may
yes that's right
23 will take place may 15th through 17th
at marco island florida
encampment 23 is going to be different
from all previous gammet events in a few
very important ways
first the name is a little different
it's now the canmed 23 innovation and
investment summit which highlights both
the nature of the breakthroughs being
presented at the event and the inclusion
of principles to fund those efforts
second cam med 23 will be held at the
marriott resort in marco island florida
this will give attendees like you the
chance to fit in a little r r at one of
the most beautiful vacation venues in
the world with amenities like
world-class golf tennis yoga massages on
the beach and more
third the summit will feature immersive
workshops to bring you up to speed in
the latest in capital markets medical
training and deep dives into cultivation
and laboratory technology
now although kmd23 will be different in
these ways some things will stay the
same we will still feature world-class
oral presentations and the areas of
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing curated by our canmed
advisory board for impact and importance
and we will continue to share that
knowledge with the cannabis community
via our kmed archive social media
platforms and of course the kmed coffee
talk podcast so even if you can't join
us in marco island you can still be part
of the khan med community
head over to canmedevents.com today to
see our updated website and learn more
about the canmed23 event i hope to see
you there
this episode i spoke with dr jeff chen
about conducting clinical trials on
cannabinoid products
dr chen is the co-founder and ceo of
radical science a health tech company
generating history's first data set and
ai to prove and predict the effects of
health and wellness products
previously he was the founder and
executive director at the ucla cannabis
research initiative
at cammed 2022 dr chen presented results
from radical sciences aces study which
was a randomized clinical trial
involving 13 cbd products and 3 000
participants
the project was possible thanks to
radical sciences unique virtual approach
to clinical trials which removes many of
the challenges that make them expensive
and difficult to conduct
topics covered during the conversation
include the many challenges associated
with performing clinical trials on
cannabinoids how a virtual
direct-to-consumer approach overcomes
many of these challenges
the value brands manufacturers and
distributors get from clinical trial
data
results from the aces study the largest
randomized cbd clinical trial in history
how radical applied lessons from the
aces study to design the radical
spectrum study
and other minor cannabinoids that
radical science is investigating in
which have the most therapeutic
potential
before we get to my conversation with dr
jeff i want to thank this episode's
sponsor planetary
female founded planetary is truly
plant-based wellness designed to keep
you moving and playing
planetary created a water-based hemp
extraction method and built a vertically
integrated company with usda organic
certified products made from full
spectrum stable cbda
the answer for plant-based
anti-inflammation is found in nature
beautifully harnessed with science
to learn more visit planetary.com
that's p-l-a-n-e-t-a-r-i-e
[Music]
dot com
okay without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with dr jeff chen
[Music]
good afternoon dr jeff how are you doing
today
i'm doing great thanks for having me ben
excited for this yeah i'm excited too
because we're talking today about a very
important topic and that's clinical
trials um i had professor matrulam on
the podcast a little while back and he
was very passionate about the need for
more clinical trials
and you know anecdotal evidence is great
individual case studies are useful but
clinical trials are the best we need
good data to silence those who are
opposing cannabinoid medicine and claim
that there isn't enough data to show
efficacy so i know that your group at
radical science is approaching clinical
trials in a new way
and i encourage people to check out your
kanmed 2022 presentation in our archive
on kim at events.com to learn more um
so to start
i'm hoping you can explain why is it so
difficult to perform good clinical
trials on cannabinoid medicines
sure
well the the first thing to realize is
clinical trials in general regardless of
what you're studying are already
gargantuan undertakings and you're
talking about
high cost
extreme complexity and also a very slow
speed to completion
a clinical trial can easily run millions
of dollars
requires a team of very talented
scientists and
physicians and can easily take years
so as soon as you
understand that about clinical trials
then instantly you already see why it's
a barrier to any sort of
compound or product
that say isn't backed by a large pharma
company
that has the resources wherewithal and
more importantly the experience to
navigate a clinical trial so that's the
first thing to understand now
there's this might be a conversation for
a separate time as to why they're so
expensive and slow but a lot of it's
they're they're they're bureaucratic
there's a lot of regulations around the
clinical trials expensive personnel are
involved again
high-level scientists phds doctors they
often involve clinical trial sites so
now you have expensive medical
facilities the experience for people in
the clinical trial is sub-optimal to say
the least so now you have to
pay them incentives to put up with all
the inconvenience and take potentially
scary
you know experimental drugs all these
things all right now let's zooming in on
cannabinoids specifically what makes
clinical trials difficult on
cannabinoids i'll focus on the us but a
lot of these also parallel other places
around the world the first thing is the
regulatory
classification of cannabinoids when it
comes to thc it's a controlled substance
and so if a researcher wants to research
thc they need to go get special dea
licenses
and if you're even after obtaining those
dea licenses they can only purchase
those controlled cannabinoids from other
people who have a dea license to
manufacture those controlled
cannabinoids when it comes to cannabis
thc containing cannabis
for
last 50 years there was only one entity
that had that dea license it was the
university of mississippi
in the last
you know six to 12 months a handful of
other entities have been granted those
licenses
um
but so that's that's the difficulty as a
researcher i got to go through all these
extra hoops to get that license once i
have the license from the dea i'm very
limited into who i can buy those
controlled substance cannabinoids from i
have to store them a certain way i have
to install security systems even though
there might be a cannabis dispensary
across the street where anyone over
you know the age of 21 can walk in and
buy stuff i still have to treat this
uh
like how the federal government defines
it
when it comes to other cannabinoids
things like cbd research is different
difficult for a different reason
so when it comes to cbd the fda is
saying okay
cbd while it might not be a controlled
substance anymore after the 2018 farm
bill
we now consider it a drug
like a pharmaceutical drug that's
because epidiolex
is a basically cbd isolate it's fda
approved so cbd isn't a drug
if you want to research cbd you need to
go through an investigational new drug
process
and
that process is both onerous for the
researcher
and onerous for the company supplying
the product to go into the study
if it was classified as just a dietary
supplement study it's so much easier for
the producer of the product to get the
product
up to spec for the study and it's so
much less cumbersome for the researcher
but as soon as the
product has to undergo the research as
an investigational new drug it makes it
very difficult if not nearly impossible
for a vast majority of in this case cbd
providers to have their product
classified and be registered with the
fda as a
acceptable investigational new drug and
in places a much more cumbersome process
on the researcher you do see this in
other countries as well there's a reason
that canada
legalized cannabis and cannabinoids
medically 10 years ago how many rigorous
clinical trials have you seen come out
of canada on any cannabinoids it's
because they still need special licenses
from the government to research
cannabinoids and then the cannabinoids
they can research have to then go
through this
you know more stricter process than say
a herbal study or dietary supplement
study
so it seems like a weird kind of
catch-22 or chicken in the egg i don't
know which metaphor fits here but
um
you know the government is saying that
you know we need more data before we can
you know make this a non-controlled
substance or you know open it up for
more research or you know legalize it
medically but
they're also making it difficult to do
any of this research in order to make to
to classify it that way
that that's exactly it and there have
been attempts to
change laws to make the process easier
i haven't seen too much traction on that
end i know there have been bills
presented in front of congress to try
and change
elements of this
but even if you can solve the
unique restrictions and difficulties
that cannabinoids face until you
fundamentally solve the complexities and
the high cost and the slow speed of
trials you're still not going to get the
data you need on any sort of
acceptable time scale and on any sort of
acceptable
rigor and volume of data to allow
people to make enough decisions
appropriate decisions on cannabinoids
there's
tens of millions of americans using
cannabinoids every day
and
with the current pace of research
studies we might not have data for a
decade or more to appropriately inform
who should use what type and what
dosage for what use case who should
avoid what type at what dosage
if they have other existing
issues for example
right so we need a new approach and
that's what you guys are doing at
radical science so explain how how you
guys are approaching clinical
trials so radical science were
reimagining clinical trials from the
ground up the first area that we wanted
to
start was to ensure that we're not
trapped by many of the same
federal funding restrictions that
universities are trapped by
and so this is why
universities even state public
universities in states where cannabis is
legal they still can only follow federal
rules study federally regulated
cannabinoids in a federally compliant
fashion that's because they take federal
funding almost all universities take
federal funding
so
instantly you're eliminating the option
for them to study things that again tens
of millions of americans are using every
day so we avoid federal funding we don't
take federal grains and because of that
we have a lot more flexibility in
studying things like cbd for example
without an investigational new drug
process or studying other cannabinoids
from hemp for example
also
we wanted to address the cost the high
cost and the slow speed of clinical
trials and to do that we adopted a
virtual direct to consumer trial process
so with the virtualization of it we can
eliminate
all that expensive infrastructure
the hospitals the clinics the fancy
buildings that many universities like to
spend money on
we go completely virtual
and then when we go direct to consumer
the data capture
is directly from consumers i don't have
a nurse or a doctor or a research staff
having to interview every single
person in the study hand them a paper
survey collect their responses then
upload that paper survey into a computer
for example i'm collecting data from
them directly so i've removed the
intermediaries
and expensive intermediaries expensive
personnel that were driving up the cost
also streamlining a lot of the
operational aspects of clinical trial
automating them with technology it's
another key innovation that we've done
as well at radical science
in addition we're vertically integrated
we don't hire some other firm to do our
recruitment we don't hire some other
firm to do our analysis and report
generation
we do everything in-house from the
design of the studies to the powering of
the studies to the technology stack that
uh collects data and manages and
oversees the studies to the analysis the
reporting everything we do end to end
and that's how we can also drive
additional
cost and speed improvements to our
clients and one other key innovation of
radical science is that we're running
template studies
and so we like to say that we've done
for clinical trials what ford motors did
for automobiles
so a hundred years ago before ford came
along you could get a car
it was just
made to order customized and hand built
by a team of guys for a year or two and
it was only available to the 0.01
and then ford came along and said you
know what screw that i'm going to build
the model t it's a template car it's
going to have four doors four wheels
this type of engine if you don't like
that you can go order
your hand-built car but for the 99 of
people that this is good enough
and this is appropriate great so we've
done that for clinical trials and so we
don't do custom studies you want a
custom study to come to us we say sorry
you can go find one of a thousand
universities and cross do that custom
study for you but if you want a template
study that's ten times cheaper and
faster and you're interested in one of
the template studies we offer pain
uh anxiety mood sleep energy cognition
fatigue
great let's talk we can turn this around
in a way that's never been done before
and drive and help you drive the r d
that you need help you substantiate the
claims that you need to your
stakeholders
wow that's interesting and i love that
analogy so so what do these templates
look like and how would they differ from
you know a clinical trial that's done in
a university um i mean obviously not not
including the things you talked about
with it being virtual and all that but
just the the study itself so that's the
thing these studies are actually
designed in collaboration with
university researchers and professors
they consult with us in an individual
capacity because oftentimes they're
frustrated
with the fact that it's basically
impossible to do these same studies at
the universities and what these
professors love to do at any one in
academia they love to think they love to
be creative they love to analyze data
what they don't love to do is
redundant bureaucratic operations and
paperwork which is now driving you know
that's that's kind of like the hallmark
of these clinical trials now in these
university environments right and so
fundamentally the design the rationale
the
controls we put in place to eliminate
bias they are no different than gold
standard clinical trials run at
universities so you know in radical
science we're running blinded randomized
placebo-controlled trials at large scale
using validated outcome measures
uh and analyzing them using kind of gold
standard approaches to biostatistics
so from that standpoint the studies are
the same caliber it's just we've been
able to
do them in a process
direct to
virtual automated streamlined to lower
the cost and improve the speed
and then with this template approach we
furthermore save time when you call
radical science i don't need to spend
six months thinking of a study designing
it
powering it building in our tech stack
and then going out to run it and being
like whoops i didn't foresee xyz issue
it's delayed now or the date is not as
great as it could be i've already run
this study
27 times you're the 28th time i'm
running it sign the contract it's ready
to go there's no anticipated delays
there's no unexpected mistakes that are
going to come about
it's a it's a factory line so when you
buy toyota camry it's going to work a
lot better than when you buy some dudes
can build hot rod in his garage and he's
driving it for the first time to your
house to deliver it to you yeah no and i
would imagine having that template
approach too and make it easier to
compare one study to another
in the long run that's theoretically
possible
although that's not that's not really an
intended goal i guess that's that's
theoretically possible
in the long run but also keep in mind
with with our
studies
the data is all confidential to the
brand so the goal here is not to show
one company is or is not better with
their approval
then yes the template nature does allow
you to look between studies somewhat and
the asus study for example was one where
all the brands specifically opted in to
this aggregate kind of comparison across
all of their uh products but otherwise
the stuff the data
both the identity of the brands we work
with and their specific study data it's
all confidential to them we only talk
about it if they give us permission
interesting yeah and so
i guess that's a good question too so
the answer is probably obvious but what
is the benefit of having this clinical
dr trial data for the brands themselves
what can they do with that or what does
that enable them to do that they
wouldn't be able to do otherwise
yeah i would say there's many different
reasons that brands have come to us
and sometimes it's not just the brand
sometimes it's the ingredient suppliers
that have come to us to do studies
hoping that they can prove
uh that their ingredients
actually work and therefore it's not a
commodity they can sell more of it sell
it at a premium price
compared to other people that don't have
that data or for some of these minor
cannabinoids generate the first ever
data of human effectiveness and
basically create the market in demand
for that cannabis now the ingredient
supplier or that distributor or the
manufacturer of that product can benefit
but there's also the end stream
downstream brands who also
engage us too and again the the range of
options are it's everything from
substantiating claims that's a major one
you know this this ingredient or this
branded product is clinically shown
clinically proven validated demonstrated
to improve xyz to do xyz so you can't
make disease claims
so you're not you're not curing insomnia
you are improving sleep quality and
that's where you don't invoke
the fda's position that this is a drug
making a disease claim
so claim substantiation is a major one r
d is another major one too so we've run
studies that are as large as several
thousand people where the company is
comparing up to for instance eight
different formulations head to head
wanting to understand which one would be
best to take to market
so you're talking about an r d process
that for and this is not cannabinoid
specific any sort of consumer health
product their r d is often like let's
come up theoretically with the product
we give it to a few dozen friends and
family get some anecdotal feedback
feedback looks good my aunt says it
looks good great now let's go make a
multi-million dollar business launch
decision on this
even though there's a very fair chance
it could be placebo
so r d is a big piece of this as well
and then other areas i think brands also
realize that having this data is
valuable for them to go raise money
from skeptical investors who see them at
like every other company out there
hawking a supplement or hacking some
consumer health product
dramatically raises their valuation
dramatically
gets trust from investors and in a
similar vein people who are trying to
get
distribution of retail you know you're
one of
1400 ashwagandha brands that i've talked
to in the last 30 days what makes you
different oh well we have clinical trial
data so you can know that you're
exposing your customers to a product
that's real and by the way our product
can make claims it'll fly off your shelf
so those conversations become
possibilities as well with the right
data
excellent and now in order to make those
claims is that that data need to be
public somewhere do they have to publish
it um either on their website or in a
journal or something like that
correct so to make structure function
claims you do have to publish the data
the
but publishing is a very broad sense it
just needs to be accessible by the
public so it could be a white paper that
sits on your website
um it could be all the way to peer
review publication as well so some
brands after the studies ready they're
happy just to release it as a white
paper on their website other ones want a
peer-reviewed publication for an extra
layer of credibility so we will we have
services where we'll help them and
submit those
papers as well
excellent yeah and you mentioned the
aces study um so i was hoping you could
talk a little bit more about that
because that was a pretty important
study a pretty large study
yeah so the aces study was the first
study that we attempted as a company and
we launched it about a year ago
at the time our company was pretty small
and pretty young
but it's it's uh i think it's pretty
impressive
and speaks on on my team that we decided
hey you know we're a company that's six
month old let's just do the largest cbd
clinical trial ever done in history and
let's get it done in six months so
that's the like
goal we set for ourselves and we pulled
it off
so we had 14 brands join us in the asus
study it involved nearly 3 000 americans
and this was a
this was a study that was specifically
intended to collect real world data
on the usage and outcomes that cbd
products might be providing to the tens
of millions of americans using it
and in order to maintain the real world
lens of the study we decided to make it
an open label study
what open label means that people got
the product in a form that was not
blinded they knew what they were taking
and in this case we wanted the companies
to submit products in their natural form
that was already being sold on a shelf
and again to mimic the experience of
someone going on amazon or walk into a
store
buying a cbd product they know it's cbd
it comes in something that's nice and
labeled right they know the company
behind it
so all these things were meant to mimic
the real world
outcomes and therefore for us to be best
able to approximate those outcomes
so we ran the study we ran it for a
month we got nearly 3 000 americans
and the americans were assigned to one
of
the cbd products
and which they got in the mail or they
were assigned to be in a control arm
where they did not receive any cbd
product but we continue to track their
pain their anxiety their sleep their
well-being and their quality of life
just to understand how it might change
over time
that control allows us to control for
the natural
progression of these conditions i'm
anxious today
and without any intervention what
happens to my anxiety four weeks from
now maybe gets worse maybe gets better
maybe it stays the same it also allowed
us to control from macro
environment
instances so for instance if i was
living in ukraine
four months ago and you see my anxiety
spike
if i have a weightless control group i
can be like oh it's probably because you
know the russians invaded anxiety spiked
across the board i can now control and
factor that in when i look at these
people on the cbd and i go now why is
there anxiety getting worse that's weird
oh that's right a war broke out because
i can look at the control group
so it was important for us to have that
control group
and what we found
uh
was and and we wanted products that have
a variety of different form factors we
had soft gels and gummies and tinctures
and sprays and
dissolving tablets and we had different
spectrums we had isolate full and broad
spectrum and we had different dosages
too again just to get a huge
representation of all the products out
there
and when we analyzed the data we found a
lot of things so
we found
that
there were
significant improvements across the
board for anxiety sleep and pain
anxiety had the largest improvements
followed by sleep and followed by pain
and
we also found that the
largest improvements tended to happen
within the first half the first week or
two of using the product
and then by weeks three and four there
were still improvements happening but
they were at a much
more reduced pace so think of it as like
if this is their
uh if this is showing the
improvement
in their
uh
well-being for example you see in the
first week or two and then you still see
it kind of increase
i guess i realize i was just gesturing
by hands as the podcast so so you see a
sharper increase
in the first week or two and then a more
still increasing but more gradually
sloped off increase in the latter half
of the week
we did some other interesting things we
looked at males and females and we found
that they were that didn't impact
the experience of the outcomes
we also looked at whether people were
naive moderate or experienced cbd users
and we did not find that that predicted
a difference in their health outcomes
from taking cbd and we also looked at
age groups and we also found that that
wasn't a predictor of effect so to recap
it seems that gender
or moreover sex assigned at birth
age group and experience with cbd
weren't
predictive of whether someone was going
to have a good or
bad result or improvement
we also analyzed the data set
by
spectrum
and by dose of cbd
and
what we found was that for spectrum we
did not find
a
significant difference by spectrum and
again i'll caveat that in a second
and when it came to
cbd dose we did not find a predictable
relationship that
a certain amount of cbd was necessarily
better than another amount
and
if you look at
and that's not to say that spectrum
doesn't matter
and that all cbd doses are the same
more likely what's happened is that
there was so much diversity in the
products
that
the products differed in multiple
characteristics right
and it was really hard for us to control
for just spectrum or just we tried our
best
um but i believe there still needs to be
many studies to dig into this notion of
what's the proper spectrum what's the
proper dosage that's actually why we
decided to launch these subsequent
studies on cbd
that
to fill in these missing gaps in the
knowledge so again to recap this is a
pretty monumental study largest cbd
trial in history we had a control arm
we enrolled nearly 3 000 people we found
that things like gender and age and
experience with cbd weren't predictive
for health outcomes we found that across
the board there were significant
improvements and anxiety sleep in pain
with anxiety experiencing the most
improvements followed by sleep followed
by pain and we also found that side
effects were rare and very mild about 10
percent of people in the study reported
any sort of side effect and they were
all generally mild side effects
great now
in those results was there anything that
stood out to you or that was surprising
or that you didn't expect
you know going into the study
we
i had expected
things like
experience with cbd to impact
outcome
and i also had potentially expected sex
assigned at birth
to also impact outcome because we've
seen from pre-clinical studies that sex
of mice male female mice have
differential experiences to cannabinoids
and actually gender differences or sex
differences
are becoming more more apparent across
all sorts of health outcome measures so
i was a little surprised
to see that but again this is an area
where we probably need many many more
studies in this realm to really confirm
what what we're seeing here and i i
forget
who this quote is attributed to but any
good study warrants many many more
follow-up studies so this is just the
first of of blip on the radar to to give
society a starting point with which they
can layer on additional studies on cbd
well yeah and that's a great segue
because you ha are currently doing a
follow-up study uh radical spectrum and
i imagine that you're applying some of
the lessons learned from aces now
correct so
radical spectrum you know in aces we we
had some preliminary findings on dose
and spectrum but again we knew that
because
these products differed not just in one
characteristic some of these products
differed in form factor
and dose and spectrum right um so spec
radical spectrum is a study
where
every company has to submit a minimum of
three things to us they're going to
submit a
placebo they're going to submit a cbd
isolate and they're going to submit a
broad or full spectrum product
all of these three submissions have to
look identical aka same bottle same form
factor
and so the only thing that's differing
is the contents
and then the isolate and the broad full
spectrum have to be the same
concentration of cbd so the only thing
differing between them is the other
stuff the other cannabinoids the
terpenoids and so this is a three-armed
study
with which at the end of the study
the brand can have several things
sitting in their data set that could be
useful they can first off they can have
proved that their product works better
than placebo
for a variety of health outcome measures
quality of life pain sleep anxiety mood
they could also potentially have proved
that their product works better than
isolate
if you look at the reason why the fda
says all these cbd supplements are
illegal is because
they resemble cbd isolate gw's epidiolex
but this data
might
be some of the first data ever
to show that these supplements do not
perform the same
as a cbd isolate and therefore you might
not be able to lump them
with something like a epidiolex from gw
pharmaceuticals and maybe perhaps they
aren't subject to
a drug preclusion principle from the fda
so you know the study is nice for the
brands and that
it allows them multiple things again it
allows them to prove their product works
better than placebo which for 99 of cbd
brands they don't have that those data
sets
they can also prove that the product
potentially works better than isolate
um at the same time the the study allows
them to do a dose titration so they can
explore multiple doses
of their product and simultaneously get
multiple shots on goal for quality of
life pain sleep anxiety and mood so
we're really excited about it for now
it's the last cbd study that we're going
to run
we're still going to run studies on
other hemp derived cannabinoids cbc cbg
cbn thcv et cetera but the fda is making
it very difficult to even research cbd
so after radical spectrum runs we're
going to table our cbd studies we'll
still be taking studies on other minor
cannabinoids because the fda has not
said those are drugs for example okay
and furthermore we're going to we
already have opened up our studies to
non-cannabinoid supplements so we're
running studies on functional mushrooms
and herbs and probiotics and the tropics
and a bunch of other things leveraging
our kind of
newly developed disruptive
trials platform
interesting yeah so first question
i take it based on the way you were
talking that the brands that are
involved in the spectrum study they're
all broad spectrum or full spectrum
brands correct yeah okay and then
secondly so
is cbd it's it's difficult to study
because of that drug designation that
you talked about earlier with epidiolex
that's exactly it yeah so
the the fda has
like starting many years ago the fda
first started saying hey you can't sell
cbd as a supplement
it's a drug you gotta
get it approved as a drug before you can
sell it and now we are
um increasingly
seeing that even the research of cbd
is going to require an investigational
new drug
uh process which universities have been
beholden to for quite some time we've
been able to do it thus far without it
but going forward we're not confident we
will be able to continue these studies
without that so that's why cbd spec or
the radical spectrum is our last study
um of any of our studies that allows cbd
products to be enrolled so going forward
we don't really have study slots or
enrollment slots open to cbd products
what about cbda
that gets a little
that could potentially that could
potentially work it's not cbd so yes
that could potentially work if there's a
way that you can stabilize the cvda and
show that it's not spontaneously
converting to significant quantities of
cbd and yes that could work
interesting okay and the radical
spectrum is will that data be made
public or is that going to be um
at the discretion of the brands that's
going to be at the discretion of the
brands
so
um
but you know so far
most if not all these brands have wanted
to talk about their data because it it
helps you know
them it helps the industry it helps
their own brand so
excellent so and before you i let you go
because you did bring it up um you're
talking about exploring some of these
other minor cannabinoids um
interested to know
um i i know you can only share so much
but um what are you looking at
in terms of you know those cannabinoids
which ones are you looking at and what
sort of conditions so we've already
we've already run studies
um on cbc cbg and cbn either by
themselves or in combinations with other
minor cannabinoids or in combinations
with cbd
we're about to start launching a series
of studies on thcv
in terms of cbc cbn cbg we've been
running studies on them for things like
anxiety
and pain and sleep for the upcoming thcv
studies it's going to be focused on
energy focus and appetite suppression
and then there's
subsequent studies as well that are
going to involve minor cannabinoids uh
for areas like quality of life and mood
and libido and things like that
great and which
in which of the minor cannabinoids do
you think is sort of
uh the next big minor cannabinoid
um look honestly
well how do i say this they're all
pretty interesting because we're all
starting from ground zero
you know
whatever people
state to be true or not true about minor
cannabinoids at least from human
effectiveness data there's not really
anything to go off of there just haven't
been studies
to prove or refute that any of these
minor cannabinoids could help certain
things so we're basically doing some of
history's first
not a sum up we are doing history's
first
human effectiveness randomized um
blind to placebo-controlled trials
to look at these things
but one thing that i think is really
interesting
just from a from the zeitgeist at the
moment everyone's talking about
how you can get better energy everyone
wants to take nootropics all this stuff
so i think thcv gets pretty interesting
where anecdotally you're hearing about
these effects
we do have human studies on thcv's
ability to
improve blood sugar levels
so definitely is modulating metabolism
and so i get really excited that we're
going to launch these studies to see how
it can really help with potentially
focus potentially with energy and
potentially with appetite suppression
and if you think about a lot of things
that americans are grappling with right
now poor sleep poor sleep and your
fatigue during the day or you're you're
you have fatigue or you've
long covered or you're not you know you
have you're anxious and you can't focus
right so the fact that thcv could
potentially help some of these areas
based on some of the
the strong anecdotal data we're seeing
that could really help improve a lot of
people's lives
who are having
grappling with these issues and wanting
better focus wanting more energy and
potentially wanting to um suppress their
appetite look i fast every day
for longevity purposes for some people
that's not achievable and other people
might need to fast more because they
have you know maybe gained some weight
and we know that excess weight is
tied to a whole host of deleterious
health outcomes from increased risk of
dementia to cardiovascular events
so i really hope that we know we'll see
what the studies show and if they're
positive and these are tools that could
really help a lot of people
yeah absolutely a lot of potential there
all right dr jeff before i let you go i
want to give you an opportunity to plug
any websites social media or additional
resources that the listeners could
engage with or read up on to learn more
about what you guys are working on
yeah so radical science we're here
running disruptive direct-to-consumer
clinical trials so
non-prescription health products can
accelerate their r d and substantiate
their claims we can do it all 10 times
cheaper and faster than anything that's
been done before radical is spelled
r-i-d-i-c-l-e kind of like particle and
that spelling of radical means the root
of a plant
and that's what we're getting to we're
getting to the root of
these health issues we're getting to the
truth behind all of these
um and so it's radical science you can
check out our website radicalscience.com
and you can follow us at radical science
on twitter and linkedin and and you know
all the usual social media channels and
so if you're curious about learning
about one of our studies
you can go to our website you can
contact us there as well and some
someone from my team will get back to
you within a day or so
excellent well jeff thanks again for
joining us on the podcast and i hope to
see you out at the next cam ed alrighty
thank you ben
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr jeff chen check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor planetary
our next episode will drop august 17th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out the
new and improved
canmenevents.com the team really did an
exceptional job updating the website
with all the information about our
kmid23 event
and of course you can still find videos
of all the previous canmed presentations
and panels in the canmed archive you can
also find all the previous episodes of
the podcast as well and while you're
there make sure you sign up for email
alerts to get all the notifications
around this innovative industry-leading
event i also invite you to engage with
us on all our social media platforms
we're on instagram facebook twitter and
linkedin just search for canned events
and lastly please leave us a review on
apple podcasts doing so really helps us
improve our rankings and reach more
listeners
alright that's it from us
stay safe stay healthy and be sure to
join us on the next candid coffee talk
[Music]
you