[Music]
y so your your study looked particularly
at persistent and post- treatment Lyme
disease well yeah so we call it that
because um in the the from our uh so a
couple things one is I didn't want to um
allude to the fact that one should treat
acute you know like an acute case with
just cannabis but also um in the data
set these are people that are are you
know filling out a form saying I have
Lyme disease so I don't know what stage
they're at um but so uh it's that's
seemed like a large enough grouping this
it's kind of safe to assume that that
they're either treating persistent cases
or post- treatment but there's no reason
that some of them couldn't have been
acute it's just unlikely if they're just
in that short treatment window of two
weeks on doxy cycl that they would enter
this world of treating it with cannabis
right yeah right the symptoms that we're
tracking like anxiety inflammatory pain
sleep those kinds of things are are
common in the later stages of life um
and again if you're treating it with
cannabis you've probably already been
through the standard round these are
those are assumptions that but we can't
interview these these patients so we're
really just looking at they say they
have lime
and they're treating X symptom and um
and the tool helps them rate it on on
different scales so what's interesting
though as as ubiquitous as lime is as
much as cannabis is being looked at
nobody had ever looked at these two
together before um and if you which is
really surprising because if you do a
just a simple Google search there's a
lot um where every dispensary is telling
you you should treat your lime disease
with canab
and lots of lots of doctors websites
have you know blog posts about using
cannabis to help with Lyme disease and
lots of lime blogs and and lime
information websites tell you CBD and
cannabis are good symptomatic treatments
but absolutely nobody has done any
academic or formal uh look at it until
now which is really weird um and you
know we're doing a retrospective sort of
naturalistic study um and we're
continuing to examine more symptoms and
and kind of parse out the data um
because it really is effective and and
it's interesting that it affects people
so the things that lme people sorry Lyme
diseas is often a root cause of things
like
rheumatoid
Ms ALS it can be mistaken for
Parkinson's um if for Lupus
fibromyalgia these are all things people
commonly use cannabis to treat right so
very so and they're not always caused by
lime but lime is one of the potential
causes of these syndromes um and so that
was very interesting to me too um and so
what we found though is that people who
like use it for arthritic for
inflammatory pain if they have lime
respond differently than people who are
using it for inflammatory pain who don't
have
them uh same thing with anxiety how so
so like higher THC formulations were
found um more relieving for anxiety than
mixed Ceno ratios um with in people with
lime whereas when we look at overall on
the other end it's usually the other way
around like a one: one or a high higher
CBD ratio Formula will be better better
for lime uh for anxiety I see so the THC
is more helpful for lime because it's
better at relieving inflammation right
got it and or and so it's interesting so
there's a lot I mean when we talk about
the data there's a lot I can I can say
about that it's pretty interesting yeah
let's talk about that I mean first of
all you know where where are you getting
this data like how yes where's it coming
there's a there's a great um uh app and
website called strain print uh strain
print.css track a fair amount of
American Products as well so it's a
really great um uh use tracking
tool um
so um and I so I suggest to people
regardless because it's helpful because
you know you might say say you use you
use and you find oh my Pain's really
relieved but it also then will ask you
are you feeling tired are you feeling um
you know a irritable or upset stomach so
helps you note side effects as well and
help dialing so kind of help dial in
your dosing that way um but it asks
people to identify their disease or or
diagnosis and then it'll give a list of
symptoms commonly associated with those
but then you can also choose your own it
tracks up to like 70 different symptoms
that's a lot um and then uh you rate it
how you're feeling on a scale one to 10
before you put in what you took and then
and then rate after and so he's got for
if you're in Canada for example all the
products in dispensaries are loaded into
that app so it tracks all the testing
data and stuff like that so it's also
useful for producing ERS and and looking
and studies to say you know what
cannaboid ratio might be good for this
Sal and that sort of thing so that
that's it's interesting that way so
we're able to track a lot of
different um ratios of uh products that
people used um and in this one we were
now is that down to like the batch level
too yeah yeah yeah if if it's a company
that's regularly submitting their stuff
yeah yeah that's awesome um yeah and so
it's it's it's it's useful in oh so many
ways it's really cool right um so the
the um we looked at a a combined of
inhaled and edible products so we kind
of put it all in one but it would be
interesting to parse that out in the
future um and we looked at a range of
cannaboid ratios of including THC only
CBD only and then naturalistic ratios so
you might in the data you might see like
a 25 to one that's that's a very high
THC um cannabis but it's still a
naturalistic ratio so it's got some meas
able amount of THC CBD and other
cannaboids in there but we're really
just looking at THC and CBD as well and
which is something I think is often not
enough but it's what we have more often
than not um and uh and going all the one
to one and on the other end of things um
and what we found in this data set was
there was an overwhelming preference for
THC very very strong preference and and
very high in the THC only
I note that to a product availability um
what's what's pushed in dispensaries you
know there's a higher margin in
distillate in in for some in some way
sometimes so um and then the convenience
factor um there as well so I think
that's part of it and then that's also
primarily what's in Edibles right they
use distill in Edibles as well because
then they can have an even measure of
dosage even though it may not be the
best delivery method so while that was
used the most most often not in every
case was it the most preferred but it
always scored very high um but when you
when you look at other ones what often
scored equally High um and uh or better
with
less dosages um uh was naturalistic
ratios or one to one um CBD only often
also didn't perform very well in general
[Music]
a