I could good afternoon to you all and
many thanks for the introduction and
take you the organizers for the
invitation to talk here
I'm psychopharmacologist from Brazil
most of you probably don't know me my
main contribution to the field so far
with the dent ocation of the endogenous
mechanism of allosteric modulation at
cb1 receptor but today I I dare to come
here to talk about a meta-analysis study
I did on the potential benefits of CBD
for epilepsy bringing together other
viable clinical data and I think it's
appropriate to express my conflict of
interest because I recently acept a new
challenge in life so I'm leading product
development as a scientific director in
Entourage
fighter lab and Rogers a start-up
pharmaceutical company who is starting
to develop cannabis based products is
starting from varieties of bad rockin in
Brazil so we are the exclusive partners
of better con in Brazil and as I said
today I'm going to talk about this
meta-analysis studies of CBD on epilepsy
this whole field is being pushed by
stories like this one that you know
Charlotte fish a small child with
treatment-resistant epilepsy who started
to take and benefit from cannabis based
treatments and there are many other
stories like hers in Brazil we also have
our Charlotte Figi she's called any
fissure his picture here with her family
and by starting taking these products in
particularly high CBD varieties of
cannabis she went from 64 conversions
per week to vertel to zero as his dad
norbert officially saying in this
picture and this is the patient zero in
brazil and she was the first patient to
receive the authorization to import
cannabis based products in brazil and
from there on there's a lot of other
patients he's starting to import these
products I'm saying port because they're
not a single registered product on
Brazil right now for this for this
children of course there there is
sativex which was recently
register but there's not a viable yet in
the pharmacist and of course Sativex is
not the best option for this children
but right now we have over 2,000 people
being able to import cannabis based
products in Brazil and the majority the
vast majority of them are epileptic
patients I'd say close to 70% and they
have a lot of products of viable but
it's quite confusing at this time the
patients don't know how to choose
they're pressing the clinicians the
doctors don't know exactly what is the
difference between the products and the
fact that these products are not
standardized and this FDA warning
letters saying that they might contain
contaminants herbicides and we cannot
trust in the levels of cannabinoids that
they express in the labels don't help at
all so this is the gap we want to feel
with the belacan varieties and proper
pharmaceutical development in enter our
fighter lab and what's the behavior of
Brazilian clinicians right now they like
to say there's not enough evidence this
is very comfortable isn't it like a
patient is pressing you there's a lot of
clinical reports study reports as sorry
case reports as we saw this morning but
the physicians are say there's not
enough evidence they're sitting there
comfortably in the chair and we rely on
just a few pioneers it's really just a
handful or two of clean
Brazilian clinicians who are starting to
prescribe I'd like to name here Paula
doll Stella which is in the audience one
of the pioneers treating over 100
patients with this kind of products
[Applause]
and and really I mean people no matter
what we do people are starting to take
this this product and do they work I
absolutely agree we don't know exactly
especially because when it comes to
Herbert products they are not
standardized so it's really hard to
raise evidence using these products but
so far we do have some evidence and
that's what I propose to do I search for
a child together with epilepsy and
cannabis cannabinoids cannabidiol all
sort of things to do a systematic review
and the idea was to really dig into this
data and see whether there is any
coherence between them and I could find
six papers in the first in the first
search and I had another one by hand
which was impressed at a time and of
course a few data from the partial
public reports of GW so this is the
viable clinical data that I included in
the systematic review you can see
they're all respected a neurologist
centers mostly from us and they're
different designs you see surveys you
see with respective and prospective
medical records some with a lot of
patients some not and different
durations of treatment I'm going to
summarize in the next slides so the
characteristics of these studies are
children and adolescent adolescents with
treatment-resistant a Pepsi most of them
with a plastic encephalopathy including
reveille and an August Oh which is very
important in this case and in many many
cases patients write at least four
different treatments for up to twelve
different treatments before trying CBD
oil so it's a very treatment resistant
population so to speak and it's it's
summer up to four 442 patients so it's
it's a lot of evidence with an average
freedom in duration of half a year and
the products are either CBD rich tracts
or purified CBD with a wide range why do
those range which is always intriguing
me like when we talk to the patients and
and the clinicians who are supporting
the patients the majority of the case
are in the low dose range one maybe to
five milligrams per kilo per day
but that's in clear contrast contrast to
what we see in the clinical trials
reporter reported so far so this is
something I wanted to understand using
this data so my main objectives is the
this systematic review was to understand
whether there was any consistent
evidence of efficacy and safety but I
also tried to understand whether there
were difference between people using CBD
rich tracts in purified CBD of course
you know that cannabis phyto complex has
a lot of different compounds just to
mention the potential anti platic
compounds we have of course CBD and the
obvious thing GC is also anti platic
it's even more potent in CBD but of
course it has more restrict therapeutic
window and also we have GCV CBD CBN and
also non cannabinoid compounds like
linen all and mercy this is the table
that summarized the efficacy results
it's quite complex I just wanted to show
that they're different efficacy rates
and and different in different studies
and all of them are complete so that's
why you see the numbers fluctuating in
the next slides but I'm going to
summarize it and make it very visual to
be easier to understand so first things
first there was clear evidence of
efficacy in a treatment resistant
population so when asked did the
treatment improve the seizures 66% of
the patients or the parents said yes
there was improvement so 66% if you
considered the traditional threshold of
improving more than 50% to be considered
a responder then this number is down to
35% so to say one-third of people are
considered responders when taking CBD
based medicines which is it's to a lot I
mean remember that we are talking about
treatment resistant population and one
in every three patients are benefiting
from from then in a very rigorous
clinical threshold there are evidence of
superior efficacy in this particular
population in dravet syndrome compared
to the general population
not for Alan August or at least in this
in this cohort in this population and
here come the more surprising things for
me when we split between the purified
CBD and CBD basis tracks there are a
higher rate of improvement in herbal CBD
as I nicknamed here in the slides just
to make it easy there a higher
improvement here than on purified CBD
this doesn't hold true when you consider
just the responders they're both high so
40% but there's no difference in this
case when you consider just people that
achieve more than 50% of improvement and
here comes the more striking thing at
least for me the average those reported
by people taking purified CBD is close
to 20 milligrams per kilogram per day
whereas people taking CBD basis tracks
report an average joe's of 7 milligrams
per kilogram per day it's quite striking
isn't this is 3 times difference so for
me it means that there are something
else in these tracks which are
cooperating for the CBD if effects so we
would say that CBD is more potent when
given in fighter strikes then purified
of course there are adverse adverse
events reported Bay is quite often
overlap with efficacy so with close to
half percent of people report the
frequency but they also report adverse
event
most of them mild just a small fraction
of people report severe adverse events
and the most common ones is habit
appetite alterations on Sunderland's
gastrointestinal pain diarrhea
alterations in weight fatigue and nausea
and rare and uncommon adverse events
also also happen but most of the time in
combination with other drugs valproic
acid and kléberson as highlights when I
did this split in data form I'll adverse
events there are also this difference a
high report of mild adverse events in
purified CBD than on CBD basis tracks
and this is also true for severe adverse
events
a higher report for purified CBD than
horrible CBD and of course it's
important to mention this is all the
adverse events which you were reported
they're not necessarily attributed
directly to the drug that's a highlight
phone from one of the studies describing
over 100 patients but I think it's a
very important one to be made is that
the the profile of adverse events was
already very high when people were
taking the anti avulsed medicines before
CBD and most of them almost all went
down when CBD was included just two of
them went up which is weight gain and
increases appetite which is not exactly
a bad adverse event is is considered
beneficial one in some populations for
instance oncological pain patients and
last but not least other aspects that
are improved by CBD aspects of quality
of life even despite efficacy in some
cases people report improvement in
alertness sleep or more behavior
language and motor skills stating that
the cognitive development of these
children children is being improved by
the drug to conclude so I would say yes
there are evidence CBD works for
epilepsy at least as far this
observational clinical data in treatment
resistant population is concerned it's
tract composition here is very very key
so one must understand what kind of
cannabis train what is the stability of
the compounds quality controls must
improve a lot in this product and CBD
rich tracks seems to be a better choice
over purified CBD at least in this
population in this meta analysis studies
here's my contact for those who are
interested to extend this conversation
and I would say that of course we will
benefit for controlled clinical trials
but not enough evidence is is not a
reasonable excuse anymore
to prevent patients from have access to
these medicines thank you
you