for a warm welcome here in boston
good morning everybody it's an honor to
be here
i got into the medical cannabis field
because of a friend who was sick my
background is pediatric emergency
medicine
which i did for about 13 years in the
los angeles area
busy hours working at night taking care
of pretty sick kids in the inner city
and east l.a
and then i had a small child at home and
i was burned out
and so i took time off and at that time
you know we all say things happen for a
reason
a friend of mine contacted me who was
sick and said i want to use medical
cannabis
and i was utterly ignorant i had no idea
i remember the college days and after
that i had
no experience so i decided to do my
research
and i started reading and because i had
time on my hands i was able to read
a lot of the scientific literature and i
was blown away
and i said i'll help you and then when i
decided to go back
to practice i decided to transition into
the medical cannabis specialty and that
was in 2008
and i really haven't looked back since
then
i take care of both adults and children
and because of my pediatric background
i in the past three years and again part
of that too because of dr sanjay gupta's
documentary have had an incredible surge
of
pediatric patients seeking care
unfortunately california has the
reputation of the wild west and i
would say that without regulations there
it is kind of hard to practice but what
i'm going to tell everybody is that
my patients are getting medicine my
patients are getting better my patients
have better quality of life
and so the rest of the country it is
imperative that we follow or the rest of
the country follows california
we have a lot of things that we can do
better there
and i think that we're working on it
with the government's
now stepped in a little bit to help
regulate i think people in the industry
are starting to recognize
that they have to sell self-regulate i
heard dr mushulum say yesterday medical
and recreational need to be separated
absolutely a hundred percent
they both need to be available in every
state
uh in this great country of ours uh we
need to lead the way for the rest of the
world because this is a plant
that has some incredible properties and
in a country where we allow people to
drink alcohol
and smoke cigarettes i mean really we
have to look at ourselves and say what
are we doing
so without further ado i'll just move on
here
so i just decided to make a list of
diagnoses of the patients that i see in
my adult patients this is just some of
the more common diagnoses
as you can see it spans just about
everything
in one day's time i can see patients
with
10 different organ systems involved and
so
again going back to the endocannabinoid
system being involved in all of these
illnesses
that's why it works you know even my own
attorney says oh you think it cures
everything and i said no it doesn't but
you have to look at where the endocannab
where the cannabinoid receptors are
located
and that will help lead you to
understand what's going on
with these illnesses with pediatrics
as you can see it's just a handful of
diagnoses by far
it's the patients that i see with
treatment resistant epilepsy
i'm seeing a lot more patients with
autism and i think john did an
excellent uh talk about how
this is such a devastating disease for
families that really impacts the quality
of life for
everybody think about siblings who
are living with this who struggle to
just go to school they have a sibling at
home that they're terrified of
this is something that definitely needs
to be addressed
advanced cancer in pediatrics which is
heartbreaking
and then i've been seeing a fair amount
of patients with severe psychiatric
disorders and also
pandas which i'll go over only a few
patients with that but i've had very
good success in just that handful of
patients
the rationale for you for cannabis use
in uh pediatrics is that
over the past decade or so uh uh with
thanks to many of the researchers
that are looking at endocannabinoid
dysfunction there is some scientific
scientific evidence showing that these
patients are having manifest
manifestation of endocannabinoid
dysfunction
if their endocannabinoid system is not
working
we are seeing illness also with
cannabis if you look back throughout
time going back even to the mid-1800s
there are reports looking at the safety
of cannabis there was one that
uh british
uh researchers went to india to look at
the safety it's a really interesting
report from 1894
and then there's been multiple repo
reports after that
of the safety profile this is safe
of course with children i like medical
supervision but
um there's no question that uh cannabis
in general is uh
quite well tolerated and certainly safer
than most of the medications that we're
prescribing to children
quality of life of course is very
important
when you have a child who's ill and the
parents in the audience who have an ill
child can tell you
quality of life is terribly impacted
when it comes to some of the cancer
patients or
some of the patients with epilepsy who
have a
terminal genetic disease just
compassionate care and end of life
importance there and there's no question
that that helps people get through that
in california of course we it since 2012
we've been able to test the quality of
products does it have a ways to go yes
and certainly after kevin's talk i've
learned a lot more about testing for
microbial
organisms but we do have the ability to
test so that patients can
be somewhat assured that the medication
that they're getting is
is clean and then of course research is
still desperately needed
there's a lot of research coming out now
the fact that we're all here today
looking at this
is absolutely inspiring to me i've met
so many people who are interested and
intrigued by this plant and all of us
need to
really go out there and spread the word
and lead the way
so what i did with my practice since i
have a lot of time today i decided just
to kind of collect my data
and so i looked at my patients who came
to me with treatment resistant epilepsy
they had to be on at least three months
of oil and some of them were even on oil
a year or even
two years and it's a whole plant oil
extract
and i was able to get results from 201
patients that responded to the um
to my emails and i the age range was
five months to 18 years and just people
always ask me how many patients do i
have i over over probably 300
plus uh pediatric patients using
cannabis
right now um and 200 responded to about
201 responded to
the email so average number of
um anti-epileptic drugs tried prior to
coming to my office
was 12 and there was a range of two
drugs all the way up to 22.
the average number of drugs that they
were taking at the same time
as they started cbd was three with a
range of zero to
seven there were 15 patients in this
group who were not taking
any other drugs at the same time that
they started cbd which definitely in my
experience makes it easier because of
the drug interactions
and then i listed the common
comorbidities i mean these patients have
a lot of challenges global delay
cp autism cortical visual impairment
feeding difficulties and so on
so it's not just one thing necessarily
that we're looking at counting seizures
we're also looking
at are these other
issues being improved by
cannabis as well and then the strains
and the cbd to thc ratios
varied charlottesville is a fairly
common medicine for patients to use and
it's about a 27 to 1 cbd to thc ratio
and then various preparations of ac dc
which is
available in california and i will tell
you that i've been doing this eight
years now
when i first started nobody even talked
about cbd
and really until about 2012 2013
is when we started talking about it and
literally
because of the push of families to get
access to this medication
um in the past year and a half it went
from one
product available to now at least
probably 10 or 12 products available
for people to try that are clean and
tested and in general
fairly so far fairly safe for my
patients
and here i made a chart of the the
results that i've seen
so as you can see some patients did have
worsening seizures and
we like to attribute that to drug
interaction but two of these
eight kids actually were not on any
medication so there's no question
that some of these patients do not do
well with cbd
no response in this particular group was
six
and i do know that i have a higher
number than that that did not respond to
my emails
so it's hard to say necessarily that's
the exact number i do believe that it's
a little bit higher than that
what's interesting is that i had about
28 patients um that responded who
reported that there was no reduction in
number
of seizures but they had a reduction in
the severity and the duration with
cognitive improvement and many of them
report that
you know because the seizures aren't so
bad we don't have to go to the hospital
as much
we're not using rescue medicine as much
and that again is an improvement and
remember these are people who are living
with seizures
sometimes in uh dozens of seizures a day
some even have hundreds of seizures a
day who are now saying we're having some
improvement in the quality of life
because we're not in the hospital
every four weeks and again the
disruption to family life when you're in
the hospital all the time
and it's funny because one of these uh
one of my patients is actually doing
quite well when the family came back for
a recheck just recently
and i said well just you know tell me
negatives positive whatever and the
first thing the father said is
i don't have to take care of the kids
because my wife is sitting in the
hospital with the sick one
and so that was huge to him that was the
number one thing
and they have five kids so it's very
hard when one parent disappears for a
week to go into the hospital
and then as you can see the range of 25
to 49
and again this is based on parents i ask
them to
keep a log to keep a calendar some of
them are very good at it obviously
it's hard to keep track of every seizure
but at the same time we have to
trust the families to be able to give us
a legitimate
number i do find that the families when
it doesn't work
they share that with you this is a
costly medicine in california it comes
it's out of pocket and when it's not
working i hear about it
so i do feel that it's uh somewhat
reliable data here
as you can see of the 27 seizure-free
patients remember these are children who
were told there is nothing else we have
nothing to offer you
um here's 27 families that now have a
child that's seizure-free
eight are actually pharmaceutical free
as well the rest are still weaning
about 40 percent of my patients have
been able to wean one or more
medicines sometimes it's only five
milligrams of a drug sometimes it's
50 percent of the medication the weaning
of drugs takes a long time for many of
these patients
they remember you can be seizure free
and then if you start messing with some
of the
aeds what happens is then you start
having seizures so many of the families
have actually chosen just to stay right
where they're at leave the drugs on
board
and let their child out grow the dose
and because they just feel that they're
in a good place and they don't they're
terrified to lose the effect
um in terms of negative side effects the
only two really that that popped up in
this were drowsiness and diarrhea
the numbers are small of course the
drowsiness may come from
if we're using very high doses or also
i find certain medications like clobazam
and others increase this uh the sedative
effect
and then if you look at the positive
side effects this is where parents
on the survey really just kind of went
uh nuts
writing things more alert better mood
better sleep more energy
better response to therapy and as you
can see and i put in quotes able to
argue one parent
actually complained to me that their
child stopped being wasn't as compliant
because he um was less drugged up and
more with the program and now he cared
if you put his shoes on and gave you a
hard time about putting his shoes on
when they left the house
so to me that's called a normal child
and parenting is part of that
no er visits less need for rescue
medication some of my families actually
measure you know they used to use
rectal valium six times a month and now
they've only used it once in the last
two months so to them they can see that
that's their objective because sometimes
it's hard to again to count seizures or
clusters
and then i have two patients that also
have uh
type one diabetes um who also the
parents reported that it appeared that
the glucose became more stable after
and you know that's unclear if it's a a
metabolic issue or if the child is not
seizing so much that you have better
control of the of the
glucose in my experience um
each and every patient is an individual
and will respond everybody says what
dose what dose there is no one dose
for every patient it is just like
everything in medicine it needs to be
personalized i usually start at about a
a half a milligram per pound or one
milligram per kilo per day
every eight hours i do find that in the
beginning every eight hours works better
some patients are able to go to every 12
hours if they've been successful and
they've been on the oil for quite some
time and then i just increase slowly
every couple of weeks
i stay in close contact with the
patients so that we can
titrate up and find the dose again
because it's expensive oil i don't want
to leave them on a sub-therapeutic dose
for three months and then check on them
then it doesn't make any sense to me
to do that we just kind of start going
up
and the average dose as you can see is
between five and eight i have a lot of
patients under that that do well
some patients are over that that are
doing well but on average i would say
the majority of patients fall between
that range
in california because there's many
different preparations if it's not
working you can change strains you can
change ratios
i have not found patients once they find
their dose that seems to work they don't
develop tolerance to it it appears that
they're able to stay at that
dose however this interesting phenomenon
has come up and some somebody asked a
question of dr mushulem yesterday
this terminology called cbd saturation
has come up
and it appears that for some of the
patients if they've been on the oil for
quite some time
if the child starts having more seizures
out of the blue they've been doing well
all of a sudden they start having
seizures they're not sick
they haven't leaned medication that
doesn't appear to be anything else
sometimes you know we somebody came up
with this term cbd saturation but really
the idea is that you maybe don't need so
much and we've been able to actually
back
down on dose and what's happening is
that the children respond to that i've
i've lowered dose in at least 25
patients and everybody says oh no you're
going to lower the dose what's going to
happen but they actually do well and
they stop having
the clusters of seizures that kind of
came out of the blue
another thing we're using in california
is thca which is a non-psychoactive
raw uh form of uh cannabis it wasn't
really readily available until about
maybe one or one and a half years ago
i've seen a fair amount of patients get
seizure reduction especially for drop
seizures
and just to mention cost in california
is an issue this is out of pocket
and the medication is can be expensive
especially if it's based on weight
and you have a large size child teenager
or so it can get very expensive now john
covered autism so i'm not going to go
over that
too much but i will tell you that
i'm getting some very good results there
is one human study showing that children
with autism have
increased cannabinoid receptors and the
question is is what does that mean
and how do we translate that but it
appears that there is some
dysfunction in the endocannabinoid
system
i have probably 70 plus autistic
patients in my practice
i again did a survey and i had 27
patients
parents who responded between children
between the ages of 3 and 18.
i did have some patients with cbd they
were over stimulated it they just became
more aggressive more agitated sleep was
disrupted
a handful of patients it didn't work and
about 17 out of these 27
the parents did report some improvement
um with calmer behavior and really the
big thing was a deuce
reduced aggression and that's very
important as john spoke about
and for many of my patients the
self-injurious
behavior is very difficult i've had
patients come in with
pillows wrapped around helmets mouth
guards all kinds of things
and if we can get that reduced it would
just mean such incredible
quality of life improvement i do find
that these patients don't need very
high doses you can do anywhere from one
to three times a day dosing
i listed the popular strains there and
again high cbd can be stimulating some
of these patients really respond very
well to combination cbd thc and
different ratios ten to one five to one
one to one
and so what i often do is have a
separate bottle of cbd and a separate
bottle of thc and
allows the parents to personalize the
medicine for that child
for pediatric cancer as you can see i've
listed here
you know a lot of the side effects i
look at at cancer in two ways one is
you're treating symptoms associated with
the cancer itself or the treatment
and then also i have some patients that
come to me who have exhausted every
option
they've read on the internet that
cannabis may fight cancer
and so again because cannabis has been
available in california now 20 years it
has
medical approval many of these patients
are accessing high dose oil and i'm sure
somebody today is going to talk about
this a little bit more
but what's interesting about this is
that i've actually seen some really
[Music]
very good results and on this slide i
talk about
i refer you to this one particular case
report that was published in 2013 of
this
cannabis extract for use in a uh 14 year
old
who had a terminal acute lymphoblastic
leukemia with terrible
genetics she after four years was sent
home
without any treatment in the parent this
was in canada and the parents obtained
some cannabis oil untested they had no
idea what they were giving her
but the doctors were able to follow her
blood work and remember with
leukemia you can draw blood and you can
follow the leukemia cells in the
bloodstream and they basically did it
every three to five days
and when they started and if you you go
to the slide or the study
you'll see that as the leukemia cells
dropped as the oil went up and it was a
clear-cut dose response curve in a
this is just you know a case report but
it did clearly show
uh two things one she wasn't on any
other medication
and because of her severe illness they
cannot attribute this to spontaneous
regression
so it was clear-cut that the cannabis
oil was doing something for this patient
i have a case report of a 16 year old
who came to me a year ago april with a
stage four osteosarcoma
metastatic to lungs to lots of different
areas of bone and they came in referred
in by an oncologist so bravo to her for
sending the patient to me
and we started very low dose cbd thc and
we went very high
we have no clinical trials i have no
idea about dosing i don't want to under
dose and cannabis is fairly well
tolerated
and the parents were willing to kind of
push the dosing
and he started cannabis oil in april
and in july 2015 he had pet scan ct
mri and a bone scan all negative for
disease
which is really incredible
he had repeat scans in november which
were negative i called his oncologist
and i said what do you think and she
said well he should be dead
and i just saw him last week his hair's
growing back he's off chemo
he's a little bit beat up from his uh
three years of chemotherapy
um but he's back in school and he's
doing really well
and there is a he was on gem cytobean
and i just
put the study on here uh for about the
first eight months of his
um treatment he was on gem cytobean
which
is in one study synergistic with
cannabinoids to increase
cancer killing so you know i am flying
blind a little bit in a lot of these
patients but it appears so far that
we're getting some good results i never
say cure with cancer because i don't
know but i definitely say extension of
life
and then i've been given the uh sign to
get off the stage here so i'm just going
to real quick just say cannabis
treatment of pediatric psychiatric
disorders
these are usually very severe cases that
come to me this is not just simple my
kid has anxiety
and usually patients have tried multiple
things
and it's pretty much the same you start
low dose i prefer to start high cbd to
low thc
because again developing brain and we
just kind of titrate up and if we have
to we had very tiny amounts of thc just
to play with it a little bit and see
what's tolerated and i've seen some very
good results
pandas if you're not familiar is
something that is still
probably under under diagnosed pediatric
autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorder
associated with strep infection so what
happens in some patients is they get
this
strep infection that basically causes a
dysfunction in the immune system that
creates a psychiatric condition and
parents say my kid went crazy
and nobody relates it back to the strep
but now we're starting to see that
there's this relationship
i've had three cases in my practice and
i've had very good results all
responding well to cbd rich cannabis oil
it's just an n of three but it's a place
to start
patients uh the parents report that they
feel like their child is uh
coming back to normal and so
that's very important um for those of
you who are making products for children
who are uh
who want to be uh part of the answer um
to this uh predicament we have with
cannabis in our country
i've listed here the most important
things that i see cannabis oil has to be
concentrated for children you cannot
give
a child 300 milligrams
when it's got four milligrams in one
teaspoon
how many teaspoons a day is that child
going to have to take so it has to be
concentrated
consistency and strain if a family finds
a strain that works
they don't want to go back next month
and hear oh gee you know what we didn't
grow that one anymore we have a new one
that's not an answer for a family who
has a very sick child
laboratory tested goes without saying
affordable
and then a reliable supply you can't go
back to your
supplier and they say oh we sold out of
that one why don't you try something
else that's not going to work for these
families
and then this is the best slide of all
these are all some of my patients
one of my patients went to venice beach
and put cannabis glasses on her
child who is seizure free and
pharmaceutical free after 13 years of
struggling with
seizure disorder i love that and um
this is i just want to say this is
what keeps me going is these kids right
here
and if you ever kind of get discouraged
by
what's going on with the government or
someone in your way
just try to focus on these families and
continue to move forward
thank you