[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben emerald i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
speaking of the canmed conference have
you gotten your tickets yet for
canmed2022
if yes then i can't wait to see you out
in pasadena this may for another
fantastic event
and if not what are you waiting for head
over to canmedevents.com now to get your
tickets
at cam ed 2022 you will learn from the
leading minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
and if you want proof of that look no
further than our keynote presenters
representing our science focus area we
have dr ethan rousseau presenting about
cannabis and psychiatry
representing our cultivation focus area
we have dr seth crawford talking about
innovations in hemp breeding
grace bandong our safety keynote
presenter will talk about building a
comprehensive analytical testing program
and finally dr bonnie goldstein will
discuss cannabis medicine for children
as our medical keynote
those presentations alone are worth the
price of admission but please go to kim
at events dot com to see the full
schedule
and if you want a preview of what you
can expect at kmed 2022 check out our
camed archive which is a searchable
video library of all the past canmed
presentations and panels find that at
cammannevents.com
at this year's event we are also
offering a full day pre-conference
medical practicum taking place on may
3rd
the medical practicum is led by dr
bonnie goldstein dr dustin sulak dr
kevin spellman and eloise
thiessen each of them will share the
latest medical cannabis research
including information on dosing drug
interactions and different product types
they will also share their clinical
experience they have acquired treating
patients with medical cannabis this
really is a must attend event for any
health care professionals who are
interested in recommending medical
cannabis but it's not limited to those
folks
anyone who is interested in learning
more about medical cannabis can and
should join us for this event head over
to kim at events dot com slash practicum
to learn more
of course if you can't make it to canmed
2022 we have a number of resources to
help you stay engaged with our community
and enjoy some world-class educational
content
you are already off to a good start
listening to the canmed coffee talk
podcast be sure to hit that subscribe
button so new episodes download to your
device automatically
second we have the canmed archive that i
mentioned earlier it's a searchable
video library of all the past kmed
presentations and panels that you can
find at kmedevents.com
while you're at canmedevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts that's the
best way to make sure you are up to date
on all the latest canmed news and
special offers
fourth we have our canmed community
facebook group which is a great place to
share and discuss news and topics
related to cannabis science the link to
that group is in the show description
and finally you can follow us on social
media we're on instagram facebook
twitter and linkedin just search for cam
at events
okay enough with the shameless
self-promotion let's talk about our
guests
leilania debois and daniel hendricks are
long-time humbled county residents who
are working to preserve the unique
culture and cannabis genetics that have
developed in the region
along with other collaborators they have
created the humboldt grace legacy
project for the purpose of working to
protect authenticate and validate legacy
cannabis genetics through collaborative
design
lele is the founder and board chair of
humboldt grace whose mission is to
empower the community in rural northwest
california through education events and
projects that promote and share the
culture of the region
lele grew up in two worlds one was with
her father on the southern california
beaches while the other was with her
mother in a homestead deep in the heart
of the emerald triangle
it was with her mother where helele
experienced much of the trauma
associated with the drug war
including raids family homelessness
death kidnapping and abuse
that experience was enough to make her
want nothing to do with cannabis as an
adult
but that all changed in 1999 when lele
sustained a life-changing spinal cord
injury
lele began to implement the alternative
healing tools her mother taught her
after western medicines failed
she now believes the cannabis plant is a
large part of her ability to thrive and
sees it as a vehicle to help create
positive change in her community that
has been oppressed by the drug war
daniel is the ceo and co-founder of
hendrix farms which holds an annual
california cannabis nursery license
providing compliant clean cannabis plant
genetics to the licensed cannabis
producers in california
daniel's journey and passion for
cannabis began at an early age in 1999
in his hometown of arcata humboldt
county california
affirmed by the scientific process
community relationships and sustainable
practices these opportunities have
flourished
with his own special focus on genetics
and breeding this unique plant aided in
his personal growth and mental health
lele daniel and i discussed humboldt
county's unique culture
the humbled residents experience with
the drug war and feelings towards
cannabis legalization
the valuable cannabis specific knowledge
that legacy growers have and why they
need to be connected with cannabis
researchers and academics to move the
industry forward
and the legacy project's mission to
preserve humboldt county's unique
cannabis genetics and create greater
access to the market for legacy growers
through auction
before we get to my conversation with
lele and daniel i'd like to thank this
episode sponsor hendrix farms
rooted in humboldt county hendricks farm
is a craft cannabis nursery that
specializes in cannabis breeding
phenotype discovery and nursery
production of elite cloned plant starts
seeds and seed starts
recognized for premium quality
scientific process and community ethics
hendrix clones can be reserved by
businesses and home growers via special
request at hendrix.farm
that's h h-e-n-d-r-x
dot f-a-r-m
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with lele de bois
and daniel hendricks
[Music]
good afternoon lele and daniel thanks
for joining us on the podcast
thank you so much ben for having us
absolutely all right so you guys are
both proud humboldt county residents
and i think most people in the industry
are familiar with humboldt or the
emerald triangle or have at least heard
of it but
for those listeners who are not familiar
with humboldt county i was wondering if
you could start by telling us what makes
that area so unique and so iconic in the
greater cannabis community and maybe
lele you can start
all right um
well i think you know you kind of have
two people that grew up here in humboldt
county
and and in my perspective and and i
imagine daniel will agree with some of
this is it's really more about our
culture than the plant
um the culture is what brought the plant
here and we utilize the plant to support
our culture
and what i think really makes us unique
is that we did build a culture kind of
different than the rest of the world um
in a lot of ways um that
that evolve around sustainability and
engaging with nature
you know i was taught to eat with the
seasons
um we grew all our own food except for
grains and things like that um we i was
raised off the grid with we built our
own solar power systems our own energy
systems water heater systems
um and it really was to bring
bring the world back to nature you know
some people call it back to the land
the back to the land movement
um you hear the word the off gridders
these days
but these communities and other
communities like it across the world
really utilize cannabis to build that
utopian
lifestyle
and to me that's what sets humble apart
we've managed to stand up against
major timber companies
and change policy around
logging
we've managed to protect our um
folks from war in one of our towns we
made it so that if you were running away
from the uh
oh what is it called daniel when you're
enlisting that you would be protected in
the city of arcata so we really were
able to take our views of freedom and
and build them here we're very engaged
with our government
which i i really appreciate
um and and it's that kind of back to the
land how do we build a better world that
created the culture here
yeah i i couldn't agree more yeah i
think that my answer would reflect the
exact same principles where it's
environmental you know land stewardship
is at the core principle you know that
hunting and fishing and farming are all
like a
core part of everyone's operational
function that organics and you know
acceptance of
race religion sexual orientation are all
principles that are like baked into the
humboldt
you know
persona you know and it ties to like the
kookiness and you know easiness of hey
we accept the plant you know we have
uh except nature we have you know people
like julia butterfly in the 90s living
in a redwood tree hundreds of feet you
know above the ground through all the
seasons
to show how much
she and the community care about you
know in the environment and it just yeah
it's this weird tapestry of like
cannabis and openness and yeah
artistic expression so yeah the culture
is what brings the plant and the people
and and if you ask almost any dinner
party i've ever been to humboldt county
somebody there has passed through
uh and experienced some of it you know
whether it's the tourism um you know
they're here for
education at humboldt state university
or or actually just wanted to see this
mythological place for real uh
yeah
and it really is mythological
um
i can't i can't remember what year or
when it was but when mount lassen last
exploded and it hit
the the um ocean it created all these
plates that created all these really
heavy mineral deposits that have a lot
of energy coming out of it and if you
look at it's called the klamath knot is
what is its mystical name
um but it impacts the water the the
environment and all sorts of things
around here that contribute to our
biodiversity
um and it's a very magical geological
anomaly a non although i can't say that
right but you know the word i mean
yeah anomaly normally there we go
all right well that's that's really cool
so
going back to cannabis specifically
though and you can correct me if i'm
wrong but sort of before before there
was really a legal market in california
humboldt county and the emerald triangle
was really sort of the
um
the epicenter for cannabis culture in
california fair to say
it felt like it
[Laughter]
i i think um where we got
in our history was during you know
during the 80s when camp came in and
where we have a unique experience i mean
there's a lot of cultures that utilize
cannabis in a lot of different ways
throughout history as we're slowly
unfolding right
but what i think is a little unique to
to humboldt and the emerald triangle is
how our culture
how we were impacted and how we
navigated the drug war you know we
really did have military helicopters
chasing us out of our gardens
and that creates
a lot of trauma but it also creates a
lot of resilience which is what i love
so much about our communities and i
think
is so valuable for the rest of the world
to understand and learn is how we do
build resilience out of hardship
absolutely i think you know humboldt
county has definitely
um it bears the scars of the drug war
for sure
and i think i don't want to speak for
you guys but i think when you know
legalization came through there was a
lot of hope that you know
the the farms and the folks in humboldt
could could prosper from that and really
take advantage and and i'm curious you
know if you could talk about what is the
current state of you know local growing
in humboldt county and
has it really lived up to the
expectations
of that
i would say that okay
so to make sure you don't answer for us
in that sense that i would say that
there was a lot of
division in their opinion of whether or
not
um the state of california or you know
any government agency was going to come
in there and fix
the medical freedom of growing the plant
um i think there was a lot of doubt that
that would work and that
specifically northern humble and
southern humboldt they were
diametrically opposed it was like
southern humble voted
down the concept of legalization in
california repeatedly and and northern
humble maybe supported it the second
time around but
you know i think there is a lot of doubt
that that that
the taxation and the state of california
would come in and and bureaucratically
fix something like the cannabis industry
so
i think that
the people might say that they all saw
this you know coming in the sense that
it invites in big business um and it
invites in
um
well heavy taxation is a problem because
it comes at every single level of
government for for a cannabis business
it's really strict from a federal level
it's really strict from a state level um
you've got any entity in in the state
can can tax you so there's a lot of
levies against it
and so people that want to do it
ecologically sensitive and
you know
make it like the smallest
footprint they can which is you know the
typical humboldt small farm uh they run
against a lot of obstacles
that are just kind of baked into the
system
so i don't think there's a ton of
surprise where we're at um and i think
that like some people are finding
success and some people are saying i
told you so
and i think daniel and i um come from
that resilience part of the trauma
of knowing that things get really bad
but when you work hard and you persevere
they get really good and that just like
nature everything evolves and cycles
um
and change is scary
you know and and it can be really scary
for a lot of people i think we have a
really long way to go before we
are
normalized meaning that we have policies
that actually support a successful and
sustainable industry
but we also have a really huge gap
between folks like daniel and myself and
other folks that have this legacy of
experience and knowledge around the
plant
and new science and technology so all
these mistakes are getting made and
that's part of what we're trying to do
with the with the with the legacy
project in humboldt grace
is how do we get those two conversations
to talk more and connect and support
each other because we know the magic
behind this plant but we haven't broken
it down into all the words and the laugh
and we need that help to build
to build a stable industry let alone a
sustainable industry
yeah and i think that's a great point
and that's probably a great segue for
you to talk about the project that you
guys are building out there to address
some of these issues with the industry
so layla i was hoping you could tell us
a bit about the legacy project and what
problems is it really hoping to address
well the humble grace foundation was
really created to help and empower and
inhale these the communities that have
been impacted like we discussed earlier
and you know nature always tells you
that you really have to start at the
core to create any solutions or the seed
and
personally what my experience around
this plant has taught me that if you
don't understand your plant it's really
hard to measure any of the other
variables and we as a community know
that our microclimates are unique
because we have this amazing redwood
curtain and so much diversity we know
that our processes are unique because
we've been working with this plant i
know someone who's been working with
this plant for six generations in this
area they have very unique understanding
and then as daniel and i also told you
the people and the culture are so unique
um and so
the legacy project is a way to start
with that seed with the genetics because
we have
volumes of genetic genetic diversity in
these communities that has not even been
touched for so many reasons one
there's very little understanding that
that's there and there's very little
data to show that's there to trust
you know these some of these genetics
are considered you know like the hope
diamond in some cases um
you know people have put a lot of their
lives into it and so how do we bring
those together
and this event and this concept and this
vision was an idea
to not only start bringing those things
out but to empower all those
small farmers that are being so impacted
and they can't get through
to
switch the market let's go small let's
grow right and let's really know how our
genetics are curating in those
microclimates because we know
a lot of us know that when when daniel
grows skunk in his backyard and i grow
skunk in my backyard they can come from
the exact same mama but they're going to
be slightly different medicines and if
we really want to keep healing people
and we really want to utilize this plant
to what it's able to do
then we have to start having the
conversation
around the genetics the processes and
the climates we also know and have seen
already that as the market grows and the
consumer becomes more mature and product
developers come become more mature the
only way to really have that product
efficacy and create that consumer
loyalty that every brand and every
company needs genetics are also a part
of that story
and we want our farmers to be growing
all those special things just like they
used to
not hurting not negatively impacting the
environment and innovating helping you
helping the industry innovate because we
do have generations of knowledge
genetics and processes around this plant
and so the legacy project
is a way for all us all of us to come
together and start solving problems but
it's also a way to educate through the
vehicle of an event
um in marketing
why these things are of value
daniel anything to add there
uh yeah you know my my motivation that's
intertwined and all that is you know the
preservation
uh
to me that's the you know one of these
great vehicles that
um
the legacy project offers is
people to come out of the shadows with
these genetics you know there's a
40-year head start
in creating these local land races and
genetics that are critical to genetic
diversity in this like amazing plant
which
you know aids in cancer research and it
aids in autism research and it aids in
wellness and self-care in a time where
you know that's a really important
factor in how we manage our daily lives
and so the diversity that exists there
if we you know look at any other crop
that's
grown in this kind of fashion genetic
diversity becomes
critical 50 years
into the crop production where you need
some diversity to
fight a pest or a pathogen or um
the stress
that the environment is going in incur
over the next 30 years as drought sets
in so
you know diversity is not just like it's
so critical and the legacy project and
the awareness around
cannabis genetics
is critical and so i looked at humboldt
county as
you know this great wealth of genetics
and and i really hope that every
buddy uh you know
is able to like access this resource
that we all have and you know we've been
privileged to for for many decades
for sure and you know
the more cultivators or folks who are
studying cannabis genetics
each time i talk to them they talk about
how
a lot of the products we see on the
shelves and dispense dispensaries and
everything the diversity is just not
there it's it's a lot of the same it's
all kind of you know high thc
sort of strains and it's all sort of the
same so
i was wondering if you could speak a bit
about some of the diversity that um that
these legacy growers may be sitting on
that um that we might
get to see
yeah it is incredible
uh because you there's
is the trend right now you know if you
make it simple is high thc you know a
certain kind of
terpene profile um
and
you know i don't want to pick on any
strands so i won't name names but you
know the most popular things that move
up the leafly chain sometimes um are the
very same that like i'm a daily all-day
smoker and i
am not affected much by cannabis
some of them give me a headache and i
know which ones do and i know which ones
don't and i know which ones are going to
keep me up and which ones are going to
help me go down and which ones before i
play basketball and you know which one
before this podcast so i think that
people get you know they're they're
missing out a lot of like the experience
and that's kind of painful to see you
know it's like well you know if you
reduce everything to a data point then
oh high thc sells faster and you know
purple sells faster
it it really locks you
you're locking yourself out of
experience and
you know cannabis isn't about the visual
and the it's about the whole experience
so
yeah the diversity is amazing and you
know what
won the emerald cup this year um
came from um canna country for the
breeders cup and it was
a low thc high fruit
bred by one of the legacy farmers it was
i happen to know cherimoya which is an
old land race which was one of the
influencing genetics in it so
the best of the best and what is
reviewed the best when you have these
competitions is not the highest thc it's
not what's available um in most
dispensaries and so if you want to have
the best experience you're going to have
to be a connoisseur and people just you
know it's going to take time and until
then we just kind of get to enjoy these
privileges firsthand us
you know up here in the sticks
i think also when you're talking about
business
is
people are going to want to be able to
get you know have a very particular
experience your brand represents
something right maybe it's a hip-hop
show maybe it's a field of flowers but
consumers are gonna have that
expectation
i like blunts and i and i got a blunt
the other day it i'm not gonna it was
named by a very feminine jeweler company
and i bought that blunt and i expected
like something that i enjoyed and it was
like skunky skunky like or more gassy
probably like a heavy og but they had
named it this very feminine name
you can get away with that right now
because it was really good weed
but
in five years from now the consumer is
going to be so much more mature
that you're not going to be able to get
away with that and so brands and product
makers
we see them calling us calling our
communities and saying
hey i really want this experience and
what we know is that this microclimate
does really high cbg this microclimate
does you know really high cbd and how
can we help curate those for you um with
what we already have here and a lot of
our breeders have been testing in ways
and working with this plant in ways that
they can tell you that before
that
plant is fully developed you know what
are those strong traits gonna be
and it can actually happen a lot quicker
than people expect these days
yeah and that's a great point if if
folks are
i mean if the market's finally going to
mature we're going to get some more
diversity on the shelves they need to
access more diverse plants and that's
where you guys can play a key role and
so maybe that's a good segue to talking
about the uh the auction that you guys
are are looking to put on um and
how how a mechanism like that can help
sort of empower these legacy growers to
protect their intellectual property and
you know maybe get some recognition and
some some compensation for all the work
they've done well daniel mentioned the
emerald cup
and folks who win the emerald cup get a
lot more opportunities you know they get
recognition there's a lot of marketing
that comes with that
that isn't on the weight of that
producer
and so it's it's kind of like that but
instead of doing a um
a contest we wanted to create more
access to the market
and you know we already have seed
auctions and things like that and and so
what we wanted to do was create a way to
promote
and educate on more complex markets than
just selling your seeds or your plants
which are licensing agreements you know
a cosmetic company could want a certain
genetic for just their skin care and
another company could want the same one
for their drink line well that's a
diverse market for a breeder those are
two different licensing agreements that
they could create
and we feel there's a lot of power for
these small communities around those
kind of that kind of market
keeps everybody small keeps everybody
innovative and curating around the plant
um and then then the the big can go
outside um and so we really wanted
daniel and i have been in these
conversations around these particular
biz um this kind of licensing business
for i don't know about four or five
years
and it just always seemed like a really
good way to empower the high quality
small farmer which is really what our
culture was created around and yet also
educate the market on the value of the
genetic diversity
um and so an auction an event i've i
like throwing hype events i like
educating through those kind of
platforms
um and
we just saw it as an opportunity
um we started with just saying hey who
wants to come
and now we're at a place where we have
an amazing blockchain company called
canopyright that has created a platform
that
all breeders can
engage in for free
it doesn't cost unless you start
invoicing it through the through the
metric system and what that does is that
allows anybody to create a digital
archive of ownership so if their
genetics get out into the market without
their knowledge they have the first step
to saying this is mine
not yours and we really couldn't ask
people to come out of the you know start
throwing their stuff out in the market
and licensing agreements unless they
could protect it
uh then we wanted you know a lot of
people like to say oh we're the best in
in this industry is full of
smoke screens and we want to be
authentic in what we do and so we really
wanted to find a way to authenticate
and that's why we chose we were we were
given the opportunity to use the pre-96
skunk one
as a beta test and and the reason we
chose that is because it does have so
much controversy and notoriety
we just wanted something that we could
build
authentication and validate and because
there's so
so much controversy it's not going to be
easy
and so that means anything that follows
um it will be much easier so this is
it's our beta to help protect
help authenticate and help validate and
and the auction is really an event as a
tool to make it exciting and bring it
all together
yeah skunk is a lightning rod for a
controversy i like that component of it
and
i think like last week you know they're
circulating and calling each other out
on instagram which is just like a great
wwf match sometimes um if you're
watching uh and
they're they're you know signaling
people and and
what is it what is it about skunk that
that is so controversial
i it it is it gets people's attention
you know some of my favorite accounts
are responding to each other and have
opposite views and
yeah so i i think the skunk is is this
in the same sense mythological where
you're never going to get back
to the original skunk you just can't
because
there's no way to prove it anyway so i
think that building all of these
different skunk variations that are out
here and
tying them together and and tying it for
what reasons is really interesting
um and the skunk's really interesting
from a scientific perspective it's
scientifically
you know has something happening right
now where they're tying the thiol which
is like a unique component
constituents that haven't been tested
for traditionally in cannabis that you
know a humboldt state
professor at one point was the first to
discover this compound in actual skunks
so these different thio variations you
know can indicate different um skunk
species and in the first tests that were
you know being published
this
year uh
are kind of supporting that uh
that there's associations here with
these thiols and the smell of skunk so
it's really exciting um
just from all angles and so you you
layer dna and you layer cannabinoids and
you layer
you know popular opinion it's
irresistible
it's really fun i get to go meet an 84
year old archaeologist after this call
who was a part of a group that took a
pack of skunk seeds that were brought
back by a carrot woman who's still alive
she was also in her 80s and they hid it
in a cave
um and and we're going to go talk to see
if maybe he wants to go pull him out of
the cave now those skunk seeds pre-exist
these other skunk seeds right i mean
they're very old
so what what's fun about it is because
of all the controversy it's bringing up
more information more stories right it's
not about is this
mel frank pre whatever it's about how do
we honor those legacies that brought it
before us and and how do we protect
those and keep those that move forward
on her because
many more genetics are going to be
created we all
living up here for as long we all know
how much we like to make new fun things
and with the science people are going to
really be able to hone in on that more
um and we just wanna show
that it's real
it's authentic
and that it's worth the value that we
we're gonna our validators are gonna say
it is
absolutely
yo and i wanted to come back to
something you touched on before lele
when you were we were talking about
sort of all the
generational knowledge that's been
accumulated um in humboldt and the
emerald triangle over the years
and sort of marrying that with sort of
the the new wave of research and you
know in science and
for me i get excited at that because you
know at canmed that's that's really what
we're trying to do is trying to bring
people from different parts of the
industry together to sort of collaborate
and sort of move the industry forward
and typically it's been sort of
having the healthcare providers talk
with the cultivators to talk about you
know the cannabinoids that they're
interested in to come maybe inspire the
cultivators to
to grow something new but i think
there's another component too right
where it's the legacy growers talking
with um you know the academics to
where there might be examples of things
where
i mean you guys know just from
experience that you know when the plant
looks a certain way or it's a certain
point in its development you do x
but you might not understand really why
that is the case and if we if we can
work together we can maybe determine
why that is and then even
optimize from there so that's that's
really exciting
it it it is and it goes beyond just the
science of the plant it goes into just
practical applications whether it be
you're giving a lecture and you talk to
someone in the legacy and they can give
you a perspective that you never had
before you know it's like it's like
i look at it as we are a region of
einsteins around this plant that have so
much experience that everyone who's
engaging should want an einstein is a
part of that conversation i've i am i
i'm trained i was trained as a nurse
before my spinal cord injury so i have a
little science background but not you
know heavy
yet i've been a part of an an artif two
artificial intelligence projects
just because they wanted that
understanding of the plant
um and and i've been a part i i i helped
influence doctor one of dr mackey's
talks on
extraction just through a conversation
that he felt really impacted that and i
think
we got to bring those two together to
really make this industry as
transformative as as it can
yeah and to that point the fact that you
that there is so much
generational knowledge and experience up
there in in humboldt in the emerald
triangle how
has there been any recruiters that have
come up there and tried to you know hire
people to go work for you know a big
corporate grow or something like that
and i mean would that even be something
that the folks up there would be
interested in
yeah we i have friends that are all over
the country right now helping people
develop their growth we we're
individuals um i don't ever like to tell
someone how to to live their life really
you know
um and personally i feel like we have to
integrate to educate so i'm really
supportive of legacy operators going and
working for larger companies or
different companies to help them not
just learn about the plant but learn
about the values of our culture so
they'll carry it through
but traditionally we are definitely a
nimby society
we we definitely have shut people out um
but i think as this market evolves and
as our community transitions uh people
are seeing that those are real
opportunities for them as well um and so
i hope we do have more people come up
here recruiting and looking for support
from from these areas
yeah you see it failing on the other end
you see it failing definitely in places
that aren't uh traditionally cannabis
cultivation locations but maybe
have experience in agriculture
in california and seeing them bring in
like i said we don't name names but
big managers from other companies that
are from the produce industry uh and are
from the cut flower industry and
seeing what doesn't convert and how that
uh without that cannabis experience that
it's definitely a recipe for failure so
you're definitely seeing people come you
know
after kind of making some of the worst
mistakes and that they should save
themselves probably a lot of trouble um
and start by integrating the the
you know
the right kind of legacy cannabis
operator uh somebody with you know 20
years of experience uh that still has
energy um
you know we've talked about how
genetically diverse this plant is
and that genetic diversity means how it
responds to its environment its food and
everything
and when you don't have someone that
understands those subtleties in your
garden it it it can
it can be a huge loss when you have
someone that understands those
subtleties helping you with that garden
or product making or whatever that is
you end up being ahead of the market in
that because there's so many shortcuts
and i don't mean regulatory shortcuts
it's really just understanding of
knowing how to navigate with the plant
and work with the plant that your
company will save
all right i do want to be mindful of
your time here um so before i let you go
um i want to give you an opportunity to
share more information about the legacy
project where can people learn more
about it and stay up to date with
everything you guys are doing
well you can go look at our website
www.humboldtgrace
backslash legacy dash project
and we meet every friday we're going to
be meeting every other friday now is a
public meeting because we're breaking
out into working groups but really
anybody who's interested or
sees value for themselves and wishes to
bring value
is welcome to come
we're almost we're right now in the
process of getting ready to really
launch the white paper around the whole
vision
and that will happen by march
but until then anyone can reach out they
can find us at the website
www.humboltgrace.org
and daniel why don't you let folks know
where they can find you because he he's
he's he's the home of the skunk right
now
oh
yeah
hendrix.farm uh we we spell it uniquely
with uh out the so many vowels
h-e-n-d-r-x dot farm
f-a-r-m uh
yeah we'd love to chat about genetics or
anyone have any questions you know we go
on and on give us a call
excellent well i can't wait to see you
guys out in canmed
uh in may i think it's it's going to be
a great event and excited to have you
guys out there and we'll talk about
genetics out there
yeah looking forward to it
[Music]
thanks i hope you enjoyed my
conversation with lele dubois and daniel
hendricks
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor hendrix farms
our next episode will drop march 2nd
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out the
canmed archive and join the canmed
community facebook group to stay
connected with us
of course you can also stay in touch
with us on social media on facebook
instagram linkedin and twitter just
search for cam at events
sign up for email alerts on cam at
events.com to stay up to date with all
the latest news and please be sure to
rate review and subscribe on your
favorite podcast app doing so helps us
reach more listeners
i do sincerely hope to see all of you
out in pasadena this spring but until
then stay safe stay healthy and please
join us for the next canbed coffee talk
[Music]
you