[Music]
welcome to the K Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I am the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on the canmed
summit well I hope You' had the chance
to check out the updated canmed
events.com to see a preview of our new
location for the Kim 25 Summit which
will take place June 17th through 20th
at the Windham Resort in Rio Grande
Puerto Rico we will be adding more
details to the site in the coming weeks
and months so be sure to sign up for
email alerts so you can get all of those
announcements
we have also added all the cammed 24
presentation videos to our cammed
archive so be sure to check those out as
well my guest today is Dr Harold Han
Harold is Chief science officer and
co-founder of vertosa and a Pioneer in
water compatible cannabinoid ingredients
for infused
products Harold designed the industrial
leading cannabis emulsions that are
widely applied in the Cannabis beverage
Brands he also holds 16 patents in
Emulsion applications and prior to
founding ferosa he had led a team that
developed the emulsification oil for Bor
Rad's digital droplet PCR
system Harold also publishes a regular
series explaining the science of
cannabis for product makers under the
name the happy chemist a nickname you'll
understand after you watch this
interview one of his recent articles
describes the different factors that
contribute to cannabis beverage potency
loss which is a challenge for beverage
brands in fact in regulated markets it's
common to see a 10 to 15% variation in
potency compared to label claims in
unregulated hemp derive beverages it can
be even
higher during our conversation we
discuss the difference between cannabis
bever bages and alcoholic beverages what
happens when canabo
oxidize how to put THC into water-based
products using physical and chemical
processes how every aspect of the supply
chain can lead to potency loss in
cannabis
beverages which beverage ingredients
accelerate potency loss how packaging
conditions can affect scalping and
oxidation rates and more before before
we get to my conversation with Harold
I'd like to thank this episode sponsor
vertosa vertosa creates industry-leading
active ingredients for infused product
makers their patent pending Nano and
micro emulsions are carefully designed
for the specific needs of each customer
and their pre-sp acous Solutions Empower
them to create incredibly homogeneous
and stable products while maximizing
bioavailability Clarity and taste learn
more at versa.com
okay without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr Harold
[Music]
h good morning Harold thanks so much for
join joining us on the podcast good
morning Ben thank you for having me well
I'm excited to talk with you today about
cannabis beverages it's one of the
fastest growing segments in the canvas
Market but it's not without its
challenges um and Regulators consumers
will often compare cannabis beverages to
alcohol so I guess my first question to
you is is that a fair comparison and how
are they
different that's a very good question
because um alcohol is what consumer and
regular know for hundreds of years which
is a beverage that is adult use that can
change your mindset that can be
impairing uh impairing you right and
from those aspects Canabis beverage are
similar to alcohol but canis beverage
maybe we can just single say uh TC
beverages right because CBD beverages
have different U impairment issues so if
you compare TC beverages with alcohol
you know the main comparison the main
difference are the active compounds so
for one is ethanol right alcohol one is
THC and ethanol is water soluble right
TC is oil soluble so that is the
fundamental difference between the two
actives so what actually leads from that
is when ethanol is water soluble it's
actually easier to be incorporated into
all kinds of different beverages right
it's easy to dilute and it doesn't the
fundamental features of alcohol is it
doesn't sculp meaning it doesn't attach
to the K liners or any packaging right
and it doesn't um it doesn't oxidize so
you can say you can save a liquor for
200 years you reopen that and still have
the same content of the liquor right but
on the other hand THC is very easy to be
oxidized right and the oxidation rate is
is like a constant so you have to work
around it but also THC because of the
hydrophobicity you have to have
different technology to get the THC into
the Beverages and through by doing that
due to this hydrophobicity the THC will
tend to stck to different packagings or
can be um sensitive to heat sensitive to
other ingredients right so that's where
the cous beverage as a whole uh subject
to you know more potency loss issues
compared to aloh
just right so you so you mentioned
oxidation so what happens when these
cannaboids oxidize like
what yeah well fundamentally from the
surface you lose potency right that's
from the COA you see that okay potency
dropped but deeper down into what what
really happened to the conoids you know
I think more research are needed here um
for example we know TC the oxid
oxidizing end results is CBN but usually
we don't see a onetoone conversion right
uh so so you you lose one molecule of
THC usually you don't see a formation of
one molecule of CBN so that indicates
some other molecules are formed along
this path right so what are those
molecules I think you know this is where
I strongly advocate for more fing and
research uh especially as a cannabis
beverage as a whole category
research on that category now is this
oxidation a challenge for other forms of
cannabis products Beyond
beverages I I believe so you know we
have heard you know the the joints the
flowers they are oxidized right the
turpins get lost over over time over the
shelf life uh but I think beverage is
unique form factor because um for
example our technology we um drive down
the droplet size right to the nanometer
size from 200 nanometers to a th000
nanometers so that formation give a um
much larger surface area right so um
which is great for the onset purpose so
consumer can feel the effect much
quicker but on the other hand um those
enlarged surface area will have more
oxygen attacking to the conoids so the
oxidation rate between a joint to a
beverages could be different so that's
that's why I I advocate you know the
research should be focusing on its own
category right I I I I would really hope
you know more University and researchers
open are open to study canis beverages
great no and you touched on a great
point there and I'm hoping that you can
explain so so we we talked about how
canabo they are hydrophobic and so to
try to put them into a beverage is
challenging right so what is that
technology and I know you mentioned em
Emulsion and everything so maybe you
know let's let's get basic with it like
how are these products
made yes so
um let's talk about how to put TC into
water-based product right because TC is
oil soluble so there are in my opinion
there are two main School of thoughts
one is chemical modification one is
physical modification so chemical
modification is you change the structure
of T's a chemical structure you you add
some functional groups to make it water
soluble to make t as a sugar or salt um
it has its own challenges of this path
because you are creating a pro drug a
new molecule right and the you need to
study the uh safety and efficacy of the
new molecule another route is the
physical route which is the main
application for most of the beverage now
the physical route is even though is THC
is not water soluble but you change the
form factor of the THC uh for for us for
example we use Nano emotion as a um
subcategory of the emotion category the
emotion can be divided into Nano emotion
and micro emotion the two parts right so
we are the non emotion um they are not
defined by the size actually they are
defined by the energy level so by how
you produce uh the emotion but either
way the end result is
the emotion process make the TC dist
into billions of smaller droplets and
they code each droplet with a layer of
suant
emulsifiers uh depending on the osif
fire origin it can be synthetic it can
be natural derived it can be organic
derived uh at vertosa we only use
organic derived osier which are safe and
widely available uh to to Consumers so
um yeah that's the basic gist so you
break the distillate or the the
molecules into smaller fragments and
then coat it with a more water soluble
um compound or um yes that makes sense
and then then mix it in and it kind of
stays in suspension and is homogeneous
right so we essentially we change how TC
exists from a big molec from a big
aggregation of thislet into smaller
Aggregates of droplets and which is are
coated by a layer of surfectants and
surfectants make that dropless would
compatible so this dropless can flow
inside the liquid uh beverages
freely excellent all right so that's
probably a good segue into talking about
so you recently wrote an article on
LinkedIn um explaining some of the
challenges for this potency loss and you
kind of kicked it off saying that you
did a a poll of your followers to asking
what they think is the most important
factor in you know preventing potency
loss and it seemed like most people
thought it was sort of this Emulsion
technology or the infusion technology
which is what you were describing um so
first of all do you agree with that
assessment and um why do you think
people think that that is the most
important um um I have seen issues uh of
the downstream P issues happening and
the root cause could be the emotion
right I have seen that but I also have
seen um many other areas along the
supply chain of making the cans
beverages when any of the sector has
issues or problems the accumulated
effect is contributing to the end
results which is opponency loss so um
yes the infusion tag is very important
because because it's complex right
because the infusion tag itself needs to
be stable right uh and then when you put
that infusion Tech the emotion or
whatever technology into the B es it
needs to be stable in a beverage so it
the self stability and the beverage
stability are two aspects right so
sometimes it's um it's hard to assume
you have a stable Emotion by itself and
you're going to have a stable product no
we have seen this U failure time and
time again um and you have to really
assess like the two lanes right U make
sure you have a stable emotion but also
this is the most interesting part part
and complex part because emotion could
be you know two to three formulas or
four formulas this could be a thousand
skewes right they are having different
PHS they have different ingredients heat
stability packaging so it's it's really
the wild part of expanding the emotion
into the finished product so that's
where vertosa actually spend a lot of
time understanding our clients uh from
the industry okay what kind of um
beverage for formulation they are what
kind of packaging Co manufacturers a
testing lab so I know you're going to
dive into it but you know that's
essentially the whole supply chain that
could potentially impact the pocy yeah
no and you're right we're GNA get into
kind of the different parts of the
supply chain but before I we get on to
that um I wanted to ask so when we're
talking about losing potency how much
are we talking about here like um are
there is there sort of a standard rate
of potency
loss um
if you ask me the standards you
know for beverages there are regulated
beverages by States and there are hand
beverages so if you if you ask by um uh
state by state there is a 10 to 15%
variation from the label claim right but
if you ask me about hand beverages so
far there is U no strict regulation yet
right so which the industry I know
they're advocating for um better
regulation better standards um so
um yeah the be hand beverages could have
you know a huge loss over the shelf life
right the shelf life they Brands claimed
and some some Brands may have um you
know not as much lost over the shelf
life some Brands may have a huge loss so
we see this um huge difference and we
see there's um big need for the industry
to better ourself because consumer love
this product and consumer need this
product and if we don't do a good job to
you if we lose the trust of consumers
and they say okay all those hand
beverages are finicky and they don't
give me enough minrs on the claim I
think that's detrimental to the whole
thing so that's where verosa as a it try
we try to lead the conversation and
educate our partners and clients hey you
need to pay attention to all the details
that leads to pocy loss you can't just
assume you had a good emotion you have a
good co manufacturer then everything's
fine right so that's where we want try
we want to try to uh educate people yeah
and I have to imagine with so many
different brands out there and so many
different products um using so many
different technologies that without sort
of that standardization like you're
right I mean some consumers might um
experience a potency loss with one brand
and sort of apply that to everyone else
where that's not really the case right
right I I feel the history will we're
early right it's it's 2024 we're early
in this um canvas beverage sector and
more research are needed more regulation
are needed right so I I'm strongly um
advocate for for those to
happen all right all right so let's
let's dive into the the supply chain
here so maybe we'll we'll start with um
can you tell us what are sort of the the
seven parts of the canvas beverage
supply chain yeah sounds like a book
title uh so uh it starts with from the
Cannabis input right THC CBD CBN so
input and then goes next step is the
infusion tag right either emotion or
powder or some other infusion technology
and then the infusion technology will go
into a formulation that's where the
beverage base is formulated the flavors
the all the other U ingredients you put
emotion to the beverage base and then
you have to select the packaging right
can glass PS and then you figure all
that out you give all this formula to
the co manufacturer who produce the
beverages for you right and after you
produce it you send to the lab right and
the lab will test for the potency and
then the final finished product will go
into distribution or retail so those are
the main seven steps for the supply
chain excellent all right so let's start
at the beginning with cannabinoid input
how can that stage sort of affect
potency loss down at the end yeah so
um the main thing is the
um how easy is the canids be oxidized um
we know um from our early data we have
seen THC and
thcv as the
most the easiest to be oxidized and and
the the quick
right um well CBD and CBG are following
right they are slower but they still
oxidized and CBC and CBN are behind that
right the as the third category they are
um much slower but they do even though
CBN you know is kind of stable in on
Theory but uh from our early um
preliminary study you know we have seen
CBN get lost in beverage too so
again we still need answers of what it
becomes to right um over time what does
the ox oxidation do to the conoids this
is where I hope more research are needed
right so so THC is one of the fastest to
oxidize that's that's um inconvenient
huh inconvenient yes yes okay so
infusion Tech is the next phase and I
think we sort of already touched on that
unless you think that there's more to
talk about about how that can sort of
affect the potency loss here um yeah um
I mean infusion Tech like I said
it's it's it's a very um um dual concept
people regard infusion Tech as simple
right because producing emotions are
relatively straightforward but actually
it's complex um you know it's it's
especially when you put that ingredients
into the products right that complexity
generates through this
process great
okay so now beverage
formulation um can you talk about some
some of the different components that
are going into Beverages and how how
they present different
challenges yeah well beverage usually
has over 90% water that's that's the
main thing right but then the rest 5 to
10% you have um flavors right you have
functions uh functional groups like uh
uh TC or U vitamins or electrolytes
right um B you know polyphenols stuff
like that and then you have a uh
supporting ingredients like
preservatives uh pH modulators so
essentially those are in my opinion the
three main
things right and so how can they sort of
affect how your how your emotion works
or how um how potency L um so far I
think verto has been infusing over a
thousand skews on the market market and
we have been collecting data of of the
Thousand SKS what's their density um pH
bricks um color you know taste was the
profile um and um um we have seen that
certain brands certain clients they have
the same packaging same emotion uh same
po manufacturer but they have different
flavors and strange enough just that
flavor difference
will cause a potency difference right
especially in the beginning of the
dosing or long-term shelf life and again
this is where
um this is where I think the industry
need mainstream knowledge and mainstream
power because we as verosa we are small
right and and the whole industry is
small we we all try to figure this out
but the complex of the base really need
beverage experts to help us understand
why certain ingredients you know on
downt the mechanism is impacting the
pocy loss right we so I think we have to
admit we see some um causation a cause B
but we don't know why this happened
right so so but my goal is to create a a
naughty list of ingredients uh naughty
list like if you uh currently using our
current infusion Tech of THC um maybe
try to avoid those five or six
ingredients in your beverages until we
figure out a technology can be
compatible with those ingredients so
that's that's where we are um as verosa
um but I think one of the thing I'm
proud of is um dollar it's a big German
company in the beverage ingredient space
and verosa dollar have some uh research
collaboration uh on in this topic and uh
you know we are really excited about
bringing bringing you know mainstream
players who have years of you know
Decades of experience on formulation to
help us interesting so a naughty list of
ingredients interesting naughty list yes
uh do you have any I know you said
you're working on it but do are there
any that that you know of yet or still
doing the research there
um couple things I can mention um
electrolytes could be potentially
a problem um polyphenol sometimes could
be a problem um some flavors um but
those flavors we still we're still
studying right but those are the two you
know top of proteins for example could
cause problem um yeah so I guess as a
consumer if I if we're looking at
Beverages and potentially to make a
purchase are there certain ones that you
know should be avoided or maybe are more
prone to maybe a potency loss and or
ones that are kind of more more
stable I
think I don't know the answer because
um I I would love to know more of the
consumer feedbacks right uh I I think
we're getting there but I I don't think
the whole industry has a lot of consumer
feedback you know how does Consumer like
the flavor how does they like how do
they like each Brands what is their um
determining factor is the flavor is the
effect yeah you know is the onset or or
something else or the packaging so um
yeah I I would love to see more data
from consumers and then then I can tell
you how we can educate them but now I I
feel like what is encouraging is
consumer now given the trial from the h
beverages going to the mainstream they
seem to like it they seem to be uh
designing uh Desiring for it because
they want to find something to replace
alcohol so this is fitting right into
that category so that's that's a very
encouraging no absolutely and I could
say personally I've I've seen more
people sort of moving towards cannabis
beverages um to replace alcohol and uh I
have to say flavor is is certainly one
of the biggest considerations because
there's some out there that don't taste
that great right right and flavor is the
U first layer of sensory right um
because you buy the canvas beverage for
effect effect and F is the first layer
of effect does this generate a a um a
joyful experience for you yeah EXA I
mean and if we're looking at alcohol too
I mean that's where where a lot of
people base their decisions on alcohol
as well you know do you like red or
white wine or you know it's the same
ethanol right exactly yeah you're not
just drinking straight ethanol that's
for sure okay so we talked about
beverage form formulation um oh actually
no one thing I before we move on from
that um I noticed in the in the write up
that you were talking about scalping
rates what is that and well what is that
right scalping is a term used in the
beverage industry for a long time it is
it describes the process of active
ingredients in the beverages attaching
to the packaging because the packaging
material could be hydrophobic right it
lacks oil so when you have a oil like uh
ingredients it may stck to the liner
right and then lose its potency in a
liquid so that that process called
scaling okay well that's a good segue
because we're going to talk about
packaging next so yeah so maybe talk
about some of the different liner types
that are available and how they can sort
of affect that those scalping rates
great um funny enough I just published a
article last Friday talking about
calendar types and uh yeah the con liner
is kind of a a big issue for the whole
industry um and we have six years ago in
California nobody's using C everybody's
using glass because all the infusion
technology are not stable in a can and I
think this is the first issue verosa
have helped come the industry solved um
we we were working with ball PPG all the
Big King companies and lender companies
with has all their generations of liners
and we summarized okay and we improve
our formula we summarized okay what
formula Works in what liner and so today
I think we can confidently make a 12
months stable beverages with a good
emotion in a good liner a good
combination but at the same time when
the H beverages brands are uh going to
the market in the very uh fast speed
right they they get what they can get
right which is understandable as a
market um but sometimes that leads to a
NE lack of the quality of the liners so
we have seen issues that clients U
picked the wrong liners and the wrong
liners will lead to much higher pocy
scoping right um and those are the
continuous issues verosa is is wanting
to educate our clients great so now did
I hear correctly that this isn't so much
an issue issue with
glass yes you're right and so what are
some of the advantages of using cans
versus glass I mean if you don't have
the issue with glass why don't we see
more Brands using glass right I think
it's the um the heaviness of the
logistic shipping and the recyclability
right and uh I think those sort of too
un
cost great okay so in addition to
scalping one of the other things that
you mentioned was um oxy oxygen Ingress
and kind of leading to that oxidation so
how how is that a factor interesting
yeah so like I said oxygen is kind of
the big enemy for cannabis
beverages actually
um I I advocate for our industry to use
beer as a benchmark because when you
make a beer if you have high oxygen the
flavor will change dramatically right in
a very short time
um so beer industry has perfected their
practice on lower the do dissolve oxygen
during the production right so uh that's
why what we Advocate our co-packer of
the canas beverage is to follow the
practice of beer so imagine you have a
um packaging that has low oxygen to
start with right but if the packaging
somehow allows oxygen to come in from
its seal or from the the body or from
anywhere then then it doesn't matter you
have a low do to start dissolve oxygen
will continue to climb up and then the
ainise will be continuously to be uh
oxidized right so that's where we we we
see this potential issue especially from
pet bottles because pet the whole bottle
will allow oxygen come in constantly but
not only pet some glass bottles with u
you know Chell resistant cap right or
even some Can U with a
a special lits right May potentially
Ingress oxygen so we are having some
resarch collaboration with a lab right
now uh to to further look into this this
is um this seems to be a easy concept to
understand but actually it's very
complex to test because you have to
remove the oxygen you have to control
the environment so it's this is a nearly
a year process right now with the with
our testing part
so stay tuned for this data wow okay so
yeah no and that's an interesting point
because I mean at least with the
Cannabis beverages I've used yeah it's
not your standard kind of um lid that
you would see on a can of Coke or a beer
or something like that it's sort of that
childproof tamperproof um tab so that
can actually um lead to more oxygen
Ingress you're saying potentially
potentially yeah
yeah okay interesting okay um so we
talked about pack so just kind of I
guess to sum up packaging sounds like
there's there's two main things that
you're trying to prevent here and that's
the scalping of you know sort of the
molecules attaching to the liner of the
actual packaging so you're it's not
actually getting to the consumer when
they consume it and it's this oxidation
right those are the two sort of main
problems you're trying to solve for yes
and to summarize it one is physical one
is
chemical interesting perfect all right
so now let's talk about beverage
manufacturer um how I I can imagine a
number of different ways that that can
introduce some problems right um so uh
interestingly there's a joke that verosa
we don't make beverages right but we
work with a lot of Co manufacturers so
we're not golfers but we're good caddies
we have seen golfers make mistakes here
and there so to level up the whole
industry veros actually we drafted a um
cannabis beverage manufacturing handbook
so this in this handbook is you know 100
pages long handbook we include every
elements of from weighing the
ingredients introducing the ingredients
um control the dissolve oxygen how to
test tank how to package um yeah it's a
lot right because the main issue I see
is producing beverage is easy right a
lot of uh companies can can make that
but canas beverage is different it's a
hybrid between regular Beverages and the
pharmaceutical layer because you have to
guarantee each can get 10 five
milligrams right so um and previously
the um beverage command their main
belief is okay I drop this bag of
ingredients into the tank it should be
there it's homogeneous right it should
be there uh for example if I make a
probiotic drink
like I claim 10 grams of fiber per can
right on the label nobody's measured
that 10 and Ure you each can get 10
grams of fiber eight grams of 12 grams
consumer okay with it um but canvas is
different so I think the fundamentally
uh this concept needs to change in the
operator's head they are making a
pharmaceutical like beverages right so
that you know that leads to the TC
is um is easy to be um Changed by
oxidation by sculping um and the
weighing right and the residue of the
emotion so all the details could
potentially lead to a filled product so
that's where the handbook really
emphasize on what you should pay
attention to and U changing the concept
it's not regular beverages is is a
medicine yeah no and and you're right it
it introduces a number of different
variables because you could you could
develop a great product um but then you
have to turn it over to the manufacturer
to actually you know produce it at scale
so if they're not paying attention to
those details it's not going to be the
same quality that you started with right
right yes I I I do believe this whole
industry need standardization and one of
one of the main part is the standardized
operation in producing the beverages
right no and then so you touched on
something um homogeneity which I know
kind of dovetails into our next topic of
of the testing of the actual product
right and so
um talk about that how how can that lead
to an issue with potency loss um the
actual testing the labeling and then
comparing it to what's actually um in in
the can at the end of the day right um I
think the testing
lab may have three categories of of of
issues right the first category is
inherent because nationalwide we don't
have a
standardized um standard material right
so you buy different standard materials
they can be just off by Purity right
from batch to batch even so so that's
inherent another issue is um Integrity
of the lab right so um some Labs give
you a inflate potency some lab will um
Pander to your potency claim on the
label and they know you want five
milligram okay I I give you 4.8 plus
that right so I I have I have heard that
happening in multiple Labs so that's
Integrity issue and another issue is the
technology issue is the um you know when
you infuse over thousand skews you start
to find certain flavors or ingredients
in the beverage may need a special
extraction method because um we're still
we we have seen the early sign of this
we're still uh uh you
know completing our um observation here
but we have observed certain ingredients
like cream or fat in the beverages will
hold on to the TC not letting go right
so you need a you need to design a new
method a stronger method to extract the
TC from the beverages so you see that
that actually is
bottom line
is maybe the ass skilles do not need one
single method maybe you have to develop
three or four methods to really see okay
what ingredients will follow what
intraction method right now do you do
any of that testing in House at at
bertosa or do you use third party Labs
we use third party Labs
um the main reason is we understand how
finicky the data could be and even from
Lab to lab they have variations right so
we um so that's why we trust UNESCO uh
in San Francisco they are a DA FDA
certified lab with 80 years of history
of running food samples and um so that
is at least our anchor of of accuracy
and consistency we often use anasco to
compare to other labs um but there are
great Labs out there like infinite
chemical like cambian labs in Michigan
again so there are good Labs over there
act Labs um but you know smeers I'm just
mhing a few that we we we work with they
they are great um but there are many
many Labs that just you know they're
smaller they're trying to figure out the
supply chain and I don't blame them it's
it's a hard business yeah running a lab
is hard it's it's a lot of details a lot
of invest on on the dollars yeah a lot
of training is hard yeah no um we feel
it too we work with a lot of testing
labs and you know definitely feel the
challenges that they face and yeah and
you bring up one of one that's
constantly coming up is that you know
cannabis is being infused into all
different things these days from
beverages to Edibles to candies to
topicals and to sort of develop methods
to reliably um deal with all of those
different uh matrices is
hard exactly yeah you you didn't mention
condiments I think you're going to be a
great a good sector a fun sector
condiments yeah infused ketchup yes hot
sauce hot oh yeah hot sauce would be
nice all right great so we're at the end
of the supply chain here distribution um
so I imagine you know storage conditions
things like that could really um cause
issues with potency right um especially
tied to the uh relation of oxidation and
oxidation will happen at higher
temperature so and we know know that
with the uh climate change you know the
in the truck when the truck going into
Florida or Texas it's going to be hot in
in a truck if it's is not specially made
for cold chain supply so how how do the
impact
for a beer or or liquor it may be
different compared to a TC because of
the oxidation issue wow so temperature
is really an issue what what temperature
is sort of the ideal range for these
beverages um
I say don't go o do not go over 35 to 40
degrees
C right so that's that's kind of my
suggestion because the reason is Canada
and Michigan The Regulators use 40 C as
they're accelerating testing condition
so you don't want to store your
beverages in accelerated conditions for
research studies right so try to avoid
um try to yeah get lower to 40 degrees
right right all right all right so we
did it we got through got through the
supply chain um that was great um all
right so winding down here um Harold
tell us a little bit more about vertosa
um what you guys are working on and um
how people can learn more great um so
verosa has been in a business for six
years uh we just had our sixth
anniversary party last week uh in our
head headquarter in Berkeley California
thank you and uh we are fortunate uh
to have this business um you know
oftentimes we ask we ask ourself is this
real right you know selling a water
compatible Canino as a business you know
is is unfadable six years ago and seeing
but but also seeing the um the fruit
that we build with our clients and
partners through the supply chain and
seeing the impact of just Pence beverage
to everybody every every consumer in
America and uh it is it's a it's a
strong belief for us to experience this
this journey um but there's a lot to do
and our focus is continue perfecting our
infusion tech there are still a lot to
learn right we are leading the industry
but I have to admit we still have a lot
to answer and U in order to find the
answers I don't think we can go along I
think we should collaborate we should
find more collaboration we should
support more researchers even
competitors you know among this this
industry we need to learn from each
other we need to encourage each other
and Propel the industry I don't think
any company can work in in Silo uh to
have okay I I I own this or something so
that's my advocate for okay more
researchers more collaboration
throughout the industry no and that's
perfect I mean that aligns perfectly
with what we're trying to do with canmed
is to try to bring together all the top
Minds on cultivation medicine um and
science of course um to bring them
together to learn from each other so
that we can push this thing forward
because uh we agree um it's going to
take all of us working together to to
see this thing forward um competitors
doesn't matter um we can all learn from
each other um so maybe one last question
I want to ask you from a consumer
standpoint um if you're looking for
cannabis beverages are there certain
things that you should be looking for to
sort of evaluate maybe higher quality
versus uh lower quality or you know
maybe not so much quality but you know
about the things that we talked about
here are there sort of indicators that
we could look for to be like okay this
is a this is a good
choice okay so if you talk about uh if
you evaluating a uh alcohol Brands beer
or letx say beer right compared to low
those TC beverages um beer usually is
flavor and packaging right how how do
how does it taste um for cannabis
beverage we discussed sensory of flavor
is the still the first you know category
of of of
judgment but I think I want to uh
Advocate to the Consumers canid Beverage
has this effect effect right the E
effect actually is what you're paying
for it's not you're not paying for a
good tasting beverages you can buy that
from Costco very cheaply right right but
you are paying for a effect that alcohol
doesn't give you so I think the consumer
needs to pay more attention to um after
I drink this pay attention to how you
feel right what is the onset you know uh
initially when can you feel something
and after you feel something how is that
time point to to the peak I call it the
ramp right how does the r feel like is
that a appearent or some sometimes you
lose the rep sometimes you feel
something but it's going out right you
feel something it's going out so is the
rep clear and then when did you Peck
right um and then how long the peak last
and when did you wear off I think um I
think it's a and it's fun to do this
it's not a it's fun to collect and uh
record and then you can compare between
different skews between different
products how does the product make you
feel I think it's more important than
how does the product taste like
excellent all right Harold thanks again
for taking the time um I'd love to put
some links in the show description to
some of the resources that you mentioned
especially that handbook that sounds
fantastic um thanks again for doing it
and hope to see you down in Puerto Rico
next year for can Puerto Rico great I
look forward to it all right
[Music]
a