[Music]
what is your process for for adding new
products that like new cannabinoids into
your
portfolio yeah um we got a big pipeline
you know the wish list is Big um um we
have prototypes and so you know things
that I find uh interesting based on
pre-clinical literature based on what
people are telling me we usually make a
prototype and share it around with the
staff and with myself and some of our
colleagues and see what people think you
know a good example of this is our I
think it's our newest product still it's
a a combination of cbda and cbga so cbga
like who knows anything about cbga you
look in the peer rreview literature
there's so little on it um you know a
few few more hits just this past year
but it's is it is it similar to CBG
which we also don't know that much about
but we know more is it different than
CVG you know a lot of unknowns there but
there was this um you know preclinical
study that gained a lot of headlines
about how it could inhibit the SARS Cove
2 virus in its infectious potential in
mice and in cells and so we thought well
you know we've seen such impressive
results with the acidic canabo the thca
and the cbda it kind of makes sense for
us to explore cbga next let's see what
it does we started playing around with
it and we found that in combination with
cbda it seemed to be doing something
special um you know we weren't testing
it against SS you know like against
covid uh we were just taking it and see
how we felt and people were reporting
very similar things that this comination
made them feel alert awake focused like
in the zone resilient to addess you know
I didn't expect that I still don't
exactly know what's the mechanism of
action um but enough of us felt like
well this is a prototype worth bringing
to Market that you know that's what we
did and we still have so much to learn
from it you know I mean even even CBG I
knew it had a lot of potential what do
we know about it in humans right now
other than the anecdotes almost nothing
right there's one survey study and the
people in that study weren't you know
that the data is um just not very clear
like it's a good starting point but we
don't know exactly how much most of them
were taking or what what other you know
canav oids they were taking it for uh
and and so because of that we currently
have an ongoing uh another survey of CBG
users to try to to try to clarify that
but what it it seems like you get you
get something that's a hit in a small
number of people you allow other kind of
cannabis uh enthusiasts to to start
using it and then before too long we've
got got some signals that are worth
following and we do the observational
research we kind of confirm what we
think we're seeing and then you know
maybe that leads to more more clinical
trials or more animal
research it's you know it's so backwards
with cannabis that we start with humans
and then we go
to after
[Music]
that
ah