thank you I'm Dr Michael Stewart uh Mike
or Dr Mike if you want to be formal
um and before I start today I need to
share some breaking news that was
published yesterday from the AMA
they have actually found that in several
different chronic disease States medical
marijuana patients have a higher quality
of life
um just some of the western backs maybe
a little bit behind us here and that is
my training as well but um anyway I was
board certified in Family Practice in
the 1990s that's a little bit after the
Jurassic period for some folks in the
room here I did mostly HIV care I
started doing that in residency and then
that wound up being the focus of my
office and uh so I became experienced in
bringing novel therapies into clinical
practice and although cannabis is not a
novel therapy our use of it kind of is
so I'm applying that
that experience that I have here into
cannabis my history as I ran with fire
rescue for seven years and that's how I
entered uh into the field of medicine I
taught paramedicine and fire science for
a while and I learned a lot of very
valuable information about medicine even
before I went to medical school and uh I
can remember while I was in medical
school and I had Advanced cardiac life
support certification that had lapsed
and I was still running in the field on
weekends and my physician advisor gave
me some very good advice when I said
what do I do if I come across somebody
my certification is lapsed and he looked
at me and he said you know what if you
keep your patients best interest in your
heart I will always back you up
and if I ever find out that you didn't
do something you knew how to do because
of a bureaucratic issue you're in a lot
of trouble and so that stayed with me
um anyway so I have a little bit
different entry into medicine if we
arrive with fire rescue a car is down an
embankment in a creek
you know and it's four o'clock in the
morning you don't say this is
inconvenient we'll come back later these
people are suffering and we need to do
something now
um so I was involved in some repurposing
of medications when it came to HIV a lot
of resistance to that that I'm
understanding much better now than I did
back then
um but people were dying we needed to be
bold
and I did a lot of uh
um interesting care
um the Ivory Tower delay kind of
confused me because that wasn't a part
of my training
um and uh I had a lot of HIV patients in
fact I was the largest Family Practice
provider of HIV care in a five-state
region I noticed that my clients who
were using medicinal marijuana were
doing even better than my clients that
we're not and you would think as an
early adopter and a bold person who has
a little bit of a renegade too that I
would have been using medicinal
marijuana back then
um regretfully it was a time when
Amendment two had passed in Colorado
where my office was we were the only
office advertising as gay and lesbian
friendly in the state of Colorado at the
time an amendment to allow
discrimination based on sexual
orientation my attorney told me not to
do medical marijuana and I listened I
was afraid
um
so at any rate ultimately
the office that uh I called my Adult Day
Care Center for my staff
really did become a great Institution
for folks who had HIV and I wound up
sitting in multiple pharmaceutical
advisory boards I was involved in some
clinical studies although I can
understand the frustration of most
investigators when I said no to their
studies because we're using very toxic
medications and Do no harm was important
um I've been the medical director for
one of the largest hospices in the world
one of their divisions anyway a home
health care agency I was the medical
director for a medicinal marijuana
company in California before they went
recreational I'm a member of the
American Academy of Family Practice the
American Society of addiction medicine
and more importantly the Society of
cannabis clinicians I think if I could
physically I'd go back to fire rescue
though
let's see today we're here to talk about
long covid so
um this is a chronic disease and as we
all know that allopathic medicine
sometimes doesn't treat these chronic
diseases quite as well as other
practitioners do
um but what are we talking about here
it's just the lingering symptoms from
the covet infection typically fatigue
brain fog shortness of breath anxiety
depression and sleep disturbance
although more than 200 symptoms have
been associated with long covet now guys
start to think about something else
myalgic encephalomyelitis chronic
fatigue syndrome
um anyway the first patients came out
around 2020 I came in contact with them
we put on a 10-week podcast for these
long haulers where I talked for about 10
or 15 minutes and then we did questions
and answers
um 28 percent of coveted patients are
expected to experience long covet
according to the CDC there are four
million Americans unable to work that's
according to the Brookings Institute but
I just invite you guys to go out into
the service industry and look around
it's a little harder to get work done
these days and I think part of this is
people are are feeling poorly it's a 3.7
trillion dollar cost according to
Harvard
um
anyway let's go on to the next one here
um when covet began I was in the process
of actually moving to Denver for my
company
um but I used to live in Palm Springs
and their HIV Center was becoming a
covid center they asked if I would give
them a hand and so I returned to Palm
Springs I still had a place there at the
time and I noticed all the continuing
medical education that I was doing with
covid the inflammatory markers were all
attenuated by cannabis and or its
constituents and uh you know we're
talking about cannabis stocks having new
and diverse ideas well I don't know if
it was really new or diverse but it was
like guys what about the endocannabinoid
system I've been studying that for about
10 years now and it sure seemed to me
like the endocannabinoid system was at
least involved here and if it was
damaged in the acute covet infection
could restoring that or supporting that
help with the symptoms you know could we
get them to disappear
um or at least attenuate those symptoms
illness you know I'm a hammer and
everything looks like a nail when it
comes to cannabis don't ask me if you
should use it just ask me how
um so the human endocannabinoid system
uh this is review for most people here
um I'm still a little gun shy because
during the covet Arena if I talked about
anything like the endocannabinoid system
or if I came out with something that
might help with covid
um boy it was censored I remember that
with a conference with Dustin sulak him
being censored once so I felt like I was
in good company anyway
um the endocannabinoid system
um it's definitely involved we've got a
lot more receptors than the CB1 and CB2
involved here but what I really want to
point out here is take a look at the CB1
and the CB2 receptors and they have
different actions and we know that THC
is going to interact with that CB1
receptor we know that CBD also does as a
negative allosteric modulator but we
want a little activity in that CB1 and
so this is why we're going to look for
the full complement of cannabis we're
not looking for
isolates of it here
um anyway we'll go into a little more of
the endocannabinoid system on the next
slide
um so how are we going to balance the
endocannabinoid system remember this is
a three-part system and fortunately
Dustin sulak's lecture talked a lot here
about these receptors which get up
regulated when we are cannabis naive and
come and contact uh with cannabis so
we've got the The receptors that we know
can be involved we know we've got the
ligands those are the endocannabinoids
or naturally occurring cannabinoids or
the phytocannabinoids
um and then we have the enzymes that
break them down so specifically for long
covid we looked at the nine most common
long coveted symptoms
um and we chose a
phytocannabinoids that we knew would be
balancing to the endocannabinoid system
and then I selected medicinal terpenes
that I knew had some additional
qualities and assumed the flavonoids
that went along with them were
consistent with what was going on there
um so this is a full blend of
cannabinoids and terpenes and let me
just see the CBD to THC ratio here is
non-euporic or intoxicating and when I
was doing HIV care I was combining
anywhere from really a minimum of three
medications but most of the time about
12.
and back then I was combining single
molecule medicines together and they
were toxic I had to be very careful I
was chasing side effects all the time
um I've been accused of creating
chemical chaos because I'm I'm blending
chemovars of cannabis together that have
hundreds of different components in them
and I maintain I don't create chemical
chaos when I trust Mother Nature so I'm
not blending synthetics I'm not blending
isolate I'm not taking the plant apart
isolating it concentrating it in
frankensteining it back together we are
using concentrations that occur in
nature
um so uh
I published a paper on the uh mechanisms
of action on how cannabis handles
constituents could attenuate what was
going on with covid and long covid
um basically if you're interested this
is kind of a scientific paper it runs
through the fact that we have a complex
immune system at the endocannabinoid
system is its Master regulator outcomes
are correlated with inflammatory
responses and we can kind of measure
these with pro-inflammatory cytokines
goes through some of the mechanisms by
which cannabis can be helpful with
preventing The Binding of the viral
Spike protein we up regulate you know a
whole bunch of different Pathways anyway
if we want to go into detail uh we we
can but I don't have time to do it today
I don't think unless we have questions
um
so what did we do we
we applied what we learned here and we
produced a product here and if you take
a look on the right hand side of the
slide here this is what we list on every
one of our products just on the bottle
and I know sometimes I'm accused of
telling people how to build a clock when
they ask for the time but I think this
is absolutely necessary on the bottle we
do have a barcode or what do you call
them instead of a barcode now uh QR or
something you see I was born in the 60s
um at any rate if you scan the code
you'll come up with our full COA that
not only includes the terpenes
cannabinoids but it's going to go into
the safety of our product as well if you
can find a cleaner product than what we
have go ahead and buy it and please
don't believe me but listen to me and
compare this so we are from hemp
um and I think everybody here knows that
hemp is cannabis it just has a lower THC
concentration I don't have a schedule
one license and I do want to do research
from the one person I know who has a
schedule one license I don't think I
want one
and I also believe that I can do 90 to
95 percent of the work that cannabis can
do medicinally and I can do it with low
THC concentration cannabis that meets
the legal definition of hemp
um so we're federally legal
um there are a lot of talk about dirty
hemp and when people are talking about
dirty hemp
um we're really talking about the
political environment we're not talking
about the plant it's the same plant as
marijuana just different THC
concentrations in the issues of dirty
hemp in my opinion are political and
they can be resolved with integrity
um a lack of Regulation does occur in
the hemp industry
we take care of that by being
responsible and I also invite folks here
in the room
just to think about whether or not there
might be a competing industry to the
Cannabis industry that is trying to pit
the hemp people against the marijuana
people
because state of Colorado has
out-of-state money coming in trying to
cause fights
um
anyway uh that was a dirty issue sorry
and the lack of Regulation our goal is
to maintain our products the way Mother
Nature Made Them and and really when I
start with the cannabis plant and I keep
it as close to the way Mother Nature
Made it
um I'm starting with a food rather than
a poison although we know that dosage is
important but the body knows what to do
with full flower cannabis
um apparently the way we can produce
things is a little bit ahead of what
other people are doing in the industry
right now because we do have the ability
to produce wet flour and we use flour
not biomass in our products the reason
for that is the terpene concentrations
and their integrity is really important
to me and I can't get that kind of
result with biomass although biomass can
produce good medicine it's not what I
use I believe I maintain the enzymes in
the terpenes and flavonoids and the
integrity of this plant much better by
using ambient pressures and ambient
temperatures
in the production of our products and
please again don't believe me but listen
to me our coas are very clear and if you
can't read them please reach out to me
and we can guide you through the coas
but we are a transparent company this
product here was designed specifically
for long covet
so it was really focusing on those nine
symptoms that who was saying were the
most common for long covid again
Botanical Fidelity is important to me
we're only using cannabis Blends in our
products so we don't use other
Botanicals in our products I know the
FDA doesn't like it but I see it quite
commonly in the field and when you see a
COA that is really sky-high in terpenes
think I think maybe it's not cannabis
terpenes so we're not using isolates or
synthetic we're blending full Kim of
ours together
and obviously the CB1 and CB2 receptors
are both important when it comes to Long
covet and our products do contain small
amounts of THC
um Dr sulak did a beautiful job talking
about low dosing here and ultra low
dosing I've always maintained that the
way cannabis works I look at it in some
ways more like a nutrient than a
medication and sometimes more like a
medication than a nutrient
if you're out and about for a long long
time and you don't get any vitamin C you
might develop scurvy and if you're going
to treat your scurvy you can treat it
pretty well with low-dose vitamin C
eating orange maybe take a 150
milligrams of Vitamin C that scurvy
should go away if you want to use
vitamin C as an anti-inflammatory it's a
good anti-inflammatory and I've used it
myself
you need to use liposomal preparations
or you need to use it IV because bile
tolerance can be reached and it's uh
it's pretty uncomfortable but it can be
used as an anti-inflammatory so cannabis
is kind of the same way at low doses I
really think it balances our
endocannabinoid systems and Dr sulak
gave us a beautiful
mechanism of action of that through
hormesis and at any rate when we start
to use cannabis as an anti-inflammatory
anti-convulsant anti-cancer agent we
need to go up higher in the doses but
even small doses of getting this plant
into people for any reason I think is a
pretty good idea
um so we took formula C for a test drive
I'm gonna have to speed up maybe a
little bit here we got a really strong
signal
um it was out in the market our chief
Revenue officer talked to a bunch of
people he found 10 people who'd used it
for long covet all 10 had a good
response from it
um so that's all perfect it's not you
know scientific information but a couple
of these people actually started crying
on the phone because it had helped them
so much so we took that as a very strong
signal in Formula C and we put together
a post marketing because this was
already out in the market by definition
this is a phase four clinical trial we
went through full institutional review
board approval up on
clinicaltrials.gov we did not go for an
investigational new drug application and
in so doing I forgave the ability to
patent this product but our patients are
more important than our patents are and
so we were able to go into a days for
clinical trial and this product is for
long coveted covet hasn't been going on
that long and we already have a product
that has been produced and through a
phase four clinical trial I think you
know we're moving in the right direction
at least I come from a family of
business people we had patents on many
products but we always want in the
marketplace so what I'm doing anybody
else can do I don't see them doing it
right now
um but I do believe that it can be done
um let's move on here the trial had two
parts to it first part of 28 days either
active product or Placebo second part 28
days everybody goes over to open label
product
um what did we find first 28 days nine
out of nine symptoms improved at the end
of the study we had eight out of nine
that have had improved two are
statistically significant over Baseline
no serious Adverse Events were noticed
and our patients uh Global impression of
change is really pretty impressive we'll
go through a little bit of that here we
do have some follow-up work being done
at the Bateman horn Institute in Utah as
well
and so here's what we found this is kind
of a busy slide
um but it shows in the green here where
we reach some statistical significance
again this is over Baseline not over
Placebo I can't go into those reasons
right now because I'll be out of time
um in the yellow was areas where we
reached clinical significance rather
than statistical
this is the patient Global impression of
change I can't guarantee you people were
doing three times as well but guys this
is a really strong signal something is
happening here and we think it's
happening in a really good way
um so where are we now we're working
with early adopters
um long covet is our our Focus right now
I have a lot of other products we love
to work with folks that are passionate
about what they're doing we've put
together an Advisory board with people
who are passionate about covid and long
covid
um my name is Michael Stewart and my
CEO's name is Isaac Foster and we are
really here to Steward and Foster
a better understanding of the
endocannabinoid system in cannabinoid
medicines
and we're very serious here I would love
to work with other people who are
inspired I think we can do this cost
effectively I'm going to get off here
but I do want to say thank you there are
a couple people in particular who have
really impacted
um my career over the last 10 years and
one of them can't be here today that's
Rafael mashulum thank you for Dr Bonnie
Goldstein and Dr Dustin sulak Dr Ethan
Russo
um and uh Dede Mary thank you thank you
thank you