hi thanks everyone thank you for that
introduction as well which to what is my
ultimate mission to bring you all to
Canada I'm here to recruit you where we
can do a little bit we have a little bit
easier access to two early phases of
research in in cannabis space medicine
so I'm here to represent my organization
Sante cannabis our team of our small
team here that contributed to this work
but our larger team back home in
Montreal Quebec so just some disclosure
so I'm going to present about what is an
investigational drug which is owned by
sponsor tetra biopharma and some work
that was done at large CRO North
American CRO so we've heard we've talked
a bit about Canada we've got some
excitement happening both with the
introduction of the cannabis act last
week which legalized cannabis for adult
use but we have a proliferation of
licensed producers and manufacturers of
products in Canada that are regulated
federally and we have access to the
Machine of regulatory investigational
processes that allow the development of
cannabis based drugs governed by the
same division that looks at other the
development of other pharmaceutical
medications we also have with the
cannabis act a lot of opportunity for
smaller cultivators processors
manufacturers to get into the game as
there is now a inclusive framework for
different sizes of production and
facilities so in the cannabis act as
well we saw a streamlining of access to
cannabis products for research purposes
and this should make working in this
this field much easier moving forward so
we don't have really a huge revolution
happening though we've had a lot of
cannabis dispensaries so a lot of the
hype around you know how much of a
change this is on the ground level
it isn't really founded because we had a
gray area dispensaries hundreds of them
operating it's more of a shift for those
of us who've been working in this field
for a long time to suddenly see these
dispensaries having closing out sales in
preparation for what our government
suppliers to take over so this is the
aunty
retailer here in our largest province
and quotes on Twitter just astounded by
the interest in their their products
which we all know very well so cannabis
means medicine in Canada obviously we
have a lot of the same opportunities and
challenges that you see here but
importantly if we look at a lot of the
challenges over here we decide that we
can look at these access access to
information research education training
stigmatization and take the the focus on
the opportunity of redeveloping research
products and investigational drugs to
address this long list of challenges
that we have so that brings us to our
mission at Sante cannabis where we exist
in in Quebec
santé very important for you know means
health in French I've had to translate
to quite a few Americans this this week
and we facilitate a series of clinics
across the province where we're
supporting patient access to physicians
and our nursing team for support
education and treatment plans but we're
also collecting a huge battery of
different research outcome measures so
to do that it does involve quite a few
different people but this is a glimpse
at our clinic and research model so we
initiate with a referral from a
physician treating the patient on in
primary care and then run that through
our system to to initiate the patient
into our research database the patient
will be seen in person at the clinic by
a nurse who will do a complete
assessment and be able to collect a huge
list of baseline data the nurse works
together with the physician to implement
the treatment plan for that patient and
then critically we have our core of our
team the nurse educators who provide
education follow-up supports
modification of dosages and product
recommendations ongoing and this is all
adhering to a physician standardized
treatment plan so what that means is
then we're able to take that experience
all data observational data which work
electing from the patient and take that
over - from a sponsor small biotech
companies experts in drug development
who are looking for keys - to their
development and start to initiate a
process where we can develop cannabis
based drugs in parallel with our work at
the clinic so as we know there's a very
complexity of treatment options we have
more than 100 browsers in Canada each
producing between 10 and 50 different
products so this translates into a huge
number price we start to then categorize
the the products that are available in
two different formulations of THC CBD
and try to collect as much data as
possible about other cannabinoids and
terpenoids selection primarily between
inhalation and oral which is what we
have available in Canada then if we dig
in to the patient use patterns at the
clinic we still see that we are in a
transitionary phase so in methods of an
administration while oil or oral
administration has been growing in
popularity and is now our most common
method of use we see a still a lot of
inhalation which has been persistent
over time so more than 50% of patients
are using inhalation in some form
weathering incorporated with oil or on
its own and in that category of
inhalation we still see a very
persistent population that is insistent
on smoking as well so vaporization has
been growing but even patients who have
a vaporizer often report that smoking
can be more effective for them and are
often using the two in tandem or in a
kind of mixed model of inhalation so
this drives this question what is going
on with this smoking and why patients
are still reporting such a difference
between vaporization and smoking
administrations so the big question of
inhalation is then you know is it
necessary we have all of these other
methods that are developing especially
here in California and other US states
where you have topical creams something
you will sprays patches things like that
but we still see this persistent desire
for inhalation and especially if we
think about specific symptom categories
such as breakthrough pain nausea
vomiting
appetite stimulation and the potential
for substitution as well of problematic
substances of abuse this kind of rapid
onset of inhalation is thought to be
very critical so if we think about the
ongoing development of inhalation as a
method of administration it's our goal
to really go back and look at the root
of the issue so inhalation methods
though we have a lot of information that
has been published about there in vitro
results such as using an artificial lung
analyzing components in the smoke or the
vapor we don't have enough information
about the in human response to these
different methods of administration so
this products to work with the sponsor
I'm highlighting here this is the
product that was developed for analysis
and comparison between smoked
administration and vaporized it's named
as the investigational drug PPV zero
zero one active pharmaceutical
ingredient both THC and CBD and a
specific ratio so this product is
standardized as a blend of three
different strains of dried cannabis at a
dosage of 280 milligrams of whole plant
material and standardized to have a
dosage of 25 milligrams THC and five
point five milligrams of CBD per pellet
then in the placebo we have zero THC and
a small fraction of CBD so the objective
of this first study which I'll present
today is to evaluate this safety and
tolerability of this fixed dose in an
inhaled or smoked THC and CBD
administration over one day and then
over seven consecutive days the methods
I involve a kind of clear standard
process for a phase one double-blind
placebo-controlled so we'll be doing at
single and multiple daily doses in both
of those cohorts so importantly this was
a very popular study and recruitment
because subjects were confined for
monitoring during the entire duration of
the period and for 36 hours pre and post
so it involved a lot of video games and
being paid quite well for that time
this was a approved according to
standard procedures and we're looking
really primarily at safety outcome so
vital signs ECG was done at various time
points physical exam and the battery of
clinical laboratory tests to look at
different safety outcomes including a
standard process for cognition the
device that was used as an inhalation
device approved actually in Canada as a
class to medical device it's a titanium
pipe which can be used to smoke cannabis
and this was a standardized controlled
inhalation to try to get as close as
possible to a standardized dose so it
was very carefully instructed to inhale
for three seconds hold for three seconds
exhale and and repeat the process for as
many inhalations is required to complete
the dose so in the first cohort these
patients were looked at were divided
into a group of groups of eight subjects
and dosage was first just once daily for
one day and then moving to twice and
three times a day with the same product
then that safety data would be analyzed
before proceeding to the second cohort
which would essentially progress through
that same process over a seven day
period so importantly in the
demographics we had a pretty good range
of age from twenty five all the way up
to sixty years old
primarily for sixty percent male but and
primarily Caucasian average BMI and
pretty standard other measures of health
so when we look at the pharmacokinetics
this is where things start to get really
interesting when we look at smoked
administration we had THC and CBD
detectable in the first blood draw one
minute after inhalation and for most
subjects this remained for about three
hours though many of them had almost
complete elimination after one hour post
administration the maximum concentration
or C max was very variable even with the
very standardized method of inhalation
that we employed with the maximum
concentration of 30 all the way to 180
nanograms per ml now 180 is something
that's very rarely observed I think
there's one report of
of such concentration in a clinical
study usually we see 50 to 60 nanogram
per ml as a c-max
in vaporization studies so the maximum
time for over on average was 5 minutes
so that's the peak plasma level
occurring at five minutes post
administration and in this cohort we
didn't see any accumulation effect at
all so part neck before the next dose
was administered there was completed
elimination of the THC CBD and the the
metabolite alpha 11 hydroxy we also
didn't see any set steady state so in
pharmacodynamics we can see that there's
an impaired cognition actually after the
first administration but that this
actually resolved as we were
administering further so we saw some
development of tolerance though in this
small population it can be difficult to
make large estimates of that effect we
also saw some limitations that we
weren't looking for functional
impairment but just a standard
impairment small sample size and and I'm
not sure yet about clinical significance
until we move to our next round of
studies so something that's very
interesting in the data is if we look in
an it's exactly at these different
subjects so this safety affect the
safety report actually stopped the study
periodically a severe adverse reaction
and to moderate ones when she involved
the subject fainting now this was a 52
year old Caucasian female she'd been
exposed to cannabis in the past so was
used to the effects and you would expect
her to have a very high concentration in
her blood but actually she was below
average with just a 50 to nanogram per
ml so this is really showing the
difference between subjects and how this
response can be also very psychosomatic
there were no clinical reasons why this
subject should have fainted and when we
think about the dosage of just 25
milligrams of THC it's quite shocking
that someone could have this effect from
that dosage considering the doses that
are sold and used in in dispensaries and
other clinical settings so in comparison
this subject 25 years old Asian female
with a pretty low birth rate and low
resting blood pressure had a very mild
side effects but had the very highest
concentration in her blood
so her tolerance to the 180 nanogram per
ml concentration was quite surprising
same cohort same dose but a very
interactive and as many of you know
working in cannabis the start low go
slow really holds true through through
clinical setting and through
double-blind trials where we saw that a
titration strategy was necessary to
progress to a seven-day administration
after subject number three had such a
response so we introduced a slower
titration to move subjects towards the
full dose as they move towards the
seven-day administration so they started
with just one inhalation and moved up to
two completing the entire pellet so this
was this was done to satisfy Health
Canada to progress to the seven-day
administration and showed a significant
improvement in the the adverse event
profile so overall you see here that
these are normalized to the number of
dosages that were administered so
actually when that titration was
administered the start low go slow
process we see that that cohort actually
had lower instance of adverse events
than the placebo did in the prior cohort
so we really see a significance there
otherwise the most common events are
somnolence dizziness and headache as
well as some euphoria so overall this
was a very successful seven-day
administration so importantly now for
safety really this big question is can
this drug be moved into Phase two and
three that was clear from the results
there was nothing clinically significant
in cardiovascular no drug-related
changes in serum hematology or urine and
everything was primarily mild that was
reported 82 and 94 percent in the two
cohorts and we had no serious adverse
events at all nothing life-threatening
or a hospital requiring hospitalization
so this product has moved into now
couple of different trials the first one
a phase 3 trial which is really a
compassionate use focus we are
recruiting for this right now in Quebec
and are looking for other sites so feel
free to reach out to us 3 minutes and
finally this was found to be generally
safe and well tolerated the protocol is
to be repeated with with a vaporizer
next month to compare the different
results and to see the the differences
in in pharmacodynamics which is very
interesting it's interesting as well to
look at now why this concentration may
exceed that would be seen in vaporizer
studies so once we verify that it will
give us a better idea of in which
populations smoked cannabis may be
preferential over vaporized and explain
a little bit of why we we see the
differences in the in the patient
reporting and then finally that the this
maximum time of a very rapid delivery
could be the most effective way to to
treat acute symptoms
finally a limitation that is worth a
really heavy investigation in tech is
that this variability in inhalation is
going to be a huge challenge and will
require some very innovative drug
delivery systems so here's the pitch if
you're interested to to study this drug
please reach out to our company or to to
tetra biopharma and it will be available
as well internationally and for any
contacts thank you very much
[Applause]
hi that was a great presentation dr.
Carolyn McCallum from Vancouver BC I'm
just wondering if you can elaborate a
little bit more on the neurocognitive
impairment if there was a standardized
questionnaire that was giving patients
or if it was a functional examination or
how you guys classified that there was a
series of tests that were performed for
both short-term memory for small motor
skills as well as the kind of standard
making mini cognitive effects for for
cognition but unfortunately we didn't
study functional impairment which is
something that we'll look at in future
studies as we would be you know
concerned about certain populations
oncology populations geriatric
populations to to use this product
without that assessment great thanks