[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
cammed conference
alright guys we are so close to
announcing the details for canmed23
our entire team has been working hard
behind the scenes to create something
truly special but we can't tell you what
it is just yet
more information will be available in
the next few weeks
we can't wait to share this with you and
we hope that you're excited as well
but there are a few things that you can
do to make sure you don't miss out on
any news about can mid-23
first make sure you sign up for email
alerts at cannemanevents.com
there's a spot in the footer at the
bottom of the page where you can enter
your email address
second follow us on social media we're
on instagram facebook twitter and
linkedin just search for cam at events
third subscribe to the canmed coffee
talk podcast i will post a special
announcement episode that includes all
the details about canmed23
and if you are subscribed that episode
will show up in your podcast app how
convenient is that
in the meantime
you can enjoy videos of all the previous
canmed presentations and panel
discussions including the ones from
canmed2022
in the kmed archive at canmedevents.com
on this episode i spoke with jenny curry
ginny is the laboratory director at
modern canada laboratories lakeland
florida facility where she focuses on
developing standardized methods for
analyzing cannabis to ensure harmful
toxins are not present
before entering the cannabis industry
ginny gained valuable research
experience at several well-respected
institutes including emory university
the national institute of aging
and the university of florida ginny
recently received her master's in
medical cannabis science and
therapeutics from the university of
maryland in addition to running
laboratory operations for modern canna
ginny is also active in other areas of
the cannabis industry
she currently serves on the scientific
advisory board for analytical cannabis
and is a member of the casp proficiency
testing task force with aoac
international
ginny and her team recently performed a
study that compared various methods of
total yeast and mold testing
their results showed that there is very
little agreement between the methods
calling into question whether total
yeast and mold is even a useful test
in the episode we discuss
why states require total yeast and mold
testing
the different types of testing methods
and how widely the results vary
how labs may not be giving yeast and
mold enough time to grow
whether the variance in total yeast and
mold testing results leads to lab
shopping
and should total yeast and mold even be
a required test
before we get to my conversation with
ginny i want to thank this episode
sponsor modern canada laboratories
modern canada is regarded as florida's
first medical cannabis laboratory and
one of the most trusted third party
testing providers in the united states
the company's mission is to help set the
standard for cannabis testing labs
worldwide by providing the most accurate
and efficient testing services delivered
with a sense of compassion integrity and
moral obligation and to attract and
attain clients who value quality data
that is verifiable reproducible and
legally defensible
modern canada is also the only leafly
certified laboratory in the eastern
united states and adheres to the
industry's strictest sops and quality
control standards
modern canada offers a wide variety of
testing rapid turnaround times and
consulting services to florida medical
marijuana treatment centers and hemp
businesses throughout the us
for more information visit
moderncanna.com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with jenny curry
[Music]
good morning jenny thanks for joining us
on the podcast
hi yes
all right so i read your article in
analytical cannabis about the benefits
and pitfalls of total yeast in mold
counts in cannabis labs and i'll put a
link to that in the show description so
people can check that out
um and first i want to thank you for
writing it because
our team at medicinal genomics we've
been talking about issues with total
eastern mold for years now and you know
we've published papers on it we've done
webinars about it we've done canned med
talks about it
but since we're a kit manufacturer our
message is sort of met with some
skepticism because obviously we have a
dog in in the fight but for an
independent lab like modern canada to
raise some concerns that's something
that we think should resonate um but
before we get into the
investigation that your team did
maybe it's best to set the table for any
listeners who aren't well-versed in
cannabis testing so can you explain what
the total easton mold testing
requirements are in florida
at least to start
yeah of course so in the state of
florida
the testing requirements involve testing
final product in its final packaging so
flour is kind of what we're going to
focus on today it's where the problems
of total yeast and mold are seen and so
with that the limit is a hundred
thousand cfus per gram in the state of
florida what's interesting is you know
you have states that have no total yeast
and mold requirements to states that
have a hundred cfu per gram yeast and
mold requirements so it's a pretty vast
range across the us and so because of
that it causes some issues as well on
that front with data and with
methodology because if the methodology
doesn't allow you to be able to meet
those requirements labs are not going to
be able to produce accurate data
so
so with that total yeast and mold um
basically we're looking at you know how
much mold and yeast are in that flower
um it's not looking at any sort of
species it's not looking at like
specifics it's just an overall kind of
big picture of what's going on in that
cannabis flower
yeah and that's that's an important
distinction to make because you know you
mentioned that some states they don't
have total eastern mold testing
requirements but they do have species
specific tests for things that we know
are pathogenic like for example
aspergillus um does
does florida actually test for
aspergillus as well
yes so we require aspergillus all four
species
to be tested and then as well as that
it's salmonella and sugar toxin e coli
and flour samples
excellent excellent so i guess that's a
good question then so if you're already
kind of testing for the known pathogenic
species you know what is the benefit of
a total yeast and mold test from a
consumer perspective
i think really it and that's kind of
where i think the misconceptions may
arise from is that consumers have been
kind of it's been portrayed to them that
okay it's telling me you know is my
flower moldy but the problem with that
is there's good yeasts and there's good
molds and so looking at a total count
you're sometimes going to skew those
results and you're going to make a
patient believe they're not safe when
really they are or a consumer depending
on if you're in a recreational or
medicinal market
yeah and i mean and that's a good
example with aspergillus too right if
you were only testing for total yeast
and mold
um
and you had a threshold set to say a
hundred thousand cfus you could have 99
000 cfus of aspergillus in your product
and
that's that's not good for anyone
correct yeah and that's one of the
things that we mentioned i mentioned in
the article is like looking at those
pathogenic species because if you don't
then a product may seem safe when it
actually truly isn't safe
right absolutely okay so now
now that we've established that so what
prompted you and the team at modern
canada to investigate total yeast and
mold like what what questions were you
looking to answer
so um basically we similar to medicinal
genomics have had lots of questions
about yeast and mold over the years
as the first testing lab in the state of
florida we originally started with
plating total yeast in mold
using like the compact dry plates and
then moved into pcr testing and we did
pcr testing and then
after certification we certified through
pcr for total yeast and mold we're
running samples um and we actually had a
client come back and say they tested
with another lab and got much higher
counts than what we got with pcr and
they used plating and so after that that
really triggered me to start diving in
at the end of the day the science is the
most important part of it and so
figuring out that science and figuring
out is their issues and how can we adapt
for those issues was really my goal of
doing this investigation
medicinal genomics has been wonderful
with helping do r d and really talking
us through some of the troubleshooting
we've seen
we
started by you know doing some dilutions
in pcr and kind of trying to determine
if there was some suppression happening
and we did see that there was in cases
where if there's a ton of yeast and mold
in sample there can be suppression on
the pcr and so
we started adapting the medicinal
genomics method to up front do a 20x
dilution so instead of doing 1 to 10
grams like the protocol calls for we
move to doing one gram of flour to 20
mils of tsb in order to really prevent
that suppression from happening and we
really saw a big difference in the
reproducibility once we started doing
that because we were no longer fighting
okay is there too much yeast and mold in
that sample right
yeah because in those cases what you
would sort of be doing a a re-run and
with a with a dilution to sort of make
sure that you aren't overloading
yeah and so that's that's ultimately
what we ended up doing is you know i
kind of talked to the team at medicinal
genomics about as far as the cq values
on qpcr what i should be seeing changes
if i do dilutions and so we started
applying those dilutions so we took a
sample and we did a 2x dilution and then
we did a 5x dilution and then we did a
10x dilution and we watched how those cq
values should change so we know that
they should change in a very particular
way and shift you know downfield to be a
higher cq value lower reported value but
we weren't always seeing that if we just
did the one to ten
okay all right and before we leave too
many people in the dust here because you
know this audience i mean i know anyone
who's familiar with medicinal genomics
they're gonna understand this but you
know this is a canmed podcast we have
some people that are more on the medical
side or are more on the cultivation side
so i was hoping maybe you could briefly
explain the difference between like
plating and culture based methods and
pcr
yeah of course so with plating basically
what you're doing is you're taking your
sample
and you're diluting it in some sort of a
media
and then you're taking that media and
you're adding that to a plate whether
that be an agar whether that be a petri
film plate whether that be a compact dry
plate whatever type of culture method
you're using you're going to add that
diluted sample to that
and there's particular amounts that you
add you know for the
agar plates you're using only 0.1 mil
but for you know petri film you're using
a full mill so you have to factor
dilutions into that as well because that
changes your result um how much you play
is going to have a significant impact on
what you're going to see your outcome be
so
versus pcr which you know is the process
of taking the sample and you're
extracting the dna from that sample and
so what you're doing is you're isolating
not only the cannabis dna but you're
also isolating the microbe dna and then
using a primer you basically take your
dna that you've obtained and you mix it
with a primer and then you load it onto
the pcr and it undergoes a process of
heating and cooling in order to anneal
that dna and when those microbes are
present they bind to that primer and
they anneal and then you'll fluoresce
have fluorescence and you'll see what
that is
the great thing about qpcr is you have
an internal control which is hex and so
that hex fluorescence lets you know that
you have cannabis dna and that your
extraction worked
that's a pro to pcr versus plating with
p with plating you have no way of
knowing if it was plated correctly and
if you're actually getting solution on
the plate whereas with pcr
if you don't get that hex you know your
extraction didn't work so you can't say
for sure if that sample really has
easter mold or not
excellent that was an excellent
excellent description um we're not going
to use that um so
in your investigation if i read it
correctly
you're primarily comparing plating
methods to one another correct
correct and we did you know compare kind
of the pcr as well we ran pcr on those
samples
but mostly it was for us to do plating
the state of florida is potentially
considering moving away from qpcr for
total yeast and mold and so if that
happens we wanted to be prepared since
originally we were only certified for
qpcr and total yeast and mold okay and
so
there's a number of different plating
methods for total yeast and mold and it
looks like based on your results that
they are all
they don't necessarily agree with one
another so like what are some of the
differences here i mean because i mean
correct me if i'm wrong but in order for
a plate to work i mean
you're
you're putting the microbes into a
solution that's supposed to be optimized
for growth for a certain
type of microbe so in this case a total
yeast and mold but as i understand it
it's very difficult to actually capture
all of the yeast and mold that could
potentially be there and
effectively exclude any of the bacteria
or other organisms that could be there
correct and so that's really the big
battle with plating is you know ensuring
that you're not getting bacterial growth
and that you are getting only yeast and
mold growth but you also are combating
the fact that aspergillus doesn't grow
well on plating so for that if you're
plating and you have aspergillus you're
still going to get lower counts than
what is representative of the sample
because you're not able to grow those
they don't culture well they don't
survive in that type of environment
which is why qpcr is so important for
some of the speciation testing because
that's the only way you're going to be
able to accurately identify those
compounds
excellent okay so let's get into your
results here so please talk about the
number of different
methods that you that you did and sort
of what your process was and ultimately
what you guys found
so what we did was we started with seven
different types of plates or agars
and used all seven of those and ran the
same sample
so we took a sample and we actually ran
the sample in triplicate and then we ran
it at three different dilutions for each
plate
it was a big study my microbiologists
were phenomenal they were troopers
through the entire study
and it was a lot of plates to manage and
to count and to keep track of so we did
looked at compact dry we looked at petri
film rapid yeast and mold petri film
non-rapid yeast in mold potato dextrose
agar potato dextrose agar with chlora
tetracycline
um
dichlorine rose bengal chlorophyll
lobe
and abdex i'm not even gonna attempt
that one so those are more kind of
formerly known as pda pdac drbc and
sabdex
right um and so we took all of those
plates we plated them we looked at okay
what type of dilution needs to be done
on the plates um those agars so the pda
pdac drbc and sabdex all needed to be
plated at 0.1 mils versus the compact
dry rapid yeast and mold and non-rapid
yeast and mold petri films needed to be
plated at a mill so we mapped out what
our dilutions needed to be in order to
obtain the same dilution on each plate
and then went about making those
dilutions
all of the dilutions were made for all
of them at the same time and they were
all taken from the same source and so
that ensured that the homogeneity wasn't
going to be in question because one of
the fights you're combating with
cannabis is it's not homogeneous and the
yeast in bold is not going to be spread
evenly throughout the product um you may
get one scoop that you know has tons of
yeast and mold and you may get another
scoop that doesn't and so in order to
standardize that and ensure that we were
getting a good true result we only use
the sample once and then we did it for
everything same for pcr we also ran pcr
on these um what we found from the
plating was it was a little shocking um
to kind of see how vastly different some
of the results were and then also how
different the incubation times were so
for example rapid easton mold on petri
film they recommend you know 48 hours
but between the 48 hour and the 72 hour
mark we saw the yeast and mold on those
plates almost double
um so if you have a lab that's you know
going by the manufacturer recommendation
and only incubating for 48 hours they
could be severely under quantifying
yeast and mold um in those samples and
so because of that we established true
incubation times for each of the
different plates we're utilizing um so
that we knew kind of looking at it how
long did it need to incubate and we did
that by we started viewing the plates at
48 hours and we viewed the plates at 48
hours 72 hours 96 hours and 120 hours
and we've looked at the change and so
the true incubation time was defined as
the point in time where no new colonies
appeared and instead the colonies just
grew in size and so we were able to map
that out and really determine okay when
do you need to incubate this too to
really let all of the yeast and mold
grow
interesting
and so
the ultimate result that you got like
when you're comparing to
um other methods did they all arrive at
the same
you know number or was it sort of all
across the board it was all across the
board um and the other thing is even in
plating we saw a lot of suppression
occurring so your lower dilutions you
know the standard protocol in plating is
to play it at three dilutions so you
know you played at a 100 x you played it
a 1000 x and you played it a 10 000 x um
but what we saw was if you took the
average of those three results which is
kind of the standard for this type of
methodology that 100x was experiencing
suppression and therefore driving the
overall result down thus skewing those
results low
so when in fact a product may
of failed had you factored in the 1000x
and the 10000x when you factored in that
1000x it drove the average down enough
that the product passed
interesting
no and that's interesting when you were
talking about sampling and there was a
really good point
what about sub sampling from that
because you're talking about taking like
a smaller volume out of that original um
sample prep right and putting that onto
the plate so i mean you could
potentially be missing other microbes
that don't get plated correct
right and the other thing being is that
you know
if you aren't able to ensure it mixed
well how do you know that you got a good
amount of you know
whatever those microbes are versus just
your media so versus just your tsb for
example how do you know you mixed it
well and that's where you know i think
pcr
has the benefit over plating is because
you are able to ensure
the process worked and with plating
there is no internal control
right and the other thing too as you
pointed out in your results here is that
you know plating it really relies on
this growth right where you know
depending on how long you let it go um
you're going to get a different number
whereas with pcr it is
i mean it is a snapshot of what is in
there at this moment like if you i mean
if you kept the isolated dna for another
you know week or so you wouldn't see as
drastic a a difference in results right
right and so that's that's kind of the
battle um
of plating versus pcr and you know the
other
comments that people will sometimes make
is well pcr doesn't tell you if the dna
is dead or alive so by running pcr
you're getting everything that's present
you're not just getting the things that
are alive and harmful but
the you know caveat to that in the
conversation that needs to be had
regarding that is that if that dna is
present that indicates it was alive at
some point and so if you have aspergilis
for example that you know is now dead
but was once alive it could have created
mycotoxins and then now you have a whole
nother contaminant you're fighting um
and so that's that's a place too where i
think that there needs to be more
education regarding the microbes and how
microbes work um because i don't i don't
think that people always realize that
that like dead versus alive shouldn't
matter because if it was there it could
have caused other problems
yeah that's a great point and the other
thing too that that we run into all the
time is is comparing qpcr results to
plating results and you know how come
they don't match up in certain
situations but it sounds like i mean
looking at your results plating doesn't
even agree with plating
right and that's kind of where i think
the more research needs to be done is
you know i think everybody kind of dove
into cannabis testing head first
and i don't
necessarily know if the knowledge in the
research um was deep enough for a head
first jump um the waters may have been a
little too shallow and so that may be
causing a lot of these problems and
that's why you know my study the purpose
of this was to get people talking about
total yeast and mold more let's get
people having these conversations let's
get people doing more research let's see
if we can involve universities who have
the time and the money and the you know
amount of lab techs that are needed to
do these types of studies so we can
really figure out if total yeast and
mold is going to continue being a
requirement in cannabis what is the best
method and how do we know that's the
best method
yeah right because there needs to be
some sort of
some sort of truth here right we're
getting a whole lot of different answers
and
um yeah we need we need to figure out
which ones which one's correct and
calibrate to that
right and and that's really where those
questions arose during our investigation
you know we found a standard reference
material from an iso accredited provider
and when looking at that reference
material we noticed that it had two
drastically different results the values
were 152 000 cf per gram compared to
423 000 cfu per gram and you know those
are concerningly different numbers and
as we did more reading we noticed there
was a footer and that footer said that
one was plated with petri film and the
other was plated with sabdex agar and so
the question is you know you're looking
at a result that's three times higher
than the other
which which is correct and so you notice
that labs i think most labs probably go
about using the petri film um rapid
yeast and mold plates they're really
easy to work with they're quick
they
tell you you only need to incubate for
48 hours and so for labs who are trying
to meet these quick turnaround times
that's going to be what they're using
but if that is in fact leading to a
result that's three times lower than
another culture-based media
is that really a valid method
right no and that brandon brings up
another point too is that if you have
different labs doing different methods
and one's using a method that's giving
lower results then we we get into this
issue of lab shopping correct
correct and so people
people you know it puts labs in an
uncomfortable position because clients
come and they're like well this lab
obtained this result why aren't you
obtaining this result and then like well
we're going to take our business
somewhere where we can get a lower
result and i think that that's why
standards in general are so important um
but especially with things where we're
seeing such vastly different results you
know with analytical chemistry you know
chemistry is one thing it's like there's
a known amount of that thing and
everybody should be able to obtain the
same number but microbes and
microbiology is so vastly different um
it depends on you know how they
incubated it did it get incubated at the
right temperature did it you know get
checked on at the right time did the
dilution get done correctly there's so
many different factors that can change
the result
and from seeing this it seems like
all kind of standard reference materials
that are created
for micro seem to just kind of be
consensus basis so it's run multiple
times by multiple different people and
whatever the average they obtain is is
that you know certified value and so
because of that you run into issues
because if they're using different
methods they're getting very different
results
interesting interesting
um so we talked a little bit about how
how qpcr performed and how it how it
compared to some of the plating results
but i'm curious too
so you talked about how
you know even some methods when you did
different dilutions or you did it in
triplicate that those results didn't um
didn't really line up how consistent was
the qpcr results when you did that
though because it's not having to deal
with the the issue of growth and things
like that
yeah we and you know
this is one of the other struggles we
kind of faced and we worked with
medicinal genomics quite a bit on this
is we were having some lack of
reproducibility there as well um with
dilutions and that's really what led us
to that bigger dilution up front is
because of those issues um and then when
you're looking at a log scale you have
to realize that when you're performing
that conversion calculation from
qc or cq value to cfu per gram you it is
a logarithmic kind of formula so that
result the larger dilution you do is
going to start to over quantify and so
that's really the big thing we saw is if
you do too big of a dilution in qpcr
you're going to over quantify
drastically because you're still going
to get that dna but it's not the
logarithmic scale is not going to be
able to account for how large of a
dilution you did
got it yeah and it's a great point you
talked about that that one to 20
dilution and we did just recently
publish an updated protocol for tym
using that very same uh dilution so
thank you for your help on that
um all right so i guess kind of wrapping
up here i'm curious what was sort of the
most surprising thing you learned during
this whole exercise
um i would say that we're not a hundred
percent sure that really
yeast and mold is figured out anywhere
in cannabis um so
we're just not confident that you know
it is a good test for cannabis material
just because of the lack of
homogenization in cannabis because of
the complexity of cannabis you know and
is it really providing what consumers
need to know that they're safe um if
you're not looking at some of these
other microbes such as powdery mildew or
you know fusarium species or penicillium
species and those don't grow well on
plates or those aren't identified even
in qpcr you're running into are patients
truly safe with total yeast and mold
testing or do we need more pathogenic
testing
and after this study i am definitely
leaning on the side of you know we need
more pathogenic testing i think total
yeast and mold testing is a great
representation for you know the grower
or the producer of how clean their
process is but i don't think it's a good
indication of how safe the product is
yeah yeah that's no that's an important
distinction it's something we
i think we agree with you as well um you
know total yeast and mold it's sort of a
a big thing to take on there to to
really
put a stake in the ground and say this
is the total amount i mean that's that's
very difficult to do yes there's lots of
species there's lots of species of mold
and yeast and you you just you don't
know you can't determine if it's all
growing on the plates
we did some consultations with some
microbiologists
and one of them actually told us that in
culture even in culture-based media
you're only going to see about fourth of
what a sample truly has
and so that's kind of crazy to think
about as well because you're facing you
know viable versus culturable
yeah no and that's a good point too
because i think i did see in your
article that you mentioned testing
irradiated products um did you find
anything interesting there
yeah so with irradiated products we
almost always never see qpcr hits or if
they are they're very very low um with
plating we saw kind of the same thing
but there was some weird reaction that
was going on especially on the petri
film and it was changing the color of
the plate so the entire plate changed to
a color that would indicate a yeast in
mold so on petri film for example you're
looking at you know you're looking for
those blue colonies um and the whole
plate would turn blue and it's like okay
wait what's what's happening here what's
what's going on um is this
a full plate of colonies is it like
blown out or what's happening um so we
did lots of dilutions and we did see as
we diluted things out those plates
turned less blue so i do think that that
radiation may have played a factor into
some sort of reaction happening on those
plates
yeah that it created some sort of
some sort of chemical reaction that just
you know turned everything blue yeah
we're we're really not sure um i think
that's another thing that needs to be
further investigated you know there's
some research that indicates that
radiation just knocks down the cells
versus fully destroying them and so if
that's the case you know if you grow
these things for even longer than 120
hours are you eventually going to start
seeing growth on them is it is that the
case and so i again
total yeast and mold needs a lot more
research done before anyone makes any
conclusive decisions about it
excellent all right so
i think i think you already said this
but i'll give it i'll give you another
opportunity to say it so so based on the
results of your your um investigation
here what what would you recommend would
be the best course for testing to to
make sure that patients are safe from
any uh pathogenic yeast and mold
i think number one more research needs
to be done
more
people need to participate in studies
and we need to do investigations and pt
providers and reference material
providers we need to work together to
try to figure out how to get a good true
representative sample that could be
distributed and tested by multiple
different you know laboratories and by
multiple different methods to see what
kind of lines up where
and then also
i personally believe that maybe moving
away from total yeast and mold in
cannabis is is the right decision and
adding some additional species i know we
would be you know happy to test things
like powdery mildew and frucerium and
penicillium species
versus testing that total yeast and mold
because you know in cannabis powdery
mildew is something is very very very
very common and it's not something that
grows well and it's also something that
if you run a standard total yeast and
mold panel using qpcr you're not going
to identify either
right right and you know it's a good
point you make like is totally some mold
a good test for cannabis is it used in
other testing food testing things like
that
it is but surprisingly in food testing
um we kind of did some looking into usp
61 versus usp 62 i mean we did see that
in food testing it's more of along the
lines of gauging how clean the process
was versus gauging if the process you
know is safe um in lettuce i can
guarantee you your lettuce probably has
a lot more total yeast and mold on it
than what you're seeing in your cannabis
because the testing that they're
performing is mostly for you know
salmonella sugar toxin e coli those
pathogenic species that are dangerous
versus those total yeast and mold you're
you're growing lettuce in the ground the
lettuce you grow on the ground is gonna
have some yeast and mold on it
especially if you're growing it in a
humid environment
right yeah and one of the
one of the examples we always bring up
too is that you know sometimes you get
strawberries from the grocery store and
a day later you open up the fridge and
they have fuzz all over them um
so
they're not completely clean either
correct yeah and i think it that also
comes down to education like you know
people
whether it's been you know legally or
not have been using cannabis for quite
some time and
years before testing was even a thing
even out in some states that testing
wasn't originally required the rules on
testing weren't developed until after a
program was started up and so in those
instances
things weren't being tested people were
you know using product without being
concerned but now that testing's
required people are more and more
concerned but i think ultimately you
know yeast and mold could even be visual
like
does the bud have
mold on it if it does
don't smoke it right
and i think that's that's also something
that where education needs to be added
is like
visually inspecting something and really
determining like you said if your
strawberries that you open from your
fridge have fuzz on them you're you're
not gonna eat them um so the same kind
of goes with your cannabis products
right a little common sense goes a long
way
all right so winding down here jenny i
did want to give you an opportunity um
before i let you go to plug any website
social media or any additional resources
that you think would be helpful for the
listeners to to learn more about what we
talked about today
yeah i think you know analytical
cannabis is a great resource uh they're
a provider who does a lot of
publications on cannabis testing as well
as our website moderncanna.com
we've got lots of information as well
kind of on different blogs on testing
and things like that
and to also be on the lookout for more
presentations from our lab um we're
doing a lot more research and
development now um and we're going to be
participating in a lot more uh kind of
presentations and conferences that are
mostly focused on standardization in
general so not just yeast and mold but
across the industry
all right excellent we'll be on the
lookout for that we'll have to have you
back on uh to talk about something else
and hopefully we'll see you out at
canmed as well
yes that would be great
all right thanks again janie
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
jenny curry check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode's sponsor modern canada
labs
our next episode will drop august 3rd
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime sign up for email alerts
follow us on social media and subscribe
to the can med coffee talk podcast so
you can be among the first to know all
the details around our canmed 23 event
alright and that's it from us
stay safe stay healthy and please come
back for the next episode of canmed
coffee talk
[Music]
you