hi everyone my name is jaime brambila
i'm the co-founder of grace health and
wellness my other co-founder is my wife
nicole
and she is the subject of the case study
that we're going to be presenting today
and my wife nicole is right here
joining us today
so
the the title of the case study
presentation
that i'm making is metastatic breast
cancer and remission following standard
cancer treatments
and adjunctive medical cannabis in
psychedelics
so in august of 2018 nicole was
diagnosed with stage four de novo
metastatic breast cancer
which was an er positive pr negative hr2
positive broncho-negative
ductal carcinoma
that it's a
a mouthful right there
so it included
metastases of the bone liver and
lymph nodes
when we first spoke to her oncologist
at the clinic at memorial sloan
kettering
her prognosis was less than favorable
they explained that she had to go
through
many rounds of chemo radiation
and
perhaps uh well not perhaps a life
life that would be
uh filled with uh
therapy for the rest of her life
so here we can see the scans uh the the
pet ct scans of what she was initially
diagnosed
the
i don't know if you can see my cursor
there but
so if you see the the slide on the left
hand side that's the initial mass right
there that's the breast mass and then on
the left hand side we see that this is
these are metastases of the pelvic area
so this is when she was first diagnosed
she took uh standard therapies in
combination with the with the cannabis
and psilocybin and so the chemo and
targeted therapy regimen that she
underwent
was a combination of taxi tear
progenitor and herceptin and in the
oncology world they call this
well they they studied this through the
cleopatra study
so what we know from that study is that
37 of patients are alive at eight years
of age when a patient becomes
metastatic their life span is
dramatically decreased
you know some statistics show that at
best
in the best case scenario
patients get to live up to 10 years if
the treatments are successful
it's a life of constantly changing
treatment because
the cancer becomes resistant to the
therapies and so oncologists have to
constantly switch the therapies so only
16 of patients
with this diagnosis and with this type
of protocol
experience no evidence of disease and
that's very important because patients
that do experience no evidence of
disease that's an indicator of how
how prolonged their lifespan can be
afterwards
in addition to this
we did do a ketogenic diet because
we had the understanding that
cannabinoids are lipid molecules and so
if we
optimize the lipid metabolism there's a
better chance of absorption
we also included supplements borage oil
omega oils all precursors for
endocannabinoids
one thing that i want to point out here
is the pea well let me go back
so the pea is an important
supplement because that's an
endocannabinoid mediator and so
there's there's limited studies on how
this helps absorb cannabinoids but we
believe that it potentiates the effect
on the absorption rate of cannabinoids
so
obviously we knew um when nicole was
diagnosed that cannabis would hold some
sort of answer for her we didn't know
what that answer would be
at best
we thought that it could help with her
standard therapies
because standard therapies have very
very harsh side effects that regular
pharmaceuticals are not able to control
so you have
patients that have severe vomiting
severe anxiety
severe pain
and the conventional tools that
oncologists have are not that effective
even though they want to convince us of
that
cbd really offers
a much better response to mitigate those
side effects so
this was the the protocol that we
figured out for nicole
and if you see this is the
sorry about that
this is the collective uh result of all
the certificate of analysis that we did
on seven different extracts
those range from high cbd cultivars to
high thc cultivars some one to one
and you know you'll see that she was
taking some pretty heavy doses of thc
over here
obviously we titrated slowly
to
desensitize her to the motor impairing
effects that cannabinoids have and we
can
thank our mentor dr dustin sulak for
providing that protocol
so we
you know
one thing that i want to point out with
this is that
if patients are seeking to use cannabis
in their cancer treatments if you see
the amounts that nicole was taking you
can't just go buy this in at a
dispensary
so in order for us to create these
medicines and make sure that they were
the highest quality
first of all we had to build the lab we
had to
understand how to extract using
sophisticated
[Music]
methods
to really
extract the right therapeutic compounds
without compromising the acid the
acidity in the compounds
uh and then we had to seek
knowledge from practitioners that have
many years of experience to figure out
how to effectively dose these
formulations
so
very important to take note because
one of the points that i want to make
here today is that
even though we're going to go through
all this beautiful wonderful information
we don't have this available in the
clinics even though we really should
so cannabinoids have
many different mechanisms of action
to turn off a cancer cell
and so the chart that you guys see over
here is just a summary of all these
mechanisms that take place
when cannabinoids
get to the cancer cell
and
exercise that anti-neoplastic effect so
we know that cannabinoids are amongst
the most potent adaptogens uh in nature
uh endocannab so
when we take phytocannabinoids
we strengthen our endocannabinoid tone
which produces homeostasis across
all of our physiology
so these compounds
have been found in preclinical studies
to work synergistically with
specifically with her two targeted
therapies
we know that independently cannabinoids
can turn off erbb2 driven
breast cancer cells which are her2
positive breast cancer cells
and then
obviously we know that cannabinoids have
very very strong palliative effects so
that we can mitigate those side effects
from standard therapies
in addition to this i'm just going to go
through
some of the main mechanisms of action so
cannabinoids have been found to inhibit
akt mtor axis
this is a very important
crop well this is an important target in
cancer drug development
because it induces apoptosis when it's
inhibited
so
we
cancer drug developers have been trying
to figure out how to turn off this
pathway and have not been able to do it
effectively without harsh side effects
because of what it does to help healthy
cells
in addition to to turning off uh akita
mtor
uh
so uh cannabinoids also activate mitogen
activated protein kinase uh so map k
recep signaling pathways are involved in
uh proliferation differentiation
and invasion of cancer
and
also we know that
so
now we have two main targets that
cannabinoids
can effectively bind to and and can turn
off a cancels off through so we also
have uh nuclear factor kappa beta
this is a very important uh
target in
cancer
development because
this uh this allows the epithelial to
mesenchilial transition oh so for those
that are not familiar with all these uh
terms basically that's
when a cancer cell
becomes from
turns from an epithelial cell to a cell
that can actually move throughout the
body and can attach so that it becomes
invasive
so
cbd provide promotes dna binding of nfkb
nuclear factory kappa
uh
and this has been found in glioblastoma
multiform uh so glioblastoma cells um
glioblastoma cancer stem cells actually
are very very hard to target um
we have some targeted therapies out
there that you know
well i guess i'm not an oncologist to
say that they're effective or not but
the
the success rate with those targeted
therapies is not very high
cannabinoids can effectively uh target
this and can halt the dna transcription
of cancer cells
so another another very important
target
are p par receptors and these are
nuclear factor receptors
in particular p part gamma is very
important uh to our metabolism because
that's the factor
that
is in charge of differentiating adipose
tissue
so we know that drug developers are
targeting these
these nuclear receptors because they're
finding out that
if they influence these receptors
cancer cells are being turned off
through different uh different different
targets that create
apoptosis so
when
cannabinoids bind to these receptors
these are these are activated
and they have been found to create
what's called lipoaptosis so there's a
there's a buildup of
lipoproteins inside the cell
which creates the the apoptosis
and cannabinoids are able to stimulate
this as well
so
through through the hallmarks of cancer
we have
cell differentiation and progression
then we have uh
angiogenesis which is when a tumor
becomes uh vascularized so
tumor sends the signal to the brain then
it needs
blood vessels to feed off of
that happens through the
creation of hyph1
and so
cannabinoids have been found to inhibit
heph1
which prevents
angiogenesis
and lab studies
and
we have the last hallmark of of cancer
which is metastases once the cancer
becomes invasive and it attaches to
another area of the body it starts to
build another tumor mass
another very very
important gene target in that process is
called id1 and cannabinoids
have been found to block
id1
so in addition to cannabis we also used
psilocybin therapy and initially when we
uh knew uh that south side was going to
work
we didn't know that it had
immunomodulatory properties we were just
using it because we wanted to mitigate
the the depression that a patient goes
through when they're going through
cancer treatments and when they're
diagnosed with the terminally
with the terminal cancer diagnosis
so
we
selected three types of strains
salicylic galindori simon tampanesis and
golden teacher all of them were grown by
me
so we did a large dose
sessions
and what i did for nicole was i steeped
the mushrooms stems caps and truffles in
boiling water to separate all the
therapeutic compounds from the mushroom
fibers
the setting that we used was in a
safe harmonious environment with dim
lights minimal sound there was a mask to
do a mask a place in our eyes to direct
the the
the experience inward
because that's where we find that the
emotional release happens
uh there was a guide present to make
sure that she was safe throughout the
the session
and then after the day after uh there
was a reintegration
counseling session that takes place and
this is so that the patient can identify
the emotional release that happens uh
during the session
so she was dosed
uh four grams in each session one took
place in november of 2018 the other one
in january of 2018 and then she also did
instrument in micro dosing
so
psychedelics tryptamines in particular
also offer
potentially anti-cancer mechanisms of
action
so we know that
psychedelics stimulate
5-ht receptors
when 5-ht receptors are activated
5-ht2a in particular which is the
psychedelic receptor these create
heterodimerization basically what that
means is that it's crosstalk between
receptors
when the serotonin receptors activate
it crop it cross talks with uh with the
map k receptors ah
and it activates
uh it activates a downstream signaling
cascade
which eventually uh inhibits pa three
akt pathways so
also
they
these compounds influence nuclear factor
kappa beta and if you notice i'm talking
about the same
targets that cannabinoids can influence
so there's a theory that
using both compounds we can potentiate
the effect and that would be something
very important to research
in the clinic
also
we know that psilocybin inhibits
hyph1 which is that factor that i was
explaining
is crucial in angiogenesis
so what were the results of nicole's
treatment so if you see the slides
on the left hand side
you see the initial slides
five months after treatment
only three chemo rounds applied
they found that nicole had no evidence
of disease
and
that was a miracle that we experienced
um we didn't know that this could happen
and we didn't know if the cannabis that
we were using was going to be effective
we didn't know
how the psychedelics were going to
influence her her health
but this is what
we received
so
[Music]
how did we how do we prepare these uh
medicines uh so that we can have
pharmaceutical grade cannabis well
it's an intricate process
at the crux of this we have the issue of
sustainable reproducibility
the chemotype expression as probably the
presenters before me explained is very
hard to achieve
because of the heterogeneity of cannabis
and how it produces that chemotype
expression so
in order to pull this off we need some
sort of
genetic sequencing
to lock that genetic profile we need
controlled environment so that the
plants only produce those
chemotypes with
the
environmental setting that that is
controlled to so that it could produce
that
we
had to use a standardized
extraction method so we used uh
cryogenically treated uh ethanol
extractions
and we
prefer that because it's been
established that it's a it's a reliable
method
so that you can extract the acidic
compounds without compromising them so
we extracted very very low temperatures
negative 60 celsius actually
so
a german pharmacopiac has identified
this method as the method of choice for
cannabis extractions
and
handling the acidic compounds um becomes
very critical because they're very very
sensitive so any temperature change
um you know even throughout mental
metabolization we don't know what
happens to those compounds getting to
the
to the cancer site
to minimize any margin of error we had
to
enlist the the help of very
knowledgeable scientists that are that
were able to
produce mass spectrometry analysis on
our extracts so we know 100 of the
content in our chemotype
expression
so why whole plant uh
and not isolated cannabinoids well
we know that uh
whole plant extracts create um well we
have the theory that it creates the
encharge effect
uh most studies have been done with
isolated cannabinoids a
study at a technion
showed that pure chichi did not produce
the same effects as whole plant extracts
we have a paper that came out of
guzman's group in spain
that showed efficacy between
isolated cannabinoids and whole plant
extractions and in particular
whole plant extractions were effective
at turning off luminal beam or er
positive pr
negative hr2
cancer cells and triple negative which
is triple negative is
still remains the most difficult to
treat
breast cancer
so for patients suffering with these
diagnosis this becomes very critical for
them
so
essentially what we're
advocating for is so that these
compounds become part of the
armamentarium to treat breast cancers
so
what what can we what can we draw from
understanding all this knowledge well we
know that
if this were was to get into the clinics
it would do
a world of good for cancer patients
suffering through this
we know that
late stage oncology treatments are
limited we know that patients create
resistance and oncologists have to
constantly try
to change therapies
so we have increased number of people
that understand these statistics and are
opting to
include cannabis and silocybin in their
and their treatment regimens
and recent systematic reviews have
validated that we have tons of
preclinical evidence that cannabinoids
can produce these anti-neoplastic
effects
but yet we don't have
relevant research
we know that there is a lot of real
world evidence out there and we see
physicians and scientists that
understand this effect
trying to get this published into the
literature so that they can show
physicians that this is real medicine
you know we're not pulling the wool over
anybody's eyes
and
if we can just get rid of that stigma
that people have with cannabis this
could really be helpful for people
so i want to just give some examples of
the real world evidence that's published
in the literature
uh here we see the first pilot study
that was uh done in in spain
with uh
with patients that had
terminal glioblastoma multiforme
uh we had very very promising data from
that
clinical trial
we see that there are other case studies
that are being published individual case
studies that of patients that are
experiencing this
taking cannabinoids
so we have
small biotechs all over the world that
are trying to figure this out and figure
out how to take these compounds through
the drug approval process here is an
example of a company out of israel
that claims to have produced
a formulation
a cannabis formulation in combination
with mushrooms that is effective at
treating breast cancer
and
where
are we and how do we fit into everything
that i just explained well
you know as i explained before
receiving this
gift
that we regard as a miracle is a
powerful thing to
to absorb
and we can't really help to think that
it was for a very important reason
and that reason is to figure out how to
get this into the clinics how to really
deliver this into patients hands
[Applause]
and you know i really just want to make
a note of this we really enjoy the
benefits of legalization and that's
great that we have dispensaries in our
locality but
true legalization true access is an
illusion because it's limited by the
budget that people have to buy these
medicines in a dispensary and if you
have walked into a dispensary this has
can become very very expensive very
quickly
the if we were to buy these medications
in the dispensary these medicines
we would be spending about fifteen
thousand dollars every month
which for a regular person how can you
ask them to make this expense to save
their life that's it's impossible
so what we've done is we've reached out
to
people that really identify with what
we're trying to do a group of
researchers from imperial college of
london
researchers from the university of
connecticut
and we have put together a clinical
pipeline so that we can test our
proprietary extracts
and in vitro models so that we can
screen for efficacy of the anti-cancer
effect that we're seeing in real world
evidence
we are
going to start our pre-clinical studies
sometime in october november
we hope to come back next year to give
you the results of those studies
uh and
so we we
encourage everybody to
look into this really
my wife nicole's testimony
that
this medicine is a powerful medicine
and she's just going to come upstage
really quick
and just deliver a message for you guys
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you um i'm really bad at this so
please be patient
um
what i just wanted to also add uh to
what jaime has been explaining um is the
following
uh before i begin jaime and i want to
thank the many pioneers
who began this revolution
and who started before i was
even a blip on the radar screen
um if it weren't for all of you
uh none of us would be here uh you are
the heroes who fought for this
miraculous plant who saved so many
we're grateful for your advocacy
and are blessed to be a part of the
revolution in medicine that's occurring
cannabis saved my life it's that simple
in 2018 when i was diagnosed
when i was told i was probably going to
die
pretty soon
the first thought that entered my mind
was what am i going to tell my mother
that was the first
and then the second was damn i certainly
don't have enough money to buy the
ferrari i wanted
so we're going to have to work on that
um
and uh
i was afraid of everything that was
about to occur
um i was a high school english teacher
and uh i was the one who was telling my
students
you know be careful what you're doing
cannabis is not
maybe the greatest thing especially
since you're not coming to class
and that's because of the stigma which
is the really unfortunate part so this
has been a fantastic lesson
because of the negative connotations
with which i was
indoctrinated regarding cannabis
my knowledge as the benefits were
totally unwarranted
untrue and ridiculous
when my treatment began i was ready and
i had a cannabis arsenal behind me
um and of course a husband who was
willing to sacrifice everything to save
my life and that was pretty cool
i was able to sleep
i was able to eat
and i was able to function even after
eight hour spinal surgery as a result of
the cancer eating away at my four five
and six vertebrae
doctors told me that i wasn't going to
be able to move for probably about three
months after about a month and a half i
was up out working driving without a
problem
and
there are minimal side effects
minimal
and
what's very interesting is
most of the medications as jaime was
explaining
are so incredibly debilitating
that the only thing you want to do is
crawl up into a hole
and die
and sometimes it's the medications that
make it worse than the actual cancer
and that needs to change
dramatically
because there is absolutely no reason
for suffering at this point with what we
know
so my question to all of you all right
how many of you have been affected in
some way by cancer
family members friends
yourselves
okay
how many of you
have been
with those people while they're
recovering from chemo from radiation
from just the depths of hell with what
those medications do
and at this point in time if we have
that knowledge
how dare us
not alleviate that suffering for
everybody else
so for this i don't want this to be in
vain
we want to pay this forward and stop the
suffering and that is what is at the
root and the crux of everything that we
do and that's why we're here today
so i thank you for your support
and i thank you for the research and for
everything that you're doing
because this this is the change we're
making history
this is where it starts
so thank you
[Applause]
thank you everybody
[Music]