hello thank you for the invitation it's
my pleasure to be here today I'm going
to talk about recent advances in
cannabinoid infighter cannabinoid and
endocannabinoid research I'm a scientist
I work with professor of human shulam so
this work this is the recent work that
has been done in our lab in
collaboration with other labs over the
last few decades research on
cannabinoids has gone through several
distinct phases
phyto cannabinoids endocannabinoids and
endocannabinoid like research and
thousands of publications have been
published on cannabinoids and some of
them are already in use as therapeutic
agents phyto cannabinoids research I'm
going to cover nausea anxiety and
depression cannabis sativa
it contains money bioactive compounds
and the most representatives are
cannabinoids flavonoids and depends and
among the cannabinoids we have the tetra
hydro we have the tetrahydrocannabinol
THC which is responsible for the
cannabis psychoactive effects and other
main cannabinoids include the
tetrahydrocannabinol ik acid can have
been all Canobie they all and kind of
dialect acid now cannabinoids they are
biosynthesized
in the in their acid form in the plant
tissue and kind of acrylic acid is the
main bio synthetic precursor of the
acids of CBD THC and cannibal
and these can generate their
decarboxylated counterparts under the
action of heat or light cbda will give
CBD THC air will give THC cannabic
Romanick acid will give connect remain
and kind of acrylic acid will
if can a bigger order now
cannabidiol acid which is the main major
constituent of cannabis sativa was first
isolated in 1955 and its structure was
elucidated in 1965 it has been shown to
inhibit breast cancer cell migration and
to have anti nausea and anti-anxiety
effects now the stability of this
compound weakens the case of developing
it as a medicine and therefore we
decided to compare it with its methyl
ester since the deep sorry okay
this deeper box elation of the acids it
proceeds through the formation of the
carboxyl anion and this is not readily
formed in the methyl ester and indeed we
found that the CBD methyl ester is
stable under different conditions up to
six months now in collaboration with
Professor Roger Parthians in the paper
and knowing that the endocannabinoid
system plays a major role in the
regulation of nausea and anxiety we we
were able to see that the CBD metal
ester was much more potent than the CBD
a in enhancing the serotonin 1a receptor
activation and therefore it was much
more effective in reducing the acute
nausea and anticipatory nausea induced
behavior in the rod capping model also
CBD a metal ester proved to be an
anti-anxiety compound
in a model of stress-induced angiogenic
responding we were able to see that when
the rat they received a kind of stress
it is the food shock stress and 24 hours
later they were given fatal or CBT or
CBT amet Lester and then they were
placed in the dark compartment of the
light dark box and the time that is
spent in the light box
it was trapped now if the mice spend
time in the light box then they have
they don't have they are not anxious but
if they spend time in the dark box then
they are anxious and indeed we found
that food shock greatly enhanced the
stress induced behavior responding in
the food shock stressed mice and cbda
Matty Lester it reduced this effect
meaning that the CBD emiti Lester has
anti-anxiety effects on the mice now in
order to expand the results that we got
with the CBD enmity Lester that it has
anti-anxiety effect and knowing that a
serotonin one a receptor is important
for the treatment of human depression we
were able together with Professor Aaron
Weller to see that CBD MIT Lester it
reduces the anti-depression behavior in
rats and usually the anti-depressive
like behavior the depressive like
behavior and mice are seen as increased
in mobility and decreased swimming in
the forced swim test and CBD a meta
Lester decreased the a mobility and
increased the swimming in these rats now
the endocannabinoids and endocannabinoid
like compounds research I'm going to
cover here two types of topics which are
antimicrobial potential and addiction
now after the discovery of THC in 1964
the first endogenous lipophilic molecule
that was able to activate the cb1 and
cb2 that are activated by THC was
discovered and this compound was
identified in 1992 to be an and amide
and shortly after another compound which
is important and the cannabinoid
compound was discovered which is 2r
cadonia literal to AG following that
Omega 6 other Omega 6 fatty acid
compounds that have kinetic properties
as well such as knowledge in ether
viroid amide and in her original
dopamine nada
there they were listed among the
endocannabinoid family and in the last
25 years and and amide and all of these
compounds they had key biological
activities in the central nervous system
and in the periphery now compounds that
are considered a amides of long-chain
fatty acids with amino acids all with
ethanolamines they represent a major
group of endogenous lipids and these
compounds they are found in the brain
and in the part of them in the periphery
they do not bind to the cannabinoid
receptor cb1 or CB 2 however they have a
a cannabinoid dependent activity and
therefore they are considered as parts
of the endocannabinoid family and these
compounds they have numerous
physiological functions in the mammalian
tissues for example palmitoyl
ethanol amid PA it is anti-inflammatory
aunt in
receptive neuroprotective anticonvulsant
allylic Anala mean it regulates food
intake our Daniel serine it's vasoactive
as a neuro protective as well and all in
Syrian was shown to have anti
osteoporotic effects now there is
limited information for the role of the
endocannabinoid system during infection
especially against invading bacteria and
we wanted to see the role of the
endocannabinoid system in East microbes
so together with professor Dorner
Steinberg we studied the antimicrobial
potential of endocannabinoids and
endocannabinoids like compounds now
quorum sensing is a bacterial
communication process and bacteria they
use quorum sensing in order to attach
themselves to surfaces and form
bacterial biofilms and the bacteria in
inside the bacterial biofilms
there are 10 to 1,000 times more
resistant to antibiotics than the free
planktonic bacteria and we use here the
Vibrio Harvey bacteria in order to study
the the quorum sensing and because it
emits bioluminescence as a result of as
a respond to quorum sensing stimulation
and what we saw that then i
endocannabinoid another might among
other endocannabinoids and
endocannabinoids like compounds it
inhibited the quorum sensing of the
Vibrio Harvey strains it reduced the
gene expression of the quorum sensing
pathway and it inhibited the mortality
of the Vibrio Harvey moreover another
kind of bacteria which is the
methicillin-resistant as our s it is a
kind of bacteria that is
responsible for many difficult to treat
infections in humans and this kind of
bacteria is a biofilm forming microbe
and the biofilms they are formed on the
implanted medical devices such as
catheters and on the necrotic tissues in
wounds and we were able to see as well
that an under mild and the
endocannabinoid like compound are hidden
in syrian they were those dependently
inhibited showed inhibition for the
biofilm formation they inhibited the
colony spread and they reduce the
bacterial aggregates addiction now a
publication in 2007 in science stated
that cigarette smokers with brain damage
involving the insular cortex they
display cessation of tobacco smoking
which implicates that the insula is a
region in the brain that may contribute
to nicotine addiction and therefore
together with another three groups in
Canada Richmond Virginia and Italy we
wanted to find molecules that were able
to treat nicotine addiction and we can
do this by searching for neuro chemicals
in the insular cortex of the brain that
can be altered by traumatic brain injury
and
by using lip Adamic analysis we were
able to see that by comparing traumatic
brain injury and normal brain areas the
traumatic brain injury elicited
substantial increases in the
endocannabinoid like compound allele
it's in now we wanted to see if the
exogenous allele glitzen will will alter
the withdrawal responses in the nicotine
dependent mice the mice were given
nicotine or saline for 14 days then the
nicotinic group they were given orally
seen or vehicle 15 minutes later they
were given the nicotine acetylcholine
antagonist Mika melamine and 25 minutes
later they were elevate they were
evaluated by the elevated plus maze and
physical somatic withdrawal signs now
the elevated plus maze this is a test in
order to assess the anxiety-like
behavior in mice if the mice they are
anxious as a result of withdrawal then
they will be they will not be exploring
the open arm if they are not anxious if
they are not anxious then they will be
exploring the open arm and what we saw
is that the mice the nicotine dependent
mice undergoing mekka melamine
precipitated withdrawal signs they had
reduced time exploring the open arm and
allyl glitzen actually increased the
open arm time indicating that it is
attenuating the withdrawal symptoms and
these dependent mice in addition
this compound was able to attenuate or
interfere with physical somatic
withdrawal science and these usually
they are seen as body tremors head
shakes backings curling's and etc in
addition we saw that allele it's in it
reduced the reward effect of riccati in
this was seen by conditioned place
preference test the mice exhibited to
neutral environments and these two
environments distinct environment they
are paired spatially and temporally with
unconditioned stimuli for example on
these two four and six they were given
the mice were given drug in the dark
compartment and on days three six and
seven they were given saline in the
white compartment and on day eight they
are given the freedom to explore both
compartments and the time spent in any
of these compartment is an indication of
the reinforcing effect of the
unconditioned stimuli and what we saw is
that allele glitzy and those dependently
inhibited the reward effect it inhibited
the development of the nicotine in
douche conditioned place reference
allele it seen didn't interact with CB
one or CB 2 however it inhibited far
which is the enzyme responsible for the
degradation of an and amide and it
behaved as a PPA our alpha receptor
agonist in order to see if we can do as
well the same with morpheme we could
find that allele it's in it blocked the
aversive effect of the morphine
withdrawal
and this indicated that only be seen
might have might affect or decrease the
impact of their morphine withdrawal and
this effect was reversed by cb-one
antagonist in addition there are somatic
withdrawal signs for the morphine
addiction and these were seen as
mouthing movement abdominal contractions
diarrhea and lying on belly and what we
saw is that a legally seen as well
attenuated these morphine withdrawal
nausea somatic behaviors and this effect
it was prevented by the PPA are alpha
and cb-one antagonist now all it's in it
has an amide bond which means that it
can be hydrolyzed in the body by
amylases so we thought of is there any
way of stabilizing this compound
metabolically by introducing something
to stabilize the compound and in a
similar molecule which is an and amide
the introduction of a methyl group
adjacent to the amide bond was able to
potentiate
its activity and stability of the anand
amide and therefore we prepared in the
lab methylated all include seen and
demethylated all agreed seen with the
hope that methylation will do the same
in all in a lit scene as it did in an
and amide and indeed we found that only
the monomyth really seen it produced a
larger or longer lasting interference
with the allele glitzy and precipitated
morphine withdrawal and to explain this
if allele it seen was given 10 minutes
before the naloxone then it had it
effect while it was if it was given 60
minute
before the naloxone it didn't give any
effect but the mono material it's in 10
minutes or 60 minutes if it was given
before naloxone then it gave its effect
and okay and this effect was as well
prevented by cb-one antagonist and epa
are alpha antagonist and to summarize we
can say that the CBD a metal ester is a
potential medicine for treating nausea
anxiety depression and other disorders
that are mediated by the v serotonin 1a
receptor activation however still we
need more research to be done more
models animal models and etc the
endocannabinoid and endocannabinoid like
compounds they may act as a natural line
of defense against antibiotic resistant
bacteria the endocannabinoid compound
like compound allele it's in it
interferes with a nicotine withdrawal
and with analog some precipitated
morphine withdrawal and a more stable
compound which is more material or
leaflets in it may be more stable agent
to combat the aversive effect of acute
naloxone precipitated morphine
withdrawal than all ill klitzy and
finally I would like to thank all of our
collaborators Roger twin Scotland Linda
Parker in Canada around valor and Ron
Steinberg in Israel in USA our own
liftman in Italy de marzo and thank you
for your attention
[Applause]
hello thank for the great presentation a
question about these compounds getting
into the brain if they're administered
systemically in the periphery so what
sort of evidence is there that
endocannabinoid or endocannabinoid
compounds administered in the periphery
or systemically across the blood-brain
barrier and can affect the brain well we
we did some tests and we shall we we
have showed that for example when all
ele seen is given and then it penetrates
the brain there is evidence and there
are studies but I didn't show this music
but it also worked for an and amide or
two AG administered in the periphery to
cross the blood-brain barrier yes thank
you um hi there I was wondering if you
compared when you were looking at the
binding of the methyl ester CBD a25 ht1
a if you did compare it to the neutral
form of CBD as well as CBD a or just a
CBD a actually it is it does not bind
deep to the serotonin 1 a receptor okay
yeah it is a activating it and it was
yes we compared it with CBD and CBD a
and it was more effective than both of
them oh cool thank you yeah thank you
for your overview quick question is
there any evidence for Fito cannabinoid
inhibition of your quorum sensing
bacteria biology the same way you were
talking about for the endogenous
endocannabinoids actually in a previous
paper we did
the same studies quorum sensing and
bacterial biofilm with the HQ 210 which
is the synthetic compound that binds to
both cannabinoid receptors C 1 and C B 2
and it did the same what in the
literature there is limited information
regarding this kind of studies there
there is only a certain cannabinoids
that are anti bacterial so cannabinoids
anti bacterial 210 HP 210 which binds to
cb1 and cb2 it acts actually as anti
biofilm formation and anti quorum
sensing and
our studies on the endocannabinoids this
is the only data we have yes
okay thank you
[Applause]