[Music]
so are there Regional considerations
here for for weed control in hemp yes
there are um you know some species are
not uh uniformally distributed across
the United States there are certain
geographies that have uh different
problems um I think across most of the
the midwestern uh cropping region the
amaranthus species are a problem if
you're familiar with amaranthus seed
it's it's basically they're plants in
the same genus as that food crop that
have become dominant agricultural weeds
and they've evolved resistances to
multiple herbicides that have become a
critical part of our crop production
systems so um as they evolve very
quickly we're losing some of the
herbicide tools that our Farmers have
relied upon and uh and something there's
something very special about those weeds
so those amaranthus weeds are dious
meaning that they are males and they are
females and they have to cross-pollinate
to produce seeds and those are the only
species in our system that are what we
call driver weeds that
um that are evolving herbicide
resistance so quickly so the genetic
Exchange between those plants is in a
sense driving Evolution and genetic
variation and uh and of course the the
plant that we're introducing into the
system you know this is our first dous
plant as far as I've worked with that is
a crop species now and does that bring
with it other uh
challenges well potentially right
because uh hemp is the uh it's the
original weed
right the name yeah
so uh you know we have in Illinois a
victory hemp left over from World War II
era that still grows in the ditch Banks
and roadsides around agricultural Fields
uh so it's still it still exists it
still is persistent so um that's another
uh another research question in the
fields where we're growing hemp for a
crop you know uh we're going to have to
manage those volunteers as we rotate
into other crops so how how easy is that
going to continue to be are we a are we
going to be able to continue to manage
hemp which is very susceptible right now
to the herbicides that we use so right
now yes yeah and I'm I'm glad you kind
of brought up the the ditch weed that um
is still out there is that and is that a
weed for all intents and purposes for if
you're growing hemp could that
potentially be an issue um well it
depends right if you're growing floral
uh CBD hemp then yes that is an issue
for you and your product quality um and
potentially for uh for other crops as
well but I think more importantly it's
it's um it's important to consider that
as a reservoir for very important
genetic traits that might be useful for
future Crop Production those plants have
existed for uh you know decades
successfully in these areas they are
tolerant to the environmental conditions
that they're being exposed to and to the
ecological interactions so so that
shouldn't be dismissed um I don't think
they should be devalued I think that in
the future they could have a very real
um a very a very real um contribution to
Future breeding
[Music]
programs