good afternoon everyone
i like a small intimate audience
my name is robert thomas and
i have my own consulting business and
i serve the educational leads of the
cannabis industry particularly
in the field of heavy metal
determinations
i've been in this field for almost 50
years and
about three years ago i ventured into
the cannabis industry
and it looked attractive a little
chaotic but
something that i love working in so
today
i'm going to focus on
heavy metals
in cannabis products
and what we can learn
from the pharmaceutical industry
first of all i'd like to thank the
organizers for inviting me to contribute
to this session very much appreciated
i'd also like to acknowledge the
financial support of shimaju scientific
instruments for allowing me to
participate
okay so let me dive straight in
this is a this is a rough overview of my
presentation
um
i'll start with the current status
of heavy metal regulations for cannabis
and particularly the fractured nature of
a state-based system
and then i'll give you an historical
perspective
of how the pharmaceutical and dietary
supplement industries
approach regulating elemental impurities
after using
a colorimetric precipitation test for
over 100 years
which was totally inadequate and the
process of moving from that sulfide
colorimetric test to using plasma
spectrochemistry
um and then i'll address what the
cannabis industry
can learn from
the pharmaceutical industry particularly
with the risk assessment approach that
the pharmaceutical industry took to it
to bring in meaningful elemental
impurity regulations in drug products
and substances
and then i'll get my crystal ball out
and
give you my thoughts of where i think
the cannabis industry is going
with regard to heavy metals and
elemental impurities
okay so where is cannabis legal in the
u.s today here's a map it's fairly is
fairly current
the light green states represent states
where medicinal cannabis is legal and
dark green where both medicinal and
recreation is legal
it is legal for medicinal purposes in 18
states
but the heavy metal regulations are very
fractured and very disjointed so let me
give you a brief look
a snapshot of heavy metal regulations
so the majority of the 37 states in the
u.s regulates the big four lead cadmium
arsenic and mercury
new york adds nickel chromium
copper zinc and
merlin missouri and a few other states
add chromium to the big four
michigan um also includes inorganic
arsenic and not total arsenic
but also adds chromium copper a nickel
to the big four some states require
heavy metals in the cannabis plant while
other others give different limits for
the different delivery methods which is
oral
inhalation and transdermal
some states stipulate consumption per
day
while others take into consideration the
body weight of the consumer
some states have no heavy metal limits
at all
so it begs the question what does new
york state know
that all the other states don't know
because they add an additional five
why does michigan regulate inorganic
arsenic where all the other states just
specify total arsenic so these are all
questions
which are unknown and
there's no real resolution to them but
they are just the fractured nature of
state-based systems
and the bottom line is that
we have to look at these state-based
systems
and consider whether it's worth
improving them
expanding the elemental panel that's
currently in place today
or maybe looking at speciated analysis
these are sort of questions
which need to have answers to i think
before eventually federal regulators
come along
okay this table
is a list of the nine elements that are
regulated by the states in the left-hand
column and going across from left to
right
the first three columns are usp chapter
232 pde limits for drug products chapter
limits for dietary supplements the
american herbal pharmacopoeia limits for
botanicals and herbal products and then
gone across six different states
california cobalt maryland new york
connecticut and massachusetts
a few things to point out the federal
limits are based on
micrograms per day so with most
pharmaceuticals they have a maximum
dosage or a suggested dosage per day
so the data in the first three columns
must be divided by the suggested dosage
for those particular products so for
example
if 10 gram is the maximum consumption
per day they must be divided by 10.
if you look at the state based limits
you'll find that some are in microgram
per gram some are in part per million
and some of them are in milligram
milligram per kilogram so unless you're
not little chemist and you're used to
dealing with different units
as a consumer
and other people who are working in this
field they might not have a good
understanding of how
these limits are the same or are
different
so if you look at the state-based um
limits and compare them with the federal
image just taking lead as an example
which is in the top row in red you can
see they are they are all very different
and this is fairly typical of most
states in the us so why don't we take a
look first at the federal limits and
then at a few state-based limits and
we'll try and get a better understanding
of what needs to be done
okay so the first slide uh the um the
federal limits for usp chapter 232
um for elemental impurities in drug
products and substances um
ich q 3d are similar limits ich q3d
um is a is a consortium of
farmers okay pharmaceutical
manufacturers in other parts of the
world including pharmacopeia's
from the u.s from japan and from europe
so the usp and the ich
aligned their methodology together
um during the 20 years it took to
actually bring these limits out so um a
couple of points to emphasize
the class or the category is the
toxicity classification of each of those
elements and i'll talk more about that
later
but basically
these are three they are based on three
different delivery methods or
administration methods oral parenteral
and inhalation and they are in microgram
per day so if you need to know what's
allowed in the actual product you divide
by the maximum dosage so if it's 10 10
grams for example you divide those by
10.
so i think it's important to understand
that these
it took a total of 20 years to bring
these into the public domain and i'll
talk a little bit about the process of
the pharmaceutical industry and
particularly united states pharmacopoeia
and how
how they arrived at that process
okay so this is chapter 2232 so this is
the limit for dietary supplements and
nutri nutraceuticals only
you'll find there's only four not 24.
and there's a reason behind that which
i'll explain later but what what you
might notice is that for arsenic
and mercury
they require speciated forms of the
arsenic we know that inorganic arsenic
is more toxic than organic arsenic and
because many plants and herbal
supplements
are grown from plants
the requirement here is if the total
arsenic
is above the pde limit per day you have
to speciate you have to find what is
inorganic and what is organic we know
that um
we know that pentavalent and trivalent
arsenic is extremely toxic compared to
organic arsenic the
asino sugars
and monomethyl
acetic acid
they are toxic but they're not as toxic
as inorganic arsenic
and with mercury because many
dietary supplements are made from kelp
products or fish oil
there's the likelihood of there being
high mercury in some of these products
mainly because mercury
once it gets into aquatic systems is
consumed by bottom feeders and then it
bioaccumulates up the food chain and the
predator fish have much higher mercury
levels
in them than the bottom feeders so there
is a chance in in a dietary supplement
that's made from
kelp or or a fish oil it could contain
high levels of mercury
okay so let's look at a few of the
states for comparison purposes i pick
california because we're in california i
thought it'd be a good one to start and
these are pretty straightforward they're
categorized by two different
categories
inhalable cannabis goods and all other
cannabis goods and these are in
microgram per gram and these are
actually the same as usp chapter 232
for inhalation drugs and oral drugs
based on 10 gram of consumption but i
think it's fair to say
that we have no way of really knowing in
what quantities people consume cannabis
so is 10 gram a realistic dosage i don't
know maybe it is but
you know we don't really know
how people consume cannabis and in what
quantities
and also what's unique about the
california regulations is that they
require a half a gram of sample to
digest to carry out the heavy metal
determination where most other states
don't put a stipulation on the minimum
weight
here's colorado they're a little bit
different to explain basically they're
categorized in three different substance
which is the heavy metal of concern the
acceptable limits per gram of intended
use and then the products to be tested a
few points to emphasize here
the
inhaled products
are derived from usp chapter 232
inhalation pdes
the topical or transdermal limits are
based on fda limits for cosmetics
and the oral consumption
limits are based on chapter 2232 for
dietary supplements so colorado has
taken approach of using many many
different sources
to regulate heavy metals
okay this is connecticut this is rather
unusual because you need to because you
need to know the body weight of the
consumer before you know the maximum
allowable limit
um in connecticut this is a microgram
per kilogram of body weight per day
so it's typical to use 60 to 60 to 70
kilogram
as an average body weight for a human
both male and female
but you don't know the suggested dosage
per day is you can't work out the
maximum allowable limit
in connecticut
okay this is a study that was put out by
the fda recently
the botanical review team of the office
of new drug products at the us fda
and they looked at eight different
medical cannabis programs uh state-based
medical cannabis programs and compared
them with the federal limits of usp
chapter 232
so if you look in the left hand column
you see the four heavy metals of concern
usp chapter 232 inhalation limits and
chapter 232 oral limits and going across
the table
you will see the limits for eight
different state-based systems it doesn't
tell you
what the state-based system which states
they are they just call them mcp128
but as you can see the data in red shows
inconsistency
and a higher than the federal usp
chapter 232 limits and that and that's
quite common across all the different
medical cannabis programs
and this study came to three conclusions
it said testing for these four heavy
metals in inhalation and oral drugs was
lacking in the majority of mcps it was
about 75 percent
and even when present
they were inconsistent across programs
and finally they did not always align
with usp recommendations so again this
shows
the fractured and the disjointed nature
of state-based
limits compared to federal limits for
pharmaceutical products
okay let's tell you a little bit about
the united states pharmacopoeia i've
worked very closely with the united
states pharmacopoeia
over the past 15 to 20 years
i work on the
acs committee for reagent chemicals i
lead the heavy metal
task force and
when usp was writing its methodology for
elemental impurities in pharmaceuticals
our acs committee worked very closely to
align the method we were working on for
heavy metals with the method that usp
was working on
so who are who are the usp what what is
their mission well
it's an independent non-profit and it's
not part of the government although they
do work with various government agencies
around the world and their mission is to
improve the health of people through
public standards
and these these public standards are
known as united states pharmacopoeia
national formulary or usp nf for short
and it's a book of compendium standards
for drug substances and products
and
they've been around for about 200 years
and they're recognized in about 130
countries and the fda designates the
uspnf as the official compendium of
drugs sold and marketed in the u.s
okay so how does the usp what is the usp
process to change a standard method or a
monograph
so this is a process which is a little
bit cumbersome in nature because it
revises standards through a unique
public collaborative process with
scientists in industry in academia in
standards organizations
and the acs was one of the interested
stakeholders in the way the usp would
change in their methods
so i lead the heavy metals task force at
the acs so we work very closely with
them
as we were both changing our methodology
for heavy metals i'll talk a little bit
more about the methodology in a minute
um but it had been around for what 100
years it was a colorimetric
precipitation test
which was semi-quantitative at best but
it didn't give you any indication of the
individual heavy metals
and
the usp method was described in usp
chapter 231
and in the acs
we developed it put it into a book of
reagent chemicals
and both methods were very similar
and because
acs acs grade reagent chemicals are
recommended by the united states
pharmacopoeia
in any analytical procedures we had to
make sure that our method aligned
exactly with the usp method
so that process took a number of years
it took it took a lot longer by usp but
we wanted to make sure that whatever usp
was doing
the acs method was aligned with it so on
the left hand side you see the book of
reagent chemicals it used to be a
hardback book it's now completely online
it's a database searchable database so
it's available anywhere in the world at
any time
so you can search
any monograph which is in the book
and
based on that united states
pharmacopoeia in their general notices
and requirements recommends that if any
pharmaceutical manufacturers are using
reagent chemicals for testing procedures
they must be acs grade reagent chemicals
so that's the reason we work very
closely with them
okay let me explain briefly what usp
chapter 231 is which is very similar to
the acs test
it's based on a sulfide colorimetric
precipitation test with an organosulfide
at a ph of three and when you do that
you precipitate the heavy metal it comes
down as a sulfide and it makes a very
cloudy
colloidal type suspension solution
and the our acs test was very similar to
the usp test except we use hydrogen
sulfide instead of an organosulfide
but both were semi-quantitative at best
and probably qualitative really
because you only made the comparison
against a lead standard so so no matter
how many elements you were trying to
assess in a sample you were only
comparing it against a lead standard so
clearly it had many limitations
so let's look at those limitations
this slide shows 12 different sulfide
precipitates
if you can imagine all 12 of those
elements were present in the same sample
how difficult it would be to compare
a combined precipitate against a lead
standard which is circled in red so it
was non-specific it only gave you an
approximation of what elements what
heavy metals were present in your sample
it was also it
also had a lousy detection capability
limit of quantitation about five ppm
which is totally inadequate by today's
standards it required a high sample
weight about five gram
and
the accuracy was dependent
on the experience of the analyst so
someone who'd been doing it for years
would normally get a better assessment
than someone who just started doing it
so it was very subjective so it was
clearly um a method that needed to be
changed and it was quite surprising that
it did last one over 100 years 1908 it
was developed so what is the timeline to
adopt these changes started in 1995
the usp pharmaceutical forum identified
issues with chapter 231 in 2000 an
article in the journal pharmaceutical
and biomedical analysis
investigated icpms as an alternative
technique but it wasn't for another four
years
when nancy lewin and co-workers at
bristol-myers squibb came out with a
method a study which compared icpms
against chapter 231 and so showed
serious limitations in it and then it
took another 12 years
for the usp to get their act together
through various expert committees
working groups stakeholder meetings
which the acs were involved with to
discuss this change and then in january
2018 usp came out with chapters 2 232
for our element and imperius and drugs
and chapter
233 which was the um which was the
methodology used using plasma
spectrochemistry together with
microarray digestion procedures and
comprehensive validation protocols
chapter 22 32 by the way came out a
couple of years before that so so that
took a little quicker to
that came into
uh in the public domain
a couple of years earlier
as an example of the limitations of
chapter 231 use a slide in comparing
recoveries of chapter
of usp chapter 231 method against icpms
icpms is in red chapter 231
is in green
you can see the majority of the elements
by chapter 231 are less than 50 percent
recovery and some of them are less than
10 percent recovery and mercury there
was no recovery at all
mercury is a very volatile element
unless you're very careful with sample
preparation
you can completely lose it so that just
showed the limitations of chapter 231 so
from that point on 2018 icp ms and icp
oes became the standard
method uh the standard method to use so
what they did they separated out the pd
pde limits for pharmaceuticals only they
call this chapter 232 they had a
separate chapter for dietary supplements
because because that's the way they were
regulated in other parts of the world
they call this chapter 2232
and they implemented a totally different
chapter for the analytical methodology
which included icp oes or icp ms
microwave digestion and comprehensive
validation protocols using spike
recovery procedures
so what are the potential sources of
elemental impurities in drug compounds
this is the process they went through to
find out
what were the potential sources and what
was the toxicity of the elements which
could be found somewhere in the
manufacturing process so basically they
separated that into four different
categories four different groups
elements intentionally added as a part
of the manufacturing process an example
of that would be platinum group catalyst
elements in the organic synthesis of
many drug substances or apis
also elements that are not intentionally
added and that could be something that's
in a um
that's in an excipient such as talcum
powder which is used as a tablet
compression aid and talcum powder is
basically magnesium silicate which is
dug out of the ground and we know if
anything is mined or dug out of the
ground it can potentially contain high
levels of transition and heavy metals
the third category was elemental
impurities
that can be introduced in contact with
the manufacturing equipment and examples
of that are iron chromium and nickel
from stainless steel containers and
vessels
and finally elemental impurities that
could leach out of the drug substance
from plastic containers and closure
systems we know that some plastics are
dirty than others and we know that some
glassware is dirty than others so if it
was if
if the enclosure of the packaging system
was based on plastic or glass there was
a chance of metals leaching out of that
into into the product
the bottom line was that
regulators required all pharmaceutical
manufacturers
to have a comprehensive understanding of
the manufacturing process and to find
out where the contact points for those
various metals were
and then actually
and categorize those elements by their
toxicity classification i'll explain
that in a minute
okay so toxicity classification here's
chapter 232 a little bit different this
is now microgram okay not microgram per
day but this is now microgram per gram
in the pharmaceutical product based on
10 grams of maximum
of suggested dosage per day
and in the second column you'll see
classification well every element of
those 24 elemental impurities was
classified
by the toxicity classification class 1
class 2a class 2b
and class 3.
there were a few changes recently and
the ones in red are the ones that they
changed very recently within the past 12
months and this version of chapter 232
that i downloaded still had those in red
okay so let's look at the toxicity
classification basically class one were
elements
including the classic heavy metals lead
cadmium arsenic and mercury
which are human toxicants and have no
use in the manufactured drugs whatsoever
these should be monitored at all times
and every time
class 2a elements were also toxic but
but not as toxic as class 1
but but they had a high probability of
occurrence in the drug product and
should also be evaluated at all times
and then class 2b elements with the
elements which have a reduced
probability but should only be monitored
if they were present in the
manufacturing process example of that
would be the platinum group metals using
catalysts and the organic synthesis of
many drugs and class iii elements which
have a relatively low abundance toxicity
by the oral route but but would warrant
justification for
inhalation drugs and those used for
intravenous purposes
so without his background information
this is the process that usp took
to categorize the
24 elemental impurities which are
required in all pharmaceutical products
today up to 24 um but it's based on a um
it's based on a risk assessment approach
to see what what contaminants are
present and the likelihood of them being
present in the manufacturing process so
if we if we now take a jump into
cannabis products we can see that
the first area of concern is cultivation
of course and we fully understand that
and
if the plants are grown outdoors the
soil chemistry has to be assessed and
evaluated
so it's important to do that because we
know that cannabis and hemp are hyper
accumulators
of all all contaminants in the soil
whether it's heavy metals toxic elements
you know radionuclides so
we know that after chernobyl in 1986 uh
hemp was planted to clean up the
contaminated soil in chernobyl um
so we know that through anthropogenic
activities there's been a ton of
environmental pollution over the year
from mining from metal refineries
petrochemical plants coal-fired power
plants and there's a whole slew of
elements where there's compelling
evidence in the public domain that the
cannabis and hemp plants are absorbing
those
and we know lead in particular is is is
a great concern because our dependent
our decades of using lead-based
materials included leaded gasoline let
it paint and let it water pipes we know
that saul near major highways contains
much higher levels of lead and soil away
from major highways
we know that leaded paint can be a
problem i live in a house that was built
in 1747 before we moved in we had to get
a crew in to completely remove the lead
paint from the windowsills and the paint
on the walls and it was a major major
problem but we had two young children at
the time and
it was something that we were extremely
concerned about because lead paint was
used for decades
and then lead water pipes we saw what
happened in flint michigan back a few
years ago and unless you have a clean
water supply if you're using water for
your cannabis and hemp whatever's in the
water
will
clearly is a high chance it will get
into the cannabis product
fertilizers we know that fertilizers are
made from phosphate rock phosphates
fertilizers can potentially contain high
levels of heavy metals and transition
metals so we have to be really
particular about the quality of
fertilizers and nutrients that we use
on cannabis and hemp
we know
we know that fish emulsions fish
extracts are being used nowadays as
nutrients particularly for indoor
growing and
based on the fact that we know
that fish based on bioaccumulation of
mercury if there's mercury
spewing out from say a power plant and
it ends up in an aquatic system and the
predator the large fish
will have much much higher levels of
mercury if those fish are used for fish
emulsions
um as nutrients for indoor plants
there's a good chance that that mercury
will be transferred to the to the plant
and we know it's in the public domain
the growth enhancers are being used
for example nickel salts are used to
enhance bud size
and silicates are used for shoot
strength point i'm making is that the
majority of these elements would escape
the scrutiny of state-based regulators
and
if you don't know
if it's if it's if it's present there
you're never going to find it because
most states just just regulate the big
four
if it's in new york maybe michigan and
maybe a few other states
you know you might find chromium but the
majority of these elements are not being
regulated today
so the next source is extraction process
in the manufacturing so so this is a
potential source as well if the
if the cultivation process has
has given you a plant which is
highly contaminated or slightly
contaminated
um the extraction process
is not going to remove those heavy
metals so if it's in the flower or the
biomass there's a very high chance it
will be in your extracted cannabinoid
and we know that depending on the
extraction process will dictate how much
metal is extracted and we know again
it's in the public domain that
certainly
some solvents um depending on the flows
and the pressure and the temperature
will produce a different extract that
some will be more efficient some will be
less efficient
but there has to be a balance between
efficiency of
extraction
and
and taking contaminants out of the plant
and so there's a balance to be made
there and
it's something which i think
is a potential concern going forward
because um
maybe um efficiency of
c of the cannabinoid is probably the
major factor behind extraction and maybe
the you know not so concerned about the
elemental can or any you know any
contaminants present so i think there's
there's some serious concern there um
also the
either process in a grinding equipment
again from stainless steel chromium
nickel and iron i remember a case in my
state maryland
where
a processor was using stainless steel
scissors and they were found in high
levels finding high levels of chromium
in the flower and it was coming from the
stainless steel scissors unbelievable
but it was true and also finally storage
and delivery devices um
glass dropper bottles for example if
they made a borosilicate glass
okay guaranteed
you'll be taking heavy metals out of the
surface of the glass so quartz should be
used
or you know a higher purity glass but
definitely not borosilicate
so
if there are bonds made of glass they
should be made of high purity um or at
least made of quartz and not
borosilicate inks are notorious for
being lead-based there's lots of
lead-based inks out there so an example
recently where a study was done looking
at um
extract in a in a graduated bottle and
what was happening was the extract was
dissolving the lead-based ink and ending
up in the extract and they did some
studies over time and they they ended up
with some of the samples were 30 to 50
part per million where the regulated
limit for lead in that state was 0.5
part per billion so these things
these things are not fully understood
and um
things happen and uh you know before you
know it you have a contaminated product
and of course vapenz i mean i i could
i could spend an entire talk about vape
pens but basically
um there's a lot of stuff coming in from
overseas from china in particular which
is not high quality um
they contain various metallic components
and if you're vaping at temperatures
you're going to be
you know you're going to be corroding
the inside of those components and we
know that based on elevated
aerosol vaping temperatures that you're
not only corroding the metal from the
internal components but it's existing in
the particulate form
there's been work done
which is using scanning electron
microscopy microscopy and any energy
disperse of xrf which is showing small
particles of metal
in the aerosol which correlates with
what was in the vaping device
there's been a couple of
there's been some um sort of product
recalls over the past few years um
i kind of look for them because that's
what i do um
it's my it's my thing heavy metals to
understand them and um i've counted 15
in the past 12 months i've counted 15
recalls and i'm sure there are more but
they're the only ones that are in the
public domain that i found
and there's five of them up up on the
screen there
two were in florida one was in hawaii
one in maryland one in michigan two
involved vape pens in hawaii in maryland
in michigan involved cannabis flower and
in florida it involved ex cbd extracts
and
these are all examples of
limits exceeding the state-based
regulated
maximum allowable limits for a whole
bunch of elements and in fact the one in
florida is going through litigation at
the moment so these things happen things
are getting into the public domain
um
which are
you know which are unsafe and
it's uh it's interesting to see um
whether if if the regulations were
tighter whether that would be the case
but
you know they are happening so let me
give you my final thoughts on regulating
heavy metals in cannabis consumer
products the current list of four heavy
metals is clearly inadequate absolutely
inadequate i'm not saying the 24
regulated by the pharmaceutical industry
that might be a little
um of an overkill
but i can tell you that elements
contaminants derived from the
cultivation manufacturing
storage delivery process would warrant
at least another 10 elements on top of
the big four
so i think a future list of elemental
contaminants in cannabis worthy of
consideration again i say worthy of
consideration we need to do a risk
assessment study of which ones are
actually in
in in the in the cultivation
manufacturing process um
[Music]
but
i'm i'm saying that at least
a list of 15 elements based on the big
four plus the additional elements in
maryland
um
michigan and new york plus international
six
from com
from compelling evidence in the public
domain
and the bottom line is these most of
these would escape the scrutiny of state
regulations
okay so um
the signs that the industry is moving
towards an extended panel
[Music]
i mean three examples here nist is
coming out with a certified reference
material for nist
for six 13 toxic elements in hemp this
is a certified reference material which
we which will be available this time
this year sometime i don't know exactly
know when
but interestingly enough the list is
there and includes uranium and i've seen
early nist data which shows there's
about half a ppm
in a hemp standard
i sit on an astm d37 committee we're
writing a method for icpms for cannabis
and hemp consumer products and we
include 23 elements
elemental contaminants
and finally usp has just published a
draft monograph for cbd for use as an
api so this is this is only for use as
an api in drugs like epidiolex or drugs
that are going through the approval
pipeline by the fda
and to comply with that you have to show
compliance for up to 24 elemental
contaminants so i believe the cbd market
will separate out into the really pure
stuff really clean stuff that's used as
an api for pharmaceuticals and then the
rest of the stuff which is probably you
know 95 percent at the moment will be
used for other purposes
uh so i'd like to finish with a source
of information from my talk i've written
three textbooks
in this domain on the applications and
the fundamentals of icpms first one is a
practical guide to icpms which came out
in 2015 the second one was measuring
elemental impurities in pharmaceuticals
which came out in 2018
and my final one i've written they just
came out with a paperback version of
that is measuring heavy metal
contaminants in cannabis and hemp and
that's the one in the middle they're all
available on amazon or through
my publishers
and um hot off the press i had an
article published in analytical cannabis
today it's a four-part series
on
the benefits of carrying out the
comprehensive risk assessment study
to better understand elemental
impurities in cannabis and drug products
and that will be published over the next
few weeks
with that i thank you for your time um i
think i've gone over but i think we
started late um
thanks for your time and i'll gladly um
answer any of your questions
thanks a lot for the presentation very
very nice talk i really learned a lot
from you today uh i i have uh i
basically want to ask the same question
that asked to the peer speaker who was
talking about uh pediatric use uh
i was wondering now with with the
uh
right now we have the regulation at
different stage you know many of them
focus on the back four yeah and then all
of them
are there's no difference between
uh recreational and medical cannabis now
even it's for people who are sick
i guess i'm just i just want to you know
i think your thought on
should there be a difference between the
regulation for the medical for for the
you know toxic element regulation for
medical versus uh recreational chemicals
given that you know of course we do not
right now the information is so scary we
don't really know what is out there
but
you know like for the patient
it should there be a difference and if
that should then how should we proceed
to there
yeah i mean
i would say that
i mean my state for example maryland
only okay currently only allows
medicinal cannabis use but they will
they will be approving recreational use
next year and they're concerned that
bringing in recreational use will affect
the quality and the purity of the
medicinal
drugs so
i think
you know based on the fact that i've
done a lot of work in the pharmaceutical
industry
which is highly regulated and
you know clearly the pharmaceutical
industry was very concerned
about producing products which
potentially could contain heavy metals
which they weren't even monitoring so
even though it took them 20 years
clearly they saw a need to do that but
not only a need to do it they needed to
comprehensively understand
where the contact points for the heavy
metals were in the entire manufacturing
process
and now every manufacture every
pharmaceutical manufacturer has to show
compliance for up to 24 elemental
impurities you know based on the method
of delivery so i've come from that kind
of background and i've come into the
cannabis industry and i see an industry
which is chaotic it's exciting but it's
so fractured and disjointed and
you know when you see that recreational
use cannabis has exactly the same limits
as medicinal use to me it doesn't it
doesn't make any sense
i mean for example
i i'm i'm working with a group at the
moment that's um
that they suffer from adult epilepsy and
they found
and and they found relief in vaping cbg
and um
okay they approached me because they
were concerned they read
in the open literature that these vaping
devices were
showing high levels of elemental
contaminants in the aerosol which would
not be unregulated
based on based on the metallic
components within these vaping devices
so even though
they tried conventional drugs for their
seizures
and they were found in relief in this
cbg in particular
they were extremely concerned and i'm
helping them
maybe find a source of these vaping
devices which are cleaner which are less
contaminated i mean i see that i see i
see now there being these vaping devices
you know separating up into the ones
which are used for the masses which are
coming in
in the millions from china and ones
which are going to be used for medical
purposes
you cannot use the ones coming in from
china because i've seen some i've seen
some data which is scary
and to give someone who's taking cbg for
a seizure
and
the cbg is relieving their symptoms but
they put in particulates of chromium
down their lungs i mean to me that's so
scary
you know
i'm
i guess i've been inverse immersed in
this area for the past three years and i
see the mistakes the industry is making
and i'm trying to help them get better
it's very frustrating
but working with groups like astm and
aoac i think we're making some headway
but
there's a lot of stuff going on which
needs to change
absolutely
um regarding the vaporizers i believe in
2019 there was a presentation here
where they went into a lot of detail on
the elemental testing of the vape
the vapor coming out it seemed to come
to a different conclusion i think they
said it was fairly low
so i was just curious if you had any
insights why that was different okay
you're not talking about the um the uh
the valley scare in 200 2019 with
vitamin e acetate to you
i believe they were looking at metals
the presentation here in 2019 on on no
okay so that was the valley scare where
the okay vitamin e acetate was getting
into consumers lungs
and um killed about 70 people um yeah
there's there's been a lot of work done
over the past few years in
characterizing vaping our aerosol for
elemental contaminants unfortunately
there is no standard method out there it
is a very complex analysis um you're
dealing with
you okay you're dealing with diluents
you're dealing with cannabinoids you're
dealing with hydrophobic and hydrophilic
liquids how do you
take the aerosol
and allow it to make a condensate and
take a representative part of that
condensate and introduce it into your
analytical technique which is typically
icp ms how can you be sure you're taking
a representative um
a representative sample from the tank
because at different temperatures the
elemental contaminants have different
um
have different vaporization temperatures
so based on the vaporization temperature
some of the less volatile elements you
know might not come over and some of the
more volatile elements will come over
first so how do you know what your
sampling is representative what's in the
tank it's a very complex analysis and
there's no standardized method some
states are trying to do it colorado is
leading the charge but i know they're
having some challenges and
you can't give this analysis to a
regular testing lab it's just too it's
difficult for someone
who's had years of experience in trace
element analysis um
virtually impossible
okay i'm okay i'm not critiquing
the the testing labs because there's
some really good ones out there but this
analysis is so difficult so challenging
and you have to throw in you have to you
also have to throw in a smoke machine
and how do you know
that the tough profile of a cannabis
consumer is very similar to an
e-cigarette user or a nicotine user
they're not you know they're not
different so all the work that's been
done up to now has been done on
e-cigarettes nicotine devices and all of
a sudden you're then going to a cannabis
device and a cannabis vapor has a
different profile
this
this is so complicated and so difficult
that it's i think it'll be challenging
sorry
okay thanks for your time