[Music]
all right
that uh Growers seem to struggle with
but total Easter mold is and we did say
that we were going to talk about some of
the factors that your your team
identified so let's get into that and I
think one of the major ones
um that you identified that was in this
paper was that the plant genetics
themselves uh play a huge role in the
tym levels
um I wonder if you could speak a bit to
that and is it specifically like the
physical structure of the plant in the
in the flowers that leads to that or is
there something else going on like does
it have something to do with immunity
yeah yeah so that that was a bit of a
surprise to us as well and I'm sort of
glad we really included like seven or
eight different types of genetics or
genotypes right in the study
um obviously when we're grabbing
whatever whatever we could whatever was
being grown at the time so it wasn't a
planned experiment but we did find
definite differences between the the
types of of cannabis that were being
grown primarily it's to do with the
morphology and the size of the flower
structure so the larger the the flowers
you know the bigger the the mass if you
wish or volume the higher the yeast and
mold in general plants that produce very
small buds smaller buds many of them but
smaller in size not as dense seem to
have less over over Eastern low so there
was definitely this physical uh
correlation in some cases I do think
there were chemical products chemicals
produced in the flower that would be
would be inhibiting yeast and mold now I
I say that because
some some of these flowers were the
Eastern mold was so low
that it was almost impossible to explain
just from the fact that the flowers were
small I think they were secreting some
kind of a chemical product a natural
chemical product that was it was
preventing these Eastern walls from
growing if we knew what those were boy
it would be we'd be off to a really good
start from a research perspective I mean
definitely that's something that needs
to be looked at I don't think it's
something like terpenes or or some of
these other volatiles that we know it's
definitely not THC or CBD because all of
these were producing THC CBD something
else that that perhaps isn't on the
radar yet something that other
researchers or breeders may want to look
at but certainly flower structure flower
size and the reason though the larger
flowers seem to have more yeast to mold
is the humidity the moisture in those
flowers is higher by three to four
percent in terms of relative humidity
than the outside air and their
temperature builds up in the flower it's
almost a mini it's a mini Greenhouse
sitting on a flower on a plant because
it traps the solar radiation and it
warms up the buds warm up two three
degrees higher than the environment so
that humidity and moisture the
temperature creates this little
Greenhouse that allows these yeasts and
molds to build up so one thing we asked
ourselves well if you if you circulate
the air you know you turn a fan on close
to the plants and let this air to
infiltrate through the flowers what
would happen
and boy the yeast and moles dropped by
90 percent oh wow now you can't go out
put a fan next to every plant but
certainly you increase your your air
flow your air movement the humidity
drops the temperature drops and your
flowers have way less yeast and mode
and it's not impractical in some
greenhouses you can set up eight or ten
fans blowing in a certain direction and
that will really reduce the yeast and
mold
yeah and you know I'm I and I imagine
Growers too would be encouraged to to
hear you say that there could be
something more than just the morphology
of the buds that that's contributing to
it
um because I mean because if you think
about it Growers want big dense flowers
and to have that be associated with
higher tym well that's that's not good
news at all well no certainly and so the
chemicals are discovered which they will
be actually uh that will be very very
useful because that's a natural way for
the plant to you know to protect itself
now plants don't have a an immune system
but they do secrete many many chemicals
and many of these chemicals are known to
inhibit the growth of mold and bacteria
and so on and so finding that strain or
strains would be very useful
foreign
[Music]