thank you you'll notice i'm lowering the
microphone
well we're going to go quickly through
this data um my email is there ethan
rooster comcast.net
i'll be happy to send a 2004 paper that
goes through some old data and i've just
submitted
a newer paper that reviews all this data
and more
hopefully when it's accepted it'll be
open source
in keeping with recommendations
so we're going to talk today about a
theory
i developed that i call clinical
endocannabinoid deficiency
the hypothesis was that we all have an
underlying endocannabinoid tone that
reflects the
amount of cb1 receptors and the amount
of the endocannabinoids
we have and how fast they're produced or
broken down
then the theory is that due to a genetic
condition or an acquired condition
such as a head injury that produces
migraine
like post-traumatic headaches
the endocannabinoid tone becomes
deficient
and a variety of symptoms result
um so i came up with this theory about
the year 2000 i had a couple of initial
publications and then
a larger review paper in 2004 which
you'll find here
what i'm going to focus on today from
this long list
of disorders is the top three in red
migraine fibromyalgia and irritable
bowel syndrome
now these are what are called comorbid
conditions meaning that they tend to
appear in the same individuals
they have a lot of things in common
they're all hyperalgesic states meaning
that the pain
is there even though the tissue looks
normal and it's
it's it's more than it should be
there's no characteristic tissue
pathology if you look at the tissues
under the microscope
and they're no lab tests for any of
these disorders
the headache disorders
headaches appeared in about 97 of
fibromyalgia patients when that was
examined
similarly over a third of people who had
chronic daily headache
had criteria that indicated a diagnosis
of fibromyalgia
similarly again about a third of
patients with irritable bowel had
fibromyalgia
and a third of the fibromyalgia patients
had a
irritable bowel in the olden days
these were called psychosomatic
disorders and if
a patient came in uh and had migraine
fibromyalgia an irritable bowel at the
same time
chances are that it was a woman and she
was labeled as having a semitization
disorder by a male
md anyway we all make mistakes hopefully
we learn we're going to start uh by
looking at irritable bowel syndrome
it's frequently said this is a lifelong
condition but a lot of people really
develop
it after a bad exposure like they had
oysters or something else that went bad
on them
so an episode of food poisoning or
especially after
antibiotic treatment and then it may
become a lifelong condition
despite being called functional or
assumed to be psychosomatic this is the
most frequent diagnosis in
gastroenterology practices in this
country
no physical signs are patho-mnemonic
again it's a diagnosis of exclusion you
might get a colonoscopy and a bunch of
other blood tests they all come back
negative and we call it ibs
there are formal criteria called the rum
criteria for this diagnosis
i really love this quote i was called a
disorder of unknown origin
as being treated by agents with an
unknown mechanism of
action in other words the everything in
the kitchen sink gets thrown at this
usually
with bad results it is a
visceral hypersensitivity uh
with features of gastrointestinal
allodynia means that even a little
stretch is
perceived as pain and an overabundance
thereof
this has been looked at in relation to
the endocannabinoid system
this group from australia looked at
colonic smooth muscle and circular
muscle and they showed that a nandamide
co-localized with the cholinergic
receptors that are the main propulsive
force in the colon
and there was some kind of non-cb1
mechanism
or an alternative cannabinoid mechanism
that seemed to be operative
uh they suggested the endocannabinoid
system is
functionally important in disease and
especially inflammatory states that
would include
irritable bowel syndrome
then subsequently these
this group looked at a small randomized
controlled study
52 normal patients that took 7.5
milligrams of thc
versus placebo and they were able to
show increases in colonic compliance the
stretch ability
also decreases in tone after meals
um and decreased pressure
on the colon with a trend towards
relaxing
so it shows that this does perform a
modulatory function in the gut
then at mayo clinic there were a couple
of studies where they looked at some of
the genetics
they're different forms of ibs mixed
the situations where
it's predominantly constipation and
those predominantly diarrhea
so in the variant ibs with diarrhea
which is the most common
uh they tried thc as as marinol
on the show to delay colonic transit in
subjects with this cnri
rs 806 378
ct-tt i'll let you read that next time
that particular genotype
and then the same group showed a
significant association of the same gene
with colonic transit in the patients
with ibs-d
and they said cb1 receptor-related
mechanisms modify colonic transit and
sensation
and may influence the development of
symptoms in caucasian patients with ibs
particularly ibsd so limiting the
applicability but
many of these same things would apply to
a more general population
a very interesting study last year on
nina clooney on her group in calgary
alberta
there were you may have heard recent
reports that people were surprised
that thc when used chronically led to
a lower weight so the the archetype has
been a skinny hippie it hasn't been a
fat
slacker but
in her group uh nina was able to show
uh the thc altered the microbiome
balance
we we heard a little bit before about
normal
flora in the gut on and so
uh in obese d i o mice that have this
uh mutation uh there was a change in the
firm acuities bacteroidetes ratio that
was statistically significant
basically thc prevented
weight gain despite a high fat diet
and this is very important it shows
again
this important interaction between
cannabinoids the endocannabinoid
system normal flora in the gut
and weight there was a bestseller last
year called brain maker by pearl mudder
all about probiotics and prebiotics
probiotics of course are normal bacteria
that you get in yogurt or kefir
those kinds of foods the fermented foods
but those are
fed in turn by prebiotics and
these are sources of dietary fiber from
vegetables
and going from top to bottom left to
right
we have acacia senegal gum arabic
chicory jerusalem artichokes dandelion
greens
burdock and then the the whole onion
family
and if you have one of these kinds of
problems that's a book worth reading
and these are vegetables worth eating um
they in turn i believe will positively
affect your endocannabinoid balance
shifting to fibromyalgia um
schleidol did an uncontrolled study this
was
really a strange study they had nine
fibromyalgia patients and they gave them
thc
their ethics committee wouldn't let them
use a placebo
so it was an observational study
because they were pushing the doses of
thc alone and has a lousy therapeutic
index
they had a lot of dropouts five out of
the nine
but the four subjects who completed the
study per protocol
had prominent reductions in their
perceived pain so these are fibromyalgia
patients whose
pain threshold is is diminished to begin
with and that was statistically
significant
as we see here now it's not really fair
to look at a
protocol population but um
you know this was the best we've got
considering the limitations we have on
these kinds of studies
in a study done in canada
they use nabalone so this is a
semi-synthetic
thc analog 40 patients with fibromyalgia
using one milligram bid which would be
equivalent to about 20 milligrams of thc
a day
and again you're going to have side
effects at that level
but after four weeks there were
significant improvements in pain
fibromyalgia impact questionnaire and
anxiety
so again a significant signal there
um our friend mark ware also in canada
looked again at nabalone versus
amitriptyline
a little bit lower doses at those doses
there wasn't any effect on pain in the
fibromyalgia patients
but or mood or quality of life but there
was
improvement in sleep which is one of the
cardinal symptoms of
of fibromyalgia it's a scenic unknown um
inferiorly there's a sleep disturbance
associated with it and the patient
will not get better until that's
addressed
um then another study done with cannabis
but acutely
this wasn't a long-range study this was
done in spain
28 patients with cannabis versus
controls
after two hours the visual analog scales
for these various parameters
uh were different uh to a significant
level particularly pain
stiffness enhancement of relaxation
but increase in side effects somnolence
as well unfortunately the
increase in the mental health component
of the sf-36
was also significantly higher going
along
with um psychoactive
changes in this as
we've been hearing uh very low doses are
probably what are required here and
those that
hopefully will not produce these kind of
acute side effects
now our best evidence is probably this
one
now i am a proponent of
randomized controlled trials it's the
only thing the
fda and other regulatory bodies will
accept
however this is a very interesting
survey
this came out a couple of years ago from
the national pain report
over 1300 patients with fibromyalgia
who answered this questionnaire so they
were self-selected but let's look at
this
we have three fda approved drugs
to treat fibromyalgia being duloxetine
melnacipran
those are a dual serotonin and
adrenergic
reuptake inhibitors so antidepressants
and then pregabalin and anticonvulsant
masquerading as an analgesic
if you look at the graphs this is uh the
percent
improvement you'll see that with the
three prescription drugs you don't have
a lot of green
you've got 10 or less showing
these to be very effective only
about 30 percent or less
showing them as helping a little and the
vast majority saying they don't help a
law
at all compared to cannabis where 62
percent
thought that they were very effective
and and very
much fewer thought that they were not um
so i'd call this a no contest at best
and it should indicate the future
direction of research
moving into migraine and we'll go
through this quickly
this was the thing that got me into the
study of cannabis
um uh 20 years ago now
but um i'd known for a long time that
cannabis was effective in
treatment of migraine both acutely and
chronically
but it's only been in the last decade or
so that we have some real
evidence of the relationship to the
endocannabinoid system
and most of the studies have come from
italy on this they showed an
increase in the nandamide membrane
transporter
and phi activity fob being the enzyme
that breaks down in nandamide
uh we're shown in the platelets of
female migraners
uh and compared to patients with tension
headache and controls
the levels of cb1 were equivalent in the
groups but there was an
increased degradation of anandamide by
platelets
and decreased blood levels in the female
migraners and
again those were significant
ackermann at all did a series of three
studies showing
a very important relationship of the
endocannabinoid system the migraine
they showed that anandamide reduced
dural blood vessel dilation
by calcitonin gene related peptide 30
percent
and also by these other agents it seemed
to work
presynaptically to prevent uh the cgrp
induced
nitric oxide release and smooth muscle
of the dural arteries
um it showed that they showed that
nanomine was tonically released and had
a modulatory role in the
trigeminovascular system
that's felt to be the patho
pathophysiological mechanism in migraine
in the next study they looked at
anandamide and showed that it
caused a increase in dural
vessel diameter caused by capsaicine
and that doses required were pretty high
um and we'll go on from there
similarly here they were looking at
synthetics
these are much more powerful than thc
but again there's a relationship
probably our best piece of evidence is
this one done in italy
in this study they looked at cerebral
spinal fluid did spinal taps on normal
patients and patients with migraine i
proposed this study in 2004 but didn't
feel it could be done in this country
viva italia anyway they showed this
tremendously significant difference in
the
anandamide levels being decreased in the
migrant nerves
one chance in 10 000 that this is due to
chance
and basically they said here that this
seemed to lie at the
the root of the problem in
migraine another study from italy
both 2eg and anandamide were markedly
reduced in the
platelets of micronerves as compared to
controls again
very highly statistically significant
this is from an animal model
again showing the importance of the
various
nuclei in the brain stem
then a genetic study youhosh at all
the cb1 gene cnr1 mapped to chromosome
6q1415 was linked to migraine
with haplotype typical tagging with high
significance
and they related this to other migraine
concomitants such as photophobia the
sensitivity of light
nausea and disability they also related
it to some personality traits such as
neuroticism
guilty as charged depression
and other tendencies towards drug abuse
so bad thing to have um
then another observational study this
came out of colorado just a few weeks
ago
these were patients selected to get
cannabis to treat migraine and
um two-thirds of the patients had used
cannabis
previously um but there was a very
significant decrease in attack rate from
10.4 to 4.6 attacks per month
85 percent had decreased frequency
and uh almost 40 percent um
had other benefits now obviously this is
an
uncontrolled population uh self-selected
um and no control group but it surely
indicates that the study i tried to
start 20 years ago should be done now
um i'd highly recommend this study by
john mcpartland i i think it's the
uh endocannabinoid article of the decade
[Applause]
there's john with this iheart anandamide
t-shirt was discovered in pigs
which is an odd thing to have happen in
israel but we'll let
rafi tell that story but
john reviewed the literature and showed
all these other
disorders that have been linked to
possible
endocannabinoid deficiency states
so read that one when you can well where
do we go from here
we need additional clinical studies of
irritable bowel fibromyalgia and
migraine
hopefully to look at serum or even csf
levels
it would be great if we have better
physiological scans of the brain to show
cannabinoid density or real-time
anandamide levels
i would like kevin and his crew to look
for common genetic markers of
endocannabinoid regulation and disk
control
and i think we'll have some better
answers there
additionally we need the clinical
studies hopefully within rich
designs to reduce the placebo effect
which is a huge problem in these studies
and i'll let you take a quick look at
this
quote from the original article
we've got many disorders that cannabis
treats where nothing else does
and there's a lesson there that needs to
be heated
finally let's keep in mind that
the endocannabinoid system can be
regulated a different a lot of different
ways with drugs
with herbs beyond cannabis with diet
with exercise
and hopefully this will lead to better
health for us all in the future
thank you