good morning everyone
so i'm cynthia bryant i'm the chief
business officer at demetrix
and um
really happy to be here today to talk a
little bit about what we do
and the research that we're performing
it's a little bit different than i think
a lot of the
other companies here we're not a
plant-based grower so
let me tell you first about demetrics
and then we'll get into the rest of it
so dimitrix the company was founded by a
gentleman jay kiesling he's a uc
berkeley professor
who started several companies in
biotechnology
that are dedicated to producing rare
ingredients to help promote human health
and wellness
and at demetrix we provide affordable
sustainable access
to rare plant ingredients for healthier
lives and we're specifically focused on
rare cannabinoids
so the way that
demetrics
operates is on these pillars of
ensuring that we have high purity
product
so 98 pure or better
we produce in a very sustainable
fashion biotechnology uses a lot less
resources than typical agriculture when
you're talking about rare ingredients
and everything we do is science-backed
in terms of the the research that we
perform as well as the technology we
develop and these three things are what
really drives our innovation
and by innovation what i'm really
speaking to is the
desire to find new ingredients to help
people and to then design production
processes that can bring those
ingredients at high enough volumes and
high enough purity to be available and
affordable to those that are in need
so how do we do this um so if we just
take the cannabis plant there's over a
hundred different cannabinoids in this
plant
but the fact of the matter is most of
these cannabinoids are in such small
quantities in the plant that it is just
impossible to be able to isolate them at
the volumes needed to properly research
them
and this is where biotechnology comes in
because what we can do is we can produce
single cannabinoids completely agnostic
to how rare or common they are in the
plant and we can produce them at high
volumes and high purity so that they can
become available for researchers to do
research on these specific isolates and
understand what the individual
cannabinoids contribute in terms of
beneficial properties for for many
indications
moving on this is a picture of our labs
in berkeley california where we're
headquartered and so
we use fermentation to produce these
cannabinoids so we take a
microorganism such as yeast baker's
yeast commonly used for
beer in producing bread and we program
it and say we want you now to make this
specific cannabinoid we develop a very
controlled
production environment in a bioreactor
which is a fancy word of saying a
fermentation tank
and we grow these yeast and as these
grow and as they are in an environment
that's conducive they start to produce
that cannabinoid and then we purify it
from the fermentation broth and we have
our product
so the benefit of this especially when
we're talking about rare ingredients
is the reduction in water
energy and land use
because
no matter if we're talking about a
cannabinoid or a fragrance ingredient
that particular plant has to produce an
entire plant it has to produce the roots
the leaves the stems sometimes the
flowers etc as well as that specific
ingredient we're after and if that
ingredient in the plant is very rare
you're creating a lot of
added biomass a lot of energy input a
lot of water utilization for just that
small component and we take all of that
out because all we're doing is using a
small
yeast and actually over a thousand
yeasts can fit into a trichome on a
cannabis plant and we're telling it only
to make that specific rare cannabinoid
so i know everybody here is very aware
of the
system
when you hear about cannabinoids a lot
of times what people talk about are the
cb1 and cb2 receptors
what we've been doing with our
technology is we now have over 40
different rare cannabinoids that we have
been taking through various
research to understand and catalog what
they actually do from a human physiology
perspective in terms of the receptors
that they interact with and also taking
them into in vitro and a little bit in
vivo
tests to then prove to understand
do they actually manifest into the
specific benefits that they we hope that
they do
based on the indications that we see
through the the receptor screening
and so what i'm going to do for the rest
of this uh presentation is talk a little
bit about one specific cannabinoid
out of the the 40 that we currently have
under research and that's cbg
or cannabis era
and so we recently uh commercialized
cannabidiol as a retail g
and with our partner evonik industries
which is a large german ingredient
supplier are now bringing this
ingredient to the market for personal
care use
so there's a couple of things there's a
lot of research out there about
cannabidiol in general and there's
indications that it's a very strong
anti-inflammatory we also see that it
has antimicrobial effects and strong
antioxidant properties
but a lot of this then we have to do
further research to understand does that
translate into an actual claim because a
lot of this is done at receptor or very
preliminary screening levels
so
the work that demetrics did was specific
to our cannabis gerald erete g which is
98 pure it has zero thc in it uh our
process is completely incapable of
producing thc has zero terpenes so this
is a very clean
isolate that that we've taken into this
research
and what we've seen when we we took it
through is
initially it was gpcr and ion channel
screening and we saw strong
anti-inflammatory properties we also saw
that it was a strong antioxidant and we
saw that it had interesting
antimicrobial
potential as well
but the next step that we did is we put
it into in vitro skin assays to
understand does that actually translate
when you start to go into industry
standard testing
and along with it we we took a couple of
other cannabinoids that we have listed
on here
through specific in vitro tests
and what we saw is that first of all
all these cannabinoids are
physiologically active and i think that
that's really important
because there's a lot of anecdotal
evidence out there about cannabinoids
but having actually screened through the
entire library of gpcrs in the human
body 40 different cannabinoids i can sit
up here and assure you that they do
interact with the human body
we also know that they interact
differently each one has its own unique
fingerprint they do not all do the same
thing
and i think that that's also another
important fact
in discovery that we've made
because
they're not the same and what that leads
us to believe is that there's a
tremendous amount of potential not only
as individual cannabinoids but to expand
research and understand the
the right combinations
of the right cannabinoids to be able to
help people with specific indications
and we're just at scratching the the
surface here in terms of the amount of
research that that still needs to be
done to really harness the true
potential of these ingredients
so here this is this is tip of the
iceberg in terms of what we've done and
also where we need to go
so in these in vitro assays what we see
is the darker color is stronger
indicates stronger performance lighter
less performance
and you can see here even among these
handful of cannabinoids we see varying
differences
the other thing that i'd like to point
out is that
we saw that cbg was a really strong and
interesting antioxidant in basic orac
dpph
tests but when we put it into
antioxidant in vitro skin assays we
didn't see that it was a very strong
performer and i think that this is also
another important thing in terms of
taking the research to the next levels
to to really prove out and to
elucidate how it translates into that
actual benefit that people need
so
with that we
also went a little bit deeper in terms
of looking at
these specific assays and understanding
the
anti-inflammatory effect of cbg on skin
so what we did here is
i just wanted to get it all up
here we go
so we we ran this in vitro assay where
we took normal human dermal fibroblasts
and normal human epidermal keratinocytes
and the first thing we did is we ran
cytotoxicity assays to understand what's
the highest dose that we could actually
use of cannabidiol as well as some other
cannabinoids in these tests
and the first thing that was interesting
is that they are different in their
cytotoxicity
so we ran these tests several times just
to make sure cbg is less cytotoxic than
cannabidiol cbd
by quite a significant amount
and you'll see that in
translated into some of the charts that
i'll show next
once we understood the cytotoxicity we
then were able to determine what the
right concentrations would be so that we
wouldn't destroy the cells in these
assays
and through
through a plate model put the
erection in with a um
inflammation
stimulated uh inflammation of these
cells and then understood through a
positive and negative control the the
performance of the cbg
so the first one we did was a pma
stimulated model and what you see in
here is the percent inhibition so you
want to inhibit pma in order to
i'm sorry you want to inhibit il-8
in order to see an anti-inflammatory
reaction so il-8 is one of the key
cytokines in terms of inciting
inflammation
the blue bar that you see is actually
the positive control and that's store
sporane so this is a known
anti-inflammatory that works very well
the red bars that you see next to it are
the the percent reduction of cbg so you
can see at the higher concentration
which is three micromolar cbg was right
at the performance of basically of
saurosporine
and we had a really nice dose response
curve with this one
now the gray bars next to it are
actually cannabidiol and what you'll see
there if you look on the x-axis is that
the concentrations are different for cbd
versus cbg and that's just reflective of
the cytotoxicity differences between the
two molecules
but what we found was very interesting
is that we hear a lot about cbd being an
interesting anti-inflammatory
and a lot of people translate that into
skin health but what we saw in this
industry standard skin model
is that cbd really wasn't a good
anti-inflammatory in terms of other
cannabinoids
now what i don't have on here is uh the
other ones but cbg i'll just share with
you was the the most
highest performing out of the the lot
so the next test we did was pge2 in pma
stimulated cells
and here the positive control that you
see is indomethacin
and
what we see here is also
a decent i would call it a dose response
what we think is we just hit the upper
limit of of the cbg response which are
the red bars next to it
but again strong anti-inflammatory
properties were seen in this model
cbd in this model showed absolutely no
response in terms of preventing
inflammation
so the other thing that we wanted to
make sure is
are these products safe and so we did a
lot of skin irritancy testing these were
in vivo and what we found is that cbg
and cbd
were both
non-sensitizers to skin they're also not
ocular irritants or
any way damaging to the eyes so that's
all that this chart is really showing
and it was interesting so we had over
100 test subjects and not a single one
of them showed any indication of
irritation with cbg which is pretty rare
so we were very happy with those results
now the other thing we did was minimum
inhibitory concentration assays against
different microorganisms that are
interesting ones for skin health
so the first one that we did here is um
for skin care is c acnes and there's a
lot of research already on the efficacy
of various cannabinoids on c acnes
what we saw was very similar to that
research so we feel that we've got a
good validation on that
the the next one are actually two oral
care targets which we were surprised to
see
so s mutants is a
microorganism that is strongly linked to
periodontal disease and is also a very
difficult
microorganism to control with natural
products per se so the the oral care
industry uses chemical
ingredients
to
help to control s mutants and toothpaste
mouthwash etc
and the fact that we now have a
potential natural ingredient that not
only showed efficacy against this but
also was not broad spectrum
so these cannabinoids are not broad
spectrum in terms of their
anti-microbial activity they're actually
quite
measured and quite specific and that's
really important because we're all very
aware of antibiotic resistance
and also wanting to cultivate a healthy
microbiome not only on our skin but also
in in our oral cavities
the other thing that it was good is that
it was
active against p gingivalis which i'm
sure all of us are familiar with in
terms of oral care
so here we have an ingredient that's
naturally derived and hits two of the
key oral care
micro
organisms that that we want to control
for for proper oral care health now when
we layer on top of this the fact that
cbg was also showed a strong
anti-inflammatory response against il8
it gets even more interesting for oral
care because there's research showing
that il8
inflammation
is a
link to chronic periodontal disease so
not only do you have to control the
microbiome but you also need to control
the the inflammation
so really really interesting results
with this
the other one is personal care and here
m firfer was an interesting target that
cbg showed efficacy against
m firfer is one of the funguses that is
often linked to dandruff there's three
of them m fervor is one and depending on
what region of the world you live and
furffer is either more important or less
important in terms of controlling
the the dandruff so mainly southeast
asia is where that's really important
but it is also one of the key reasons
that some people suffer from tinea
versus color so this is the skin
condition that often shows up on the
backs where people have white patches on
their skin
and this can be a very difficult
condition to treat and to have yet again
a natural ingredient that shows efficacy
against this m for fungus
shows a lot of promise to help people
not only to look good but also to feel
better about themselves
so
in in summary what we're seeing
specifically with cannabis gerald or
rettayg
is that it shows
a lot of promise for
um
aiding and being a good bioactive for
skin care
not only for what i'll call the more
cosmetic concerns
in terms of anti-aging support a lot of
anti-aging
or a lot of the aging from our skin is
an inflammation response so if we can
control the inflammation we can slow
down the the aging process is the theory
but it can also help in some other
conditions that
quite frankly probably have a lot
stronger or greater impact on how people
feel about themselves and and their
well-being in terms of helping with acne
also as mentioned tinea varus of color
and then oral health i can't stress
enough how important oral health is it's
linked to
not only you know
diseases within the mouth but it's also
now being linked to
certain cns concerns
with things that are microorganisms
potentially
going through the blood brain barrier
and through the oral cavity and creating
issues with
mental health
it can also
be linked to
digestive support as well
so being able to balance the microbiome
in our oral cavity has wider range
benefits than just having a pretty smile
as mentioned we are looking at other
cannabinoids we have over 40 that we're
taking through many of these various
assays and and also we'll be taking into
clinicals with our partners and what i'd
like to just leave you with is that
i'm super excited about
where we are today in terms of helping
people with health and wellness as an
industry
this plant has so many interesting
ingredients in it that hold so much
potential to really help people in a
safe and an effective way and i think
that as an industry we owe it to the
consumers around the world
to do the proper research and to provide
products that we know will work time and
time again and understand how they work
and why they work
so that we can provide real solutions
time and time again for people that are
in need for that
so we are always happy to to share more
about the research we're doing we
believe that education is key in this
industry
and that we need to stand on each
other's shoulders so to say
so we
welcome conversation and for people to
reach out to us to learn more about what
we're doing and our findings we will
also be communicating a lot of these as
uh we we learn more
and look forward to to speaking with you
all uh about what we're doing in further
detail
thank you
[Applause]
hi very interesting presentation
of the 40 somali cannabinoids that
you've isolated are you able to say how
many are identical to those produced by
cannabis sativa as opposed to new
chemical entities
they're all 100 percent identical so
every single cannabinoid we produce can
be found in the plant they're just
in such small quantities we can't
physically isolate them from the plant
but they're all natural okay thank you
yeah
wonderful talk i was just wondering if
you were able to look at the acid forms
of some of these are you just producing
the neutral forms
i i'm sorry i had a hard time hearing
you sorry i was wondering if you were
able to look at the acid forms of some
of these compounds or you're only able
to produce the neutral forms no we can
produce both so we we are looking at
both acid in neutral forms and i will
say the acids do behave differently than
the neutrals physiologically speaking
does neutral mean decarboxylated yes
okay i'm just just checking um this the
the the cbg for the
um
the clinicals that you did do you know
what percent concentration
or do you have a recommendation for a
percentage of concentration for a
product application
yeah so in in skin care specifically you
usually don't want to go above one
percent and this is consumer product
skin care
um so we're currently doing clinicals to
see its efficacy at that one percent
but for an otc or pharmaceutical
depending on the formulation you could
go higher but the clinicals would need
to be done to to check the actual
efficacy within the formulation
hi
are the commercial products are they
topicals are they something that you
would ingest orally yes so right now our
partner evonik is specific to topicals
personal care but we are currently
working with the fda as well as essa to
get the proper approvals for ingestible
products
hi thank you for the nice nice talk um i
was
that you had very little um reactions
like negative reactions when it was on
people's skin did you have any issues
with it clogging pores or the molecules
the right size so that it's not going to
cause any like fur like it might reduce
some breakouts when i produce some or
how is that
yeah we we did not see any um issue with
clogging pores these are fairly small
molecules it really depends also though
on the formulation that you put the the
can of a gel in because cannabidiol
itself
is a solid so you have to solubilize it
in something to apply it to skin and
depending on what you solubilize it and
then maybe you can get into comedogetic
issues yeah but the canopy gerald itself
is non-kinetogenic awesome thank you
thank you so much for your talk uh what
was the method that you used to measure
il8 and pge2
levels
um i believe it was
fluorescence i'm looking at
eliza i'm sorry i was an eliza
thank you so much for sharing your work
that was really
enlightening
i had a question
about the 2 percent that's left after
the 98 cbg i wonder if you've
fractionated and taken out the cbg to
look at efficacy as we saw last night
with daddy mary's talk sometimes that
really low percentage can be really
effective as well
yeah so um the key thing to keep in mind
is that we don't use any plant material
um so the the two percent that's left in
our product actually comes from the
yeast that's used to to produce the the
cannabinoids so it's mainly things like
carbohydrates and proteins there's no
terpenes in it or
other cannabinoids except for maybe some
cbga that wasn't fully decarboxylated
hi
thank you for
presentation um just quick question why
the particular focus on il-8 keratins
were like
why
why not il3
yeah so there's
there's a lot of different
inflammation markers within the skin and
the skin assays but if you hit il-8 then
that's kind of like the the key
indicator that you are going to see an
anti-inflammatory response there's
others like il-6 etc but the assays for
those are not as
robust and so that's why we picked iol8
because it's a much more robust assay
and if you hit isolate then you're
pretty assured that you're going to see
an anti-inflammatory response in skin
versus some of these others where you
might get a false positive or a false
negative
go ahead kevin
excellent talk you're a good speaker um
so i'm just trying to clarify in my own
mind so the
you're producing cbga but they're the
yeast of producing cbga and then you're
decaboxylating yes yes good
clarification the yeast also just like
the plant produces the acid form
but because of the way that we produce
we are able to easily purify to keep the
acid form if that's what we want or we
can decarboxylate it into the neutral
form so if that's the case
why no research on cbga or have you done
research we have done research on cbga
as well yeah it's just we um we launched
cbg first so can you enlighten us on any
of the cbga research
yeah so cbga was um
for for skin it was
more active for hyperpigmentation
and ros support
um looking at the receptors it focused
more on the pain
receptors thank you yeah
i had a feeling he might ask my question
so i wanted him to go first i also have
a question that was similar to that but
i also wanted to know how
have you guys done any comparisons with
cbg isolate or cb have you been able to
do those type of comparisons and did
what did you find
i know it's different like from plants
from the plant yes the comparisons yeah
so we did and they're they're similar
they're they're basically the same
thank you yeah well it but i'll use the
caveat as long as it's a high purity
plant
isolate yeah
yeah
well great well thank you so much look
forward to
you