[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed conference
can you believe we are only three months
away from canmed 2022.
i for one cannot wait for cam at 2022
but when you consider it's been 28
months since our last event i guess
three months isn't that long to wait
but that doesn't mean you should wait to
buy your ticket to the event no head
over to cannemedevents.com now and get
your tickets today
we have three full days of world-class
cannabis educational content scheduled
for may 3rd through 5th at the pasadena
convention center in pasadena california
it all starts on may 3rd with our full
day medical practicum led by dr bonnie
goldstein dr dustin sulak dr kevin
spellman and eloise thiessen
each of them will share the latest
medical cannabis research including
information on dosing drug interactions
and different product types
they will also share their clinical
experience they have acquired treating
patients with medical cannabis over the
years
this is really a must attend event for
any health care professionals who are
interested
in recommending medical cannabis but
it's not limited to those folks
anyone who is interested in learning
about medical cannabis can and should
join us for this event
head over to kim at events dot com slash
practicum to learn more
as wonderful as that practicum is it's
just the appetizer
may 4th and 5th is the main course two
full days of oral presentations panel
discussions posts or presentations and
industry exhibitors covering the latest
advancements in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
we are really excited about this year's
program it might be our best yet just
look at our keynote presenters
we have dr ethan russo presenting
cannabis and psychiatry dr seth crawford
talking about innovations in hemp
breeding grace bandong will talk about
building a comprehensive analytical
testing program and dr bonnie goldstein
will discuss cannabis medicine for
children
those presentations alone are worth the
price of admission but please go to
canmedevents.com to see the full
schedule
and if you want a preview of what you
can expect at cam mid 2022 check out our
can med archive which is a searchable
video library of all the past candid
presentations and panels find that at
canmedevents.com
which brings us to this episode's guest
dr ethan rousseau
as you just heard ethan is a canmed 2022
keynote presenter and ethan is no
stranger to canmed
he was an attendee at our early events
at harvard medical school as well as a
presenter at canmed 2018 at ucla
he is one of the most experienced
cannabis researchers in the game ethan
is a board-certified neurologist a
psychopharmacology
researcher an author a lecturer a
consultant the man does it all
and today he joins us to talk about the
research that has been done to determine
whether cannabis can be used to treat
covit19 and or prevent infection
more specifically we discuss
what role the endocannabinoid system
plays in preventing and clearing a viral
infection
the different levels of clinical
research
the importance of peer review
and we also talk about some specific
studies
most notably the university of chicago
study that claims cbd inhibits sars cov2
replication
the oregon university study that claims
cannabinoid acids can prevent covet
infection
animal models showing cbd can calm the
cytokine storm
a pre-print study claiming cbd primes
the innate immune system
and we also look at claims that cannabis
smokers have a greater risk of covin-19
infection
before we get to my conversation with
ethan i'd want to thank this episode
sponsor project cbd
founded in 2010 project cbd is the first
and longest running website dedicated to
research in education on the benefits of
cbd and it's the premier destination for
both curious and committed cbd consumers
often the first to report on
cutting-edge health issues project cbd's
reporting reflects a deeper
understanding of developments in
cannabinoid science and therapeutics
learn more at projectcbd.com
and without any further ado please enjoy
my conversation with dr ethan russo
[Music]
good morning ethan thanks for joining us
on the podcast well thanks for having me
absolutely all right so
throughout the pandemic we've seen
headlines about cannabis as a potential
treatment for coven 19. but as is the
case with most things these days it's
hard to know what's real and what's
being sensationalized for clicks so
first thank you for coming on to be a
trusted expert that
can help us
find the signal and all the noise
well we'll try um you know
a lot of this by saying that there's a
big difference between the way i would
like things and the way that i think
that they are
so let's issue that caveat and this is
where i remind people that my training
is as a neurologist not a virologist but
um hopefully we can translate some of
the
scientific
jargon into things that are
understandable
great so
maybe it's best to start broadly um and
then we can kind of get into discussing
some of these specific studies and and
see which ones have the most promise
so first given what we know about
cannabinoids and the endocannabinoid
system
is there potential for cannabis medicine
to be helpful in the fight against covet
perhaps
there are always
there is always more than one
consideration here
um
first would be
uh are there medicines that uh help
prevent infection
uh or
kill the virus
or in the case of covid
are there things that help with the
aftermath or preventing further damage
people are probably familiar at this
point with the idea of the cytokine
storm
this may have less to do with the virus
itself than it does with the body's over
reaction to its presence such that it's
attacking its own tissues particularly
the lungs
so all of these are branch points where
any medical intervention might help and
so the question then becomes
could cannabis or components help here
here or here
so all of these things need to be
considered
excellent
and another thing to consider at least
when we're kind of looking at the
research that's being put out is
sort of the different levels of clinical
research
and i was hoping you could kind of help
explain that again to kind of set the
table because from what i can gather a
lot of the work that's been done on
cannabis and covid is very preliminary
which means that the results that are
seen there might not hold up when we
start working with actual patients
yeah exactly right
so i mean the first step is looking at
things in the lab uh maybe at cells and
culture and sometimes they do things
like use agkl's hek cells which stands
for human embryonic kidney
those are used because they're easy to
hook
on
cell receptors to
so that you can test the hypothesis
however it's a long way from matt
to saying that something's going to work
in the human body
so the next echelon up is animal studies
but again do these translate well and as
we'll we'll see sometimes they're
injecting very large doses
into a rodent
and it's not the same as what can be
achieved in a human
third
and most important would be human
clinical trials
and typically these go through three
phases
on phase one is only possible after
you've established to the satisfaction
of the food and drug administration
that the compound you're testing
is safe and
not toxic
to a degree that is going to be
dangerous by itself
after that steps passed phase one means
that you test your drug in normal
patients
or normal participants
to see what its pharmacokinetics and
pharmacodynamics are that's a fancy way
of saying
how much gets into the blood and what
kind of reactions do people get to it um
then phase two you're actually studying
the disease process and how people
are affected by it so these are called
safety and efficacy studies
along the way you also have to go
through chemistry manufacturing control
to show that
your
study drug is consistent over time and
is made to
what are called good manufacturing
practice standards
finally phase three is in large numbers
of people
again looking at safety and efficacy
if you pass all that
you get fda approval but this is a
process that often takes 10 to 12 years
and upwards of a billion dollars
on now with a neutral product there's a
possibility of it doing in less time
case in point would be epidiolex
but they are again we were dealing with
decades of information regarding the
relative safety of cannabidiol
in humans
and then getting it through clinical
trials for a very uh important set of
disorders um where basically
conventional medicine has fallen short
um so
you know it was also under what's called
an orphan designation meaning that less
than 250 000 people in the us were
affected
so that's a shortcut with covid you
wouldn't necessarily have that shortcut
but you may have other shortcuts because
of the uh severity and wide reach of the
pandemic
uh anyway that's a long-winded answer to
a
short question
yeah and
at least from what i gather in in the
studies that i sort of put together for
this conversation i didn't see anything
getting beyond animal models is that
accurate
ah yeah
there was on the new yen study that i
just read yesterday this is called
cannabidiol inhibits sars cov2
replication through induction of the
host er stress and innate immune
responses
they did look at humans but in a very
indirect way we could go into that
detail if you like right now
yeah sure
okay so what they did um and this is a
little bit hazy because in the
methodology section they didn't go into
this in a lot of detail but purportedly
they looked at people
who were on a high potency cannabidiol
preparation which i assume was epidiolex
because they described it and it's the
only one i know of
basically 100 milligrams cbd per
milliliter
in patients so this must be epidiolex
um and they looked at the incidence of
sars
cov2
in patients on that preparation compared
to patients who were not on it and
supposedly
um they were comparable in demographics
but there weren't a lot of detail there
now why is this important well first who
gets epi dialects
it is approved in three groups of
patients those with travail syndrome
lennox gastow syndrome and seizure
disorders associated with tuberous
sclerosis
these are all generally children
sometimes adults
with extremely severe seizure disorder
syndromes and developmental delays
one would have to think that in the era
of covid that these are patients that
are really being sequestered uh by their
family they're not gonna be out and
about and they're not gonna be eating in
restaurants unmasked or this kind of
thing so
could the
uh was there a benefit to them being on
this high potency cannabidiol
preparation or was it more that they've
been isolated
and we're getting less infection so this
is something you cannot answer
from the available evidence now
there were statistically significant
differences i think it's intriguing but
it is very preliminary i hope it's true
but let's keep this in context
let's suppose it is true
the concentration is very high
and the doses required
would be very high
um
extrapolating from the studies they did
in rodents
um this could be anywhere from
113 milligrams of cannabidiol a day up
to 450 milligrams
um in the patients
where they're actually describing use
and reduce covid uh incidents
um generally the dosing on that is 15
milligrams per kilogram per day of
cannabidiol
so in an adult this is going to be
upwards of 1500 milligrams or 2 000
milligrams a day
um
that
even if available is going to be
prohibitively expensive right the
projected average cost per patient of
epidialex in the us is 32 500 a year
and if we're talking about something
that's given as a preventive
not as a treatment at the time
that's an enormous cost that you could
not bear
across the large population i mean that
would absolutely bankrupt the system we
have enough drugs that are bankrupting
the system right now so
again
interesting is what i'd say uh the
answer absolutely not and not yet
um so we need a lot more work um to see
if
there's something there
um yeah i hope it's true but again um
we have to throw some cold water
uh on this as uh being anything more
than a little bit intriguing at this
point
right and so this was looking at it um
using cbd as a preventative to have that
right
prima primarily um you know there would
be a role for treatment um they showed
um
that
cannabidiol at least in the animals
could
decrease replication
uh and inhibit viral gene expression
uh etc
and um yeah this may be really helpful
um
again i i hope it's the case
but you know the animal studies they did
also were done by doing intraperitoneal
injections so in other words they lift
the skin of the abdomen and inject this
and it goes around
the gut um so that's a highly vascular
system and it absorbs relatively well
there's a big difference between that
and saying that an oral dose in humans
is going to be absorbed to a sufficient
degree to come anywhere near close to
the tissue concentrations that were
achieved in the animals
similarly in one of the other studies uh
one that's been out longer and gotten a
lot more play this is the van bremen
study about cannabinoids blocking
entry
obviously in that organ
yes it is now they're different it
wasn't cbd it was cannabidiolic acid
cbda and cbga
um uh
now here
the problem is an even greater one
and
you know i i think again this is a very
interesting study
there was good science involved but i
fought this one
the way it was reported i fought that to
lack of adequate peer review now what
does that mean
to be published in a peer-reviewed
journal it means it's got to go through
a panel of experts
who critique the article and suggest
changes of corrections and i think that
that fell down somewhere along the way
so for example with cbga
cannabidrolic acid
um they described an
inhibitory concentration of
[Music]
35 micrograms per milliliter
now
the problem is that's not the way that
we usually report things it's done in
what's termed a tissue concentration
now converting that uh we get a
calculation of 97 to 102 micromolar for
cbga micromolar means millionths of a
mole a mole of the molecular weight in
grams per per liter um
so
what this means is
that a tremendous concentration
uh is needed generally anything above 10
micromolar is considered non-druggable
non-druggable is a
term of the industry meaning whether you
can turn it into a pharmaceutical or not
and
people who have experience in this area
will tell you that i think it's totally
impractical
that you could create these kinds of
tissue concentrations
by giving this orally to someone
it's true that the cannabinoid acids
have sometimes been shown to have a
greater bioavailability ability to get
absorbed and into the body
than the neutral cannabinoids but i
don't think this is achievable
again it's possible you could do this on
a surface
um like spraying it on the virus
but
you know to be fear
you can spray 70
ethanol
or rubbing alcohol in that concentration
on the virus and you'll kill it because
it's what's called an envelope virus
if you knock out the envelope the virus
can't work
um
you know and this has led to the kind of
misconceptions like with president trump
um at the time recommending uh people
ingest bleach uh to kill the virus no no
no no not quite you do not understand
the science um
so
um
in the article and this this is again
where i fought the
what i think is a lack of
peer review
they felt that these kinds of
concentrations would be clinically
achievable i dissent
um
yeah and again i've talked to many of my
colleagues about this and we're in
agreement that this is just uh not
practical at all
so it's not even the fact that it would
be cost prohibitive it's just that it's
just not achievable is that right that
that's what i believe and again not what
i'd like i'd love for this to be true
now there could be an a's in the hole
here
they got a good response with both cbda
and cbga
what happens with the two of them
together they didn't test that if there
were some kind of synergy a boosting of
effect
of the two together which often we see
with botanical mixtures
maybe they could get it into a range
where it's more meaningful but right now
it's not even close
um you know again um
numbers that high you just don't see
in
a drug that goes to market it just
doesn't happen
and so so we know that cannabinoids are
um or phytocannabinoids are plant
compounds that mimic our
endocannabinoids that our body makes
ourselves so
is there some takeaway here or some
application here where
you know there's something to boost our
our own endocannabinoid production that
can help you know prevent an infection
right all right well let's take a little
bit of leap of faith here
let's say that
there's some signal here that indicates
that cannabidiol can influence the
cytokine storms
and
could reduce damage associated with the
virus
well you know that that's really
possible again i don't think that that's
been demonstrated uh this would require
clinical trials
but one of the things that
um
overall the endocannabinoid system is a
homeostatic regulator or physiology in
other words it keeps things in balance
if a system is overactive it brings it
down into the normal range if it's under
active it brings it up into the normal
range so a lot of this has to do with
protective influences
and
one of the things that cbd does
is inhibit the breakdown of anandamide
one of the endogenous cannabinoids and
so over time cannabidiol may well
increase the gain of the endocannabinoid
system and offer
protective effects
particularly against these sort of
immunological battles
that people go through after a severe
covet infection
so that's that's a maybe
and again the last thing i would want is
to say that none of this has any
application
or future viability i just think that a
lot more research needs to be done
and i would point out that um yeah it's
really possible that compounds from
cannabis or other natural products
are going to turn out to be part of the
answer here
um but it is all
too soon
right
right and i know sort of just talking
about
cannabis as as regulating your body's
homeostasis and one of the things is
that
depending on the patient's situation
that cannabis can be an immune booster
or it can be an immune reducer
and one of the the pre-print studies
that came out just this month was
talking about cbd
being used to potentially
prime components of the innate immune
system increasing readiness to respond
to viral infection so
um
is there some potential there as well
uh perhaps um you know i'd say this
about preprints
uh
first i'm again it
um you know the in the past
you
had to submit your
article for review in a journal it went
through peer review and then hopefully
was published
now
there has developed this tendency to put
things online
and they get a lot of press coverage
before they've been through peer review
at all
sometimes they never even make it um
so
i think
it is a situation that does fraught with
pitfalls
um
you know an earlier study in relation to
cbd
and
sars cov2 was a kovalchuk study
on this was the idea that
cbd was going to interfere with
binding
to the
spike protein of covid
that where it binds
to the ace2
receptor
the problem with that study was that
they looked at different cannabis
extracts different levels of cbd
and there was no dose response effect in
other words some worked better than
others but it really didn't relate to
the concentration of cbd
um and um
you know again there might be something
there but it equally could be the case
that it was another component of the
extracts that was really uh responsible
um so
again it
really it is absolutely essential that
people look at this very skeptically
with a proverbial jaundiced eye
to try and find out what the bottom line
truth of the matter is
yeah and that's a great point you make
about pre-prints right is that
as you said they haven't gone through
peer review they haven't gone to the
same scrutiny as something that's
published in a in a true journal and i
think that's some a good thing to keep
in mind as people are looking into this
yeah absolutely i mean i've taken a
stand that i wouldn't uh do preprints on
on
research that we've done even when we
think it's really exciting and we'd like
to get the word out
um
but it's
the internet age and um
again what i really don't like is that
these things get publicized and
misinterpreted
because of this exposure without the
proper degree of initial scrutiny
right it is a double-edged sword though
right because this being an ongoing
pandemic and
there's really a
need for information so that people can
um can act appropriately that waiting
for to go through the full peer review
process might not be prudent
always
perhaps however
it is our best defense against uh junk
science
that's true that's true it's yeah it's a
it's a difficult spot
so
as we're sort of getting to the end here
i did want to sort of bring up the
the question of
is there a potential that cannabis use
could actually be detrimental to
someone's experience with kovi could
actually you know as we said
cannabis can regulate your immune system
in either way could it be that cannabis
could
actually reduce your immune response and
make you more vulnerable to covet
infection
uh maybe i mean the main danger would
relate to smoking and
the
damage to the lung tissue
it is simply inarguable
um the issue of whether smoking's good
for the
lungs
it's true that
smoking cannabis does not lead to lung
cancer epidemiologically
however
it is absolutely clear that it does lead
to irritation cough and phlegm
greater susceptibility to upper
respiratory infections and
perhaps even a greater susceptibility
to covid
however
this would not relate to
immunological damage um
the
dosing of thc for example that immune is
immunosuppressant is very high
previously estimated at 50 to 100 times
the psychoactive dose
so yes
various cannabis components can be
immunomodulatory
but you know cb2 activity may be helpful
you know it's again it depends on what's
in it and how it's administered smoking
not good
for the lungs and certainly would be
something to avoid at this juncture
less of an issue with vaporization
obviously oral administration is going
to be safer with any kind of of lung
issue
um
so on the one hand yeah um people should
avoid smoking um in general
anything
and
but beyond that it's unlikely that use
of
cannabis-based medicines is going to
cause harm in this instance
bigger question is can it uh help in any
respect and the answer right now is
maybe but it's got to be proven
right and you know when you mentioned
that the the amount of thc to kind of be
immunosuppressive is is really high it
seems like this is sort of a common
refrain throughout the conversation here
is that the dose is really
what might be the limiting factor here
absolutely
okay
i think i think we covered most of the
studies that uh that i had pulled out
for us to discuss is there anything that
that you had that that we missed
well no i mean i just advise people to
um
you know if you read something about one
of these studies and aren't sure try to
talk to somebody that might be a little
more familiar
um be skeptical
and
good advice would be wait until
um higher authorities
um say what seems to be helpful and
what's not and that's a moving target
we've got a situation now
with uh some of the antibody treatments
uh that used to help don't work on
omicron um but there's one left that
does and now there's some oral agents
that work
um you know keep up with what the cdc
and fda might be saying now not what
they were saying three months ago
because everything is in a state of flux
yeah absolutely it's always changing and
it's funny you said that about the
monoclonal antibodies because that just
the alert just came up on my phone
before i came in here to talk to you so
um
yeah it's ever-changing
you bet
all right ethan well thanks again for
coming on and talking with us i'm going
to put links to all these studies in the
notes so people can read up on it is um
i guess one final thing if you want to
share any websites or social media or
ways people can keep up with the work
that you're doing please plug away
okay well uh you know our our company is
credo science and that's credo
c-r-e-d-o-science.com you can see what
we're up to there
um on the news front we just last week
released a
diagnostic screening test for
cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome
information on that can be found on what
is chs that's what
dash is
chs.com
on there's a lot of useful information
and links there
absolutely yeah that's great we've had
alice moon on the podcast before talking
about cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome
so it's great that we're
we're getting to a point where we can
and start
determining what's what's causing that
because that seems to be quite the issue
well we think we have an answer in
genetic susceptibility basically we
showed five genes
that were statistically significantly
different in chs patients as compared to
patients who used high amounts of
cannabis but didn't have chs
so we believe that
there are some underlying
susceptibilities and this is again
worth exploring further
absolutely
all right well thanks again ethan and i
look forward to seeing you out in
pasadena for canmed 2022.
we're going to get there we're going to
do it this year
we hope so thanks so much
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr ethan rousseau
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics and studies that we discussed and
thanks again to this episode sponsor
project cbd
our next episode will drop february 16th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out the
canmed archive and join the canmed
community facebook group to stay
connected with us
of course you can also stay in touch
with us on social media on facebook
instagram linkedin and twitter just
search for cam at events
sign up for email alerts on cam at
events.com to stay up to date with all
the latest news and please be sure to
rate review and subscribe on your
favorite podcast app doing so helps us
reach more listeners
i do sincerely hope to see all of you
out in pasadena this spring but until
then stay safe stay healthy and please
join us for the next canbed coffee talk
[Music]
you