foreign
[Music]
Coffee Talk podcast where we talk with
the leading Minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I am your host Ben amaralt I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the cam Med conference the can Med 24
Innovation and investment Summit returns
to the JW Marriott Resort in Marco
Island Florida May 12th through 15th and
we are excited to announce that
registration opens October 6th
kmad 23 was our first time at Marco
Island and the feedback was
overwhelmingly positive the beach the
food the amenities the networking
opportunities and of course the content
presented were all exceptional and
kmed24 is shaping up to be even better
featuring new dedicated networking
events New workshops and a number of new
faces sharing their latest research and
Innovations in the Cannabis space
if you haven't yet head over to
cammedevents.com now to sign up for
email alerts so you don't miss any of
the announcements I hope to see you in
Florida this spring
my guest today is Dr Danielle McCartney
Danielle is a postdoctoral research
associate at the Lambert Initiative for
cannabinoid Therapeutics at the
University of Sydney
her main role is to coordinate Clinical
Research into the effects of cannabis on
simulated car driving performance
Danielle and her colleagues recently
published a systematic review of 20
studies that examined the next day
effects of THC
as the study States the length of time
an individual should wait following
cannabis use before performing safety
sensitive tasks is a critical issue
some government agencies and experts
recommend individuals avoid performing
safety sensitive tasks for at least 24
hours it should not surprise you to
learn that the data suggests a much
shorter impairment window during our
conversation we discuss the different
types of studies the authors reviewed
and the criteria they used to evaluate
them
the different tests administered to
measure impairment
how next day effects of THC compare to
the acute effects
how next day effects are different in
medicinal cannabis patients versus
recreational users
what methods are available to determine
THC impairment in drivers and what is
the reasonable impairment window for THC
before we get to my conversation with
Danielle I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor medicine Women Health
medicine women's team of Specialists
includes Medical Doctors naturopaths
medical cannabis experts nutritionists
and Alternative Health practitioners
these integrative teams evaluate health
issues and design targeted protocols to
promote personal healing
medicine women's protocols have
successfully alleviated symptoms of
cancer autoimmune diseases and
neurological conditions as well as
providing overall health rejuvenation
learn more at medicinewomenhealth.com
okay without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr Danielle
McCartney
[Music]
thank you
good morning Danielle thanks so much for
joining me on the podcast
all right so you recently published are
you and your colleagues recently
published a review of studies that have
investigated the next day effects of THC
on cognitive function and safety
sensitive tasks which is a topic that
has implications on a number of
different policies which I'm sure we're
going to get into but first I'm curious
to learn a bit more about your
background and why you and your
colleagues were interested in studying
the next day effects of THC
but yeah so I'm a research fellow at the
Lambert Initiative for cannabinoid
Therapeutics which is a
philanthropically funded Center for
medicine
business research at the University of
Sydney and so the Lambert covers or
studies a whole wide range of different
areas related to cannabinoids but I
guess most of my research falls into the
sort of cannabis and driving domain so
um the effects of cannabis and THC use
is sort of a Hot Topic in that domain at
the moment hence our review
um yeah I think that's all I have to say
excellent so you mentioned cannabis and
driving which is certainly
um a Hot Topic
um so but again let's maybe not get into
that quite yet so
um let's let's talk about the result
results of your research so how many
different studies were you able to to
look at and what were sort of the the
main takeaways there
yeah so as you said our review looked at
the what we considered to be next day
effects of THC so basically we were
looking to identify any Interventional
studies so studies where either cannabis
or THC had been administered in some
form
um and their participants have been
required to undertake or perform some
kind of uh either simulated safety
sensitive tasks so things like driving
or there's some studies on simulated
airplane flying uh or some more sort of
standard and sort of common I guess
computerized cognitive tasks and there's
a wide variety of of those sorts of
activities and so to be included in the
review the studies had to have done this
and measured performance at least eight
hours following cannabis use because
that's sort of what we consider to be
um I guess your typical overnight
recovery period And so studies most of
them administered the tasks between sort
of 8 and 12 hours following cannabis use
and and some administered all the way
through
often they conducted testing at multiple
time points they might have measured it
12 hours and then 24 hours and sometimes
all the way up to 48 hours so we found a
total of 20 studies that had done this a
little published quite some time ago
there was a little bit of recent work
but largely historical and they measured
quite a number of different outcomes I
think it was several hundred uh
different sort of organist of sorry
several hundred different tasks and
that's across all the studies at all the
different time points and um under all
the different cannabis conditions so
often the studies would administer one
dose of THC on one study and our
different dose on or sorry one dose of
THC on one arm of one study and a
different dose a different arm in the
same study so you end up with like you
know the amount of data sort of just
increases exponentially as you start to
include these different arms and
different time points so yeah it turned
out to be a reasonably large undertaking
um but yeah that's what we included in
our review
okay and what were the results are were
you finding that people were impaired
after eight hours or or no
um so the vast majority of studies
showed no next day effects of THC so
that was across a variety of different
cognitive tasks and safety sensitive and
safety sensitive sorry simulated safety
sensitive tasks there were a small
number of studies that detected next day
effects
um but I guess an important element of
this review is not just to look at
quantity although they were overwhelming
majority showing no next AFX but also to
look at the quality of the studies and
what they're sort of showing and when we
looked closely at this sort of small
number of studies showing um subtle next
day effects they tended to be not such
good quality so
um none of them were randomized
controlled trials for example which is
our most rigorous form of Interventional
study and they often
um and they didn't tend to have the
um employ the best sort of
standardization procedures so what I
mean by about is we're really interested
in making sure that the studies we
um were sort of reading into used
um didn't allow their participants to
sort of consume alcohol 24 hours prior
to you know undertaking tasks caffeine
stay up all night all of those things
that can go on to affect cognitive
function we wanted to be sure that they
had been controlled out of the sort of
context so
um basically the gist is the studies
that did show next day effects which
there were very few of
um tended not to be great quality
um whilst there was a couple among those
showing sort of no next day effects that
were quite good quality so that seems to
be where the evidence is at the moment
yeah and I imagine they probably
established some some baseline
performance and did they also
study kind of acute facts effects of the
thc2 and compare those
that's a really good question so that
was another element of our review
so as you see say they admit or as I've
sort of said that when they've
administered their treatment cannabis or
THC or whatever they have chosen
um often they'll administer these
cognitive tasks or safety sensitive
tasks at several different time points
following use and whilst our next day
effects review was primarily interested
in those tasks administered more than
eight hours post THC use we did also for
all of the data that were available on
the more acute effects so if they
administered the same tasks one hour
later or two hours later where you you
know much more likely expect to see
impairment and the reason we did this
was because we wanted to know well okay
if we're showing no next day effects we
want to know if that's you know if the
studies have also seen acute effects
because if you haven't seen an acute
effect to your probability of seeing
your next Affair seems really really
sort of low so by collecting the sort of
acute data we were able to get a little
bit of insight into whether or not sort
of the doses being administered were
impairing to begin with and if the tasks
being used to assess impairment was
sensitive to begin with
um unfortunately we didn't get a lot of
uh
I guess there was quite a number of
tasks that didn't show or I guess um
quite a bit of
what would you say like our we found
that a lot of them didn't show acute
effects if that makes sense or either
didn't didn't show or didn't measure
acute effects but I think 20 of our
tasks of the tasks we identified I hope
that made sense that was a bit confusing
no no no it does and I know I and I
looked at the at the
um the study that you published too and
it looks like there were quite a bit of
different tests that were administered
to sort of measure this
um it looks like almost a dozen or so
um now
are some of these better indicators than
others
um what are your sort of your thoughts
there
um possibly yes I think uh there are
certain tasks that seem to stand out as
being
um better for identifying impairment I
think
um one of our probably preferred tasks
would be you know
um simulated driving because it's
an ecologically valid way in which to
look at impairment you're taking someone
and putting them in an activity that
they would typically
um or that you don't want to see them
impaired on and so actually using that
specific task is is kind of Ideal and
the main thing that we look at when
we're measuring
um sort of simulated driving performance
is a marker called standard deviation of
Lane position which is basically how
much lateral movement the vehicle makes
as it's moving along the road so sort of
swerving and that seems to be quite a
sensitive measure of impairments
um other than that in terms of the
computerized tasks one of the areas that
seems to show up quite a bit is
information processing speeds seems to
be quite heavily affected by THC and so
for example a task of information
processing speed might be something
one we use in the lab and I'll see if I
could explain it because it's always
hard to explain to even participants but
I'll see if I can make sense of it but
it's like a pattern generating task so
you see on the computer screen a series
of patterns and then the computer will
say okay I want you to produce pattern
one when you have to use the keyboard to
make that pattern and so you're sort of
identifying and then copying and
coordinating a few responses so that
tends to be reasonably sensitive
whereas kind of at the other end of the
spectrum our more sustained attention
type Focus tasks seem to show a little
bit less impairment
um but yeah it's hard to hard to compare
I mean the main thing when these kinds
of tasks is that the participants are
really thoroughly familiarized to them
otherwise you can kind of
um mask impairment with learning so uh
that's really really important
okay no in it's interesting you say
driving because that does seem to be you
know sort of one of the main problems
you're looking to solve for so
um going back to kind of at least
comparing the next day effects to the
acute effects what are you seeing in
terms of acute effects of THC on driving
performance
yeah so it seems to vary somewhat um
depending on the population that you're
studying
um the dose THC used and the root of
administration
um on average we would you know sort of
say that THC tends to be impairing uh in
the acute phase
um but uh we do note that regular
cannabis users seem to experience less
THC induced impairment than occasional
cannabis users likely due to the
development of Tolerance but also that
lower doses seem to produce less
impairment and the timing at which
impairment Peaks varies depending on
whether THC has been impaled which
usually right as quickly after whereas
orally ingested takes longer for that
impairment to sort of ensue
yeah and it's interesting you bring up
kind of inhaled versus Edibles too does
that
um is there a difference in the next day
effects of inhaled versus Edibles as
well because like you said it does take
longer to uh to kick in usually within
edible
that's right yeah
um so we've done a previous review
looking at the duration of impairment
that focused on the sort of less than
studies looking at the effects of THC
less than 12 hours following use and
when we conducted that review we did see
that oral THC induced in payment lasted
longer than inhales
um but the review predicted that the
impairment from orally administered sort
of THC would still subside within
um sort of about eight hours depending
on the dose provided that was with about
a 20 milligram oral dose
um looking at our current sort of next
day effects review we didn't sort of see
any patterns of you know studies that
administered THC orally being more
likely to detect impairment than those
that administered THC by inhalation and
it could just be because it was beyond
that eight hour window all of them were
relatively likely to be recovered within
that time so yeah no real patent emerged
the main sort of drivers into the
quality of the studies that we were
looking at to be honest interesting so
and I know in the paper you you had said
that you know whether it's some
um lawmakers or potentially employers
they sort of give some guidance of you
shouldn't be driving or operating heavy
machinery uh within 24 hours of uh using
cannabis but it seems like based on the
research that window is really eight
hours
seems to suggest
you know provided the doses you know
within reason right it becomes a little
bit more ambiguous
um but certainly 24 hours seems quite
conservative
um not a lot of data to support that as
far as we can find yeah yeah no and and
it's a good point too and I think one
that you brought up earlier is the
difference between a medical cannabis
user and a I guess an adult use
recreational user um one of them is
certainly looking for an altered effect
which would probably produce impairment
whereas the other one's looking for a
therapeutic effect which might be at a
lower dose
yeah that's a really important
so all of the research included in our
next day effects paper was based on
healthy individuals who use cannabis I
don't know some of them occasionally
some of them regularly little for
primarily sort of for recreational
purposes and that's just on the basis
that there was no studies looking at
medicinal cannabis users and that is
basically the picture across the driving
sort of space in cannabis and the
research area and driving in cannabis
and there's very little research looking
at medicinal cannabis users so as you
say that population could respond quite
differently you know when compared to
recreational users and medicinal
cannabis users are often you know
they're using the products on a very
regular basis so there's good
opportunity to develop tolerance to its
impairing effects they're typically
using lower doses to you know avoid
rather than induced intoxication and
they're also experiencing a clinical
benefit you know some improvement in
symptoms that might you know themselves
impaired driving so things like pain and
insomnia so it's definitely an area that
warrants for the sort of exploration and
something that we're very interested in
yeah
yeah and I know that um you know a
former a can Med uh presenter Dr Stacy
Gruber I know that she has done some
work in this in this area and she's even
demonstrated that some medical cannabis
users perform better in cognitive tests
after taking cannabis so there's a lot
of a lot of things going on here yeah
like I said really interesting area and
they could react quite differently so
I'm yeah not totally surprised by that
finding yeah very interesting yeah and
so it all comes back to this idea of
um I guess trying to keep impaired
drivers off the road and you know and it
seems that lawmakers or law enforcement
is really kind of fixated on on finding
a biomarker to kind of determine
cannabis impairment sort of like a blood
alcohol or breathalyzer
um
to your knowledge are there any
biomarkers that are reliable or that
were that were close on for determining
cannabis impairment or is that still a
bit of a Holy Grail
yeah like if you're talking biological
like in some kind of fluid biomarkers uh
at present no we just uh we don't really
have anything that's particularly good
so the most commonly looked at things uh
probably urine blood and oral fluid
urine um is probably the worst of the
lot we know that
um THC and it's metabolize
um things persist in urine for a really
really long time particularly among
regular users you know comfortably over
a month
um blood is is not particularly good
either it can hang around in blood for
extended periods of time and this is
largely because THC
um so it's a lipophilic molecule meaning
that it likes to get into fat and sort
of stay there so it accumulates in
people's fat stores and then just sort
of slowly leaches into blood meaning
that it can be there for again weeks and
sometimes longer after use
all fluid is a tricky Matrix
um it sort of has some benefits I guess
in that it is the Matrix that THC leaves
most rapidly
um so if you take someone who only very
occasionally uses cannabis and a
minister an acute dose you'll probably
find that it persists in all fluid for a
few hours and then dissipates
um which is kind of consistent with
impairment but there are a number of
kind of significant limitations aside
from that
um for example the first being that uh
so the only way that THC can end up in
oral fluid is if it enters a via direct
contact so you have to you know have a
smoked or you know ingested in some way
that it actually contacts the oral fluid
meaning that if you avoid that contact
say for example if the THC is
encapsulated
um You probably won't have any THC in
all fluid
um which means it's not a marker of
impairment at all the other factor is
that there's been really little research
research looking at Oral fluid THC
concentrations in regular cannabis uses
and what seems to be the case is that
whether THC is present in oral fluid and
regular cannabis uses is just a it's
completely variable sometimes it's there
12 hours later sometimes it's not
detected and it's just a little bit all
over the shop so
on the face of it there are some
advantages to that approach but when you
dig a Little Deeper it sort of falls
apart really quickly so yeah
um we don't currently have a
particularly good way of identifying
cannabis impaired drivers
now with something like a field sobriety
test be a good standard
yeah that's certainly the direction that
we're heading you know if you want to
measure or identify impairment the thing
that you maybe want to be looking for is
impairment um
tests are able to tell us the tricky
thing is
um identifying something that can be
carefully standardized across a lot of
people so for example you know if a
police officer asks people to stand on
one leg you know you're going to get
huge variations in how people are able
to do that and you know might depend on
you
um certain disabilities could affect it
and all kinds of different things
um even just age so
um you know that's not going to be you
can't stand there with a stopwatch
sometimes I want to go oh you know
you're impaired because you didn't stay
on your leg for as long as what is
typically average
um so we need to look for uh biology
sorry behavioral tests that
very sort of not very much from one
person to the next because we just don't
have a baseline measure or a drug-free
measure to compare against in the real
world
um in workplace settings where they
often also perform sort of drug testing
to screen out
um impairment uh Baseline measures may
be an option
um because people come back in every day
we can test them regulates that might be
a little bit of an easier uh sort of
question to answer but I do think we're
kind of heading in the right direction
with the behavioral tests and possibly
some combination of a behavioral and
biological test might give us kind of
the answer that we're looking for where
you know if you don't perform so well on
the behavioral test you're given the
drug test and you know you have to have
a look at the results of that but yeah
we'll just have to sort of see there's a
lot of interest in that area and a lot
of work being done so hopefully we can
find something
yeah and I have to imagine like you said
the the goal here is to keep impaired
drivers off the road regardless of if
it's cannabis or alcohol or uh opioids
or anything like that so having a a way
to identify impairment like again
regardless of the of the source is
really the goal exactly I mean fatigue
is a huge uh problem and we don't have a
biomarker for that so if it just so
happens that you know you can you know
pick that pick things like that up as
well and and discourage people from
driving just in general whilst impaired
that that would be great yeah yeah so
your findings being that
um we don't really have good evidence
that
cannabis users eight hours after after
using show any signs of impairment so
what sort of implications do those
results have on
um you know how employers set their drug
testing policies or even how patients or
clinicians
um either recommend cannabis or use it
um so in terms of patients and
clinicians I guess I mean ultimately how
um people take their medicine has to be
dictated by their clinical need
um but I guess what our research
suggests is that if they are using
um THC containing products in the
evening before bed which I think is
quite common for people with pain and
insomnia and things like that
um they should have relatively normal
function the next day
um whether or not that's something or a
factor that clinicians want to take into
account when prescribing or recommending
dosing regimes that's that discretion
but uh at least that's something that
they can use to inform their their
decision making hopefully
um in terms of policy for workplaces and
things like that I mean they face a very
similar problem to the roadside drug
testing where you know our research
would suggest that people who use
medicinal cannabis are relatively okay
to function the next day
um but they are still employing the
biomarkers that can produce positive
tests and we don't have a behavioral
alternative so it's a tricky thing to to
sort of work with I mean our data
suggests that if people are using their
medicinal product in the evening they
should be fine to function the next day
we'll see what they do with that
information
right and now you mentioned too that in
looking at the studies a lot of them
were maybe poorly designed or didn't
have proper controls and things like
that so I guess I'm going to put you a
little bit on the spot here but if you
were to design the perfect study
um what would that look like
oh tricky um yeah
a little bit on your manipulation so
maybe we'll start with
um you know healthy individuals who
might use cannabis recreationally I
think they were there were a couple of
quite good studies that our review
identified in this space
um and uh I think a similar design to
what they've employed would be
appropriate we sort of I think you take
um your your population of healthy
individuals who use cannabis
occasionally
um allow them to
um consume cannabis probably as they
usually would
um sort of AD libidden in quantities
that
reflect their usual use
um and then keep them overnight in a
sleep lab or something like that and
then look at function the next day
um I think ideally I mean in a fictional
world you probably
um and I say fictional because in
Australia I'm not allowed to do this
um but you'd probably use an on-road
driving test to assess impairment and I
know that's something that their experts
at over in the Netherlands
um uh because it's you know super
ecologically valid and sensitive to
impairment and you know well researched
and things like that so that would be a
great way I think to look at next day
impairment
um and that overnight sort of component
ensures that participants aren't you
know out doing things that you don't
want them doing during that overnight
period continuing to use cannabis
um you know drinking alcohol staying up
all night all of those things can affect
the results of the study so I think that
would be one approach
I think the medicinal
um uses is a bit more complex to study
uh I think
I mean maybe ideally you'd take uh
people who were just initiating
um treatment uh and titrate them up to a
dose that they find efficacious whatever
that may be
um and then assess performance once
they're on that sort of Maintenance dose
um either you know 12 hours later or 12
hours following Placebo maybe you'd even
have a couple of arms um where people
weren't
um sort of chronically treated
um initially put them on a placebo
titrate them up to a therapeutic dose
and then administered either THC and
Placebo and look at impairment so that
would be give you sort of four groups to
to compare but that one would be quite
the undertaking
um yeah need some funds to support that
absolutely
um and so I guess
there is a difference between measuring
impairment the following day and the the
quote-unquote Cannabis hangover
um
I imagine there's a difference there
right you could still feel some After
Effects the following day but it might
not necessarily be impaired impairing is
that fair to say yeah and this is why
we've used the phrase next day effects
throughout because it's really blurry as
to whether or not we're looking at you
know the
I guess tail end of impairment or if
we're looking at
um hangover kind of effects
um you know when you study alcohol
hangover you can you know administer a
dose of alcohol and then test that
someone has a breath alcohol
concentration of zero and you know that
okay we're no longer measuring the acute
effects of alcohol we're now measuring
the effects of the alcohol Handover
that's really blurry in the Cannabis
space
um so hence the term next day effects
interesting uh yeah
um so we can't
completely separate them but
um I know uh so one of the um excuse me
a postdoc here but uh at the time she
was a PhD student she recently completed
a RCT looking at
um
the uh I mean the primary aim of the the
trial was to look at the effects of THC
and insomnia or medicinal cannabinoids
and insomnia but she did look at the
sort of next day effects following
evening dosing and um I believe there
was a subtle effect
um for the treatment to increase next
day feelings of sedation which might
kind of capture some of those measures
you're talking about but interestingly
when they administered the
um what's called the maintenance of
wakefulness test which is the most
boring task that you can ever administer
basically participants have to stare at
a wall for 45 minutes and try not to
fall asleep
um they did that several times the next
day there's four participants and it's
considered sort of the most
um or it's considered an objective
measure of next day alertness or things
like that and so despite having that
subtle increase in sedation maybe that
was the wrong thing that that was sort
of what they reported
um
they didn't detect any effects on the
maintenance of wakefulness test so um
you could be right where you can feel
possibly not 100 but still be functional
if that makes sense yeah yeah that it's
actually that's actually interesting and
it goes in line with the what we were
talking about with fatigue being
um a problem with driving performance
um so that you know even if you weren't
under the acute effects of cannabis but
you were fatigued as a result that would
be an issue too but it sounds like
that's that's not the case they can
stare at the wall for 45 minutes and not
fall asleep yeah I mean that was a good
night's sleep maybe I'll
probably yeah I shouldn't share too much
but yeah really interesting findings
there and that's that's still to come
excellent well speaking of things to
come
um I'm curious um what research you're
you're working on now and what we can
expect to see
oh
um so a few different things but I guess
the overall theme is that we're
interested in moving into the you know
medicinal cannabis user sort of space
um within the context of of driving and
safety sensitive tasks so
um as you've said that's this issue of
you know biomarkers of impairment how do
we identify
um uh that on the roads so that's
something that we're interested in we're
also interested in you know whether
medicinal candidates are users are in
fact impaired
um when they use their treatment
um as instructed under you know careful
medical supervision so that's something
that we would like to investigate
further
um and yeah that's probably the main
sort of things at the moment so before I
let you go
um I wanted to give you the opportunity
to share any other resources that are
sort of related to the topics that we
talked about and I'll be happy to put
them in the show notes for people to
learn more or if there's a website or
any way to get in touch with you if
people want to connect please plug away
oh
um I guess we have the Lambert
initiative website so I'm sure if um
people go to Google and type in labid
initiatives they'll be able to find that
and that should link people to our
ongoing clinical trials
um probably our sort of Twitter page I
know that that's quite um active at the
moment uh and should allow you to get in
touch with any of the researchers at the
Lambert initiative that you might like
to speak to so that's probably a good
point that's cool yeah excellent yeah
and I'm definitely going to put a link
to the study in the show notes so people
can can dig into the data all right
Danielle thanks again for for getting up
early and talking to us and uh hopefully
hopefully we can do this again soon
sounds great thanks Ben
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Dr Danielle McCartney check out the
links in the show description to learn
more about the topics we discussed
and thanks again to this episode sponsor
medicine Women Health
our next episode drops October 4th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please like comment and
subscribe on whichever platform you use
to listen to or watch us also please
check out camedevents.com to sign up for
email alerts and learn more about our
annual Innovation and investment Summit
that's it from us stay safe stay healthy
and be sure to join us on the next can
make coffee talk
[Music]
thank you