[Applause]
well thank you all for staying to the
bitter end um there we go um yeah so my
name is josh werzer i'm the president of
sc labs
and we're in analytical testing
laboratory we're located in california
we have a location in northern
california in santa cruz
hence the name essie labs and a location
in orange county
and we've been in business for about
five and a half years but i personally
have been testing
cannabis for seven years i started out
as a research and development chemist
um worked in small molecule synthesis
and then silicon polymer synthesis
and uh um just kind of wanted to get out
of it um
silicon polymer chemistry uses some
pretty gnarly chemicals and uh
just kind of was looking to see what was
out there one night and read a post on
craigslist for a job
and uh normal posting for a director and
analytical laboratory and
at the very end it said must be
comfortable working with medical
marijuana and
at the time i didn't i was not aware
that there were any type of laboratories
that would
test medical marijuana or that their
marijuana laboratories and
being a connoisseur of cannabis i
filled out my resume and i was just
going to go in and see what it's all
about is
more just kind of you know snoop on what
they're doing um
i sent it in about two in the morning
because i had to stay up late and make
my resume
and i got a call at eight o'clock the
next morning come in for an interview
went in on my lunch break they offered
me the job
and i didn't like my job so i figured
yeah i'll do this for maybe a year
and leave it off my resume and go get a
real job
and uh seven years later i'm still still
doing it so one of one of the really
cool things
about what i do is um that i've been
able to kind of sit on the sidelines and
see
everything that's happened over the last
seven years i i was there when
we found the first cbd strain as far as
i know that was
confirmed cbd for the medical community
in california
um it was a it was a og kush
um blueberry cross yeah that came out of
harborside
um and uh you know things like that
along the way i've gotten to see all the
developments and that's been really
exciting so um what i'm gonna do is just
kind of briefly talk about what we do
i'm not gonna keep you here too long um
what what kind of issues i see in the
testing industry
um over the years and going forward and
kind of share some of the data we've
collected
um one of the cool things also is that
we have a huge sample size we get to see
pretty much everything that comes
through the state
um and and it's it's kind of really fun
to uh play with the data and see trends
over time and
and all that stuff so um i'll uh
apologize if i hurry through this but i
got a kind of a lot to cover so
um why would we test cannabis so first
of all a lot of states um
california excluded right now but um in
about a year we'll have mandatory
testing
um but uh require testing and and you
know that's gonna always need to be done
at a third party lab
and and uh we sort of serve that
function voluntarily for our clients now
uh no one is required to do any type of
quality control analysis or or there's
no type of oversight as it sits in
california
and it's been that way um but but we
still have a fair amount of the
the industry that at least does some of
some type of testing
activity um not necessarily what they'll
do under regulation
and then the rest of these you'll see um
are are not necessarily um
tests that will ever be required um and
kind of going to what mark said and dr
jacobson said
um you know i i have a presentation i do
in front of
infused products manufacturers and you
know i talk about stratified sampling
and getting an idea on
on your batch batch runs and your rsds
and all that stuff and
everyone just kind of glosses over and
that's you know kind of a real problem
we see with with with our clients is
you know someone might bring in an
edible product that you know they
do a run every day and once a month
they'll bring in one of their products
and test it and
two months later they come back and say
well why is this you know 20 higher than
the one i made two months ago
um and and so i think um what we would
like to see
is is is producers get a much better
handle on their production processes and
as people are getting more sophisticated
um we do see people that are that are
you know have a good handle on their
production processes
know know their their deviation
throughout
you know from from batch to batch and
throughout a batch throughout a
production run
um and product improvement and i also
agree with mark i mean i probably
shouldn't be saying it's kind of a
little counterproductive to to my
business but
i i see the big infused products
manufacturers and probably a lot of the
big producers
um having in-house laps and i think
that's absolutely essential i think
um the the the service that we
we provide is is more of going to be a
third party kind of verification and
we'll do quality control like for the
small guys but
the the bigger producers really should
be doing a lot of this
in-house so what kind of tests are
applicable and this is not even a
comprehensive list is cannabinoids by
far
what we do the most of and when i
started testing that's pretty much all
we did we also did microbiological but
there's only one or two clients that
bothered with that and uh you know
potentially for for safety and well
maybe not necessarily as much for
quality but for safety
probably the the least important test
until you get to the infused products
from fused products
obviously it's very important but um you
know for
for herbal cannabis that you're going to
smoke uh the difference between 15
thc and 20 thc is is is gonna be nominal
for the end user
um as far as safety goes um
microbiological contamination pretty
straightforward same thing you do in in
food testing applications the only
difference is with cannabis being
inhaled
into the lungs in a lot of forms some of
the some of the issues are some of the
pathogens are slightly
more or i guess less important
mycotoxins
pesticide residues residual solvents um
in
in solvent-based uh extracts and and the
products made from those solvent-based
extracts
uh heavy metals moisture terpenes um
plant fertility testing is something
that we're getting more and more
requests for
and then genetic sex determination
genetic sequencing all the stuff that
mgc does such a good job of
so first one uh cannabis measurement um
cannabis produces dozens of compounds
this is news to you and when we first
started doing testing it it was really
kind of boring um you know when all we
did was and then
when i worked at stepo we we only had
three reference standards available thc
cbd and cbm and we tested on a gc
and i sat there and looked at the exact
same chromatogram all day long and it
was it was the worst job
in the world but um but yeah so uh um
more and more we're starting to see a
little more diversity with cannabinoids
but still um thca
is is by far the dominant cannabinoid in
pretty much everything we test and
pretty much
the the only cannabinoid that's there in
significant quantities and most of what
we test
now there's three different uh
instrumentation instruments that that
people commonly use for
cannabinoid testing and and they each
have their pros and cons i kind of
always use analogy of
well there's a socket wrench there's a
crescent wrench and there's a tire iron
and all of it can remove a bolt
um but depending on what bolt you're
trying to remove um
there's a best tool for that job and i
think everyone's kind of using
liquid uh hplc liquid chromatography for
for cannabinoid testing now
um allows you to test the acids it gives
you the sensitivity that you need that
you can't get with spectroscopic methods
and
in the the lower limits of detection
limits to quantification and in better
linearity
um this isn't the the most interesting
sample of cannabis you've ever seen this
is a check stand
check standard because again i want to
show you some peaks so this is this is a
run on uh
uh hplc and uh i've
not seen mark's presentation even though
i do know him but this is
pretty much the exact same uh curve he
showed you if you
um notice it we've got the same numbers
um and this comes from the emerald cup
flowers so
um we test for this event it was
actually one of the first um jobs we did
when we opened our lab was test for the
emerald cup and we've been testing for
them ever since and so
it's really interesting we've been able
to see the trends over time
with cannabinoids and once we started
adding terpene testing
it's really cool to kind of just watch
the trends and a lot of these things are
seasonal
um they varied over the years um and
some of that data if i had more time i
would love to share it but
it's really super interesting but yeah
so this is the the distribution of of
cannabinoid content
um for the emerald cup and i'm going to
get back to kind of why
why i'm comparing the emerald cup and
why it's interesting data
um this is also from the emerald cup so
this is a total cannabinoids for
concentrates
and this right here is a comparison of
the emerald can
emerald cup the same the same
distribution you saw before
compared to our samples from october
and you know that so so the october
samples are about eight or nine thousand
samples
um and i just kind of want to compare
the emerald cup to our general
population of samples and see if there's
much variation and there isn't that much
variation with
total cannabinoids and in in really the
uh
the kind of historical or the october
mean um is a little bit skewed because a
lot of we get a lot of kind of
r d stuff trim stuff like that that ends
up falling under flowers so
you get a little bit our um wider or
standard deviation and you get a little
bit lower mean but essentially really
similar
um and and that's not too surprising
um but you know with emerald cup and
with the emerald cup is kind of the best
the best
norcal breeders that have been doing
this for years and in
most of them grow from seed it's it's
it's supposed to be an all-organic cup
and we'll get into that in just a sec
um and uh um it's people who you know do
a lot of breeding on their own so it's
really good
um genetically diverse pool to kind of
to look at
and uh here's some some uh
some distributions from you know
individual cannabinoids
the one on the left is is cbd obviously
most the samples had very little cbd if
you if you kind of
cut out any any sample that has um
less than one percent cbd then you get
the light blue line and you move it over
to about
um we got down here uh 11.3 percent
and so this is the um so so the emerald
cup is is a cup
so they have and another reason why i'm
i'm showing you the emerald cup results
is they have
very good judging process so we go to a
lot of these cups and in
a lot of the judging processes are um i
guess less than stellar
um they truly anonymize their samples
and they pull really really good people
experts in the cannabis industry to do
the judging
and i and i just want to illustrate a
point here so if you look at the
top 20 samples out of 487 flower samples
i want to believe
i want to say um there is uh
really no difference in the top 20
samples versus the overall mean as far
as cannabinoid content so
you know a higher cannabinoid content
isn't going to get you um in the top 20.
and it shows no correlation actually
there's one sample in top 20 that tested
like 32 or 30.4 or something like that
and kind of skewed it to the right or
maybe the the winners would actually
have a lower
mean than the than the general
population and
and you know i think that's one of the
kind of things that the testing industry
the disservice the testing
industry has done to uh i guess the
cannabis industry
is that when people started testing
cannabis and it started becoming common
it became
the score game who has the highest
testing strain and a lot of really good
strains
just kind of disappeared a lot of your
perps bubba kush i like confidential
i'm forgetting a bunch but a lot of
these really good strains that have very
interesting terpene profiles
were you know had had a lot of value
went away because they didn't test in
the 20s and or
in the 30s and and and so um you know i
think with
kind of our understanding of of what
really is important in in in that's the
terpenes
is uh um we'll start to see some of
these strains come back hopefully
and so this is where where you get your
winner so you you map the winner's total
terpene content versus the
the standard um mean and uh
you get a full standard deviation
difference between the two and so
um you know that's the only real
predictor of of
where a sample is going to rank from
from the numbers
is terpene content it's it's not
cannabinoid content at all
and this is just a chromatograph so for
terpene testing
um we use gcfid gc is is
you know ideal for for testing terpenes
similar to mark's method
uh you get good sensitivity a longer
linear range
um and and uh um really good separation
on
we have 34 compounds in our terpene test
and then getting back to the emerald cup
winners um
we have i i normalized all the samples
based on um based on their uh
overall terpene content so we're
comparing apples to apples and then i uh
um i i this is kind of a map of how many
standard deviations they were away from
the means this is the top 20
samples again and in which terpenes in
those top 20 samples were prevalent so
you see
um it seemed like the the judges in this
instance really uh
like their mercy dominant strains um
alpha terpenine
isopuegola um those are kind of minor
cannabinoids so it's hard to say how
much they
they uh contributed um but but they
definitely were there in large amounts
in the winners
um and a lot of these terpenes actually
track with other terpenes so you have
terpenes that kind of pair up
and if one's high the other's high and
if one's low the other is low and if i
had more time on i get into that but
um so yeah and then terpinoline alpha
pine and beta pinene we're all
we're all relatively abundant in in the
the
desirable strains and i also mean that's
another one
um and then here here's uh the mercin in
emerald cup flowers if you
graph it like that you get something
like that but then if you normalize it
for
with the overall terpene content most of
your terpenes start to look like this
you have um or at least the major ones
you have a lot of samples that have very
little a third to a half of them and
then you kind of have this even
distribution um
you know in in in in certain terpenes
you know mercy goes all the way out to
75 of the overall terpene content and
you have uh
limonene that doesn't necessarily get as
high but very similar
very similar uh histogram but then the
only one that's kind of
interesting is trapinoline and these two
pineally dominant strains i i cut the
top off this so 377 strains out of the
470 had essentially
no interpenaling and then you had
this handful of strains that had a whole
bunch of it and there's your penduline
dominant but
it's just it's one of the terpenes that
kind of behaves like like none of the
others
just kind of interesting um
so this is the chirping content of
concentrates and if
if i had shown you the the slides where
where we saw the winners
here you would see that all the winners
were in the last last three
bars um with terpenes so with the
concentrates
um high chirping content was even even a
greater predictor
of where the the the um sample would
actually end up scoring in in the cup
and i don't know what happened to my
distribution curve there it looks a
little wonky but
um all right so the next test that um
you know it's kind of important
in in in part of basically any state
that's that's
requiring intestines regulations is uh
is microbiological testing
and uh these are all three petri dishes
with asp
different species aspergillus and i
didn't put aspergillus on this list for
some reason but uh
these are the kind of common tests um
california is going to be requiring apc
total yeast in mold e coli coliforms
salmonella shigella and then listeria
and pseudomonas in some places
um pseudomonas is required in the city
of berkeley i don't know of too many
states that don't require it and it's
pretty debatable whether
anyone should be requiring pseudomonas
testing i'm against it but
it's two that's a whole different story
listeria for for some
food based uh infused products i think
makes sense
general cannabis probably not and then
again
just give you kind of idea what you know
what happens with samples again the
emerald cup is supposed to be all
outdoor so this this would be an
outdoor kind of more of a homogeneous
sample than our general sample size but
if you look at the general samples that
come through the door
the numbers are almost identical i
didn't even make another slide to show
you those because they're almost
identical
um and these are based on the ahpa
guidelines um so apc
um 2.7 were over the hpa limit for
for apc aerobic play count um yeast and
mold
is always trouble um at 100 000 um
cfus per gram uh that's the one we have
the most failures i guess with and uh
pseudomonas none of them failed under
the the well that was berkeley
regulations
salmonella we didn't detect any
salmonella in the
in the emerald cup samples coliforms one
point seven percent were over the limit
e coli four percent had e coli um so as
you can see
um other than yeast and mold even an
outdoor crop
um produced by you know all different
people can can uh
um come in come in pretty uh
pretty pretty safely under the limits
that are kind of being established out
there and the hpa guidelines kind of
being adopted everywhere
um pesticide residues so pesticides are
a really big issue for us now
um and it was a really big issue um
starting with emerald cup testing
because this is the first year we did
pesticide testing for them and
uh it's supposed to be an all-organic
cup so um
of course no one used pesticides in
their plants and i'm sure that's that's
the way it was and
and so it was definitely a big
controversy but it really i think kind
of sparked a conversation and it was
you know it's kind of a little scary but
fun to be a part of it um and
and and for us um our pesticide assay
again we're not in a regulated market no
one's being forced to test so
our our pesticide assay is actually very
basic and our rsd
our limits of detection are are
relatively high they're probably
um 10 to 100 times higher than than the
action levels in in oregon so so
they're very generous and in we do that
a to keep costs down
and uh um again to kind of incentivize
people to do the testing and it saves us
you know kind of expensive sample
cleanup and as you can see
um it's still we still see plenty of
failures so
um let me go just straight to this thing
i'm gonna
i'm running out of time here but uh um
these are failure rates i took the month
before the emerald cup in the
three months following the emerald cup
i'm just kind of showing our overall
failure rates for pesticides
um and thermal cup you know it was much
better
than the means so so most of the people
were pretty honest and then i think
there was a few people that
um you know and i guess that's the fun
thing we use you know a
conformational mass spectrometer lcms ms
with triple quad
so you know it's very hard to get a
false positive um
obviously if something's below or
limited detection it's going to sneak
through but but it's very hard to get a
false positive so it's the next thing
with the pesticide test and
and um you know a couple times the the
laboratory issue got brought up and
i agree wholeheartedly one of the big
issues with with laboratories is
there has been very little oversight and
california did a really good thing with
their new regulations by requiring
everyone to get iso 17025 certified
that's kind of the bare minimum
analytical laboratory should meet and
hopefully that'll that'll help things
but
um you know cannabis laboratories are no
longer different than environmental
laboratories or
or any other um i guess you know
analytical or diagnostic laboratory
um there's always going to be incentive
to to not
fail people and there's always going to
be incentive to uh um cut corners
it's it's tight margins our margins
aren't necessarily the same as the
cannabis industry and
and right now in california someone can
throw a gc in the back of a van or even
a near infrared in the back of a van and
drive around and call themselves a
testing laboratory and that's who we're
competing with so
um i i get it i understand but uh um
across the board with the pesticide test
it's nice because we don't get a lot of
that because uh
you know 99 out of 100 times someone
comes up to you and well why did i fail
this and
you know i failed for michael butano
what's up with that and well did you use
eagle 20 oh yeah well that's
i can't use eagle 20. so i think also
too and with kind of the
grower community as they get more
sophisticated uh you'll see a lot less
mistakes but uh um yeah so october we
had 49
of our our samples we saw failed and
again pesticide testing
and the the the pesticides we detect in
samples
it it varies seasonally and so october
is kind of the outdoor crop coming in
we got some rain early in the season
right before harvest um
people probably had to uh to resort to
the microbutanol which is a fungicide
and so uh we failed 49 of the the
pesticide samples that came in the door
then and
and actually you know we don't do every
test we get through the door isn't
necessarily tested for pesticides so
um you know these are people that kind
of i guess
theoretically would have self-selected
for for testing
um and and still half of them half of
them failed um
and then it got a little bit better
after the emerald cup um after the
emerald cup
we definitely lost some clients which
which is fine and uh um
and in you know people knew that you
know not to bring their stuff in so
um if they'd use pesticides so so it's
actually kind of steadily declined since
then which is which is kind of
interesting
um and uh again yeah the emerald cup we
still 13
of the the samples had had one or
another one or two pesticides
or three i think a couple had three but
uh um yeah so
back up here that's just a graph and
those are the pesticides that we test
for so we only have
i think 12 up there um and we selected
those because those are the ones people
are actually using so
um you know with cannabis your big pest
and your big pest concern is going to be
mites there's aphids and there's thrips
and there's a few other things that will
attack cannabis
but but what people with what destroys
crops and in in
in people's biggest concern when it
comes to cannabis are mites so there's a
handful of pesticides that are people
are using
to to kill the mites and there's a you
know there's there's one or two
fungicides people use and there's a
couple plant growth regulators so
um paclibutrizol and diminized are
actually plant growth regulators and
um those those are compounds that were
packaged in a lot of hydroponics
products kind of sneakily too we're 99
natural and not necessarily labeled and
they're making buds really hard and they
keep the plants nice and short and
and improve your yields 20 30 40 percent
and and you know why wouldn't i use it
and uh um we've seen a lot less of that
now there's
it's been harder to get a lot of the
products have had have had diminished
impeccable beaches all pulled because
they're not meant for any type of
crop that's used for human consumption
and uh and people have kind of gotten
gotten hip too and by and large your
your cannabis producers aren't aren't
trying to
to do it wrong a lot of them a lot of
them have the best intentions and just
just didn't know any better so
um we see less and less packed leviticus
all in dimension but that's that's our
pesticide
assay and we're still still failing 50
of the people and and again
um you know with that's not necessarily
the case across the board there's a
there's
um you know a lot of labs that test for
60 100 they they do a
whole panel for agrano chlorines it's an
eliza kid and
everyone passes so um we have 12
and we fail 50 and we have really bad
limits of detection
but again that those will decrease by
about a thousand times
when when regulations come in so those
numbers will go up a little bit
um and then i just want to briefly touch
on residual solvents because i think i'm
out of time
um and so yeah so residual solvents with
with solvent extracts coming on on the
scene and
and the kind of the extraction histogram
i showed you for the emerald cup
um you know the there's a lot of samples
that came in 40 50 60
um cannabinoids and that's because it's
an organic cup
all the concentrates were supposed to be
solventless and
we see less and less of those if you
show the general population histogram
for
what we see for concentrates 95 to 96
percent of the concentrates we see now
are all
either solvent extracts or co2 extracts
and there's there's very little water
hash there's very little key
out there these days um and and it's
just kind of what the market is
is determined whereas you know five six
years ago um
it was probably flip-flopped you'd see
maybe 80 or 90 percent
keef in in in water hash you mean once
in a while you get a really cool salomon
extract in
gonna be unique but but with kind of
dabbing coming on and all that stuff
um we see very little of the of the old
type extracts so
residual solvent analysis pretty simple
um instead of dissolving your sample in
a liquid and having all your gases that
you're trying to measure bubble up
um you put it in a much bigger vial in a
solid form
it goes into an oven gets shaking a
little bit
gases get liberated you've got a
partition coefficient you sample from it
and uh um you measure the gas is pretty
straightforward um most of your solvent
extracts that use solvent are made with
butane
or propane or a combination of butane
and propane
there's some people still out there
making extracts with kind of the heavier
hydrocarbons or
maybe alcohol but it's definitely very
few
so um mycotoxins that's another test
that's coming up and it was kind of
brought up um
in in kevin's kevin's talk and uh very
tough one also um with pesticides it's
hard enough to get through the matrix
effects but when you when you're looking
kind of a couple orders of magnitude
more sensitive for mycotoxins um it's
definitely a challenge and it requires
pretty
pretty um expensive mass specs that can
they can go really low and a lot of
sample cleanup
um that's what that talks about so yeah
my time is out
um sorry i kind of hurry through that
but uh yeah that's the testing industry
so
it's definitely been an evolution in the
testing industry it has gotten better
and
and we've seen seen kind of the industry
as a whole get more sophisticated and
growing up and
and so uh um you know it's been an
interesting
interesting trip the last seven years
kind of just seeing the evolution
of the whole cannabis industry and and
and and yeah thanks to medicinal
genomics um for for putting this on and
and that's kind of one of the cool
things i've seen the evolution in the
industry five six years ago
um you know conference at harvard
harvard medical school with with kind of
the uh
the level of of presenters that we had
today um
wouldn't even been on my radar so um
it's been exciting and i can't wait to
be back in seven years and see where it
goes then so thank you