thank you everyone for joining us I am
being joined on stage for the panel
entitled the future of cannabis testing
although I would like to acknowledge
that these people have really been
leaders in the industry for the past
five years I think everyone on this
stage has been testing cannabis and
stringent regulations were even passed
in the state so not only have they kind
of driven the direction of where
cannabis is going to be but they've
already kind of set the standard for
where it is now so for I would just like
to give them a couple minutes to
introduce themselves the audience so you
know who you're talking to so firstly we
know good morning I'm Savino seguirá
I've been testing cannabis in the
analytical setting for the last eight
years working on mostly method
development method validations according
to different state and federal
regulations everything from pesticides
to cannabinoids and everything in
between I'm Steven Goldman
I'm the laboratory director of a testing
facility in Denver Colorado called Fida
Tech we opened in 2013 so going on six
years now and we've been lucky enough to
test over 150,000 compliant samples and
many tens of thousands more R&amp;D so
starting to get to a place where we can
really leverage the data set that we've
acquired good morning my name is Annie
ophea currently scientific director at
can a safe labs I'd like to believe the
largest lab and the world's first
accredited lab in cannabis current
market shareholder testing just about
over a third of the products that go
into shelves here in California
good morning I'm Cindy Orser i'm the
chief science officer for digi path labs
it's a testing lab in las vegas
I have been practicing science for over
30 years I got my PhD at UC Berkeley
where I worked on a biogenic ice
nucleation which is a fascinating topic
I'd like to tell you all about one day
it's basically responsible for frost
injury worldwide I consider myself an
innovator starting with my PhD I came up
with a way to control frost injury but
the EPA prevented that product from ever
moving forward we actually filed the
first environmental impact statement for
GMO so that was very interesting sort of
set the stage for my career I've worked
across many disciplines from toxicology
trying to create a way to measure human
mutation rate of describing D
halogenation reactions how
microorganisms co-opted existing
function to break down man-made
chemicals i've been valid developed
rapid Diagnostics for homeland security
for biological toxins and about six
years ago I fell into what I call the
black hole of cannabis testing when a
headhunter contacted me and asked if I
would be interested in building out a
cannabis testing lab for a public
company in Las Vegas and actually one of
my first hires was any apphia and I
could not have done it without him it
was a amazing experience starting out
with basically nothing there are no
validated methods there were few
certified reference standards so it
really was quite an undertaking
thank you so much and for those who
don't know my name is Andrew Pham from
Alchemist labs we are ad a registered
botanical testing lab of over 20 years
of experience in the lab testing
industry and thank you all for joining
us thank you for caring about lab
testing there's a lot of reasons to care
about lab testing and I don't think you
need to go any further than to look at
the news and think about the vaping
crisis that's affecting hundreds of
people across the country the CDC's
reported over three to five hundred
cases for both nicotine and cannabis
related vapes
most of them sourced from the black
market and I just really wanted to ask
the panelists do you think lab testing
could have prevented this crisis or do
you think it's too soon to say well I
think that lab testing as it currently
stands wouldn't have prevented this
crisis because we're not looking for the
things that are supposedly causing this
vape crisis so we've heard a lot about
vitamin E acetate a little bit about
mineral oil B and and other dope ins
being added to the vape carts in order
to dilute the product or to keep a
proper consistency but unfortunately we
don't
those aren't common things that are
tested for in an analytical laboratory
because they're not contaminants and as
well we a lot of the manufacturers don't
disclose the ingredients they keep them
for Praia Terry and so a lab wouldn't
know and until regulations change in
which they have to start disclosing
these things we might continue to see
this yeah and in Colorado there are
about it's an open market so there's
about 3,000 licenses many but not all of
which test with our company and and you
know less than 10% of them test what's
outside of the required testing panel so
it's definitely the minority of
companies that are looking at these
things we do almost zero raw materials
testing in the state you know a lot of
the manufacturers are just now learning
what GMP or good manufacturing practices
are so you know I think it's it's just
in its infancy right now we're not
quite to the point where we're starting
to think about assessing risks and
minimizing risks during manufacturing so
I agree I don't think testing would have
cut this process correct jumping on that
lab testing wouldn't have prevented this
but it's important to note when the
issue that began it was pertinent for
labs to jump on it and provide as much
information as possible know which kind
of safe did quickly developing a method
for vitamin A acetate although it's not
known to be the culprit but it's a
common denominator in these illicit vape
cards we actually went out and bought a
lot of illicit vape cards and tested
them ourselves
along with some of our clients products
and notice that yes they contain high
levels some up to 40% of atyminius State
oil with low label claims and pretty
much at least 10 to 20 different
pesticides so it's not quite known what
is the cause but contribution of all of
these factors could be very disastrous
so it's important all the labs on tests
for this excipients and whatnot it's
important to jump on it as soon as we
feel that public safety is at risk and I
think it's a responsibility for the labs
in the state to to get on this
additionally perhaps if the federal
government made this federally illegal
it would allow for or not allow for some
of these black market players to be in
the space and perhaps increase consumer
safety yeah I think the whole vape
cartridge issue
we're facing right now is was fully
expected by myself that's for certain
four years ago ago I wrote a blog on the
hazards of vaping there's a myriad of
issues starting with the fact as was
already mentioned that the producers
don't have to list the ingredients that
they put in there
state regulators are so far in over
their heads they don't even realize the
complexity of these products and the
pending health crisis that we could be
witnessing I think the industry for the
first time is going to see class-action
lawsuits because now these companies are
making enough money and there are enough
individuals that are being a being of
impacted there was a case study that was
in the news from the UK a 19 year old
individual who had been vaping for two
years and they shared the x-rays of his
lungs
they were like half-full of a substance
that resembled bacon grease I don't
think it's a good idea to inhale lipids
or to inhale oil droplets and this
points to the lack of oversight and in
this industry and I think that we should
all come together and and require
stricter standards there have never been
any inhalation studies I mean the
tobacco industry got off without having
to conduct these studies for decades and
decades I think that we should insist
that we see some animal inhalation
studies done on the constituents that
are used in these products
honestly I'd like to jump on that that's
important because I think a lot of
producers out there use ingredients that
you know they tout as grass that is by
the FDA you know generally recognized as
safe but those studies weren't done in
inhalation so yeah you can rub vitamin E
acetate or vitamin E oil topically but
it's never been started what happens
when you ignite inhale right and there's
like no like in Germany there's a list
the ingredients that can go in beer and
here we like it's it's just totally up
to the imagination of the producer I
mean yesterday we heard in the terpene
talk that some of these babe fluids are
up to 60% terpenes so terpenes are also
oils and they can penetrate your skin
they can coat your tissue I think one of
the positives from out of this could be
that there will be a return to vaping
flower which I consider to be the most
effective and safe way of using cannabis
all right so thank you very much for
your thoughtful responses it kind of
seems like there's a very interesting
consensus here that you all acknowledge
that the current state of cannabis
testing probably wouldn't have prevented
this crisis from happening so in your
opinions what in the future do you think
what kind of new regulations or new
standards of testing should be
implemented in order to prevent this
from happening well as far as
regulations go they could start
regulating what sort of deal you ins and
other additives ingredients should be
allowed and it should be a very
restrictive list and it shouldn't be
very many things we shouldn't be allowed
to add anything cheap or untested into
that even a lot of manufacturers will
use propylene glycol vegetable glycerin
and these aren't necessarily the
greatest things ever but they're highly
prevalent in the tobacco industry in the
- back in the nicotine vape industry and
so until all of these things start
coming under a set of monitoring lists
that that will look for some of these
additives and regulate them I don't
think there's anything we can do and as
an aside all of these vape cards were
all illegal they were they were not
being monitored they were not being sold
on any legitimate market and so until we
make an effort to bridge the the legal
and illegal markets we won't be able to
control this yeah I would say you know
even simpler than that in Colorado
there's no
we'll process for a product so if you
want to make a product with the
cannabinoid in it you do that and then
you sell it and and as long as you're
not contributing you no flower to the
black market there's very little that
will stop you to do that you know one
example of the openness of the market is
our native nasal spray products which
started appearing on the market and you
know we asked the regulators at the
Department of Public Health are you
concerned with applying products that
could have you know very sensitive
microbial agents in them directly on
someone's mucosal membrane and they said
they're selling those on the market
right now so there's there's literally
no oversight or product approval process
or thought to what additives and risks
are going into these products you know
we were discussing earlier whether these
are acute toxicities or due to long-term
exposure I think Cindy kind of touched
on it earlier in that essentially we're
all you know guinea pigs in this right
so people have been vaping probably the
illicit black market material for quite
a while now and now it's becoming a
problem
so what other issues are we going to see
from long-term exposure to these toxins
Regulation wise it'll be very difficult
to enact regulation to stop some of
these excipients or diluents from being
used because well to do that you need to
perform a study right and generally it's
a long-term thing and I don't see that
happening overnight and you can't just
you know handicap the cannabis industry
from producing vape products but I would
like to say this while you guys are out
here this city I don't believe has legal
shops yet so as you're you know enjoying
your products just be careful what you
buy out there that there are a lot of
illicit stuff out there even mimicking
licensed vendors
so I think first and foremost the
producers should be required to list
exactly what they're putting in their
products that would just be a first step
so full disclosure that you at least
would know what you're vaping into your
lungs I think we probably have gotten to
this point because the industry has is
lightyears ahead of the regulators
because this is such a creative
fast-moving space but overall I think it
points to the issues that surround this
industry because of the disconnect from
state and federal levels and I think
that's what has led the black market
explode and the vape cartridges they're
so easy to make you don't have to say
what's in them you know we have the
synthetic cannabinoid issue as well that
could be a culprit in this but it's
really because we have not had federal
public funding to do basic research so
that we can actually understand what are
the health impacts of not only the
cannabinoids and the terpenes but some
of these excipient so it would be just
really great if there is a source of
federal money so that we could do the
proper basic inhalation studies I think
a good word to touch on is probably
transparency then if they're required to
list what's in their product and I think
manufacturers need to be more
transparent in doing that and
cultivators need to be transparent and
how they grow their products as well
with pesticides you can stuff like that
but kind of pivoting just as importantly
is that testing labs needed to
transparent with their methods as well
so it's a very common complaint I'm sure
you've all heard this that can send a
sample to ten different labs and get ten
different results and some of that is on
us and some of that isn't but there's a
million reasons why that happens and I
was wondering if you guys could kind of
share the intricacies of why there are
inconsistencies between results from
different labs and what we can do to
kind of fix
so it's it's definitely a multi-part
answer so first of all the plants if
you're talking about cannabis flower the
plant itself will very impotant see by
up to 15 percent that we found in some
of our tests that we've done between
laboratories as sort of a gauge to see
okay everybody's testing this different
why is that so we send the same sample
to all these different laboratories and
see how everyone reports back and
different parts of the plant have tested
up to 15 percent of the value as being
different and this is talking about THC
percentage in particular and then the as
well you have the methodologies
everybody's methodology comes with a
certain amount of what they call
uncertainty and so when you have a
certain amount of uncertainty that can
make your release a result you say
that's 26% but actually it could be
really between 24 and 28 percent and
this exists in every other industry in
existing pharmaceuticals that exists in
environmental lab testing and so that's
what we need to educate the consumers
the cultivators a little more to say hey
when you get a result the result you
know it we report it as this but there's
actually a swing from here to here and
that really depends on everybody's
methodology equipment practices and
whatnot but every laboratory should have
that number calculated and so it should
be known to anybody who is actually
compliant with BCC and ice ISO
regulations yeah in in Colorado the
Department of Public Health
actually mediates an inter lab
proficiency test study I think a lot of
you are familiar with the protocol but
there's a 13 page document that
describes how the Department of Public
Health
actually homogenized this flower and
sends it out to the lab so 13 pages just
to make sure that the sample is
homogeneous so it a lot - a lot does go
into it on the sampling side but you
know I do want to reinforce the idea of
transparency you know we're maybe a
little too aggressive with our clients
as well and trying to bring them into
our lab show them our methods you know
force them
look at our method validations to see
our method uncertainty because those are
the types of things that are gonna you
know bring awareness to the consumer end
that that those are the questions that
need to be asked on the lab side as well
I think that's important you know meta
uncertainties is a required calculation
and the newest revision of ISO 17025
2017 and that's something we've
performed at our lab taking into account
all the different factors that may aid
to uncertainties you know technician
pipetting whatnot and unfortunately it's
not reported in the co way due to
various reasons for one it's not
required by the state but it can always
be asked by our client what does
uncertainty values are and you know
savino they're totally right there's a
wide range and a lot of things factored
into that apart from your method
uncertainties is you know statistical
sampling generally when you get the
complaints it would be from a client who
sent one but one lab one but another lab
but there were two different samples so
you can't expect to get the same results
out of that even the spread of things
like mycotoxins or pesticides are not
homogeneous throughout the plants if you
do apply them so it's really difficult
to say that you know whether you can't
compare apples to apples in this case so
I think it's important for labs to
really work on not labs with industry
just think of statistical sampling
homogeneity well how does that play into
what values you get from the labs and
how are you really offering off that and
one way we see this difference is or one
group that does it well is let's say in
terms of the emerald testing running
that and sending to you know labs across
the nation and applying statistical
analysis to the values that are reported
what is the spread if we have a certain
margin a sample that sent through that
would be the the factor to consider that
would be where to look how are the labs
really different from each other apart
from their method uncertainties as
opposed to just a random you know sample
data client or somebody sent two
different samples to two different labs
obviously I agree with everything that
was said so you know collectively this
is all called measurement uncertainty as
any set that's a term common in
analytical chemistry but not widely
understood by the regulator's and as any
said it is an ISO 17025 requirement now
to determine your measurement
uncertainty for every analyte you
measure in the lab and typically a
measurement uncertainty in our lab for a
cannabinoids is six percent that's not
six points so it's not like twenty
percent versus twenty six percent its
0.06 of that twenty percent and and also
in analytical chemistry and a plus or
minus fifteen percent is pretty good so
if you are coming in with a thirty
percent THC a value that means you
should accept or expect a range of
twenty seven percent to thirty three
percent and in fact I have advocated
since day one and Nevada and I've
probably said it in Colorado is that we
should be reporting ranges not an
absolute value because of all of the
kunal of the components that add up to
your measurement uncertainty and I would
also like to say that one of the biggest
contributors to the difference between
labs is which certified reference
standards they're using a colleague of
mine Breanna Cassidy who's a lab
director at CDX analytical and in
Massachusetts did a comparison of five
different companies certified reference
standards for cannabinoids and she found
a 17 percent difference so you can see
right there depending on which reference
standards your lab use this versus a one
you are comparing it to that
could could alone account for the
difference in the results so you all
touched on a very important thing and
it's statistics statistics can be used
to kind of even out these results so I'm
a lot of labs right now are reporting
things as singular true values without
reporting that actual measurement
uncertainty so what do you think it will
take for labs to actually report within
a range rather than a single true value
what it's going to take the regulator's
to allow that and it's going to take
some public education to all of these
clients that are getting the results
that say okay what is this range mean
how do we interpret it why aren't we
doing a single number because when when
it comes down to it people are using
this number to value the product and so
they want to value it on a single number
because it's easy but unfortunately
things don't work that way it science
doesn't work that way plants don't work
that way so we have to educate all of
the the consumers as to okay well when
you have a range this is how you deal
with it this is you know it's it's
normal it's something that should be
anticipated and you know you have to
account for that saying twenty-five
percent versus twenty six percent is not
significant in any of the context that
we're talking about yet a lot of
cultivators and dispensaries will use
this as a price breaking point you know
luckily a lot of the industry on the
manufacturing side is moving towards GMP
right and part of GMP is producing a
product to specifications specifications
obviously have a lower and an upper
limit you know and so the concept of
these range is I think is going to
become more and more comfortable on the
manufacturing side making it more
acceptable for us to report it from the
laboratory side so so luckily I think
over time this problem will probably
take care of itself but you know I agree
that the regulator's have to be the one
giving us the big initial push right
nothing more to I had essentially it
will be up to the regulators because if
you look at it this way if my lab is
giving a certain value for so
crop and they additionally tested at lab
B with a higher value well the client
tends to go with that LabVIEW of a
certain higher percentage because well
it's more value so until the regulator's
can stop and ask for reporting in a
range based on your method uncertainties
this will not change
another part another really important
statistical thing that you brought up
Savino was kind of how things are
sampled before they get to the lab so I
know in California you were actually
required to send a sampler and they have
to follow that internal lab SOP and make
sure they get a statistically
representative sample but if you just
have a client that's submitting one
sample and trying to do an entire
formulation on it what would you say to
them in order to get the best
statistically valid sample how would you
ask them to collect their sample before
it gets to your lab well if it's a
flower I would ask them to collect lots
of different size buds from different
parts of the plan or if it's already
mixed up you know did select from
different physical locations in the
batch if it were concentrated asked them
to heat it up and try to mix it and
homogenize it as much as possible same
with a liquid and sample from different
parts of that and and have them realize
hey this is as representative as samples
we can get but expected to vary by this
much it may vary by 10 to 15% so when
making their formulations for edibles
take that into account and not try to be
at the very edge of what's legally
allowed of the 10 milligrams per edible
just realize hey there's a little bit of
a swing if you try to make all of them
ten there's a possibility that one might
come outside of an acceptable range and
I would try to work with them and do it
multiple times so that they really get
used to how to sample and how to
properly submit them for testing and
then how to properly formulate their
final product yeah California has pretty
set rules for statistical sampling for
compliance but when it comes to R&amp;D you
know it's up to the lab and generally
what we've seen is people make kilograms
of oil and they have in 15 different
jars but they will bring you you know or
a two gram sample - from one jar and
that's not representative of the whole
of the whole lot so we usually get to
each bottle Sam
from each bottle marginally and run that
because what has happened many times is
you sample from one jar let's say for
contaminants it's you know
clear clear of pesticides however
because you collected different
fractions through your run certain
fractions will have higher levels of
certain pesticide that you know was in
the crop and now you've just completely
missed that and when it comes to
compliance sampling now you're
statistically sampling it per California
rules of about 0.3% and now things pop
up that they miss in R and B because
they did not sample Rd representatively
and in Nevada the regulator's tell us
what we can take which is 12 grams per
every 5 pounds of the labs do go out and
do this collect the samples themselves
but at the site we are supposed to just
take one gram from 5 pounds and that is
what is analyzed for micro so you know
it's it's very arbitrary how that came
up was based on some sampling document
that somebody read about how they sample
you know pill manufacturers but actually
we need here from Colorado because I
think Colorado finally came up with a
good sampling strategy they did so we
have not man mandatory sampling so I as
the laboratory and almost never go out
into the field and do the sampling it's
all in the manufacturers in fact if I
offer to go do the sampling I've never
never been taken up on it yet so the
samples that we get are pretty
interesting in Colorado there are some
sampling SOPs that are pretty fantastic
where you take twenty nine half gram
samples from different points around the
harvest if it's a flower harvest or
similar statistical methods for
concentrates but you know almost nobody
adheres to those SOPs right now so I'll
still get my
one very nice green flower for potency
and my one very nice brown flower for
microbial testing
[Music]
so kind of pivoting a little bit I just
want to bring us back to one of the core
tenets of good science and that's
collaboration obviously to do good
science you can either collaborate with
different minds different viewpoints
kind of see problems from different
perspectives and come together for a
certain solution but in the lab testing
industry it's a little bit hard to do
that a because you can't ship samples
across state lines because it's
federally legal be because we're
actually in competition with each other
rather than kind of on the same side
from a business perspective that's kind
of in contrast with the spirit of
science but I think there are
opportunities for labs to collaborate I
think a lot of labs just don't know
about them so are there any ways in
which you think that collaboration would
both help your business and help your
science well I think collaboration would
absolutely help in a lot of ways one of
them is being able to share data about
contamination be able to share data
about some of the interferences that
different instruments have with with
cannabis so trying to find one pesticide
in particular cannabis strains with
different instrumentation I think it
would be really beneficial for some of
these laboratories to share and avoid
getting false positives or false
negatives and as well sharing a chemical
profile data terpenes cannabinoids and
whatever because really if these if
we're really gonna understand this plan
we definitely need to look at this data
in a big aggregated way and no one
laboratory has enough data to really
make a significant set to really tell us
something about the plant so alone these
datasets aren't worth very much but
combined I think they they can do a lot
so we need to figure out a way to
incentivize laboratories to share data
and then share in whatever profits
couldn't possibly come from that data we
have 11 the numbers always fluctuating
but we have 11 laboratories performing
testing in Colorado at any time
we have formed a nonprofit organization
actually called the Colorado Lab Council
where all of the labs meet usually on a
monthly basis to discuss some of these
issues and so that's one way that we've
kind of organized a way that we can chat
and keep the lines of communication open
but you know I personally don't believe
that you know I'm in competition with
most of the labs out there right I need
them to exist myself right I couldn't do
it alone what I'm in competition with is
actually just bad science right and and
so we've asked a lot of our competitors
to actually come into our lab into our
laboratory in in you know and ask to do
the same of their laboratories and so
far only four of the other laboratories
have taken us up on that but you know
four is a lot better than zero right so
slowly we're changing I think the
perception of collaboration and and
transparency in the state yeah
collaboration is very important I mean a
prime example is a heavy metals talk
that we just did with Kyle can a safe
kind of writes itself and is wanting to
do more of that in the future
collaborate with not just other labs but
other scientific minds and I think it's
important however there's a few things
that kind of prevents you know data
sharing or analysis of data regulations
from the different states for instance
if we want to interpret cannabinoid data
California requires moisture to test be
added so values are seemingly higher
than maybe Nevada that doesn't add
moisture or terpenes or using different
instrumentation I think until we kind of
get to either a compendium method or are
more open with our methodology it'll be
harder to evaluate that data accordingly
because of minor differences but it
isn't very important in the scientific
industry obviously to share data what
that data has to be accurate and
reproducible and I might say that that
method method standardization helps that
a lot so as our methods become more
standardized
we're actually able to share that data
because we're not trying to project an
IP of a method where our IP is in the
rest of this laboratory and yeah that's
true that's true actually one thing we
usually encourage your clients if they
disagree with the data that I produce I
encourage them to send it to another
accredited lab that I you know sir
trustworthy we've compared our values
are we looking at the same lob that look
use instrumentation similar methodology
similar I ask my clients to actually do
that and I think you know that's a way
to kind of bridge start to collaborate
slowly and start you know some somebody
new one said it's a co-op position and I
think you know it's a very important
phrase for sure the flap business
depending on where you're located can be
very cutthroat and very competitive but
I've been able to find collaborators
across the country and I feel like I
have a very rich experience because I
have other lab directors that I can call
up and and discuss certain issues for
example getting in a new edible every
edible we get in it's like a mini
research project we have to first pry
out of the producer what they use to
make it and then we basically have to
deconstruct it and try and extract the
cannabinoids and terpenoids
that they expect to see so I think it's
changing I think you know the lab
business is not the segment of the
industry to be in if you're looking to
make a lot of money because it's it's
just not happening in the lab business
so I think because of that and the we're
getting a higher quality scientists
involved so scientists are just
naturally curious and they do like to
collaborate because science is a layer
cake and all of these different analytes
we've had to develop methods for it
works much better if you have
collaborators to discuss it with
yeah so from a research standpoint you
guys are actually in a unique position
because if you're doing a federally
sanctioned study and you can only get
raw materials from one source but you
guys are actually getting things from
your state that are hitting the shelves
really high quality products and
presumably clean if they're actually
hitting the shelves so do you think the
labs have a certain kind of a advantage
in having in ways they can research
novel ideas and new products just
because you're getting so much of these
into your labs for example any you're
doing the research on heavy metals and
big it's a really great pilot study and
how would you say to other labs to
encourage them to do things similar to
that um honestly getting beyond simply
being there to make money
you have to generally are sciences are
here for the science you know making
money it's a bonus so we have to get
away from that mindset it's cannabis and
maybe we don't care or maybe we're here
to make money but that's not the case
in my lab we generally we genuinely care
and we have fun while doing it if you
ever look at an Instagram post we have a
lot of fun but we care about the
consumers in the industry and you know
the collaboration it I had the idea but
I give credit to Kyle and Robert who
came to me with what they wanted to do
and then we collaborated so it's being
open to people that are contacting you
or seeing what's out there what is a
consumer safety risk
what can you study that would make a
difference and I think the data that we
collect in the lab kind of gives you an
indication of what you can pursue next
we were getting in a lot of vape cart
failures in heaven metals so while
something had to be done start studying
what's going on with these vape cards
why are they failing so you know ideas
like that come up and you kind of pursue
it and find some other brilliant minds
to collaborate with yeah I would say you
know we've never had the thought of
competing with manufacturers right but
our goal is more to assist the
regulators right we have a pretty
limited list of solvents that we test
for in Colorado
but you know analytically it's not it
not much of a challenge to look a little
bit deeper right so part of the value in
our data set is actually providing that
for the regulators and saying you know
hey maybe Athol acetate is something we
want to add to the list we're seeing it
so often and at such concentrations that
it may be worthwhile or maybe there's
another solvent that we want to take off
the list because we never see it so we
see our data set as being a little more
valuable in that manner that we can kind
of drive public health in the direction
that we want to see it go and I just
want to add to that that most analytical
laboratories are their main business is
the product analysis and so the time and
money to do any kind of outside research
is very limited and so we cannot get to
the extent that you would see at a
university or anything that had outside
funding for their research specifically
usually the chemists are trying to do
this in-between trying to handle their
clients and other samples so I think
that as the industry matures as a
competition kind of falls out and the
main laboratory players survive they'll
have a little bit more time and
resources to dedicate to this research
and I think we'll see more and more of
that as as time goes on yeah and I will
just say that having the ability to
conduct Rd Studies for our clients and
things of interest to us is is really
what makes it palatable and the fact
that Nevada does let us use our retained
product for our indeed that's a
legitimate use of it so that is one tiny
sliver of brightness in this industry
and I can tell you there are endless
number of experiments that could be done
it's so so that's exciting
I'm something that's just on their
horizon is a hemp testing so it's kind
of like what the cannabis industry we
hope will become in the future so right
now the big kind of a testing
consideration for hemp is that the plant
material itself has to have less than
0.3 percent THC on a dry weight basis
and this is actually way more
complicated than people think it is so
what kind of like technical
considerations do you undertake when
you're testing have persons cannabis
well it's pretty much the same methods
as you would test regular cannabis
flower you'd make some alterations to
the sample prep and and that's about it
but they're very minor what the the big
issue becomes is that these regulations
and they say 0.3 percent THC these were
set years ago when gas chromatography
was the standard and so now that the
industry has evolved over the last
thirty years we need to go back and look
at those and say alright does that mean
just 0.3 percent THC or is that combined
THC THC a and I think that's how a lot
of people go about it just to be careful
but we really need to get clarification
and updates on those regulations to know
exactly how we should go about it so
this is a special topic for me I'm
strongly advocating for the ability to
use molecular genetic screening to
distinguish industrial hemp from resin
CBD hemp and drug type THC cannabis
because what we've shown we've actually
developed a a molecular assay called
true hemp ID it's based on two genes
snips that can make this distinction
across these three groups we've tested
over 500 samples and we have shown that
what is being grown in the US right now
that 68% of it is over 0.3% THC and the
definition from the 2018 farm bill is is
decarboxylated THC were so we're talking
about Delta 9 plus 0.8 7% of THC a-and
and that is really shocking I mean you
don't have to be an expert you can drive
down the road at 35 miles an hour and
you can tell that is resin CBD hemp
because they look like little Christmas
trees they basically look like marijuana
and it's not industrial hemp which is
more like an erect stock so I think this
is a critical issue for that for the
hemp industry is that we get some levy
ation from that strict 0.3% cutoff for
THC
we actually are seen that a much more
reasonable cutoff is 1% and the state of
Vermont has already adopted the ability
to use genetic screening as well and
we're just hoping that the federal USDA
when they release their regulations will
provide that alternative you know that's
a very good point because from the
testing we've done if you take a look if
you have dried flower of this so-called
hemp
most of them are over 0.3% when it's
dried and ready for consumption now in
the CDP H Department of Public Health
California said specific set of rules on
how to test hemp here and matter of fact
can't say if it's been testing a whole
lot of compliance hemp lately from the
farms here and it's easier to be less
than 0.3% when you're taking into
account the whole plant mass so the CA B
pH says okay you have to dry this hemp
before testing to a certain consistency
till the mass stops changing essentially
and follow through the certain
procedures but when you take the whole
plant mass with the stems and everything
on the leaves and test it generally yeah
you'll be perfectly fine with a less
than 0.3 percent THC however you get a
dried but
trimmed maybe for smoking or whatever
and you will find that it will be over
0.3 percent THC so how do we deal with
this arbitrary number I think you know
it's still a challenge and and that
reflects the older methodology that they
used to use for testing cannabis that
was seized by law enforcement they used
to just put the stems and seeds and
everything together grind it up if you
look at a lot of an item methods from
90s and 2000 they just ground everything
up together which is not how anybody
consumes it anymore right exactly and
that's what we've been seeing and so
when you get that value and
testing by HPLC represent that acidic
molecule and you know you'll have people
asking well can you write by GC well
generally people are not using GC
because you want to see the full profile
of the plant but it can't be done but
you know it goes into what you were
saying before when you do use GC and
grind everything up you know there's
other considerations as to whether
you're actually accurately quantifying
that THC with your GC and lead and the
rotation whatever you gotta do and your
results are much less efficient than the
0.87 times th CA that they recommend of
lines up being more like 0.5 yep so we
got time for I think one last question
this is something I personally wondered
what do you guys think is the most
technically challenging part of cannabis
testing and what do you think the
greatest demand for good scientists lies
in the States I've worked no doubt the
most technically challenging are the
pesticides because basically you're
looking for contamination that is a
similar molecular weight to the actual
main ingredients and so you're looking
for something in the parts per billion
range in noise that is in that is way
way higher thousands and thousands of
times higher than that and so that that
becomes a bit of a challenge and it's
been a challenge in a lot of different
states they set these pesticide levels
really really low before actually
testing to see whether they are actually
possible with instrumentation that's
currently available and we've seen this
in Nevada as well they took captain off
the list because the state lab wasn't
able to see it consistently down to the
level at which they demanded everybody
else do it for the last three years so
there's a lot of learning there and I
think to me pesticides is the most
challenging requires the most expensive
instrumentation the most extensive
instrumentation and I think the most
sample prep and then these guys could
probably comment on that as well yeah I
think you know the battle between
wanting to look as low as we can
possibly look for for public health
versus achieving that in the
laboratories you know never gonna go
away but I would think you know in terms
of someone who I want on my team
communication to the industry is one of
the most important thing
right oftentimes in a competitive place
if you fail somebody they're gonna go
somewhere else where they don't get a
fail right so communicating that that's
not a fail that's an opportunity to
improve on their manufacturing process
is a delicate one in something that's
not inherent to a lot of scientists so
definitely something that we try and be
really sensitive about I think it's any
kind of touch it in earlier it is the
various matrices that you get in every
time you know I never cease to be
surprised in this industry and it's it
is truly a little science project each
time a week ago we got a candle and
infused with CBD so imagine a candle
infused with CBD now how are you really
receiving the benefits but that's beside
the point
but then testing elucidating the CBD
from this candle and all this there's
all sorts of excipient source all sorts
of matrix interferences so we have to go
in on low science project you know bring
out the chemistry bird go back into how
can I extract my CBD in the midst of all
this interferences with compounds that
are eluding at same retention time same
similar structures conflating results I
mean we see everything from that
toothpick suppository
you know gels just name it there I never
seems to be surprised so it actually is
what keeps this industry and it's
exciting for me because never know what
you're gonna get in the door that day so
that is a challenge on its own and it's
up to the most reputable labs or
thoroughly vetted labs to be able to
accurately extract and analyze these
compounds in these various matrices and
that could lead to having you know
hundreds of SOPs depending on you know
what you get in the door water is
another big one not only are they
infusing water but it's being
encapsulated so there are certain
encapsulations that you have to break
membranes to be able to get at the
molecule or even concentrate down you
imagine a 8 ounce or 16 ounce bottle of
water and there's five milligrams of CBD
in there and so somehow you have to
concentrate that extracts from the
membrane
and report accurately so some of the
challenges remains but you know that's
what makes this work fun I agree with
all the comments I'm not sure I even
remember the question but there are a
lot of challenging things in this
industry and you know when when a state
comes up with the list of pestis so on
the issue of pesticides they come up
with the list of pesticides these are
the pesticides the lab is gonna spring
for so great I won't use those
pesticides you know there's a hundred or
200 other ones so the pesticide game is
a big issue and in nevada we're also
actually instructed if we see another
pesticide not on the list that we're
supposed to say hey you know we saw this
and in fact we do and it's actually for
me it's really disappointing at the
human level that growers are willing to
use these pesticides that we know there
are neurotoxins we know that no one
should be inhaling them and we see them
pop up so that's one thing that's really
annoying that and disappointing it's
annoying and it's disappointing this
game that's being played with regard to
pesticides the other thing is because
the value of cannabis is based on its
THC content if a grower at some point
got a 30% THC a and we come back with 28
he will go lab shopping to get to your
point
Stephen you'll go lap shopping and he'll
find a lab that will give him what value
he wants because the frailty of human
nature we see the same spectrum of
personalities existing within the
cannabis testing space as well yeah it's
a really interesting phenomenon it's
like you go to a doctor and he tells you
you have a disease and you're like I'll
just go to a different doctor it tells
me I don't have it
well it's just very strange but anyway
so we're short on time I like to leave
the rest of the time we have to open up
questions for the panelists so if you
want to make your way to the microphone
please do but in the meantime let's give
our panelists a round of applause first
one up good morning thank you through
this wonderful panel so you've been
talking a lot the title of this panel is
the future of cannabis testing and we've
talked a lot about measurement
uncertainty and different matrix types
I was curious what you think about what
Labs might look like in over the next 10
years do you think Labs will start to
specialize you know I could easily see a
lab that only does flour and concentrate
and then a lab maybe that's also
registered with the FDA later testing
mostly edible products could could you
speak about how you see cannabis testing
evolving over the next five to ten years
well in every other industry you would
see labs specializing you'd see a lab
specializing and doing pesticide testing
you'd see a lab specializing and doing
this and that and and if you submit your
stuff to a lab they could sub out to
other laboratories that's how you would
see it in environmental testing a lot a
lot of states especially California has
specifically prohibited that but I think
we'll see over the years that's starting
to change and having it start to mimic
what we see in other industries for sure
in a lot of the ways labs can
distinguish themselves is by offering
other value-added tests and so I think
you'll start to see a lot of
diversification that way you know some
labs that will do lipid omics some labs
that will do full smoke and vapor
testing and everything down the line
there most definitely once it becomes
federal legal it essentially will be
necessary it's there's really no other
industry where you're forced to use all
this different instrumentation in one
space and still report those results
within two days it'll change I think
we'll see centralized lab testing
because the way it's set up now it's
it's really rather absurd that
at a minimum you need two million
dollars just for the basic
instrumentation the spectrum of tests
that have to be carried out is extreme
so centralized testing I think will also
see an expansion of genotyping testing I
mean a digit path we do a lot of
genotyping we do snip analysis so as
growers want to protect their IEP or or
defend the fact that it's really is blue
dream there will be more mandatory
mandatory genotyping I believe thanks hi
my name is Garrett two quick questions
in the state of California specifically
it's based in the BCC that we have to
take up to 32 increments whenever you're
sampling a batch large batch of flour up
to 50 pounds realistically are you going
of looking at this 50-pound batch after
you confirm that it is indeed 50 pounds
and taking 32 increments where we have
this competition between labs that you
like you only only see them taking 11
grams to 13 grams in order to complete a
full panel well you do have to take
those increments and we actually do and
you know a lab should be recording those
increments now you you're not
necessarily going to wait there 50
pounds because you're not carrying that
scale so you have to rely on the track
and trace system such as metric that you
know they are following those rules we
can't police all of that but you have to
take those increments and you really
need that mass based on what the BCC is
now required half gram minimum sample
mass for each analytical test you'll
find that you'll quickly run out of that
half man especially if you have to do
replicate analysis which have to be in
duplicate and have to concur and if they
don't concur you have to repeat that so
if a lab is not taking the required
amount well you know kind of it's bad
news for them and yeah thank you second
question really quick what would you all
look for inside
of a compliance officer for your boards
right because some control consultants
are kind of saying that compliance is
not science which is absolutely absurd
it makes no sense inside of an
analytical lab but I've also seen the
other spectrum where like the compliance
officer is like a full PhD statistician
modeling algorithms for diabetes and
their communication style isn't
necessarily the best either so what
would be your sweet spot for your
compliance well you definitely want
someone who has experience either doing
compliance for a laboratory or working
or running a laboratory to the degree
that they were they were themselves
tracking all of this information that's
required to be tracked you definitely
need some science literacy to be able to
do this or either that or if you have
just compliance experience you need a
lot of training to be able to fully
comprehend all this data that's coming
through and then check it every day
because as a compliance officer you're
gonna be checking every single result
that goes out and and trying to catch
mistakes that either the director didn't
catch or the technician and you're
playing devil's advocate on your
pretending to be the state and saying
okay if I were going through this what
would I try to point out where all the
possible mistakes that could have
happened here oh yeah it's very
important I mean I can't say we have
more than one compliance officer and you
need a high level person you you're
talking about the state requires that
you produce a data packet per sample
that you produce out there in the data
packet includes chromatograms your raw
data your Ben Sheets everything so you
have this essentially 100 page packet
per sample that you receive in and for a
lab that tests over a hundred samples a
day you can imagine what kind of work
that takes so you need a team and not
just any you know Joe from the street
being your compliance officer amazing
thank you so much I think we only have
time for one more question
hello my name is Christian saucier my
question is we've heard over the last
two days a lot of call-outs for more
collaboration across competitors about
data and more specifically even across
borders a lot of this is really relevant
to clinical research obviously you guys
are potentially more on the consumer
side but are your labs involved you are
you seeing any sort of meaningful
industry-wide effort for third part
independent third party obviously to
help collaborate all this that that can
help you aggregate once you know and
while you retain ownership with it but
help you as an apps to aggregate your
data together so we can do proper
analytics in the future yes we we
certainly are I mean we ourselves have
published two or three papers on large
datasets where we've analyzed the
cannabinoid content versus terpene and
obviously the the terpene profiles are
way more informative than the
cannabinoid but from as a third party
companies like Leafly or even confident
cannabis we know that cannabis there
they're making efforts on comparing
datasets across the country actually
even the Emerald tests when they do
these blinded tests where they send out
blinded samples and then you see where
you come in across all of your peers and
they have the median and the
distribution and so little snippets of
data like that are incredibly
informative but one of the barriers to
combining and compiling all of this data
from different labs it's the fact that
we're using different certified
reference standards we're dealing with
this confusion of strain naming where
growers will change the name of the
strain from when you pick up the sample
before you get back to the lab and so
strain aims don't necessarily have as
much meaning as they may have at one
time therefore the importance and need
to move toward incorporation of genetic
testing with all of these samples but
the effort is is happening yeah and I
think the market is starting to demand
it more and more we're starting to see
demands from cultivators manufacturers
to to sort of get together and see okay
how can you make your methods be more
similar such that the data can be
aggregated such that if we take
something from
here and tested here and here that the
results will be not exactly the same but
at least within a reasonable swing and I
think it'll happen more and more as the
industry grows and as everybody's data
set gets kind of bigger and as you have
larger companies corporations that until
now haven't been getting into cannabis
because of the federal ban on it
you'll see them getting to banking now
they'll have their bank accounts we'll
be able to get into this industry and
then they'll be able to purchase these
data sets or at least work with these
other laboratories to learn what they
learn and once there is a financial
incentive I think you'll see a lot more
people collaborating you're done well
that's all the time we have we will keep
you from lunch but ladies and gentlemen
our panelists give them around the clock
[Music]
[Applause]