foreign
[Music]
Coffee Talk podcast where we talk with
the leading Minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I am your host Ben amaralt I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the can Med conference
all right here we are we're in November
already and you know what that means the
holidays are right around the corner and
with that comes a lot of things to do
people to buy for parties to plan
wouldn't it be nice if you could check
something off your to-do list right now
well you can you can register for can
med23 if you haven't already heard can
Med 23 will be taking place May 15th
through 17th at the Marriott Beach
Resort on Marco Island
this industry-leading event will feature
three full days of cannabis science
content from more than 30 presenters and
instructors representing our key Focus
areas of science medicine cultivation
and safety testing and new for cam
mid-23 we will also explore psilocybin
and psychedelic mushrooms
now due to the limited capacity of our
new location cam at 23 is an invitation
only event and we expect that it will
sell out so if you've already gotten
your invitation to cammed23 please
register and get that off your to-do
list and if you haven't head over to
cammedevents.com now and request your
invitation I hope to see you there
Our Guest this episode is Dr Ziva Cooper
Ziva is the director of the UCLA
cannabis research initiative in the Jane
and Terry Semel Institute for
neuroscience and human behavior
she is also an associate professor in
the department of Psychiatry and
biobehavioral Sciences and Department of
anesthesiology at the David Ruffin
Institute of medicine her current
research involves understanding
variables that influence both the
therapeutic potential and adverse
effects of cannabis and cannabinoids
through double-blind placebo-controlled
studies one of the variables Ziva and
her team are studying is the difference
between men and women and their response
to the abuse related and pain relieving
effects of cannabinoids and the role
that circulating hormones and
endocannabinoids contribute to these
differences and that's the subject of
our conversation today we talk about the
key differences in how cannabis affects
males versus females how females
metabolize THC differently than males
cannabis use tolerance differences in
males versus females how female
reproductive hormones play a role in
sensitivity to THC the importance of
placebo-controlled studies and male
versus female differences in
self-reporting pain side effects and
more
before we get to my conversation with
Ziva I want to thank this episode
sponsor planetary
planetary is the first and only organic
certified water extracted cbda
female founded planetary is truly
plant-based Wellness designed to keep
you moving and playing as the only
company to use water extraction
planetary keeps cbda in its raw living
form the way it's actually grown in the
hemp plant
cbda is 18 times more bioavailable than
CBD and is a powerful anti-inflammatory
acting on the same pathway as NSAIDs
like ibuprofen for more information
visit planetary.com that's
p-l-a-n-e-t-a-r-i-e.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr Ziva
Cooper
[Music]
good afternoon Ziva thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast
Ben thanks so much for having me on the
cammed Coffee Talk podcast it's great to
be here all right so today we're talking
about sex differences when it comes to
cannabis and I got the idea for this
topic because we were gonna I was
excited to have you on the podcast and I
was looking through the many
Publications you've authored and
co-authored and I noticed one of the
most cited is sex dependent effects of
cannabis and cannabinoids a
translational perspective uh which I
thought would be a great topic to dive
into and I noticed that there are other
papers in your in your repertoire who
that explored sex differences so I I
imagine it's a topic that's that's close
to your heart or at least
um very important to you so I guess my
first question to you is why do you feel
it's an important topic to explore when
it comes to cannabis
I think in general there's an increasing
awareness of how important it is to look
at both sex and gender effects across
medical research at this point right so
it's interesting I was looking at some
some of the landmark cannabis studies
back in the 1970s and all of those
landmark cannabis studies involved only
men between the ages of like 19 and 30
and I just think that you know since
then we've evolved so much
um in our appreciation for really
understanding how
biologically and also culturally how
important it is to understand
across you know pharmacological classes
and across different Medical Health
endpoints
um the differences between men and women
are males and females and so you know
cannabis is definitely not any exception
to this and it's especially relevant
given the fact that there's been a sharp
increase in cannabis use among females
over the last decade and specifically
medical cannabis use so we're starting
to see that a lot more women are
starting to gravitate towards using
medical cannabis for specific
indications and that even more gives us
you know the real justification and need
to understand the effects of cannabis
and cannabinoids between both men and
women
and understand if there are differences
and why there might be differences
between the two sexes
great and so what I imagine one of the
main differences could be and you can
tell me if this is the case are there
sex differences when it comes to the
endocannabinoid system
interesting
um so we know that there are
fluctuations of endocannabinoids across
menstrual cycle phase
um so you know we know that even in
women themselves if you just take them
that their endocannabinoids are going to
be changing over the course of of that
month at least in
premenopausal women we don't actually
know very much about how these how the
fluctuations in in post-menopausal women
and of course this is becoming a area of
Interest especially since a lot of women
are turning two cannabinoid-based
products for
perimenopausal symptoms
um there's been some documented studies
looking at the CB1 receptor in humans
using Imaging techniques and how those
receptors change over time and how there
are differences as a function of sex and
age so you know we're learning more
about the endocannabinoid system and I
think that
um some of the key studies that
that have tried to understand
differences in the endocannabinoid
system between males and females are
a lot of them are based off of you know
the pharmacological studies so
understanding
um differences between males and females
in their response to THC and what are
some of the
um
hormonal modulation of those differences
of THC and so that kind of gets at
sex differences in the endocannabinoid
system
great okay so let's let's talk about the
effects of cannabis and how they may
differ so what are some of the key
differences that have been observed When
comparing how cannabis affects males and
females
the key difference is thus far that we
know of
um again I always like to to turn back
to the animal literature and a lot of
that is is rooted in that in that one
paper that you first talked about
we've learned a lot from the animal
literature with respect to how males and
females might differ and what we're
doing now in the human lab those people
who study humans Volunteers in the
laboratory is we're really trying to
translate what's been observed in the
animal studies and to see if those
effects are
are preserved or translated to to humans
so some of the key things that
pre-clinical researchers or animal
researchers have found is that
across the board female animals seem to
be more sensitive
to thc's effects now you know THC has a
lot of different effects and what's
interesting here is that females seem to
be sensitive to a lot of those different
effects so it's not just one end point
it seems to be a number of different
endpoints for example
females appear to be more sensitive to
the pain relieving effects of THC
compared to males and here again we're
just we're talking about animals here
female animals are also more sensitive
to what we call abuse related effects of
THC and THC like drugs compared to males
now it's interesting
um in those animal studies is that
although there is clearly a sensitivity
to THC into two THC like substances in
female animals compared to compared to
males what's interesting is that when
you when you give these groups of
animals THC or THC like substances
um these drugs repeatedly for many
different days let's say for two weeks
or three weeks what you see is that both
groups do develop tolerance right so the
effects of the THC will be lower such
that you'll you'll need higher doses to
achieve the same effect that you get
with that first day of Drug
Administration
but what's interesting is that among the
female animals the tolerance is much
more Stark so the female seem to develop
tolerance at a much faster rate or at a
higher magnitude than the males
um and we see something very similar
um in in our human studies
we can go into that a little bit then if
you like
um where what we've found this is
similar to the animal studies where you
know females
um women will actually show a blunted
pain response when exposed to THC I'm
sorry a blunted analgesic response when
exposed to THC compared to men but
what's interesting is that we see this
specifically in in people that are using
cannabis every day or almost every day
so we're we're dealing with a population
there that is that is using cannabis on
a daily basis and presumably
probably more tolerant to thc's effects
and let's say somebody who's using
weekly or maybe you know bi-weekly
um what's interesting also is that in in
that group of people we're not looking
at people who who have a chronic pain
condition where we're looking to see in
a normal healthy population if we look
at a pain response
um due to a painful stimulus will THC
decrease that pain response and so we
see that pretty clearly in males but not
but not in females and so we're building
on that now to understand
um how much this tolerance play a role
in that effect so do we see the same
effect in people that don't use cannabis
every day or several times a day and
also
to what degree do do the hormones do
female reproductive hormones play a role
in in differences here between the males
and the females
excellent so now you mentioned animal
studies versus human studies so
are you seeing a lot of the results in
the animal studies you know confirmed by
human studies or is there a departure
there
so thus far based off of the the studies
in in our laboratory as well as other
people's studies it does seem like
there's an inter interesting kind of
parody here between uh the animal
studies and the human studies so it
doesn't always work out such that
um
what's observed in the animal world is
necessarily translated into humans right
I mean humans a mouse is not a rat is
not a non-human primate it's not a it's
not a human right so we have there's
there's a there's a long chain of
evolution here
um and so it isn't always the case that
what we see in a rodent model is going
to be translated to to humans but there
are some really nice
um data suggesting that there is some
nice translation between between animals
and humans here and one of these areas
um is with respect to how males and
females metabolize THC differently and
how pharmacokinetics and the way that
the way that THC is metabolized of the
pharmacokinetics of THC
we think probably has a
um direct effect on
its impact on physiology and behavior
right so if somebody metabolizes THC
very quickly into metabolites that are
inactive then that
plays a role in what we're going to see
on the behavioral endpoint the
physiological endpoint
and so what's nice is that other labs so
lab and Johns Hopkins with Ryan vandry
and spindle and and scholar and others
they you know they've found in humans
that um females
metabolize THC in a different way than
males in a very similar way that's been
and show that's been shown in animal
studies as well where females
um will show higher levels of an active
THC metabolite after a THC
Administration compared to males so that
active metabolite is 11-hydroxy THC and
the group at Johns Hopkins also sees
this effect where females will show
greater 11-hydroxy THC levels after
being exposed to THC compared to males
so there there have been some nice
parallel parallels there as well
excellent so males and females actually
metabolize THC differently I have that
right
yeah so based off of animal studies and
and based off of human studies
um as far as as we know right now you
know it does it does seem like they are
metabolizing the THC differently now why
are they metabolizing the THC
differently that's like uh you know
that's an important question it could
have to do with the
um the metabolic enzymes they might be
different in both in both
um the animals and the humans with
respect to males and females
um it might have to do with other other
aspects that impact metabolism
um in our lab we we're looking at uh
differences in how THC is metabolize or
the pharmacokinetics of THC between
males and females
to try and understand
why there might be a behavioral
difference so why it is that males and
females might respond differently to THC
on the pain relieving aspect of things
as well as other aspects like mood
related effects abuse related effects
and we're also looking to see if maybe
some of these differences are due to
differences in
endocannabinoid levels and so we're
drawing blood from women to see if the
differences that we see between males
and females if they're somewhat
associated with differences in Baseline
endocannabino levels or is it you know
are differences really rooted in levels
of female reproductive hormones which is
an interesting variable also because in
animal studies there's data to suggest
that
estradiol
plays a significant role in the
sensitivity to THC in female animals so
it does seem like females food
productive hormones do play a role in
sensitivity to THC
great and now how wide is the difference
yeah I mean you say that you know
females are more sensitive or they
metabolize THC differently is it vastly
different is it slight
right so in science we say significantly
different right right
um but no so here's here's a sense of
things um Ben
um
this is one difference and again we're
probing this right now to figure out
what variables are underlying this
effect and it's something that I
mentioned before where in our volunteers
who are using cannabis daily and again
they're not medical cannabis users
they're using for non-medical reasons
but when they come to our lab and we
give them cannabis
with THC in it specifically I'm not
talking about other cannabinoids at this
point when we give them a cannabis with
THC and we look at the pain response
between males and females essentially we
see a significant
analgesic effect in the males uh such
that you know it's significantly
different from Placebo if you looked at
the data you'd say okay they the males
in this group the male Volunteers in
this group are getting some pain relief
here when you look at the females the
the female volunteers after a smoking
cannabis with THC in it essentially they
look like they just received Placebo so
Placebo cannabis with no THC so there's
really no difference they're not getting
um any type of that pain relieving
effect of THC that the males are getting
and so in that case it is quite a stark
contrast between the two
we have and keep in mind again these are
people who are using cannabis every day
and so we think that there's probably a
development of of Tolerance the
development of Tolerance is probably
different between these two groups and
males and the females
um as shown in in animal models we're in
animals when you expose them to THC
every day the females will show this
robust tolerance to the pain relieving
effects of THC that the males show but
not as as significant of an effect there
are other aspects where we don't
necessarily see such a stark contrast
um so for example
among some of our female volunteers when
we ask them how how them how much they
like the Cannabis you know what kind of
good effect they have
um they'll they'll rate that cannabis as
having a good effect to a higher level
than the males the male volunteers and
that's also it's similar to what's shown
in the animal models but it's not as as
Stark of a difference as you know what
we see on the pain relieving end of
things
um so I think that depending on the end
point
depending on the person
um depending on how much cannabis
they've been using and for what reason
they've been using it
will probably probably see differences
in the magnitude of
how much sex plays a role in cannabis
effects
um and
you know it's it's going to take time to
work out what are some of the variables
in play here
um but it will be really important
information I think
as more women are turning to cannabis
for pain in this case right for for pain
relief
understanding you know what
what
can people expect with respect to the
dose that might be helpful the mode of
administration so here we're just
talking about
um inhaled cannabis right what happens
when they use it orally right and so
that's a that's a very different
metabolic process that occurs when
people when people are using THC orally
And So It ultimately the hope is that
this information will be helpful in
informing people what they might expect
when they use THC and other cannabinoids
for pain relief
both for the pay relief side but also
you know potentially for some negative
aspects as well so you know it's been
shown the Groupon does Hopkins has has
shown that females might be more
sensitive to the anxiety provoking
aspects of THC right and so that's
something important to relate to uh to
the community as well is that you know
females might be more sensitive to that
aspect of of cannabis as well
yeah no I think that is important and
now I wanna
talk about you know the difference
between animals and humans again because
correct me if I'm wrong but when you're
measuring the effects of cannabis in
humans a lot of it's self-reported
correct where you know the the patient
is telling the researcher you know yeah
it reduced my pain or yeah it gave me
anxiety talk a bit about the difference
between males and females and how they
re they self-report because when I spoke
to Daddy Mary on the podcast a while
back he he observed that there was a
difference that you know the females
might be reporting more information or
have more thoughtful responses and then
the males need a little bit more
prodding to get to get the information
out of them yes Ben and I think that you
know you're hitting the hammer on the
nail of how important it is to do
placebo-controlled studies especially
when you're relying on something like
self-report right and so when you do a
placebo-controlled study what you can do
is you're essentially looking if it's a
what's called a within subject design
where the person is exposed to all the
different drug conditions so in the
placebo-controlled study they're exposed
to the placebo drug and they're also
exposed to the active drug so in this
case let's say it would be cannabis
without THC and nothing else or Placebo
cannabis and then our cannabis with THC
and then what you would do is you can
subtract out the placebo response from
the active response and so there you're
you're actually looking at
people as their own controls right and
so yes females they might show
differences with respect to their
self-reported
pain or their or their self-reported
um
anxiety uh or how good of a drug effect
they have but presumably they would have
a similar
um
a similar self-reported
um behave self-reporting Behavior under
the placebo situation as well or under
the Lo the very low cannabis dose right
whatever whatever you're doing in our in
our lab we generally look at a couple of
different Doses and so you're able to
kind of subtract out that type of effect
but you're right so animals are are you
know they're they're good test subjects
right because
um you don't have to worry about if
they're blind to the dose uh you know
you're you're really looking at
objective measures of of behavior there
that you can that you can you know feel
good about the data and say that you
know these are objective you don't you
have to worry about the animal telling
you things but at the same time
at the end of the day you know when
you're talking about patients and you're
talking about thinking about how certain
medicines might be helpful or you're
thinking about
um
uh symptoms and disease states it is so
important that the patient can
communicate to The Physician or to the
scientist to the researcher about what
it is they're feeling right so you know
when somebody talks about pain and and
the objective measure of pain what to
what level does this chronic pain
patient have an objective measure of
pain
versus what they're telling you how and
how much pain are they how much pain are
they feeling right now
when you're giving them a medicine
you know to help reduce their pain
hopefully you know you're really trying
to get at that you know what they're
what they're telling you they feel you
know so having an objective measure of
pain is important but really you know
they're self-reported pain is really
critical and also understanding
how that self-reported pain might be
impacting their quality of life for
their daily functioning and so those are
other proxies that I think are really
important to address when doing you know
randomized clinical trial of chronic
pain patients and understanding how
cannabis and cannabinoids might be
helpful so having a a range of endpoints
there not just self-reported pain but
also understanding how is that pain
impacting you know the
holistically their life
um from that lens
right yeah because at the end of the day
we're just trying to help people feel
better right exactly yeah
yeah all right so I wanted to shift a
little bit and maybe talk about how
males and females use different cannabis
products
um is there much information around that
so Ben I think that
um
there there are data and you know I'm
I'm terrible I forgot
I can't I can't recall
a good study that has looked at how you
know women are using cannabis products
versus men and what the you know are
there differences like I do
inhaled cannabis even though there are
lots of different products available now
inhale cannabis is still the most
popular mode of administration at a
population level
but what we hear is that you know from
media sources and you know anecdotally
is that you know females women might be
using
um oral cannabis products
um they may be they might gravitate
towards those more than inhaled for X Y
and Z reason but and I can't I don't
have a good paper to you know usually
like I I like to pull out those peer
review Publications and say this
researcher and this place demonstrated
that females use this mode of
administration where the males
um I will say though that you know as
the Cannabis Market is evolving we are
starting to see products that are
available specifically for medical
indications in women right and so some
of these products
are geared the the way that they're
administered are specifically geared to
females
um and so you can imagine some of those
different products that might be geared
more towards females that don't really
aren't relevant for males
um and I don't necessarily know you know
the rates of use of these types of
products among females I think it'll be
interesting to see over the long term
you know as there becomes some
generalizability with respect to what's
available across States right because
right now states are functioning very
differently and you know there's one
product that's available in California
but it's not available in New York City
I think over time as you know the dust
settles and there is
um there is some continuity between the
types of products that are available
across States it will be interesting to
see what types of products females are
using what are they using them for
um compared to males and
how do the motives are the reasons for
use differ between females
um
and you know as an example like there's
certain
um Health indications or you know
medical issues that are more prevalent
among females than males for example
fibromyalgia right so
um more females have fibromyalgia than
males and so what type of products are
are those patients uh drawn to we have a
um a study look we haven't talked about
cannabidiol yet but we have a study here
at UCLA that I'm working on with a
principal investigator who I
um who's really wonderful her name is
um Vino ranganath and she's a
rheumatologist and we have a study
looking at cannabidiol for rheumatoid
arthritis
and what we're finding is that you know
as expected we have a lot of females in
that study just because you know
rheumatoid arthritis occurs at a higher
frequency among females and males and so
you know that's an example of over time
we're going to see how
different
um males and females might differ with
respect to their reasons for cannabis
use as well as the type of cannabinoid
they're using and the mode of
administration
yeah you're right we have been the the
conversation has been centered a lot
around THC so what do we know about the
other cannabinoids are there sex
differences there as well
yeah and even in the pre-clinical
literature right now then
um you know this is an area that is so
new uh
as far as I know you know the one or two
studies that I've looked at cannabidiol
and sex dependent effects and animals
they haven't really found
Stark differences
um and I know that uh there's been a
study
um comparing males and females with
respect to cannabidiol and hail
cannabidiol again this was our
colleagues at Johns Hopkins
um that show that females might be a
little bit more sensitive to how the
drug makes them feel how cannabidile
makes them feel compared to males but
you know this is just kind of the tip of
the iceberg you know cannabidiol
understanding how males and females
differ in their response to cannabidal
what about some of the other
cannabinoids that people are using now
people are being drawn to for example
Canaveral CBG
um CBN so we're seeing in California you
know CBN is becoming more popular people
think that CBM might be helpful for
Sleep
um so are there sex dependent effects
with CBN what about terpenes right and
so you know we're starting to see an
Emerging Market of cannabis based
products that have specific terpenes in
them and so are there sex dependent
effects with terpenes too and the truth
is is that it's hard for me to
hypothesize if there will be a
difference because even in animal
studies right now they're haven't really
been
good efforts to understand if there is a
sex dependent effect in part because the
studies on those cannabis constituents
are kind of just starting also so you
know I think that pre-clinical
researchers are now just trying to get a
hold of what do these terpenes do what
do these minor cannabinoids do
and then to try and delve into you know
are there differences between males and
females so there's a lot of work being
done in this space and I think there is
a lot of attention being paid to
how
sex can impact
the biological if that's physiological
effects
um
effects in the central nervous system so
over time I think we'll get a better
picture of
you know what's happening as a function
of sex and then also you know we didn't
talk about sex versus gender you know
and I think that's also a really
important topic that as scientists the
scientific Community as a whole I think
were just kind of waking up to you know
understanding does gender how somebody
you know defines their gender not sex is
a biological variable but gender you
know can that also impact
um how people use cannabis and
cannabinoids and what the outcomes might
be and I think over time as well we're
going to see uh some nice data in that
area specifically because I think that
the the funding agencies are starting to
pay more attention to this as well so
you know this idea that you know there
can be sex dependent effects of drugs
um you know we're able to really look at
this in part because there is funding
available to to study it because there's
clearly an interest and need for it and
there's also funding from federal
federal sources
and now you know the NIH is is becoming
very interested in gender as well as sex
so it'll be
you know interesting to see how the
stories how the story unfolds over time
yeah for sure and I've been trying to be
precise in my language and and say sex
and male and female but I did want to
you know ask the question too that you
know we've talked a lot about the
biological differences and are there
cultural differences that could be
playing a role here and that would sort
of factor into gender identity
absolutely and I think that
um you know we think about
socio-cultural differences I mean
you could take you know the United
States as an example I mean even with
respect to you know what jurisdiction
you happen to live in and if that
jurisdiction
um has
cannabis dispensaries is there
um a perception of stigma around
cannabis because that will also you know
impact
what people are using and how they're
using it how open they are with our
physicians to talk about it or are they
in a place where there's dispensaries on
every block right and so that just in
and of itself like you know you're where
you are geographically who who you are
um socializing with what is your family
like what is
um
what's your occupation right um all
these different aspects are going to
feed into
you know who is using cannabis for what
reason
um and what are some of the Health and
Social outcomes of of their use of
cannabis um will it be
helpful or will they feel like their you
know their uses
um stigmatized and
um will it have to be done
um you know secretly for whatever reason
or are they are they scared of law
enforcement all these different things I
think are going to go into over time you
know
what is the impact of
of cannabis use on health outcomes right
yeah a lot of things to consider all
right Ziva Before I Let You Go I want to
give you a chance to mention any other
papers or resources uh that you could
share with the audience if they want to
read more or um and then for you
personally if there's social media or a
website that you'd like to plug please
let us know Ben thank you so much for
the opportunity so one thing I would
just like to plug we talked a little bit
about this in the very beginning was
um you know the importance of looking at
age as well as sex so so we know that
there has been a really
uh
sharp increase in cannabis use among the
older population
um and we know very little about the
impact of you know the pharmacokinetics
and pharmacodynamic effects of of
cannabis in in the older population just
because that's probably been studied
very much
and so understanding you know the
effects the potential therapeutic
effects potential risks associated with
cannabis use in that older population
but also as a function of age so like I
said before we know from animal studies
that you know reproductive hormones play
a role in thc's effects well what
happens you know when when we reach an
age where you know
circulating hormones change drastically
right specifically in women who are
perimenopausal or postmenopausal and so
at UCLA we are we're we have a grant to
actually look at this question that
we're really excited to look at not just
you know inhaled canop cannabis with THC
but also look at Oral THC Administration
as well so to try and understand you
know differences across mode of
administration
um so we're really excited for that and
you know just a plug for our Center at
UCLA so the University of California Los
Angeles we have a center for cannabis
and cannabinoids in that Center we have
our our lab that does control Drug
Administration studies but we also study
cannabis from a public health
perspective public policy perspective
it's a really wonderful Center
um so so you know feel free to look us
up UCLA cannabis and then you know we
have a Twitter handle as well although
we're not that good about about keeping
up with it but it's UCLA cannabis so
thank you so much ben for having me this
was a really wonderful conversation yeah
I really enjoyed talking with you and
we'll put links to all those resources
that you mentioned in the show
description so it's easy for folks to
find and yeah thanks again Ziva this has
been great and hope to see you out in
Canada
great thank you so much you too
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Dr Ziva Cooper check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and thanks again
to this episode's sponsor planetary our
next episode drops December 7th that's
two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out the
new and improved canmanevents.com the
team really did an exceptional job
updating the website with all the
information about our camid 23 event and
of course you can still find videos of
all the previous can Med presentations
and panels and the can bed archive you
can also find all the previous episodes
of the podcast as well and while you're
there make sure you sign up for email
alerts to get all the notifications
around this Innovative industry-leading
event I also invite you to engage with
us on all our social media platforms
we're on Instagram Facebook Twitter and
Linkedin just search for candid events
and lastly please leave us a review on
Apple podcasts doing so really helps us
improve our rankings and reach more
listeners
all right that's it from us stay safe
stay healthy and be sure to join us on
the next can Med Coffee Talk
[Music]
foreign