welcome back to the can med coffee talk
lounge here at canmed 2022 i'm here with
any afia lab director of candisafe
chief science officer oh i am sorry
chief science officer india thank you
for correcting me
good to see you annie thank you thank
you for having me it's uh great to be
back at an in-person event now oh it's
fantastic i'm glad you were able to make
this happen yeah yeah and now in your
opinion what's the main value that you
get out of coming to conferences like
kmed
honestly the networking is invaluable um
just the ability to socialize and given
what's happened in the last couple years
just the ability to socialize with folks
that's invaluable but for me it's about
the tidbits of new information that you
always learn um you know the cannabis
plants so complex that anytime you get
to sit with some bright minds and and
see what they've been doing over the
last year or so in this case it's been a
few years
lots of great research i'm really
excited to really get to learn
especially what we've just been through
with medical practicum oh yeah you were
sitting in on that one yeah we're
sitting on that one and it is fantastic
i tell you
no matter how much you think you know
even if it's a regurgitation of the same
information from
previous years you always find things
you've missed previously
just being able to see the research
that's done not only on individual
cannabinoids but also
on whole plant medicine sure it's been
fantastic i mean we're learning more and
more about this plan um i think it was
uh dr sulak that spoke about there are a
whole new class of compounds that are
being found
that have to do with um
tryptophan or so in the cannabis leaves
i mean it's really interesting stuff
that you get to learn every time you i
come here so yeah no it's interesting
you say that too that even if you think
you're a
cannabis medicine or just a cannabis
expert there are those little tidbits
that maybe you didn't pick up on the
last time and that you can take away
yeah precisely i mean it's just like um
a little bit of relearning i mean in
anything you do you have to practice
right so even if you know we're just
hearing it again over and over it starts
to stick and you get to understand a
little bit more so i think it helps us
all in the industry just grow absolutely
um you mentioned the practicum any other
presentations at kmed that you're really
looking forward to um well i mean apart
from mine
um honestly i see a lot of great info
coming out of there i'm looking forward
to hearing what dr muchum has to offer
um now he'll have a video presentation
it sounds really interesting
with what he's got coming up so yeah i'm
really looking forward to that excellent
excellent um so your presentation that
you mentioned that we're all looking
forward to um is about preparing for dcc
standardization
and i know that one of the problems that
the dcc is looking to solve with the
standardization is lab shopping so
i was hoping you could maybe explain
what the problem of lab shopping really
is and how it kind of negatively affects
multiple factors of the industry um yeah
so essentially
lab shopping is when uh your clientele a
certain clientele go from lab to lab
either looking for specific results or
at least going to be able to compare the
results that are being given by the
different labs and potentially find
favorable results and from a certain lab
and they would get testing with that lab
for their compliance coa so this is
generally done in r d
um and as we know california has uh 40
something or so labs so there's plenty
of options
to continually you know travel and check
labs out until you find your favorable
results
um you know unfortunately it's one of
those situations where it's it's
not positive for anybody
i like to put it in a sense that
everybody loses in that case you know we
talked about how for one a consumer
loses let's say for instance you're
talking about a potency result if
somebody's shopping for certain
potential results on flower sample
a consumer ends up buying a sort of a
potentially inflated result right you're
paying more for something that's not uh
particularly what you thought it is so
right you lose you lose money right
there um even the
through a distributed distributor
getting sold that way if you're paying
higher because of a potentially falsely
high result they're losing they're
paying more you know all this sort of
leads to a slippery slope where
regulators lose control
think about even the labs that do this
thing so labs start to lose in a sense
that uh they are producing these false
results labs that don't produce this
end up you know maybe losing revenue
eventually closing down or you know
laying off employees in that case the
employees lose right keeps going
employees lose right they potentially
get on unemployment
state loses right we as taxpayers end up
paying for this so it's just a slippery
slope of
continual losses that um there is really
no winner in this game yeah no and you
mentioned that there's a large number of
testing labs in california and there is
i imagine some
pressure of labs to give favorable
results in order to like you said keep
keep their business open so yeah that's
a really unfortunate situation you know
it's really unfortunate and yeah there
is that high pressure and it's it's not
easy i mean i've faced that pressure
myself you just have to be able to
you know be able to meet your consumers
or i should say your clientele's need
without going into unscrupulous areas
sure right
somehow it's not easy to stay in
business but there are plenty of ways
lab can stay in business as they sort of
pivot around kind of cannabis testing
there's much more you can do apart from
you know potentially giving um inflated
potency results sure yeah and i know
that one of those ways that labs can
kind of provide more value to their
clients is offering more r d testing or
offering testing services that aren't
necessarily on the compliance panel like
virus testing for example and i know
that you would it can safely be doing
that
precisely i mean we're always looking
for uh what offers more value again this
industry we're only getting to learn a
little bit more um
there's so much more to learn we're only
learning very tidbit of what it has to
offer so yeah we're offering um some
value-added services like
viral testing hlvd beat curly we're also
looking at stability testing you know
something that folks are not really kind
of um most folks are not paying
attention to but they should be because
that's coming up as you start to talk
about expiry dating how are you really
determining that is it per ich guideline
so we start to offer some of those um
value-added services that uh are
undervalued yeah that's excellent no
kind of going back to the issue of lab
shopping and potency in particular i got
to imagine part of the issue with that
too is just this idea that thc values
are the determiner of quality um and
maybe if that weren't the case then
there wouldn't be so much pressure in
getting those high potency numbers you
know that's really it i mean that's a
great point um we're you know you go to
your dispensary and the first thing you
see is usually you know you have several
shelves and they have the top shelf and
it's really the thc numbers that get
highlighted
it's really interesting because the labs
do all this work to produce a beautiful
coa with all these assays terpenes and
other things and yet the thc gets
highlighted and nobody
apart from the buyers and sellers ever
really gets to see that coa it's really
meant for the consumer um so there's a
lot more in there that i think we need
to pay attention to you know a lot of
i'm starting to do a lot of work on some
other compounds such as flavonoids we
know has some great medicinal effects
just to push the attention away from thc
you know i'm starting to see
interestingly even states starting to
put limits on
thc um there is state like mississippi
that's coming out with regulations that
um they're actually limiting their
flower to 30 percent so essentially if
those regulations thick when you test a
flower that's above 30 it's an automatic
fail wow and the interesting thing is
they're um adding in all the thc so the
variance the
thc delta a and all of the above so um
it's something that perhaps maybe it's
not such a bad idea yeah right well
especially when you consider that
flower testing
uh
especially when you consider that flower
is rarely ever higher than 30 that's
true you really got to consider what is
the
capacity you know how much did the kind
of flower really produce right uh we're
looking we're talking in terms of
percent mass right so 30 percent is
really pushing it and some some reason
you know there are folks that grow 30
flour i think it gets pushed a little
further because we're doing by dry
weight right the labs are
the regulations that you should test by
dry weight so when you say it's 30
and then you it's about 12 percent 10
moisture and you add that in right it
bumps it up to high 30s and now you're
pushing 40 so people can kind of see how
you know depending on how that moisture
content and how that dry weight is uh
is added back into the math yeah you
start to push those limits so the real
flower percentage really is around maybe
mid-20s but then you end up pushing 30
because of driveway interesting no and
that's funny too when you said that in
mississippi if you test higher than 30
percent you see you might fail right so
you may have some lab shopping going the
other way right
it's really interesting because that's
what's going to happen so now
i guess if you grow anything good
relatively good don't go to mississippi
um right so lab shopping is going to be
the opposite way
now when you consider that you'd have to
yeah add in all these other thc
components um
also it's not even just flour they're
the regulations state something about um
uh concentrates or limited to 60 so
forget how all this 90 vape pens and
isolates
and whatnot so it's going to be
interesting to see if any other state
kind of adopts those sort of regulations
or if those mississippi regulations
actually stick yeah that is one of the
interesting ways um it's one of the
interesting outcomes of having multiple
states enacting different regulations
right it's kind of like all these little
test kitchens so you can see how these
regulations work yeah very true very
true and you know it's sort of what
exacerbates the condition we're in with
the different states having different
regulations so you know these
multi-state organizations may have um
producers in certain states you know
they they look for certain type of
results in another state they look for
another type of result so there's got to
be some kind of congruency in this
result we have to start to be able to um
standardize some of these things right
it comes back to standardization yes sir
so in addition to your talk on
standardization you're also
participating on a panel discussion
that's all about nutrients and the role
that they play in yield on cannabinoid
output i'm curious from the testing lab
perspective do you see a lot of
correlation between
nutri uh certain nutrients that are used
and sort of the the values that you see
on your tests you know that's very hard
to pinpoint you know great question
uh we do get
client requests to sort of do a nutrient
analysis
um but what ends up happening is
it's hard to say for a fact that it was
because of certain nutrients that you
are having this certain profile
what we do try to do for some of the
nutrient analysis they're looking for
you know you're looking for things like
calcium magnesium potassium all of those
is we have to sort of determine the mass
balance so
what is your input
and then you're testing the runoff water
what is that and then you're testing the
plant how much is left in there and
you're trying to do sort of a mass
balance okay my plan is up taking this
much and it's wasting this much or this
much is going to the runoff and and see
at what stage is uptaking certain
nutrients or is it just being you know
washed off essentially
but it's been quite difficult to exactly
say because you use a certain nutrient
mixture that your terpenes were greater
certainly there's an effect
but i think more research has to be done
it's definitely an effect on using high
quality nutrients and the right uh
proportion of nutrients at the certain
growth stages that's something you have
to consider that it's not you know the
same throughout is not a pre-mixed new
that you carry throughout the process
um
but it's really interesting to note that
yes you know something i meant to say
was that
um when we talk about nutrients not just
you know the beneficial one so things
like metals
um if they happen to be in the nutrients
the plants holds onto it sure what i
found is that it's really cultivar
dependent you know a lot of people do
flushes at the end but we found that
certain cultivars like for instance
cadmium we'll hold on to that a little
bit more so if the same nutrients that
unfortunately contain cadmium was fed to
your entire grill different cultivars
you'll find that there's varying levels
of cadmium some passing and some failing
the regulatory limit once you do your
final coa
um just because of how the plant
actually holds on to that you know we
know these plants as a bioaccumulator is
uh yep but they can be released but the
residual levels are different for
certain cultivars yeah that's
interesting no it's interesting it kind
of it echoes the idea of the entourage
effect right like you have multiple
nutrients that are kind of having a
synergistic effect to help your plant
most certainly most certainly i think it
plays throughout the whole uh cannabis
uh
industry yeah really yeah
and even here at cam ed it takes all of
us from all the different disciplines
from the
scientific directors here into the
medical professionals to all come
together to better understand this
that's the beauty of it that's the
beauty of it covering all facets you
know that the
clinicians are learning from the
analytical chemistry we're learning from
the clinicians and it's all being tied
together i mean i don't think any of the
work can be uh separated in that sense
you we can we sort of have to work
together because uh
um you know whether they like it or not
the results are always tied together so
um
you know some i like say this but
somebody always said all boats rise in
the tide and that's always clear in this
industry all right i think it's a great
place to stop so
thanks again annie chief scientific
officer of safe i got it right this time
thank you thanks again to our sponsors
medicine women health
and the hemp coffee exchange