[Music]
welcome to the caned Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
ameral I'm the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the the team that puts on the camed
Summit all right the camed 25 abstract
submission portal is now open and will
be until November 15th so if you have
done any novel research in the areas of
cannabis science medicine cultivation or
safety testing we want to hear from you
if your abstract is accepted by our
Advisory Board you will receive a 50%
discount on the camed 25 full Summit
package which includes three nights at
the Windam Grand rainforest Beach and
Resort with all the associated
amenities full access to the caned
medical practicum industry workshops
oral and poster presentations and
networking events and all-inclusive
meals which include a welcome reception
lunches and themed Beach dinners not
only will you get to present your work
on the stage at camed 25 but a video
recording of your presentation will be
added added to the canmed archive and
the medicinal genomics YouTube page for
additional exposure after the event and
let me tell you more than one of our CED
videos have reached up to six figures in
views use the link in the show
description to submit your abstract
today or go to camed event.com and click
the button our guests today are Megan
bang and Cody Peterson Megan is the
Revolutionary force behind trusted Canon
nurse with over 10 years of nursing
experience in diverse Fields like
oncology labor delivery and hospice care
she brings a unique perspective to her
practice she also holds National
certifications in three nursing
Specialties and a master of science
degree in medical cannabis
Therapeutics Cody is the chief science
officer at the kma and a practicing
pharmacist with a passion for
cannabis-based medicine given his
diverse pediatric Pharmacy experience
and knack for educating Cody aims to
educate as many people as possible about
the medicinal potential of
Canabis Cody and Megan have launched a
new IRB approved survey through the
University of California that aims to
better understand the signs symptoms and
challenges of cannabinoid hyperemesis
syndrome they want to understand the key
indicators of this condition hear about
any remedies that work and learn more
about navigating Healthcare as a CHS
patient if you or someone you know has
suffered from CHS and are over 18 please
take a moment to fill out their
survey not only will you be helping this
vital research but participants will be
entered into a drawing to win one of
three $100 gift cards I'll put a link in
the show description so it's easy to
find during our conversation we discuss
an overview of CHS symptoms early symp
symptoms and the prodrome
phase clinical experiences treating CHS
patients the potential causes of CHS
challenges in diagnosing and treatment
and abstinence from
Cannabis before we get to my
conversation with Megan and Cody I'd
like to thank this episode sponsor
trusted Cana
nurse trusted Cana nurse was founded by
Megan bang and Arian Williams two nurses
who are dedicated to Bridging the Gap
between traditional medicine and the
world of cannabis and
psychedelics they specialize in creating
evidence-based treatment plans for all
ages that address chronic illnesses
treatment resisting conditions mental
health autism and more learn more at
trusted Canan nurse.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Megan bang
and Cody Peterson
[Music]
good morning Megan and Cody thanks so
much for joining me on the
podcast morning thanks for having us all
right well I'm excited to talk to you
both about the mysterious canabo
hyperemesis syndrome longtime listeners
of the podcast or perhaps people who
have checked out the camed archive may
be familiar with CHS we've done a couple
episodes on it and I know that Ethan
Russo presented at cmed 24 about some of
the research that he's done but really
the first time we discussed it at canmed
was back in
2019 and if I remember correctly we
actually kind of had a hard time filling
that panel because the topic was still
very new and not a lot of people knew
about it but you know since then
awareness has increased but there are
still a lot more questions than answers
when it comes to CHS so I'm thrilled
that you guys are are doing the good
work to try to better understand this
condition but with that said I always
like to start with the basics for folks
who might not be familiar with the topic
so Cody would you please summarize CHS
what we and what we do know about it
yeah thanks again Ben uh for for the
complimentary words there's a lot of
people talking about this topic because
it's increasingly important because more
and more patients are showing up with
this collection of symptoms and really
it's kind of a a pretty simple list of
symptoms it's uncontrollable nausea
vomiting episodes of That So this
lasting for hours or even days and we
see this associated with someone who's
using cannabis very regularly oftentimes
daily or more and these are uh
refractory vomiting condition that does
not respond to normal antiemetics
but is often relieved by um a somewhat
peculiar phenomenon that is hot showers
or bathing and talking very hot you know
in the shower is the only time they're
getting relief from this very intense
nausea feeling um and sort of that
little collection believe it or not is
the is the vast majority of what we know
or what we're what we're trying to call
CHS um but there's a lot of questions
around that as well um but definitely
repeating episodes of intense nausea and
vomiting doesn't respond to other
medicine patients who consume cannabis
and might be relieved with hot
baths great Megan anything to add
there um we'll get into it all right
very good all the things I have to add
cool and so kind of before we get into
you know the different things that we're
curious about or you know that we're
trying to uncover with CHS I was curious
about the two of you being clinicians
you know your experience dealing with
patients who are kind of suffering from
this um so yeah let's talk about that
and Megan maybe maybe you can start
there like um have you worked with
patients suffering from CHS and sort of
what do those cases maybe have in common
or what's unique in what you've seen
yeah uh before we get into that we'll
plug the study real quick that we are
recruiting right now for our CHS survey
where we're it's a two-part survey where
people will answer detailed detailed
questions on their CHS symptoms and
their cannabis use history so um I don't
know where we're going to post the link
but um we're recruiting for that be
multiple places we're going to it'll be
all over the place yeah I'll definitely
put it in the show description for this
episode too so people can e easily find
it perfect perfect thank you um so what
I see oftentimes I see people in the
early stages of CHS in What's called the
prodrome phase which is Phase One of CHS
and this is a phase that can last for
months years
maybe even a decade or two and common
symptoms of prodrome are waking up with
morning
nausea um anxiety like kind of GI upset
heartburn just not feeling well and
alcohol intolerance is one that were um
that's surprising a surprising like
early symptom but very common among CHS
patients and so I get those people a lot
that that say that they have these
symptoms and oftentimes cannabis can
help these symptoms you know they wake
up feeling nauseous they use their THC
and then they feel better for a limited
amount of time and then eventually this
rolls into the hyper medic phase and
I'll let Cody um we sort of touched on
that that's sort of like what we're
characterized with which is this intense
nausea and vomiting once again for no
other reason you know when you come into
the hospital where I see patients in the
hyperic phase um they're not reaching
out to me online but rather I I still
work in a a traditional hospital setting
as a pharmacist and we're seeing
patients come in in these these intense
bouts of vomiting kind of unaware of
this unwellness or the cause of this
unwellness that Megan just described for
extreme periods of time and now they
come into the hospital we do what's
called a full workup we scan them we we
check every you know potential cause of
nause and vomiting the top 20 most
common things that cause vomiting in
kids and none of them are they're all
clear you know you might find a little
inflammation in the belly or something
like that but generally almost nothing
and um sometimes if they don't say
anything about their THC use we don't
even know right because we didn't do a
urine screen we weren't looking for it
this again I deal with kids so they're
under 18 so they might not be honest
let's be honest adults are also not
telling their doctors about their
cannabis use and so they go undiagnosed
and so we frequently see this with
patients with c HS as well is they get
into this hypomesus phase they kind of
recover they fall back into this
unwellness maybe they have a GI doctor
they're in the Health Care System but we
don't know um and then they bounce back
in this intense vomiting the right
person or the right doctor or the right
lab those sort of three things align and
there's a light bulb moment like ah this
is probably cannabis um and I see this
with some some frequency I mean look I
saw a patient definitively with this
condition last two nights ago in the
hospital and then last night I was asked
to come see check out a patient um and
and assess whether they had CHS and and
it looked like probably not and so like
there are times where this isn't the the
diagnosis but I'm seeing this more and
more in person myself who's a big
skeptic a huge proponent of cannabis I'm
not trying to to demean the plant or or
raise alarm Bells but the Cannabis
products whether it's the itself or
something else in these products is
causing this syndrome this collection of
symptoms in an increasing amount of
people American citizens our friends
smoking legal weed potentially are
getting sick
why no and you touched on a good point
the the amount of cases are growing is
that just because of a better awareness
we we're better able to identify it or
is it potential something else there's
evidence to say that that's that you
know well into the knowing about this
disease like
200 five is when it was first described
now this this was actually first
described in in Australia by by a doctor
who noticed this in these patients who
had been consuming a lot of cannabis
word kind of slowly spread and we've
seen more and more there's still a lot
of lack of awareness and there's still a
lot of stigma so we're seeing both sides
of the coin of overdiagnosing and
underdiagnosing lack of awareness or
lack of sharing right it's all kind of
swirling to make a bad situation for
patients who are just really trying to
understand why they're sick and most of
them have no idea that it's their their
cannabis which they believe to be highly
medicinal and have very little negative
effect and that is the case for the vast
majority of our patients um but for some
reason and Ethan Russo you kind of
alluded to maybe for genetic reasons
there seems to be some patients who just
cannot tolerate cannabis um in large
doses over long periods of time you know
we don't fully understand why
yet excellent no and you I was glad that
you brought it up Megan about sort of
these early warning signs of CHS um and
it seems like you you've described them
so when patients come to you with that
um sort of what is your advice or a way
to sort of uh prevent them from getting
to the hyper edic stage well first I
asked a lot of questions on what does
their use look like how long have they
been using tell me more about your
symptoms and what you know what you're
feeling and what you're experiencing um
a lot of them have like almost textbook
exact same stories they've been using
for a long time they wake up with
morning nausea uh cannabis helps a
little bit you know in the interim um
they seen 10 different doctors they've
been treating with two different three
different GI medicines yes you know like
they've done all the scans they've done
ruled everything out no one seems to
know what's actually causing their
illness and it's not just not just belly
pain or the EM the emesis it's this
overall malaise and like uh the
prodromal phase is not fun people don't
feel well even though they're not in the
vomiting phase so those individuals who
haven't figured out that it's the
Cannabis they're consuming daily or or
near daily is what most it seems have
developed it although there's some
variability there that we're trying to
tease apart in our study like how often
are individuals developing this
consuming is it once a week or does it
seem like everybody's consuming multiple
times a day you know are they smoking
High CBD flour or is it mostly high THC
products are you getting your products
in the dispensary or are you growing
your own and there's so many questions
that we don't have at least even like
weight to right it's just sort of
opinion that we've heard on the internet
and so we were really trying to put some
weight to that and help guide doctors
and uh inform patients about what could
be going on with them yeah and I think
one of the one of the really interesting
nuances of this syndrome is that it's
not is how the THC can help in the
interim but it's when
patients get towards you know not
consuming they've like maybe that's
because they're they've either been
sleeping or they go on vacation and
that's when the symptoms tend to start
to rev up and they start to have like
the nausea the GI
distress Cody what else do we see but we
see that in oftentimes like days two to
three of abstinence from canabus which
kind of that that rebuts the whole neem
oil pesticide thing that like in the
absence of that wor seeing these
symptoms I would say the other two
things that that are pretty commonly
seen and yes sometimes in the morning
not exclusively by any means are um in
thermo disregulation which is a fancy
way of saying my temperature is
fluctuating a lot I feel hot and cold
I'm sweaty I'm I'm you know flush but
not feeling not being able to regulate
that normally and ex intense anxiety
abnormal anxiety uh you know it's you're
kind of like your heart's already racing
in the morning and you're already Doom
and Gloom uh and stressed about your day
but you're just started like and that
not normal for you some individuals that
that is actually just their Norm um but
you know when it when it's not then this
is another I think kind of lowlevel
disregulation alarm that I would call
most of what Megan has described in the
Pro Drome and again that's speculation
we don't fully understand the condition
but we know there's a disregulation we
see these cycles of nausea and vomiting
we know there is a weight being put on
the scale which is cannabis product
again usually as far as we know high THC
cannabis products and trying to figure
out how would we push on that scale at
all comes out to this vomiting condition
we're trying to pick apart and there are
theories that it's not the THC by the
way have you heard one yeah yeah I have
heard what's the one you've heard the
most Ben um pesticides NE oil pesticides
neem oil specifically right first of all
I would say for a lot of weed people we
like natural things right need oil is
extremely natural it is the you know it
is the actual oil from a a tree nut and
so um a tree maybe just the tree pulp
but either way from the neem tree um and
you know there's not a lot of evidence
here Ethan Russo very definitively you
know puts his his uh Line in the Sand
here and says this doesn't look like uh
and I'm going to mispronounce the active
ingredient in me but this doesn't look
like that toxicity and when I talk to
you know uh toxicologists and emergency
physicians who I work with closely it
doesn't really look like acute pesticide
toxicity in almost all the forms in
which we know because the response to
the toxin is not immediate which is
almost always the case especially if
you're smoking it um and and so you know
it would be very weird to have repeating
episodes in this cyclical nature every
couple months and that is correl ated
with potentially your menstrual cycle or
stressful events or whether you drink
alcohol it just doesn't it doesn't
totally line up with it I wouldn't even
say totally it doesn't line up with a
traditional toxidrome which is being
Intoxicated by a substance or being imp
um having that poison in your body so
you know there's a lot of reasons it
doesn't look like neem but I'm
open-minded there could definitely be
increasing amount of pesticides in our
cannabis and we need to study that but
it would be a little naive to call it
pesticides when we know some patients
smoking what is presumed to be clean
cannabis there's an argument to be made
about what the definition of is but
legally purchased regulated cannabis who
are still developing CHS right so then
if I look at what's in that product and
I can definitively say there's not very
much of any of this other stuff but
there seems to be a lot of one
particular thing that thing is CHC and
it tends to be the warmest you know know
uh in in a doctor is like that's
probably the thing that's causing it the
thing that exists in 30% not less than
05% because it's under the detectable
limit right aam's Razer right I mean the
most logical explanation is typically
the right one yeah and and I want to
point out so my expertise is in the
endoc canabo system I love this system
I'm doing a talk on it two of them in
the next in the next two months at
either MJ uh unpacked in Missouri or at
um Society of cannabis clinicians in
Baltimore I love this system this system
is homeostatic regulatory system
connecting all of the other systems in
the body including the adrenal system
which we know is disrupted in the ECS
including your thermo regulatory system
which we know as I've related it's
related to your GI motility it's related
to your pain sensitization it's related
to your again heat sensitization your
hot bath and hot shower complex we can
explain away without even much of a
stretch how THC interacting with CB1
receptors could disregulated well not
just CB1 but the endoc canabo system
could disregulated in a way that could
explain almost all of this um and and so
for me that is the warmest Theory but we
need real science this is a theory and
and a loose one of best I it's not even
a hypothesis or maybe it's a hypothesis
and not a theory either way it's the
lowest one and and but we need to do
this work and we need to start with
asking the right questions and is the
right question is is this what pesticide
toxicity looks like the answer is almost
a resounding no especially when you
consider the hot
bath I haven't seen anybody get exposed
to Organo phosphates at a farm in you
know Sacramento where they rush into the
hospital and place into a warm bath
yeah no and we you kind of touched on
other you know hyper edic type of
conditions that may sometimes be
misdiagnosed as CHS but so I'm curious
in those cases are the hot baths um
helpful for other sort of similar
conditions or is that very much unique
to
CHS it wouldn't use the word very much
do you want to take it Megan sure sure I
had to do this uh as part of a program
or a part of a project in grad school so
you know their CBS is like the umbrella
CHS is a vomiting syndrome is the big
term for conditions like this and then
CHS is a subsection within that right
and with c CVS uh oftentimes that's not
related to cannabis use oftentimes it's
related to Childhood stressors or
traumas and that's how like the stress
manifests in kids and teens is cyclic
vomiting and THC cannabis helps those
with CVS and it doesn't make it worse
and that's like a big differentiating
factor there is some evidence that hot
showers can help those with CVS but it
is like predominantly like in CHS it's
like one of the pillars of of the
syndrome itself so yeah I think just to
to C go back and and I guess rephrase
because I agree so you've got hot baths
and showers it's not common that people
would do that for nausea vomiting but
it's not also unheard of you feel unwell
you're going to go take a hot bath and a
little bit better so just throwing that
out there for not even cyli vomiting
like some people would argue you can
feel better from a hot bath now these
patients report a significant difference
from I want to die I'm so nauseous to I
can tolerate life on this realm you know
and it's like a big Stark difference but
setting that aside cyclic vomitor which
Megan alluded to we don't fully
understand but it's definitely
associated with childhood stressors and
traumas but there's a there's an
imbalance or a disregulation of the of
the the systems now now those
individuals are still hard to treat but
we do treat them with traditional
antiemetics they typically respond more
to the Zofran the serotonin blockers
that we give normally um the other thing
is like Megan said it's so um almost all
of them will have developed this
condition before they started smoking
cannabis uh because it is a childhood or
like teen developing although it can
happen in adults too but but I'm trying
to speak in generalities you're going to
see earlier and these patients often
report benefit from THC but don't forget
Megan mentioned that a lot of patients
who develop CHS also get a some benefit
and now I've got a patient who's got a
cyclic vomiting disorder who say smokes
cannabis who says it makes him feel
better now the doctor is like oh this
could be CHS especially if they don't
know that patient or know their history
very well so there's a misdiagnosis
there even though they're not taking hot
baths it's because the THC showed up in
their urine there's a cross
confusion lastly I want to say
differentiate around the hot baths I've
seen both I've seen a paper that
suggests yes that's a good indicator and
I've seen another paper more recently
that suggested actually both cyclic
vomitor and cannaboid hyperemesis
sufferers both find some relief from hot
baths which sort of mutes out that as a
diagnostic Factor only making the job
more challenging right like truly
identifying which condition we're
dealing with is it the weed that's
causing the condition or does this
patient have an underlying condition in
which weed is helping them but they have
the same vomiting problem um cyclic
vomitor don't typically have prodromal
symptoms in the same way that that c CH
sers do and um I think headache if I
recall correctly is a more common
precursor to a cyclic vomiting episode
um but it can happen before a CHS
episode as well so it's not a clear
picture
right and with the hot bathing too I
think with CHS it's like it's labeled as
like pathological hot bathing like like
people will burn their skin get second
third degree burns on their skin from
needing to be in the scalding hot
showers for long periods of time yeah
wow Yik I yeah it's we've seen some
pretty severe cases you know the average
person isn't doing that but they will
rack up a $500 gas bill or you know
water bill and they just run the all day
long we can't parents will be like we
cannot get him out of the B like he
won't come out at in the morning we're
late for school like all the things
because the
showers and now is total abstinence from
THC a a
solution I would say it is the textbook
solution um how in your experience um
with
abstinence uh how do you people do
can be difficult leav some to be desired
right uh Megan Have You Ever Seen I'm
sure you've seen patients go abstinent
but have you ever seen anybody you know
not go abstinent um I mean all the time
people continue to to use often not
believing their diagnosis right right or
that they feel like they can still
continue to use low amounts and manage
their symptoms that way um but for the
like that is interestingly like one of
the only published criteria for CHS is
you know the symptoms if your symptoms
go away after six months of abstinence
then it's likely that you had CHS six
months ago so um but it is you know if
it's like the the presumed cause then
taking away the cause is likely going to
be the solution and I think that for
some reason that pisses a lot of people
off like we're actually getting at the
root cause of this and they're like
there's no cure for it well you take
away the cause of it which is uh that's
an interesting you know Paradigm that I
see um but but yeah it's um that really
is the only the only known thing to help
with CHS and it's recovery is a roller
coaster it's not like you stop using and
then your Syms go away and you know
stopping use can then trigger episodes
down the line and um and people are
using their cannabis to stop an episode
from happening and then they stop using
and then it triggers an episode or they
have stopped using for a couple of
months and then they eat some food that
triggers them or alcohol or stressful
event triggers a CHS episode and they
haven't used in three months so recovery
now they don't think they have CHS right
right because this disregulation or this
imbalance sort of lingers in our system
for an extended period of time patients
sometimes reporting 12 months before
they feel whole again from a GI
perspective the damage and the the
inflammation that went on during their
EP and you remember people suffered for
years without knowing right there are
people on these discussion boards that
suffered for 15 years with a condition
they'd seen every doctor no one knew
what it was right and they've been
taking medicine and had all the Scopes
and done everything um but the where did
how did I get on this point Megan um
don't remember you just talking recovery
recovery being a roller coaster right so
so what I always counsel my patients on
is like you know we like patient
yesterday hadn't consumed cannabis in
nine days and she was in the middle of
an episode and it was triggered you know
at Disneyland from uh a hot burrito uh
beia taco or something of this effect
right and that's what set her off into
into this this problem so we don't you
know um we don't
fully know what the the timeline looks
like we're going to ask you questions
about this if you take our survey or you
send this to your friend we're going to
ask about how long after you quit did
you have symptoms but I can tell you in
my personal um you know practice
experience I am not a CS CHS sufferer
but in my experience talking to patients
that have it we're
seeing um easily 7 days usually 21 to 30
days and sometimes 60 plus plus days of
oh I just had an episode again don't
know what it was didn't know maybe it
was stress like Megan said maybe it was
some weird food that you thought you
could try again because it made you sick
a long time ago but it happened we don't
know but we're trying to put that
together so we can use that to educate
patients to help them know because
Physicians aren't telling patients to I
shouldn't say any most Physicians are
not not telling folks that hey you might
have more vomiting over the next few
days you should expect to have more
vomiting over the next few days even
though I believe you and you quit three
days ago and that conversation is not
happening because Physicians aren't
aware enough or frankly the data doesn't
help them right now there's not a lot of
evidence for them to lean on and say oh
yeah most patients will have another
episode in the next 21 days they don't
have that information so that's what
again the survey is trying to give them
some info to lean on to more quickly and
definitively know
sort of how to categorize and then how
to treat as opposed to throwing a label
on something throwing an anti psychotic
to help get them out of the emergency
room and sending people on their merry
way which unfortunately happens more
often than not yeah no that's that's new
to me like I said done a few episodes on
this and seen some cannmed talks on it
and obviously seen other things um I
didn't realize the the the roller
coaster of recovery there I thought you
know you you abstain your your symptoms
go away um it's really interesting that
other things can sort of trigger it and
I mean not that I'm a clinician but my
thought with that and you could tell me
if I'm on the right track is you know
other things are interfacing with the
endoc canabo system not just canabo and
other things can can kind of cause uh
spikes in your endoc canabo so do you
think that's perhaps what's going on
like certain stressors triggers um can
sort of just
disre I'll h on one point of that is
that um oftentimes people in
recovery some people will exercise and
work out and then sometimes that can
trigger symptoms and you know we know
what exercise does to our ECS so some
people are told to like yeah exercise
but don't go overboard because you don't
want to trigger anything Cody go ahead
yeah and we know that part of the endoc
canabo system's role is to chase the
Circadian rhythm and we're seeing this
weird sort of morning presentation once
again there's not good data on how many
people are having this morning is
mentioned in the literature but how many
is is unclear so we're hoping to get
some hands on that but the ECS naturally
follows the cortisol level so as
cortisol comes up the ECS comes up and
turns it off okay but if your ECS isn't
working and the cortisol is running out
of control and now you've got this sort
of inbalance we see this almost every
day I guess is what I'm getting at on a
micro scale on a macro scale yeah we
some women are reporting their menstrual
periods which we know there's a dramatic
shift in endoc canabo and function
throughout the body and and the you know
reproductive track um just like so many
again like ways to kind of tease it
together I do think there are things we
can do outside of um THC right that that
interact with our ECS but very few are
as powerful of a hack as sucking down
the Plant medicine out of a a battery 18
times a day and you know I don't think
no amount of meditation will be able to
sort of replicate that sort of stimulus
to the system and so you know I I still
tend to lean towards like yes there are
things that happen but the the ECS is
highly Dynamic and it's working real
hard even when you smoke weed all day to
keep you in balance in check awake when
you're supposed to be sleeping when
you're not Etc and so if it just doesn't
have the muster and that's maybe what's
leading to to the this disregulation um
you know sort of a suppression of the
natural ECS because of too many phyto
canabo um then it seems pretty obvious
that treatment would then lean towards
trying to restore balance without the
introduction of that phyto canabo this
very powerful modulator of this system
um so back to and I wanted to finish
where Megan was going and I'm so glad I
just remembered is to like um
what cannabis can you use right
abstinence is look I tell all my
patients the textbook answer is you got
to quit and the truth is I you
definitely have to quit for now I don't
know what the future holds for you I can
assure you what you're doing right now
you don't get to do this again like you
you you don't get to go and just consume
cannabis willy-nilly like it doesn't
have an effect on you we now know you're
for lack of just using poor terms a
carrier right right of you have this
genetic makeup you have this
disposition and therefore if and when
you decide to go back to cannabis know
that this is a risk what you're dealing
with right now is a very much a risk and
you're going to need to be aware of it
because remember those symptoms that you
had five six days ago that was your body
telling you that we got a problem and
you didn't listen or just as an example
but you know I think there's a
conversation to be had that is uh well
you know there there's a risk and uh
therefore you shouldn't do it it'd be
like somebody who contracted an STD and
you told them hey no more sex for you
buddy that stuff's dangerous right and
instead of teaching them mitigation
factors acknowledging that we're humans
and potentially that that person had was
deriving substantial medical benefit
from Cannabis medicine and that's where
they started right they didn't just
start consuming cannabis all day because
they were bored I mean I'm sure there's
a couple examples that most people are
using it because they're are anxious
because they're dealing with pain
because they're they're dealing with uh
the stressors of this crazy you know
modern world we live in
so you know to deny them of any cannabis
medicine is challenging and I think that
there might be hope for other
cannabinoids as well and if if you're
listening and you have CHS or you're you
know you're you're hearing about this we
want to hear about what you've tried
that works what did you change to what
what has you know not set you off
because we know people are doing this
I'm willing to bet I hope the data shows
this probably half are floating this
like I don't fully accept or I know that
I have CHS but I still smoke on occasion
we've got some people who who've gone
hard you know they develop CHS and they
discover mushrooms and they're like holy
cow I can't believe how cannabis wasn't
serving me like we see this whole
spectrum of experiences among these
these sufferers and we really just want
to catalog them and document them um so
thanks for having us on to talk about it
yeah absolutely um and I did want to
sort of talk so we talked about the you
know the contaminants and you know
whether or not that's that's a a factor
the positive factor I believe there are
contaminants in cannabis sure I believe
they can cause certain illnesses just
not convinced that this collection of
symptoms that we're talking about here
today is that you know I think people
are getting sick from contaminants
whether it's in hemp converted products
or whether it's in pesticide ritten
legal products that are even in
regulated markets that's just not what
I'm talking about I'm talking about this
very specific set of symptoms of
hyperemesis and prodrome that doesn't
line up with a typical toxidrome right
so it's much more likely that this is a
cause of high doses of THC correct um so
talk a bit about sort of I mean what
patterns you've seen in terms of like
what's the run of administration like
are these people consuming concentrates
versus Flour Edibles what does that look
like have you seen any studies on this
Megan like have you um I have not seen
studies but I do have lots of anecdotes
of people who come to me and this is
exactly what we are this survey is for
is to tease this apart but I the people
who come to me will say either I've been
smoking for a decade or two or three or
five um usually smoking flour or I've
been using concentrates for a much
shorter period of time um that's what I
have seen and then they start to develop
those six months one year two years for
concentrates as opposed to this decade
that you feel like you're most of your
patients Megan and I have talked about
this so I kind of knew what right right
and and it's interesting that in teens
the teens Cody has worked with more
teens than I have but the few teens that
I have seen has been like a short short
period of time of using concentrates
like two to three months of using
concentrates go on vacation and then
start to have CHS like symptoms with the
pro Drome in there
too yeah that sounds shorter than
average um not denying that it happened
I think you know that individual may be
more predisposed from a genetic
perspective we we know that there's at
least six uh mutations that Ethan was
able to identify you know just in his
preliminary relatively small studies so
we're gonna learn more as well um I
think what we've seen in data so I'm
trying to reach back in 2019 you had
Alice moon on in your your uh guest I
was in 2021 I was my class president at
um Maryland we did a online education on
on CHS and we had Alice as our guest
Alice was able to present her survey
data that she had done which ended up
not ever being published I think she
recently collaborated on a new study
that should be published soon out of
UCLA looking very similar to what we're
doing which is great because we got to
get more data we need to help we need to
help and one stud is nothing like we
need robust um decision support so what
I'm getting at is Alice shared her data
back then with me and when she showed us
she did show that the majority of of
consumers had been smoking greater than
3 years sorry inhaling cannabis for
greater than three years and um there
was a mixed collection the vapor dabbers
and the smokers they all had sort of
developed it but very few had been
edible only people very even less had
been CBD people um there's a couple
other distinctions in her data that were
interesting um but that's the one that
comes to mind it was very clear in her
data collected from like two or 300
patients that she personally interviewed
because she was afflicted by this
condition and no one was doing this work
so every time someone would express to
her that she had CHS she would send them
her survey um she would collect that
data and uh you know it was enough to to
kick Alice off as as to be a powerful
voice and advocate in this space which I
which I'm happy she she's able to be you
know she's taken a lot of yeah kicks and
Jabs um for her role and I think that's
representative of the stigma that the
community gives off to many patients
Afflicted patients don't want to share
that they've developed an intolerance to
the medicine that they loved and also
that their friends consume every day and
their friends would not understand or
say they're making it up or tell them
there it's not what it is it's neem oil
you're smoking the wrong weed there's
all these things the stigma is real and
we're trying to measure that in the
study
too yeah see I'm getting excited we're
pushing it out like this week y'all if
you're listening to this survey we're
pushing it out which is great this thing
has been I don't want to say a thorn in
my side it's been my baby but this needs
to fly yeah so talk more about the study
so if people are listening here and
they're curious about whether or not
they're a good fit or who you're looking
for talk about you know who should be
participating yeah so uh Megan me um our
our principal investigator Dr Ariana
Nelson at uh UCI uh where this this
study has been uh submitted and approved
through their IRB um we are looking
specifically for just really simply uh
two criteria basically are you an adult
we need 18 or older um there's just too
much uh complexity in trying to get this
info from kids hopefully we can start to
uncover more about Pediatrics later so
we need you to be an adult who either
has been diagnosed with CHS or is
believes they're suffering with CHS
right we don't need you to be diagnosed
by a doctor but we we need you to kind
of think like this is this is what I'm
pretty sure what's going on um and we're
going to we got a Litany of questions
right it's two parts each part's going
to take you about 25 minutes it's a long
time I do recognize but to make it more
valuable for you you will be entered
when you complete the survey into a
raffle for $100 gift card um we're
leaning towards Amazon but not the brand
drop uh but we're gonna we're still
figuring out where where that's going to
come from um but yeah it's we're really
excited to drop this two-part survey to
understand both the symptoms and use
pattern
and then also the burden how much health
care you know how how hard has this been
on you and your family and the truth is
it's going to be what organs did you
have removed that's literally a thing
right did someone cut out your appendix
during the process of trying to discover
that all of this inflammation was
because your endocan ammonoid system was
out of balance because you've been
smoking uh too much cannabis or
marijuana as they
say and now so we talked about before
sort of that early stage uh pro pro drom
is the dral yes um now people who are
listening to this and think oh that kind
of sounds like what I'm dealing with
like is are you interested in those
folks too or or only kind of in the
later stages um we're looking for
individuals who've experienced uh
hyperemesis right so I understand that
they're what Megan and I talked about
which again we're trying to understand
better too as part of the study but what
we talked about is that early sign and
we've seen that those are not the
patients we're trying to talk to because
we want to understand more about your
hyperic phase and and what might have
changed leading up to it so for those
folks I would encourage you to um go
read about cannaboid hyperemesis
syndrome I would encourage you to go
understand it more and not to freak out
I've also had people who are so anxious
about developing this you know and they
don't want to get this because cannabis
is so helpful to them it's unlikely that
it's going to happen but what's the most
definitive fact
is going to be um thoughtful or
conscious or mindful cannabis use as
opposed to continuous all day you know
use and some people need cannabis all
day Some people prefer cannabis all day
um and and in individuals who prefer
cannabis all day and develop CHS the
truth of the matter is is we probably
can't make that that decision that way
anymore um but I wanted to acknowledge
that medical patients very much need
right to get through their day CHS and
unfortunately some of those individuals
have developed you know CHS as well and
then we got to fight through how do we
you know switch to Pharmaceuticals or
how do we change your
canabo to try to do this so there's a
lot to learn but right now those who
have CHS or those who believe they have
CHS but that we would look for
specifically for people who have had an
episode of hyper Amis just so we can get
the the most understanding of their path
through the through the hospital system
um but yeah for anybody who's
experienced what you just described
those Pro dral symptoms but you you're
not sure it would be really reflective
on the way cannabis feels it might be
time to take a tolerance break and see
how you feel in five to seven days you
might be astounded right and and so it
could be a really really powerful
experience um and if you happen to
develop hyperemesis while you try to
stop THC I need you to take my survey
uh that just I'm teasing but seriously
because this is another one of our
leading hypo not not leading but like
this is another idea that we've kicked
around as a group um you know knowing
that we see this sort of withdrawal
induced yeah like again it makes sense
in the in the setting of like
disregulation if it's all out of whack
and it's been gotten used to having the
THC and then you pull that back now the
system is out of whack again and so that
might be it but again that's that's full
speculation
by excellent all right well Cody and
Megan thank you so much for the time um
again we're going to put the link to the
survey in the show description so that
people can find it and um you know
anyone listening please spread the word
let people know that this survey is out
there and that you should be
participating um but before I let you go
I'm going to let you both um share any
other additional resources uh around
this topic that you think might be
useful and then you know information
about yourself and how folks can maybe
uh get in touch or connect with you yeah
I think one of the one of the
fascinating places to actually learn
about this in real time we get a lot of
flack for this but it's the Facebook
groups it's the online CHS Facebook
groups where you get realtime anecdotes
from people and their experience and a
lot of that has triggered what we are
putting in the survey and how we have
asked the questions in the survey so
that's a fantastic place for people to
not only like learn about it as
clinicians and cannabis consumers but to
share their experience and get advice
from peers on what has helped them how
long their symptoms lasted because it's
so nuanced so Facebook groups are one um
there's one that that's called what is
Katie's group called uh it's run by a
nurse friend and colleague of ours who's
working with us on the study um safe
space safe space yeah CHS a safe space
to learn it has a purple um you know
purple on it and she's she's a nurse and
she helps people directly you know going
through their CHS episodes so that's a
fantastic
resource and uh trusted canon.com
obviously well yeah yeah I mean we don't
we typically refer people out to her if
people are wanting to like stop the
cannabis use and kind of like um you
know if they need help with that part of
it then we talked about this last year
this is what we do micro doing of
psilocybin for to help them desire
cannabis less but in the immediate
hypermed phases that's where like Katie
is a fantastic
resource awesome our study as well she's
one of going to be one of our authors um
and it's going to help us get this into
those communities on Facebook um so
first I want to speak to anyone who
listened thank you so much for making it
this far I appreciate your time um I
know that you may or may not more than
likely just statistically you don't have
CHS but you could share this podcast and
you can share our poster which will be
shared in in this as well come to any of
my pages it would mean a lot I just
we're trying to get this out here the
more people we talk to the better data
we get the better we can lead Physicians
to not make some of these standard
mistakes the help more we can help
patients to understand what to expect
there's so many benefits and really no
downside all you got to do is share you
just got to say hey weed is really cool
but it's not perfect um you know you can
also call me out say this guy thinks he
knows all about this CHS stuff he
doesn't know anything go tell him what
you really experien tell him its name
that's fine too too Shar
anyway uh other than that um you know
I've got a YouTube video on CHS if you
want to hear more just sort of like my
solo preach just Google my name CHS and
you'll find a Youtube video um the other
thing is uh Ethan Russo we talked about
him already his website what- is- CHS um
is a place where you can purchase a DNA
test to see if you have one of these
mutations um there's also some facts and
is useful resource and education
um so you can check that out and um you
know when we maybe drop the paper we'll
come to another podcast show up at
canmed do a whole thing absolutely we'd
love to have you yeah I hope to see you
both down at canmed in June um either
talking about this or any of the other
great work that you guys are doing so uh
thanks again for the time and uh we'll
see you soon thanks for having us
[Music]
a