i'm very grateful to be here thank you
so much for i know it's been a long day
everybody yawn stretch
take a second to increase your energy a
little bit here
i'd like to start out by telling you
just very very briefly what brought me
to cannabis
and it was chronic pain i was a patient
initially myself i had had bacterial
spinal meningitis that left me on 26
pharmaceuticals in a wheelchair on
fentanyl patch neurontin many many many
other horrible medications
now i'm on three and cannabis i will
tell you right now that i'm a huge
proponent of pharmaceuticals when
they're used correctly
but i think that our doctors and our
medical community can do a lot better
job
of figuring out ways to treat people
using
integrative medicine and not just going
to their pdr to pick the next drug
and adding one on top of another so i
think i'm a testament to the fact that
i'm standing here instead of rolling up
the aisle
and able to talk to you coherently and
not
be drooling and nodding like i was on
the opioids
so thank god for cannabis in addition
i'm very very excited about the work
that cordogen's doing in particular
because i come from a family of
you're pretty well if by the time you're
60 you'll have been diagnosed with one
form of a cancer or another
and there's still using the same types
of treatment protocols they were using
in the 70s
the 80s the 90s the arts etc
and there's got to be other ways or at
least ways to bring cannabis in with
some of the results we're seeing
i know that the conference topic is
primarily
looking at neurological disorders but if
you'll humor me i'm going to talk just a
little bit about
cancer here because i think that it's
something that's not nearly
addressed enough and i've just been
having some casual conversations here
with some
attendees some doctors they said you
mean you use cannabis for the
side effects of palliative and i said
well that too
depending on the objective of the
patient but we also use it to kill
cancer
so so the question i'll be addressing is
can cannabis be consistently
inaccurately dosed
and the answer is hopefully clear from
the show okay so the first thing i want
to talk about is the fact that
we do in fact promote whole plant
extracts and not isolates
isolates do in fact have a role for
standardization of medicines if you have
whole plant
and let's say you're trying to
standardize something to 60 milligrams
per mil
and it's coming out your your whole
plant extract somewhere at 55
57 58 there's nothing wrong with using
an isolate to help to standardize to
bump up the numbers
but you have to have the entourage
effect you have to have the synergy
between the terpenes
the flavonoids everything else that's in
the plant in addition to the
cannabinoids that are in there and even
the cannabinoids working together
have a synergistic effect we know that
mercine which is
an old hippie trick of eating mango
before you got high and it got you
higher
and now we know of course the reason for
that is that mercine helps to
increase the bioavailability and break
through the blood-brain barrier
limonene something that's in limes gives
a much more uplifting
experience we know enough about the
terpenes now to know
which ones work best with certain people
and certain diseases
but the one the thing a recurring theme
that you've heard here today over and
over again
is that there is no one-size-fits-all
one terpene might make me very sleepy
and it might make somebody else very
very activated so you have to work very
closely
in communication with your patients to
find out immediately getting feedback
with what works for them
now the entourage effect is you know if
they've identified i hear
sometimes i hear 200 different terpenes
100 different cannabinoids sometimes
i've seen reports that said 400 terpenes
i don't know the answer to it i'm not a
scientist i'm actually an engineer
so i come to this from a background of
data
and wanting to see patterns and wanting
to see what's working and what's not
working and
take track you know looking and
analyzing these things and looking for
the patterns
but i can tell you that with all these
various combinations i tried to run the
formula last night
of how many various combinations if you
just had
two compounds present in any plant and
you took the hundreds of cannabinoid
potentials
and the hundreds of terpene potentials
and you
added them together and you figured out
which plant headed it's a pharmacy and a
plant i mean
every different combination will give
you a different effect slightly
variance depending on who's taking it
and how it's going to impact them of
course
but it is in fact a i tell people have
an infused
uh cbd in your medicine cabinet have a
jar of uh of flowers
and then have an extract and you've got
pretty well a whole medicine cabinet a
whole pharmacy
in your in your bathroom now
this is a slide that i borrowed um with
her permission from dr christina sanchez
at completely university
where she talks about the mutation of
the cancer cells like what actually is
happening
when it goes through the process of you
know some not all but some most
cancer cells have go through the
angiogenesis process
and then they go through and they go on
and they metastasize and they spread and
go on to other
uh other parts of the body and then of
course that goes into the staging of the
cancers
but the traditional treatments are
designed
traditional chemotherapy treatments are
designed to work on
proliferating cells because your cancer
cells are
rapidly proliferating cells within your
body most of your cells are not
proliferating most of your cells
are pretty well stagnant i'm not a
scientist i'm not a doctor i can't
explain more than that
but i know that that's the understanding
as a result
your hair falls out because your hair is
continuously growing you're nauseous
you're vomiting because your stomach is
your your digestive system is
is a constantly active thing so cannabis
is found to work very very effectively
um against the things that we have here
like hair loss anemia constipation
diarrhea
pain joint pain is in in bone pain is a
very very big problem
with people that are going through
chemotherapies the toxicity
levels the canvas can help quite a bit
with and the lack of appetite
in addition lo and behold it also works
on the tumor progression
cannabis has been shown to be very much
significant
in apoptosis now the
cannabinoids or the cb1 or the cb2
receptors
are activated by the cannabinoids and it
begins the chemical cascade
that results in apoptosis everything in
between
the top where the i don't know where my
clicker excuse me
everything that goes between here
and here is up to much smarter people
than me in the room to explain to you
i just know it does now i asked
christina i said dr sanchez i said could
you please explain to me
what is the difference between necrosis
and apoptosis because
they both end up with dead cells and she
said the difference is that necrosis is
like a car wreck
it causes a lot of damage the cells
cause damage to the surrounding
other cells and the tissues around it
which results in inflammation which
results obviously in a negative
prognosis
which is why they have to be very
careful with the speed at which they
kill cancer cells with chemotherapy so
that you don't have too much necrosis
going on
and causing too much other disease
they'll end up developing the body
where apoptosis is cell suicide which is
very
intimate experience it's very the cell
basically uh
collapses within itself and that's a
layman's
description and uh and and dies
leaving behind and being being captured
by the other healthy cells so that it
doesn't leave behind any residue which
causes any disease and problem within
the body
the second thing i want to and then
excuse me and also the id1
gene is something that dr sean
mcallister
has done work on looking at which
cancers that have id1 involvement id1
especially is a problem i was speaking
to one of the parents
last night you know because of the id1
which is something you see
in infants newborns and fetuses and
children it's something that's when you
have a lot of growth
going on the id1 is very involved
unfortunately it's also present
in quite a few different cancers the
the good news on that is that cbd is
seen to be to down regulate the
expression of the id1 gene
and the id1 is what causes when it's
present you're going to have a lot more
proliferation and metastasis of the
cancer cells
so when we look for certain cancers you
know we can go okay let's start out at
least like with a prostate cancer or
breast
cancer or something else and say okay if
we know that it's a non-small cell lung
for example
we might start out with a much higher
level of cbd and lower in thc than we
would in one
for example the majority of
glioblastomas
multi-form the gbms that we've looked at
have not had id1 because they've not
responded as well to the cbd
sometimes they do and so that's where
the experimentation and the not
being one size fits all comes into play
the second thing i'm going to talk to
you about today is chronic nerve pain
and thc has been shown it has five
mechanisms involved with pain reduction
the cb1 and cb2 activation
i can read this to you if you'd like me
to retards electro
chemical reaction at peripheral pain
receptors and i have had this explained
to me multiple times
interrupts pain signal at the dorsal
root ganglion interrupts pain signal
with the neuron
activation of cb2 at leukocytes triggers
anti-inflammatory response
much like a steroid would do and the
psychoactive euphoric effects and
short-term memory reduction mitigate
stress response to pain
now why this is really important is the
same way as dr mishulam says
that we don't want to walk into a
grocery store and remember 500 people's
faces that we see there
we also have the gift of forgetting it's
almost like having a break
or having a freedom from the suffering
that we have
it just gives us a break from it
anybody who knows anyone with ptsd and
they have this recurring fight or flight
response that's going on they have the
ability to have a break in that and have
the calm
and get out of that fight or flight and
it's the gift of the of the forgetting
that goes on
the cbd in this case works
anti-inflammatory mechanism
which works very much like a cortis
hydrocortisone
but with much much higher success rates
in many many cases
i tell you myself personally i was
having i have pretty severe asthma
and about once or twice a year i would
have to go on a
steroid as a result of every time i got
an airplane i got an upper respiratory
infection
you know it always attacks the weakest
part of the body and
i would have to go on to steroids and
then it would take me months and months
to get off of them
with extreme bone pain and all sorts of
side effects
i have not been on a steer steroid now
for over three and a half years
because of cannabis so
all right here's just a visual
representation of the nerve
okay so i want to show you how we do it
so
we started collecting data on patients
back into end of 2010 beginning of 2011
saying okay
nobody can tell you how to dose nobody
can tell you what's in the medicine
nobody can tell you how this works i
mean we went around to some of the best
places and the best
people and at the time there was like
you know they were beginning the testing
labs and they were still using gas
chromatograph to do
uh cannabinoids which of course we all
know it actually decarboxylates
in the process of testing it so it's not
an inaccurate it's not an accurate test
if you're really trying to know what
milligrams you're taking
you'd go to a dispensary and it would
have
a rice crispy bar and a piece of
cellophane that somebody stuck a piece
of masking tape on it and wrote
one to 20 doses whatever that meant
there was no labeling there was no
understanding so we said we're going to
you know we can do better than this
there's got to be a better way that's
when the engineer and me and the process
came into collecting the data we started
collecting about 300 different uh data
points with patients
and looking for patterns and what was
working for various diseases
and seeing what if we could find a way
to be able to predict
moving forward with somebody else based
upon various
different variables what was going to
work at what for which diseases
one of the interesting things that we
found was that
there's five questions that if we get
those five questions answered
we can do i mean obviously the
confidence level
in our results is going to be slightly
uh lower than it would be if we asked
300 data points
but we found that if we find a person's
age because
there's a uh i think you may have picked
up on a pattern of this today
there's definitely a correlation between
age and dose
the younger the patient the higher the
dose the older the patient the lower the
dose at least that's the patterns that
we've been seeing
so one of the most important things that
we look at is the age
then we look at the diagnosis of course
and
if it's a if it's a cancer whatever it
is we look at staging and everything
else
and other treatments that they're having
we look at all the pharmaceuticals and
supplements with the medications that
they're on
we also then look at their previous
experience with cannabis or cannabinoid
therapies
and then we look at what their objective
is because somebody might come to me
and say you know i've got breast cancer
and blah blah blah and so i'm
immediately thinking okay we're going to
put him on this we're going to put him
on that da da da we're going to start
killing the cancer
they just want to they just want to not
be nauseous and now you know what that's
their right
it's not up to me to tell them what
their goal should be with their with
their treatment that's a
discussion between them and their doctor
and frankly we want to put this back
into the hands of the doctor so we've
been developing a software
all these years it's a cdr med it's now
in alpha it's moving into beta
in fact i think the site just went up
again last night
to be moving into beta to help to make
it a conversation that a physician can
be having now with his
patients instead of having to have
somebody like me doing it i'm not
qualified
so the first patient i'm going to look
at here was a 43 year old female
that came to us with breast cancer stage
and her goal was killing cancer cells
that was absolutely she wanted to live
and she was going to do whatever it took
to
to live so uh the first recommendation
that we made to her
now this was this was a while ago was
150 milligrams of thc
and 75 milligrams of cbd now
when i say this is our first people want
to know where they're going in their
treatment they may not ever get there
or they may have to go way past it but
this is a starting out goal
we can make adjustments we start people
out on a third of a milligram
we've standardized our infused oils at
10 milligrams per milliliter
and it's between 28 and 30 drops per mil
which means that each drop is one third
of a milligram
and that way if we can start somebody
out and we can tell very very quickly
how high we're going to have to go
before we start having a therapeutic
effect
of course our extracts are much much
higher and we're getting ready to move
them into standardized as well
at i believe 30 60 and
i'm not sure if there's another one in
there not milligrams per mil
of major cannabinoid so this was the
first one the doctor recommended
150 milligrams taken in two doses
and then the cbd we also recommend that
people separate out
their major cannabinoids and not take
them together when they're doing cancer
treatments
um cbd is a uh is an antagonist
and thc is an agonist so we want the
agonist in there doing its job
and and being effective and we and a
couple hours later you introduce
the cbd there's still synergy going on
in the body but in the meantime
we know that all the cb1s have been
activated
that need to be we also want there to be
beta-carotelline whenever possible
so that we have the cb2 activation as
well
so this was how we were able to do it so
how do we turn that recommendation from
a doctor
or from a or a clinician into results
based upon what's available right now
with the state of products so the first
thing we looked at was
lab results this one happened to be one
that was done
at steep hill hayland a long time ago it
doesn't matter the point is if you have
a good testing lab a good reliable
testing lab and that's kind of an
oxymoron unfortunately at this point
right now
because there needs to be a lot more
standardization and regulation
we recommend that uh people have their
their medicines tested
multiple times at multiple locations to
find out what really is
closest to accurate anyway in this
particular one
the thc had 650 milligrams per gram
of extract in the ac dc which was the
high cbd had 580. so
by eight we were able to then give them
from the sour cush keef which you see
here on this strain on the left and on
the right
we were able to then make a
recommendation to the patient to take
this
instructions on how to actually take
this medicine
correctly in order to achieve the exact
150 milligrams
that was being recommended by the doctor
okay
the second thing we're able to do we're
able to repeat it again and again
and again then the person was in
remission
we were able to move to a maintenance
dose
of 100 milligrams of cbd at this point
and only 50 milligrams and what we do i
asked her the question asked to the
panel earlier
that we said that if after a person goes
through two full
cycles of showing any d then we will
then reduce them to between 10 and 12
percent of what they're ever their
highest
that's the goal to go on for a
maintenance dose
it looks like i talked too much at the
beginning so i'm not going to be having
a chance to show you
but this is how we then ended up were
able to achieve the
maintenance dose for this patient
and then this is just showing the
patients what they took throughout their
uh the whole treatment protocol and how
they were able to consistently take the
medicine through this
on the chronic nerve pain i just take
one minute very quickly to show you
we had to go through a lot of
experimentation with this particular
patient we did it with the cannabidiol
excuse me the the thc first 25
milligrams
very very quickly the patient just
zoomed right past that to a hundred
and that still wasn't enough so we then
introduced
thc a into the picture
the thca because i'd rather want to have
that because they were having some
stomach issues
and we were able to dose that accurately
with these medicines fulfilling the
doctor's recommendation
then we brought in then cannabidiol
it turned out that a 80 milligrams of
thc
and 60 milligrams of of cbd was the
magic ticket for this particular patient
and we were able to
do it over and over again repeating that
to keep them the same one
if you'd like for more information you
can go to cdrmed.org
and ask for beta access i just you know
i think i've covered pretty much all
these things
we must have clinical trials it doesn't
need to be in the hands of people like
me
i'm glad that my software is going to be
able to put it into the hands for the
clinical trials and the doctors and all
but i'm very very happy to be here and
i'm very excited about the work that i
heard today thank you
uh the patients everybody the one the
chronic pain patient is
that's their maintenance dose and
they're doing their wife they're going
to work they're having a lovely life
and the breast cancer patient is still
in remission and doing fantastic
yes
thank you mara