hello everyone I'm very excited to be
here my name is Akeem Gardner I'm CEO of
Canada Inc and we are a pre-clinical
biotechnology company from Ontario
Canada
we specialize in looking at all the
prenilated flavonoids the still beans
and the benzos and the cannabis plant
and today I'm going to present to you
one of our research projects looking at
glioblastoma Invasion and survival with
cannabis derives with flavonoids
so can 5 and a and b are penelated five
enolates found in Cannabis sativa they
have the flavon backbone consisting of
two fennel rings and a heterocyclic ring
about 36 years ago Baron and all
identified these five flavonoids as
Inhibitors of the prostaglandin E2
production
and what she demonstrated was that they
had anti-inflammatory effects up to 30
times more potent than aspirin but with
a different mechanism of action one that
was presumably safer for us than our end
seeds
these molecules are highly lipophilic
and their this nature allows them to
easily accumulate into cells and
potentially interact with membrane-brown
enzymes and receptors
now recent Studies have explored the
potential of these molecules in cancer
research
one study found that can 5 and a induced
apoptosis and decreased Invasion and
bladder cancer cells
a 2019 study pre-clinical study found
that an isomer of can 5 and B cathlonome
increased apoptosis in pancreatic cells
in vitro and limited metastatic
progression in Vivo the FDA has recently
granted an IND to allow them to further
this work
however none of these studies proposed a
mechanism of action for how can violence
actually interfere with cancer
progression
earlier this year we had this study
published in phytomedicine plus and in
this study we took a look at how can
fibon's activity actually affected
cancer and what the target of this
activity might be track B and I'm going
to take you through a little bit about
what we found today
so first off our work started off by
looking at a protein called the activity
regulated psychoskeleton Associated
protein or Arc for short
think of art like a super smart
scientist in the brain it's really
important for helping our brains adapt
and learn new things our neuroplasticity
it plays a big role in how we think and
understand stuff the brain's cognitive
function
now art doesn't work alone it has a
friend the brain derived neurotrophic
factor or bdnf
and bdnf is like a messenger that
carries the instructions to Arc it's a
growth factor which means it helps
things grow and develop in our body
bdnf tells Arco sorry
now bdnf tells Arc to produce more of
his mRNA and protein sort of like
telling it to clone itself
how does bdnf send this message it does
so through activating a special type of
receptors called the tropomyosin kinase
B receptor track B
so you think of bdnf like a mailman
track B is the mailbox and Arc is the
scientist that reads the male
now back in 2017 researchers in our lab
identified a bunch of compounds that can
change how art gets produced and they
found these molecules by screening
through primary Mouse cortical neurons
among the identified compounds five
flavonoids enhanced Arc protein levels
dietzine and ginseng were two
isoflavones that increase our protein
levels as demonstrated by nuclear Arc
expression measured via fluorescent
immunostaving
so for us we wanted to know what can
five and Zach similar would they act the
same
so we adapted this previous experiment
this time focusing on the effects of can
5 and a and b on Art protein expression
using the same primary Mouse cortical
neurons and our hypothesis was was that
can fly and a and b might actually
increase the amount of Arc protein when
added to the neurons that were already
stimulated with an external source of
bdnf
now who however very surprisingly
instead of seeing the arc protein
increase as expected can flavins at
concentrations between 1 to 20
micromolar actually prevented the normal
increase in our protein caused by bdnf
this was observed through Western
blotting and by examining the protein
expression in the nucleus via
immunostaining so the results that we
found were actually quite different than
our initial expectation
so our team wanted to find out if Camp
atoms were causing the arc protein to
break down or if they were affecting how
the arc mRNA was being copied which is a
step before a protein is made
to do so they performed a experiment
called the quantitative polymerase Chain
Reaction or qcpr for sure
this is a fancy way of saying we were
copying and measuring the amount of Arc
mRNA and we used two molecular scissors
that targeted different parts of the arc
transcript
and doing this we discovered that camp
Islands at a specific concentration
about 10 micromolar stop the usual
increase of Arc mRNA expression
now putting this together with the
results from the early experiments the
scientists concluded that effects of
Camp vitamins happened after Trek B is
is activated by B by bdnf but before the
Machinery that controls Arc expression
gets switched on
so I'm going to use a little a bit of
analogy to talk a little bit more about
Trek B we're going to imagine track B
activation as relay race
bdnf is the runner at the start of the
line and track B receptor is the Baton
once the race starts bdn F binds to the
Trek B receptor similar to a runner
grabbing the Baton
this binding leads to the diametization
of two track B receptor Parts similar to
two hands holding of baton and once
these parts are together tyrosine
residues on The receptors which are like
the batons marking get flagged or
phosphorated this tagging recruits and
activates halter proteins such as Schick
or gerb II kind of like signaling the
next Runner to get ready
so what we wanted to see is what did the
can flavins influence this relay race we
focused on two important markings on the
Baton the y515 and y705
and once again using Western blot we see
that both can 5 and a and can 5 and B
like unexpected hurdles in a race slow
down the tagging of these baton markings
in a dose-dependent manner
this means the more Camp items we add
the less tagging happens which
ultimately prevents the activation of
the next runners or Downstream signaling
Cascades
let's continue with the race analogy so
after the Baton has been picked up and
the race is underway there are several
tracks that a runner can take these are
like the simulink pathways that are
controlled by Trek B
specifically you have map key Act mtor
and the s6k pathways you can think of
these Pathways like the different Lanes
in a relay race
so what we decided to do was look at how
can 5 and a and b can impact these lanes
and using Western blotting we found that
camp violence A and B significantly slow
down the runners in these Lanes
they reduced the bdnf induced increase
in map k
Act
and the s6k pathways
so in our race analogy if bdnf is the
starting pistol it usually makes these
runners or Pathways speed up but with
Cam Flav and Zane B it's as if they're
running on a track filled with obstacles
slowing them down
what's more is that we notice that the
changes in speed across these Lanes
happened independently of each other
with limited interactions and this
suggests that can flavins likely set up
their obstacles very early on in the
race right at the start of track B
signal activation
so what does all this mean for cancer
research
well track B is a little bit of a
troublemaker in many types of cancers
this includes breast liver lung and very
severe type of cancer of brain cancer
called the bleobustimo multiform GBM for
short
GBM is the worst kind of brain cancer
it's top level it can show up anywhere
within the command center of our body
our central nervous system
GBM has the ability to grow rapidly with
proliferation it can invade nearby cells
Invasion and it could also send this
henchmen to other areas of the body with
metastasis
and guess who's giving GBM these powers
yep it's our problematic friend Trent B
sorry it was supposed to be here
because of its effects in the human body
we often lose the war against GBM with
survival rates less than two years
right the current weapons that we have
against GBM like surgery chemotherapy
and radiation can help us fight battles
for a while but things often end up in
relapse and GBM taking control and this
is why it's very sorry this is why it's
very important for us to understand and
control the molecular abnormalities in
GBM
as if we can figure out a way to take
away traffic track B's ability to a GBM
this could lead to more effective
treatments in our fight against GBM and
other cancers
so in our next batch of experiments we
wanted to select a control that can make
sure that our work was valid and the
control we selected was Anna 12. Anna 12
is a unique molecule because it's
selectively inhibits track B with
minimal impact on other Trek Family
receptors or rtks
it crosses the blood-brain barrier and
non-competitively antagonizers track B
receptors LinkedIn binding domain
preventing bdnf activation
a 2017 study demonstrated the
dose-dependent efficacy of Anna 12 on
u87 GBM cells assessing cell viability
over 72 hours
so our goal was to find out what happens
to these GBM cancer cells when we expose
them to more and more of these Trek B
inhibitors
so first we started with Ana 12 we
tested out on two different types of GBM
cells the ae-172s and u87s to make sure
we can get the same results as the 2017
study
next we moved on to can Flavin a
and then we looked at can 5 and B
and when you look at the bar graphs of
the results you can see that as we
increase the dose and the amount of time
cells were exposed to these Inhibitors
the cells responded way more than when
we just used DMSO control
next we wanted to see if these results
were the result of toxic molecules no
one wants those so we conducted a
cytotal toxicity ldhsa and results
showed low percentages of LDH for cant 5
and a and b in both cell lines most most
doses exhibited five percent or less
except for high dose can Flavin B
and what this indicates is that the
decrease in cell viability is not due to
necrosis caused by the molecules
to assess how these compounds inhibit
cell migration we perform the 2D scratch
I say this is where we use a tip to
scratch a monolayer of cells on a plate
and then live live time lapse Imaging
captures the migration of GBM cancer
cells with the addition of Ana 12 and
can flavins compared to DMSO
you can see how they're moving here
now interestingly what we found was that
the cells migrated faster with canned
flavins but then they slowed down after
48 Hours when you compare them to the
DMSO control
next We performed a 3D spheroid
migration assay and after 24 hours low
doses of the Inhibitors reduce the
number of area cells migrating from the
spheroid compared to the DMSO control
you can see that data here
we want to see how these substances Ana
12 candy can be can affect the way GBM
cells Invader spread and to do this we
use the Boyden chamber assay this is a
special setup where we put the cells on
a jaw that represent the environment
around the cells in the body and then we
give the cells about 24 hours to do
their work
after that we clean up and we add a
special a special diet of the cells and
we can see them better under the
microscope
and from our early results it looks like
even small amounts of Ana 12 canny and
can be can slow down these GBM cells
making them less able to spread through
the gel this is a good sign because it
suggests that these substances can
potentially slow down the spread of GBM
cells in the body
so in a nutshell our researchers first
found that can 5 and a and b are able to
put the brakes on activation of a
particular signal signaling pathway in
cells called track B
this pathway is often overly active in
many forms of cancers including those
found in the breast and the Brain
and Camp Robinsons have demonstrated
their power against these GBM cells by
being able to reduce the viability of
these cells and even better doing this
without being without any toxic effects
we discovered that these canned vitamins
can slow down the movement of these
cancer cells this was seen in both 2D
and 3D environments with the cells
moving slowly after 48 hours and 24
hours respectively when compared against
the control
foreign
we also found that even in small doses
Camp Islands were able to decrease the
invasion of these cancer cells after
just 24 hours this suggests that can
flattens have a strong potential in
slowing down the spread of certain
cancer types opening up a new
possibility of cancer treatment
so where do we go to from here
looking forward our team is eager to
continue this work and in the coming
months we'll start to use cerebral
organoid or mini brain co-cultures to
delve even deeper into the potential of
canned flavins to Halt cancer invasion
moreover we're preparing to utilize
assays that track the movement of cancer
cells that Express a green fluorescent
protein
and by pre-treating these cells with
camp flavins we aim to further
investigate the compounds at capacity to
put a stop to cancer metastasis
now it's important to note that this is
just one branch of our comprehensive
research programs right we have amassed
a significant amount of data that
underpin our ability to take our
laboratory findings and apply them in
living organisms in Vivo
for instance we have encouraging results
from a trial involving transgenic C
elegans this is a type of worm over
expressing a human Tau protein that
tends to aggregate a common feature in
many neurological diseases
now in this trial we used an extract of
can 5 and a and b mixed at a three to
one ratio and found that it had a modest
positive effect on their survival of
these transgenic C elegans
now most crucially in relation to what
I'm talking about today we found that
can flavins at a variety of different
doses do not cause neurotoxic effects to
the living worms and this is very
promising a discovery when considering
canned filings as diseases for the CNS
and the Brain
so I'd like to thank you all for coming
to my presentation I want to acknowledge
all the researchers who have done well
to perform this science and move us
forward including John holbring the
alarm lag the aptar lab our converted
team my tax and Circ and the University
of golfer funding this project we're
very excited about the work we're doing
up in Canada thank you all for allowing
me to present to you today
delicious
you that's very interesting work I'm
curious your perspective on these two
different entities GBM and Tau protein
Alzheimer's Dementia in which the trick
B pathway would be an important
reparative and preventative pathway in
Alzheimer's where you might not want to
suppress it how do you tease those two
apart and the role of canaflavins in
each of those conditions
you're asking how do we adapt the data
from well I'm just curious your thoughts
right inhibiting trick B could be useful
in GBM yep but it seems like in models
of Alzheimer's increased trick B
activity is beneficial understood
so we're going to have another
presentation a little bit later today
Hunter land at BRC will take you a
little bit more through the transgenic C
elegans study there we looked a little
bit more at Tau and in order for me to
not step on his toes I'll let him share
with you what we found about Tau and
Alzheimer's in regards to canned flavins
but also cannabinoids as well
what's most important I think from this
is that we know that glioblastoma
um to less than two years survival and
keep people and patients are looking for
anything that can help prolong the
survivability of these patients and
that's what we found in these models so
that's the thing that we were most
excited about here
oh
yeah that's um interesting so I'm
wondering are there are there other
Therapeutics that are being developed
that Target Turk B and I'm wondering
what's special about the flavins from
cannabis
uh these seem like some of the most
expensive flavins I could get right
well I don't know if you can actually
get them which is why we're excited
about the work that you're doing these
molecules are extremely rare in the
cannabis plant they're usually found in
under 0.014 so you're never going to get
these molecules from smoking our
medicinal cannabis this is where our
company specializes we have a variety of
different
um production processes to allow us to
capture them in clinical and Commercial
quantities so that we can now do this
work and like we originally said these
molecules were first discovered to have
extremely high anti-inflammatory
properties but a different mechanism of
action than most of our end seeds the
different mechanism of action presumably
allows them to be safer than most of our
end seeds and we also know that
systematic chronic inflammation is the
root cause of many disease everything
from cancers tumors neurodegenerative
diseases so on and so forth starts with
chronic inflammation
yeah
there are like millions and zillions of
in sort of anti-inflammatory or
reductive molecules so yeah I'm
interested in what specific or curious I
would love to follow up with you more
and hear more
excellent excellent talk loved it um now
what do you perceive the route of
administration will be obviously these
won't survive pyrolytics and it's going
to probably be either oral or injected I
mean what do you anticipate there for
Rod Administration
so there's a couple of interesting
research projects that are going on
right now that we're following very
closely to see what the best way of
delivering these
um to the site of action in GBM as I
mentioned earlier the FDA is recently
granted an IND to cathlonome and in this
in their IND they're using smart
radiotherapy biomaterials to deliver it
straight to the site of action alongside
chemotherapy and without so we'll learn
as the science continues to progress and
we'll also continue to explore our own
our own roots of administration
thank you very much