everyone how are you you guys enjoy
yourself here UCLA right on go Bruins
I a little big back little back story
and I'm gonna try to rush through some
of the more laborious slides so that you
guys can relax and maybe incorporate
some of them some of the main findings I
did my I was a tech here back in the
early 1990s
I studied pediatric brain tumors for a
long time we started studying these
things called cancer stem cells and
brain tumors it it was was it was
fascinating it was remarkable it really
I found a future and a purpose in it and
then I did my PhD here in molecular
medical pharmacology so I'm a
pharmacologist and drug developer I did
my postdoc in bioengineering because
it's developing drugs and especially
cancer drugs are very difficult so I
took some extra training and
bioengineering
I lose my talk my hitting the right bud
all right all right so the malignant
brain tumor glioblastoma brain cancer is
a largely untreatable deadly cancer
median survival ranges from 12 and a
half months around 12 an f-1 to 16 and a
half months disease is characterized by
extreme cellular molecular genetic
heterogeneity the standard treatment
involves surgery radiation and
chemotherapy it is the first soft tissue
cancer to be shown to be a disease of
cancer stem cell origin and there's
really no predisposing factors the
cancers happen and we just don't know
exactly who or when it's going to happen
but glioblastoma have a tendency to be
too tendency to be related to older age
but we also find a glioblastoma in
pediatric populations as well
brief history cancer stem cell
biologists this is about 15 years in one
slide cancer stem cells are essentially
highly malignant super cells they hijack
natural stem cell survival and cell
proliferation process processes they
self renew to replicate themselves it's
very important in stem cell biology and
then they create the cells which
produced the tumor bulk and which
patients ultimately succumb in 2003
cancer stem cells were first isolated in
vitro and expanded from pediatric brain
tumors like I was describing and in 2013
10 years
later which sort of describes how long
it takes once you go from a discovery to
application in 2013 cannabinoid receptor
agonists both cb1 and cb2 were found to
be potentially effective in killing
glioblastoma cancer stem cells this was
drug screening we did and it was
directly on these cell populations and
it was a way for us to see oh we can use
these types of cell models to study drug
development and we can also find insight
into what drug classes might protect
potentially be used therapeutically for
glioblastoma and in the last 15 years
which this this point relates to the
fact that the cancer stem cells aren't
just in brain tumors they're in a number
of different cancers and the same models
have been used repeatedly with regards
to the culturing processes of taking
these taking cancers putting them in a
petri dish looking for stem cells on it
and it's called a sphere system and you
can see at the bottom those are those
are balls of cells and that's how stem
cells look like in a petri dish except
these are cancer stem cells so in the
last 15 years cancer stem cells have
been identified and a number of
malignant and metastatic cancers breast
prostate ovarian colorectal pancreatic
melanoma and some others as well this o
on the right they looked a pretty
picture of orange and green and whatnot
that is when we try to differentiate
these cancer stem cells spheres to see
whether they can turn into other cell
types and so the greens the green
labeling is for a marker for four
neurons and the orange labeling was
actually red but there's red and green
and they make orange and those are the
red markers were markers for neural
progenitor x' and those are some of the
earliest studies that we were doing and
trying to see what we actually had in a
petri Edition and study this cancer stem
cell phenomenon the science behind
cannabinoid based cancer therapy is
rooted in signaling pathways if you walk
away from this meeting and you want it
somebody asks you at the dinner table
what what is this deal about cannabis
potentially being used as a treatment
for cancer it's based in signaling
pathways that we've been studying for a
very long time they're very complicated
to develop drugs for I'm going to just
zero at zero in to what we need to be
focused on in this slide is that in the
very middle you're going to see a red
and green it's a KT and M tour and tour
in a KT R
sitter sort of like a therapeutic
graveyard if you will we we try to
develop these drugs they don't get the
clinical for trying to target a KTM tour
very difficult drugs to develop a lot of
the drugs that we that we try to move
through the clinic don't make it they
have they fail in preclinical so this is
going to become very important so I'm
gonna talk about a KTM torn they're
gonna walk away with a KTM tour like oh
my god this is a thing these are the
things that we're gonna be using in the
future to treat cancer the bottom of the
slide is all the cancer things that go
on in a cell regarding cancer so on the
right side epithelial mesenchymal
transition called the MT transition
that's that's a mechanism by which a
cell could pop off from tumour and then
go somewhere else so that's a mechanism
metastasis it's a stem cell process
tumor progression in angiogenesis cell
death autophagy apoptosis that's all
we're looking for when we try to develop
drugs is can we kill the cell through
pop ptosis which is cell popping and out
of figis is a realignment of the cell
that produced cell death cell
proliferation obviously very very
important internal biology and then cell
cycle we try to block the cell cycle
that the green hours are activating
signals and the orange button is an
inhibitory signal so there's a lot of
activation and in hittin efficient going
on in a cancer cell and a lot of this
happens in cancer stem cells the little
pink thing up top is EGFR that's going
to become important to some of the data
that's an epidermal growth factor
receptor it's sort of like her to but a
different variant of that but it was
very important in terms of the data I'm
about to show which is single cell
header in genesis of glioblastoma cancer
stem cells there's a lot of in order for
us to to use this as a procedure or way
to identify what's what works what
doesn't and develop therapies we had to
have some decent better tools because
most of cell biology is is is done we
use a lot of different cells and then
we'll we'll crack open like a million
cells and then analyze them and single
cell analysis basically takes all is a
lot more high content its quantitative
and it allows us to like label the cells
identify signals incorporate other
signals that might be going on in
parallel or in in concert with and we
use these microf oolitic chips to our so
so on the top slide is global by stone
we take the global stoma we dishes
it's cells from a petri dish Speirs form
then we break up those spheres and then
we put them in these little microfluidic
chips and this allows us to do really
high sensitive low cell number analyses
these the microchips were developed at
the Californian I know systems Institute
just about a block and a half away from
here we're looking at you GF we were we
were looking at the relationship between
EGFR and tumor suppressor p10 phosphate
KT and an mTOR and what happens is we
did we overlay the cells it's basically
quantitative you know static chemistry
we can quantitate the signal based on
the amount of protein that is
fluorescently labeled so the colors
represent the fluorescent labels and we
as I said we looked at EGFR p10
phosphate KT and then the third thing is
validation which is a way to quantitate
and see like do it the signals you find
are they relevant can can we make use of
it experimental data set 15 samples for
biomarkers that was it cells a sample
60,000 data points 15,000 cells is all
the cells I needed to do the analysis
and I'm about to show you more
quantitative mathematical analysis
algorithms basically drive the
relationships with it within and between
cells and patients we use
self-organizing maps they'll take a
molecular signature in the data set the
markers quantified self percentages are
mapped this is what these signatures
look like 15 samples and their molecular
signatures in each little circle
represents a one unique molecular
signature so brain cancer stem cells
have essentially up to 49 molecular
signatures and this just sort of
organizes that and it's according to the
patient to the patient sample so very
very so it was a real decimate
heterogeneity from that we from that
mapping we do a thing called
neighborhood frequency vectors and then
we do unsupervised clustering this is
the thing that just excited me it's
excited me for years and years and years
now that we're finally getting ready to
we now have some good good data set
enough enough understanding of this data
to make sense of it and publish it and
on the on the Left there's a
unsupervised hierarchy clustering each
column represents one patient each row
represents a unique molecular one of
those 49 molecular phenotypes
to walk away from this because the time
started going out molecular signatures
are defined by differences in EGFR
expression which is in pink an
activation of a KT in red and mTOR in
green and there's a little cheat sheet
on the lower left hand corner like I was
saying that's the therapeutic you know
that there's the the places that we have
very difficult time to develop drugs the
little black circle a KT and M tours
right in the middle of that incredibly
important for developing therapies for
cancer and cancer stem cells we did some
validation measures real quick we just
basically grew spheres and then counted
the spheres and found out whether there
was a malignancy associated with the
cluster 1 and cluster 2 cluster 1 had
had a higher malignant signature because
we needed less cells to plate to form
these little spheres and then cluster 1
we needed more cells to to get an
analysis of saying oh you know how these
spheres grow and it was just a you know
lots of set lots of spheres come from
highly malignant brain cancer stem cells
not a lot of spheres come from cells
that are not very malignant and so you
need more cells to put in a petri dish
in order to do your studies and so
that's what that represents a KTM Torr
activated cluster to had significantly
higher sphere formation and had higher
sphere forming efficiency as an
indicator of malignancy we looked at
patient outcome because we had the data
on the patient while we were working in
the lab these patients would eventually
succumb to disease so we had outcome
measures of progression and survival and
these things are cos curves and the
curving is but if the curve goes farther
along the x-axis the patients doing is
doing alright they're surviving longer
or they have less they're not they're
not progressing or in the MRI doesn't
show a recurrence or anything
if the x-axis is closer up to the origin
the patient doesn't do as well and we
use these in terms of identifying what
molecular signatures are what we're
supposed to be looking at might be
related specifically to a patient's
survival as an outcome measure and it's
very important in drug development is
having effective outcome measures
targeted cannabinoid therapy cannabinoid
receptor agonist may target cancer stem
cells by directly inhibiting pi3 kinase
Akt mTOR or torque 1 which is a complex
one and
they're hard to target cancer signaling
pathways I'm not gonna go into this and
a lot but basically it goes right back
to the fact that these are very
difficult proteins to target they are
part of the cancer stem cell machinery
and we're and we're gonna I'm going to
show some clinical hope and promise
now I had to skip straight from basic
science right into clinical hope and
promise because this is really exciting
this is the thing that I was able to
look back at my data and say oh we have
something here that the story makes
sense in early 2017 GW Pharmaceuticals
found positive results in Phase two
proof-of-concept study in glioma or
recurrent glioblastoma with 21 patients
they used a THC CBD formulation they had
one-year survival of 83% using the THC
CBD formulation versus 53% placebo or no
formulation at all and then their median
survival is eighteen point three months
with the four on the formulation versus
twelve point three months placebo in any
and in most universes that would be
considered blockbuster or approaching
the direction of blockbuster so you know
this is really really exciting things
it's very good for the field it's very
good for our understanding of cancer
biology how we're going to be what we're
going to be looking at in terms of
treating cancer how we diagnose things a
little bit better so that we can apply
the appropriate therapy if it's a canoe
enoyed therapy or it's some saw the
signal transduction on pathway blocker
you know we've got to sort these things
out they'll closer we get to the exact
signaling pathway what a patient has the
better chance that we can do better
clinical trials and directly target the
right therapy for the exact patient with
the exact sort of mutations that they
might they might have coming from there
the press release from GW Pharma
cannabinoids have been shown to promote
auto Figgy which is a process of and I
always mispronounce that the process of
regulated self degradation by cells via
several distinct mechanisms including
acting on the a KTM tor pathway which is
an important intercellular signaling
pathway that is overactive in many
cancers so it's basically a convergence
I don't work for GW Pharma didn't really
know about what they were trying to
accomplish but our data it converged
with their data and perhaps the future
might be yes we're now looking at cancer
themselves these are brain cancer stem
cells we're looking for there in the
patient tumor the condemned annoyed czar
targeting these specific cells and this
is a potential improved way to look at
treatment be it as an adjunctive or as a
full-on therapy but we now have the
science there we now have the potential
these botanical drugs there and this is
all all very promising and when multiple
groups come up with the same solution
that's the sweet stuff that's what we
need to be doing all right cures come
through collaboration choked up spent a
long time since I left UCLA like five
years ago and it was like I got it got
to go do my own thing now and so it's
great to be back in the cancer stem cell
biology crew professor Harley Kornblum
really stewarded all of the brain cancer
stem cell work he was a mentor of mine
professor ed Munoz Ian he's a pediatric
oncologist here down in Harbor professor
media Cho was a resident in the lab a
lot of basic science studies that were
working on she is now in the brain
injury program and the Department of
Neurosurgery like a lot of other cope on
Tiffany jack
Eric these are my best friends we worked
very hard on very difficult problems and
I love the way they supported the work
that was going on micro fluidics
professor Jenks son is a professor in
China now she was my postdoc when I was
a grad student professor Ken Khmer he's
now doing stem cell work down in Japan
biotechnology and stem cells in Japan
Manohar says she is going to be an MD
PhD candidate here in the School of
Medicine dr. bill Wong pathology taught
me every single thing I knew about
pathology and was just a Grutter
incredible source of support in
neurosurgery professor gheorghe lazar if
he is a pediatric neurosurgeon that
basically green-lighted this all these
studies to begin with and went on to do
some he's a professor emeritus now he
was a close close mentor to mine along
with Harley Kornblum and Lynda Liao was
was there the two neurosurgeons Jorge
and Linda had done excellent working
making sure that we got the samples we
needed and you know these are all
through extensive collaborative efforts
Linda is now the chair of Neurosurgery
at UCLA and then in bioinformatics we
had another great team Tom graver and a
Nicholas Graham they really really just
came through and we had all this rain
sell data and they really made good
sense of it and they're the tom is in
CSI and Nick Graham went on to USC so
I'm I want to thank you can med go
Bruins
we're all in this together and you know
I just I think we've got a great future
with cannabis based medicine for some
going after some really really difficult
and harder to treat diseases I really
wanted to make time for questions but I
got like a couple minutes here so if
anybody has a real question come up to
the mic real quick so we can get it in
I'm going to talk about this isn't more
memoriam to our lost Mavericks Senator
John McCain died of a brain tumor this
picture was taken if you can look o at
see it you see his left eye right I left
I left I he had just come out of surgery
a few days before this picture and he
was back in Congress doing what he
needed to do and he died last month Beau
Biden Vice President Biden's son died in
2015 and then our partner on the
agricultural side we were in the process
of trying to you know we've got to
create this medicine from somewhere so
so I worked with our cultural partners
and you know moving forward and Josh's
Stanko was just an agricultural pioneer
taught me every just about everything I
need to know about the nature of how
we're going to turn this into medicine
and me coming from the lab and then all
of a sudden being embraced by an
agricultural field was really really
really wonderful and we lost him to a
car accident last year just out of
nowhere but that's just how it is so in
more into our lost Mavericks we do this
for a living there's always somebody
that were that were going to be helping
out as we move forward so all of us that
run into all these catch 420s get used
to it but you can do great work with it
one minute thank you my name is Kristen
Walsh legal I'm an RN nerd oncology
nurse navigator doing this work for
about two years
exclusively with cancer patients using
cannabis as well as integrated into
conventional care I see a trend that I
haven't heard talked about in research
recently neuroendocrine tumors seem to
be very vulnerable to some combination
of cannabinoids whether it's
neuroendocrine tumors of pancreas cervix
small cell lung cancer metastatic
prostate cancer and I just wanted to
raise
awareness because it sure seems to fit
in the category of stuff you're
interested in looking at lower electric
and differentiated tumors yeah I'd love
to talk to you and follow up about this
because these are the kinds of things
where we have these conversations and
then we have to go through what is the
real clinical process that we would take
to do a clinical trial and if we start
talking then we might be able to put a
stitch in time with regards to these
clinical trials and get these therapies
to out to the fields and into the
doctors heads quicker quicker thank you
okay thank you round of applause please
Michael master in Smith