[Applause]
thank you
thank you very much indeed thank you for
getting back
up so early in the morning to hear a
scientific lecture
so i'll try to give an overview of
what we know in several fields of
cannabis research and i'll be delighted
to to answer any questions that you may
have
at the end of the lecture and that's why
my title the title of the lecture is
looking back
and ahead for looking back will give us
some background
of what's going on at the moment and
looking ahead is
well let's hope that we're looking ahead
to
better medicines we're looking ahead of
helping a lot of patients
in a lot of diff with a lot of different
diseases now this was not what
went on many years ago when we started
work
and many years means about 50 years ago
i was just appointed to one of the
institutes research institutes in israel
and
as i'm a natural products chemist i was
looking for
interesting projects in the field of
natural products chemistry and
pharmacology
and one of the topics i
chose was looking into the chemistry
pharmacology and later hopefully
biochemistry
of cannabinoid cannabis and i was
surprised very surprised to find out
that while we knew quite a lot about
morphine which had been isolated from
opium many many decades previously and
the same was true for
cocaine from coca leaves the chemistry
of
cannabis was not well known as a matter
of fact the
active product or products had never
been isolated in a pure form
the structure was unknown and this is
not just
an academic matter uh there today
it is impossible to do pharmacological
or biochemical or clinical work
unless we know exactly what we're
working on i mean
you cannot do a clinical trials and tell
a patient
take cannabis and then publish it
because
physician today and rightly so will not
accept it as data
they want a scientific
re-based quantitative data they want to
know
rightly so what's going on exactly and
so
the starting point was still is
let's start with the chemistry elucidate
the chemistry
and go ahead into biochemistry
pharmacology and
hopefully clinical trials but there was
completely
there was not no interest at all as a
matter of fact when we started
working we couldn't get a s
a grant from nowhere uh
which was unpleasant we had to do
everything
uh some a colleague minor a few
colleagues of mine myself
we had to do everything by ourselves
there was absolutely no interest
whatsoever as a matter of fact
at the scientific institute where i was
working there telling me why don't you
work on peptides it's much more
important
than looking at a
plant out there well now things are
different
when we were asked last year to
write a review in nature nature
neuroscience
and cannabis and they had actually
four reviews one after the other on the
same topic on cannabis in different
aspects of cannabis there uh one came
out with a history
and background they put it on the front
cover with
as you can see with the brain from which
cannabis is
coming out well things have changed
so i can see so many people coming here
at half past eight in the morning to
hear
scientific lecture it it couldn't have
happened
uh 30 40 years ago well
why is the interest there there is a
review recently published by two nih
scientists very distinguished scientists
and they say amongst many other things
modulating endocannabinoid activity
may have therapeutic potential in almost
all diseases affecting humans and i give
a long list of
diseases and a huge number of references
which i've taken out
uh and you can see it's
neurodegenerative inflammatory et cetera
et cetera
and cancer and so on now i
do not know any other biochemical system
biological system
which uh for which we can say
that it has therapeutic potential in
almost all diseases affecting humans
this is very very unusual we cannot say
this
for the dopaminergic system we cannot
say this for the
serotonergic system it is something else
entirely
so obviously uh even if it is only
70 80 90 percent true it is still of
great interest and i assume that this is
one of the reasons why so many people
are now
interested in the cannabinoid system
from many points of view
so i'll try to summarize uh some of the
things that
i see is interesting but let me start
back a few years ago three three four
thousand years ago
with the assyrians they actually knew
quite a bit and we know that they knew
because they left uh
evidence most of the other tribes that
were around
most of the other nations that were
around at that time didn't leave that
much evidence
but the assyrians left the evidence on
stone and so we can read it
as long as it has not been destroyed by
those crazy people now
fighting it there but this particular
one is uh
in london so it's still there well they
had the name
for cannabis depending on its activity
rather than
on the plant itself and they called it
gansey gunu and i had somebody
and a syrian scholar translated for me
and it said
that it is the drug that takes away the
mind which is not a bad definition
probably better than pot or something
else so but the director takes
away the mind is just for the
psychoactivity
but when it was used for a clinical
uh when the use was clinical and we are
not exactly sure what kind of
diseases they were treating it seems
that they were treating neurological
diseases
they call it hazalo and they also used
it in religious rights which i
understand that also
not unknown here but if we jump ahead a
few years 2000 years ahead
we see that the romans and the greeks
also use it
but surprisingly not for the
psychoactivity
and i i think that it can be well
explained
uh european cannabis hemp really
does not contain dhc and therefore they
didn't see any psychoactivity
otherwise i'm sure that the romans would
have used it they
really try to to find
ways to to
enjoy themselves well the pliny said
that they're good for
pain and their squared is said it is
they are good for inflammations and
these cory this was a major
influence over 2000 years the book or
the book
of the ascoridus on drugs was really
repeated and translated
and copied and people used it until the
mid 19th century but if we jump another
2 000 years ago
[Music]
the physician of queen victoria
called russell reynolds used to
get cannabis from india for queen
victoria
that suffered for migraines and he found
that the european cannabis was not good
for her
but indian cannabis was very good for
her well we know that's true
under certain circumstances uh migraines
can be treated or can be prevented or
the activity or the
uh action of
the migraine can be lowered but so
we have known a lot about cannabis but
as you are well aware
then interest
probably was there to a certain extent
but because of legal problems and
because of
supply problems nothing or not much was
done
although two major groups worked on
cannabis in the 30s
roger adams in the us and alex stout who
got a nobel prize
for working something else they worked
on it but they never
succeeded in act actually isolating
the main compounds there and therefore
work
didn't go ahead we got from the police
and in all my early papers i say thanks
to the police which is not very usual
in scientific papers we
we got a cannabis so hashish
hashish is a cannabis that's grown in
lebanon and put in
small bags and smuggled so we got part
of the smuggled material
and we started the extracting smuggled
material and using
modern methods or at least methods that
were modern at that time
we were able to isolate a huge number of
compounds
now this is maybe the reason why science
or why chemistry
had not developed until then the mixture
is
so complicated that people or scientists
chemists were not able to identify to
isolate the compounds in there
so we started isolating
individual compounds and we were
surprised to see that
there are a huge number of compounds now
those of you that remember their
chemistry will see
these compounds are closely
related if you wish and we gave
their names depending on
the terpene part of the molecule we
called it canopy general
and we called the canopy cycle and
canopy chromine
and so on but although today they are
known about
oh i would say 50 60 maybe 80
compounds of this type two
of them have been investigated properly
they are the major ones
these are two of them are
cannabidiol cbd and tetrahydrocannabinol
and only one of them the thc causes the
psychoactivity
so there has been a huge amount of work
over the last decade i would say
uh on thc somewhat less than
cbd and cannabidiol because it doesn't
cause the psychoactivity and therefore
the people were less interested now
nowadays it seems that
actually interest is
going on more on canopy dial because of
its uh
therapeutic activities and not being
toxic and not being psychoactive
it can be given it can be administered
to patients at
huge uh amounts without any side effects
so there is a lot of interest in
cannabidiol and i hope to
have the time to tell you of some of the
work we and
others have been doing and both
compounds
well what do we at that time what did we
mean by
active well we didn't know much about
the activity so we tried it on
rhesus monkeys and only one compound thc
caused sedation to the monkey
here we have one of the monkeys without
getting any material very active
a little bit dangerous to get near it it
can bite you but
the other one injected with uh about
three
milligrams total dose of thc became
sedated
and my students usually say that
well that particular rhesus monkey looks
like a professor
thinking
well for the next nearly 20 years
a lot of people looked at these
compounds
and we got to know a lot about the
mechanism the biochemistry the
pharmacology of
these two compounds one thing that was
not known
uh and there was a mistake in the
literature was the mechanism
there was a mistake in the literature a
group at
oxford in the uk a major pharmacological
group
decided or wrote or brought some
evidence
that thc acts in a non-specific manner
maybe dissolving a nerve or dissolving
the nerve sheet and so on and that's why
it acts
and it was not a very great interest and
people didn't do much about it
well we didn't think that that's correct
and we found
evidence that actually it is not correct
and therefore
there should be something more specific
whether it's an
enzyme whether cannabinoids work in an
enzyme work on a receptor
work in some other biological way and
a group here in the us allen howlett
did some excellent work and found the
first receptor
and that receptor was found in the brain
in mice in exactly those areas
that are relevant areas that have to do
with movement control
with body movement coordination learning
and memory higher cognitive function
reward pathways and so on so this was
exactly the areas of the brain
one would expect a receptor to be found
now we know
that receptors and not found just
because there is a plant out there
does we it doesn't work that way
otherwise we'll have
a fantastic number of receptors in the
brain and it is
not true we have a limited number of
receptors and they're there because we
or animals produce
specific compounds that
bind to these receptors activate them
or block their activity and
that's the way receptors work
so we had to go out
and find the compounds that we produce
and these compounds would stimulate or
block the activity
of the receptor that allen howlett had
found now how
do you find a receptor it's not found in
great quantities normally it's found in
very
small amounts uh frequently like
cannabis endocan
endogenous cannabinoids they are found
uh
they're formed when and where needed so
we would expect to have absolutely
minimal amounts
not very simple to do it well how does
one do that in general one takes a
compound
that is very potent and in this case we
had a compound that's extremely
important
we called it h2h hebrew university we
we took that compound which is very
potent labeled it
and uh try to get it to bind to the
receptor which it does
and then we tried fractions from the
brain
that will kick out
this particular labeled compound from
his binding to the receptor
and those areas that do that then we
can take them from the particular area
of the brain
and try to analyze it and so on it's
easy to tell about it
doesn't take much time it took us two or
three years to do it a lot of
the work because it turned out that the
compounds
ultimately are not very stable but after
two years so three years of work
my post docs bill devane
and others found and we were able with
some modern equipment to determine the
structures and the
two structures we found out
two compounds which are present in our
brain and
in our body the first one we called
anandamide
ananda in sanskrit is a supreme joy and
we thought
probably correctly to a certain extent
we thought that it may be
involved in our
in enjoy the effects
and we called it indeed anandamite the
other one
uh we should have called an under ester
but we're not sure at the beginning
that it is indeed a natural product so
we called it two aging d
turned out that both compounds are the
major
endogenous cannabinoids in our body in
our brain
and thc in fact mimics
the activity of these endogenous
compounds so here we have
endogenous compounds of extreme interest
at least to us of extreme interest
and these two compounds are being
mimicked in their activity
by thc so
here we had a good basis and it has been
supported by
hundreds of papers and there is a lot of
interest in the escape
in these compounds now those few that
remember their chemistry will see that
anandamide and two aged endogenous
compounds
are completely different structurally
from tetrahydrocannabinol
and yet they bind to the same receptor
they're essentially
equivalent in their activity although
thc
stays for a longer time in the body
because it has to be
metabolized and
takes some time and that's why the
activity is prolonged
while anandamite and two ag are formed
when
and where needed not throughout the
brain
not throughout the body when and where
needed
they cause whatever they have to cause
lower pain or do something else
and then they are broken by specific
enzymes
so we have now a system which
has become quite complicated first of
all we have the two
there are two receptors one of them it
causes the psychoactivity
the other one and i'll try to talk a
little bit about the second one
does not cause any psychoactivity but it
is a protective enzyme it seems to be
and it seems to be a receptor that has
to do
in parallel if you wish with the
activity of the immune system
it's a protective mechanism
activation of the cb2 receptor is
a protective measure it's like the
immune system
the immune system guards us against
mostly it does all kinds of other things
but it guards us mostly against
proteins microbes come coming from the
outside
this but there are many things that are
not involved this particular system
complements the activity of the immune
system so we have two receptors
we have two major endogenous compounds
that
affect these two receptors we have
enzymes
that form
these endogenous compounds and enzymes
that break down these endogenous
so we can work on them if we suppress
one of them those that form the
uh endogenous cannabinoids and we have
lower amounts of those
endogenous cannabinoids if we suppress
the enzymes that break down
these two endogenous cannabinoids then
we have higher levels
so there is a lot of there are a lot of
possibilities
and this is what happens in the body
then we have
thc and cbd dhcx and the receptor cbd
does not
we really do not know when
and where cannabidiol works we have some
indications in many diseases in many
different physiological states we know
that particular activity that our
cannabidiol works but there is something
missing
we still i'm not sure what how
cannabidiol works in all cases
and then we discovered and many other
groups also discovered that
that in addition to anandamite and 2ag
there is a
huge huge number of compounds closely
related chemically
now an underbite is a simple compound
it is a fatty acid in the body there are
about 20 of them there is a fatty acid
bound to amino acid that's it simple
a little bit of a few changes but that's
it fatty acid bound to amino acid now we
have
a few a few fatty acids we have a few
amino acids they can bind
to each other and therefore we have
something like
200 of them in our brain in our body
and we know very little about the
activity of these
200 or 150 200 compounds some of them
present in minute amounts
some are present in somewhat larger
amounts we are starting to learn about
them
and it turns out that those that have
been investigated
all of them all of those that have been
investigated have
some kind of activity not necessarily
cannabinoid type activity they may have
all kinds of other activities and i'll
mention some of them so the field is
becoming very complicated
we have so many compounds now why does
the body make
so many compounds difficult to say maybe
it has something to do with
other things that are happening maybe it
has to do with
our personality information of our
personality but
so we have an endocannabinoid system
which is becoming
quite complicated and
changes of this endocannabinoid system
may lead to pathological state to
diseases
for one type and another and we have to
learn that and
in order to modify the changes which
cause the disease so after making things
very complicated i'll
try to go into uh specific
uh diseases if you wish but let's see
what did the endocannabinoids do my good
friend dimaso said well
that was almost 10 years ago well
the endocannabinoids call person to
relax
eat sleep forget and protect well you
can see that out of these
five activities uh four are certainly
positive relax eat sleep protect
forget is that so positive well it is
positive
if you go into a supermarket and you see
500 people there
you definitely don't want to remember
all of them this
so forgetting is also positive
as long as it is in the right way of
doing it
now we know that it's much more
complicated than that
this is a slide that i prepared some yes
a year ago and we have a
short list i can probably add another 20
activities and they the endocannabinoid
system is involved
from anxiety appetite blood pressure etc
etc
down to movement disorder neuro
protection pain reproduction
stress so it is essentially all
essentially all activities so if there
are any changes
in the endocannabinoid system we can see
changes in that kind of activity well
not a very simple
situation certainly not a very simple
situation uh
for um for a clinician uh he cannot
treat all of these things
so i'll try to show how
specific these changes can be i will not
go into the biochemistry
not going to the physiologists it will
take too much time i'll
mention just one thing
as we know the nerves are not a
nerve is not a string from one place to
another definitely not
we have
breaks in that a
string if you wish and the break
is in order to make
possible regulation of the
symptom of the signal signal that goes
from one place to another place
and this break is called the synapse and
we have the pre-synaptic part and the
post-inactive part
and the movement the
movement of the signal from one part to
another is chemical
there are chemicals that go from the pre
synapse to the post synapse
well the body does it more complicated
it has to regulate that
movement of chemicals
dopamine or any others or glutamate
it has to regulate it how does it
regulate it
one of the ways is by the
endocannabinoid mechanism
then the cannabinoids when needed are
formed under post-synapse
they move from the post-synapse to the
pre-synapse
they bind to the to their own
receptors and then they can block the
release of neurotransmitters
from the pre-synapse to the post-synapse
so in addition to the activity
their own activity the activity of the
endocannabinoids
they also regulate the activity of many
other neurotransmitters
and that's why it ha they have so many
activities because they have activities
of their own
and they also regulate the activities of
quite a few other neurotransmitters so
things are becoming very complicated but
i will
not go into that part of cannabinoid
research
but we'll go and speak about specific
uh situation or clinical situations
uh like neuroprotection
my good friend esti shohami
she's a specialist in brain trauma
we looked at the levels of one of the
endocannabinoids
after brain trauma in in mice
and we saw that one of the
endocannabinoid 2ag
goes up nearly 10 fold
after brain trauma
so is that just because the brain has
been traumatized and
doesn't know what it does or is it just
a reaction
of the brain in order to lower the
damage
and the red thing you can see here
shows the level of 2ag after the brain
trauma
with after four hours quite a bit and we
thought well let's see
whether it's a protective mechanism
so we synthesized enough 2ag
and gave it to traumatized
mice and went on to look whether
the damage that has been done on the
brain
goes down and indeed i will not go into
great details we gave
we did all kinds of things but we gave
these brains to
the histologists and they were surprised
to find out that those brains
the brains of mice that had been
administered to
ag had 50 percent less damage
you can see the damage the white part in
the brain
those that receive 2ag have much less
white part that's the damage power
that's a dead part if you wish
then the controls that didn't receive to
2ag
and that was done several times that was
published in nature
quite quite a few years ago and so we
believe we strongly believe that
these compounds are neuroprotective
after brain trauma now why this has not
advanced
to clinical trials although we've
completed quite a lot of work on that
and other people have done also work
and that i have no idea but this is
something quite general
we have a lot of interesting data
in mice and that's it it has not
progressed further
although brain damage contestants are of
extreme importance nowadays
not nowadays it always have been
what about actions that go through the
cb1 receptor
well uh those clinicians here or
general public knows that cancer
chemotherapy
although it may be very valuable and at
times
causes side effects again at times which
are
very very unpleasant and we decided to
try
a thc in cases of cancer chemotherapy in
children
i was in close touch with a colleague of
mine head's a department of
pediatric cancer in one of the hospitals
and of course she was telling me about
the tragic situation
children getting cancer chemotherapy uh
being crying most of the time and
feeling terrible and it was a tragic
for them and for the families could we
do something
so we decided to try thc and do a double
blind study
50 of the children will get a placebo 50
will get
thc in addition to the cancer
chemotherapy of course
and after a week she came back to me
said i can't do it
i know exactly who is getting it maybe
double blind
or triple blind or four times blind i
know exactly who is getting it
those that are getting the thc do not
vomit they feel fine
those that are not getting it feel
terrible
so she did an open study we ultimately
published it
and we found that indeed thc
given to those children in uh
olive oil under the tank helped
essentially 100
of the patients very strange because one
doesn't see in
clinical trials 100 of uh activity but
that's what she found
we published it and i believe that it's
being used here and there but not
enough and it it can be used it's
innocuous and we can help children
suffering from that what happens here
i i can't move the slides can you help
oh here it is
then we tried something else we knew
that feeding eating
is affected by cannabinoids
so pups
were injected with an antagonist
to the system to the cb1 and
we saw that the pups did not
[Music]
go to the mother and did not suck
anymore
although they obviously should have
sucked in order to remain alive
they just didn't sat around their
brothers and sisters did that
and continues uh growing
those that didn't just sat around and
after a week or so would die
so obviously the cannabinoid system is
important in certain
uh if as i said if we block it they
don't suck
but if we in the middle after two or
three days is seated
perps are not certain we give them thc
large amounts they will start again and
go grow and so on so obviously
it's a very important factor in
child feeding and sucking in this case
now a company
looked at that and they also saw that in
cases of
ace for example if aids are given thc
the patients remain at their
weight for a much longer time to those
that got
placebo so the company sanofi
had a an antagonist and they gave it to
pay to overweight patients and they
knew that that's a huge number of
patients the us
in most of the western countries and
they'll have a
huge number of patients they make a lot
of money and they
develop this particular compound called
it ramona band
and they put it on the market and after
uh
just a few weeks they took it out and
the reason for that was
they didn't think enough about
the other effects of of uh the
cannabinoid system
the cannabinoid system has to do with
anxiety it lowers
anxiety and if you give an antagonist it
not only blocks
appetite or lowers the amount of
a food one it takes but it also
enhances anxiety because we block
the system the system which has to do
with with anxiety
and quite a few patients became anxious
and i believe that one or two
wanted to commit suicide i'm not sure
about it i heard rumors that this was so
and they took it out of the market well
so we have to know
quite a lot before doing something of
that sort
maybe they should have told the patients
if you're anxious don't take it
well anyway rimono bound was taken out
of the market
and then another
effect that we worked on and this was a
small clinical trial
on traumatic stress disorder ptsd
there are quite a lot of patients with
ptsd we had about 10
some of them were soldiers who had been
involved some
maybe a friend of theirs was killed next
to them and they went into a
post trauma there were two women that
were raped
there were two
men and a woman i think that were
involved in a traffic accident
and we started giving them a thc
five milligrams a day twice or three
times a day
and the clinician who did that work dr
roidman a psychiatrist
he as i said gave them five milligrams
per day
and he looked at a lot of the effects
and there are
all kinds of clinical uh things that
people that are involved on ptsd have
developed
and they uh wrote them down and looked
at the frequency of nightmares
the sleep quality uh the
global symptom of severity and so on and
indeed he found that there were positive
effects he didn't
see any complete elimination of the ptsd
but he saw very a great improvement in
particularly in sleep
these patients frequently cannot sleep
or are afraid to go to sleep because
they are afraid that
they will uh recall the
if the effect that caused other
trauma that caused this effect whether
it was a
rape or whether it was a an accident
whether it was a person killed next to
him
so i believe that it can be used it
should be used
in a way that
we can help uh ptsd patients
what about the cb2 receptor which is
more interesting because the cb2 does
not cause any
uh side effects well um
as i said i believe that the cb2 system
parallels to a lot extend the immune
system
uh it has to it can do a lot of
a lot of things which in which
external proteins are not involved and
indeed there are long lists of effects
which certainly going to show in that
direction
and we believe that the cb2 system
the research on the cb2 system will lead
us
to a lot of information showing that
the two systems together the immune
system
and the cb2 action work together
and are of major importance to what's
going on
and indeed we have prepared synthetic
compounds
which act only in the cb2 receptor and
these compounds do not bind to the cb1
receptor
you can see the numbers there doesn't
matter generally
the fact is they do not bind to the cb1
receptor
they bind only to the cb2 receptor and
therefore they can be used
hopefully as drugs in the cb2
system and the work that has been done
at nih
by a group has shown that
one of these compounds which we call
hu910 attenuates inflammation
lowers damage associated with hepatic
reperfusion
injury and there's all kinds of positive
things so i believe that the
cb2 specific cb2
action will be of considerable
importance
and quite a few both academic labs
and industrial labs are looking at the
cb2 system
because of its lack of side effects
it has been shown to act in crohn's
disease in
inflammatory bowel disease in asthma all
this
is in animals unfortunately no
clinical trials yes the most important
or most
interesting most advanced thing is
actually work
on cannabidiol as i said
no cannabidiol does not cause any
side effects it does not bind to the
receptors and we have seen that it acts
on anxiety
very a good action in anxiety in many
cases
we have seen that in mice mice are
anxious all the time they are afraid
of of cats they're afraid of us if
positive they
stay in a dark part and there is
something called the elevated plus maze
which is up meter above
that place where a mouse can be in the
dark or
it can get out and the amount of time it
gets
out of the dark place shows the
lowering of anxiety a lot of psych
people that work in psychopharmacology
using this method
and we found that indeed a cannabidiol
as well derivatives cannabidiol do that
they lower the
anxiety of mice and as we well know
cannabidiol also lowers the anxiety in
humans unfortunately
again we don't have many
clinical trials i think we have just one
or two
inflammation a good friend of mine
together with the group in the uk
the person that did the work in the uk
was in london at that time and now he's
at oxford
and we found that indeed cannabidiol
lowers rheumatoid arthritis and
in mice but here we saw something which
seems to be quite typical
for cannabinoids at okay
5 2.5 milligrams per kilo we saw no
effect
at five milligrams per gallon which is
the red one
on the bottom yes there is a very
positive effect
i wouldn't explain how we get a clinical
score but we get a very good effect
of anti-rheumatoid arthritis
great but then if we go to higher doses
we get less effect so here we have
something
which is a double-faced i mean nothing
at a very low
level quite a bit of activity at a
somewhat higher level
but then the activity disappears at even
if the concentration of the drug has
gone up
so this is not very uh
simple to to to lead us to clinical
trials because we have
to find the amount of material that will
be relevant
to humans but again it should be done
now
this particular disease arthritis is an
autoimmune disease
the body attacks its own body so we said
okay
if it works and then this kind of
arthritis maybe
it will work in diabetes type one
which is also an autoimmune disease
the body attacks the cells that produce
insulin
and although there are drugs that work
in diabetes type one
insulin by itself works maybe
we can have a new type of drug which
will be very efficient
and indeed when we gave cannabidiol
to a strain of mice that all of them
develop
diabetes type one we saw
a extremely good effects and we started
giving the drug
after the mice had were already
developing the disease
that is to say that during the 12th
or 13th week of uh uh
of their lives when they start
developing diabetes type one
their body attacks the cells that
produce insulin
and normally 80 to 100 percent of these
mice
get the disease and they die from the
disease if we give cannabidiol
at relatively high doses we see that
only
30 percent of the mice get the disease
now here really it is
open to clinical trials because the
disease in this case is exactly the same
it's not just a simple model it is
exactly the same
here we have a
situation which the body attacks
the cells that produce insulin this is
what happens
in diabetes type one in human patients
we should be able to do a clinical trial
essentially at once uh and
unfortunately although we published that
quite some years ago
it is still not it is it has not been
tried
very unfortunately because i believe
that here we have an open situation
and if you look don't forget everything
else just the
percent intact eyelets the cells that
produce it
though the controls only eight percent
of the
cells are still intact but
if we give cbd 77 of the cells
that produce insulin are intact a huge
difference and here we have a
good explanation and i see no reason why
it shouldn't happen
in humans as well we shall have a
lecture
on epilepsy later on but
try to tell you something that we did
more than 35 years ago
after looking at animals in animal
trials we decided to go into
epilepsy in humans gave we took 15
epileptic patients that nothing was
helping them anymore
or separated into those that got the
placebo and those that got
the drug and of those that got the drug
we gave them for
four and a half months pure cannabidiol
at very high doses
now that was not simple because i had to
prepare in the lab
about 400 grams almost half a kilo of
pure cannabidiol which it's not very
simple for an academic lab to do
but we got the 400 grams send them to
south america and they did that that and
found that
the four patients out of eight remained
almost
completely free of seizures and three
had a
partial improvement and one showed no
improvement
which was what one would expect in a
clinical trial
and of course the placebo people
continue to have
their seizures so we thought 35 years
ago
well here we have a small trial
it should be expanded by a clinical
group or by a
company and here we can have a new
anti-epileptic drug and we know that not
all epileptic patients
are helped by the drugs that exist at
the moment but then nothing happened
for 35 for almost 30 years
nothing happened nobody bothered to
repeat it nobody
bothered to go ahead and give it to
adults or children
but then parents that had epileptic
children nothing was helping them
learned of this paper learned of
observations that show that well some
cannabis
strains with a lot of cannabidiol help
let's try it because nothing else
helps so there have been a lot of
individual
cases in which patients parents have
given
the drug to their children and it has
helped and there has been quite a lot of
noise around it
in the u.s in particular and therefore
two years ago
a clinical trial was started and i
understand the
results are quite positive at the moment
in israel cannabidiol strains
cannabidiol containing strains
are officially allowed to be
administered
to be given to children and there are
quite a lot of children that get it
and so this is also happening here but
it shouldn't have waited
35 years it could have been done
30 years ago why didn't well it didn't
there is there is so much that the clint
that an academic lab can do and i'm
and this is the situation with quite a
few of the things i'm describing
uh schizophrenia slightly different
we had shown that in individual cases
cannot be dialed very high doses help
schizophrenia
and a german group did a relatively
major study
they looked at schizophrenia and they
found that
indeed a cannabidiol
is equivalent to one of the major drugs
that's being used today
in schizophrenia with one small
difference
although the results were as the same
between the
drug that's being used today and
cannabidiol the drug that's being used
today has side effects
many of these drugs have side effects
strong side effects
cannabidiol had no side effects so
they come as i said they compared cbd
with sulprite
and they found that they have
the same type of activity and i hope i
sincerely hope
that cannabidiol will be used in
schizophrenic patients but i haven't
heard of any additional clinical studies
although the
german paper was published 98
about four four and a half years ago
and i will end
because of lack of time with graft
versus hose disease now
this is a
man caused disease many patients
with certain cancers have
their bone marrow transplanted
and this causes
serious side effects many of the
patients are very sick
and the disease is basically again a
disease in which the body attacks its
own body in this case the
body attacks something that we have
transplanted
and the transplant itself attacks the
body
so what's going on is that the person
is very sick in cases of children
i've seen children that have
transplanted
a bone marrow and they're in a terrible
shape really one cannot stand that
and it was found that
it lowers the effects
by nearly 50 percent uh
in 100 patients that served as control
we had 46 percent with
gbhd with the disease and only 12
percent
in those that got cannabidiol and those
that really had a bad
bad case is called the three or four
grade
of uh gvhd we lowered that from 10
to 5 and now a further clinical trial is
going on
with many more patients now um
i think that uh i'll have to stop here
though
i have quite a few other things i would
have liked to tell you
like new cannabidiol type compounds
and some regulation vasodilation
and just mention one thing the
endocannabinoids like anandamide
are additional compounds as i mentioned
first was i said the beginning
quite a lot of additional compounds way
which do the same thing
on the top you can see an andamite on
the bottom you can see a compound called
arachido oil serine which are not very
different structurally but they do
completely different things and we hope
that
investigations will go on with these
compounds
and we shall know quite a lot
about them within the next few years
and i want to
summarize the endocannabinoids are
involved in a large number of
physiological processes
with both thc and cbd there are those
compounds which i didn't have enough
time to discuss
that are fatty acids bound to amino
acids we still have to learn
a lot about them i believe there are
extreme importance
surprisingly we know very little about
it and i hope
that specific cb2 agonists will lead to
new types of drugs and i
want to thank the collaborators in
israel you can see
on the left people that worked in my lab
i collaborate with a lot of colleagues
my lab is
essentially a chemical about chemical
lab but i collaborate with people that
work in
bones in traumas and so on
and i work with a
large number of colleagues abroad and
here are some of them
uh roger pertwee in the uk and you can
see bone and
the czech state and many many others and
they visit me i visit them and we drink
a lot of coffee together
and we enjoy unchanging information
and i've visited all of them enjoy going
in
to their labs i've been to all of all of
them except
one dr masloff in siberia
had a meeting in a few months ago in
february
and he wrote me that no you don't have
to worry
the the weather is okay usually it's
minus 35
centigrade now it's only 25 centigrade
and i said thank you maybe next time
thank you
no problem
we have a few minutes for questions
folks so if you'd like to ask the doctor
a question please step up to one of the
mics
any questions at all we'd love to have a
few questions
i'd like to ask a question
if i'm clear you're saying we have found
anandamide these endocannabinoids and
now we're finding 200 more
and you're sorting out that code to all
those
endocannabinoids is there being a
correlation
made just the way anandamide correlates
with thc
are we seeing or are we studying the
correlation of
all those other endocannabinoids and
associating them with the
action or chemical structure of all the
other
phytocannabinoids from what we know at
the moment
anandamite or thc mimics an endomite
it doesn't mimic the other compounds the
body
[Music]
is uh lazy so once it knows how to make
an endomite
it makes a lot of other compounds uh
going to the same enzyme system but the
compounds that are formed not
necessarily
endocannabinoids in their action they do
all kinds of other things
this is known throughout our system for
example
the steroid system once the body knows
how to make the steroid
by making small changes on the steroid
you get different type of
compounds estrogens that work
as female hormones but you have
compounds that have nothing to do with
estrogen
again with the same basic structure here
we have the same
we have the same basic structure an
amino acid
bound to a fatty acid but it has
completely different
activities and as we have 150 compounds
of that type
who knows what they are doing so we have
yes
anandamai that is being mimicked by thc
but we also have a lot of
other compounds of which we know
just a tiny little bit one compound that
i may
discuss this afternoon is a compound
which we found that
has to do with osteoporosis and it
blocks
the destruction of bones after a certain
age
so here we have something completely
different and yet
it goes following the same chemical
system
because the body knows how to do it well
to make a correlation you've discovered
this
endo chemical that affects osteoporosis
and then would there be
a logical jump then to cbg or another
phytocannabinoid
that is known as bone growth stimulator
probably i think the answer is yes
probably yes
thank you so much
hey my question for you dr micholim is
how much research are you doing
specifically with terpenes and terpenes
in conjunction with cannabinoids
and what i mean by that is dr sue sicily
who is studying
ptsd with cannabis
she's not permitted to study terpenes
with her research
and we all know that you know the
d-limonene is what causes
ptsd patients to have bad reactions
whereas linalool
is kind of the opposite effect how much
of your work is devoted to terpenes
well uh the cannabis plant
contains a large number of additional
compounds
compounds that are not cannabinoids
tonight's terpenes
flavonoids all kinds of other things
many years ago we
found that there is something we call
the entourage effect
we call it entourage effect meaning that
compounds that by themselves are not
very
active or not active at all change
the activity of other compounds in this
case of cannabinoids
and indeed this has been seen by many
people
taking cannabinoids saying well the
total plant
works much better than just plain thct
it sees
an official drug in this country but not
a
particularly successful one
but the plant is and it seems to be that
there is a
major uh thing for going on
and it's this unto raj effect
unfortunately
in addition to our own paper quite a few
years ago
there has been very little work done
undone to raj effect we know that it
exists
but it has to be much more
investigated and it has not been
investigated which is a
pity but again it's one of those lacunas
if you wish that
have to be looked into thank you
thank you hi my name is valeria and i
wanted to ask you
first of all thank you for a wonderful
presentation
secondly i wanted to ask you to share
your
ideas about the role of cannabinoids and
the transmission of the pain
signals in in the body the reason i ask
is that
i went through the literature and i
found out that
many researchers indicated that
thc and cannabinoids they do not have
profound effect on the severe pain
they may have some effect on the local
pains
and i know that the recent studies made
in the uh
performed in the united states by the
combination of cbd and thc
in the cancer pain didn't produce any
hopeful results so i want to hear what
you think about that
well i believe you're right it seems
that a mixture
in the case of pain at least of cbd and
thc
seems to be better than thc alone
i wish we had more information of the
amounts of the types of pain or not
every pain of course is the same
cannabinoids do not work on
acute pain but they work on neuropathic
pain
and we have to know more about it
yes chances are that it's better to
have both cbd and dhc chances are that
it's better to have
thc and maybe some of the other
compounds
done to rush compounds but again the
data
in the literature is insignificant
thank you we have time for one more
question
and then uh uh dr machula will be
available during coffee break because
your questions
um so if you will be out in the lobby
and uh you'll get a chance to meet him
uh after we break here sir
first of all thanks for speaking that
was mind-blowing um but i wanted to say
i just wanted
to like when you're talking about the
the cb1 receptor i can't hear you well
oh yeah hold on yeah let me see
when you're talking about the there we
go um the cb1 receptor and how you had
that whole
um program for like how the synapses
work i was wondering what were like the
obstacles you were facing with the
like with the cb2 receptor i know you
were saying we don't know a lot about
that when compared to the cb1
i'm sorry i mean i didn't get what did
he
ask just like the difference between
studying the cb1 receptor when you have
the nerve synapse before
compared to the cb2 well
there should be investigations in both
the cb1 is acted upon by thc by both
endocannabinoids
the cb2 is also acted on
by thc and both endocannabinoid
receptors
it acts therefore the activity is
dispersed
i believe that the way we and many
others are going ahead
by trying to have specific
cb2 agonists is very promising
having the activity only in the cb2 and
this
in this way eliminating any possible
psychoactivity and this but at the
moment
there isn't a single drug on the market
which is
cb2 specific this is yeah
if this was if i understood you well
thank you thank you doctor
thank you i appreciate it
you