hello my name is TJ Martin today I'm
going be talking to you guys about the
chemical origins of fruity and savory
exotic cannabis
Aromas and
so so why are we looking into this and
why should we all care about why
cannabis smells and tastes the way it
does well a lot of what when consumers
are going to a dispensary and they're
making their purchasing decisions a lot
of it may be based on te HC content it's
obviously a very well-known quantity in
the industry bag appeal especially when
you're thinking about things like how
the flower butt itself looks or when
you're looking at concentrates what's
the color of the concentrate and the
consistency but another thing to
consider is also how does it smell and
taste right when a consumer takes this
product home they are going to smoke or
and consume it um they they have some
predisposition or some thought about
what it's going to Smart taste like when
they bring it home and if it's something
they enjoy it's going to be something
that may um Drive these decisions for
why they decide to repurchase said
products and the r of cannabus has this
broad range right it can range anything
from gassy and sweet Woody and citrus
spicy
creamy even things such as grape
tropical gassy Citrus skunky chemical or
even more more nuanced things like
papayas and
pineapples and so what is some of the
chemistry that we know right now a lot
of it this a sanky diagram what a sanky
diagram does it breaks down the
metabolites of Interest into how they
are based on weight and so this is these
are proportional to the weight that's
inside the actual cannabis flower
material obviously canab noids take up a
large portion of it specifically thca
because what I'm looking at today is um
THC high THC cannabis but then also
breaks down into other things like other
class which would be flavonoids fats
waxes
um and Aroma compounds and Aroma
compounds you break down into things
like tpin or flavorant tpin are a subass
of flavorant but for the purposes of
this I will keep them separate and
flavorants break down into Esters
alcohols alahh can of sufur compounds
and these are some of the lowest weight
com um weight content materials in the
plant but they may have some of the
highest odor impacts to the actual
material itself
and so the AR
Aroma aromatic categorization of
cannabis as we know it today obviously
have prototypical that's your
traditional OG kushes things like
wedding cake Gorilla Glue are very spicy
herbal and gassy as well as Jack herror
and hazes that have some Citrus notes
them very piny very terpenic but when
you start thinking outside of the
classical range you think of things
about like sweet Exotics and savory
Exotics so when we started this we
really wanted to understand what makes
Mak sweet exotic cannabis smell and
taste the way it does obviously we know
a lot about tpin tpin are in the plant
have been studied heavily but what are
the correlations in the plant that lead
to make a strain like zittles have some
of its unique candy notes so more exotic
Berry cannabis like blue icy blackberry
kush have their dark berry notes and as
we're going through this we running some
um more sensory panels internally and
ask giving people free questionnaires
like hey can you please describe this
cannabis hiid as liberal of terms as you
can be open and honest about it we were
originally starting to look at just how
does sweet differentiate from
prototypical and we were using actually
garlic cookies as a control and one of
our panelists we asked them like hey is
this would you consider this a exotic or
not they said well it's not a sweet
exotic but in the context of is it
prototypical no not really either right
it's more of a Savory exotic and so as
we started going through this we're
wondering like hey is there chemistry
behind this that explains how there's
also SA exotic and cannabis and as you
start seeing the trends in the industry
today we're seeing things like Donnie
burger and pot roast coming in more
popularity the meat breath strains right
obviously funny name right but that's
just how the industry goes but these are
new more Nuance strains that are
definitely not sweet but they're also
not prototypical either so there's got
to be some chemistry there that can
explain those
differences and so we started everything
from specifically rosin in this study
the reason we used cin was it allows us
to get more a higher concentration of
the volatile flavorant than flour flour
has a range of half% to 3 or 4%
depending on the specific Cult of our of
choice whereas rosin can from 5 to 15%
depending on the C of our and how it's
extracted it also allows us to get a
homogeneous sample going onto our GC
when someone makes rosin they're using
multiple plants that are going through
its extraction process if you take just
a singular flower Bud you're pulling it
from Just just one plant depending on
where you pull it from the plant may
have different impacts on the aroma this
allows us to get a homogeneous sample
also has minimal processing we're not
worried about solvent carryover solvent
contributions to anything it just
strictly allows us to get what is truest
to the sample with as minimal processing
and most hity
possible and so some of the data that
came through our initial sensory panels
we running through this um we have on
top our four most sweet varieties and on
bottom are for most Savory varieties as
you can see on what we have here are
density plots this allows us to
demonstrate how much some of these terms
were used to describe these strains so
things like grape pie doido had a lot of
sweet fruity dark berry notes claimed
and things like papaya Peach and
Juiceman had a lot of sweet fruity as
well some tropical and citrus notes
being claimed but not very many Savory
notes um whereas the Savory varieties
had a lot of these savory acious
sulfuric chemical notes coming up and
the reason we did this is with the study
we really wanted to correlate Trends and
sensory data to actual hard chemical
data on the samples that we were
measuring and see if we can start to
find certain compounds that are highly
responsible for why these strains smell
and taste the way they do if you look
something you'll notice as well is that
all these all have the prototypical AR
of cannabis always noted Within These
strains there's slight variations from
cultivar to cultivar but is always there
which is really important to
note and one of the first things we need
to know is is this is any the Exotic
Aroma due to specifically the uh the
main turbines that are present the major
weight
compounds and so we plot here on the
left in figure a is we have exotic score
from 0 to 100 how was ranked by the
panel as well as where that ranked in
relation to one another and as you look
through the plot there is no real Trend
but between any of the major turbines
it's kind of all over the board same
thing on the right when we try and trend
is it is there any specific Trends with
the total number of Aroma classifiers in
the context of sweet exotic there was
when it gets more of a sweet exotic it
gets a lot to the consumers it's more
nuanced it gets more difficult to
explain so you get a lot more
descriptors versus savoring prototypical
there's not as much
correlation so we went ahead and looked
at what however all these correlated to
one another so we have here is a
correlation Matrix um and from
decreasing exotic score from the top to
the bottom and what this plot allows us
to do is compare each cultivar to one
another from all their sensory
descriptors and say hey how are these
similar or not are there any
relationships between each cultivars and
so the lighter the color the more
similar they are the darker the color
the less similar they are and we noce
there was a huge diversity here which
was great that's what we wanted we
wanted a lot of diversity because that
allows us to start looking to the
chemistry find Trends and start to
understand more about this complex field
of cannabis science um something was
interesting we saw Gorilla Glue was this
specific sample was very similar to
garlic cocktail number 7 I'll come back
to that a little bit later but it's
important to note that these should not
really have much similarity to be
honest so now we have our sensory data
now we can go in and start actually
doing some of the hard chemistry what
we're doing is we're using uh GC cross
GC with a Toof Mass Spec detector and an
FID GC cross GC is a type of
two-dimensional gas chromatography what
that means is allows us to employ a
traditional gas chromatograph where you
separate based on compound size but then
at the end it has a pulse flow modulator
which allows you to then separate on a
second column in that same GC but then
bipolarity so you can get a greater
degree of separation and you can see
more of what's in these samples than
what you'd originally have access to
and as we are going through this we used
we built out a custom standard for all
of our quantitation worked with
different standards companies to get as
many compounds as commercially available
in an actual calibration standard so
these can based on calibrated values and
really try and find these Trends we're
also using direct injection over headp
space this allows us to get as accurate
reproducible data as possible and get
more mass on column and see more of
those low analytes because a lot of
these like I showed in the sinki diagram
are very low weight amounts so you have
a high chance that you may not be able
to see it if you don't get enough
material on the GC
itself and this is the data we got we
ran through all 30 samples ranking from
Super Savory to classical to Exotic and
everything pretty much looks the same
when you look at a top down view of it
because what you see on the GC is a lot
of the major compounds which don't
differentiate that much between cultiv
tic cultiv are and so unfor when you
look at it it's like here we have great
py doido are most fruity exotic and GMO
are most Savory and the chromatograms
look almost identical the set the monot
turpine region looks very similar the
sasat turpine later region looks almost
identical so I'm going to dive deeper
into this so what we know aromatically
from sensory these are different they
smell different they taste different but
the GC data looks very similar so it
means there must be some minor compounds
that are heavily contributing to these
differences and so went back to our
correlation matrices but instead of
looking at actually just the sensory
differentiation now let's actually do it
on all analytes so here on the left we
have all analytes detected for the
samples we put it into a correlation
Matrix again based this is based on how
light it is is how similar they are how
dark it is how different each strain is
to one another and you can see some
differences
but not a ton to be honest other than
bubble gum Zid um Gorilla Glue and train
wreck train wre obviously is a high
tpine based strain which is one of the
few turpening based rosins we actually
find in Southern California for this
study so that one is going to be
different but if you go down and now
break it down and Well's look at just
compare just monot Turpin and
monoterpenoids it looks pretty similar
you don't see a lot of heavy differences
again showing that monot Turpin
monoterpenoids while important to canab
aren't the differentiating factor in
these exotic Aromas and if you go
further and look at sespan and
sesquiterpenoids they look almost
identical like these are all
09599 or even 10 similarities meaning
it's they're 95 99%
similar now if you take it a bit further
and go just the flavor and remove
everything else out move all the
turbines monps cesco turps out you see
huge differences this is where you start
seeing a lot of the variation but
between these cultivars and that plot
now looks a lot more like our sensory um
correlation
matrices and we started looking and data
we found is a whole bunch of different
flavorings and these are some of the key
ones we wanted to call out because they
are really important to these various
Aromas so and some of these are these
are all well-known compounds by and
large in the traditional flavor
chemistry realm but not necessarily in
the context of cannabis and what it does
in cannabis flavors and Aromas and so on
like the flu fruity side fruity floor
you have things like methyl anthranilate
really common like concord grape purple
grape soda
flavor um some of the really interesting
ones are the creamy sweet compounds
these like six AML Alpha pyone and some
these are compounds in that around that
of purple these are very much your stone
fruit coconut flavors chemical napil
these are heterocycles we've never
really seen nitrogen heterocycles in
cannabis nor we think about flavoring
we're thinking of carbon oxygen POS
sulfur these are super interesting to
see um tropical Citrus is a new class of
tropical sulfur compounds in cannabis
that they've been found other places but
these are driving some of these unique
flavor notes that are in tangu strains
these weird Citrus notes you don't get
anywhere else um fusil Suite these are
seates these are when you're thinking of
think of strains like Zid um runts
gelados really heavily in zittles to be
honest these comp compounds give it that
what makes zittles unique and different
from other Exotics that are even Berry
notes is these CIO compounds and in the
fruy suite these ethylate ethy isov
valorate really important EST uh very
sharp top note that helps again push
this Aroma for
cannabis and so when you think about
Savory Exotics why does SA EXA why do
these GMOs these garlic cookies have
this unique scent to them
and so we found we were looking
comparing our sensory data to our GC
data we notice as there are some key
non-turing compounds that correlate with
this intensely Savory Aroma and these
was indol and Scat scat is found in
human feces and malean feces it gives
poop it smell um and has a wider range
of aromatic impact it's used heavily in
the fragrance industry as well because
depending on the dose rate you use it it
can impact things from we know savory
Bary and cannabis all the way to just
chemical napthol like moth ball scent
and very pretty offputting to be honest
but if what's interesting if you look at
chemical structure it's actually very
similar to what you see in melatonin and
this is again indol and Scat all pretty
ubiquitous in nature is interesting to
see in
cannabis but to highlight just how
difficult it is to actually see these
this is just um we're looking here is
GMO rosin which is some of the richest
in these compounds we've measured
on the top plot there you have a linear
scale I've highlighted in the box with
the red circles you can't see them now
if you put on a log scale and start
really blowing it up you can see it a
little bit you really have to zoom into
the region and see that there's these
tiny little Peaks that are really buried
in the chromatogram and if this was on a
one onedimensional GC it would have been
incredibly tough to find this unless you
already knew they were there and built a
method for detecting it and so these
were again kudos to the scci to an
chemist working on this Dr Ian Oswalt
for finding these really buried in there
but these are so important to why GMO
chem dog these various strains smell and
taste the way they
do and just another interesting piece
about these scat is very similar to 33
diol methane it's a CB2 receptor Agonist
that specific compound has promising
anti-cancer properties for certain cell
lines it also is found in various um
vegetables B what that compound is it is
two scats um bonded together so maybe
scat has some impacts for different
aspects of cannabis whether it's the
mood effects or medicinal
properties then getting more into now
the tropical vscs these other compounds
that are being when we looked in our
data correlated heavily with wio these
tropical and petroleum citrus strains
smell so unique and different from other
strains we notice is there is three
mercapto hexanol three mercapto hexol
acetate and three mapto hexal
beate um interestingly enough this is
the Gorilla Glue I mentioned earlier had
similarities with garlic cocktail number
seven garlic cocktail is a very
petroleum Citrus tropical strain Gorilla
Glue is not Gorilla Glue actually when I
went and procured the sample for the
study we win got it as a control for our
sensory panel to use because Gorilla
Glue should be very spicy herbal some
gassiness earthiness and we brought it
in I remember opening it in our sensory
panel and I smelt it I was going to R do
sensory and just knew on the spot like
this was not a real gorilla glue Gorilla
Glue does not smell tropical and this
isn't just was kind of sucked for the
study because we're hoping to have a
nice control but it's also a positive as
well right this is a good use case that
can show how you can use the chemistry
of cannabis to start
um authenticating our certain strains
the ones that we say they are right
industry is well known to have renames
people borrowing genetics from one
another things can be Lost in
Translation over the years but the
chemistry doesn't change if the strain
is cier is what it is and this shows
very heavily so this Gorilla Glue is not
a gorilla glue it's very much a Tangi
type because glue would not have
these and here are the these are some of
the SES we identified in like I said
some of the zidle strains these are a
new class of flavor compounds in
cannabis they have Aromas arranged from
fruity banana pear green apple the very
top note heavy some of these don't exist
in other fruits some do um these are
also not commercially available so we
had to go in the lab and synthetically
create purify and isolate all these and
then put these through our sensory panel
um to see what do they smell like right
because I can't just go buy this online
and bring it in and taste it so we can
only smell it what is their aromatic
contributions and this is really what
helps different andate Zid differently
from other exotic
cultivars it's also important to note
that this is not present at all in ogs
and other mildly Exotics and not these
really intensely sweet fruity ones it's
just not
there I want to see is like just Aroma
percent and some of these specific um
major class of compounds do they dictate
Aroma quality so we know they don't push
the the exotic notes of these and we're
not it's not correlated to the
exoticness of cannabis samples but does
it relate to the aromatic quality of the
sensory panel so relating the aromatic
fraction weight and the Exotic score and
you don't see again with these major
tpin again no correlation flavorant you
have this huge correlation monoterpenes
monoterpenoids basically Flatline cesit
turpine catenoids actually
decreases um kind of makes sense CES
turpine sidoides are associated with
older age cannabis typically because
these are some of the things that flash
off the last and they volatize the
slowest rate so there may be some
negative connotation there for some
panelists and now looking to maybe
there's maybe it's just not just monot
maybe there's a specific monot turpine
that does Drive some of these aromatic
exotic Aromas and the perceived exotic
Aromas and so you looked at them all and
really there was none they were all
pretty much flat lines for the most part
um indicating that again while these
major monot Turpin are important in the
context of cannabis they don't
differentiate the Exotic nature of these
various
cultivars so when to look in the bottom
is like well maybe it's related to
flavorant maybe it's related to the
tropical vs in the middle or even the um
heterocycles like indol and Scat on the
bottom right and we noticed is that it
is that's what those heat plots are
showing is that as things be as they get
a higher concentration we start seeing
more of these compounds it does Trend
with these compounds which makes sense
as we were comparing the sensory data to
the GC data we expected these written
this just further confirms that
notion and so with this now we've been
able to expand our understanding is of
the Exotic cannabis Aroma spectrum and
able to start flushing out what is sweet
uh exotic cannabis what are the
compounds responsible as fruity Berry
tropical unique Citrus notes as well as
on the Savory side what's responsible
for those onion garlic chemical notes
and get a broader more in-depth
understanding of why exotic cannabis
smells and tastes the way it
does and so some of the conclusions here
um we notice Turpin minimally if at all
influence the perceived exotic nature of
cannabis the small concentration
compounds your flavorant are really
combining to heavily impact the unique
attributes scat is one one of the major
components with indol impacting that
chem Funk sewer unique node these acious
not not only acious but it gets
perceived as such in these exotic Savory
straints and then the tropical VC's
really impact those unique Tangy Citrus
notes some the future work we're looking
into is looking at PCA and another
statistical classification analyses uh
different formulating algorithms to
accurately predict some of these
aromatic properties can you Rel
these into more digestal metrics for
consumers um obviously you're very
sensitive and understand that this is
very hard chemistry a very complex
compound names it doesn't really mean
much to an end consumer butting you have
three more cap to hex elocate on a
container at a high level means nothing
to them if anything it's probably scary
right but these are meaningful impacts
to chemistry there's probably a way we
can use this in a meaningful way to
educate consumers in maybe various
ranking scores and systems right or
other there's got to be another way to
educate consumers and at least help them
move away from just THC and realize
there is other things that play driving
these experiences that they so much love
and enjoy and then lastly structural
solution of other unknowns there's lots
of other unknowns in these cannabis
cultivars that we have and solved
cannabis produces tons and tons of
compounds we publishing on these as we
find these we understand the unique
chemistry that relates to the aromatic
proper and what these relationships are
but there's still a lot more out there
and just one other thing I would like to
mention on this whole thing is that this
can be often times like perceived as
tpin are Irrelevant in cannabis which is
not true right when this study was
originally published we saw a lot of
Articles out there take this and put in
the context of turpins are irrelevant
they're not irrelevant actually if you
because when we did this and we created
a lot of our different products we
stripped out all the tpin and made
blends with just the flavorants just all
the fruity flavoring the chemot the THS
everything except for the tpin and it
has no semblance of cannabis doesn't
smell terrible but doesn't smell like
cannabis at all because tpin are the
foundational piece to why it smells and
tastes the way it does it helps bridge
and marry everything together it's the
right ratios everything that can give
you that Symphony that is each each
cannabis
Aroma that with that i' like to
acknowledge the team huge thanks to Dr
Ian Oswald heavily LED this study and
found a lot of why these things smell
and taste the way they do with me um
twinkle and Manny Marcos did a lot of
the lab work a lot of the data analysis
with us man he did all the synthesis of
the seu weights um Kevin our CSO for
always helping support and helping drive
this research
forward huge shout out to 710 Labs great
collaborator of ours they provided a lot
of high-end fresh rosin that soon as it
was done that way we could have ideal
samples um something isn't lost on us is
that the fresher the sample the better
the data so you want as fresh as you can
possible cuz then the GC can only detect
so much and then shout out to rest of
the entire abstract team step solve
analytical marks International for all
the help and collaboration over the
years with that I'll take
questions the um shelf life and delicacy
of some of these U things you're finding
um these Esters um I I've noticed from
cultivation you pull down the stuff um
it's great through trim you package it
and you start to lose a lot of these
Esters incredibly quickly have you
looked at at the delicacy of any of
these compounds responsible for some of
these fruity sweet notes so not not
specifically to these sweet notes over
time time um in our first publication we
did look at sulfur compounds and how
they age one how it forms throughout the
growth cycle where it forms during cure
and then how it lasts throughout
packaging we saw with P merap which is
responsible for the gas here that that
really starts peeking around right is
your finishing cure but then a week or a
week week and a half after packaging
depending on your packaging scenario you
can lose 50% of those Aral compounds by
weight so packaging plays a huge role on
why these things are either retained and
delivered to the end consumer or lost
right and so also this is just goes to
highlight how important curing is
storage properly treating the plant
because these are delicate compounds
Esters are more volatile not all of them
but a large portion of them like
ethylate is as volatile or more volatile
than a lot of monot turbines so if a lot
of these monot turbines are being lost
in the first 30 days start with these
fruity EST nodes but you can help
mitigate that by proper proper packaging
scenarios if you're using a like a mild
like think of your classical sandwich
baggies right from the traditional days
Legacy days like it's not helping
protect the material at all it's
probably going to last a couple days
before it's fully dried out and you lose
everything what if you have a really
well built out packaging solution
because you have I mean put a lot of
time an effort in growing and curing
that cannabis if you can get in a nice
packaging so you can help protect it to
that end consumer
hey
TJ um when we talk about um stability
have you looked at the stability of the
various compounds and even worked with
some of the manufacturers to look at the
stability from a flavor perspective and
even a talkx
perspective so like a flavor perspective
it's tough on flour for sure when you
have extracts one of the benefits are
you have an ideal storage one you have
more by weight so you have more that can
be lost before like percentage wise that
can be lost before it has an specific
aromatic noticeable difference to the
end consumer right and it's also in an
ideal Matrix it can be stored in a
fridge or a freezer to help protect
those compounds but have we looked at
the toxicology of say a one rosin or one
flower not really we've looked at
specifically compounds of interest and
what those toxical components may be
because obviously we're using abstracts
as obviously a flavor a tpine flavor
house and a cannabis extraction company
so we care to see one what makes it
smell and taste the way it does but how
do we do this in a safe or more
acceptable meaningful fashion right and
so we're not delivering anything
negative to our customers and then
consumers but as as far as how raws and
ages on a shelf not necessarily at least
not in the context of
this all right if there no other
questions yeah