thank you so much for having me today
I'm going to be talking about Delta 8
some of the earlier talks did talk about
Delta 8 but more from a product
perspective Purity issues quality issues
so today I'm just to talk just about the
actual molecule itself both from a
scientific perspective but also from a
historical perspective
uh here's my disclosure so we've worked
with some companies on the pharmacology
of Delta 8 in the past but really we
have no ownership in any company that
produces or sells Delta a so no real
direct conflict of interest I'm not
trying to promote any particular
cannabinoid
so interest in Delta a or awareness of
Delta 8 is something pretty new amongst
the amongst the the general population
if you look at just internet searches
for Delta 8 as a measure of awareness or
interest well you see that before 2019
really nobody was searching for it
probably nobody or very few people even
knew what it was after around 2020 you
see that interest and searches just kind
of exploded and this this block goes up
to 2021 but I'm sure that has just
continued to go up uh you see this this
plot is by state you see the States
where there's the most interests or
actually those States in which Delta 9
Still Remains illegal at the at the
state level which isn't really
surprising
but the fact that awareness of Delta 8
is fairly new has given some people the
impression that Delta 8 as a molecule is
new
and so I read pretty regularly quotes
like this one so this is a quote from an
article in Forbes that was published
just this year so it says Delta 9 has
been studied extensively for nearly 60
years but a little research is published
on Delta 8. well I don't think this is
true at all in fact research on Delta
Aid is not a new thing that's been going
on as you can see from the title of the
talk for over 80 years at this point so
obviously not quite as much research as
Delta 9 can't compare it to that but but
quite a few studies so we published a
review article on this last year so we
pretty much looked at every single
pharmacology study of Delta eight
there's well over 150 Publications not
getting into the chemistry or anything
but just getting into actual studies of
the pharmacology of Delta 8 over 150
Publications
so I'm going to give you a quick
overview of some of some of the findings
today so first of all what is Delta
eight I think most people in this room
probably know here's Delta 8 structure
compared to Delta 9 and you see overall
they're they're very similar they're
isomers just one slight difference of
the location of this this double bond
so this gives it just a slightly
different three-dimensional shape so
perhaps Delta 8 can fit into the
cannabinoid receptors a little bit
differently perhaps it can fit in a
little bit differently with the enzymes
that metabolize THC
then there's also one additional layer
of complexity so when you take Edibles
or when you take THC orally it's
metabolized fairly fairly heavily before
THC reaches the general circulation and
one of these metabolites is actually
active so this is the 11-hydroxy
metabolite it's formed both for Delta 8
and for Delta 9. so when we consider
what are the differences between these
two molecules we have to consider not
just the differences in in the parrot
molecules but also is there any
difference in in these metabolites of
11-hydroxy Delta 8 compared to
11-hydroxy Delta 9.
so just to give you a historical frame
of reference a pretty famous here in
cannabinoid research was was 1964 where
Delta 9 THC was isolated and its
chemical structure was identified by
Raphael mashulum and Delta 9 was
recognized to be at that point the the
primary active or psychoactive component
in cannabis
but I want to go back even 25 years
earlier than this
oh
so 25 years before the the isolation
identification of Delta 9 was actually
the first synthesis of Delta 8 and
actual testing in animals and in humans
this perhaps isn't quite as well known
but this this gentleman that you see
here his name is Roger Adams he was an
American chemist at the University of
Illinois
and it's it's kind of an interesting
story so in 1939
the US government this this is two years
after the federal government the de
facto made cannabis illegal with the tax
act uh 1937 then in 1939 the US
government had actually asked this
chemist to isolate the intoxicating
compact of cannabis well we know he
wasn't successful in that because we
know that michulum did it 25 years later
so what's one of the reasons that he
wasn't successful well the US government
actually gave him samples of Minnesota
fiber hemp to work with which most
people know has very very little Delta I
THC
so he wasn't successful in actually
identifying this at the time but what
does fiber hemp have a lot more of
cannabidiol or CBD so he actually
published on the isolation of CBD in in
1940 in a partial structural
identification
so what does this have to do with Delta
8 well at this time Roger Adams started
playing around with the molecule making
derivatives of CBD one of the things he
did was he put CBD in an organic solvent
he added a little bit of acid and heated
it that's the reaction that I'm pretty
sure every chemist in this room is
familiar with it's how even today were
were converting CBD into into Delta a so
this reaction was first done over 80
years ago
and so what he discovered at that time
is that if when he did this reaction CBD
was can could be converted to two
different molecules and he was able to
partially identify these molecules and
and realize they were too chemically
distinct molecules that they were he was
able to partially identify the ring
structure and had an idea that these
were tetrahydrocannabinol molecules but
couldn't actually tell exactly what they
were
but he tested them both in animals and
realized that they were both
psychoactive and so he hypothesized that
perhaps one or some combination of both
of these molecules were what was
responsible for the psychoactive effects
of of cannabis
now we know today in retrospect that
these are Delta 8 and Delta 9 THC but at
the time he wasn't quite sure what he
was working with nonetheless he decided
him and his colleagues decided that it
was time to actually test this in humans
so the first clinical testing of Delta 8
was actually done prior to 1942 or it
was published in 1942 and so this was
done at welfare Island Hospital so
welfare island is now known as Roosevelt
Island in New York City at the time it
had a prison and the penitentiary
Hospital on the islands
and so they actually did a clinical
study using volunteer prisoners where
they administered various different
types of cannabinoids one was just a
crude cannabis extract which of course
has Delta 9. he also administered the
CBD Drive Delta eight and then there's
also two other cannabinoids that he
tested as well that I won't get into now
but given this was a study with with 77
subjects even today this is essentially
the largest clinical study that we have
had of of Delta a THC and at the time
they didn't even know what it was
so this was published in in 1942
actually a very interesting article that
basically Roger Adams subsequented to
this study decided that he wanted to do
some additional studies some additional
testing he sent samples of Delta a to
about a dozen different chemistry
colleagues then they wrote letters to
him saying hey I tested it I took it
with dinner this is what I felt and some
of those descriptions are pretty
entertaining so I can definitely provide
the reference for people to to read this
this article this pretty pretty
entertaining
uh but the effects of Delta a that were
actually observed in this study in the
prison were pretty familiar so you saw
elevated pulse rate dry mouth sometimes
anxiety sometimes Euphoria increased
hunger drowsiness laughter and for those
prisoners who had been high before or
used cannabis before they said this
feels a lot like using cannabis
so this was the first indication in
humans back in 1942 that it looks like
Delta 8 is acting an awful lot like
Delta 9 or like cannabis even before
they even knew what Delta 8 actually was
after this it was a pretty slow period
for cannabis research
after 1942 U.S centered World War II the
the research priorities of the US
government just changed Roger Adams
essentially went on to retire from
cannabinoid research he worked on other
things and it was just a slow 25 years
or so for a cannabinoid research until
1964 when michulum identified Delta 9
THC and shortly after the the structure
of Delta a THC was identified and now
they really had the tools to assess
Delta 8 versus delta 9 THC
quantitatively and see is there any
quantitative difference well they
started giving Delta a Delta 9 to to
animals to different species and they
could clearly see well it's overall
doing the same thing qualitatively we we
see the same effects as as cannabis
Delta nine
but when they started looking at
individual species they started to see
some differences so they tested these
are the very early animal studies in the
1960s early 1970s tended to be on
monkeys on dogs on rats and what they
saw was a pretty consistent Trend that
Delta eight was always a little bit
weaker than Delta nine so this is the
first time they had really observed this
so in monkeys you needed about a
four-fold high of a four-fold higher
dose of of intravenous Delta eight to
have an equivalent effect to Delta 9 in
dog and rat assays you needed about a
two-fold higher dose so it was starting
to look like there was a consistent
pattern here
but over time researchers started using
you know monkeys and these dog assays
less and less and started using mice
more
so they developed these uh it's called
tetrad essays it's a set of four assays
they typically do in mice and if these
assays have positive results in all four
that usually indicates it's a
cannabinoid Agonist so when they tested
Delta 8 in these in these tetrat assays
and mice they actually saw something a
little bit different from the other
species they saw that Delta 8 had the
same potency as Delta 9. so that was a
little bit weird they didn't really know
exactly or I imagine they didn't really
know what to make of this at the at the
time
um but keep in mind that at that time uh
they never tested Delta 8 in humans
except for that one very early study
where they didn't really know what they
were testing so they didn't know would
humans look more like mice would Delta 8
be the same the same potency would they
look more like monkeys and have very
different potency at that time they they
just didn't have any data to say
or at least no published data
so they didn't have to wait till too
long in 1973 they actually published
there's two studies published almost
simultaneously one from a group in the
U.S one from a group in Brazil
and between these two different
Publications they actually tested
intravenous dosing oral dosing like
Edibles and and smoked as well
both of these studies compared both
Delta 8 and Delta 9 THC at a range of
Doses and so I just kind of repotted the
data from from all these studies you see
on the y-axis essentially just a scale
of of subjectively How High people felt
or how strong they they felt the effects
were on the x-axis you see different
doses so overall what you see across
these different routes of admission
Administration is very consistently
across all different doses at any one
given dose the effects of Delta 9 are
almost always stronger than Delta a and
while of course we we kind of all know
that's true today at a time in 1973 this
was like totally new data because people
really didn't have didn't really have
any idea at that time
so now they knew it was different they
knew Delta 9 was more potent than T
Delta a THC but otherwise they knew it
was doing about the same thing but how
how could they explain this why is there
this difference
well they didn't really have any ability
to test this because in 1973 they didn't
even know how THC worked there is one
hypothesis that there was a receptor for
THC there was another hypothesis that
there was no receptor that THC molecules
were just kind of perturbing the
neuronal membranes in a very
non-specific manner so they had to wait
another 15 years before they even
identified that the actual mechanism and
the specific receptor for THC to
actually start looking at the mechanisms
of why Delta a and Y Delta 9 are are
different
uh so it was 1988 they first identified
in the red brain the this cannabinoid
CB1 receptor and then shortly thereafter
they closed the receptor meaning they
identified the actual DNA sequence they
could put that DNA sequence into cells
and cause the cells to produce the
receptor in order to to study it better
so now 15 years after the first clinical
data they finally have this ability to
actually see okay at the cannabinoid
receptor what is there is there any
difference at the level of the receptor
of what Delta a is doing and it turns
out that every species has a slightly
different version of the CB1 receptor
the human CB1 receptor isn't equal to
the the mouse CB1 receptor has a
different DNA sequence it functions
slightly differently
so they actually did these Delta 8
versus delta 9 tests in using
cannabinoid receptors from all different
species so for example
Rats first they they did the rat
receptor well as I said earlier in Vivo
and whole rats they saw about a two-fold
potency difference and sure enough
looking in vitro effects of Delta eight
and Delta 9 at the at the rat CB1
receptor it looked like Delta 8 had
about two to three fold less affinity
for the CB1 receptor about a two to
three fold difference in the the potency
and its ability to activate the
receptors so this seemed to make some
sense that this is going to explain this
difference in affinity for the receptor
is going to explain why CB or sorry why
Delta 8 has a different effect in Vivo
and rats well they repeated this in in
mice and remember mice seemed to be a
little bit of an outlier that in Vivo
and mice Delta 8 had about the same
potency as Delta nine I mean on average
there's probably over a dozen different
studies where they tested it in mice and
there's a range of results but on
average it was about the same potency
and so sure enough when they looked in
vitro at the mouse version of the CB1
receptor they saw that Delta 8 had about
the same Affinity the same a potency as
as Delta nine so it seemed like this
difference that the receptor was really
what was driving the difference in whole
animals so that seemed to make sense
but then the next piece of data came out
a little bit I would say unexpected
which was the human version of the
cannabinoid CB1 receptor so we know in
humans everybody has their own idea of
what the difference in potency is but uh
let's say on average give or take about
two folds
And yet when they looked at the human
CB1 receptor they actually saw a
six-fold difference in potency so Delta
eight had six-fold less Affinity than
Delta nine well that's kind of weird
because we don't see a six-fold decrease
in potency in in humans so I think this
is something that's not 100 on not 100
understood exactly why there's this
contradiction between what we see at the
human receptor and what we see in Vivo
You could argue well it's different
experimental conditions because
different Labs have these different uh
conditions in which they run these
assays and perhaps it's just not a very
accurate result but three different
independent Laboratories have published
the the six-fold difference give or take
between Delta a and Delta 9 at the CB1
receptor so there could be some other
mechanism going on here that we just
don't understand yet
so finally to to finish up I want to
talk more globally about potentially
other differences in the effects of
Delta 8 versus delta 9. well one
possibility may be kind of an
uninteresting possibility Delta eight
does the exact same thing as Delta 9
it's just a little bit weaker
it's possible uh clearly there's a lot
of overlap but is it doing the exact
same thing maybe
another more interesting possibility is
that it actually has distinct
pharmacological effects that actually
differentiate it from from Delta 9. so
one example of this that at this point I
would say it's just a hypothesis we
don't know for sure it hasn't been
tested in clinical studies but some
people report that Delta 8 produces less
anxiety than Delta 9 at a dose that
otherwise gives equivalent overall
effects
so that's one possibility and there
could be other differences in subjective
effects or therapeutic effects and we
just don't know yet there's just not
enough research there is currently one
or two ongoing clinical studies which is
good to see but overall we have very
little data to actually see if there is
perhaps a case where Delta 8 could have
a different therapeutic effect than
Delta 9. so hopefully we'll see some
more research
but is this even something that's likely
or is there a mechanism that could
explain why Delta 8 might be different
than Delta nine well I think there is
mechanistically a possibility for this
an example of this this potential
mechanism of how Delta a could be
different is at the CB2 receptor so I
already told you Delta 8 is weaker at
the CB1 receptor than Delta 9 but Delta
8 has the same potency as Delta 9 at the
CB2 receptor
so let's just imagine a hypothetical
scenario this is really just me all
hypothesizing well the CB2 receptor
tends it's it's expressed very heavily
in in immune cells it potentially has an
anti-inflammatory effect a very
different effect from the cv1 receptor
so let's imagine this hypothetical
scenario which is which is just based on
in vitro binding data so on the left
um
you have Delta 9 and according to this
data of this particular publication 18
nanomolars of Delta 9 that concentration
will produce about 50 percent binding of
the CB1 receptor which means out of all
the CB1 receptor half of it is bound to
Delta 9.
well CB2 receptor binding Affinity is
about the same as CB1 for for Delta nine
and so maybe according to this
publication a little bit weaker so where
you have 50 occupancy at Delta one you
have about 30 occupancy it at CB2
well now let's consider the situation of
Delta eight what's one thing we know
people will hydrate the dose to the
effect we they want so if they want to
feel a particular effect of Delta a
they're just going to take a little bit
more of it compared to to Delta 9. so
let's assume the person takes a slightly
higher dose of Delta 8 to compensate for
this slightly weaker effect and and
still they end up with 50 receptor
occupation at the CB1 receptor
well because now they're into a higher
dose range and because the CB2 Affinity
is the same as Delta 9 they would
actually end up with something more like
85 percent occupancy of the CB2 receptor
so if you're kind of lost with what is
all this receptor occupancy data mean
let me just put it in the the more
simple clinical terms at doses which
give equivalent psychoactive effects
Delta 8 could have at least
theoretically a greater
anti-inflammatory effect compared to
Delta 9. this is just kind of my
hypothesis this has not been you know
clinically proven nobody's directly
studied this yet but I just want to
provide this as one a kind of
hypothetical example of how Delta 8 may
have different therapeutic properties
compared to Delta 9. obviously there's
going to be a lot of overlap between the
two but perhaps there's cases where one
could be more appropriate appropriate
for one patient and another more
appropriate for a different patient
so I'll end there thank you for
listening we did publish this paper on
Delta 8 in in British Journal of
pharmacology last year so if you want to
learn more about Delta 8 you can you can
read that it's open access otherwise I'm
happy to take any questions now if
there's time or or later you can always
just send me an email thank you
foreign
thank you I look forward to reviewing
your paper I question any idea of the
differences between Delta 8 and Delta 9
at other clinically relevant targets
like the P powers or the trip channels
they have to the best of my knowledge
and you know this was a year ago we
reviewed the literature pretty
comprehensively so unless it's something
very new they haven't assayed at any
other targets besides cv1 and CB2 got it
thank you
uh okay so I'm getting kicked off stage
so thank you for listening