all right welcome everybody
um
we are gonna shift gears and you know
take it from from the human and go back
to the plant
um and talk about what we've seen what
we're going to work on with with drying
and curing
all right so to give you a little bit of
my background and just an idea of
of where i come from and and where some
of the this research comes from you know
i grew up in south carolina
you know we're able to grow hemp there
but no cannabis
after grad school went to san diego
worked there for about three and a half
years in the medical industry
and then bounced back to my home state
south carolina
where now we grow hemp
large scale production of liners so
clones
lots and lots lots of other plants
we're vertically integrated so we do a
little bit of everything
but you know my passion always goes back
to the research and so i'll talk about
the
research group we've formed
later but you know of course that's
where my passion is and and that's where
this data comes from
all right so
you know drawing and curing what is it
um you know i was asking this question
back in 2016 when i was
in san diego
and you know the i think the answer then
was a lot of i don't know but i think da
da da da and i think that answer mostly
is still i think but dah dah dah
we've got a few answers um
like the last speaker speaker was saying
one good study just makes you have more
questions and more things to figure out
so
this is just um a bite of where
hopefully you know will be a long run uh
lots and lots of answers
okay so
you know if you think about a quality
smokable flower because that's what this
talk is about you know it's not about
extract it's about the flower you know
no matter where it's grown
harvesting and having it do something
else in another situation
but like anything you know it's it's not
just about
um you know the second it goes into the
dry room you know if you want a quality
product it you have to start well from
the get-go you know you need
disease and insect-free plants you need
to harvest delicately because you'll
knock the trichomes off um and then you
go into drying and curing which is all a
part of a path to a high quality product
and so you know why do we care about
this why do we care about you know we
grew a beautiful plant
you know post harvest why does that
matter
well to some extent
um you know this is for preserving a
color if you dry fast or if you dry
improperly you might turn a really nice
green flower to brown
you may handle it roughly and so you're
beating the trichomes off and so again
the flower may turn brown maybe for a
different reason
you're wanting to preserve the smell
terpenes you want to preserve those and
the other secondary metabolites that
lend to that smell
um
talking about smokable flour you know
you want it to be a smooth smoke
this is one key part that we just do not
quite understand you know what is it
that
what is it that's happening when you put
the flower in a bucket that is going to
make it a smooth smoke or not
um we don't know
uh and potency you know potency is not
necessarily affected by as far as
cannabinoids go it's not
affected by the the drying and curing
um
but of course really rough handling you
knock trichomes off
you are you are in fact reducing potency
just because of that mechanical damage
all right so you know i come from the
ornamental industry did a lot of work in
post-harvest of
unrooted cuttings you know shipping them
all over the united states you know and
we we would look at
you know how do you ship them properly
what do you need to take away you know
the the ethylene gas there's gas that
builds up you know if you think about
bananas you know you you take the at the
lean away if you don't want them to
ripen you add ethylene if you want them
to ripen
and so you know how how does that apply
to
buds right because you're not keeping
the plant alive which you're wanting to
do with rooted cuttings or if you think
about cut flowers you're not necessarily
wanting to save the cut flowers to have
roots but you want to prolong them where
they're pretty
and so you know research for these sorts
of things have been happening for a long
long time and so you know we try to
combine the research that's there on
those flowers
and plants and figure out how can we
apply this to cannabis and figure out
what's going on in the drying of curing
so that kind of gives us our paths of
what we need to explore but it's not
exactly the same
and so a couple
a couple words i want you to know and
understand going through this talk
because they're important
all right if we think about
transpiration that's basically just the
plant losing water
um
you know this could be a natural thing
this could be because of
really it's really hot you know it
happens at different speeds but
basically um in short you're thinking of
the water coming through the roots up
the plant which is how a lot of the
nutrients are are translocated up
through the plant um and then out the
top
all right so if you cut the roots off of
a plant if you have a bud
it can still transpire but it's not
going to take up more because it doesn't
have roots
all right and then respiration so
pretty much photosynthesis right the
plant
takes in oxygen
and spits out carbon dioxide
i got that backwards it takes in carbon
dioxide and gives us oxygen
um
but you know what this is is the plant
making use of of those ions and the or
those photons in the sky and and turning
it to sugar so
you know that's important to remember
i'll know some of the new next slides
all right um
so the harvest part's easy um i'd say
it's the least complicated you can
harvest the full plant you can break off
limbs and harvest individual
you can even harvest the buds and dry
them individually you know i think the
biggest takeaway here
is you know be delicate if if you're in
hemp like you see in this picture you're
not delicate you do not care how they
look you're just extracting for for
cannabinoids but if you are going for
smokable flour you know not throwing
them on top of each other um
really removing those trichomes because
that's important i'll show you on a
slide later how important that is
something until recently i didn't
realize how significant
trichome loss is to potency reduction
the other big thing a cultivator would
want to think about and that kind of
matters
is leaf removal so if you have a drying
facility that you know is struggling to
keep up as far as reducing humidity
you know one easy thing you can do is
just remove more of the leaves prior to
putting in it to the dry room so less
less physical material to actually have
to dry out
okay so why do we dry you know of course
number one is this is how we preserve
the plant
this is how
you know think about raisins or coffee
you know all food products uh have to be
um
have to have the water removed in order
for it not to spoil to rot
um you know
back in 2016 when i when i joined the
industry and
and actually today it is a pretty decent
indicator but you know when i would ask
well how do we figure out when dry is
dry you know what is that factor and
they would say well you snap the stem
snap
which you know i thought was outrageous
at the time but now it kind of it it
correlates pretty well to the to the
data we took to back that up so that's
kind of cool to see over time
but the two common methods are
water activity i think it's getting more
and more popular which is what the food
industry uses and then moisture content
and those do correlate pretty pretty
well together
but you know water activity is super
important because it's not just
it's not just the water that's there and
in the cells it's the water that those
microbes could physically grow on so
once you get down to a certain water
activity
you know you may have spores or whatnot
still they're present but they're not
going to continue to grow and
peripherally peripherally
so here's just a quick example you know
like i said other other
food industries make use of this it's
very important it's very well known
where it needs to be for certain things
not to grow
we've got some solid ideas for cannabis
i think
more so on the how it looks
and consumer preference not necessarily
how it correlates with microbial growth
i think that's going to come out where
we have a standard of it has to be at
this point minimum um of course if it's
bone dry we know we're there
but you know
cannabis is different you know it's it's
big and it's got different levels
um it's not just a you know a flat piece
of dried fruit let's say
it's complex
so this is a
a graph i found quite a few years ago
and it this is kind of what really got
my my brain spinning of what's happening
in curing specifically so you know if
you look at the bottom axis you've got
your water activity
and then you have all the other
reactions that are hap that's happening
this is just in plants in general
at these different water activities and
so you know
one being
straight off the plant you know of
course it's wet
it's going to have the capability to
feed those microbes so you have a much
higher chance have the higher water
activities as you go down you have a
better chance of not having continual
growth of microbes but you're still
getting some of this
enzymatic activity that's happening
that
you know we're contributing to this
change this improvement and curing
um
and then of course you have well
it's not always it doesn't always match
what the consumer wants and and what
science wants per se so then you have to
include that all right well is this too
dry for the consumer is this too wet for
the consumer so throwing that into the
the race as well
and then of course once you get to a
certain drying point that enzymatic
activity stops
um so you know this is kind of
the big picture of of what to
investigate how to investigate and and
how it's shaped around
water loss basically
all right so i made this a few years ago
i've learned a lot since then but it's
still
a rough guide right so
step one you harvest your plants and you
want to get out water as quickly as
possible to stop microbial growth and
it's it's a tricky balance because if
you're drying fast
it may be harsher conditions meaning
you're losing your terpenes that you
want to save
but in order to not have a ruined crop
you know very fast getting down to that
water activity where at least botrytis
is not going to grow anymore
holding on to a higher water activity
level for those enzymatic activities to
continue
and then of course drying it low enough
to
to be at the consumer preference so this
is just a rough guide there's still tons
of work to add to this
um
but
this is this is what we're looking at
for for food safety purposes really
and so you know what is drying it's
it's basically the same thing we do for
living plants you know we've got our
humidity that we want to reach we've got
our temperature that we should reach
but
the easier thing to do is to
combine those two things basically and
look at it as as
the vapor pressure deficit so
you know you've got the green you've got
your bud
you think about high humidity well the
plant is going to
lose the terpenes in the water slower
makes sense it's trying to homogenize to
its environment um lower humidity same
thing but then you throw the the
variable of temperature into that
it changes it as well so you know i know
a few large growers actually are
monitoring their dry room by vpd um but
i think it definitely will become more
and more popular over time
um and so just as a you know in case uh
you aren't a cultivator you know the the
norm the what you shoot for is really 60
60 so 60 humidity 60 uh fahrenheit so
pretty cool temperatures
all right and so this is
part from the study we did with the
cannabis research coalition
looking at
well
how how can we
take those two variables as well as
adding time and see how long does it
take to dry at different temperatures
and and relative humidity so we graph
this out you know makes sense
you know very very relevant but this
data in a whole allows us to
shape a shape
a creation of a vpd chart
that
if you're a grower you've probably seen
this for your grow room where there's a
there's an area you want to stay in for
vpd in order for the plant to
lose the moisture or
not to lose moisture i guess we could
put it but it's a little different
because these these don't have roots you
know we're not growing that we're not
putting it in a condition to
continually grow we're putting it in a
condition to dry the way we want it to
okay so obviously you know
you're you're getting into a really long
days of drying because it stayed very
moist in the room
um
too slow high risk of botrytis and then
if you're drying it really fast
obviously negative negative things
happen loss of terpenes
it gets very crumbly lots of reasons why
we need to understand this middle ground
to
end with a nice product
okay and so this is not perfect there's
lots more rips that need to go into
making sure this is perfect but we've
got to start somewhere so this is the
vpd chart looks just like the one that
you would use for a grow room
and so we're understanding you know how
can we really change our humidity or
temperature depending on what our
facility can achieve
to have a certain vpd to lose that
moisture
so you know this is still in the works
but
it's definitely a guide we need as an
industry
okay
i've been i've been working a lot with
terpenes
the last couple of years mainly because
you know i'm in hemp and uh
we play with smokeable flour but
terpenes are also very exciting
and so you know this is a study that you
know i first looked at
and you know of course you think well
you're drying even in a great condition
you're drying and you're going to lose
terpenes you're smelling them they're
leaving
well how much are you actually losing
that
and so in this study you can see the
citation there in this study even at
really good drying conditions you know
the the best a cultivator could provide
you're still losing over half of your
terpenes
it's very significant and so if i'm a
hemp farmer growing for terpenes
this is this is significant you know i
have
three acres of of plants and i want to
extract terpenes well am i going to go
through the steps to dry it lose half of
my terpenes and then extract the
terpenes
maybe you want to extract them fresh
so this got my mind turning
and we did a few experiments to kind of
follow on top of it
all right so this is you know the
thought well
why why even dry
and there's different purposes for this
and i'm sure a lot of you have heard of
you know people are going down the road
of cryo drying and and that sort of
thing um but this is a study that was
done
by lindy who is a gas company
um they they sell nitrogen so they were
very interested in in doing this
i read a red arrow is a marijuana
company in michigan and then
marcus over at cd
cbdvl
we actually work together down in san
diego
but what this study looked at was
with the different ways of drying how
does it change cannabinoids
with different ways of drying how does
it change your terpenes
and so
um
what i just want to make sure that you
you know if you're not a scientist if
there's anomalies
ask more questions if you if you know
the the author so for example if you
look at the total cannabinoids it looks
like okay well
freeze drying you know you're
you're losing a lot
how could that be
well when you dig in a little further
what happened in that situation if you
look at the picture on the bottom left
the uh the freeze dryer was pulling way
too hard and so you know the tube from
the vacuum was just covered in trichomes
there was trichome loss so it's not that
this the freeze drying itself was
was lowering potency it was a it was a
mechanical problem
next we look at total terpenes and so
you know again the one that circled wow
freeze drying is
growing terpenes
but this is in fact not true as well
because the fresh flower in this study
was not supposed to be dried at the
laboratory
and it was
so
you know it lost some terpenes at the
testing facility
so
you know
whereas there's lots of holes as there
is and a lot of research you you take
those holes and you fix it for the next
experiment and then you work off that so
that's what we did
all right so we did
an acres worth
we looked at oven dried flour we looked
at freeze-dried flour we looked at flour
that
was
ran through a liquid nitrogen
conveyor and then freeze-dried which
saves a lot of time because you're
putting in flour this already froze
and then i
i had
fresh flour tested at the testing
facility and i made sure they did not
dry it
which meant i had to do math to account
for
the moisture the dilution that they were
they were showing not perfect
um but we don't have our own testing
facility so this was the best we had
you know again these are this is for
hemp
but i think the the big takeaway that we
saw with cannabinoids is that
you know unless you're being
mechanically abusive to the plants
um
all that different drying methods are
actually doing is
decarboxylating it or not
and so
you know for for him
it's not a big deal either way um for
for marijuana i guess it's situational
but terpenes is where it got really
interesting
so the first
the n2fd that's
nitrogen and then freeze-dried
freeze-dried oven and then baseline
so
theoretically the plant if not
manipulated should have about 2.5
percent terpenes by dry weight so that's
the bottom number there
obviously if you dry it with an oven at
harsh temperatures
you're losing a lot a lot
freeze-dried um it's better but you're
still going to lose something
and then of course if you're instantly
freezing it right out the field and then
freeze-drying it um you know that that
was the least lost terping content
and so that's kind of the high level
look at this experi experiment but it
gets even more interesting when you look
into the individual terpenes
all right
and so this this data just came to us
like last week so
um i haven't ran
statistics thoroughly but i think
the takeaways here
kind of speak for themselves so
if you look you've got you know a
baseline
of each terpene by dry weight which is
in that flower
at the bottom you can see the the red
indicates the loss of terpenes compared
to the baseline
and the green is the gain of terpenes
compared to the baseline
and so you know this you know what we're
looking at here is not just well it was
you know two and five percent
differences these are significant
differences
you know we're looking at
humulene
as it's oven dried it increased by 84
percent
i'm not a chemist
but i
will definitely be running this across
chemists i know and biochemists to to
help understand you like what's
happening here you know
there is
conversions happening
um
but yeah very very very interesting so i
think you know this
you know what the story is here is that
no matter how you're drying it
the terpene profile that the plant has
as a fresh plant
is going to change
so
yeah basically understanding
how you how you want it to smell
based off how you dry
you know you can you can kind of tweak
because you'll end up with something
different with each drying technique
okay so curing
you know this is this is something that
for years i questioned is it
is something actually happening here or
is it just homogenation
well you know
is it removing uh excess water
is it
homogenizing throughout
the the container
um you know what is ethylene doing in
this process
are the plants still alive once they've
got down to this 0.6 water
water activity you know what's happening
with the carbohydrates the ph the
organic acids there's so much to
question and once we understand that
then we can optimize and speed things up
and be efficient
okay so this is the easy one this is a
very easy one so this was the ver the
burp process project
if you look at the bottom axis we have
different types of burp so you know
once
open the bucket for 30 minutes once a
day
no open
you know
an hour for three days etcetera etcetera
but again the the really big takeaway
here is that the bottom portion of the
graph it shows the water activity
at um
at the beginning of curing right so
we've got
pretty big
ranges of samples so if you see the um
oh gosh what's this called the variance
so you know pretty big variance of
samples water activity
but after it stays in the buckets for 14
days you go back you take water activity
measurements again
and at first glance it looks like well
these
these flowers are
gaining moisture
but that's not actually the case what's
happening is you know when you're drying
in an environment the big flowers and
the small flowers everything's drying at
different rates
and it comes from the outside of the bud
first so the insides are all different
depending on bud size structure etc but
when you put them into a chamber where
they all experience the same humidity
they have time to homogenize throughout
the plant
meaning you know the flower
within the bucket should be the al
should have all of the same moisture
content within so it's homogenization
that one's very easy to quantify
but then we get to the chemistry side of
it and
where do you start so we look at plants
that are similar
but nothing is exactly the same as
cannabis
but you again you've got to start
somewhere so we look at the curing of
tobacco
you know
there's lots of ways to cure tobacco but
some of the takeaways here are well yeah
it's done for flavor and smoke ability
but they don't care about terpenes
um
you know it
for for
um for tobacco you know they're they're
using this process of it kind of being
alive getting rid of the chlorophyll uh
being in this zombie state to achieve
the enzymatic processes they're looking
for
but our flowers stay green
so we're
though we may change
chlorophyll and and harshness is it
actually related to chlorophyll content
it's still green
um you know other things that are looked
at within the tobacco industry are you
know starch to sugar conversions
um
degrading uh carotenes
you know leaf maturity you know all
these things have different impact of
what the tobacco industry looks as as a
great product
again there's things we can pull from
here to test but it's not a one for one
so
where do we start
we just want to see what's happening you
know but we can't do experiments until
we have a little idea of what's going on
so
we got
gas
gas sensors co2 o2 and ethylene
and we put them into these sill jars
all right so
obviously you put a fresh bud into a
sill jar
it's going to mold and rot
it's too wet but we wanted to understand
what's happening with ethylene what's
happening with o2 and so remember back
to the definitions
all right we're going to look at the
step by step the yellow line is humidity
so this is a fresh bud it's pretty much
um ethylene
this bud is alive we just picked it
if you're good at rooting you might even
could make this be another plant it's
kind of hard when it's in the flowering
stage like that but in theory it's still
in a live plant
ethylene goes crazy
you know these numbers we're seeing of
ethylene
in this
fresh stage meaning
high ethylene in the the drying room
because it's not dried yet
um ethylene in your grow is super high
and so if if you're in a situation and
you're growing facility where you're not
bringing in fresh air because you're
wanting to ramp up your co2
you know how high are you getting the
ethylene in there
i'm not sure this is something i want to
understand and then is it bad or is it
good that it's in there or do we want to
tweak it right when it's ripening
but takeaway is
in a jar it gets very high in ethylene
the other takeaway here is you know
looking at o2 and co2
this plant is still alive because we see
it breathing
you know we see there is active
co2 there is active o2
being produced
okay and so
this on the other hand is
a graph showing
co2 and oxygen after he hits 0.6 percent
so we've dried it we're at the end of
our dry
is dead
it's not necessarily breathing anymore
but that does not necessarily mean that
there could be other microbes on the
plant
doing certain things which
we've got some research coming out kind
of looking at that of of that
interaction
so respiration is insignificant
so that's looking at co2 and o2 but if
we look at ethylene ethylene is still
being produced
so again
why
not sure
if we manipulate it a certain way will
we get one result versus
the other better or worse we don't know
but at least now we have a target of
what's happening and so from here we can
shape
uh manipulation to see what will make
for a better product
then the question is well what does a
better product mean because then you got
to get people involved to give opinions
that's harder than this
props to the speaker before me
yeah so you know from from these very
upfront quick experiments to lead into
the next ones that will have more
significance you know what we found is
that there's a lot of water there's a
lot of water in the flower you know
almost 80 percent
moist buds have high respiration so in
your dry room where you think
the
it's ambient to maybe outside it's not
there's a lot of respiration going on
there's a lot of ethylene being produced
but once you get it to you know the
water activity where you would want to
put it into the next stage the curing
you know it's not
which was surprising to me i figured
there would still be a lot of gas
exchange happening
you know meaning
we burp we burp and so
you know is burping actually important
and is there a gas
that we're not tracking that is
making this
uh you know the the theory that
curing is making for a better smoke
so as you can see a lot of
yeah it did this but
what's next
um
so you know going back to this there is
there's so much more to investigate
um
it's it's been a lot of fun
but
so the the way our research works is uh
the hip mind which is my company and
clemson university is where i went to
school
um
with my old major professor we've
actually created
a coalition called the cannabis research
coalition
that
looks at that includes the cannabis
industry
um it funds the research and then the
research goes to those members
um you know this is this is
stakeholder focused you know this is not
just research that other researchers
want to read this is research that is
going to tell you all right well
if you give the uh if you give the
plants
two more hours of light per day you're
going to increase your yield by 20
and if you're a multi-million dollar
company that 20
is a big deal
and so
you know we want to provide research
that
yes is is
is science-based as you saw but we want
it to be very applicable immediately to
a grower you know what rooting hormone
to use you know what's what's going to
take you from having 70 percent success
and rooting to ninety percent
um things like that that will strengthen
the industry immediately
um you know
now of course a university is involved
meaning they're going to publish but as
you know not a lot of people are in a
hurry to get publications so it could
take a year or two to get those out
meaning those members do get that very
early perk one-on-one
of what they could potentially do to
to use science to make their grow more
efficient or profitable
and that is it
i don't know if we have any time for
questions
[Applause]
thank you very much for your work i
appreciate it as a registered nurse i i
did presentation on this for the
american cannabis nurses association but
i digress what is your opinion of the
new boveda packets and those humidity
packets that are we find so often in our
thc products in colorado do you find
that that is going to
cause issues long term i just want to
hear what you have to say about that
thank you
yeah
um
i
so i haven't done a lot i can't speak to
the microbial effect of it
um
in theory you know they're they're
there's different choices of humidity
packs you can use so if if you're able
to stay under that you know 0.6 or 0.6
water activity then in theory you
shouldn't be you know introducing water
to in increased microbial growth
you know i have seen
with that said i have seen very dry
crumbly flower you know become a better
state with these
um
we are actually working with boveda
that's where some of the the funding
comes from um
and so you know they're looking to make
themselves better by having you know
very nitty-gritty data
so
yeah yeah i've seen good things and in
theory it should not be have a negative
effect
for health safety i guess i could say
great thank you for your work and a
great presentation um i'm will vasuete
from buyer scientific and we do
measurements of emission rates in the
ambient air and we see significant
emission rates almost an order of
magnitude higher in the drying room than
we do in cultivation and so my question
is have you thought about or have you
done anything about using ambient
measurements not the terpenes in the
plant but in the air to try to optimize
or look at
optimal drying rates and also have your
alternative drying rates done anything
with odor emissions those are the two
questions
oh goodness um
so yes the one of the next steps for
this research
is looking at the headspace in the
curing containers
to see you know because you open a jar
and you smell it you know it's it's
combing out it's volatilizing and so
understanding you know what are we
losing through this this process as far
as individual terpenes and what is being
left in the flower and and what makes
that difference and and how can it be
manipulated
what was your other
odor
so you know to be honest
in him nobody cares about odor um and
everywhere i've worked uh as far as
marijuana goes that's that's not been a
a requirement
so i've i've not had to go down that
road of figuring out how to stop it
i guess i'm i'm just trying to figure
out how to keep it
is the mic one
as far as
terpenes or
we haven't looked at that specifically
but there is a huge difference in drying
you know if you're if you're pulling off
just the stems um
you're you're usually leaving the large
bases behind and so we're definitely
able to dry faster because there's less
physical water to remove
um
anecdotally not set experimentation
we've not seen much difference as far as
cannabinoids or terpenes
so not exactly
great presentation thank you quick
question if you can prevent botrytis in
the drying stage does a longer dry
period lead to a better end product
past like the 15 day point
right i've i've seen people cure for
six months you know and i've seen people
cure for three days
and again
by nose
i've seen the three-day cure smell just
as good as you know months and months of
cure
but that's just aroma
is there is there a longer stage where
some of these conversions could happen
for a maybe a better smoke which then
gets very tough because that's
you know that's that's qualitative of
how it makes you feel
but
at least
on data
i've not seen a big difference between
the two and i think with starting to
understand this more and more we
eventually will be able to say okay well
you're seeing this effect from three
months
but it's because this is happening over
three months but now since we know
what's happening let's do it in three
days and achieve the same end result
so that's that's kind of the goal is to
be able to to understand it fully where
we can guide those things because i mean
people aren't curing for three months
just for fun i mean i'm sure they've
seen differences over time that that are
have that are allowing them to to make
that call
because if you're a if you're a grower
i mean that's a long time to wait for
your money for your crop so
i imagine there's a there's a reason
it's been done
traditionally
thank
[Music]
when we were you
yes there are actually companies that
that make these automated devices um i
think autocures one where basically it's
a container and
you know if humidity gets to a certain
amount or it could be on a time or where
it just it purges
but that's the thing we
i have anecdotally seen
by smell a great difference between
burping and not
but i haven't been able to put a data
point behind that yet to match it
so you know at this point in time i
can't tell you
on from science experience that
that is a something you should do
but as you should do it
but my science can't tell you why
okay thank you
all right thank you um
curing and drying has fueled many
conversations in the cultivation
community and we all have our opinions
and i'm one of those guys that believes
in a long slow cure my flower stays on
the stick for over three months
and one thing that we've noticed
anecdotally among all of us when we
break out our bags and our boxes and we
start sharing with everybody is we've
noticed a difference in plants that are
grown full term and full sun
retain and have a broader profile and
retain that profile for longer than a
flower that's grown indoors from clone
that has a forced photo period and we
call it the nutrient density of the
flower you know taking that into account
or seeing the information with that and
also the curing versus on the stick
versus popping the buds off and curing
it that way we notice on the stick we've
got uh longer retention of a broader
spectrum but this is anecdotal
no i i definitely believe that i
if you were to take the same cultivar
and put one outdoors and one indoors you
know so many differences probably light
levels spectrum of light all of that's
going to affect it i mean even
let's say you're growing under hps
lights and you're very close well that
that radiant heat is going to change the
terpenes that are there because you're
losing a lot more than you might would
under leds and so all of that is
changing you know to the extent where
you you can measure that you know
um so you know i definitely believe that
and you know i would ask you and your
experience because this matters to apply
to the science you know why do you
choose to do it three months
uh i was trained by cultivators who have
been doing it for generations and we
have i have five-year-old flower that i
smoke and it's beautiful wonderful you
open the bucket and it smells amazing
and it did we noticed like the
difference between a triple second a
grand marnier you get that age with a
wine or an alcohol and you find that it
brings out other terpenes and i know
frenchie cannoli did some studies with
his hash where he's noticing new
terpenes being produced like cashew
sheen and so that agent in that
mellowing we find it's a mellower smoke
and it's we consider it a connoisseur
class because we noticed a lot of the
dispensaries specifically here in
southern california they won't buy flour
that's over
six months old and they hate outdoor
flour they want the blingy indoor flash
fresh but we notice if you take a
one-year-old bag of outdoor flower
versus a one-year-old bag of indoor
flower the outdoor still is almost like
the day that you know you were working
with the cure and the indoor doesn't
seem to have the longevity
that's extremely interesting um
again
i can't tell you what or why but
hopefully in a year we'll have some
some good data points but
i mean what i would like to say is
i would love to be able to sample from
you know batches like this and us put
some data points on you know what is
being done
legacy style
um and and and figure that out so now's
the time to do it there's a whole lot of
outdoor flowers sitting unused up north
yeah
wow okay yeah everything he just said
also is uh very much pertinent but i
really appreciate your work so much it's
really helped me over the past couple
years understand post-production so i
follow your research
i guess my question would be around
ethylene blockers and if you have
experimented with ethylene blockers in
post-production yeah absolutely so
that's that's something i just i just
squeezed it in 30 minutes but we did um
so in those still jars we would add one
mcp so inhibits and then we actually
added ethaphon so adding ethylene
and
as far as cannabinoids and terpenes
there was no significant changes which
was extremely surprising
we need to repeat that study
um you know i want to look at it in
something bigger than a jar
you know i think there's some value to
that but
i think in in curing it's not as
important as it might be in drying and
in the grow
you know we're not seeing those changes
in curing but that doesn't mean that
it's not affecting something differently
that we hadn't measured yet so even
though there's no change in terpenes or
or cannabinoids well maybe that extra
ethylene accumulation or release because
we burp
maybe that is contributing to
it for example starts to sugar
conversion
and that's why it's good but if you're
just testing those two simple things
it's going to look like it doesn't
matter
so
that is next step next step is looking
at headspace
it's looking at some of those other
factors so
ph you know that's a really important
one in tobacco
is the ph you know that affects the
smoke
looking at total sugars looking at
nutrient content and pairing that with
with flushing because yes if you flush
it it takes down
it takes down the actual nutrient
content in the plant
but
then what
so
thank you
one more little bit is i really do think
that it's incredibly important because a
lot of people are speaking to how
product has to be so fresh in order for
it to be sold and i do feel like we
don't have science to back that up and
there's a lot of people speaking
publicly that this is a fact and it's
not science so i'd love to see more
around that and thank you for again for
yourself yeah absolutely
all right thanks everyone