I think it is a very important event
here understand is the second second
time this is happening bringing together
all aspects of the field of cannabinoids
and what are the value of having this
field in health related issues so what I
want to do in these minutes I have is
talk to you about how we're approaching
this field and what my connection is
with the cannabinoids and perhaps give
you some feeling for where we are today
and where we are going so I I operate
something called the Center for drug
discovery and the Center for drug
discovery has as its mission to develop
new medications so do we have to have
some tools to be able to develop new
medications and I would say almost all
of our entire effort is based on the
cannabinoid system and to do this you
need a variety of tools that work
together you need to do some
biochemistry you need to do some
chemistry making compounds make a lot of
compounds we clone these receptors that
you have heard or the enzymes we study
their metabolism we do some biophysical
work and some computations and we also
do form ecology so this can be used this
approach and the tools can be used to
develop new medications however they can
also be used to study cannabis because
using the same approaches we can study
the different ingredients of cannabis
find out what each of these ingredients
does which is really the wave of the
future how we're going to find out more
about this it's just THC or is it THC
and CBD and cannot be general and other
things so we have all the tools to to do
that very quickly and you heard about
this is an old history he is starting
from China and then he came here to the
West
and you see way back in England and then
my good friend referred me shulam who
dis discovered and made delta nine
tetrahydrocannabinol 1964 so
subsequently i want to point out an
important ingredient of cannabis and
that is a trichome and you'll hear more
about it here but the trichome is a
little engine here it's a little engine
there we go
and manufactures all these ingredients
you know THC CBD the terpenes you've
heard a lot about the trapeze they're
all made here I'll give you a quick
glimpse of how these are manufactured
and for those who are not really
chemists or chemically oriented excuse
me but just follow how these things mix
together because they all come from the
same ingredients you mix them
differently you get a different array of
things that's why you have cannabis with
different proportions of constituents
etc but the building blocks are all the
same and you can see how these bioactive
molecules can have work in many
different conditions you've heard some
of them from dr. McCollum and then let
me identify the prints of all this
situation Delta nine
tetrahydrocannabinol THC which was the
beginning of the story prior to that we
didn't know very much about what's going
on there but then a team during the late
80s we found out about these cannabinoid
receptors and now then we had some idea
how these things operate in the brain
and in the body itself and of course you
all know what happens if you smoke
cannabis you get an effect in the eye
and the heart all of these details here
dryness of the mouth and of course the
heart beat very quick heart beat and let
me spend just a couple of minutes on how
these ingredients
are manufactured you see they all start
from gimmick acid here mixed again they
need the sunlight coming in here and
this is one of the big building blocks
they cannot be general carboxylic acid
and you see the details here how they
keep building we start from the ad and
they can go all the way to Canobie diode
or they can go to THC carboxylic acid by
the way what you find in the in the
plant as you know is not THC itself but
the THC carboxylic acid and then the
sunlight hits it or some heat or
something it drops out the carboxylic
acid becomes THC or while smoking it now
let me differentiate THC and CBD they're
actually very very similar these
molecules here all you need to do is tie
this oxygen in here it becomes from CBD
becomes THC and some people believe that
some of the CBD you take gets
transformed in the body into CBD in to
THC that's probably true and that's
probably how the reaction however if you
look at them chemically they have a very
big difference one of them is a flat
three cycles here it is tri cyclic and
abhaneri structure the other one this
tri cyclic structure is interrupted
right here and you see how they turn
around each other and they form CBD
because of that difference these
compounds appear to have very different
properties even very different way with
which they interact in the body now
additionally and you may have heard that
so THC has this tail
5 carbons very characteristic it turns
out that the tail is very important
because if you play around with the tail
and we did a lot of playing with these
things make all sorts of things and so
on the tail is very critical you make it
into a seven carbon tail all of a sudden
becomes much more potent however the
plant also has some ingredients that
have only
that have only three carbons in the tail
and they're called Canada Varian this is
gonna be very in dial this is gonna be
very in itself of the carboxylic acid
very much so so the difference is right
here
this has five carbons the THC this is
three carbons is that cannot be very why
is it important it looks like this also
plays some role there's some intriguing
things happening and they've been using
it with combinations we don't know
exactly what it's going to go now the
major metabolic pathway as you see here
oops
you have THC and then it gets
metabolized here that's very important
when you put one oxygen here very
important eleven hydroxy THC but then
when you put one more oxygen it becomes
a carboxylic acid and that is not active
in fact when you do forensic medicine
etc you measure the amount of Delta 9
THC carboxylic acid now you heard that
from dr. McCollum way back from Israel
talking to us here and tell you how we
found out why this THC does its job it's
because it has some targets some
switches and these switches are what
produce the different effects of THC I
like to talk to you about these switches
there are really two receptors we call
them GPCRs or g-protein coupled
receptors and if you look at them
schematically if you look at the year
they have these seven hilly seas then
they have these three loops here three
loops here one tail on the top one tail
at the bottom and it turns out that also
another friend of it was discovered
about three years later and that's a cb2
and
what we know today that there are only
two cannabinoid receptors the cb1 and
cb2 but they do talk to each other very
well they combine to produce effects
they work either synergistically or in
different directions so we have been
very interested in these things and
we've been working with these for a
while we actually make them we clone
them and make things with them and also
you see they're distributed differently
you see here the the cb1 is distributed
in all of these places including liver
very important actually surprise liver
and also the fat cells that's why it C
b1 has a lot of control on the heat
that's produced in the body but also the
fat content of the body the CB tools are
more in places like the spleen and also
in anything that has to do with
inflammation and this is a very complex
picture but you see basically what we
have here you heard about something
called the synapse this is the nerve
this is them and the Tor acceptors are
sitting on the upper part of the synapse
which is called the pre synaptic
Junction here so there are the two
players so if you want to tweak them and
that's what THC does it tweaks both of
them works on both of them a lot of the
ingredients of cannabis tweaks both of
these and then we have these enzymes
there's one that breaks one set of of
these are the cannabinoids the other
breaks the other set so for a chemist
got a lot of different switches can play
with also when we take these cannabis
they affect all of these switches they
affect the production of these so if you
want to really learn about it in some
detail you need to go after all of these
switches to understand how they work and
to make compounds that turn these
switches on and off agonist antagonists
now here is a little thing here your
soul looks here and now here is the
receptor
and we did some work early on to see how
this receptor is turned on you see right
here this molecule here is produced in
the membrane it's right there and guess
what this is an animal you've heard
about it and the way it turns it on see
this tail here
this is helix six its tinkers at tail
and as a result of this the receptor is
turned on acceptor is turned on what
does it mean
means your mouth is right your eyes are
shot it's an agonist now you also know
this this is what we call a phyto
cannabinoid right here THC and from
these guys here which are the
endocannabinoids there are two families
actually there are two of them and an
amide and twerkin and a glycerol and the
other sort of over the princess of the
endogenous area are they the only ones
well let's see so you see these are
actually molecules and they're not very
important you know you'd think for
example this molecule is less potent
than THC but then you can make a
molecule and we have that is a hundred
times more potent very very important so
by tweaking molecules by playing
chemical games you can produce molecules
that can do modulate a lot of the
functions of cannabis itself but also
the endogenous compounds and as a matter
of fact because we're used to saying an
amide into AG the story is longer
there's a whole family of those and they
all get but these sort of made the good
news to AG in and an amide so we decided
to make all of them and also tag them so
as we come to measure the ingredients we
have exactly right we put them in
repository among them etc and you see we
made all this family very useful now you
mentioned about these and the
cannabinoid
they are made up from enzymes inside the
body and these enzymes are all present
in the membrane and they work together
and sure enough at the end of the day
they make what we know which is an an
amide is an an amide right here or two
AG right here and these you can't have
them just floating around forever
they have to be destroyed after they do
their job and there are enzymes here
that do that there's an enzyme that
breaks down all these esters and an
enzyme that breaks down these amides
they called far fatty acid amide
hydrolase they called mono acyl glycerol
lipase and some other enzymes and we
work with all of these actually this a
very intriguing enzyme don't have time
to talk about it today but it does a lot
with inflammation now okay so we we have
now the tools what do we do with the
tools we'll be spending a lot of time
making molecules also studying the
switches what do they look like with a
lot of biophysical work that sort of
thing
why do we do that for two reasons first
we want to understand what cannabis does
how these effects are modulated if you
smoke cannabis but also we want to
discover new molecules that produce good
results for health issues so it's a two
hand operation on one hand we want to
accrue all the benefits that you can get
from cannabis but hand-in-hand with that
we also produce new molecules that make
health related issues and and we use
this model how to make these and we have
actually made quite a few of those just
to give you an example we've made
compounds for appetite am six five four
five neuropathic pain you heard about
that neuroprotection somatic peripheral
pain a very interesting molecule we just
made it now and also you heard that how
these fight addiction so we have now the
tools we have been working a lot of
these made a lot of compounds some of
them you may recognize them under the am
number am 251 and whatever it is my name
McCree honest greek name okay so now how
do we make these we have we need to have
some template and we started doing this
with a nice discovery in which we made
just very recently and what we did is we
took one of these receptors the cb1
receptor and made it into a crystal
first time made very tricky very tricky
business been working a long time with
my colleague ray stevens who also
crystallographer want to show you what
they look like here we go this is a
molecule we made right here am 6 5 3 8
turns out to be a cb-one antagonist we
know exactly now how it fits right here
and that's important to us because we
could use this as a template to come in
and synthesize before we synthesize just
ongoing the lab and just make anything
we need to know what we're gonna make
and how we're going to make it this
gives us a template then and this is the
cb1 cannabinoid receptor structure some
more pictures here
more details right here and then using
this we could use a computer and put
these different molecules in to see how
they fit in that hole there and then we
come to the end of my talk i try to give
you a sense how you could take cannabis
and the new medications that are
synthetic medications good medications
both of them very valid we work on both
sides thank you
you