um thank you very much and I'd also like
to thank the McCrone is for asking me to
participate in this and also for being
very wonderful colleagues and as Brian
said I'm gonna be talking about the role
of cannabidiol and the treatment of
refractory pediatric epilepsy and this
has been a huge focus of our work over
the past three years so it's really an
honor to be able to come and talk with
you about what we've been doing
importantly I have been very involved
with GW Pharma in these clinical trials
in the expanded access program so those
are my disclosures and then I thought
it'd be good to start since this is a
mixed audience first kind of really
describing what epilepsy is first of all
a seizure is a disturbance in the
electrical activity of the brain and
epilepsy is simply defined as two or
more unprovoked seizures occurring
greater than 24 hours apart and epilepsy
is actually a spectrum of disorders
there's many many different types of
seizures there is many many causes of
seizures both in children and adult with
some overlap but some quite distinct and
there's also many epilepsy syndromes as
well as types of epilepsy medically
refractory or intractable seizures are
defined as seizures that are not
controlled by anticonvulsant medications
or are controlled only by medications
that have significant side effects and
it's estimated that one-third of
individuals children and adults who
develop epilepsy will go on to have
intractable or refractory epilepsy
looking down at how what an unmet need
for treatments are in this country the
incidence of epilepsy in United States
per year is estimated 150,000 new cases
and the prevalence of epilepsy in the
United States is about 2.2 million
people the prevalence of epilepsy
worldwide is greater than 65 million
people and the estimate of prevalence of
refractory epilepsy in the United States
is about seven hundred and thirty
thousand people worldwide it's 20 1.7
million people I'm so quite a
significant healthcare issue currently
in 2017 we do have options for children
and adults when they develop refractory
epilepsy in fact medications we've had
17 new medications become available over
the past 20 years there's also an
important rule for dietary therapy which
can be very effective in
epilepsy as well as our nerve
stimulators both the vagus nerve
stimulator and the responsive
neurostimulator and there's also a role
for epilepsy surgery I've been in spite
of these treatments particularly the 17
new medications the incidence of
refractory epilepsy has really not
changed over time which demonstrates
that there continues to be really a
significant unmet need for effective
safe and tolerated therapies so then
kind of making a case for cannabidiol
first of all I say most of this audience
knows but the medical community is kind
of naive and ignorant of as this is not
really a new idea and so we've had some
discussion today I'm also going to just
briefly review through history some of
the references to the treatment of
epilepsy I then we'll look briefly at
the mechanisms of action today make
sense as a possible treatment for
epilepsy look at the preclinical studies
that have been done in the animal models
of epilepsy and then turn to what is the
clinical data and then what do we still
need to know so as this audience knows
cannabis has actually been used as a
medical treatment for thousands of years
the first reference in the use of
epilepsy was in Texan 2200 BCE from
Sumeria and then from the Middle East a
kind of also descriptions in the 1100
and 1400 seee about using cannabis
specifically in the treatment of
seizures more recent history in 1842
O'Shaughnessy reported that cannabis
reduced infantile convulsions then
suggesting also that could be effective
treatment in infants with seizures as
well as others as well as hydrophobia
lockjaw and rheumatism and in 1856
McQueen's reported the successful use of
a tincture of cannabis indica in for
children with epilepsy including a
seven-week female in 1881 William
gaolers who is a very very famous child
neurologist and every neurologist knows
his name reported that cannabis had been
recommended for epilepsy by Russell
Reynolds in 1861 as sometimes though not
very frequently useful small value is an
adjunct to the bromide but is sometimes
of considerable service given separately
and Gower's actually administered
cannabis in many cases with the effect
of delaying the Paris's
and mitigating the severity in some
individuals and actually in the 1800s
and early 1900s I think that cannabis
was used very frequently and widely in
the United States and elsewhere in the
treatment of epilepsy and then as we all
know in 1851 actually the u.s.
dispensary can assist convent cannabis
compounds were suggested for neuralgia
depression hemorrhage pain relief muscle
spasms convulsive disorders and other
ailments and then 1860 the Ohio Medical
Society Committee on cannabis indica
said that efficacy was claimed for
infantile convulsions epilepsy and many
other disorders so again a mounting
evidence over time including 1800s that
this could be a very effective treatment
for epilepsy very important then because
at that time there were only really only
one medication available in the
treatment of epilepsy and then as we all
know and I was actually sad to learn
that it was my blue state of
Massachusetts in 1911 that became the
first state to outlaw cannabis and thus
ending the prohibition of alcohol and
the other states quickly followed with
the marijuana prohibition laws and then
as we all know in 1970 the u.s.
Controlled Substances Act pact a pest
Act passed classifying marijuana as a
drug with no accepted medical use and I
think as we've discussed today as all of
us are aware then not only not put kind
of incredible limitations on this
clinical use but also of research into
the possible benefits of the compounds
in the cannabis plant in 1996 California
became the first state to legalize
medical marijuana and by 2015 medical
marijuana was legalized in 23 states
again regulated at the state level by
the DEA and CBD specifically was made
legal and in additional 16 states and I
think that this has been a fabulous and
incredible movement to watch because I
think a lot of this was really driven by
the patient community that really wanted
access to this treatment not only for
their children with epilepsy but for
other disorders and I think as we're all
aware over the past several years
there's been increasing anecdotal
reports about the efficacy of medical
marijuana especially the CBD enriched
formations in the treatment of pediatric
epilepsy and this has been
I think every child neurologist and most
neurologists in this country have not
seen a patient with epilepsy in the past
three or four years without the patient
or their parents asking for access to
this as a treatment for their seizure
disorder so Catherine Jacobs and Brenda
Porter I kind of did a Facebook survey
and solicited data I'm on Facebook serve
150 families whose children had been
using chemical Abaddonn rich cannabis to
treat their drug resistant seizures they
had a low response rate of only 12 point
7 and the patients or the kids included
Dravet Syndrome kids do syndrome which
is a myoclonic a static epilepsy another
very highly refractory epilepsy one with
Lennox Gaston which we'll be hearing
about later by dr. divinsky one with
idiopathic epilepsy and this population
that responded the survey had been on an
average of 12 prior anticonvulsant
medications overall 84% noted a seizure
decreased frequency and the CBD
including two that had experienced a
complete remission so that's a low
number but remember these children had
been on a prior above no mean of 12
medications so really highly medically
refractory and then cannabidiol was
associated with adverse events and
drowsiness was fairly common as was
fatigue and also was noticed some
positive benefits better mood increased
alertness and improved sleep a similar
study was done by the folks at UCLA and
they also did an online survey of
parents of children with epilepsy who
had also use CBD products they received
117 responses the mean latency from the
onset of epilepsy to the use of CBD was
5 years and I'm kind of these kids also
were refractory having been on a mean of
eight prior medications and their
population included 53 kids with
infantile spasms which is also
considered a catastrophic or malignant
form of epilepsy or Lennox Gaston
syndrome and similar to the other survey
85 reported reduction is seizure
frequency including 14 who became
seizure free and again many reported
improved sleep alertness and mood both
of these studies did remark that there
were limitations they were subject to
participation bias the people who
responded to the survey it's unknown
formulations of cannabidiol products
these kids were receiving and there was
also no control group I mean at that
time
there was a lot of pressure and I you
know this is really a concern to us as
John said earlier as being child
neurologist of wanting to do right by
our patients and making sure what
they're taking is safe well tolerated as
well as efficacious and kind of as okay
and then kind of looking then it doesn't
work via the end the cannabinoid
receptors as we've talked about you all
know better than I do
cannabis is the only plant species that
contains cannabinoids and we've already
discussed the cannabinoid receptor
family but this has had me interested
for many years and could this be a
potential treatment for epilepsy since
these plants contain chemicals as we've
discussed that our brains have receptors
for and we've already discussed the end
of cannabinoids but kind of could they
be playing a role somehow in epilepsy
and there is some evidence
lower levels of Anantha might have been
found in the CSF of patients with newly
diagnosed temporal lobe epilepsy in
tissue resected during epilepsy surgery
was found to have lower levels of the
cb1 receptor mrna and also reduced
expression of the amazon responsible for
the synthesis of 2ag but as we've
discussed cannabidiol does not appear to
exert its main neuronal effects through
the activation of cb1 receptors and in
fact it may function as indirect
antagonists at high levels so of course
there is a lot of interest and I know
many people in the room work on this but
what could be the possible mechanisms
then of cannabidiol in the treatment of
seizures and it has been shown that it
decreases presynaptic release of
glutamate glutamate being the main
excitatory amino acid in the brain and
it's been shown to do this by binding to
the members of the trip family of cat
ion channels it's also been shown to
activate serotonin receptors inhibit
adenosine reuptake both of which we
think are somehow involved in epilepsy
it's also thought that it could have
anti-inflammatory properties
antioxidant properties and there's some
interests that it could modulate the
mTOR pathway which we know as a pathway
involved in a disorder called tuberous
sclerosis complex where 85% of those
individuals have epilepsy often
refractory and it may also be involved
in other forms of epilepsy so what of
the animal models shown us CBD has
actually been shown to be effective in
several acute seizure models any drug
undergoing development for seizures I'm
is used in several different animal
models of induce seizures including the
PTZ model mes pilocarpine induced
temporal lobe seizures as well as
penicillin induced partial seizures so
it was effective in all of those models
there's less convincing data in chronic
seizure models but that is very similar
to Leavitt racetam or keppra which over
the past 15 years has become one of our
most widely used and effective
anticonvulsant medications it's also
been shown that CBD increases the after
discharge threshold and reduces the
after discharge amplitude duration and
propagation in electrically kindled
limbic seizures and rats I'm so pretty
good preclinical evidence through the
animal models that this could be
effective for epilepsy so several years
ago now we became involved with GW
Pharmaceuticals they were - they have a
product licensed in over 30 countries in
developed in the United States called
sativex which is 50 percent THC 50
percent CBD I'm used for ms best hissing
also pain and they were doing
preclinical studies looking at Kevin
cannabidiol and would be it would it be
effective in the treatment of epilepsy
their product up at dialects is a 99%
pure oil based cannabidiol extract of
constant composition and it's in a
hundred milligram per mil sesame oil
based solution so with with GW Pharma
initial activities was the expanded
access program and about almost four
years ago now five academic centers got
together with GW to discuss could we try
and see if this would be safe and
effective as well as tolerated on a
patient population we all approached the
D
FDA and the DEA and each site was given
permission to put 25 children on a
podiatrist reitman t' and we actually
had to send biographies of each child to
the FDA describing the child their
epilepsy what it was due to how many
medications has been on how many
medications they were on how many
seizures they had a day many of these
kids had had epilepsy surgery many of
these kids were on dietary therapy many
of these kids had devices but all of
these children continued to have pretty
significant frequent seizure activity so
there are five initial sites and several
were added afterwards the MGH ended up
enrolling 57 i'm total patients in the
expanded access program the initial 25
started the medication in April of 2014
so we have many children who have now
been on this as a treatment for their
epilepsy for three years then as dr.
divinsky will talk about in the next
talk GW then went on to sponsor trials
in Dravet Syndrome and the results from
the first RCT has been have been
released and dr. divinsky will review
those two trials and Lennox guess
Syndrome both of which had been complete
and the data has been released and then
also they are now enrolling in a trial
in the treatment of refractory epilepsy
and tuber sclerosis complex others also
planned trials and infantile spasms so
I'm gonna do the rest that time is just
discuss what we've seen from the
expanded access program and this is the
first data cut right now in 2017 there
are over a thousand children on up a
dialects through the expanded access
program and also some of the state
programs that GW has been working with
when we looked at this data there were
214 kids ages 1 to 30 years who had been
on greater than 12 weeks of CBD
between January of 2014 and 2015 the
purpose of this again it was an open and
open label expanded access compassionate
use program but we really wanted to
determine the safety tolerability as
well as the efficacy of CBD in treating
our patients we ran it like a trial even
though it was not so 12 weeks safety
tolerability data was available on 162
kids at this data
and efficacy data on 137 and this data
was collected from the eleven eleven of
the sites involved in the expanded
access program again it was
compassionate use open label this was
not a controlled trial all of these
patients had significantly medically
refractory epilepsy and we did kind of
come up with the shared trial design so
we'd be able to pool the data to look at
the experience and the bigger population
rather than each of our individual
twenty-five so the kids were started on
2.5 to five milligrams per kilogram per
day of the CBD increasing weekly
initially to a goal dose of 25
milligrams per kilogram per day if
children were tolerating that and
continued to have a seizures the FDA and
the DEA then gave us permission at some
sites to further titrate up to 50
milligrams per kilogram per day similar
to a clinical trial we did do a
four-week baseline to kind of get a
sense of the seizure frequency at
baseline before starting this and the
kids had to have a minimum of four
seizures during that time and then
during that during the trial period all
medications diet and vns were stable for
them at the prior to enrollment and were
continued kind of at stable doses
throughout the 12 weeks and parents
maintained daily detailed seizure
diaries who would be able to really
follow the data
the age range the mean was 10.5 years
with a range of 0.9 to 26.2 years the
sex was about equal between boys and
girls the background Aedes was an
average of three with a range of a 0 to
7 and the seizure frequency monthly
these kids were having a lot of seizures
the median was sixty point five seizures
per month
with a range of nineteen point six to
151 what we looked at safety and
tolerability was there at were adverse
events in about seventy eight percent of
the patients somnolence and about 25
percent which we now appreciate is
largely do a drug drug interaction with
those children on Club ISM there is a
decreased appetite and some diarrhea
which actually many of these parents
thought was a positive side effects
because a lot of these kids with highly
refractory epilepsy and significant
neurologic issues often have very
chronic constipation so they viewed this
as a positive in many cases
fatigue and then convulsions and again
convulsions this was a population of
kids with highly refractory active
seizure so it's just probably typically
their normal fluctuation of seizure
activity serious adverse events includes
status is the most common again
reflecting the epilepsy condition of
this population diary and weight loss
however only five withdrew from
treatment due to an adverse event and
what we saw for efficacy we were very
encouraged by 36.5 median reduction of
motor seizures over the 12-week period
somewhat higher and those children had
dravet syndrome and five patients became
seizure free of all motor seizures and
again that's five but these are some of
my most highly refractory epilepsy
patients so the fact that any of them
became seizure free I really thought was
fairly miraculous 54 or 39 percent had a
greater than 50% or were considered
responders greater than 50% reduction in
motor seizures again some children doing
extremely well and 32 of the patients
had atonic seizures and that's when the
children fall very suddenly to the
ground so those seizures carry with them
the risk of significant injury and those
are the kids usually see wearing the
helmets
I mean impressively 56 percent of those
with atonic seizures had a greater than
50% reduction and 16% became seizure
free and this is a graph from the paper
and what you see here the x-axis is
actually looking at each individual
patient and as you can see down here
there were some children who did not
seem to benefit from the CBD treatment
in fact some had an increased seizure
frequency but as you can see here many
of the children had a significant
increase with a decrease of up to 100%
this is in the last four weeks in the
study treatment and then these five
children were seizure free throughout
the entire time so again we were very
enthusiastic about this this was
criticized since this was open label no
placebo there was a great concern that
due to the excitement and hype about the
possible role of CBD in treating
epilepsy that there would be a
significant placebo response but as
you'll see when dr. divinsky presents
the data from the randomized controlled
trials it was very similar actually with
the efficacy so kind of what do we need
to know all efficacy
until recently has been anecdotal or
open labels so there clearly has been a
need for these randomized controlled
trials then also it's important for us
to educate our families and our medical
colleagues that CBD is not medical
marijuana it is purified CBD that we've
been using so I think we have a lot to
learn about the various medical
marijuana preparations both worth regard
to efficacy safety and tolerability in
the treatment of epilepsy and then kind
of what we have learned a CBD may be
effective and well-tolerated epilepsy
treatment some or many and GW
Pharmaceuticals as we've discussed has
the CBD purified from cannabis and has
these ongoing trials and then there's a
company called as an herb afar Masuda
coals that has a transdermal CBD that
they're planning to trial in refractory
epilepsy fragile X and osteoarthritis
and then I think the remain big question
is what about other forms of medical
marijuana kind of I'd really like to
thank this has been a huge amount of
effort for us over the past three years
we have about eighty kids either in the
expanded access program in these trials
and so I'd really like to thank what I
used to call our CBD team now I think of
as more of a village and several oh
these people are here and then just in
an extra twenty seconds I will tell my
anecdotal story one of the kids who
entered our first 25 was a little girl
with myoclonic a static epilepsy she had
daily seizures ever since developing up
lefse she'd be on every medication we
had that could treat her seizures shed
the vagus nerve stimulator she was on
dietary therapy when she started CBD
she'd just gotten a $14,000 seizure dog
and the parents tracked her progress in
the trial by pictures of the dog my
favorite if I go dog laying on his back
asleep with a sign behind it 256 days
unemployed this this is when the dolor
girl was seizure free for one year the
dog is now retired on the beach and this
little girl has now been seizure free
since starting CBD she's been able to
taper off most of her medications she
said such dramatic improvements not only
a seizure control but her overall being
that we're talking about college for her
and three years ago that would not have
been a conversation we could have had so
thank you very much
you