I would like to start by expressing my
appreciation for you Stacy for asking
extraordinarily relevant questions
getting answers driving this field
forward thank you you are doing great
work maybe one more as well as my
appreciation for all of you here to
learn and I'm sure take this message and
spread it and and to can med for
organizing this and having me back today
so my name is Dustin Sulak I'm an
osteopathic general practitioner I've
been practicing cannabis medicine in
Maine for the last ten years and it's
been an incredible gift to myself and my
patients so oh we've got the slides up
here but I don't see them down here
maybe we'll just dig right in so today
I'm talking about cannabis and its role
in integrative medicine health promotion
and disease prevention and so to begin
with well here's an overview integrative
medicine principles we'll just go
through as a roadmap and I think
probably a lot of you aren't aware of
these principles which are a great
solution to some of the biggest
challenges we have in healthcare today
and it demonstrate a really nice example
of how cannabis
is not just helping patients but also
helping change medicine we'll also touch
on psychoactive adverse effects and
psychoactive benefits natural acidic
cannabinoids their bioavailability
dosing and if we have time a bit of
their utility and how to use cannabis to
prevent disease so I want to start off
with a little attention to a very big
problem that we have here in this
country
we are doing a terrible job taking care
of people our health care system per
capita spent 10,000 we spent 10 over
$10,000 per person per year on health
care that's almost 18 percent of our
gross domestic product totaling three
point three trillion dollars spent in
this country on health care but despite
spending more on health care than any
other country we fail miserably we rank
less
or near last on dimensions of healthy
lives access to health care F efficiency
and health care equity actually in in
2013 the Institute of Medicine reported
that we have worse health and premature
death rates than any other country at
every age group and every income level
we are clearly spending a lot of money
and doing something wrong so what's the
solution to this problem well they're
actually outlet let me start here what
are the contributing factors
there's many but I believe that one is
this over-reliance on monomolecular
therapies we know that we are complex
systems with multiple redundant pathways
and multiple nodes for each disease
states and the idea of using a single
molecule to influence that system in a
direction towards health it works
sometimes but it doesn't work a lot of
the times and we really overuse that we
tend to manage chronic disease instead
of prevent it that's a mistake
we and and I just hope the whole
healthcare infrastructure and the
economics of healthcare really promote a
benefit to the system when people are
sick and their diseases manage not when
it's cured or prevented so the
incentives are all backwards
and there's many other contributing
factors so there is a solution and as
you'll see many times in this
presentation I give a nod to one of my
beloved mentors and friends Andrew Weil
who has I just respect him so deeply for
profoundly changing the direction and
trajectory of medicine because I believe
what he said 20 years ago at some point
integrative medicine will simply be
called good medicine I think we're
starting to see that become true so
there are eight principles that have
been identified by a consortium of
integrative medicine establishments and
I'm gonna walk through them the first is
a partnership between patient and
practitioner in the healing process and
partnership this is something that's
kind of new to medicine it used to be
this kind of top-down I'm the doctor I'm
going to tell you what to do that does
not work with medical cannabis why
because there's so many different form
Stacy pointed out so many different
types of cannabis delivery methods
individual responses the need for dose
titration to find someone's optimal dose
an optimal regimen there's a lot of
back-and-forth between patient and
practitioner it's a real partnership in
the healing process this is essential in
getting great results with medical
cannabis patients become empowered to
feel like they have the reins on their
own health and they can make decisions
that it improves their self-care because
now they're there making those decisions
that are administering the cannabis to
themselves they're taking notes and at
least in my practice and building self
awareness which leads to self-efficacy a
can-do attitude of feeling like they can
get better and they can participate in
their healing and then there's the
therapeutic horticulture which is an
incredible aspect of cannabis that's
often not mentioned but when a patient
can take a seed or a cutting and put it
in their backyard and watch the plant
grow and celebrate its growth and look
at the beauty of this plant and then
harvest it and produce a medicine in
their home
that's cost-effective that they can use
for the whole year and take care of
themselves that is incredible that is
empowerment that's a solution thank you
and for everyone in here that's involved
in the cannabis industry if you have any
influence in politics and lobbying
please there's many states right now
where it's still not legal for patients
to grow and produce their own medicine
whether it helps or hurts your bottom
line as a community we all have to
promote that availability this is thank
you this this is a picture from my
backyard the second principle is the
appropriate use of conventional and
alternative methods to facilitate the
body's innate healing response this is
something that medicine often overlooks
we're focused on the disease not on the
health the founder of Osteopathy said
anyone can find that disease the job of
the physician is to find the health in
the patient so if we're talking about
innate healing response the question is
will
can we do to support that innate healing
response and what can we do to remove
obstructions from that innate healing
response and he won't have an idea of a
system that might be a good target for
doing just that
right the endocannabinoid system
involved in every disease and every
symptom known to man widely distributed
throughout our body as you can see here
cb1 and cb2 receptors addressing the
endocannabinoid system to help treat
disease and promote health via enhancing
our innate healing response makes
perfect sense and we've got a great tool
to be able to target this system it's in
our backyards if it's if that's possible
and it's and it's available more and
more now we don't necessarily need fancy
pharmaceutical drugs to target the
system even though there's a place for
them the third the third principle is
the consideration of all factors that
influence health wellness and disease
including mind spirit and community in
addition to body I want to focus on mind
spirit and community so the psychoactive
adverse effects versus benefits what are
the adverse effects impaired memory
confusion anxiety paranoia dis
coordination dizziness being tired these
are things I see is side effects in my
practice typically related to excessive
doses of THC and also related to factors
in set and settings so what is someone's
internal mindset what are they expecting
out of cannabis and what are their goals
and intentions and then what's their
external setting that influences a
person's response to cannabis these are
usually mild and self-limited some
people will complain of residual effects
the following day but what are the
psychoactive benefits of cannabis well
to begin with this euphoria which has
been described as a side effect in many
papers in my opinion this is a gift to
patients that are suffering if we can
help them feel positive mood relaxation
laughter socializing time distortion
which allows them to come into the
present moment and then the
intensification of ordinary experiences
which can be leveraged for a practice of
mindfulness called savoring savoring is
a
recked antidote to anhedonia which is a
major culprit in depression and
especially opioid use disorder when
people are no longer able to experience
pleasure from the natural things in
their life that should give them
pleasure then they go seeking something
that temporarily gives them a stronger
pleasure signal and that's a downward
spiral and so just having to use a drug
or a substance to feel normal
cannabis can absolutely break that cycle
especially THC when used intentionally
to support a process of savoring people
can restore the natural pleasure they
get from these healthy activities in
their lives including eating listening
to music having sex just connecting
taking a walk smelling the flowers now
there's also something I've seen over
and over again in my patients this
unbundling of symptoms and suffering
where they first come in and it's just
this ball of suffering and they they
feel like they need to escape and after
experiencing the psychoactive effects of
THC dominant cannabis or balanced THC
CBD cannabis they're able to tease this
apart and they realize there's this
sensation that's more neutral and in the
past they felt like that sensation was a
really bad thing but now they're not
judging it as much anymore so they're
not suffering as much from it anymore
less anxiety about continuing to have
that sensation that's now more neutral
and then less of the pain behavior
associated with that which impacts their
whole family and their whole community
this unbundling is an essential gift of
cannabis and then this return to
normality for all the cannabis
clinicians and caretakers and dispensary
agents in the room I wonder how many
times you've heard someone say this
plant has given me my life back can I
see a show of hands this is I thought it
was like a planted phrase that patients
were told to tell me because it just
happened so many times again again I've
gotten my life back but this is really
what people say and this was described
in a qualitative study that came out of
Israel and they called it restored self
a return to normality they feel like
they've lost their lives in canvas gives
them
life's back and what's interesting is
people report this even when their
symptoms don't improve their pain their
anxiety all their symptoms could be the
same but they still feel like cannabis
has given them their life back it's
incredible oops that's and went
backwards and then what our patients
reporting increased self-awareness a
sense of connection to God and nature
the universe viewing oneself from a
different vantage point these are all
really profound things that no
pharmaceutical medication will just give
to someone and and it goes on and on
feeling of acceptance of their place in
life and finding creative solutions to
their problems and this mental emotional
and physical capacity to change which is
likely correlated with enhanced
neuroplasticity now people experience
this during the acute effects of THC but
these gifts persist after the THC wears
off they take this with them the next
day in the next week this is a change in
their relationship with themselves and
with the world around them this is
profound hard to get this without the
psychoactive effects of cannabis and
then there's community the cannabis
community which we are all here together
in this cannabis community and I hope
that all of you that are new to the
community continue to have this
experience of wow the cannabis community
is really something special
people care people are altruistic
they're willing to help to lift each
other up there's a lot less greed a lot
less a lot less selfishness and more
more giving and this is the spirit of
cannabis and I hope that any of you have
a chance to experience this and that all
of you can become a part of that and
contribute it because if you let
cannabis in and let it teach you how to
live it teaches this community which is
really essential not just for fixing our
healthcare system but for healing our
world and we're not gonna get into all
the big problems in the world but
communities essentials so principles
number four and five a philosophy that
neither rejects conventional medicine
nor accepts alternative therapies
uncritically and the
cognition the good medicine should be
based in good science being inquiry
driven and be open to new paradigms so
of course we have some pretty good data
nicely summarized by the 2017 National
Academies report and there's conclusive
evidence that cannabis is effective for
chronic pain chemotherapy and induced
nausea and vomiting multiple sclerosis
spasticity at least subjective symptoms
and moderate evidence that cannabis or
cannabinoids associated with
improvements in sleep disturbance this
is great this comes out of big clinical
trials this is a start but this is a
very early start we need a lot more
we need new paradigms of thoughts
including what dr. Gruber has been doing
I think she's you know how I feel about
her work I also want to mention that
this doesn't all have to be limited to
artisanal and herbal cannabis the
concepts that we're learning here in
cannabis medicine using the herb can be
applied to the pharmaceutical industry
to drug research and drug development
and there's a perfect template for that
something called Network pharmacology
which is a new a newish approach to drug
discovery and it involves network
analysis to determine a whole set of
proteins critical in any disease and
then chemical biology to identify
molecules capable of targeting that set
of proteins it's usually a
multifactorial treatment that involves
multiple compounds and multiple targets
this is one example of a Chinese
medicine Qi Shen Yi Qi which treats
heart attack and other heart disease and
you can see here all the different
pathways the different genes that are
targeted and the different molecules
involved this is the type of systems
biology we need to take pharmaceutical
drug development to the next level and
stop looking for a single molecule and
hope that's going to solve all our
problems it hasn't worked and I don't
think it's going to
principle number six is the use of
natural effective and less invasive
interventions whenever possible has
cannabis demonstrated any of this well
to begin with when I was 19 years old I
read through this report from the
Institute of Medicine right after it
came out I was involved in cannabis
activism and I was so happy to get this
quote on my Flyers when I was tabling
except for the harms associated with
smoking the adverse effects of marijuana
use are within the range tolerated for
other medications no fatal overdose no
organ damage no permanent cognitive
deficits and adult heavy users and
actually improve neural cognition in
medical users a very low risk for abuse
especially with medical preparations
this is harm reduction this is less
invasive and less dangerous than
narcotics and opiates exile attacks
antidepressants nonsteroidals and so
forth look at the drugs that people are
using cannabis to substitute this is
much safer for the population a great
example of integrative medicine moving
on to principle number seven use of the
broader concepts of promotion of health
and prevention of illness as well as the
treatment of disease let's talk about
promoting health and preventing illness
and we can look at some of the leading
causes of death and we'll just start
with heart disease since that's high up
there but this conversation around
cannabis applies to cancer accident
strokes and perhaps lower respiratory
disease as well now here's an
interesting study where two micrograms
per kilogram of body weight of THC was
administered by injection to mice two
hours before giving them a heart attack
and this tiny tiny dose of THC which
most of you would expect to do nothing
which I would expect to do nothing ended
up protecting the heart from the heart
attack
improved fractional shortening decrease
the least the release of troponin which
is an enzyme that signal shows us the
heart cells are in trouble decrease the
size of the dead cells in the heart and
decrease the inflammation and
accumulation of neutrophil
to the area two micrograms per kilogram
I can't emphasize enough how tiny of a
dose ed is and this dose has been shown
in two other animal studies to have
effects both on protecting the brain and
protecting liver many of you that know
my work know I'm extraordinarily
interested in the ultra low dosing range
of cannabinoids there's something
special happening there so does this
work out in humans do people walking
around with tiny bits of THC in their
system actually have better outcomes
after a heart attack looks like the
answer is yes based on this
observational data of over a million
people comparing those who self-reported
using cannabis to those who didn't and
you can see that after having a heart
attack those who were cannabis self
reporters were less likely to die they
were less likely to have invasive
interventions like intra-arterial
balloon pump and percutaneous
interventions but they were more likely
to be put on a ventilator likely because
they were cannabis smokers and had some
impairment and their respiratory
function but do we know direction of
causality here no we don't there's an
association between self-reported
cannabis use and doing better after a
heart attack and I think that's a good
lead the preclinical data supports it
now what about preventing the the steps
that lead up to a heart attack right in
my opinion it's not just enough to
protect someone when they have a heart
attack we actually want to prevent that
from happening so we need to look at a
thorough sclerosis atherosclerosis it
turns out that a fairly low dose of THC
in rodents can prevent the development
or at least slowed down the development
of atherosclerosis this is a cb2
dependent process so THC could help with
this beta carry ethylene could help with
this this is an in general and
anti-inflammatory and tissue protective
activity that's happening inside the
blood vessels moving from heart disease
to brain injury some more human
observational data looking at people who
come into the hospital with a traumatic
brain injury and dividing them into
those that have THC in their system and
those that don't and guess what those
without THC eleven and a half percent of
them died those with THC only 2.4
percent died what might be caused
this well we have a little bit of
evidence you heard dr. Michelle M
speaking about it yesterday that the
cannabinoids are neuroprotective agents
and I think that most of us in this room
that really recognize this have kind of
that plan that we've told our
significant others about hey if this
ever happens to me I want you to get
some of these cannabinoids in my system
ASAP because it's likely that they're
protective or we could just keep low
levels in our systems anyways there's
another observational study another
observational study looking at brain
bleeds and again you can see that in the
cannabis negative group only 3 percent
survived or yeah 3 percent had no
symptoms 19 percent in the cannabis
group survived that brain and brain
bleed with no symptoms and you can see
that whole cannabis group on the top is
shifted over to the right there is a
neuro protective effect that is showing
up in human patients what about obesity
and diabetes are these a big deal is
this worth talking about with disease
prevention and and health promotion you
can see what's happening on the map here
look at what's happened to our country
we've become a country of obese and
diabetic individuals there's a big
problem here the medical cost of
diabetes and obesity looking like over
300 billion dollars and that was several
years ago I'm sure it's probably four or
five hundred billion dollars now I want
to help put that into perspective in
2008 the UN estimated the cost for
feeding every hungry person in the world
for eliminating hunger in the world
thirty billion dollars per year and if
we would all get together as a global
community and spend 30 billion dollars a
year for ten years in a row there would
be a sustainable infrastructure to
prevent starvation and hunger ongoing
what are we doing instead we're over
feeding ourselves with a bunch of crap
and then spending hundreds of billions
of dollars on the sequelae there's a
problem there but I also do like to put
that into perspective compared to our
u.s. annual defense budget now what if
our defense strategy was to eliminate
poverty and to eliminate hunger do you
think that would make us safer
I think that might help end war maybe
maybe that's the new mission someday
now cannabis use is associated with
lower incidence of obesity you can see
from two large data sets here also
associated with a lower incidence of
diabetes and then just in the last year
we've had a lot more data come out
showing this is from the Pittsburgh
youth study which followed people over
more than 20 years and found that
greater cannabis use was associated with
improvements in all of these cardio
metabolic risk factors this beats the
pants off of a statin drug we yeah I
mean this this is again no direction of
causality this is an association but the
data comes up again and again maybe it
is just that cannabis users are more
likely to go exercise and be runners and
make healthier choices and maybe it's a
direct physiologic cause or maybe it's
some combination maybe the cannabis is
actually helping people wake up and
realize that they are beautiful and they
are lovable and they're worth taking
care of and it makes sense to make the
right choices to support a healthy and
happy life that's what I'm seeing now is
there a preclinical basis for a causal
effect of cannabis preventing obesity
absolutely you can take mice and give
them an obesogenic diet but when it's
given in the presence of THC they do not
become obese they maintain their normal
weight that's something I think that
maybe we're starting you know this isn't
a cure-all but I think that cannabis is
likely to help most people with their
metabolic function in their metabolic
physiology when I started my practice as
a cannabis clinician I was very scared
that my overweight patients were going
to get more overweight that they get the
munchies and this is one of the major
potential side effects and I have not
seen that in a decade of practice most
people's weight normalized those that
are over weight lose weight those that
are underweight gain weight cannabis is
this great homeostatic regulator and
it's doing that at this level as well so
how to use cannabis for Health Promotion
and disease prevention
well this is a metaphor that I use with
a lot of my patients so I'll walk you
through it
cannabis can be a crutch and
this can be a tonic so when someone
breaks their leg if they want to still
move about they do need to get the
weight off of that fracture because if
they don't it's not going to heal so
they use a crutch for a while they are
now able to walk around and let that leg
heal but if they never stop using the
crutch the leg will not finish its
healing that's because it's the force
vectors going through the bone in the
connective tissue that actually
stimulate those final stages of knitting
together and healing so at some point
they have to put down the crutch and
start bearing weight people have to do
that with cannabis as well our sickest
patients can use cannabis in a way that
helps them manage and helps get through
their life but then as they start to
heal they tend to shift their cannabis
use patterns and need less of it and use
it in different ways and eventually
they're feeling so good it's no longer a
crutch cannabis becomes a tonic so
what's a tonic or an adaptogen a tonic
is a compound or a substance or perhaps
a practice that improves our resilience
to stress we live in an incredibly toxic
environment chemically toxic socially
and psychologically toxic there's so
many challenges to being healthy
nowadays that I think a lot of us
recognize we need to rely on botanical
medicines in order to support our health
and to stay healthy so what does it look
like when cannabis is used as a tonic
well first of all I recommend strongly
using the lowest effective dose because
if you're building tolerance to THC then
you're likely building tolerance to your
endocannabinoids and you're undermining
the efficacy of your primary homeostatic
modulatory system that endocannabinoid
system so don't build tolerance to THC
use the lowest effective dose and many
of you would be surprised how low that
dose can be number one and number two is
use cannabis to promote restorative
sleep this is my primary goal in any of
my patients that aren't sleeping well
THC works so well for sleep use cannabis
to reduce stress use cannabis to enhance
health promoting activities cannabis is
not to be used as a pharmaceutical
medication it can act that way but it's
even more powerful as an adjunct to
other treatments an adjunct to lifestyle
change especially so cannabis with
exercise cannabis with meditation with
the savoring practice I described
earlier incorporate the psychoactive
benefits into your life so for a lot of
my patients that come in and say I don't
want to get high I never want to get
high okay that's fine how are you
sleeping terribly we're gonna start
using a little THC right before bed they
come back three months later they're
sleeping beautifully the next step is
okay once or twice a week when you don't
have much going on in the evening take
that THC dose from bedtime and bump it
up to dinnertime and just let me know
how you feel and they come back oh that
was so wonderful I felt happy I was
relaxed it wasn't like I thought it
would be I thought it was something like
psychedelic hallucinatory thing no it
just felt good I liked it way better
than two glasses of wine that's what
people come back and tell me and then
avoid or limit combustion I think that
avoiding combustion in my mind means
avoiding so-called vape pens or
combustion pens and we don't need to say
any more about that but if you're having
a toke once or twice a day or once or
twice a week I don't think that's really
hurting your lungs very much but the dry
flower the herbal vaporizers are
probably the best way to inhale cannabis
if inhalation is a desired route and
then finally I want to end up with raw
cannabis which I think from an ethno
botanical standpoint and based on my own
experience in myself and in my patients
it's the raw cannabis that is the best
form of cannabis as a tonic if you want
to use cannabis to stay healthy and to
prevent disease check this out so this
these is some this is some of the first
pharmacokinetic data of oral absorption
of THC and CBD a and just nine people
with medication overuse headache and
they took like a type 2 variety of
cannabis had some THC some CBD in it
made into a decoction which is like a
tea except it's covered and simmered for
a bit in water or an oil and you can see
the these are the pharmacokinetic data
showing the bioavailability you might
notice one peak that really stands out
there in orange on the left we have the
decoction and on the right we have the
oil that orange peak is THC
a THCA is being absorbed far more than
THC if you look at this one CBD a look
at the bioavailability of CBD a compared
to CBD this is impressive at the top of
the slide here you can see what the
actual composition of the oil in the
decoction look like but I did the math
for you these are the areas under the
curve so in the decoction THC a was
absorbed 50 times better than THC CBD a
was absorbed five times better than CBD
and the oil THC a was absorbed 32 times
better than THC and in the oil CBD a was
absorbed 11 times better than CBD high
bioavailability so how do we do this how
do we use cannabis to promote health and
prevent disease well these pictures
aren't actually that accurate so stop
taking pictures of them I'm I'm gonna
I'm gonna tell you how to do it you take
a little bud
hopefully it's a type 2 variety that has
some CBD and THC A in it you put it in
your mug and you pour the hot water on
top of it or the hot coffee or whatever
tea however you like your hot beverage
in the morning include a little nugget
in there and then when you're done
drinking it if you willing take that
thing and eat it that's it by little but
I mean something about the size of a pea
you really don't need much it can be
tiny and what my patients tell me is
when they start doing this they don't
notice much until about two weeks and
then there are thright it starts feeling
better the resilience of stress starts
improving this is not as fast acting as
the decarboxylated cannabinoids but
extraordinarily powerful and I encourage
you to try it try incorporating it we
don't need the you know maybe there's a
place for stabilized acidic cannabinoids
but trust me if you've got some of these
buds in your cabinet or in your fridge
you can absolutely take those and start
using them right now without a lot of
without waiting for a pharmaceutical
product it's right there at home the
acidic cannabinoids and then finally I'd
like to end up with principle number
eight training of practitioners to be
models of health and healing committed
to the process of self-exploration and
self-development I hope that as a
cannabis expert of physician and edge
educator and a steward of this plant
that I am walking my talk and living
this principle thank you
[Applause]