hi everybody thank you for everybody
that stay and survive to be here with me
and so if somebody don't know me I'm my
name is the dead Amerian professor in
the Technion which is the Technology
Institute of Israel similar to the MIT
something like that we don't have
literature we have just accurate science
and a few years ago around three years
ago so four years ago I got my own lab
in the Technion doing a cancer biology
but my background I have a master's in
biochemistry PhD in plant molecular
biology and postdoc in cancer biology
when I came back to Israel and I got my
own lab to do cancer biology I look how
to bring plant back to my research
because I thought it will give advantage
and then I started to do cancer biology
but from then my lab spread to do a lot
of cannabis research so today from 45
people in my lab a team 42 is working on
cannabis 3 is not working in canvas
because if somebody asking me if I'm
doing just cannabis I have excuse to say
no so I'm just talking because it's not
moving that's all hey I want two minutes
spare after that it's not working guys
no just a moment oh it's upside down
okay
so I want to speak today a little bit
about the in terrassa fact and what I
think about it people think that we need
all the plant other people's think that
one molecule synthesize can do the same
effect and more accurate and I think
it's somewhere in between and I want to
talk about it and to show one example
from my lab that fit to my philosophy
that 50% is right and 50% is wrong so we
have the enter the endocannabinoid
system in our body that cannabis is
influenced mostly through that system I
won't talk about it too much because I
guess most of the people know but our
body built from cells and the biology
teacher in grade 5 showed the cells like
that but usually it look like that and
cell is the basic unit which call it
life so it's the basic units of all the
live creatures but even though it can be
itself and can be an own entity that the
lives of these are cells that crawling
on the plate and web creatures that are
one cell like yeast or bacteria in our
body cells organizing tissues and they
need to communicate very well so when
I'm moving my hand the cell from my
brain sends signal to selling my my
muscles to contract and they must be
very coordinated with other cells in
order to have this contraction so then
cells in our body need to communicate
between themselves very tightly and very
organized and then doing it by sunny
sending messages to each other so these
are two cells at sending messages so one
cells send message and the other one
need to read it and the way they are
doing it we have messengers and we have
receptors that know how to read it in
the endocannabinoid system the
messengers are the endocannabinoids or
the cannabinoids and the receptors of
the receptors on the end
the cannabinoid system so the
endocannabinoid system usually we
mentioned two receptor cb1 and cb2 and i
saw in the last two days at least five
times this figure and i think except a
except few times people didn't mention
that there are many other receptors so
there is GP r 55 GP r 18 and many
receptors I'm familiar with 32 receptors
of the endocannabinoid system and I'm
familiar with 30 there it's probably 50
also about the endocannabinoid usually
mean we mentioned ananda my day to AG
but there are more than 100
endocannabinoids my lab today have the
ability to analyze more than 120
different endocannabinoid so in the
blood so with a lot of messengers in a
lot of way to read them and this create
a complicated system cannabis affect the
system through the cannabinoids that is
creating so we have in the plant that
this unique plant the ability to create
a structure that is similar to the
structure that our body creating and
binding the same receptors but again in
the cannabis we don't have tea it's in
CBD web at least 10 families of
cannabinoids and altogether I know today
to analyze from the plant 144 different
feet of cannabinoids and these Fito
cannabinoids is actually and we also
have the tippin's I will skip it and we
have a lot of chemo vows in my lab I
have over than 650 different cameras it
each one of them will have different
profile of cannabinoids and this
cannabinoids is binding these
endocannabinoid system and actually
doing a bypass instead of getting very
accurate message to our body doing it
very very accurately when we move near a
barbecue and we smell the barbecue sauce
small molecules from the barbecue
is entering to our nose going to our
olfactory system that signaling to the
neurons to create a specific
endocannabinoid that will bind a
specific receptors that create appetite
but when we smoking cannabis with
floating this with a lot of compounds at
binding different receptors and grating
a complicate reaction so when we are
talking about the in terrassa fact
usually at least what I'm hearing from
people and if you read the papers the
first paper that published by a
professor Ben Shabbat and professor a
famous ulam the idea is that one
compound is not enough to give the
signal to the receptors so one compound
is not strong enough but if they are
coming as a group they can activate the
receptors so this is the entrez effect
the pimalia effect the familia effect so
usually when I'm giving these talks in
Israel said it's like you're going in
the beach and some kind of a guy
starting it coming and pushing you
usually feel unease can do anything but
if he's coming with his familia effect
then you're in a big problem so it's
nice story but it's not working like
that in biology because this is backward
just a moment
okay because in biology usually the lie
again the message should fit to the
receptors we call it a lock and key
principle it doesn't matter if you're
coming with a lot of kids you need one
to fit today to the receptors in order
to open a tune to activate it so it's
not fit to the theory that you need a
lot in order to push it at least usually
this not the way it works so why we have
the enter effect again because we have
many receptors and many signals that
coming together operating many signals
in the in the cells and we're getting a
complicate reaction so
and prove it so this is the so if you
thought that this is complicated this is
the real picture part of that so going
back to my lab when we started to do
cancer research we do few different
types of cannabis and few different
cells cancer cells and we try to see how
its affect the cells we read the papers
by Manuel Guzman and Kristine Sanchez
that's sitting here and so in breast
cancer in glioblastoma that cannabis can
create apoptosis can kill the cells I
must say that this clock is killing me
it's like bombed that going down I don't
care about the organiser no way that I'm
finishing nine minutes so now I was
kidding I was kidding I'm on time guys I
was in our in the army you know time is
time so there isn't penalty not staying
or not paying it standing in time so we
grind the cells in a play so these are
cells very low magnification every dot
there is a cell these are colon cancer
cells and we create an extract that was
a plant biologist I know how to do
ethanol extraction we create an extract
and we put very low amount on these
cells and surprisingly they were all
dead we put extract number two and they
were all dead we put extra number three
and it didn't affect the cells so we saw
a specificity between the types of the
cannabis since affecting this colon
cancer we did that breast cancer was so
very similar phenomena but when we do
did a prostate cancer they extracted
kill the breast cancer and the colon
didn't affect the the prostate cancer
the same thing with extract number two
but extract number three that didn't
kill the colon and didn't kill the
breast kill the prostate cancer when we
use colon cells without cancer mutation
it didn't affect them as it affect these
types of cancer so this is one way to do
it in order to take it to the next step
we said okay we don't know what is
affecting them
we can do it in high-throughput
screening so we can grow the cells in
plate like that but we also can grow
them in play that have many holes and we
can use equipment that can read in
heavy-haul can take images from every
hole so this machine is incubator that
cell can grow live in it but also can
take a lot of images so this is how
we're doing it we can put markers on
that so every time that the cell print
look red it's dying and every time that
is blue Israel alive so you can see that
on top there is a control cell that that
dying cells that are alive and what I
want to show you here is these are
melanoma cells is very similar to what I
showed you before you can see that there
are every color it's a different game of
our different strains of cannabis and
you see that there is bunch of cells
that bunch of extracts that not
affecting the cells bunch of them that
killing 50% a bunch of them are very
effective but when we try to align them
according the T it's in the CBD amount
we saw that there is no correlation
about the amount of the T it's in CBD
and the ability to kill the cells so now
we're doing another trick we're taking
these one-one types of Kim over one
types of strain and we're extracting
just the THC in the CBD and we put
purified it's in CBD from these strains
on the cells and even if we put 20 times
higher it's not affecting the cells so
what I learned from this that it's not
that it CBD alone or it's not them at
all but at least it's not that it's in
the CBD alone so if to complicate that
even if we take the same types of cancer
these are colon cancer and you see on
the upper type of the colon cancer there
are few strains that are very effective
killing that but on the lower one even
have tried 650 different strain none of
them affected and it's the same thing
with prostate cancer so there is even in
the subtypes of the cancer there are
differences
so how can you look on it we said okay
let's look even more narrow let's look
on cells with one types of cancer and
one type of mutation that caused it to
be cancer we call it driving mutation so
I won't go the details because I don't
have time but the idea is blue is
without mutation this become more and
more severe that the yellow it's more
severe so we starting starting to check
and every bulk like that it's a
different strain so you see that this
one didn't affect the cells and these
strains kill the cells in correlation to
the mutation when we find it something
like that we going deeper and deeper and
because I don't have in time I have four
minutes 55 seconds who can't who counts
I will I will skip and I we said we
going and looking deeper and deeper and
we prove ourself that what we see is
right we're doing a rescue we bring back
the protein without the mutation we
check different strains that look very
similar to the strain we suggest this
strain is very specific we're going
forward and forward then we're going to
a mice model and we check in mice model
and we see that this strain is also
decrease the size of the two more it's
very effective when we're doing that now
I'm asking myself do I need the whole
extract or do I need single compound so
my lab have the ability to read all the
compounds in the cannabis it's very
complicated in this train there is
around 100 different compounds
cannabinoid twopence flavonoids so what
we are doing we are running it on
equipment and we are fractionated we
said let's put 25 compounds in the first
tube 25 other compounds the second
you'll be fractionated and we're going
back to the cell oh the demise and we
check it and we see in that case the
just one fraction every color is a
different fraction and the red one is
the whole extract so we saw that we have
a lackey and just one fraction is
working as the whole plant so we
eliminate 75% of the old
compounds and we're going another step
forward said okay fraction two was the
one that walked now is left with twenty
five compound that fraction them now two
five five five and five and we're going
on and on until we find the minimum
compound they doing the maximum effect
this is my slogan to the students I
don't care if it's one seven twenty or
all of them I want to know what is the
minimum compound the doing the maximum
effect
three minutes thank you I don't see it
at all like okay so in that case in that
case we find out that we need three
compounds in order to get the full
effect
just three compounds if you take one of
them out it's not working anymore
but if you have the three of them you
get aligned exactly like the whole
extract so for me this is a proof of
concept of the inter effect it's not one
compound it's not the whole extract it's
few compounds that activating different
pathway that creating this effect one of
these three compound it's even unknown
don't have a name we call it three three
one be you know my chemist analysis are
very creative so one of them is even
unknown it's not a minor it's almost one
percent in this extract but it's unknown
nobody looking on that and if you're
taking out you won't get this effect so
if I'm looking on that even deeper we
saw we know all the password whites
degra dead bees active proteins whites
sending it to the gradation one day
cells dying
and one of the reason is because you get
a flux of calcium in the cell so you see
this is the whole extract we could get
flux of calcium so we checked the
receptors there is seven receptors on
these cells from the endocannabinoid
system we suspect that one of them trpv1
is responsible to these flux so we block
the tear
pv-1 and we block just half of the flux
and again if you look on the cells when
we're blocking this is the whole extract
this is blocking trpv1 we block just
killing part of them one minute so
actually this for me it's like proof of
koskoff concept one compound and we
already know which one is binding trpv1
and starting a flux of calcium the other
one binding different receptors and
altogether you get enough power enough
things that happen in the cells that
killing these cells this is how I see it
operate and this is what my vision to
the next year that we find define which
compound is doing what how the binding
which receptor they're binding and are
we getting this effect so just say thank
you to my okay and this is what I just
said 30 minutes 12 10 so just saying
thank you to this amazing group that
walking with me this is my lab so this
is shirley berman that did all the
cannabis analyzing this is liran boron
dr. Elaine brown they did all the cancer
research
this is dr. Gil Leavitt us they did the
mice work thank you very much