first i want to thank all of you for
being here
i see a lot of people that are a part of
what we call the legacy project in the
room so thanks for supporting your
teammates
um
i'm going to get out my glasses because
i'm going to get nervous
um today we're going to discuss some of
the hurdles the emerald triangle legacy
operators have faced
the vast collections of genetics they
hold
some of the solutions being created to
empower both the operators and the
genetic diversity and how not
integrating the knowledge and the
genetics these legacies
of these legacies impact the future of
medicine and science around cannabis
in 2014 humboldt county claimed over 10
small medical cannabis farmers today we
have less than 1300 cannabis licenses in
humboldt and trinity county
these communities hold over six decades
of experience with breeding cultivation
practices and medicine making around
cannabis and are being shut out of the
new industry
the new industry that was legalized
around the premise that cannabis is a
very diverse medicine
yet as this industry grows and the
legacies get shut out we are losing vast
amounts of important genetics research
and experience that can move us all
forward towards a healthier future
i'd like to introduce to you some of our
legacy project leaders in our panel
today
rob golightly at the end over there is
the co-owner of last coast distribution
and a 25-year medical cannabis farmer
daniel hendricks is the co-owner and ceo
of hendricks farms as well as a native
of humboldt county
jeff hamilton is partner at farella
braun and martell llp
and founder of canopyright and dr dale
hunt is senior attorney of plant and
planet law firm and founder of breeders
best
hi guys
jeff you wanna why don't we just kind of
all say a few things about ourselves and
our experiences and then we'll dive in
to the questions jeff you want to start
sure um
can everyone hear me
uh i'm a partner at foreign martell in
san francisco
i focus on cannabis transactional work
um i've also the founder of a company
called canopyright which is
attempting to build a blockchain-based
botanical registry for cannabis
cultivars um
i sort of
started
i discovered the plant as a teenager
um i was sort of like an
anxious
lonely
strong high strung kid and
you know all of a sudden there was this
miracle that made my life better and
gave me this
opportunity to
find
self-confidence and sort of organize my
life and really think through my
problems and so as a lawyer when i got
the opportunity to start working with
cannabis
clients i just never i never learned
back and so
um
what i'm focusing on right now is really
the issue that we're going to talk about
as a group today
um
i think i will
leave it at that awesome thanks daniela
hello everybody i'm daniel hendricks um
i was
born in my backyard in humboldt county
to two humble undergraduate students and
i feel like symbolically i've always
followed the plant it was 1996 when the
compassionate care act passed i was a
freshman in high school and i knew that
was something that i really wanted to
pursue i saw a change in politics and
the global view of cannabis and i
i hoped i could be part of that so we
founded hendricks farms
it's a nursery that focuses on
preservation and delivery of powerful
and endemic to humboldt county plants
and genetics for both home farmers and
commercial licenses
thanks daniel dale
yeah
my name is dale hunt i am a plant
scientist
did a bachelor's degree in botany
masters in genetics
phd in molecular and cellular biology
and then i went to law school
and i've been a patent attorney for 26
years
apologies to people who've heard this
before
i say it a lot but
it's kind of necessary i guess
as a patent attorney i've always worked
with plant breeders in addition to lots
of other kinds of inventors
and i've helped plant breeders protect
their inventions
all over the world i think something
like 30 countries and we've done
licensed deals in about 20 countries
i've seen firsthand how
companies that have valuable genetics
can scale globally on a really big scale
just by licensing others to grow their
to grow their plants
and
i know that this can be done in the
cannabis industry as world markets open
up
got into cannabis about eight years ago
as in a professional sense and um
uh
have really enjoyed working with plant
breeders one of the
my favorite things about my job is just
getting to know
the the independent
plant breeders that have been doing it
for decades and seeing their passion and
seeing their creative drive
and
the fact that they put
making better plants and better
medicines and helping people way above
even making a living
some of them are doing well and a lot of
them aren't
and as i started visiting breeders on
their farms
it went from being a really interesting
job to being a passion and a cause and
so
i started my company breeders best in
order to help
cannabis breeders that couldn't afford
to patent their own things
if we think that there's something that
really has some potential
then the company will pay for the
patenting
and in exchange receives an exclusive
license
and meanwhile the breeder always owns
the patent
and the license revenues that the
company generates
go back to
go back to the breeder after obviously
it's shared between the breeder and the
company
it is
a lot like a record label where the
breeder is a creative person making
something great
and they get to focus on their creative
work and they don't have to do all of
the other things that that lie between
the creation and the revenues that's the
job of the company
and um
it's a huge honor to have some members
of the breeder's best team here today um
they are uh
every bit as passionate as i am about
the plant and um
about the potential
for that we have to make a difference
so
um i'll stop there
i can go on
hey ron hey how's it going my name is
rob golightly and i'm i'm a lifelong
cannabis activist i started collecting
signatures for proposition 215 in 1993.
um
i've been growing cannabis and selling
it legally in california since
over-the-counter sales started around
2006 i've been aligned with
collectives that were licensed by the
city of los angeles since around the
same time and
have constantly grown
different medical strains out of humble
and breeded
legacy genetics from different elders
that i've been gifted seeds throughout
the years when people pass away and
certain things happen on genetics get
passed around and
i've also been a big nursery person too
before
prop 64 came so i was doing a lot of
clones and humble also and you know
picking
specific varieties that would work for
good for
not just medical reasons but also for
commercial cultivation so that they
could grow large quantities of it at a
time
and we also you know i have a
distribution company legally now and i
also have a legal
ten thousand square foot farm in
honeydew california and that was one of
the first hundred to get licensed in
california
thanks rob great job
so my name is lelania dubois or a lot of
people know me is lele
and i'm a second generation cannabis
cultivator and community developer in
the emerald triangle i'm also the
founder of the humboldt grace legacy
project and cco of canopyright
the humboldt grace legacy project was
formed as a strategy to empower the
decades of knowledge around cannabis in
the emerald triangle
the people who hold this knowledge we
call legacy
our goal was to build a pathway forward
to preserve and validate the genetic
diversity of these communities
reinventing how the market values the
plant and the legacy experience
so today we're going to kind of talk
about what are some of the hurdles that
it that that's going on with the legacy
right now what are some of the solutions
and then why does it matter to people
who are involved in medicine and science
so to start you guys
why don't we talk about what some of the
hurdles we've all seen from our
different perspectives
jeff do you want to start i'm going to
sit down so i don't fall down
um sure i'm happy to start so i my
experience is completely different than
everyone well maybe not dale but
um i think for
for me working with cannabis clients
you always saw
two things on the jar right there's the
brand name and then there's the cultivar
name and it's always pretty clear to me
that the brands got paid that made sense
but
the cultivar what is that did the person
who invented it get paid do we even know
who they are could we find out
and so
um so this is a personal experience um
sort of with me and a particular client
but also several clients all with the
exact same problem well
my i've got all of these these cultivars
they're really like my most valuable
business asset
if i didn't have my my seed library i
wouldn't have gotten all this investment
money i wouldn't be able to build my
facility
so
i'm you know you're sitting there you're
having lunch with these clients and
you're this red light goes off in your
head well do you own your cultivars do
you like
what
can you even own your cultivars and so
i i ended up in this rabbit hole but you
but i guess
when i'm talking about the hurdles
facing the industry right now it's that
it's really hard to document
cultivars in a way that makes sense that
allows for the people that spent decades
developing those cultivars including
sort of the legacy community to get paid
from it it just didn't make sense to me
um and so i guess that's what i would
say is that the hurdle that i've seen
not being valued for their work not
being valued and not not even not being
valued but there not even being a way to
evaluate right right
daniel
anyone yeah there's there's lots of
hurdles
for the legacy
farmer i would say the biggest hurdle
they have is
getting their product to the consumer
there are several supply chain pieces
that
being removed in a remote location
up in the hills
working with environmentally friendly
practices
you have a really long supply chain
visit to get us down to la
so because of that
they're dependent on the distribution
networks to
sell their product to the farmer to the
distribution company that's going to
white label it and create something for
the retail customer
and to simplify their jobs
the distribution companies focus on
singular
metric points they want high thc
they want purple they want certain
specific lead terpenes and so
i see it is really challenging
to
motivate yourself to preserve diversity
in the cannabis gene pool right now
because in order to make a living you're
forced to kind of follow
the pathways that you're given and
not being vertically integrated
puts a lot of humble farmers at a
disadvantage and i feel like it puts the
consumer at a disadvantage specifically
the medical patients and actually
reaching the diversity and the different
effects that they want um so i i do see
that access point being a really big
challenge i would love to see um
e-commerce and direct-to-consumer
opportunities
develop for the
legacy farmers and i
i like i'll just insert the word
heirloom because there's something that
i feel like legacy might not even
communicate what we're doing here which
is
heirloom and
if you guys go to the grocery store
you'll probably see heirloom tomatoes
that cost more and maybe have a better
flavor profile different than your
commercially bought tomatoes and so
we're at the very beginning here in
cannabis where we're trying to hold on
to those heirlooms and we see the
agricultural
tools that are coming in and the mono
cropping that's coming in
is going to create a period where
the consumer isn't going to have access
to these heirlooms unless they go and
value it
and with that big separation in between
the farmers that have preserved these
heirlooms and the consumer that
maybe doesn't know how the different
effects could be curated from these
different profiles there's just a
disconnect there and it would be really
nice to see the farmers and the
consumers interact again
like actually you know sadly before prop
64 when people were kind of able to work
directly with
the grower to get exactly what they want
so
that's one of the hurdles that i see is
just reaching the consumer
well in the science like with dr
sicily's research right everyone someone
mentioned it yesterday
how
the research said that you know cannabis
doesn't really work that well but she
didn't really have access
to high quality medicine right
absolutely in our community she was like
i wish i could study it here yeah yeah
sue sicily she's a great example because
she's so tough um
in her nature and refuses to
follow that path of these kind of
you know not diluted but whatever the
dea has in their library which doesn't
reflect the diversity
that you know people want to interact
with when they want to interact with the
plant so good for her for
sticking to that point and kind of
refusing to
do another study that's really just
going to invalidate the truth
dale rob do you have anything to add to
hurdles i know you do rob well it was
pretty amazing when sue was in humble
and she recognized our legacy genetics i
was there with you a few years ago and
she really did
recognize that we are sitting on better
medicine to be running tests and trials
of with the veterans um that's really
exciting
but i for a legacy farmer for someone
entering the metric right now um and say
you were able to pay all the bills and
pass all the stipulations of the
regulatory process um the biggest
problem for a burrito right now is
they're not allowed allowing new
genetics into the metric in california
and so um right now the big buzzword
with the dcc was having public comments
just a few weeks ago and a lot of people
are upset because they can't get their
genetics into metric and so
yeah we're pretty much locked out right
now in california and also right now in
california we've reached a point where
70 of all the genetics in the metric
right now are related to each other
and so
like daniel was saying just a second ago
i go to the collectives every week to we
dispense to probably close to 70
collectives and the medical selections
for diversity of genetics is
is disgusting it's no longer a medical i
don't consider it medical marijuana
anymore it's become wrecked marijuana
and um
you know as we lose
the different gene pools it'll just
becoming more and more wreck
and you know speaking to the trends of
it too
we've watched this purple thing get
really trendy where og was the old trend
um and we're already seeing the purple
trend fade and we're seeing the og trend
is about to come back in the next few
months and it's just wild how the market
can be dictated by
rappers and fancy
you know commercials
i just
there's one other thing that i think
it's been a problem for the last few
years uh but it's
i think it's still pretty significant
and that is just the issue of trust
um
in the old school communities i think
people and i wasn't part of them so i
can't pretend to speak for them but my
observation is that they knew who they
could trust they trusted their neighbors
they trusted
um people in their community
and they knew not to trust the
government and they knew they didn't
want to deal with lawyers
they didn't want to deal with big
companies
and uh
things have gotten really complicated
because
oh and they knew not to to
you know
interact they didn't interact much with
science and technology companies
somewhat but not a lot
and things have really gotten shaken up
because now
i've heard plenty of stories from
breeders that have said yeah i gave my
friend
this
this particular selection to put in his
catalog
and i never got paid
i've seen that a lot i've seen that even
recently
uh people just not getting paid they
think they can trust somebody and then
they can't
and then even more distasteful they
might have to somehow trust a lawyer or
trust the government to get a patent
and to just engage parties they never
wanted to engage and to start
questioning
it really is hard to figure out who you
can trust in this industry
um
and it i i like to use the word
community but i think it has as its
transition from community to industry
uh it's gotten very confusing i don't
know sir that i have any great solutions
for that but um
uh you know there are
lawyers and and companies that are
trying to be trustworthy but you can't
just
somebody tells you oh you should trust
me
you probably shouldn't
you got to watch watch them walk the
walk but you can trust me when i say
trust dale
or when we ask dale why we shouldn't
trust him and then he answers us in
front of a bunch of other people
just to preface how i view both of these
attorneys i think the word activist is
synonymous with lawyer when i picture
their identities and i think that's an
important com component that um there's
there's an element of activism
in genetic preservation in cannabis
right now because there isn't money in
it we'll tell you that much
i want to add one more thing to the
hurdles
where's the money in cannabis at
good question is anybody in here making
no ask the lawyers
i think it's in the government
right they definitely got the taxes yeah
i want to add one more thing to their
hurdles and i think that's education you
know we're talking about genetics and
and
one of the things that i see as we're
building new products and and
creating all these new things out of
this plant when we're talking about like
consumer
loyalty and when we're talking about
healing people i'm a patient i have no
l4 l5 and a torn spinal cord and i
really have to understand my medicine to
be functionable and genetics are really
important in that conversation when
you're trying to heal somebody or when
you're trying to make
a joint that makes people feel a certain
way and and and the gap in that is huge
yet these legacy communities literally
have we know people who have been
working with this plant for six
generations
and so bringing those two together i
think is going to help create a lot more
real medicine too
and and
push the research forward
um in that so learning
why all this diversity matters
so
how about solutions
solutions um
somebody else these guys jeffrey has a
solution
i am um you know believe business
and solution you would have to be an
activist
in your business to try to create
solutions i'm more on the ground i'm
caught in the fight i think
what jeff created shows a really good
perspective on potential solutions um
because protecting your varieties
you know somebody holds something that's
very special and has unique cannabinoid
profiles that they've worked on for 25
generations of the plants breeding so
maybe that's 25 years maybe that's 15
years but extensive work and it's really
life's work that people pour into these
things
so
you pour your life's work into something
and then you find yourself outside of
the commercial sphere you have to ask
yourself how am i going to get this
valuable medicine to somebody and how do
i do that
you know
there's an element of trust that you
have to have a partner that you do trust
um
and i think that
people are looking for answers because
they
are probably evolved now to the point
where the right contract or the right
agreements
probably look pretty enticing in terms
of a way to get their medicine to reach
people
and
dale and jeff have both presented
solutions that you know i'd never
considered before you know you won't let
you guys talk about your agreements and
your software but really exciting
yeah um yeah well i mean
i wouldn't be sitting here if i wouldn't
have ran into met dale and then youth
came to me because
we have all these amazing people in our
community and i'm really a community
builder but there was no way to go to
folks and say well you're protected
especially people like what daniel's
saying that are shut out of the market
we have a lot of breeders with i know
one breeder in particular who has over 4
000 different cultivars that he's been
seed hunting for 60 years and that's
just one person
yet he has no income
and jeff came and said i think i have a
solution
and it's this blockchain but
and he said something that was also
unique that i want the community's help
i want the breeders to help me make this
so it really works for him and that's
how we got started on understanding that
there was a solution that we could start
building off of out there
um cool should i start talking now
all right
um so
in thinking about
how
cannabis genetic diversity works i've
i've always thought about
um comparing it to music and how the
music industry works
um and so
when when you think about what a
cannabis breeder does when they're
developing strains it's it's really art
and that cannabis strain is really a
work of art and if we could figure out a
mechanism for cannabis breeders to get
paid for the commercialization of their
cultivars like artists get paid for
their art then maybe we could create a
fairer system that resulted in sort of a
more equitable distribution of the
profits from this industry but also
gives people an opportunity to protect
their work that they've spent decades
building so
what we come up with what we came up
with was
a system for doing that
and we've been working with the humboldt
grace legacy
calls project
every friday at 11. i did your pleasure
anyone can come and anyone can come
[Music]
so the
the main mechanism
is to define a cannabis cultivar as
in original work if you have something
that you think that you want to
commercialize
you can take a cutting of fresh leaf
material you can stick it in a tamper
evident package with a qr code and then
you can close the tamper evident package
take a photo of your sample and you can
keep it in your own freezer so
if you think that somebody ripped you
off you can open up your freezer you can
send your sample to mike at medicinal
genomics and you can sort of
determine whether or not you got ripped
off
but the value of having your frozen
sample is
and the value of how we're building it
through blockchain is that you can you
can build out a profile for your
cultivar and then if you want to enter
into a licensing agreement it's pretty
simple to do so
when you think about how the track and
trace system works
you have to put a little tag on every
single flowering plant in the legal
market and it's you know it's bad for
the environment but it's good for
inventory control and the fact that the
state is making you do it regardless um
really presents an opportunity to
to take this example of
licensing cannabis genetics like music
to another level so
if you think about a cannabis breeder as
an artist and a cannabis strain like a
song and a cannabis plant like the
equivalent of the play of a song
roughly the same functionality of music
streaming services can be applied to
cannabis
um and so that's what we're that's what
we're building
we're working with the legacy project
and
that's my story
in the legacy project we released a
white paper i guess a couple weeks ago
and and what we're taking is all this
information
to show folks how they can not just
secure or protect but how they can also
validate and authenticate their work and
then we're going to have an auction in
november to really educate not just on
the hype but like
show
i like to say we're going to show
everybody's panties because instead of
saying that we're the best it's going to
be you're going to look at this and
you're going to tell us what you think
through
the chemical profiles through the dna
through the stories that the breeders
give so we can start
helping folks we look at this plant a
little differently and maybe
empower the market to come to our
communities instead of asking for how
much weed they have we can
they'll ask oh
i want a joint that gives me this kind
of experience or i really need a strain
that's high in thcv
and because of what these communities
have been doing so for so many
generations we already know this is
going on we just have to bridge the gap
in that conversation
dale so
why does this matter to doctors we're
just doctors i love being here it's so
exciting to be a part of a science
conference but why why
why should they listen why should they
want to talk to folks that are involved
or that are from the legacy experience
i'm tempted to
turn about something that happened
yesterday i was watching
my friends back there at the middle
table doing a podcast
and they dragged me onto it to
participate with them these are the
breeders best folks
nisha whiteley ethan rousseau and mojave
richmond
ethan would be the very best person to
answer that mojave would also give a
great answer anisha wrote a book on this
stuff so
but i'll try to speak for them and then
i might hear about it if i get it wrong
but basically
cannabis is a rich rich source of
biochemical diversity
of different molecules that contact the
most widely distributed
receptor system in the body and it
affects
pretty much every function of the body
and
given that that's kind of the if you
think of that as the infrastructure for
signaling with medicines to get the body
to fix itself or to do something
differently
then you've got the plant makes the
tools to interact with this
infrastructure
and to
address all kinds of problems and the
the real beauty of that is
to use the term that uh that dr russo i
believe coined and and is very fond of
it is the entourage effect which i
describe i just think of it as synergy
between the interactions of one thing
touching a receptor and something else
touching a different receptor or
interacting with the same receptor you
get
really different and sometimes extremely
elevated activities at the receptor
level because of of the interaction of
more than one molecule and i think
that's the weakness of single molecule
drugs they don't allow for any synergy
but as soon as you have
a whole plant medicine or an extract
from a plant and you've got lots of
different things that can interact with
that receptor system in a synergistic
way in a cooperative way then you've got
the potential for incredibly more
powerful medicines at lower doses
so i think that's that's why
doctors should be interested in genetic
diversity in cannabis because if
everything you've got out there has the
same two or three terpenes in the same
one or two or three cannabinoids then
you're limiting yourself
and you're it's like you walk into a
library
and you stop at the first shelf and you
pull off the first couple books and you
walk back out
that's that's a a huge um
uh
under utilization of this vast potential
so
i i think that the genetic diversity the
biochemical diversity and the potential
that we have to
with with the help of the great legacy
breeders as well as uh
molecular technologies to develop plants
that really can
uh provide
new and extremely powerful medicines
that are extremely safe is a promise
that is going to revolutionize the
health of everybody on earth
well said
ethan might be smiling under his mask he
might be drowning
yeah the different varieties i think are
really important and evaluating your
medicine based on the effects
i think is something that's just totally
underutilized right now i don't know if
the consumer
really responds to okay either i'm high
or i'm not high that's a very like
binary vision of cannabis and that if
you drink a glass of wine versus a glass
of beer versus a margarita or a shot of
tequila you're gonna feel different
based on those inputs and cannabis has
an even wider range of effects that it
can have and so just to touch on a few
ringo's gift high cbd cultivar nearly
unmarketable in the commercial market
there are mothers that say they've heard
their children say mom for the first
time in three years by
utilizing the plant
we will do anything to make that person
feel better whether there's money
involved or not uh
blue skunk and orange cream frost two
cultivars one bread for ptsd the blue
skunk orange cream frost bread for its
beauty and its aroma
the orange cream frost will level you it
will
shut you down you will stop talking
you'll go inside your head and the blue
skunk will make you on a day where
you're just having a bad day blow off
the thing that really doesn't matter the
distressing you out so we went to a
podcast and the breeder brought these
two herbs and the order
was that they were the podcast
interviewers were going to smoke the two
strains and talk about it they smoked
the blue skunk we had a great interview
and then they smoked the orange cream
frost and he went catatonic he did not
say one thing until the sound engineer
just shut it down okay it's over um
that's the power
of those genetics and if you choose the
really purple flashy one you might get
leveled when you really want the bright
green one that's going to make you feel
really good for the day
and then to touch on one more and the
cannabinoids and the minor cannabinoids
is pink boost goddess
where it is documented as the highest
thcv so
tetrahydrocannabirin i got that right um
that is a rare cannabinoid that some
labs can't even distinguish between thc
and thcv so
we might be missing the whole point when
we look at oh this thing's got twenty
two percent it might have
ten percent and seven percent tcv and
two percent thcp which is
on there are still undiscovered
cannabinoids here so the diversity and
the preservation
and is super important and the doctors
should be looking at the necessity of
that we need a data bank where we're a
bank where all these genetics exist and
we should be inviting the home growers
to pull all the seeds out of their
you know forbidden closets and preserve
these things and i will go further to
say it shouldn't be any government
entity that holds those data banks it
should be the community
that holds them here
rob you got you know
following up with dan
the the cannabis plant is the only plant
on earth that holds every single terpene
profile on earth
and so i think that there's a huge
research to do with just the variances
of all the different terpenes that are
out there and definitely
you know we're gonna find terpenes that
are might only have a hundred seeds left
that represent that terpene profile at
somebody's house that was growing at 50
years ago and
definitely
locking our data into blockchain is
a way to preserve this quickly it's it's
something that i had a friend that's
been doing nfts for almost four years
now and he was you know telling me that
i should try to find out something that
can connect with cannabis and it was
easily the first thing i figured out was
we could lock our dna codes into the
blockchain so that we can't get them
stolen and we can claim them so no one
else can ever claim them
and then second i had the idea that if
we could create contracts just for
selling cannabis so that we could
control circumvention in the metric and
create contracts that we could read the
metric
and sure enough somebody in our group
created a smart contract before i could
get a hold of my code or friend to tell
him to do it and we have a contract that
can read metric which i think is is
really invaluable to
um small cultivators to make sure that
we can watch and track where our things
are and make sure people don't steal
them and
take them awry
all right thanks you guys does anyone
have any questions of anybody on the
panel up here
hey eric
there's a mic
then they can record it i think yeah do
the mic
hi guys um thanks for being down here um
my question is i was wondering if you
could actually just run through what
the the com the parts of a transaction
like what that would look like like
somebody
sees a cultivar they're interested
a client so how does that could you just
sort of go through a
an analogy of what that
looks like in the different pieces how
that comes together in how it's
happening now or through canopy right
what we've developed well through your
um i guess it's still in beta so i don't
think it's operating at this point but
when it does launch
what would that
how would that look whether
like somebody licensing what would that
look like canopy right is the the engine
is built and now the the the 2.0 design
is coming out thanks to kelsey so it's
really user friendly but do you want to
answer that josh
uh yeah i'll i'll answer that um
so
the way that it works isn't dissimilar
so it's similar to how it works now
except for one important change
so
the way that it works is if a grower
wants to grow a cultivar from a breeder
we have them negotiate a price on a per
plant basis
and
once there's an agreement and there's a
there's a mechanism for negotiation
um the negotiation follows a few
different paths so
one is the price per plant again we
invoice based on the flowering plant
tags that are on each plant when they go
in when they're entered into the
traction tray system but that's really
only one aspect of a transaction right
because you're not just buying
a plant you're also buying how you grow
that plant and so
we sort of create a space for people to
input cultivation requirements quality
standards
um
late fees sort of it's not just what
you're charging per plan it's what
you're charging per plant to get the
cultivar that the breeder wants to be in
the market
but once that happens it's
the
when the cultivar's flowering plants are
entered into the track and trace system
we pull that
data and then we generate an invoice
based on the agreed upon price per plan
we
are tracking it
you know periodically and then we
invoice on a monthly basis
that's the basic mechanism but i think
it probably helps to talk about the
privacy aspects of it because i think
that that's
you know a thing that is a problem in
the industry right now is if you
there's a lot of trust issues and also
there's a lot of experience
i know rob was talking about it
but like everyone has a story of how
they've been ripped off and so we want
to just create a system that is
completely private if users want it to
be private
and if i could just i am often asked
about the difference between canopy
right and patents and i i think it's
it's helpful to
explain the two because i think they're
really compatible and i am a big
supporter of canopy ride even though i'm
a patent attorney so
one of the things people ask me is is my
plant new enough to patent is it
different enough that i can get a patent
on it and the answer is if you bread it
it is different enough it'll qualify for
a patent we can get you a patent the
real question that you should be asking
instead is is this plant worth patenting
because there's no super inexpensive way
to patent it it's going to cost you
by the time you're finished it's going
to cost at least ten thousand dollars
and maybe up maybe a closer to thirty
thousand dollars to get it patented now
if you've got something that's going to
take the world by storm and it'll be
commercially viable for for a decade or
two then that's just that that's just a
rounding error on the rounding errors
it's not going to be a significant
amount of the value of that plan but
there are a lot of things that people
want to be able to commercialize without
hiring a lawyer without spending that
kind of money and with extremely quick
efficient transactions and that's what i
love about canopy right it lets people
skip the whole lawyer thing
and go straight into into commercial
transactions
and then canopyright notifies them that
okay look as soon as you do a
transaction
you are starting a patent deadline for
yourself you need to if you want to get
a patent on this you need to act within
a year and so these are not these are
systems that i think are very compatible
and it's a great solution for people who
who don't want to spend the money on a
patent and then another solution for
people who don't want to spend the money
on a patent as breeder's best because we
pay for the patent work the breeder owns
it but we have to be pretty selective we
can't protect nearly as many cultivars
as canopy right can handle because there
is so much cost associated with it so
it's only when we think we see something
that we think we could put all over the
world and really have an impact for a
long time
that that's when we say okay yeah we'll
commit to this we'll spend the money on
this and with confidence that it will
end up producing enough revenues that
the breeder can really benefit from it
and that we can recoup our investment as
well so they are they're different
systems but i think they're highly
compatible and it it opens up a form of
protection to a lot more plant
varieties
um the last thing i would say is um just
full disclosure um so we we the
registration functionality we're not
charging for and we will never charge
for um it's just an essential service
that we think that we're going to be
providing
so
we're going to charge a royalty
fee when people enter into business
transactions with each other because we
wrote your contract for you and i'm a
lawyer that's what i do
but i just we are trying to offer the
system of you know creating a
registration of a cultivar and we're
trying to do it for free
and just the model that they're
discussing i mean our business has used
that exact licensing model since its
inception
to economically empower breeders so
things like the blueberry muffin and
other varieties
were curated with these concepts
at the very beginning that we didn't
want to share that without empowering
the breeder and
i think that it's a great first step to
you know initiating asserting your value
over your genetics is to put them into
canopy right and say i'm going to take
the first step to acknowledge the value
here and i also want to say how cool it
is that they use the temper
proof
the tampering proof bags which are
kind of like an evidence
police thing and i just think that's the
irony there is really awesome
it's a great design
thanks
yeah and and like daniel kind of
mentioned the whole licensing agreement
idea isn't a new concept it just wasn't
very
accessible and and what jeff has created
is made it accessible so we can build on
that hi evian hi i believe the gentleman
over here had a question
she had one too
well i think she had a question maybe
even before so
come on i work with them so you could go
ahead
well thank you i apologize for being the
last question
um
so i think that you all and the other
talks this week have done a really good
job of highlighting that um
you know the the medical benefits of
cannabis are probably really
really come from having this diversity
in the cultivars and having many
terpenes and different profiles and even
from the adult use perspective i think
that's really important right in
producing the different effects that the
consumer might be looking for
but right now there's this huge
proliferation of synthetically derived
cannabinoids like delta8 and hhc and and
obviously those are being driven from a
certain economic perspective and the
fact that cannabis is illegal in many
places so it's convenient to then gain
access to something that will get you
high or whatever
but um i heard someone yesterday and
effort at many other conferences that
people think that um
you know the biosynthetic derived from
yeast or again these laboratory derived
cannabinoids are perhaps a huge player
in the future of the cannabis market but
they seem to be pretty threatening to
you know trying to maintain this
diversity that is actually relevant to
medicine and to again consumer
satisfaction i think so i just wondered
what all your thoughts are do do they
really have a place in the future of
cannabis um and if they do how does how
does it all balance out so that we don't
lose what you are all trying to preserve
thank you great question anyone want to
take that
i mean my brief research into delta 8
and the other cannabinoids definitely is
because you know they're not letting you
know thc across state borders we have
plenty of thc to serve people across the
country
but i have seen that there's research
that shows that it does do combinations
with thc and people do get good effects
from taking delta eight with th thc
added and there's actually there's
brands in the metric market in
california now that have been adding
delta eight in the last six to
six months to a year that i've noticed
coming out online so
it's definitely been used in california
even
and from a patient's perspective
you know i've always said whatever works
but
what i've learned over the years and
i've watched us is we're getting closer
and closer to morning i was raised by a
midwife and and she was very much a
naturopath in the way she she took care
of her patients
and i really i was a nurse and i really
thought science knew everything and what
i saw what i've seen the past two days
is that science is starting to validate
what indigenous studies indigenous
medicines and plant medicines is known
for centuries we just haven't had the
tools to define those and i see science
defining those things not really
changing it so maybe this plant will
help us realize that we don't need all
those chemical things and that plant
medicine might have a little more power
than we've given it credit to
[Music]
[Applause]
i would love to just uh hear if you
could if the panel could speak to
uh the work that the ethical data
alliance has been doing for the past two
and a half years and how all of these
projects kind of tie together with that
and the eden protocol with the
blockchain and just how it's a kind of a
gift back to the community and also the
ethical gatekeeper of everything that
we're doing
well i just met the ethica data alliance
about i don't know eight months ago
but i'm very familiar with philos and
all of that and dale actually
dale and i ran uh i went to a meeting
that dale was at and i was actually
invited to meet dale about
four years ago before covet and i said
oh no i can't go there because my
community won't trust me it's dale hutch
and so i got invited to a small group
meeting and i was able to ask him you
know you seem great i appreciate what
you have to say but why am i told that
maybe you're the big bad devil trying to
steal all our genetics and he gave me a
really good answer and then he saw what
some of us daniel and i have been
talking about for quite a few years is
creating this auction in in how it could
tell the story and help empower these
small farmers and he said lele i want to
help you out and i'm going to be your
pro bono a journey and he said you need
to go into the eda
i am not a technologist i'm not a
breeder i am a cultivator i have i i
know the plant very well
and i'm not a scientist and what i am is
a community builder and i didn't i don't
didn't know much about blockchains and i
went into the eda and i just said look
you guys i'm told that you're trying to
protect our ip
here's what i think i'd like to do
help and really quickly
jeff came to the table another gentleman
caleb came to the table
another gentleman jason with fall score
came to the table and said look we have
these we think we have solutions
and the ethica data alliance is really
like
you know
the mothership i i see them as the
mothership helping this entire industry
preserve and protect their ip through
all these technologies and helping us
through the humboldt grace legacy
project because we're really about
community and the plant
ensure that we're doing the right thing
through these technologies and and
through our communities and so they're
really
a really great resource i think for
anybody in the industry who is looking
at innovative ways to use blockchain and
crypto
technologies to empower themselves and
their communities in more ways than
genetics
it definitely is an amazing organization
and we would not be where we are right
now and this project is like going like
wildflower locally we have a lot of
support and i mean we would we just
would not be here i would not know jeff
and now i have the pleasure of working
with jeff with canopy right
if it was not for the eda so
please if you think you have ip
that you need to preserve and protect
go to their meetings because that's what
they're doing
anyone else want to add to that i mean
you turn on the board there's a donation
button on the website it's a non-profit
we really we have one paid person on the
eda and um
he works really hard and and we we need
that funding so uh please
any donation large or small would be
greatly appreciated
yeah the eda for me is the network that
has brought us all together
absolutely that i met dale
in 2019 here at canmed after a really
inspiring panel that he gave and i was
fortunate enough to speak as well and we
connected and the eda kept us together
so ethical data alliance is my favorite
group of cannabis nerds that care
about the good guys and the little guys
and it was formed in the wake of
kind of some nefarious acts by
you know a well-known cannabis dna
sequence collecting company not
medicinal genomics or leaf works
i want to also add another reason that
we're at this stage and here today is
because of medicinal genomics
brendan kevin and mike have been at our
friday calls in fact i don't think
they've missed
one of our friday calls as medicinal
genomics
and have been really supportive and i
want to thank you guys for inviting us
here to have this conversation it's a
great opportunity thank you and thank
you
[Applause]