[Music]
welcome to the CED Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I'm the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on the camp Med
conference well another canmed
Innovation and investment Summit is in
the books thanks so much to everyone who
joined us at Marco Island for the event
this year it was fantastic we had some
great panel presentations workshops oral
presentations poster presentations and
got a lot of good time on the beach as
well hopefully if you joined us for
camed 24 you'll come back for camed 25
and if you missed out on this year's
event we hope hope to see you next
spring details around camed 25 will be
coming out very soon so stay tuned for
that so if you haven't already signed up
for email alerts atkm events.com do that
now so you can be one of the first to
know when tickets go on sale also we
recorded all of the oral presentations
at camed 24 this year and those videos
will be going up on our YouTube page and
our camed archive in a few weeks so
again sign up up for email alerts and
you will get the notification as soon as
those are available our guest today is
Dr Shannon Smith Shannon received his
PhD in molecular biosciences from Middle
Tennessee State University there his
research focused on plant biotechnology
with work in cannabis Panax and vidus
tissue culture and
manipulation this led to the development
of new and unique Technologies for the
production of both plants and secondary
metab aites he later founded Greenway
lab a plant biotechnology company that
collaborates with agricultural Partners
to implement plant biotech solutions to
Botanical challenges facing the modern
agricultural
industry during our conversation we
discussed the many advantages of using
tissue culture and cannabis
cultivation particularly for use in
propagation
cryopreservation and for store storage
protection and Reclamation of genetic
IP so without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr Shannon
Smith
[Music]
good morning Dr Smith thanks so much for
joining us on the
podcast uh thank you for the in
invitation excellent well I'm excited to
talk with you today about tissue culture
at caned 24 you're presenting a poster
about recent advances in plant tissue
culture that may solve three key
problems facing the Cannabis industry
but before we get into those I was
hoping you can give us an overview of
what tissue culture is and how it's
potentially revolutionizing the Cannabis
industry I'd be glad to um so tissue
culture is isn't of itself a sub um a
subdiscipline of plant
biotechnology um plant biotechnology is
just basically the science of using um
various techniques and understandings
that we've developed over time to either
make more plants or to investigate you
know the plant kingdom and specifically
tissue culture itself relies on a set of
evolutionary strategies that the plant
kingdom has conserved plants are by
their very nature sessile creatures that
is to say um more except for some key um
like exceptions uh plant tissue itself
can't move on its own like obviously
like pollen can move and there's certain
exceptions but as a whole plants can't
move which leads them to having to deal
with a threat that other like creatures
in the animal kingdom um they have to
have a different strategy for it if say
for instance a predator is coming after
like a gazelle or something gazelle can
just run if say for instance you and I
find an absolutely delicious AOC avocado
tree the avocado tree can't get up and
leave so what the plant has to do is and
what the on the conserved strategy is
that they have they have favored is
plant cells can be a little bit more
plastic in their expression so if say
for instance a plant is injured by
either a predator or disease or a pest
like say for instance something's chewed
on it or we've ripped off a section of
it
Etc the cells that are killed send a a
last gas message to the rest of the
cells and the plants in the environment
now this chemical message then tells the
plant cells that are remaining hey look
we've been injured so they start a
series of defensive strategies to
convert themselves into a undeveloped
tissue and then replace the tissues that
they
lose or and also with some of them it
tells them hey look we're under attack
from this threat you need to switch
production from this to this uh those
are two things uh in plant tissue
culture uh that are basically the key
Concepts behind a lot of the expressions
of the technology that we use in
Industry so how how does the tissue
culture process sort of take advantage
of those
adaptations okay so with that um I've
got a a few
um I've I've got a few
sources so for a lot of
um this uh for a lot of these things if
the audience wishes to do a deep dive um
this is a review article that the
Canadian uh academic Community worked
together with um the Canadian cannabis
industry to look at uh tissue culture as
a whole and to justs like basically
here's a list of all of these various
strategies um it's a little dense and
it's a little big so but it it it's a
review article so it's very useful sure
um so
um with that a couple of the things that
you can do with it was um you can take
advantage of these uh various techniques
to either propagate tissues um to do um
long longer term
storage uh to try to select for a
certain Elite traits um say for instance
you you want a crop any or the fruit is
bigger or let's say for instance you're
making a um you're making a cannabis
line that produces a specific oil or
like produces a harder fiber you can
select for
those
um you can do like I said you can do
long-term storage you can propagate and
you can um help guide um uh growth and
um breeding
opportunities also uh there is um some
aspects of it that help um in disease
prevention and disease recovery because
again um we're leveraging the defense
strategies of the
plant and uh we can then actively select
like okay hey we have this situation so
let's specifically do this to deal with
this
problem right so could you walk us
through the process of of tissue
culture okay uh sure I'm going to give
you a very brass tax uh very basic
explanation of the tissue culture
technique and also I have some um images
from both our research and also some
cartoony ones that are a little bit
easier to see if like the screen small
like they're just watching it on their
phone so uh the basic T process of
tissue culture is first you do a
selection of of
materials that you select a plant and
you select the tissues in question
and then you
um then you take
and oh we'll pull up this cartoon so
you'll take um a cutting from those
tissues and sterilize them this is so
that you only are dealing with the
plants that you wish to deal with and
not of of any of the pathogens or any of
the other materials you're specifically
getting you're only selecting for like
say for instance you only want Maris
which is like Bud tissue or you only
want Leaf tissue so you just get that
and then you uh plate the tissues on a
media that has um these cell signaling
compounds that's those compounds that I
said beforehand were like the plant
saying hey look this happened you need
to do this so it grows
into um a mass of these Undeclared
majors of cells of like undifferentiated
tissue called callus and then you take
and you start giving it signals to say
like hey I want you to make roots or hey
I want you to make this compound or hey
I want you to make shoes and for in this
micropropagation
slide um what you're doing what this is
doing is we're taking uh some of the
body tissue converting it into callus
and then converting that tissue in that
callus while we're making the callus
grow over and over again we're also
telling it to make more plant babies now
you know that's the cartoon tun version
um these are some of the research
pictures they might they might not
necessarily be as clear so this is this
is an example where that upper left the
white tissue that is that was some
cuting that I took off of a a
economically threatened plant and we
grew a whole mass of that tissue
normally that amount of tissue would
take about two or three years to grow
because it's it it's it's a perennial
this was grown in months and then we
convert those tissues into a special
subtype and start making plant
babies uh that's one example um this is
um this is from our lab currently uh
we're working with um some of our
partners and working doing some work for
them so I took some cuting off of one of
their mother plants and then did a then
selected for tissues plated very small
tissues and these guys what they start
doing on that little jelly media that
they grow that they they're in they grow
they reproduce they grow they reproduce
they get bigger they reproduce and more
and more and then as they get to a
certain size they start throwing shoots
off and then we cut the shoots off and
you know propagate cut the shoots off
propagate until you get basic this is
probably a little bit more easy for the
the audience to see so so that's like
the base basic process of tissue
culture so how long does it take to get
to that sort of last stage that last
picture that you s showed there so um
with again
um
um to you know th this review has uh
several uh authors where they talk about
that um and from my work and also from
the work of Dr LA and their colleagues
you can get
um you can initiate a a callous culture
that that mass of cells normally in
about like 2 to 3 weeks and then they
start and that just starts growing and
growing and growing and for it varies
per plant but since we're you know since
we're talking about cannabis uh normally
that you start um the the shots and the
roots that the shots and the full
regenerated plants off of that callus um
they're ready to go into the ground
after a month mhm and the callous is
just sitting there throwing shoots
constantly and getting bigger throwing
shoots constantly so instead of say for
instance you having a mother room where
you have very tightly crowded plants and
um you have threats from like mold and
mildew and um fun and other fungal
contaminants and like spider
mites spidermites are a swear word to me
um cuz they just get in and they never
go away uh these are kept in a sterile
environment and in a much smaller space
and you can produce a larger amount of
plants for square
footage in a relatively quick
time so because for example um so for
traditional um cutting so like this is
like an image of you know so you have
your mother plant uh you cut it down to
the 9 Hells and then you get that amount
um
so with microor for instance you're only
taking a smaller portion but you can
that smaller portion like the little
circle area can produce the same
amount you know as
that so you don't necessarily need as
much you don't need as much square
footage to do the same job so if you
need to expand you you have that
available because no one's making more
Earth s right no and so when you were
describing the process I think it's kind
of clicked in my head maybe for the
first time is that so you're taking the
small piece of tissue you're putting it
in the media and it's sort of just
sitting there waiting for instructions
and then you're telling it what to do
with the hormones and everything that
you're adding to the culture right yeah
yeah see the the compounds in question
um they're cell signaling compounds some
of them are hormones some of them are
other things um but like it's literally
the chemical communication Network for
cells and it's their regul regulatory
system the cell is like hey I'm getting
food but no one's telling me what to do
and then you you have in the media you
have oh you need to do this and cell's
like cool and just starts doing it until
it's told to do something else excellent
okay so what are so you mentioned sort
of the the space saving advantage of
using uh culture for propagation um what
if any are other advantages to to this
method okay so again um our Canadian
colleagues go through and have pages of
of advantages um to ex to summarize uh
the sterility process um removes a great
deal of the threats that are currently
um in field grow and Greenhouse uh
growing operations So you you're less
likely to have to deal with certain
vectors coming in um you
can
produce um Elite clones that um so for
instance one of the strategies that you
have with um tissue culture is you start
opening
up um Avenues of long-term
storage um that is not normally
available using traditional methods the
the best traditional method for
long-term storage is normally converting
to seed and then getting it into a seed
Vault now that has a problem because
seeds will over time lose their
viability um so tisue culture opens up
both
cryopreservation and artificial seed
generation um and um artificial seed
pres preser uh uh preservation is uh
moderately long-term storage uh strategy
cryo pres preservation is a long-term
storage strategy um that is for a
situation where a client has like an
elite uh genome or Elite germplasm that
they are very concerned because they're
the only one in the world that has it
and it's only in this one location and
they're one fire or one hop Len virus or
one fungal contamination of the
extinguishment of that species or that
subset so what you can do is you can
convert it into tissue culture and then
um do a cryopreservation which is a
really quick
freeze and you can go store that
longterm off
site um and that allows to where you
don't have all your eggs in one
basket and then at a later date you can
bring that tissue back up and since it's
very plastic and convert you can then
put it on tissue plated tissues and um
grow it up and then start you know
having the cow start throwing shoes
again and just regenerate from there um
it also allows op breeding opportunities
uh genetic modification and um
compound um compound modification where
you can tell the plant specifically
since since you were telling it what to
do you can use techniques to say hey I
don't necessarily want you say like say
for instance hyp pathetically you have a
plant that produces uh something that
interacts with the endoc canabo system
but one of the compounds is uh legally
um
dubious so you can say for instance
suppress the uh the the compound that
could possibly get the grower in trouble
while upregulating the compound that
they're actually growing the plant for
so you that you can stay in a
hypothetical
situation um of a plant that has one
compound that is legally regulated while
the other ones are perfectly
fine you can then I I'll use tissue
culture techniques to make sure that
your grow doesn't go
hot and those are just some go ahead so
explain that a bit more how how does the
tissue culture process allow you to sort
of you know regulate those genes okay so
uh the again this is tissue culture
going this this is going back into the
whole faction that this is plants
conserve defensive strategy
IES um they there are and it tells the
plants to do you know like hey I need to
grow this hey I need to grow this the
secondary metabolites are defense
compounds they are not grown for the for
our benefit even though we can take
advantage of it they're actually grown
to end us it's to be poisonous it's just
that in like with all things the poison
is in the dose um often times those
things that are compounds that are risky
or poisonous to an organism at lower
levels can lower INF inflammation stop
like you know you know redirect cells to
where like immune cells are no longer
attacking their own body so on so
forth um
so for plant tissue culture and for the
various biotechnological things you can
we know what tells the plant to go
produce these compounds more because the
compounds are being produced in response
to a threat you trick it into thinking
it has this particular type of
threat and it makes a particular type of
compound well it doesn't at the end of
the day it only has a certain B budget
of sugar so it has to take it from
somewhere so if that you push something
up something else has to go
down and with these you can use these
techniques to say for instance um take
an elite germ plasm that produces a lot
of of a certain oil and say hey produce
more of this because you're under this
attack when in fact it's not so it's not
taking the damage that would normally
cause it and cause it to produce less
tissues you're just telling it to
produce more of the oil and it's still
keeping the same amount of
tissue so how does that translate once
you put the plant um you know into soil
or some other media you actually grow it
as a plant or are you just keeping it in
tissue
culture so there's a couple different
strategies for for that uh one of the
ways um that you can do is you can grow
it in a you can grow it in a um callous
suspension culture to where you just
have a slurry of cells and it's just
producing this compound over and over
again but what specifically I was
discussing is um a technique that I and
some of my colleagues developed where we
can hijack that cell signaling pathway
in plants that are already in say for
instance the hydroponic system so
they're already plants they're already
doing things and we just use the
technology that is currently that
Growers are currently using for
propagation we just say hey um give this
cell signaling compound under this
dosage to the subject at these key
points of development and then it will
switch over and start is like oh I'm in
a environment that has this threat so I
will respond according accordingly so
they don't have you don't have to have
it in tissue culture for for the client
um you just we can leverage uh the
defense strategies of the
plant and have them use the technology
that they're already used to yeah so the
same concept of when we were talking
about earlier of you know using the
compounds or hormones in the petri dish
to send signals to the plant you can
actually do that in the hydroponic
system like through you know the the
water and nutrients that you're giving
it to produce the same
effect yeah it's just a it's just a much
larger petri dish excellent all right um
so what are some of the most significant
uh I'm sorry that is the wrong question
um it's fine what are some common
misconceptions or myths about tissue
culture that you'd like to
debunk um okay so I'm not sure if
they're common myths or the like but
there's a there's several questions that
the clients always come come to me when
I'm discussing this so I don't know if
it's a myth or if I'm just getting a
small sample size uh so I I'll go with
those sure uh one of one of the concerns
that um uh I've had several Growers H
specifically because of regulatory
threats they were concerned okay so once
we start doing this stuff you're doing
all the science things um what's going
to make how how am I going to be sure
that what when when I give you these
plants they're going to be like they're
they're hemp right now uh
but what if they go hot and I'm like do
they have a history of going hot well no
it it's less than like it's less than 1%
okay
well are you going to make it into
marijuana and I'm
like no so like some of the uh things
things that I I don't think several
people understand is when you're doing
tissue culture you are making an exact
clone of the mother the donor tissue um
unless you doing genetic modification
specifically which is another step if
you just clone that process whatever I
it's whatever genetics it has is what
the daughter is going to have sure so
like it's not going to suddenly like
it's not a like point
02 per THC plant is not suddenly going
to go 20% just because it crossed the
threshold of my door right um so unless
we do a lot of extra heavy lifting to to
like insert things that's one thing um
another one is that they have a lot of
questions is whether or not um it will
impact the grower organic certifications
um which um that it's not necessarily
like a science myth but it's like um it
it's something that is very much so of
of interest to the client
um what is organic or not is a
government regulation and tissue culture
does not impact your organic
certifications at all like it's apples
to aircraft
carriers so like it it would it would
have no more impact on your organic
certifications on whether or not you
used an electronic vehicle to transport
your cannabis versus like a gas powered
vehicle it's just we don't it doesn't
the regulations don't apply to us
because what we're doing we're only
like we only have the genetic
expressions of the plant that we begin
with and the the daughter is the exact
it's an exact clone of the mother so if
if you know once I hand it to you if you
continue to your Organics it's still
organic you know I haven't I haven't
messed up with any of
your um those are the two that I always
get asked yeah um so I don't know if
they're myths but it's like questions
that the clients always have so I
thought I'd bring it up yeah no awesome
and that that brings up another question
too so when you are working with a
client so we talked about the different
applications of tissue culture whether
it's propagation preservation
remediation or um sort of genetic
modification so what is like the most
common application that you're using
with your
clients um so with some of that I'm
going I I need to be um a little bit um
Cy um in the sense um I can't say what
I'm doing with my clients but what I
because of ndas sure just like sort of
in general in general there's a couple
different things that the clients are
all that are always asking for um the
three big ones would be uh plant
propagation um and and and this is also
probably I think this is also probably
like industrywide for tissue um plant
propagation um see
here um storage for safety because of
the various um um disease outbreaks and
some fires that happened
uh last year in certain States uh some
of the Growers lost some of their crops
uh due to
wildfires so they they need some form of
like um third party
preservations uh so the propagation
preservations and um disease prevention
those would be the three things that the
industry as a whole very much so is is
very interested in and that's because of
the way that tissue culture
works you
know there are solutions for for the
client's problems excellent and now
interest in general for tissue culture
even awareness is that growing in your
opinion growing very slowly um interest
interest High understanding um there's a
barrier to entry uh so they they they
want to know they hear the term but they
they want to know what it is but um they
don't have access so things like this
podcast is uh very helpful for for them
um and it's not the Growers or the
industry's fault um agricultureal as a
whole has has very wholly adopted plant
biotechnology and tissue culture for
their production methods and various
other things um but due to regulatory
restraints um cannabis has has been a
lagging the Cannabis industry has lagged
behind it's not their fault um there's
barriers to getting that information
tuned from and uh tuned from the
scientific community so yeah uh things
like canmed um and the various other
cons are starting to you know clients
are starting to come it's like who do I
talk to in the industry who do I talk to
in Academia I I don't know and so these
events yeah there is a growing interest
um and a
growing understanding but we're due to
several of the regulatory roadblocks um
the Cannabis industry is having to play
catchup from the rest of the
Agricultural
Community okay so I guess with that in
mind are there certain things I mean I
guess now here's a platform that you
wish Growers Growers I'm sorry let me
let me start over so with that in mind
are there certain things that you wish
Growers knew about tissue culture um
that they might not have a good
understanding of right now
um yes um there's several of the um with
the ongoing um changes that they're
facing um from a biological perspective
um in my region uh our rainy our rains
are coming in different time periods uh
our Winters are not as cold so um pests
and threats and pathogens that weren't a
problem in my region are suddenly
becoming a problem um and uh Industries
are having to play catchup well for
several of these problems that are that
are future facing because farmers and
agricultural they have to drive well
ahead of the hood of their car so like
the clients right now you know even
though it's like 2024 and it's just
spring agriculture is like okay we've
got 2024 what are we doing in 2025 what
are we doing in 2026 how how are we
going to be dealing with that um so with
these problems that they the future
problems um plant tissue culture options
um are available to help future proof
you uh you can help work you can you
know store your uh store your germ plasm
you can uh produ you can actually have a
facility built um at your location and
be trained and have to where through
Partnerships you can do your own tissue
culture work and like you um start to
retire certain um aspects of your
production that are high risk for
infection um or bottlenecks for
production those would be like you
know the the there's some problems that
you guys are facing and they're only
going to get more complicated so it's
it's the quicker you adapt and adopt the
the new strategies that your colleagues
over in the other the rest of the
Agricultural fields are doing um the
safer you're going to be in the more
long term that we can help make you be
as a company and as a client right now
is cost a barrier or a perceived
barrier cost um startups costs can be a
perceived barrier um depending on what
you're doing um if you're if you're
trying to if a client is trying to build
a full fully functional cloning
facility
um that is obviously if you're doing
that um that's going to be a capital
intensive but you can part there are
companies you know slight you know
slight self-plug you know my company for
instance um that um they will they you
can partner with them and uh you can
work kind of a situation where you know
you go havies in on the work and you
know over time maybe convert a facility
a lot of individuals don't realize that
you don't necessarily have to build this
facility from the ground up sometimes uh
you can just convert a section and um
the for instance B
um th this um review goes into um where
in with several of the can industry in
Canada uh they were able to flip and
convert originally they thought like hey
yeah this is a you know high cost
barrier to entry but they were able to
actually
convert and um it ended up being a cost
saving method and they were able to
redirect that Capital into other
Ventures and expand that way so yeah um
it is a
perceived uh it is a perceived barrier
but it is not necessarily always as
accurate as people believe it is it's
not as it's not as much of a barrier as
people think yeah they just don't they
just don't have the technology or the
experience and you can't blame them for
that yeah and that was going to be my
next question is you
know can the average cultivator do they
have the skills necessary to be able to
do tissue culture or is that a very kind
of
specific um set of skills that you need
to sort of hire for or or consult with a
company
um that's a hard question to answer
because it depends on uh the
cultivator um you can be
trained um if you are good enough to
handle the In-N-Outs of agronomy plant
breeding running a greenhouse handling
um various fertilizers and vertiga
systems being able to handle all of
those techniques that's that's a lot of
that's a lot of experience and Technical
knowhow if you have the skill set to do
that you can learn um you can also hire
individuals coming out of Academia uh
there are a a slew of good programs for
where the and here's one thing that is a
disconnect and something that I I I want
to have like tell the agricultural
Community um the agricultural Community
is like hey look we're looking we're
trying to find these people that have
these skill sets and Academia is like
we're producing these people that have
these skill sets I wish I could find a
job with these skill sets
um that's uh there's this like this so
close so
close so like yeah you can uh you can
hire individuals um but like a
technician you you don't need
necessarily to get a um PhD you
technicians that are like Bachelors you
know lab tech lab heads that can be
Masters those those levels of Education
are um easily able to handle it but also
you can be
trained yeah so like if you if you can
handle a vertiga system you can handle a
bsl2
cabinet yeah no and that's one great
thing about about cannabis Growers and
probably Growers and and farmers General
is they they have to be a little bit of
a jack of all trades and um you know be
familiar with all different systems and
sort of create their own solutions to
problems too so um yeah for example um
one of the partners I have he's an
agronomist uh James Clint Palmer um he's
an agronomist um very much so breeds his
own uh cannabis lines great Greenhouse
guy but he also knows how to use an hplc
mpect and he has like a a an an an
analyzer in like one of his you know
closets that he uses to analyze the
chemical profile of the plants that he's
that he's breeding so like the Jack of
all trades it's like you would if you
know if you ever meet Clint which I
actually do recommend he's great guy and
very knowledgeable when it comes to
plant braiding um you would not you
would be like you have a what where
right it's like oh yeah let's just go
run an analysis it'll be fine and it's
like so yeah for so that's just an
example of an
agronomist who a lot of people if I say
hlc mpect they'll they'll be like so are
we doing CSI or something you know so
yeah like they can
learn excellent all right so so winding
down here I was wondering if you could
discuss any ongoing research or
collaborations that you're currently
involved with uh related to cannabis
tissue
culture um I can very
vaguely the lawyer slight suddenly
appearing in my office NDA um so we are
working with uh individuals to um uh
breed some of they they have some very
interesting germ plasm that produces
some very interesting traits and they
want to make a lot of it um there was
again this is a little bit more um and I
have to be very careful um not only for
my own legal reasons but because you
know this is
regulatory uh but in the region that I'm
in um are last two seasons have been
very
rough uh on on the the agricultural as a
whole but um several of the Cannabis
Growers who are growing completely legal
h
suddenly went hot and they only had hemp
license so they had to lose my comment
about like you have to they have to
drive their car several car car hoods in
advance well a tree just jumped out in
front of them so uh we're developing
Technologies to specifically make it to
where um they can lessen their risk of
it going uh out of control just from um
just from environmental stressors wow um
yeah so to you know developing those um
when I get permission to I'd love to
show you the curves that we're that
we're getting in our results they're
very they're very smexy uh it's it's
very very very nice plots and Excel
spreadsheets um so is actually
environmental factors sort of messed
with the cannabinoid
ratios oh yes oh very much so yes canabo
ratios are a defense strategy for the
plant and the plant will try to defend
itself versus environmental stressers
just as much as it will defend itself
from versus
um uh versus like chewing damage or you
know various other predatory damage so
yes very much so um so working on
something to make it to where they can
future proof their uh their crops versus
you know these environmental threats um
and there's also not cannabis related um
but it's tissue culture related there
are certain um companies that produce um
I I'm pretty sure you've heard the term
superfood you know what I'm talking
about with that it's it's a it's a food
that happens to have like a massive
amount of something like a vitamin C or
something um so we're working um with
some people with some
plants um to make their Elite um
varieties more Elite like more
concentrated so that they can go hey
look here um um we're producing um I'm
going to say we're producing a
tangerine um that has like more vitamin
C than you could ever imagine um editors
not we're not working with t um but like
using that as an example so like that's
some of the ongoing work that we have
excellent so and then finally uh I know
you already shared a few great resources
that folks can um look at or or read
about to learn more about this topic um
hope you you can include um other ones
you can mention them here send me in an
email I'll put them in the show
description and then lastly um if people
want to learn more about you the work
that you're doing or me perhaps get in
touch with you please plug away any
website social media anything that you
use to to connect with folks uh so um so
first let's go with the
citations um so
for um if they're wanting to more learn
more about cryopreservation
techniques um I'm going to pull up here
are two um articles one is in nature and
the other one is in plants um those go
into detail about cryo
preservation um specifically
also um you can also for understanding
how um tissue culture is used to deal
with viral threats
um here is here are two articles that
they can go into a deeper dive uh Under
Siege the virus control and plant M
stems and progyny and the elimination of
hot lat vroid from hot plants by Cold
treatment those go with um several uh
the the techniques and the explanation
of how to do
that um so those are some more U primary
literature
sources uh me and if you want to contact
me um there is our company has um a
website Greenway lab.
um we have a contact us there um there's
also uh you have my professional email
uh that'll go directly to my office so I
can be contacted there um both of those
if you are interested in say for
instance discussing say like hey look we
would like to do some tissue culture or
hey look we're interested in maybe doing
building a tissue culture facility and
expanding in an area or hey hey can we
talk about you know
preserving um we can be reached out um
that way um either through Greenway lab
Co um which um if you if you don't have
it after we're done I'll I'll give you
I'll give you the
link um so you you put in the show notes
Perfect all right
so I think we covered everything yeah I
think we did I think it was a great
conversation I really appreciate you
doing it Shannon and I look forward to
seeing you down in Florida for K4
looking forward to it I appreciate it
and it was a pleasure um and again like
anytime you want to anytime you want to
hit up and just nerd out about plants or
have some questions feel free to reach
out excellent uh that's one that's the
one thing about uh plant scientists
um if you're like hey what's this um we
we'll have a drive it's like if we don't
know we'll will'll be like I don't know
I must find out and it's like here let
me share you with this so yeah feel free
to reach
out excellent all right we'll see you
soon
[Music]