hello everybody and good afternoon
first of all I would like to thank the
organizers for inviting me to give this
talk and to share with you some of the
activity that we do in my lab
in this work
we are collaborating
with Michelle and Bruce Kendall
and this work
is the vision and Legacy of a very
unique lady
both
please
[Applause]
in early 2016 at just the age of 43
Michelle was diagnosed with Advanced
stage ovarian cancer
she went through
conventional treatment and entered into
a you know
altering sequences of remission and
recurrence
in 2018 she stumbled across the then
emerging literature on cannabis as a
potential treatment for cancers
and quickly got to the point of
realizing that
the responses of cancers to cannabinoids
was specific to every Cancer so she came
to the question what do I need to take
to secure my cancer and ovary and cancer
at this point and some of you may
remember her from can Med 2019 when she
was here with this glittery hat
um with a with a videographer in tow
handing out bumper stickers and asking
everyone that she could could could find
who's working on ovarian cancer
um and the answer what she got was
nobody
well so the film she did make her film
um and it was ready to go on to the film
festival circuit
um in March of 2020 and of course that
all got canceled
um
and then uh she turned and together we
we turned and decided that it was going
to be up to us to find the research that
uh that that might cure her disease
um
so at that point we um she she made
contact with with Hannah neet
um and we entered into an agreement
where we would we would fund the
research
um in in each lab to look at the
pre-clinical
um studies of cannabis on ovarian cancer
both with the hope of helping saving
Michelle's life but also looking for a
cure to this terrible disease which has
a very high mortality rate because it's
almost always diagnosed to be on stages
um
this is the hard part
the
we had you know the internet went to
work very fast and we got some really
promising early results but by the time
we could turn those results into a
formulation that Michelle could use
um she had already progressed to organ
failure and it was just too late
um for this to save her life
but before she died in September of 2021
three yeah 2021.
um
she asked both of us to promise to keep
pushing this work forward in the hopes
that we might find a cure for
all the other
um
all the other women who are afflicted
with this disease so
in a neat
um
you know Nate and I are carrying this on
I'm is really mostly hiranit who is
doing the work but I'm so happy
that she's my partner in this
thank you
[Applause]
thank you both it's not easy to continue
after your your words
Okay so we are
we all cannabis and we know that
cannabis produces hundreds of different
compounds
and that we are usually
not sure what compounds are a really
important and more more than that what
is the the preferred composition or the
best composition to confer the Entourage
effect that Dr Russo was talking about
and this is especially in light of the
of the of the variety of of different
strains can be strains that contains
different compounds
in my lab we ask what is the best
composition of active compounds for the
optimized treatment of each medical
condition
and to answer that in my lab what we do
is we extract canopies from different
strains
um
we separate the extracts to fractions
and by that we are able
to to simplify in a way the chemical
composition
and to ask the question
what compounds and what composition of
compounds are working based on
biological essays
of iron cancer indeed is a the second
most common and the most liver
gynecology
malignancy in the western world and and
very few women survive five years after
diagnosis there is only little little is
known about the activity of cannabis
against the vine cancer definitely the
active compounds were not identified
before we started our work
so first of all we do
the four different strains in order to
find the best ones that are mostly
active against ovarian cancer cells we
looked for self-viability of ovarian
cancer cells of of several cell lines
and we were able to identify one of the
strains in this case it is DQ
which is a high THC strain and we found
that this strain is a highly active in
comparison to others then we
fractionated
the extract and were able to find and to
identify the actual fractions
that are highly active
following chemical analysis we were able
to determine the API the formulation
that is highly active in terms of
cytotoxic activity against of iron
cancer cells and the formulation
contained a mostly THC some CBC and just
a little bit of CBG
in order to prove that indeed this is
the active composition what we did is
with then a used purified
phytocannabinoids to a to a a in this
composition in this ratio in order to
prove that indeed this composition is
the active one and indeed once we used
phytocannabinoids only and remember this
is originated from a fraction which
contains many more compounds rather than
only this but yet when we re-established
this composition using purified
phytocurabenoids then activity was
gained as much as in diffraction so this
led us to the understanding that the
actual active compounds are these ones
in in this certain ratios
a following we have determined using
antagonists and inverse agonists and
blockers we determined receptors that
many mediate a cannabis activity a F7
diffraction and also the standard mix SM
and we found that the CB2 is mostly
involved and there was some evidences
for trpv2 as well
however it is most reasonable that that
to treat patients we provide cancer the
treatment will not rely on cannabis only
but rather cannabis will be a will be
used as a core treatment with another
um a chemotherapy and indeed we have
examined the activity of cannabis of
diffraction and then the standard mix
with a different chemotherapies we found
a a Synergy with some of them
um
and in this talk today I will focus on
the pop one inhibitor near parib near a
parib is the second line of treatment of
ovarian cancer patients
what we could find is that the actual
diffraction
diffraction and not the standard mix but
the fraction itself from the plant
led to Synergy with near a parib so what
we see here is sensitization of ovarian
cancer cells
to the papuan inhibitory
then
we wanted to examine the activity of the
combination of diffraction in the upper
rib against normal cells
we were able to show that this
combination was 50 times more active on
cancer cells than on normal cells these
workers
in this case
and then we have
we were able to show that the
combination of cannabis fraction and
nervative
was indeed active more venerative only
on Michelle's cells
cells were isolated from Shell tumor and
were shifted to Israel to my lab and
indeed you can see the result
we've conducted in Vivo study and
conducting additional ones already in
the first experiment there was an
advantage for the use of cannabis with
Nila parib avastin was added in this
case
um
versus a treatment with
neapolitanavastin only
and and then we wanted to get deeper and
to better understand the mode of action
of cannabis and era parib against
ovarian cancer in Vito
first of all we showed that the activity
is a conveyed via apoptosis
and not necrosis or other form of cell
death but travel indeed there is an
induction of apoptosis by the especially
by the combination of Nera parib and the
Cannabis fraction
foreign
we have looked at the wind pathway the
wind pathway is deeply associated with
cancer in general and ovarian cancer in
particular
a cannabis the the combination of F7 of
cannabis fraction in your parib led to
reduction to significant reduction in
some of the components of the wind
pathway including the receptor which the
frizzled receptor FC in the in the
drawing here which is a essential for a
activation of the wind pathway so
cannabis by its own by the way and the
combination of cannabis
reduced significantly the expression of
the receptor and additional components
we've also
um showed that the combination of a
cannabis and neuroparib F7 in Europe
lead to relocation of proteins beta
Catalina in this case Again part of the
wind pathway relocation to the cell
membrane
this this and others are very important
features of their mesenchymal to
epithelial a transition
phenotype cells are those that are
related and responsible to metastasis
and Visa usually resistant to
chemotherapy
once these cells were treated with F7
and Europa rib
the mesenchymal features changed to
epithelial features and this is
associated usually with cells that do
not are not metastizing and are not
resistant
usually
so
indeed we suggested that cannabis
treatment of February and cancer cells
reduce the proportion of Amazon cell an
increased proportion of octotic cells
and this is by altering the wind pathway
and this is all published it was
published last year in molecules
but following we wanted to go even
deeper into the mode of action of F7 and
era parib and to do that what we did is
we sequenced a cells from two cell lines
of ovarian cancer that were treated with
the combination of F7 and near parib we
found hundreds of different
genes and several dozens of genetic
Pathways that were significantly altered
by
the F7 plus neuroparib treatment in both
cell lines
these
these biological and signaling Pathways
that were altered
suggested
some features of activity of F7 and
Europa rib that were verified and are
still being verified in an ongoing
research and these included for example
a inhibition of cell migration and
differences in cytoskeletons
acting rearrangement
and led to a better and more
comprehensive understanding of the
activity of F7 and Nira parib and the
basis of the synergy and the ability of
cannabis to synthesize cells to
chemotherapy PowerPoint inhibitor in
this case
so if I summarize in few words
we have started with many different
compounds many different strains and the
inability to to determine what compounds
are active in one com what compositions
are the optimal ones doing using
different bio essays chemical analysis
we were able to get the formulation of
API and get deeper into the targets and
mode of action
um this this of course have to go
through toxicity studies and additional
in Vivo
to a to determine a a the actual
activity
and the ability
to go into clinical trials and and of
course only successful clinical trials
will prove
and then if the actual formulations that
were identified might serve as a base
for chemovas of cannabis that will be
optimal for treatment of this and other
diseases
so the information on the API
formulation
may be translated and I hope it will be
translated in the future not just into
new cannabis based products that will be
specific and a pharmaceutical grades but
travel this information would serve as a
base
for breeding for new cannabis a chemovas
with a certain activities
and with that I would like to thank
my team
in the lab and especially Norwich
which is with us today and she is
leading This research in my lab
thank you
[Applause]
do we have time for a question that was
really interesting
it blows my mind that this specific set
of cannabinoids in this ratio is
suddenly so active
um how specific is it or how how have
you have you ever tested the tolerance
of these kinds of specific ratios to see
how close you have to get
absolutely absolutely uh what we did and
I indeed I did not show that yeah but
what we did is we determined the range
of of a of a ratios that we need to use
in order to start to to to have Synergy
so definitely what I showed you is just
an example rather and it's in estimate
so you can understand that free quarters
should be THC and a quarter should be
and so on CBC and so however we
carefully determined the boundaries of
synergy
and by that using these four components
we could draw the Synergy in terms of
activity and a a between between the
four cannabis compounds but also with
neuroparib
okay so yeah
thank you