[Music]
welcome to the cam Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
ameral I'm the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and proud member of
the team that puts on on the caned
conference you may have heard but
aspergillis has been in the news quite a
bit as of late and many in the industry
are questioning whether it's appropriate
or necessary to test inhaled cannabis
products for pathogenic asilis full
disclosure we at medicinal genomics sell
qpcr testing kits designed to detect
pathogenic aspil on cannabis products we
have also published several resources on
our website that that describe the
potential harms that can be caused by
inhaling pathogenic
asparagus and we cite more than two
dozen asilis cases in cannabis
users we have also recommended that
states that are considering Cannabis
Testing regulations adopt pathogenic
aspergillis testing not because we sell
aspergillis kits but because we want to
protect
patients by almost any measure cannabis
is one of the most safe and effective
medic medicin available and in many
cases the potential harms that come from
using cannabis are not caused by the
plant but rather
contaminants and although cases are rare
the documented cases describing
aspergillosis deaths from contaminated
cannabis vastly outnumber the published
clinical risks of any other contaminant
for which cannabis industry tests there
are no documented deaths for cannabis
derived heavy metal
mot toxins pesticides or incorrect
cannabinoid labeling the same cannot be
said for asilis so that is our position
but of course we acknowledge that we are
biased and we are not experts on
pathogenic fungi however our guest today
is Dr David Denning is a professor of
infectious diseases in global Health at
the University of Manchester he was the
founding president executive director
and chief executive of global action for
fungal infections an organization
dedicated to reducing the worldwide
burden of fungal diseases in 2016 he
became the director of the national
aspergillosis Center in Manchester which
treats patients with chronic pulmonary
aspergillosis and he also led the
committee that developed the first CPA
guidelines he chairs the editorial board
of a website which focuses on
aspergillis and he leads an organization
which provides education on fungal
diseases in short Dr Denning is one of
the leading authorities on all things
aspergillis and we asked him many of the
questions that have been debated on
social media recently those include
should cannabis be tested for pathogenic
aspergilus should there be an allowable
limit for pathogenic aspir gilis is
aspergillosis this only a concern for
immunal compromised patients are the
number of aspergillosis cases under
reported how difficult is aspergillosis
to diagnose and treat how ubiquitous is
aspergilus in the air we breathe and
much
more before we get to my conversation
with Dr Danning I'd like to thank this
episode sponsor modern Cana modern Cana
is regarded as Florida's first medical
cannabis Laboratory and one of the most
trusted third party Laboratories in the
United States the company's mission is
to help set the standard for Cannabis
Testing Labs worldwide by providing the
most accurate and efficient testing
services delivered with a sense of
compassion integrity and moral
obligation and to attract and attain
clients who value quality data that is
verifiable reproducible and legally
defensible modern Cana is the only
Leafly certified laboratory in the
eastern United States and aderes to the
industry's strictest Sops and quality
standard controls modern Cana offers a
wide variety of testing rapid turnaround
times and consulting services to the
Florida medical marijuana treatment
centers and hemp businesses throughout
the US learn more at
modern.com
okay without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr David
Denning
[Music]
good morning Dr Denning thanks so much
for joining us on the
podcast good morning it's it's a
pleasure to be here right well I'm I'm
excited to talk with you today um as
some of our audience may know
aspergillis has been a bit of a Hot
Topic in the cannabis space recently
most notably growers in Oregon recently
petitioned the state to Halt aspila
testing on cannabis products arguing
that the testing was unnecessary
unnecessary and negatively infecting
their business we at medicinal genomics
disagree but of course we also
acknowledge that we may be a bit biased
which is why I reached out to Dr Denning
to come on the podcast and discuss the
topic so to get started Dr Denning why
don't you tell the audience a bit about
yourself and your experience studying
asilis and
aspergillosis great um well my
background is in clinical infectious
diseases I trained as a physician in the
UK uh did some postgraduate training in
the UK and then spent three years at
Stanford uh doing further training in
infectious diseases and microbiology and
have been working in Manchester for over
30 years since that
time um to my research work and a lot of
my clinical work has been on patients
with fungal diseases and my area of
focus has been on aspergilus and
aspergillosis infections and for about
10 years up until about three years ago
I led the UK's National aspergillosis
Center and we received patients about
300 patients a year from all over the UK
with difficult complex ASP cases uh and
and disease
problems
great so what is it about Aspirus why
did you choose to focus on
that it's a very remarkable organism
aspis because um while it's present all
over the world and in almost every
breath of air that you breathe in there
are certain species that cause disease
and not most of them don't and there are
also um different types of disase disas
caused by the same organisms so for
example if you have leukemia and you
have a ASP regillus in your lungs or you
breathe in a substantial amount of
Aspirus then you can get what's called
invasive
aspergillosis and that is usually a
fatal disease if it's not diagnosed and
treated
correctly and because it's a fungus it
doesn't respond to standard antibiotics
it's important to use antifungal drugs
um other patients at risk for invasive
aspergillosis patients who've had a
transplant patients with severe flu who
are on ICU patients with severe coid on
ICU and people taking
steroids um so any imun compromised
group of patients really are at risk uh
and at different levels of risk um so
the the other groups of patients that
get aspergillosis infections are people
with severe asthma um and aspergillis
and a few other fungi as well make
asthma
worse so your symptom control is worse
you're more likely to get exacerbations
more likely to end up in the ER uh if
you're exposed to fungus and and that's
a problem so it doesn't affect the those
with just very mild asthma that
occasionally need to use their blue
inhaler you know once a week or what
twice once or twice a day it's the
patients on steroid inhalers who have
had problems with their asthma over the
years that's the group that are at risk
and then the third group of of patients
at risk of those with chronic chest
problems uh typically patients with COPD
or people with sosis or people who've
had TB in the past and those with
bronchiectasis there's a whole list of
long-term chest complications and those
patients can get um worse if exposed to
vasp and it can also cause a very
chronic difficult to treat
infection um that the name for that
infection is chronic pulmonary
aspergillosis or CPA and that was what
we specialized in in in Manchester um
but it it occurs all over the world we
just tried to do an estimate of how many
such patients there are in India and we
think there's about one and a half
million people in India with this
condition so it's not it's not very rare
um it's sort of uncommon I think would
be better to say so so just to summarize
you've got three different types you've
got invasive which is imun compromised
or Critical Care you've got chronic in
these patients with chest disease and
you've got allergic which is related to
severe asthma and occasionally cystic
fibrosis as well interesting and
so I'm sure it depends but typically how
are these patients becoming exposed to
the Aspirus in order to this infection
so on a normal um standard day poshing
about one's home maybe going to work and
in an ordinary office or uh school
classroom or you know retail um uh
venue we would typically breathe in
between 100 and 2,000 spores of Aspirus
every day that would be a typical
number
and unless you have a very severe IM
immune problems our um normal immune
system
will attach the itself to those spores
and kill them pretty
quickly you get some cycling so they
take some time to kill and not all of
them are killed every day but they can
persist for some
time um and so that's the normal what
what is a concern is is when you're
exposed to many many more Sports than
that so for example if you were to um
dig out your compost heap and spread the
compost on the garden um or you have
bark chippings that you're spreading on
on the garden which have come and
they're a little damp and it's been a
bit and warm and damp you may be exposed
to many millions of
spores and those spores can set up
infection for the very first first time
um and cause an overwhelming infection
in the lungs which can lead actually to
like a pneumonia and if that's not
diagnosed then it usually isn't
because you know you when you arrive in
the ER or the doctor's office of
pneumonia the assumption is that it's
bacterial or it might be viral but
rarely do people think about it being
fungal um so a big big Spore exposure
causes disease in normal people but
particularly in people who've got
chronic chest disease or are imuno
compromised interesting and
now so we are exposed to aspir Gillis
throughout our day and for the most part
our immune system can handle
it is there a scenario where you could
be exposed to a good amount of asparagus
that your immune system does clear but
sort of in the interim you are
experiencing some system some symptoms
whether it be a istent cough or you know
something that you might otherwise
attribute to like you said before um a
virus or something like that is that
reasonable to assum yes so some people
will get a
temporary problem I remember a husband
wife pair who bought a new house and it
before they got into it it got very very
damp and the wallpaper that was there
was moldy and they stripped it all off
in two days both of them ended up in
hospital for several days and um and
there was just fungus everywhere and it
wasn't just aspell probably it was loads
of fungi I think so you can get that and
they both recovered one of them went on
to get some long-term chronic problems
in the chest the other one fully
recovered um so your scenario that you
paint is is possible um but of course it
carries some risk because of the
uncertainty about making a diagnosis
treatment and actually the labeling of
the disease is actually quite difficult
in that context as
well right and that's and that's a great
Point too in in reviewing some of the
materials that that you've produced and
some of the videos that it does seem
that there is a difficulty in
identifying diagnosing and even tracking
cases of aspergillosis is that fair to
say yes that's true so there's lots of
reasons for that the first is that not
everybody produces some fleem or sputum
to send to the lab the second is that
the lab doesn't usually do a fungal
culture unless it's
requested fungal cultures are only about
30% sensitive so they miss 70% of
patients and so we supplement that with
antigen testing which really only works
in leukemia or if you do a
bronchoscopy and in the patients with
chronic disease or Allergic Disease
there's antibody testing so you can do
do an IGG antibody or if you have a
largic disease IG antibody and they are
helpfully positive but they're not
perfect tests because they're not
perfectly sensitive and perfectly
specific so there are difficulties and
then of course there's Imaging so you
can have an x-ray or a CT scan on the
chest and that can show abnor and will
show abnormalities in in patients with
aspergillosis but again they may not be
very specific frasers they may represent
other things they sometimes The Chronic
ones look just like TB for example so
this disease is often mistaken for TB um
and in Allergic Disease it's more an
Airways infection so there's not very
much on the x-rays it's more an Airways
infection that's causing the in the
disease so the diagnosis is tricky and
across the world uh possibly only a
third of patients are actually diag
noosed I mean I don't know the precise
figure because it's a bit unknowable how
do you know how many are not diagnosed
right so but it it probably it's you
know somewhere between 20 and 40% are
only are diagnosed across the world of
all the different types of
aspergillosis now is it also difficult
to sort of mine the data that is
produced from from the hospitals or for
the from the healthcare providers like
is there a difference in how it is sort
of coded or tracked that makes things
difficult as
well so one part of that is that most
coding only occurs if you end up in
hospital and stay a night in
hospital most of coding doesn't occur
for out patients so a bad asthma attack
which is handled in the doctor's office
with of course of steroids and
antibiotics and so on may not get coded
at all for example so so that's one part
of the Gap in coding it's not completely
true because some of the Kaiser units
and some of the other units do document
everything but many only document in
patients that's one problem and secondly
because of the difficulty in diagnosis a
lot of the cases don't actually um uh
hit the radar as it were because they're
just not they're
missed and then because many of these
patients have other problems as well for
example if you have bad COPD related to
smoking or uh occupational exposure and
you end up in hospital with an
exacerbation and you're unwell it all be
down to the COPD in the accuration and
aspis will be down at the bottom end of
the corner if it's mentioned at
all and whereas that might have been and
often is the driver for that
exacerbation um so there are lots of
reasons why coding isn't perfect and
you're quite right to point it
out okay and now forgive me if this puts
you a bit on the spot but so one of the
main arguments that the Oregon cannabis
Growers have used to resist ASP regillus
testing is that the state was not able
to produce a case of aspergillosis
caused by contaminated cannabis now
given what you know about the difficulty
of tracking diagnosing
aspergilus um is that necessarily a
surprise to you and is it reasonable to
assume that there could be unreported
cases yes it's reasonable to assume
they're unreported
cases and it's not a surprise to me
because most doctors wouldn't report an
exposure like that
also because it's not the only place you
get exposure to absolutely pin it on a
joint that you spoke three weeks ago or
two weeks ago or even yesterday is not
always obvious so to the cause and
effect piece so if you can imagine
writing a an article for a newspaper and
trying to make that cake
the editor is probably going to say well
we just don't believe it you know
because we there's lots of other ways
you can catch it so the cause and effect
is difficult to prove as well in in many
instances so the cautions
about uh smoking cannabis um should
probably relate to people who have
anything wrong with their chest or any
immune
dysfunction so the majority of people
probably isn't going to affect them
that's the reality of it unless you
smoke quite excessively large amounts or
it's incredibly moldy weed so some of a
bit like these houses that we you know
people talk about black molding houses
and all that you know if it's super
moldy that's not a good idea um but if
it's just a standard bit of weed and
you're completely healthy and you have a
joint or two joints or something
probably that risk is pretty low it's
not zero actually it's you know because
there's no nothing in life that's zero
risk but it's a low risk um however
there are a lot of people out there
who've got
cancer semic cured but their immune
systems are not right got bad chests
asthma very common in many many groups
um and people with undiagnosed things so
there are some genetic disorders which
lead to
aspergillosis and one of the first cases
reported linked to cannabis was unveiled
that that genetic disorder this young
lad wasn't able to fight off asilis
smoked a joint and ended up with a new
diagnosis of a genetic disorder showing
that he couldn't handle aspila so so
there are risks even in apparently
normal people although they they're
small as I as I point
out probably the big deal here is two
things one of them is it's that
fumigatus aspir fumigatus is the most
pathogenic of them so other species of
aspas are less important flavors is
somewhat important niga somewhat
important possibly terus but there's
about 300 other species out there then
they're very very very rarely caus toas
so it's fumigator is the Big Driver for
this that's the first thing to to say
but of course if you're looking at a a
cigarette or a bit of weed or something
you're not going to know whether what
the species of fungus on there is
uh and so knowing that is probably is
helpful and the second is the is the
amount so and many people smoke without
a filter so you get uh the spores um may
be drawn in so the end of the cigarette
is hot where you've lit it but the rest
of the cigarette is not so hot and the
spores of aspir fumigators is incredibly
heat resistant so it can survive up to
70 degrees
C um
and uh and grows up to about 50 degrees
so it isn't going to be healed by the
passage of hot smoke coming down the
cigarette and and if there are spes in
the rest of the cigarette then those
will get
inhaled
um but it's about quantity so if in that
cigarette there's 10 spores or 500
spores of ASP that's probably not going
to be very serious but if there's 10,000
spores or 100,000 spores and there might
easily be if that mold is if the if the
marijuana is wet or damp um then that's
a big that's a big dose um and if you
only take one if you share a um um a
joint with somebody and you only take
one um breath in with it that's going to
be lower risk than if you you know you
make a big big joint and you have three
of them so so there's a quantity effect
here as well as uh so the species is a
quantity and and the quality of the
actual Mo the of the of the weed that's
being
smoked no and that's that's actually a
very interesting point because the
regulations in Oregon and in a lot of
States as well the limit is one cfu per
gram so essentially what they're looking
for is that one gram of the Cannabis
batch should be completely devoid of any
pathogen
aspil the ones you named flavis fumatus
terus Niger um so with that in mind is
that
an is that an overly conservative amount
should there be a higher allowable limit
in your opinion yes I I think that is
too stringent for this problem because I
don't know how much joint ways you can
tell me but you know if it's 60 gr or 50
grams or something like that that's only
five fif you know 50 spores that's a
very low number of spores so I think it
would be okay to do two things one of
them is to raise that limit so maybe
it's 20 spores per gram or 10 spores per
gram somewhere in that range so quite a
lot higher than one gram and secondly to
put a warning on about not smoking if
you have any imuno compromising effects
if you have asthma or you have chest
disease
um and if if those two things probably
would mean that the the number of people
who would get ill from aspose would be
very very very small
indeed um I do want to quickly come back
to the the issue of imuno compromised um
because I think you know we had talked
about cancer patients and folks with
sort of chronic disease um they they are
certainly imuno compromised but there is
some literature talking about that you
know even if you have influenza or
perhaps coid 19 you could be quote
unquote imuno compromised and therefore
maybe more susceptible to an infection
from aspergilus is that is that correct
that's correct so those two viruses and
there's another one in um Korea and
China which greatly increase the risk of
getting life-threatening invasive
asilos so in the coid uh outbreak this
was really well demonstrated so that if
you ended up in intensive care with your
coid you you know very breathless on
oxygen possibly the tube down um the if
you had asilis as well and somewhere
between five and 20% of people got
aspergillosis as well uh so it's quite a
lot of people um your risk of uh
surviving was hared it it Asis doubles
your risk of dying and that's true for
influenza as well um there is a slight
difference between them because the risk
of getting aspergillosis with influenza
is as you go into ICU it seems to be
very very early in the process and so
influenza is definitely
altering the um the way that the body
responds to the fungus and it just can't
get rid of it if you have influenza so
that would be another warning on the
pack is if you have a viral infection do
not smoke that would be a very helpful
piece that could be added um with coid
it seems to be a bit later in ICU so
people who get it tend to be have been
in ICU for a week or so before they get
aspergillosis and that's probably partly
because they're given steroids as part
of the treatment for coid and which is
helpful for the coid but unhelpful for
ASP regillus so ASP corticosteroids
knock out the immune system so you can't
respond and they make aspirers grow
faster so they have a double whammy um
steroids
and um and so so those you're quite
right to point those those things
out just as if there's a bit of
technical background there a very
careful study was done in seven
intensive care units in Belgium and
Holland over five years during Flu
seasons and the background rate of
aspergillosis in their normal ICU
patients coming through the door was one
in 20 was 5% so that was quite a high
rate um but if you had influenza it went
up to 19% so it was a four times higher
rate and it as I said doubled the
mortality so influenza and ASP are not a
good mix at
all interesting
so another thing too in talking about
the risk of aspergilus as it results to
cannabis um so first there there's the
users right who who are actually using
the product but then also the farmers as
well is something that that has come up
or or the trimmers or or the folks who
are sort of processing the actual plants
um risk for them as well as they're
doing that that they could be inhaling
sort of these large um amounts of of
bores if if it's not properly U dried
and and processed yes so there is a
definite risk that there is we know from
other occupations that um multiple
fungal exposures do lead to lung disease
um it's usually people are doing that
are fairly healthy before they start so
that's a good start um and not everybody
would get sick some people just don't
even seem to notice ASP just they get
rid of it fine so it isn't a a risk for
everybody but it is a risk for
some and so I think um there are a
couple of ways of handling that one of
them is ensuring that the plants are
dried as quickly as possible so that
there isn't very much dampness and if
there is a flood or there's damp gets
into the um Bales and it's a damp thing
they should probably just all be
discarded because there will be masses
of asps in in
those um and the second thing is that
you can wear masks there are N3 masks
which prevent infection with TB and
other things and they would also mostly
prevent infection with ASP gills the
problem is wearing a mask for hours on
end is pretty uncomfortable and a lot of
people end up you know they get all
sweaty behind them and and then they end
up moving it around their face because
it's uncomfortable and so it doesn't
work perfectly I think it's fair to say
but with with dry plants the risk is
much lower than it is with them
plants um so I guess more broadly here
what do you see as the major Rising risk
factor for aspergillosis again this
might be in general not necessarily
related to cannabis but what do you see
as the major Rising risk factor for
aspergillosis that researchers should be
examining so the
um the the area that's underdeveloped in
research terms and clinical terms is the
patients with
COPD uh who typically are between 50 and
75 years old they've usually been
smokers but not always um and they're
pretty breathless and the standard of
care for those patients is when you get
an exacerbation you're much more
breathless possibly related to a virus
or a bacterial infection or or or a
chemical exposure in some patients
they're given steroids and that those
steroids probably increase the risk of
as
asilos so we did an estimation two three
years ago now how many people probably
have aspil losis in the context of COPD
and it's in the millions it's a lot of
people across the world uh particularly
large group in China because they
there's a lot of smoking in China um but
it's true in other parts of the world as
well and I'm sure it's true in America
and it's quite a difficult diagnosis and
it's not always picked up and if the
patients aren't better then you give
more steroid and that's bad for this
entity so uh I think that's one area and
then the other thing that we're going to
see as patients with many complex multi-
diseases as you we get older we collect
diseases in general um and um so I think
the patients at risk in their 60 plus
who have diabetes who are on a bit of
steroid who have a bit of a bad chest a
bit of heart failure a bit of this a bit
of that those patients start to become
at risk as well and if they end up in
intensive care then that's the group the
5% group that get disease in intensive
care
basically well that's interesting well
and it's interesting too I guess in the
context of cannabis where the over 65
demographic is the fastest growing uh
user base for cannabis so um maybe
something to consider there
yes um and one thing I I do want to
Circle back to what we were saying about
the farmers and you know repeated
exposure to um to the fungus would that
also possibly apply to users like if
they are continually using a a product
that is contaminated with sort of low
levels lower LEL levels than we were
discussing earlier could sort of that
accumulate over time and be a
concern I think it's possible yes it
does depend how often it's used and how
much Aspirus is there the other there
are other things of course in cannabis
cigarettes it's not just aspergillis
there's cannaboids and other things and
they may have an effect on the lungs as
well uh we know that forar and tobacco
is example um and the other thing is
that many people smoke um cannabis
without a
filter and that has two things one of
them me needs more of that crud ends up
in your lungs compared with being
filtered out and it also means that the
smoke is much
hotter and we we we did see one man who
smoked like 20 joints a day I mean he
really you know he was was you know and
he's he basically destroyed his lungs
and he had ASP regillus as well but
probably it was the heat of the
cigarette of the of the joint that
actually did most of the
damage difficult to prove you know how
do you prove that not easy um but but I
suspect that there there other factors
so it isn't just ASP regillus that can
damage lungs it's these other things as
well right and the damaged lung is going
to be a more
the damaged lung is going to be a more
suitable or um a better habitat for the
as to sort of take hold so it may be a
self-perpetuating circle um in a
negative way that's correct
yeah all right so I guess so winding
down here is there one thing that you
wish sort of the general public
understood about aspergilus and
aspergillosis again this doesn't have to
necessarily even apply directly to
cannabis sure so I think patients who
have bad
chests um whether it's because of asthma
COPD or some other chest
disease when they get ill they should
ask the doctor and probably every doctor
they see is it a fungus in my
lungs
because it's very easy for doctors to
not think about it to not remember about
it and if there reminded then there are
special test that they can order and
they can actually get to the diagnosis
so and often it's thought about by Senor
very experienced doctors they think
about it but you don't always see one of
those doctors when you first arrive at
ER or in the thing and for a family
doctor asperos is a very rare disease
apparently because they wouldn't make a
diagnosis in Family Practice probably so
they won't think about it very often so
I think it's being aware o of it and
alert in doctors to it if you've got any
chest problems particularly ongoing
chronic chest
problems excellent and sorry this is
going to be a bit out of context so or
out of order so I might have to go and
and edit this but we did get a question
from uh someone that I wanted to make
sure that I asked you so cannabis
Farmers have expressed concern over the
use of fungicides to prevent asparagus
contamination um what could possibly be
the impact of using fungicide um
sorry what could the impact of fungicide
use be for ail resistant aspergillosis
in cannabis processing or or farmers and
could it possibly be a cannabis
farmers's lung in our
future so it's a so the issue of
spraying crops with fungicides is a very
important issue because there is a
bystander effect of of um emergence of
resistance to azol in ASP regillus so
the aspil fumigatus isn't really a crop
pathogen but it lives in the soil and
when it's warm and moist and there's um
degraded plant material it will grow and
so you spray the crops and something
like a third of all fungicides used are
azoles around the world and there's the
number of AOL being used in the US in
crops has gone up and up and up in
recent years
so what happens then is you get the
emergence of AOL resistance in fumigate
ASP
fumigatus and then people breathe in
azal resistant Aspirus and then they
don't respond to oral to the normal and
the best therapies the best treatments
for uh asilis are all azol and the only
oral treatments are
azol so if you have a resistant bug then
you may have to have IV therapy and have
it for long periods of time which is
very
uncomfortable the current rate of ail
resistance in the US in where it's been
measured is around
3% in Europe it's around uh between 15
and
20% and in Southeast Asia it's between
80 and
95% so we we are going to see probably
the loss of uh azol as treatment for
aspergillosis if we continue to spray
the crops with large amounts of of
AOL wow and if you don't have that
option as a
treatment you know what do you have you
you have intervenous drugs which are
less effective and obviously need
catheters and nurses to administer and
much more expensive and one of them is
much more toxic as well um so it it's
it's a big deal losing azol and it was
one of the issues we had in our national
Center because patients would develop
AOL resistance on aold therapy um
because we gave it for such a long time
because they had such difficult disease
and then we got really stuck we couldn't
really treat them properly so there are
new drugs in development but they
haven't arrived yet uh they're probably
about between one and three years away
in the US now are there better fungicide
treatments that don't use azol that well
yes there are lots of there are lots of
different ones actually there's around
20 that are used and they're often used
in mixtures and and sequential so you
have you know mixture a and then mixture
B and then mixture C and they're sprayed
at 10day intervals at certain points it
depends very much on the crop and and
how it's
done um but yes there are about a third
of the um fungicides that are used in uh
agriculture are um are not are asol and
two-thirds are not asol a lot of people
the term that's used of course in
colloquial language is pesticides but
it's actually fungi caused 90% of plant
diseases so it's actually fungicides the
biggest issue and then you've got some
weed so there's herbicides and the
pesticides are for the mosquitoes and
the and other um you know insects that
eat the crops um but fungicides are the
the major thing that is
sprayed excellent all right Dr Danning
um winding down here I did want to give
you an opportunity
to mention any other resources that
might be of interest to the Watchers and
listeners here if they want to learn
more about this topic and also I want to
give you an opportunity to plug any
websites or any anything else that you
would like to share with with the
audience so that they can get in touch
with you co so we do run um a website
called the aspas website which is ASP
gillis. org.uk and there's loads and
loads of materials on there including a
short section on um cannabis and um
aspil
Lois um we also run an educational
website primarily for healthc Care
Professionals called fungal
education.org which is in English and in
Spanish and that's got a lot of
videos um of about the dis dises and
diagnostic tests and small numbers on
radiology and anybody on antifungal
therapy on both of those websites
there's a link to drug interactions so
one of the problems with AOL and many
other drugs is that they interfere with
other drugs so you can look it up
there's a whole section for patients and
the normal and the public uh as well as
Healthcare professionals on on drug
interactions so those those may be
helpful for you
excellent I will put those in the show
description so people can check that out
so all right so I think we covered a lot
of ground here today and it seems like
we've arrived to somewhat of a
conclusion that there is a risk for
cannabis users maybe certain ones in
certain situations um fair to say and
that you know
testing is probably prudent but maybe we
need to rethink the uh the
limits yes I would agree with that and
and I think you know I don't I know
manufacturers don't like to put warnings
on cigarettes but um and their products
but I I do think um a general
information about um patients at risk
would be
helpful excellent well again Dr Denning
thank you so much for the time and um
good luck with everything good thanks a
lot all right all the best Take Care
thank you
bye
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Dr David Denny check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and thanks again
to this episode sponsor modern can of
Laboratories our next episode drops
November 1st that's 2 weeks from today
in the meantime head over to camed
events.com now to learn all about the
camed 24 Innovation and investment
Summit happening May 12th through 15th
at the Marriot Marco Island Resort in
Florida and book your package today cuz
registration is open we have assembled
an amazing Advisory Board and we are
currently accepting abstract submissions
for oral and poster presentations so if
you have some novel research you would
like to share please submit your
abstract today of course you should also
follow us on social media at camed
events and be sure to rate review And
subscribe to the podcast so you never
miss an episode all right that's it from
us stay safe stay healthy and be sure to
join us for the next CED Coffee
Talk
[Music]