my name's michael levinson i'm a trial
attorney i usually speak to about 12
people right in front of me
uh so i'm going to imagine that there
are 12 people right in front of me right
now or everybody can move to the middle
either way
how many doctors do we have here
how many lawyers do we have here
okay
reason i do that is because when i do a
trial i usually i know a little bit
about the jury before i start talking to
them
i had thought about different ways to do
this and i think what i finally decided
on
not i don't think what i finally decided
on i know what i finally decided on and
i'm going to get my timer started so i
know exactly how much time i'm taking
uh
is
in simple terms
uh everybody remember the glamour
magazine back in the i think it started
maybe in the 70s the 80s used to have
the glamour fashion do's
and the fashion don'ts
so there were glamour do's and don'ts
well we're going to touch on some of the
more important medical legal cannabis
do's and don'ts
there's your glamour magazine
so
when it comes to fashion a dew as an
example
is always considered basic black for
formal affair never go wrong wasn't it
was coco and chanel or someone who'd
invented the the little black dress and
it's never failed anybody in a formal
affair
that's a do
this is a don't
don't do whatever this is supposed to be
i have i couldn't figure it out between
my wife and my friends nobody knew what
this was but everybody knew it was a
don't
the basic considerations for a doctor if
you're going to be recommending medical
cannabis
it really depends on what state you're
in
uh california is very kind of loose
so in california excuse me there are
several
listed conditions by the way
of the doctors here who were in
california
okay how many no doc no california
doctors how many obviously everybody
else is from another state
well the first thing you really need to
do is you need to make sure that you
know the rules in your state because
they really do vary in california the
first medical marijuana state
the rule was
the the way that it was put into
existence was through a voter initiative
called the compassionate use act and it
listed several conditions aids glaucoma
et cetera et cetera or any condition for
which marijuana provides relief which
was pretty vague
other states is very strict okay and so
you have to very much know what your
state rules are or you can run into
trouble and that's the whole point of my
talk is so that you don't run into
trouble
what kind of history and exam is
required these are the questions you
need to think about if you're going to
be doing this
in california now
the medical board does not have specific
requirements but it does require or does
recommend strongly
that you get medical records at least
relating to the condition for which
cannabis use is being sought
so if somebody says that they i i'll
disclose that i have a little bit of
pulse rate of colitis right so when i
went to the doctor to get a
recommendation for cannabis they said
what's your condition i said i have
ulcerative colitis they said that's fine
have your gi doc send me some records
uh that's basic you really need to do
that and if you think that if you think
that i'm telling you that because people
already know that
uh there's a lot of doctors that maybe
know it but they aren't doing it and
they're running into trouble for that so
you don't want that kind of trouble
what kind of cannabis would work best
for your patient
um well
i mean that's what seminars like this
are for i can't certainly tell anybody
really about that i mean i've had enough
exposure to this industry for long
enough i probably have some pretty good
idea but
you come to seminars you communicate
with other doctors there's literature
but it's not all the same i mean
you know the time was you know when i
was first litigating cases of this kind
the whole you know marijuana it's all
just marijuana how could that help
anybody well that that ship is long
since sailed that it's a it's really a
designer drug and there's various kinds
uh excuse me that last speaker i had a
chance to speak with her before today i
mean they're literally and they're and
in the uh uh
you know exhibit hall where the
companies are you know selling their
wares they're selling genetic tests to
match
the patient to the drugs that they're
going to use and that's being done
already and some other kinds of medicine
and it will certainly be done in medical
cannabis
when it comes to quantities what very
and i say very general and the reason
for that is dosing dosing is like the
one of the biggest issues
and it's a tricky problem for doctors
both medically and legally and the
reason for that is because
you can't really prescribe it in the
same way that you do other medicines
because you don't really know when that
person you don't know when you write a
script for
50 milligrams of whatever it is and they
take it down to the pharmacy you know
what they're getting okay you know that
they're getting
the medicine that you've prescribed for
them you can't really know that when
they go down to a medical cannabis
dispensary you can have some idea a
pretty good idea now that they've honed
the medical
uh
production so you have six to one and
four to one and so on but you also don't
have the analytical data that you would
otherwise have it just doesn't exist so
you have to be
very careful about talking about dosing
and i'm going to probably say this two
or three times as i go along but one of
the things that you
for sure
want to be careful about saying is that
this is what i think you should do
it's better to say this is what i have
found through my patients or my
experience with my patients to have
worked for them
and that makes it which is if true is
really what you are saying anyway
but you need to be very careful about
how you word your medical orders or your
medical advice
will i ever have to go to court to back
this up well you know let's hope you
don't but you always have to be thinking
about that because you may need to go
into court somebody that you have
recommended cannabis to could get
arrested
or i've had this happen where i've had
to represent parents who had their
children taken away
because a doctor recommended cannabis
for their child the child was
smelled like it at school
the children were taken away luckily
they got to me we got the case beat
pretty fast
but that's not an experience that that
parent will soon forget and it was a
protract once we got them back into the
home pretty much right away it was about
a two months protracted legal battle
that cost some good deal of money and
uh you know untold amount of stress and
that's not you know something you want
to deal with
that that particular scenario will come
up a couple more times in my talk but
the gist of it is if you're going to say
something to a patient and recommend a
can a cannabis treatment to them
you should you have to keep in the back
your mind somebody may ask you about
this one day and you may want you may
need to show why you did this why you
did it the way that you did it how much
when who etcetera
uh well er well will i ever have to
justify my actions to the medical board
and let's hope not but you might
um in california currently in order to
recommend cannabis what you're supposed
to be
is you you are now required to consider
yourself the attending physician which
means you are taking primary care
primary responsibility for the patient's
care at least as it relates to their use
of medical cannabis
uh that doesn't mean you have to treat
them for everything it doesn't mean you
have to be on call for them 24 hours a
day it means
that you are responsible for their use
of cannabis and for being able to
explain to the medical board why for
example
uh
this schizophrenic patient that you
didn't get the records for
and didn't really inquire into then
wound up having all of these problems
because you didn't pay attention to the
fact that you probably shouldn't
recommend cannabis to a schizophrenic
uh that's a problem that three of my
clients have had before they got to me
so that's something you want to pay
attention to
okay that's something you want to pay
do remember we're doing the dues and the
don'ts this is a medical cannabis dude
do get sufficient medical records before
evaluating a patient you would think
that that would be just
you know der-riguer right nobody would
ever think about not doing that and you
would be wrong
uh you can now
very easily
this is well
you can walk into some dispensaries that
sell the cannabis in the state you can
do plink plink plink on an ipad that
they have in the front lobby and then
you will going back and they'll say did
you get approved and they'll go plink
plink plink and you will have been
approved you'll have never spoken to
anyone you'll have produced no medical
records you will have done nothing more
than show them your driver's license
okay
there's a word for that
illegal okay all of that
is illegal and it's being done now you
might ask well ha how do they do it how
do they get away with that if it's
illegal well you know i mean i drove
down here from the bay area
on late monday and i was going about 85
miles an hour i didn't get a ticket well
why you know just not enough cops to
catch everybody that's speeding and it's
sort of the same thing in this business
they just don't police it that tightly
and nobody really reports these things
the way that they should i suppose and
so that's what happens
excuse me
don't
don't tell your patient a list of
complaints that would qualify and tell
them to pick one
okay
i have had two doctors as patients who
did that excuse me as clients who did
that
somebody came into their office they
said you know i really don't
want to use i don't really you know have
a medical problem i just want to get an
excuse that i can use medical care or i
can use cannabis i can smoke marijuana
okay now that was before
uh prop 64 which made it a lot easier if
you're over 21
to use cannabis you can just buy it you
can possess it you don't have to have a
medical excuse for it
but
uh you can still run into this problem
with someone who's between the ages of
18 and 21 in this state and and in any
other state they still have to have a
genuinely qualifying condition right
well
what happened in these two cases
essentially somebody told the doctor
look i don't really have anything wrong
with me i just want to be able to use
cannabis and i said well look the doctor
said well look i can't
give you a recommendation unless you
tell me there so here here's the list
just point to one and we'll write it up
that way
now that doctor did that twice
and then the third time and the fourth
time and the fifth time that he did it
the people that he did it to were
undercover investigators for the
california medical board
and he was then brought before the board
very serious charges
they had this all recorded okay because
they were wearing a wire when they were
in his office
there were different people they were
very convincing they're very good at
this
and
he ran into some trouble he didn't
remain my client
throughout the entire process because he
was quite indignant about
the thing that he was frankly most
indignant about was the fact that they
had recorded him inside of his office
how could they do that this is a private
medical consultation
this is a violation of my rights and
their privacy and so on and so forth
and the only answer to that is yeah but
how else would they catch somebody doing
this without recording
excuse me he was this was a you know
basically
what my grandmother would have called me
suga and he just couldn't
get it and he wanted running into some
serious problems but the point being
don't do that or don't do anything
similar to that just find out what's
wrong with them if they can say and if
you feel that there's sufficient records
to support it and if you feel that it's
appropriate then you can recommend
cannabis
do start by recommending the least
amount necessary to relieve symptoms
correct correct me if i'm wrong is that
not
the basic medical rule for uh
prescribing medicine how much do i do
well if you're not sure the least amount
necessary with the least amount
necessary to relieve symptoms
start i guess i don't know whether it's
visible there start low
and go slow is what it's supposed to say
there and i think that is
that is generally the rule and
particularly when it comes to cannabis
because
again even if you know now if you can
know that you're recommending a four to
one or a six to one oil or something
like that
you don't know exactly how much they're
using it you don't know the regular
basis that they're using it on and
there's the i mean the overarching
scientific problems i guess with
recommending cannabis or the reason it
can't really be prescribed traditionally
is there are there far too many
variables to know
which of the variables is is at play in
changing the patient's condition either
to the positive or to the negative
because you don't know for sure which
one of the multiple variables in the
chemical itself let alone their
variables are affecting this so rather
than
the the simplest way to deal with that
problem is to just
titrate
small
increments and see what changes you get
and then
evaluate and that requires infinitely
more work than most of the doctors that
i know unfortunately and have dealt with
in this business
there are
some very very good ones and what they
do is they're in constant communication
with their patient emails telephone
calls it's a lot of work to do this
right and and it's not just a matter of
you know
taking the
money with the left hand and handing the
letter with the right hand and then
saying see you later which is what many
of these unfortunately many of these
businesses still do at least in this
state
okay don't don't use a pre-printed form
this particular doctor right was the
doctor for a client of mine
who got in trouble for how much he was
growing this is recent this is the kind
of thing that used to happen before prop
64 all the time and it's still happening
in a different way these are not
currently charged generally as crimes in
california this is a civil uh violation
with this gentleman as being excuse me
they're trying to get multiple thousands
of fines against him for how many plants
he grew but if you see at the top it
says he got a 99 plant recommendation
and he can it can have a certain amount
of weight okay that's a big big
don't you can't do that
because first off you're not an expert
in cultivation second you don't know
what strain is this person is growing
you don't know how large these plants
are et cetera et cetera there's so many
things that you simply cannot and do not
know
that you cannot write it that way not
there there's a whole
legal explanation for the 99 plant
letter which was sort of like the big
deal in the in the between about 2004
and about 2016.
uh excuse me that that was all
it's not worth the time to explain it
was all sort of this way to kind of do
this little dipsy do around federal law
and state law and medical cannabis
uh it doesn't never work
now the other problem this is this is a
don't i'm gonna give you a i guess a
double don't off of this one which is
that 99 plant recommendation that was a
pre-printed form when i asked the doctor
about it i said so why did you write a
recommendation for 99 plants and she
said i didn't write it we had two forms
there was the 50 plant one and the 99
plant one
the 50 plant one that's 145 bucks
the 99 plant one that's 245 bucks okay
now there's a word for that
what's the word illegal okay
very illegal you go to the doctor
i if i had some shoulder surgery a
couple years ago if i'd have gone to the
doctor see doc you know my it's a lot of
pain
can you get me something for it and he
says well listen i can get you the 25
milligram one week oxycontin
that's the hundred bucks but if you want
to go full bore you you want to really
roll with this thing you want the 50
milligram you want three weeks that's
250 okay there's a word for that
illegal very illegal and
this doctor when i spoke to her about
this was absolutely flabbergasted she
this is what she told me when i had and
this was recent this
that kind of thing right there that was
a little more common
10 years ago maybe right
i asked her i said you know we were
discussing this and i said well look you
know i mean you really i don't know if i
can use you as a witness because now you
have
a fifth amendment problem if you testify
to what you did there you'll be
admitting
if you your truthful testimony is the
admission of a crime okay i'm not saying
you're a criminal i'm just saying i
can't as a lawyer i have to advise you
about that you'll have to get counsel if
i'm going to call you as a witness she
said really everybody does this which is
all this is common practice in the
medical business in this state
and i was like well okay well you know
it's like what did your grandmother tell
you just because everybody else is
jumping off the brooklyn bridge you're
going to do it too right whatever
be prepared to back your recommendations
and opinions in court this is a do do be
prepared and by the way i just i had to
get a picture this is the doctor who
testified this
absolutely wonderful doctor who
testified in that police murder case in
minneapolis this is the pulmonologist
with that lil thing irish accent to
explain
what the police did and how it happened
and and if you ever want to learn how to
testify in court as a doctor i i advise
doctors about that too
excuse me just watch his youtube
testimony it is an absolute textbook i
mean it is a textbook and how to handle
it how to say it how to come across well
how to explain technical stuff well i
mean it's just genius it's it's
absolutely beautiful
don't
don't disappear or avoid your patients
when they have a legal issue
the client that i was telling you about
whose
children were taken away
the doctor that recommended cannabis to
her
for her daughter who was autistic was an
orthopedist who was moonlighting as a
medical cannabis doctor writing letters
for i don't know how much a pop i never
asked him that
it took me
for calls to just have him get on the
phone with me and explain what why he
did this and what he had done but
one of the reasons that this mom's
children were taken away was because the
child protective service when this was
going on before they took the children
away called him
four times
never picked up never responded to their
calls okay so they just figured out he's
a schlockmeister we're not going to do
it we're not going to worry about this
and so then they wrote
in their affidavit
for taking the children
the warrant that they got to take the
children they said that she had not
consulted with a medical professional
even though they had a written
copy of the recommendation letter they
assumed they just said later in court
they thought it was fake they didn't you
know the doctor never followed through
never called called them etc okay not to
mention excuse me just as a
as an aside this is the number one
complaint when it comes to lawyers
and doctors in that sense are probably
not terribly much just different in this
regard
the number one complaint for since i've
been practicing law every time i go to
one of the
continuing legal education
seminars how to not get in trouble with
your clients return their phone calls
return their emails be
responsive to them some of the some of
the clients that have liked me the best
and sent me the best referrals are not
necessarily the ones that get the best
outcomes
they're the ones that felt like i
cared about them you know that i
actually and i do care about them but
i'm saying you have to
respond to them so plea and even if it's
not just for a business from a business
standpoint your
patients can get in trouble and if they
don't get if somebody who's looking into
their status doesn't get through to the
doctor that can be a problem
do evaluate the patient's needs for
cannabis this one's a little bit
repetitive when i was putting this
together i was working with my son and
he was teaching me powerpoint and i
i tripped a couple of times but this is
about getting medical records that
should be the first question you ask
when someone calls can you send us
records i have a very good friend who's
a pretty prominent uh cannabis doctor
and the first question that their
uh uh
uh staff asks when somebody calls is
can you when can you send us or to the
effect of can you send us your records
and if they say they don't want to do
that they just say thank you we can't
help you
you get the records you look through
them
then you make the appointment then you
go from there
don't recommend specific amounts unless
it is required in your state which i'm
not aware that any state recommend
requires doctors to describe excuse me
to prescribe specific amounts of
cannabis but otherwise don't because you
can't really prescribe cannabis in the
same way you just can't do it there
isn't the analytical data there are too
many variables
and there are too many other there are
too many variables in the product that
may end up in the hands of your patient
so it's all about go start slow start
low
go slow
don't i'm going to shift gears a little
bit to driving this always comes up when
i give this talk or something similar to
this talk
about driving don't fail to advise your
patients on the effects of cannabis
combined with alcohol or prescription
drugs for driving okay don't do that
cannabis itself excuse me isn't
necessarily all that damaging when it
comes to driving in california excuse me
one has to be considered impaired not
just under the influence but impaired if
they're driving and there is a
difference
under the influence means that the
medication or drug is having its
intended effect
that is not necessarily impairment
um
the general uh let's see if i got this
in the right order
okay
the general the general uh admonition
that doctors and please correct me if
i've got this not quite right but this
has come up in my court cases the
general admonition the doctor is to give
a patient about driving is
with the exception of alcohol which has
a per se limit of blood alcohol
concentration that everyone agrees at
least legally speaking agrees is
unlawful to have in your blood when
driving
that's not true for cannabis it's
actually not true for any drug
in california for example it is unlawful
to drive under the influence of alcohol
any drug and that includes prescription
medications or the combined effects of
alcohol in any drug
so excuse me but when it comes to a drug
if it is having its intended effect you
are not presumed to be impaired okay the
the general way in which uh the courts
have now ruled the way in which to
determine whether someone is genuinely
impaired by a drug
is primarily by the way that they're
driving
and then if it
actually involves a police officer
called a drug recognition expert who has
to do this kind of complicated exam when
it comes to cannabis there are largely
only two
sobriety tests that are supposed to
really matter
one is lack of convergence
so presumably the doctors know what this
is right it's a as an object moves
toward
your eyes they're supposed to converge
and if they don't converge just right
that's evidence that you may have
cannabis on board
but i guess it's also the case that
something like 25 percent of the
population has lack of convergence
anyway
so it's maybe not all that conclusive
the other one is called the
slowed internal clock which means
that what they typically do is they have
you close your eyes and estimate when 30
seconds have passed
oh okay
close your eyes and have you estimate
when 30 seconds have passed if it takes
you too long then they can say that
cannabis may have may have caused that
it's consistent with cannabis use
do familiarize yourself with the laws of
your state your their state's many
doctors on the possession and use of
cannabis
don't
think that an hour or two of legal
consultation is too expensive
i'm not saying this for myself i i do
mostly criminal defense
i get i mean i've been around long
enough i get pretty good fees from
people that do really twisted stuff so i
don't need to worry about consulting
with doctors all that much
so this isn't some sort of advertisement
for me this is
for your own good just you know find a
good lawyer and wherever you practice
medicine
uh and just you know pay for a couple
hours of their time an hour to their
time to make sure that you're not you
know
bumping up against the law because the
law is an unfriendly cat
don't give legal advice to your patients
boy oh boy people i the doctors i know
that do this that i do consult with
they're constantly saying well what can
i tell my patient about the laws and
what what's legal for them to do
and the answer to that is
nothing
you have to refer them to a lawyer you
really can't give legal advice that's
excuse me that's a very dangerous game
to play
refer them to a lawyer you can if
there's published materials in your
state which there probably is certainly
refer them to that but do not give them
legal advice even if you think you know
you're right even if you think you know
you're right
do tell your patients what you have
found to be effective in your practice
for your patients
that's the best way to prescribe it or
to recommend it
is don't say this is what you should do
there's in california for example it's
extremely tricky because doctors are not
allowed to have any financial
relationship with any producer or
provider of cannabis
so you can certainly run into trouble if
you start going down that road so just
say this is what i have found my
patients have found to be effective
don't recommend specific amounts this is
one of those somewhat redundant ones
oops did i miss one
do understand the the difference between
hemp and marijuana the long explanation
is that the fda has not yet approved
or given its signature to hemp
for medicinal use and if you that's why
when you hear those ads on the radio for
it's legal in every state and it's the
greatest minimum what's that last
tagline this is not in this uh product
is not intended to diagnose treat or
cure
any medical condition okay
if you're if it is being advertised as a
medical product as a health related
medical product
then there's a word for that
illegal and the fda has not approved
this yet
they're not policing it because like
when i'm driving 85 they just don't feel
like it's something they're going to
expend that much and they feel that
eventually they will
and they're changing their rules but
right now they they haven't and
everybody knows that marijuana
is the plant with three percent of thc
uh delta nine et cetera et cetera and
there is a difference but that that farm
bill that everybody thought you know
just turned the world around in it
not yet and we're not there yet
do excuse me don't think that hemp is
legal to buy and sell as medicine i
think i've already covered that
do understand the difference between
clinical data and trial data clinical
data and i'll let a doctor correct me if
i'm wrong clinical data is your
experience with your patients
trial data is what pharmaceutical
companies produce through
double-blind studies which really
haven't been done with the exception of
a couple of medications that are
currently approved do realize that with
medical cannabis what you do is more art
than science i remember when i was a
little kid my pediatrician i remember
seeing this sign that said medical arts
building and when i got older i used to
take the bus by the building they
thought medical arts isn't medicine
science all right
well there's a lot of art to this
practice of medicine and if it's
particularly when it comes to cannabis
because the science is limited uh but
that doesn't mean that a good doctor
can't practice in this regard
uh but you have to
you know kind of get a feel for what
you're doing and have a feel for your
patients
do finally ultimately make what the the
ultimate standard the thing you'll have
to answer to for the medical board in
court whenever you have to ultimately
answer to it is what is
the standard of care
and the standard of care is nothing a
hundred percent set in stone it's what
an expert in your field would say it is
and what would be this uh agreed upon
standard of care
excuse me i think probably most people
know it most doctors know what it is
it's some intuitive level you get
records for people that you're going to
look into
you stay in contact with them you follow
up
you make sure that you don't over
recommend or over prescribe you don't
ignore your patients
i feel like i'm my grandmother telling
me what to do but that's what that's
what it is you know sometimes for myself
my standard is what would my grandmother
have said i should do and that's a
pretty good standard and it probably
works most of the time
you know it's common sense but it's it
it doesn't always you know in any
particular situation you just have to
take a step back what is the standard
what kind of what do i feel comfortable
with what would i want
someone to do for me what would i expect
others to do for me
so i made it 30 minutes
[Applause]
hi michael thank you sure um i'm uh i'm
not a doctor but i play one on tv
i'm also the host of a co-host of a
podcast with chella cannabis helps
dementia i think she spoke to you last
night about uh ryan's law brian's law
and rcfes and could you uh speak to
ryan's law in california and is it going
to help us get cannabis into rcfes or is
it specifically six months to live
hospice well there's six months to live
part i'm not it is hospice this is
i think it's one year actually is the uh
okay so
ryan's law is a law that says
essentially that the state passed a law
that says
that
hospice care hospice providers are now
required to allow the use of cannabis by
patients who are in hospice
i didn't look up the the time factor but
i believe it is
if they are terminal which means one
year uh predicted life
uh based on the current dog prognosis
the the provider is required to allow
the use of it and to create a protocol
for how it's to be used and distributed
the other big uh requirement is no no
inhalation of cannabis is allowed so no
smoking and no vaping interesting so it
has to be either be philosophy orally
consumed which means either an edible or
an oil right and and that that's it now
if someone's sick and in hospital
hospice care in california they almost
certainly have a primary caregiver which
is someone who cares for them that's the
person who's going to be buying it and
bringing it to them or finding it or
growing it and bringing it to them
that would have to be allowed they'd
have to have they'd have to allow a
primary caregiver to bring it out of the
premises
a primary caregiver is also someone who
administers it which is there's a whole
legal uh definition of administering it
but more than likely in this scenario
somebody's pretty sick it means putting
it on the spoon or and giving it to him
you know
uh the hospice personnel are are not
required to store it or administer it
but there are required to allow it
got it so i hope that's a pretty good
explanation yeah thank you sure
okay
[Applause]