well good morning everyone welcome back
thank you Ethan for a great opening
talk wait a moment for the slides to
come up
so this talk um which I alluded to uh
yesterday in some ways kind of came out
of this experience that I had and that
Bonnie also shared that she had and some
of the other clinicians that have been
doing this for a while where we started
our career mostly working career in
cannabis I should say mostly just
working with THC with our patients and
then after a few years Along Came
another option to work with CBD and we
could combine that with THC and then
another option came along you know we
discovered the acidic cannabinoids had
value we kind of added those in and then
CBG came along and now there's some thcv
and cbdv and I can imagine that for a
lot of people just coming into this
field it's a little over in because
there's a lot of options and many of
them have over overlapping therapeutic
effects therapeutic potential and you
see a certain patient with some symptoms
and you wonder well where the heck do I
start and so what I wanted to do with
this talk was just bring in some Basics
from the preclinical and clinical
literature to show you what happens when
we combine these cannabinoids I think we
all in this room are aware that their
combinations are often Superior to their
isolated usage but how do we how do we
do that how do we approach it and make
sense of it so and um and just for the
folks in the back yesterday I had like a
full screen down here it's not essential
but it's a little easier to see so in
the next 28 minutes what we'll go
through is just a little reminder like
yesterday about how complex this is
we'll talk about the major chemotypes
acidic versus
decarbox the the role of choar I'll just
mention that and then the types of
interactions and then on the right
column here we're going to go through
all of these combinations some very
quickly what I'm really going to
emphasize is the THC plus CBD one
because I think a lot of us bring a
limited understanding of what happens
when we combine these and so I want to
go into some of those nuances and give a
more complete picture of that so uh
yesterday I talked about this is a
multi-compound multi-targeted medicine
that interfaces with the ECS there's
incred ible complexity here and if you
have this tendency to want to be
reductionistic and to really understand
what's happening at what receptors you
know that might help in some cases but I
think what's more helpful is to kind of
zoom out and look at uh pattern
recognition and Trends and and what
we're seeing with our patients and also
in the
literature there are four main
chemotypes of cannabis this is just the
the nomenclature chemotype 1 is THC
dominant chemotype 2 has a relative
balance of THC and CBD three is CBD
dominant four CBG dominant there are
some thcv rich varieties of cannabis I
don't know that we have any that are
truly thcv dominant without you know the
very Trace levels of the others yet but
I'm sure that's coming and so this is
what I want to use as a framework for
thinking about when a patient comes in
to see me where am I going to start I'm
going to start with typ Al one of these
major chemotypes you know and then
within each one there's this question
about is it in the acidic or raw state
or is it decarbox which can be very
different in some
cases and um and then Within These
chemotypes of course there's different
chemo vars the different varieties that
can have very different properties you
know very distinct properties but the
way I see that in in a lot of cases most
most of the time is like the
old-fashioned radio where you have the
big tuning knob to kind of find the
station and then the little tuning knob
to do the fine tuning I consider the
chemotypes like the big tuning and the
the chemo vars uh the the finer tuning
to really dial it in to maximize the
benefits or minimize the adverse effects
and um I'm not going to talk a lot about
the chemo virus here even though some of
them are very special and there can be
highly selective responses um that's
also a hard thing to accomplish because
the naming is all over the place and the
consistency from one batch or one store
to the next is problematic so I I
encourage you to focus on the chemotypes
especially if you're getting started
here and even if you're not and then the
two main types of interactions that we
might be thinking about here are the
pharmacokinetic interactions which are
interactions having to do with
absorption metabolism excretion
distribution and the pharmacodynamics
having to do with their actual
physiologic
effects and so uh well I'll apologize in
advance it looks like the formatting got
a little messed up I did correct it this
morning but some of the slide some of
the images here are going to have a
clear background instead of a white one
and I apologize for that so here's an
example of a PK interaction this was a
really interesting uh rodent study where
they compared blood levels of canabo
administered in a full spectrum extract
with the same quantities of those canabo
but administered alone and they were
given orally to mice in a single
dose and so this is what it looks like
this full spectrum extract as you can
see here it had a little bit of just
about everything it was around half
decarbox or or somewhere in that range
there was CBD cbda THC thca and and um
cbdv a cbga and so they tested those six
isolated canids in the same quantity
against the full extract and what they
found here here's an example with CBD
and this this is kind of what you would
expect in the uh light uh colored uh
line here we have the purified CBD and
in the dark we have the same quantity of
CBD in the context of the extract and
you see there's much better absorption
with the purified CBD and and the
typical reason for that is that fat
soluble compounds when they're taken
orally at the same time they compete
with each other for some absorption you
see this with fat soluble vitamins and
and other compounds
but what they didn't expect was this so
here we have
cbda getting absorbed much better in the
context of the full extract than it did
in the isolated form it was 14 times
higher area under the curve so what the
heck was going on there why did cbda get
absorbed so much
better and uh the diligent researchers
this was uh Jonathan Arnold's group out
of Australia they ended up figuring out
that this happened to do this had to do
with an elux pump in the intestinal
border and so just to orient you I I'll
show it on on this slide here we have
the the uh Lum the Lumen of the
intestine would be here and here's the
blood supply and so when the canabo get
absorbed some of them are kicked back
into the Lumen through this efux pump
and what the researchers discovered was
that low amounts of CBG or THC would
inhibit that brcp elux pump prevent the
cbda from getting kicked back out and
therefore increase the absorption of
cbda now this was in rodents we don't
know if this is exactly the case in
humans but we do see very high levels of
cbda bioavailability when taken orally
in humans so there's a high likelihood
so this what would be the take-home from
this it might be that if you're using
cbda it would probably be helpful to
have a little THC or a little CB G with
it to maximize the potential for
absorption all right so that's an
example of a PK interaction now let's
move on to the the main topic here which
is THC and CBD and we'll start with kind
of where we're all coming from here's a
study of 177 patients with cancer pain
who are on opioids they were treated
either with nmols the THC CBD
combination or the same dose of THC or
or the same um
basically spray method of THC alone and
they were allowed to titrate up to
however many sprays was effective
without adverse effects and then looked
at the levels of pain it turned out that
the people who were receiving the THC
CBD combo they ended up using somewhat
more sprays not a lot but a little bit
more sprays per day on average and
that's likely because it was somewhat
better tolerated but then if you look at
the at the results here so this first
one is a a 10% or greater reduction in
pain and there's really no difference in
the proportion of people that achieve
that between THC or combination THC CBD
but this is more clinically relevant 30%
reduction in pain or greater and you can
see quite a big difference here much you
know about 40% more of the people in the
THC CBD group achiev that compared to
THC alone and the adverse effects in
both groups were similar because they
were allowed to titrate in the way that
wanted to and so the the idea here is
that uh THC was um causing some side
effects that limited the dose and CBD
was probably mitigating that while
adding some of its own benefits and that
that's kind of what we what we tend to
think about with t CBD you know add it
to THC you're going to mitigate the
adverse effects you're going to enhance
the benefits it makes perfect sense
let's put them together and I think that
a lot of times that's the case and it's
certainly the case with the severe
adverse effects this is showing toxic
psychosis threshold in terms of
milligrams of THC taken orally and um
this is from a paper from Ethan in 2018
and when you look at you know just pure
THC around 18 milligram that could cause
toxic psychosis in some people of course
it's a temporary experience but when
it's combined with CBD you need a much
higher dose to achieve that severe
adverse side effect so this is a summary
slide I'm going to keep coming back to
pharmacodynamic interaction is that CBD
is a negative alisic modulator at CB1
and it can dampen the adverse effects
especially the more severe ones now
here's a study in fibromyalgia patients
who were vaporizing cannabis either type
1 type two or type three or Placebo and
they were looking at their uh subjective
pain results after vaporization but also
at their blood levels of cannabinoids
and what they found was that CBD
inhalation increased the THC plasma
concentrations but diminished the
analgesic effects these authors
suggested this was a synergistic
pharmacokinetic interaction meaning the
presence of the CBD slowed down the
metabolism of THC allowing for there to
be higher levels but an antagonistic
pharmacodynamic interaction those higher
levels did not result in better pain
relief it actually resulted in less pain
Rel belief and so um there were also uh
reductions in spontaneous pain in the
study that correlated with the
subjective rating of drug high so what
does that mean that means that to help
the pain in these fibromyalgia patients
it seemed like approaching this
psychoactive this THC effect is what was
really helping them the most and CBD
diminishes that so the question is
beyond dampening and adverse effects can
adding CBD to THC dampen the therapeutic
effects and I think in some cases the
answer is yes and then we have this
pharmac pharmacokinetic interaction
where CBD could be increasing THC levels
by slowing its metabolism now here's
another study and I apologize again for
the slides THC versus a ratio of 1 to3
THC CBD vaporized in adults and in
adolescents uh looking at their
subjective experiences after doing this
and this would correspond to about a
quarter of a typical joint the dose of
THC that they were getting 8 mg and what
they found was that the combination of
THC and CBD at this 1:3 ratio was no
less psychoactive than the equivalent
dose of THC CBD augmented THC levels
again so it's that pharmacokinetic
interaction slowing the breakdown of THC
but despite higher plasma levels of THC
and that combination treatment uh the
stronger effects were not absor not
observed uh likely again due to that
phod dnamic antagonism so the group that
received the combination had higher
levels of THC but did not have more
psychoactive
effects and then here's a study that was
a double blind randomized control trial
with 26 healthy cannabis users that were
vaporizing either THC combination THC
CBD or CBD or Placebo again uh and
looking at their driving performance and
a simulation and what they found was
that the group that had THC dominant
only no CBD they were this is their
standard deviation of lane lane position
basically how much are they swerving
back and forth and that uh deviation was
2.33 CM on average the combination of
THC and CBD actually had a stronger
deviation and the CBD dominant uh Vapor
didn't change it at all but what's
interesting is the cut off here 2.4
cm is considered typical of a 05% blood
alcohol concentration and is thought to
indicate clinically relevant driving
impairment so in this case the same dose
of THC administered with
CBD was more impairing slightly more
impairing than THC alone now what what's
going on there well first of all that
and that was just at um that was at the
40 to1 100 minutes test there was no
change later on at 240 to 300 in any
group the drivers who consumed THC were
generally more aware that their driving
was impaired but the group that received
both had less anxiety they also rated
the drug effect as lower and they had
higher ratings of confidence to drive
than THC alone so these findings
challenge the myth that CBD can amarate
the psychoactive effects of THC what
what seems to be happening here is that
CBD mitigated the THC induced anxiety
which it tends to do but maybe a little
THC induced anxiety is a good thing if
you're about to get behind the
wheel and so um beyond beyond decreasing
the adverse effects and decreasing the
therapeutic effects could the
combination of THC and CBD decrease the
awareness of the impairment or increase
the anxiety related to impairment and
therefore increase the risk I think this
study suggests that that's
possible and it's probably not in
everyone but there might be some
settings and some patients where that's
going to happen now um this is a uh
strange study uh because it it was uh it
involved a very high doable THC and CBD
taken orally in a brownie along with a
whole cocktail of other cyp drugs I'm
not going to spend lot of time on it but
the brownie either had 20 milligram of
THC or 20 Mig of THC and 640 Mig of CBD
so this was a 1 to 32 ratio of THC to
CBD pretty strong brownies but the um
the people who received the combination
with this high dose of THC were more
impaired and they rated the experience
as Less Pleasant than the people who
received the the 20 migs of THC alone
now a lot of you are probably surprised
by this you're thinking well if I if I
overdose on THC but I'm taking it with
this massive dose of CBD isn't that
going to dampen down the activity at the
CB1 receptor and protect me from feeling
too stoned well in this case which was
an unusual study it didn't and um what's
hard to see on these uh line graphs here
is that the plasma levels of THC and of
11 hydroxy THC were much higher in the
group that had the brownie with the CBD
in it compared to the THC brownie alone
so there is significant
pharmacokinetic uh synergism Happening
Here increasing the levels of THC and 11
hydroxy which are both
psychoactive so the question is um is
there a pharmacokinetic potential to
increase impairment at high doses when
CBD and THC are taken together and I
think the answer is
yes now here's an interesting study on
some uh Young people with epilepsy
treated in the UK and they had a variety
of treatments that they could start with
there was the CBD broad spectrum the CBD
isolate the um and the CBD we could call
it full spectrum in the study they
called it broadspectrum plus
THC um but those those were the options
for treatment and I think if you can see
this and follow it along uh only four of
the 35 patients ended up starting off
with this broadspectrum plus THC pretty
much everyone started with either CBD
isolate or CBD broadspectrum but when it
didn't work they would move on to a
different treatment and this is where
they ended up down here and so just to
summarize these results on the next
slide in in total of the 17 who tried
THC 16
responded and 13 of them tried CBD
dominant no THC first and then of
everyone that re responded to the THC
treatment all of them were also taking
very high doses of CBD at the same time
was this necessary was this needed maybe
in some it was and some it wasn't but
kind of a waste of time for many of them
starting with this CBD isolate and CBD
broadspectrum with zero THC and so I
bring that up because in this situation
what I'm suggesting is that lowd dose
THC in many cases can add benefit to
high dose CBD and if you get a partial
response with high does CBD switching
over to a full spectrum extract might be
helpful so um so that's all I've got for
this and we'll we'll summarize it again
later but this is you know I'm I hope
that I've brought in your mind a little
bit about some of the potentials for THC
and CBD to interact with each other
pharmacodynamically and
pharmacokinetically when taken via
inhalation and when taken
orally let's let's move on to thca this
is pharmacologically distinct from THC
it is not psychoactive it has a lot of
beneficial properties
anti-inflammatory neuroprotective
hepatoprotective antiemetic uh very very
strong anti-emetic a lot of people don't
think about that with
thca many other
targets and thca is is different than
THC especially because it doesn't act
upon the CB1 receptor at least not as a
partial Agonist like THC does and so how
do these two go together well they have
similar metabolism and so you there even
though this hasn't been shown that I'm
aware of in humans there's likely going
to be pharmacokinetic agonism there if
you take thca with THC it's likely to
slow the breakdown and could potentiate
the THC pharmacokinetically there was
also one study in rodents that showed
that thca was acting as a CB1 positive
allosteric modulator now this is
exciting because uh this would be you
know if this is the case a positive
alisic modulator at CB1 has great
therapeutic potential when we take THC
as a CB1 Agonist we are globally
affecting our endoc canabo system which
can be a good thing but I think
affecting our endoc canabo system with
with greater Precision the Precision
involved with our endoc canabo synthesis
would be in many cases Cas is even
better so imagine if we could use
something like thca to selectively
enhance CB1 signaling where it's
happening when and where it's happening
in the body based on the wisdom and
precision of our own endoc canabo system
so and there's been a lot of pH
pharmaceutical uh exploration looking
for a good positive alisic modulator for
this reason now cannabis te is a great
delivery method for thca especially
because the solubility of thca is much
greater in water if especially if you're
not adding anything like cream to the
water you're going to have at most a 1
to5 ratio of THC to thca so you get a
lot more thca when you make cannabis
T now let's switch gears to CBD plus
cbda while THC and thca are quite
different CBD and cbda are very similar
they have many similar Targets in the
body but one of the main differences is
at the CB1 receptor so all that I showed
you about CBD interacting with THC
pharmacode dynamically dampening those
effects through negative alisic
modulation this is not likely to happen
with cbda cbda is also more bioavailable
but CBD has greater ability to cross the
bloodb brain barrier and so what are the
take-homes from this CBD is also much
more excuse me cbda is also much more
potent than CBD at least in many animal
models like 10x the the potency of CBD
in a rodent model of D syndrome even
though it barely crosses the bloodb
brain barrier 100x the potency of CBD in
a model of
hyperalgesia and 10,000 times the
potency of CBD in a rodent model of
nausea vomiting so cbda can be more
bioavailable and more potent these
rodent studies don't rely on oral
absorption their their int peraonal
injection and then it really makes some
sense to combine cbda with THC
especially in people that do well with
THC and that don't want the potential of
dampening the pH pharmaco um of
dampening the therapeutic effects of the
THC right we're we're avoiding that
negative aleric modulation so cbda and
THC go really well together as
demonstrated in this model of
inflammatory pain where the tiniest
doses I'm not going to get into it that
was my lecture last year but if you see
this study you wouldn't believe how low
the doses were that were effective when
combining cbda and THC for inflammatory
pain now U moving on to
CBG CBG has many mechanisms of action
but one of them that I think is worth
bringing up in this lecture is its
activity at the 5 ht1a serotonin
receptor the serotonin this serotonin
receptor is thought to be the target of
CBD and cbda a in its anti-anxiety and
anti-nausea effects CBG has been shown
to be a neutral antagonist at this
receptor and um could potentially oppose
some of the effects of CBD at least in
one animal study um it was shown to
oppose the anti-emetic effects of CBD
and it could be unpredictable when
combined with other serotonergic agents
I haven't seen a lot of this but it's a
caution maybe I've seen a couple cases
now where CBG seems to have altered the
effects of CBD but it's something just
to watch for if you're using them
together I think in most cases they go
really well together and remember this
is just one of their targets one of
many for example CBG is also a par gamma
uh Agonist with stronger Affinity than
THC or CBD and um in Vivo this was shown
in animals where CBG could enhance or
the the effects of CB BG on this
receptor were enhanced by CBD so I think
combining these two there's some
potential for antagonism there's some
potential for
synergism and then U moving on to
thcv this is a CB1 antagonist at low
doses a CB1 Agonist at higher doses it's
probably most well known for producing
weight loss and decreasing uh body fat
uh it also has anti-convulsant
properties and um it lacks the adverse
effects of inverse agon agonists like
Rano so rabant is a CB1 blocker the
anti- munchy drug that was marketed in
Europe and almost here in the US but it
makes people really upset and suicidal
not a good idea to block cv1 in humans
thcv can gently block CB1 uh and get
some of those same metabolic benefits
without causing those types of adverse
effects actually it can be experienced
as quite
uplifting but that's us usually in well
even even when administered is an
isolate and so this was a a study that
looked at a very low dose of thcv in
humans 5 milligrams taken orally twice
daily for 13 weeks it decreased uh
fasting glucose it increased at a ptin
it improved beta cell function um there
were mild to moderate adverse effects
but when the thcv was combined with CBD
those metabolic benefits vanished even
when it was combined with a low dose of
CBD they they tested it both against 5
milligram of CBD and 100 Mig of CBD and
those metabolic benefits vanished so
very interesting that CBD May attenuate
or remove some of the benefits of thcv
so let's review all of this and then
we'll do a quick case THC and CBG May
enhance the absorption of cbda via the
intestinal e-lux pump CBD and THC have
pharmacokinetic agonism and
pharmacodynamic antagonism sometimes
that antagonism is good because it's
blocking the side effects sometimes it
might not be good because it's blocking
the therapeutic effects and there are
complex cognitive and subjective effects
including more confidence driving in
that one study cbda and CBD are similar
and likely have pharmacokinetic agonism
and different potency and brain
penetration thca and THC are distinct in
their activity they likely synergize
pharmacokinetically thca may be a
positive ostero alisic modulator at CB1
which could enhance endoc canabo
function and enhance the activity of
THC cbda and THC may have some
synergistic effects together in
inflammatory pain with ultra low oral
Doses and in general seems to be a good
combination for my patients CBG can be
synergistically with CBD via parar gamma
May block some of the serotonergic
effects and CBG cannot replace THC or
CBD but it adds distinct effects so I I
I know that when you're thinking what
should I do switch or add I think that
sometimes the combination of all of them
can be useful but we wouldn't start
there CBD can block the metabolic
benefits of thcv so my recommendations
when you're approaching a patient and
you're thinking where do I start start
work with full spectrum chemotype
categories think to yourself am I going
to start with one 2 3 or four what
what's what am I coming out of the gates
with try one at a time explore dose
response effects and then add or switch
so you have kind of a starting dose you
have a dose that you're going to titrate
up to if there's no adverse effects
you're going to see how they do within
that range as Bonnie says you're kind of
ruling it in or ruling it out is this
chemotype going to be effective and then
depending on how far you get you can
switch to something else or you can
layer something else on top I still
think that the combination of THC and
CBD this type two is a great place to
start it's very effective but if you're
relying on it to produce decreased
psycho activity that that may not be the
outcome that you see in everyone it's
certainly going to be that way in some
people include at least a little thca
with your THC trust me don't fully
decarb your THC it's going to work
better if you don't um the possible
exception to that is in people that need
THC but are Ultra sensitive to it and
you want to have a you know a more
precise low dose include at least a
little cbda with your CBD they work
similarly and the cbda is much stronger
include at least a little THC or CBG
with your cbda to enhance its absorption
observe closely when you're adding CBG
to CBD you might not get what you expect
and avoid CBD with thcv if you're
looking for the metabolic benefits these
are some general recommendations things
to look for and I'll give a quick case
in the next last minute here so autism
spectrum disorder age five came in with
nighttime Awakenings intermittent
aggression and hand biting so I started
him on a balanced ratio the the products
that we work with that I get the the
great pleasure of working with I've
designed and uh healer makes so this is
our one: one but it's actually a 1: one
to one: one it it's half DEC
carboxilate um one drop is 1 milligram
and so he started off with five drops in
the morning so a little more than 1
milligram of each of those and um and
then I chose a formula called healer
pain at night which was a THC to thca
one:1 formula for for bedtime and the
reason I chose that was really because I
wanted to incrementally adjust in half
milligrams instead of full milligrams of
THC and so uh came back one month later
Global Improvement in all areas he's at
peace the medicine has been a
GameChanger I'm in absolute awe of how
it has changed his life he's even
willing to try more Foods he had
titrated up to 15 drops of balance in
the morning so almost 4 milligram of THC
in that dose 10 drops in the afternoon 2
and2 milligrams uh pain was four drops
before bed so 2 milligrams before bed
but 4 months later he had started public
school and his symptoms worsened they
had had titrated up on the balance
formula so we were still exploring the
dose response curve we went up on the
balance and the pain symptoms improved
some but he was still pushing his peers
attempting to bite others slapping
himself in the face waking up at 3:00 or
4 in the morning and he was still making
developmental progress so uh we changed
the nighttime formula to our more
sedating THC dominant healer Knight and
then we started adding our CBG formula
during the day he started sleeping
through the night squeezing or giving a
little pinch instead of being more
aggressive
was stable at 25 and 20 drops of balance
in the morning and the night again
that's so that's around almost 6
milligrams of THC in the morning and
five in the not in the night but in the
afternoon CBG 10 milligrams twice daily
night 6 milligrams before bed and the
efficacy was maintained for the
following six months so I think that
shows you a case where here's what I
decided to start with balance during the
day THC dominant at night symptoms
returned I titrated up we didn't get the
results we were looking for we layered
in CBG that was my next choice and we
got the symptoms under control and that
is all I have for you today thank you so
much
[Applause]