thank everybody for joining us sorry for
the delay my name is jeff chen i'm the
director of the UCLA cannabis research
initiative really excited to be here and
host canta med here at UCLA i actually
earned my medical degree and my MBA both
here at UCLA so I'm a Bruin any Bruins
in the audience yeah we got a bunch
right okay and just a quick 30 second
blur about what is the UCLA cannabis
research initiative so we started the
program about a year ago and it was
through a generous gift from Terry and
Jane Cemil and our mission is to advance
the scientific understanding of the
impacts of cannabis on body brain mind
and society and so we have 37 faculty
members from UCLA who've joined the
initiative it spans over 15 different
departments in six different schools
here at UCLA so it's an incredibly
collaborative multidisciplinary effort
and today we're here to talk about
Alzheimer's disease and by 2050 it is
estimated that one in two seniors when
they pass will suffer from some form of
dementia one and two and Alzheimer's
disease is the most common form of
dementia and that's why we're here to
talk about this so I'd like to introduce
our panelists so to my right here we
have dr. Jamie Cox he's the chief
medical officer of sundial growers which
is a cannabis producer in Alberta Canada
dr. Cox works with healthcare
organizations universities and industry
partners to help them understand
cannabis as a viable medical treatment
he has over two decades of senior
healthcare leadership roles including a
stint including his role as medical
director of General Motors to my right I
also have dr. Gary smalls he's a
professor of psychiatry at the UCLA
Semel Institute for Neuroscience and
human behavior he's also the director of
the UC a longevity Center and the
director of geriatric psychiatry he's
developed brain imaging technology that
can detect Alzheimer's years before
symptoms start he's also tested
medications that can delay the onset of
Alzheimer's and he's developed healthy
aging lifestyle and memory programs that
are widely used throughout the
les Scientific American magazine named
him the world's top 50 innovators in
science and technology and he's written
the New York Times best-selling book the
memory Bible and finally at the end of
the table we have dr. David Schubert he
is a professor and co-founder of the
neuroscience program at the Salk
Institute he established the first
additional chemistry lab at the Salk
Institute and his recent work has
focused on developing treatments for
neurodegenerative disorders including
Alzheimer's and Parkinson's he has
developed synthetic derivatives of
naturally synthetic derivatives of
natural plant compounds that have much
improved properties over their natural
analogs and he's starting phase one
human studies for one of his drugs j14 7
for Alzheimer's disease he has also been
conducting drug screening on various
cannabinoid compounds to elucidate their
neuroprotective properties in
Alzheimer's disease so please join me in
a warm welcome for our panelists today
and so I think the first question to
start off with is maybe let's talk about
the current state of evidence and state
of treatments for Alzheimer's in terms
of actually the progression of the
disease what what treatments are
available right now what are the
benefits what are the side effects that
we're looking at well I can start with
that we we have several medicines that
are called symptomatic treatments which
means they help temporarily with the
symptoms they don't cure the disease
they don't stop its progression and
they've been around for several decades
so they're already directly marketed to
consumers you've probably seen ads about
them on television and we use them
routinely when patients have mild
moderate or severe Alzheimer's or other
forms of dementia there's been a lot of
drug development and other treatment
development in trying to come up with
what's often termed a disease modifying
treatment so that would mean that this
treatment would actually get into the
brain and have an impact on either
stopping the disease or slowing it one
way to think about symptomatic versus
disease-modifying if you had pneumonia
you would take aspirin as a symptomatic
treatment but you'd have to take an
antibiotic as a disease modifying
treatment unfortunately more than 99% of
the disease modifying treatments have
failed there actually
all of them have failed thus far so you
know we're all looking for better
approaches to try to deal with this
devastating illness yeah I'd like to
comment on that
certainly yesterday it was well
demonstrated by the at the CME session
the neural protective benefits of the
various cannabinoids and for us not to
start looking at that seriously I
believe as a group the service to
protential e half y'all in the audience
okay because one and two of us are gonna
get it so it's up to us to start making
a difference you know the the old saying
keep doing what you've
you're gonna keep getting what you've
got it's time for us to make a change
so I'm full on to the looking at the
camera noise in them in the proper
perspective because like dr. small said
99.9 percent failure rate it's not very
good I wouldn't say so let's try doing
something slightly different and maybe
on that note you mentioned disease
modifying agents what are some of the
currently used disease modifying agents
how effective are they what are the
potential downsides well for Alzheimer's
disease there are no disease modifying
agents that are being used there are
several that are being studied and
tested most of them there's quite a few
in development right now most of them
have focused on trying trying to clear
out the amyloid plaques that build up in
the brain alois alzheimer defined the
disease in 1906 when he did a brain
autopsy study on a middle-aged woman who
had the clinical symptoms and he
revealed to the medical community for
the first time abnormal protein deposits
called neurofibrillary tangles and
amyloid plaques that collect in the
centers of the brain that control
thinking and memory so a lot of the drug
development has been to try to clear out
those plaques that hasn't worked at this
point they're trying to use those
treatments earlier in the course of the
disease so they'll look for families
where there's a genetic mutation and
treat people who they know are going to
get the disease as a result of the
mutation to try to prevent the disease
and I think that's progress and a lot of
the research we're doing is trying to
target people before they have dementia
this is a very slow insidious gradually
progressive condition that our studies
and other studies have shown that the
these abnormal protein deposits actually
collect in the brain decades before
people have symptoms so I'm a big fan of
trying to protect a healthy brain rather
than trying to repair damage once it's
extensive and and dr. Schubert what are
some of the MEC
in isms through which cannabinoids might
be able to have therapeutic potential
for some of the actual disease
progression of in Alzheimer's well I
think that's a tough question but I just
sort of like go back a step because I'm
a big fan of plants and we do have
synthetic drugs which we're trying to
get into clinic and some of these are
pretty well long at least in the
preclinical stage and so if you look at
the history of you know drug development
the majority of the drugs in the clinic
today are based on plants I mean this
chemical scaffolds are basically those
from chemicals that derived from plants
so the problem with Alzheimer's is we
realize a long time ago or so maybe ten
years ago is that this amyloid idea is
was a very good idea to begin with and
where you hear accumulate the plaques
and the tangles and whatever the initial
description but that may not be the only
thing that's going on so so we took an
approach that we did some library
screening of big collection of plant
extracts and found some compounds that
worked quite well and these we developed
a series of essays which mimic the old
brain what happens in the aging brain
and then we screen compounds and trying
to find ones that work and then modify
those so that they could make a better
pharmaceutical the appropriate drug and
so the question is in the cannabinoid
field how you would go about doing that
and I think the plant itself as you've
heard this morning has a lot of
attributes and probably a lot of things
are going on in what when you are
exposed to this plant that you really
don't understand as far as the
therapeutic potential so so I think if
you want to talk about specific targets
I think that may be something of a
mistake because I don't think you know
what this target should be for
Alzheimer's disease and you have a
couple ideas obviously the cannabinoid
receptors are widely studied but there's
obviously some problems looking at
directly at those
so the idea has been to sort of take
away take apart the plant and look at
their 500 so unique chemicals in the
plant and screen those and assays which
we have used to to identify potential
therapeutics and that's that's what
we're going to do hopefully and but you
know I think it's probably not a good
idea to try to pre-select a target for
this particular disease because you're
looking at genetic based targets and
looking at pre selected targets that
sort of implies you know more about the
disease and what you really do so
particularly with a lot of these
neurodegenerative diseases this pre
selected target idea is probably not
good so we like to do sort of screening
assays without knowing their target and
trying to find drugs at work and and can
you clarify when you're talking about
target are you referring to a target
drug to study are you referring to a
target receptor in the body that you
want to design a drug around usually
when you're talking about drugs you're
talking about a molecular target and so
that means one molecule the drug
interacts with and what if you what what
have you discovered as to the properties
in of any cannabis derived compounds
that you've done in your lab that might
be relevant to neurodegenerative
diseases well what's unique about our
lab I think is the screening assays we
use to pick up these activities and and
they're based on as I said they're
basing on aging things that happened in
older brains so so age is the biggest
risk factor for Alzheimer's disease and
people have known that for a little I
mean the last hundred years of it but
people the drug discovery world has not
really paid much attention to that and
so I think that's a big mistake so so if
you look at the cannabinoids in the
context of what we've learned from our
own work I think there's a number of
pathways which are affected in the
answer inflammation is a major component
most neurodegenerative diseases systemic
information contributes to that there is
something which is sort of hidden in the
literature but it's it's appreciating
the aging field as this mTOR pathway
which is an anti-aging pathway and we
were just we found that our drugs affect
this very much like these anti-aging
compounds is sort so called Jarrow
protectors and so the cannabinoids
actually influence this pathway in a
pretty profound way so I think that
could be a target pathway but there's no
really serious studies in the way of
neuro degeneration in this pathway this
target particularly so you mentioned
inflammation
you mentioned the mTOR pathway there was
also some work that your lab had done I
believe with THC and amyloid buildup
could you speak briefly on that so one
of our drugs which were should start
clinical trial approval next week
actually the it works in part by
activating one of the cb1 pathway and I
think this is an indirect activation of
this pathway so so we know that these
drugs clear out this ham Lloyd which
accumulates inside neurons and very
early stages of Alzheimer's disease and
we've looked at like 10 non psychoactive
components of the cannabis and they also
do very much the same thing CBD CBD CBN
and one potential explanation of this
these are anti-inflammatory there
antioxidants and some respect and so we
think that this there's a structural
we've been looking at the chemistry of
these molecules because we do medicinal
chemistry and we're trying to figure out
if there's some structural motif which
probably identifies a different type of
receptor and brain tissue that it can be
engaged by these molecules and they're
clearly not working exclusively through
the cb1 cb2
because we have a one of our screening
of assays uses cell a nerve cell line
that doesn't have these receptors so
there's something else going on we're
just trying to figure that out thank you
and so we've been talking a lot about
the underlying mechanisms that cause
Alzheimer's we just touched on some of
the underlying mechanisms through which
cannabinoids may have some therapeutic
potential let's shift gears a little bit
and maybe talked about and you touch on
this very briefly dr. smalls is the
symptoms of Alzheimer's and I think
anecdotally there are folks who are
using cannabis to manage the symptoms of
Alzheimer's and is there any grounding
and science for that what are the what
does the literature say maybe let's
start with talking about what are some
of those symptoms of Alzheimer's and how
do we treat some of those symptoms right
now so early on when Alzheimer's strikes
people generally develop memory issues
but they also can experience mood
changes and behavioral changes social
withdrawal anxiety depression a months
or even years before the diagnosis is
made so there can be quite diverse
mental symptoms that present although
memory short-term memory seems to be the
biggest complaint as the condition
progresses there are there's worsening
of the memory problems there's confusion
there are language difficulties there's
problems of course with paying attention
their personality changes there are
visual spatial problems so pretty much
all areas of cognitive functioning are
affected and as you get further and
further into the disease there is more
and more emergence of behavioral
symptoms aggression psychotic symptoms
paranoia and it can be quite difficult
for caregivers to manage that the
treatments are generally the symptomatic
medicines that I mentioned before
medicines like to nepo sill rivastigmine
and memantine that are used to help with
these symptoms and we also try to
counsel families on dealing with the the
difficult behaviors along the way
another approach that we've championed
and others have gotten behind this is to
try to help people with their everyday
lifestyle there's there's been a lot of
compelling research showing that
genetics don't account for all the risk
factors for developing dementia
certainly age is the greatest single
risk factors that was just mentioned but
people who are physically inactive
people who don't get adequate sleep
individuals who are obese and midlife
people who don't eat a healthy diet who
are stressed out chronically these are
all risk factors for developing
cognitive decline and we try to help
people with that as well and just to add
another reality-based issue that a lot
of the senior population have especially
those afflicted with early onset
Alzheimer's is the polypharmacy
that we see bereft in the older
population one of my prior roles was a
medical director at a large extended
care facility and the number of
off-label drugs that are used in the
older population is really overtly
concerning to me too we're already
dealing with the brain disease as dr.
small has elucidated with with the
inflammation which leads to the
Alzheimer's add on top of that atypical
antipsychotics benzodiazepines
neuroleptic medications and then try to
function knowing that you've also got
this coexisting condition that's
creeping up and beers report is really
underutilized in the senior population
in my opinion and if we had a clear
focus on the pharmaceuticals that are
being used in this population and
started weaning these ineffective
medications off
it would give us a much greater
opportunity to actually impact people's
lives which is what we as physicians are
responsible to do improve quality of
life do no harm so if I can just expand
on that a bit more another common
problem is people take over-the-counter
medicines for sleep or they take
antihistamines that have an
anticholinergic effect now that's
important because one of the
neurotransmitter systems that gets into
trouble in Alzheimer's is the
cholinergic system so that will in fact
several the drugs that are have been
developed and used for Alzheimer's are
cholinergic drugs so that's a problem
and as as I mentioned some of the
behavioral problems that emerge later in
the disease which which generally lead
caregivers to to get their family
members into nursing homes and
institutionalized facilities we don't
have great treatments for that we have
these antipsychotic drugs there are
black box warnings and there are
problems with that sometimes you use
antidepressants so there's a lot of
research going on right now looking for
medicines that might calm people down
now there have been some studies using
marijuana products to treat that and the
results are a bit mixed sometimes they
cause side effects sometimes they seem
to calm patients down and what are some
of that you mentioned black box warnings
for some of these medicines and kind of
described ions what what that is and
what are some of the risks associated
with these medicines so there are
antipsychotics typical and atypical
antipsychotics that can increase the
risk of a stroke or increase the risk of
diabetes and so there's been a lot of
concern about that so doctors try to
even though they can be quite effective
when patients are psychotic and
aggressive we're concerned about the
side effects from that and the other
issue with that is the use of atypical
antipsychotics in this population
is not meant to be chronic use of the
pharmaceutical if it's if there's
aggressive behavior or psychotic
behavior it's supposed to be used at
that time and then it's supposed to be
weaned off
unfortunately I've seen about 60% of
some senior populations in extended care
they're on atypical antipsychotics until
that they're done watching there's no
drug right now that's been approve to
treat the psychosis associated with
dementia there are several compounds
that are in development that might
succeed but we have nothing right now
and in terms of you mentioned some of
these clinical trials of cannabis or THC
and that sometimes they were associated
with side effects what are some of the
biggest concerns and risks for the use
of cannabis or Camden cannabis products
in Alzheimer's patients well you know if
you if patients get overly sedated they
can fall and hurt themselves and we know
that with dementia people often have
unsteady gait so that could be
compounded they will become more
withdrawn which is a problem when a big
issue I see is people widowed
individuals living alone at home and
they're completely isolated so they
can't deal with their daily activities
they're not always safe in the house
they can wander off and if they're using
cannabis could make those symptoms even
worse yeah and that's why the need for
studies there we're going to be
embarking we're fortunate enough in
Canada I am from Canada a so the we are
fortunate enough in some provinces to
have policy on use of cannabinoids in
extended care so we're actually going to
be embarking on a formalized trial not
using high THC but rather a higher CBD
which has a more satisfactory
side-effect profile in the elderly
population to see if we can truly impact
the anxiety and aggression that can be
seen in this population
and and so it's maybe speaking to that
because medical cannabis has been more
widely used and regulated in Canada what
is the current state you mentioned
there's certain extended care facilities
that have lenient cannabis policies what
does that landscape look like right now
for the use in extended care or memory
care facilities it's it's really
evolutionary to be quite honest with you
um the the policy in the province of
Saskatchewan was guidance policy on the
use of cannabinoids typically cannabis
is not used in extended care facilities
in Canada it's still considered to be a
locked drug the same thing as a narcotic
so it has to go through significant
protocols to be even able to be used
I'll say on the floor by the nursing
staff to dispense it that's why we're
focusing on Saskatchewan first because
they've already got an accepted policy
and the goal is certainly in no way
shape or form to create any sense of an
individual being stoned it's about
trying to improve their quality of life
the ideal scenario would be to see some
people wake up again you know from the
polypharmacy it's it's brief though
there folks I tell you and so we've been
talking a bit about the symptomatic
management I'd like to almost bring the
conversation back to some of the
underlying mechanisms that might target
the disease and dr. Schubert one
question I had for you is you mentioned
how you traditionally you take naturally
natural compounds and then you develop
analogs
so things that look similar but you
modify them slightly to improve various
attributes of them and what did what are
your thoughts as to where you want to go
with your cannabinoid work you've
mentioned these various phyto
cannabinoids you've been working with
well I can first offer these should
define the problem because the problem
is we've initially was 10 15 years ago
started working with natural products
and tried to use these in therapeutic
you know contacts of helping with
Alzheimer's Parkinson's these types of
Z's but the problem with natural
products is it's basically from a
pharmaceutical point of view they're
dead end because nobody is going to
support a clinical trial for something
down to Walmart or someplace and buy and
so we worked for many years and we have
natural products which we think and
other people like people like great coal
here has been working on curcumin at
UCLA for years and it's just extremely
difficult to get a natural product into
a clinical trial and people in the
cannabinoid field are going to you know
there are ways to get around that but
you know the clinical trials for
Alzheimer's are extremely expensive and
difficult and so it's somebody has to
make money out the way their government
the United States or the world set up in
order to give something into the clinic
so our the only way we could get the
compounds that we were really thought
we're helpful into the clinic was by
making synthetic patentable duties of
that and then even with that in the
Alzheimer's field has been very
difficult to to to you know get funding
for their clinical trials and for the
preclinical development so that may
change there's more money in the
Alzheimer's field now than there was a
couple of years ago so but the rationale
for doing the clinical medicinal
chemistry is to make the drug more
potent and more bioavailable and their
problems with natural products in the
sense there are some chemical issues
that that medicinal chemists don't like
and so you you we felt in order to
survive as a lab and you know try to
move things towards the clinic we just
had to do the medicinal chemistry to get
things moving and I think there are
going to be issues in the cannabinoid
field of the same problem it maybe you
can organize it and learn from what's
people in the past working on natural
products I've learned but it's going to
be I think a little bit difficult so you
mentioned curcumin and you know we just
published a study using a bioavailable
form of curcumin that's manufactured by
a Japanese company and we studied people
not with dementia but people at risk for
dementia so they had what's coughing
called mild cognitive
or even just normal aging and we studied
them for 18 months and we compared the
compound to placebo and curcumin is a
component of tumeric so it's basically a
spice that's been around for thousands
of years and it reminds me a bit about
of cannabis because it ticks all the
boxes in terms of effects it's
anti-inflammatory its antioxidant anti
and so forth but we had even though it
was a relatively small study it had a
fairly robust effect on memory and
attention and so we're gonna be
following that up with a larger study to
confirm the results but I think this
offers a model for testing cannabis
products that have the right balance of
ingredients so you don't have the mental
effects that might be problematic but
you have the effects on inflammation and
oxidation and even possibly amyloid
buildup and you test it in people not
with dementia but people who are at risk
for it earlier in the stage of their
neuro degeneration
I think you can go back a little bit
even further than that so there's this
concept which has been around for a
hundred years and recently been sort of
revamped by the aging Institute NIH and
the buck Institute up in Northern
California's idea is something called
zero protectors and zero protectors are
the idea is if you can define compounds
which maybe extend life and model
organisms in index Inlet and the
extrapolate that to humans and if you
extend lifespan to a little bit you'll
and you'll you'll forestall the advent
of these age associated diseases like
Alzheimer's and Parkinson and so it
turns out we we've looked at a lot of
the pathways involved I look like with
curcumin and our drugs which heard Rodya
curcumin
and other sort of known dural protectors
for example like alcohol restriction is
a you know it's obvious what that is and
others two others are metformin which is
anti-diabetic drug it has other problem
uses too then rapamycin and so it turns
out that all these drugs have are these
compounds in caloric restriction have
the same molecular pathways which lead
in model organisms to life extension and
so when I just went this weekend I was
looking at what's happening in this CBD
sea-tac field and it turns out these
compounds they were affecting oh they
sent same pathways as curcumin and some
of the flavonoids and our curcumin
derivative so I think there's this
opportunity for for the cannabinoid
field is since these drugs are mostly
cannabinoids are anti-inflammatory is
sort of even before you have like mild
cognitive impairment or whatever and the
Alzheimer's world you know there's some
long-term dural protector I mean this
really hasn't been looked at as far as I
know in the cannabinoid field but I
think this is a potential no use for it
you know I think eventually that may be
the case one of the challenges though
and doing human studies if you start
very early and very young people you
might be able to have a signal on a
biomarker but to see a clinical signal
is very difficult and it isn't until you
get people with what we call normal
aging which be it would be the precursor
to MCI or mild cognitive impairment
which would be the precursor to dementia
in normal aging you you are able to see
neuropsychological tests that are quite
sensitive and you can see changes when
you test compounds like curcumin but
metformin there is a large study right
now look
and lots of aging targets and I think
that makes sense but let me also add
another point when you talk about going
in earlier we and others have studied
what the brain looks like late in life
in people who are heavy marijuana users
early in life and it's not a pretty
picture it turns out that you have
atrophy or shrinkage of the medial
temporal cortex which is an important
area of memory consolidation so you know
when we talk about any kind of
medication or or plant or supplement
whatever it is it's really you got to
take timing into consideration and
dosage and the contents of the compound
to optimize the therapeutic effects and
minimize any adverse effects
thank you about the great point about
potential confounding factors as to
timing and onset right there's a lot of
concern about the use of cannabis with
the developing brain one area that I had
a question on is there's been some work
on the aged breath this is an animal
studies that on the aged brain and the
impacts of THC on memory and even
neurogenesis on the aged brain no no if
there if any guys I've heard very
anecdotal commentary on that and I guess
- we're in a unique position in Canada
I'm gonna go a little bit tangent but
I'll come back to it cannabis is
legalized in Canada so it is so the
choice of whether to use cannabis or not
is now left in to the individual we as
individuals in the space of having the
ability to do some research to share our
knowledge and anecdotal is a funny word
dr. Russo yesterday showed a slide for
those who weren't there was fibromyalgia
and it was 1,400 people self-reporting
how they were doing on traditional
pharmaceuticals which were clinically
approved randomized trials but they
weren't doing very good these people
were using cannabis to treat their
symptoms and they found it's superior to
traditional pharmaceuticals that's going
to happen in Canada as well so for us to
be able to look at it a little bit
different and look at in Canada we've
got the a reality like I said it's legal
so let's make sure that we have
information that we can provide to our
aging population North America we're all
getting older we're not getting younger
so if we focus more on a holistic
approach and actually identify an
outcome based on how an individual is
doing I think that may be a slightly
different slant on the research the the
horse is already out of the barn in
Canada to be able to take a long multi
million dollar research funded grant
that's going to take five years to
demonstrate that level of outcome I
don't think it's going to happen to two
doctor Schubert's point is very
expensive to do a lot of research in the
lab where by only 5% of any research in
the lab is ever commercialized it stays
in the lab so we have to be nimble in
this new environment and perhaps think a
little bit differently one so just to
reiterate I think what dr. Cox is saying
is that the the opportunity to almost
reverse translate findings so
translation is where you go from animal
studies to human studies here we have an
opportunity to reverse translate
findings where we learn from the
anecdotal evidence we don't take it for
face value but based on that we try
maybe engineer the animal studies or the
clinical trials we know what right
questions to ask to actually test
whether or not this is a real effect
yeah and I think it's important to
really demonstrate effective analytics
of data when you're looking at thousands
of people with all variables not
controlled but like everyone in the room
we're all different physiologically
the unique thing and I've seen 3,000
patients for referral from for cannabis
use for primary care and specialist is
it's interesting that everyone uses the
same mantra when we're talking about
treatment with cannabis go slow and
gradually up titrate to effective dose
when you're looking at some of the
pharmaceuticals on that are currently
available there's no ability to micro
titrate if you got a capsule that's 300
milligrams guess what you're going to
get 300 milligrams so it's the education
gap that we have within the physician
community needs to be narrowed but we
have an opportunity ask clinicians to do
it correctly and with our remaining time
I'd like to open it up for questions
thank you I'd like to shed a little
light on this from a physician
standpoint in Northern California where
we're using residential care facilities
for the elderly as a place for cannabis
use in in dementia care there are more
than one regularly using cannabis on a
two three time day daily basis we
usually start at about 10 milligrams of
THC and 10 milligrams of CBD per dose
we'll go down sometimes but usually
that's a starting dose it'll knock
elderly demented patients down for a
couple days and then they get up and
behave much differently with a marked
reduction in their agitated behaviors we
can use the Cowan Mansfield agitation
index as a scale to watch these changes
and they're doing quite well
families are reporting some improvement
in cognition overall the patients are
happier the families are happier and the
staff is much happier so this is going
on at this time these are not I are be
approved studies these are people in
institutions whose families want
cannabis used and under California law
we're able to do this for them so I
would hope to put some light on this as
far as what we are already doing some of
the doses have to go up very high and/or
to cover the needs for these agitated
patients up to 30 milligrams of THC and
CBD per dose in order to control some of
these very very agitated behaviors it's
not only helping the agitated behaviors
it's helping the pain the insomnia and
and many other aspects of these elderly
patients so could I just clarify that so
you you give them a dose of 10
milligrams THC plus 10 milligrams CBD
one time one per dose correct for
Hallett or max and then you have a
sustained effect after that how when do
you reduce them usually they get a dose
first thing in the morning again
sundowning at about 3 p.m. it's a daily
dose you use this is a this is not a
divided dose this is a per dose so we
may go it's 2 or 3 times daily in this
patient population thank you yeah and
one of the elements of that just to add
on that because of the the duration that
it takes for the cannabinoids to get on
board when you take it orally and the
bioavailability is significantly
impaired as well as we move forward with
different delivery mechanisms you know
we talk about the mucosal oral
absorption but there's other routes as
well be it nasal sprays for the more
quicker onset of action it's going to
give us an ability to titrate throughout
aggressive behavior in a slightly
different way as well that is true and
we are able to use oral doses as a PRN
order as well in this patient population
for agitation and insomnia thank you and
just in the interest of time I know
there's about six people standing right
now please and I just remind us to keep
we'll keep the questions to questions
and then and keep them brief because we
only have ten minutes and there's six
questions we have to get through hi
thank you guys for everything that
you're doing are you familiar with dr.
Chow at University of Florida's work on
Heil elects he's using THC curcumin and
melatonin as treatment for Alzheimer's
and I agree with dr. Jeff my mom with
Alzheimer's uses cannabis as well as
another friend same dose roughly 11 CBD
7 THC
times a day and helps remarkably I'm not
familiar with that word well there are
some animal rodents studies in
transgenic mice on combination of CBD
and THC and also with I think THC and
CBD alone and if there's some variation
and their results and so I can't I won't
say anything specific but in general
there seems to be an improvement it
tends to agree with what we've found in
behind simpler systems actually and
there is of a pretty high-end paper and
I believe Nature Medicine a year or so
ago showing the THC when put into the
directly into the brain has an effect
and positive effect on memory and older
animals so there's mounting scientific
evidence that these compounds actually
have an effect also there's a great
documentary called prescribed grass some
people might be familiar with it about
this population in Israel but I think
what you gotta distinguishes are these
things working do you need the
psychoactive component or not and my
feeling is in our the way we've looked
at it you really don't for the things
that we look at and so I think the
emphasis should be maybe on some other
compounds as he bd+ maybe other
compounds in cannabis do more research
we're gonna and again we got it we got
it we got eight minutes we got four more
questions to go through please keep your
questions to questions yeah it was just
curious if any of you guys especially at
UCLA or in general know of collaboration
with dr. Bredesen x' work on his kind of
root cause approach to Alzheimer's
prevention and treatment and using the
endocannabinoid or Fido cannabinoids you
know in collaboration with him at all
have we haven't been collaborating with
him hi I'm sorry more of a comment -
from Canada in the in I'm a cannabinoid
physician and specifically I do see a
lot
of patients in long-term care setting
and just to your point we are seeing
some real efficacy with reducing
responsive behaviors generally the the
dosing we're seeing is one part THC four
parts CBD for most of the the oils we're
using and it's really interesting
because in Ontario again we can do these
we have these anecdotal evidence but
antipsychotics without a diagnosis is a
reportable outcome for the government
when they do inspections of long-term
care homes so it's really we're really
utilizing it to reduce our
antipsychotics in that setting a because
it's the government's mandating it and B
were having success doing it Sunnybrook
just there's a study going on they're
using NAB alone and that'll be the first
randomized control trial study and the
evidence shows that they they had some
efficacy with nav alone reducing
responsive behaviors with dementia so
that's a new one it's not I don't think
it's published but that data was
presented at a conference in Chicago do
you have a question yes okay good this
is going back to dr. small I think you
mean a comment about the shrinkage that
can occur with prolonged use of cannabis
specifically in adolescents my question
is are are there isolated studies where
we know that that's occurring based on
cannabis uses usage as opposed to maybe
also alcohol playing playing a role in
that
so did I see you at Woodstock I'm trying
to no no then you bring up a point there
could be some related behaviors that
could have contributed to that and those
studies didn't show shrinkage in
adolescents that showed shrinkage when
those adolescents were older so there
could be confounded variables of course
yes that's right that's what I've come
across so I mean we try to control for
them in the studies but it's it's never
100% unless you're doing a prospective
mais controlled trial it's often very
difficult to tease out those confounds
but to even catch an effect like that
in any sort of a clinical trial them
sorry to catch an effect like that in a
sort of clinical trial the follow-up
would have to be quite long well the way
it's done yeah it have to be quite long
the way that study was done they
recruited people who you know have you
been a heavy marijuana user in the past
that's how they did it
yeah and the issue with that is what are
they using exactly right
is it 2 percent is it 15 percent is it
20 percent is it contaminated does it
have secondary pesticide you know what I
mean there's that's the problem with a
lot of the states that the studies are
out of they come out of the US no
disrespect intended I used to work here
but the the studies aren't legit okay
they say okay people are using this no
they don't know what they're using so
how can you have a clinical outcome
based on what you don't even know what
you're doing well first of all I
wouldn't say that the studies are not
legit you know I would say it's a
different kind of study and the quality
you know the the how compelling the
evidences depends on the design so
usually when these studies are published
in peer-reviewed refereed journals the
referees look at all those details to
try so that what are interpreted is it's
done in a fair manner so it but I would
say that a randomized controlled trial
usually if it's done well gives you more
compelling evidences called as in terms
of cause and effect thank you I
represent dr. Romer Sean and that first
intro presentation he went through was
talking about how we've been able to
stabilize the acids sorry so I represent
dr. Raphael mushrooms company and what
we've been able to do with Raphael is
stabilize the acids and then create
their synthetic derivatives of those and
you're mentioning that that's certainly
a part that you've been taking and I'd
like to hear voices around that versus
the actual natural plan
I'm yeah I'm familiar with his work but
I didn't quite understand the question
so the question there was you're
obviously going through the synthetic
option which is something that we're
pursuing well I mean this is the for us
it's very difficult to do anything but
that because we don't have the
facilities or the means to do there any
clinical trials and considering how it
is difficult it is to do and to work
with natural products and get any
leverage as far as interest in it it's
in in in some sense I mean Alzheimer's a
particularly difficult field so that's
what we're doing yeah our the goal is to
try to find a natural some components in
the marijuana plant that are effective
and we have to test these animal models
and really look good then we can modify
them chemically to be able to make them
into better compounds and some of the
metabolism of the of the cannabinoids is
tricky I mean they break down quite
readily some of them CBD it's it's so
they're from the chemistry point of view
there's ways to improve these compounds
and that's what we have done and that's
or where we're focusing have you been
working with the actual acids as such or
just the molecules of the plant we're
just that we've actually just starting
this we're just applied for an NIH grant
try to work on this we've done some work
with stuff we can buy chemicals can have
it always we can purchase but we're just
starting their work thanks hi my name is
Dustin Sulak I'm an osteopathic
physician I've been practicing
cannabinoid medicine in Maine for the
last nine years and one thing that we
often see in cannabinoid medicine is a
failure of clinical trials to be well
informed by those of us on the front
lines with clinical experience so I'm
really glad that you brought up this
topic of kind of reverse translation and
I my question to the panelists is how
can you inform yourselves on what's
happening in the world of klint
cannabinoid medicine on the front lines
so that you get better efficacy and
results in your trials and development
of
that are more likely to help people for
example in my practice I find like dr.
Hogan rather the THC is extremely
important and effective at sparing
antipsychotics benzodiazepines and other
beers list medicines and that there's
typically a therapeutic window where
there's a dose that reduces agitation
and a higher dose that produces
intoxication well the only way you can
get around that and their problem is you
got to do it in people so you can go
through all the toxicology studies that
those response studies and try you try
initially animals to get some idea how
much blood concentration you need in
order to get a therapeutic effect and
then you have to find a safe dose and
then work go tenfold Laura that started
you know with human see as they
metabolize the drug the same way as in
animals and so now you're sort of doing
this backwards everything is going
you're from humans to animals so that's
the question how that's going to work
out in the long term we'll see so so we
are we are out of time but I wanted to
add one thing to that is that we
actually have a road map just like how
the development of curcumin is almost a
roadmap for potentially how we pursue
cannabinoids as natural products the the
FDA recent approval of epidemics that
was based off of overwhelming anecdotal
data that precipitated drug development
and interest so there is a way to do
this there is a roadmap and it's how can
we learn through prospective
observational studies through surveys
and to help us design the clinical
trials and understand the questions we
need to be asking and unfortunately
we're out of time but I just wanted to
wrap up everything that was spoken about
here give us a round of applause for our
panelists at the end of the day sound
data data is mixed it's inconclusive
there's a lot of work that needs to be
done
animals aren't humans and last thing I'd
like to add is that the use of
cannabinoids for Alzheimer's disease for
both disease modification as well as
symptom management that's one of our
priority areas here at the UCLA cannabis
research initiative so thank you very
much enjoy lunch one more round of
applause for our panelists