good afternoon uh thanks everyone for
showing up this afternoon i appreciate
the organizers keeping the place so cold
so we all stay awake
um and it seems like folks don't like
flies so i don't know you know maybe we
scared a few of them off with the title
um dr douglas is not here today he
welcomed a new member of his family not
too long ago so he's managing that
little wrangling um tons of fun those
little ones but he's sorry he can't make
it and hopefully i can carry you know
carry things properly in his absence
so
you know horrifying title who let the
flies in
what we wanted to talk about there were
some things that we think are coming
down the pipeline in terms of concerns
questions and what else may be of
interest to
understanding the products that we're
using and understanding how to best
utilize the compositions of interest to
ourselves and especially to medical
patients
um it's probably not lost to anyone here
especially in the cannabis arena about a
valley you know it actually did happen
we had concerns with products that were
being utilized for vaporization
where those products were at what
exactly was in all of the compositions
of them
how many of them
actually persisted
unfortunately the pandemic certainly
curbed the
cdc's reporting um kind of sucked up all
the resources the last update was
february 25th of 2020 actually on the
valley website on the cdc's home page
there
so
we do know what happens we do know it
can happen so how do we think about what
happened what have we learned from it
and how do we best avoid it and a big
piece of that was we really need to
consider what we do for inhalation the
molecules that we're going to inhale are
very different in terms of a
toxicological profile than what else
we've used them for whether it be
topical use even oral ingestion routes
our lungs and our route of ingestion
through inhalation is very different
than if we are to consume them orally or
apply them topically
and
to consume them via inhalation we have
to heat things so
the rule in chemistry is about every 10
degrees in celsius chemical reaction
rates may double
and that's not a very big temperature
change when you start to think about how
hot some of the handheld devices might
get how hot a vaporizer might get
e-cigarette hardware
and especially when you go all the way
up to combustion so
it's something to not overlook it's
something that we definitely have to
consider and we need to kind of pay
attention to what might be the molecular
fate what might these things decompose
into how much of them might be around
and how do we actually you know concern
ourselves with this before we put
products out in the marketplace so that
we can avoid a situation like we saw
with the valley cases
what's presumed to be the major culprit
that formed ivali is
shown here vitamin e acetate and we
believe chemists believe that it is the
phenolic acetate function that caused
that to happen if you heat that hot
enough you start to see it break down
into a molecule we call ketene and this
is a highly reactive molecule so this
molecule is most likely what was causing
the chemical burns and the problems
inside the lungs and the airways and it
forms when you really really really heat
compounds like this
one current concern that i've got um we
heard it uh mentioned a little bit
earlier today thco or thc acetate it's
also a phenolic acetate now i don't
think anyone's done thermal degradation
studies on it to see its propensity to
form ketene
it may or may not form ketene under
typical conditions in vape hardware
and it's still a question that's out
there and hopefully we don't see other
problems like we saw with vitamin e
acetate
it's also interesting that vitamin
acetate may still be going around not
everybody necessarily got the memo and
it is raises the question is that
related to vitamin e acetate in specific
hardware or was it only always just that
molecule so what temperature
temperatures do things get to how hot
are these devices what does the molecule
experience for which period of time
all important questions
and i want to highlight the point that
vitamin e acetate is grass it is
generally recognized as safe for uses in
foods so it's not generally recognized
as safe for any and every use certainly
not for inhalation
this work presented here is
work from the strongen lab in oregon
state and they were exploring
cannabinoid degradation what's the fate
of cannabinoids when i heat them up via
a vape cartridge or via dabbing where
the temperatures might be a little
hotter they use both delta 9 thc and cbm
and you can see that the volatile
volatile organic content actually
comprises a number of different
molecules and i'd like to highlight that
there is acetone seen on the top two as
well so and i'll bring that up a little
bit later
but i think that the basic takeaway from
this is it's not only thc all the time
right so i start with thc but if i heat
it up it might decompose it falls apart
into other molecules some which may be
of interest some which may not be
and those things are really what's going
on when we're heating vape devices we're
utilizing those and through combustion
processes so we had previously published
we know how much is in a pre-roll and if
you go and combust that you do not find
100 of the thc going into the airway and
in fact you can't find all of the thc's
fate because it breaks down to things
like this which are hard to capture
terpenes unfortunately do the same thing
and depending upon which terpene you
have and again which temperatures you've
got you will see them start to degrade
in different ways and you will see a
different profile of the other volatile
substances that form
and here i'd also like to note that
acetone is a lot more prevalent i don't
know if there's a laser pointer on this
one or not
um but it's you know the second one
apologize for the chemistry the second
one on the mercedes one uh acetone the
third one on the lymanine one so we see
certain amounts of acetone and again
i'll bring that up a little bit later
but and beta-carotelline forms
predominantly acetone along with some
others so we've got a little bit of a
clue about what might be going on when
we start to heat these molecules under
different conditions and again it is
very condition specific so
we produced pure terpenes complex blends
from them and we started to do a lot of
analysis and you start to see
testing laboratories come back with
residual solvents you know like
how does this start to happen you know
where is the solvent coming from um
because it's not okay to put any
solvents into these products they should
shouldn't be around and if these
materials are coming from distillations
they should have no solvents such as
acetone or the other light volatiles in
there either there really
wasn't a rational reason for why these
things might be showing up on the tests
so the first part that we did was let's
just take a vial an empty vial put it
out there in the lab atmosphere and see
if there's acetone floating around and
maybe showing up
on some of the results because these
methodologies are very sensitive and can
detect these things at very low levels
residual solvent analysis is done via
headspace analysis with gcms so it is a
sensitive technique you can see very
small amounts of these things and it is
possible that you've got you know a lot
of acetone in a lab or other solvents
that might be confounding these results
we did not see that here that first
block there is the empty vial didn't
matter what happened in there was not a
lot of acetone present in the lab or
even in the vials
then we tested a series of other pure
terpenes and terpenoids we also mixed
them all together one to one to one and
we made a complex formulation that
mimicked one of the cultivar profiles
that we've seen as well and you can see
each of them started to show this
general trend and it's a little hard to
read perhaps because it's small but the
first
data point on the left is when we took
the vial and purged it with argon to try
and flush away as much of the lab's
atmosphere and impart a neutral you know
inert atmosphere of argon into the vial
sealed it and use that inside the
injection the next one is just
laboratory air that was pushed in after
we flushed with argon so we tried to
fill it up with air and the third data
point was when we added something with a
high oxygen content so boost oxygen type
stuff that we bought let's try to put as
much oxygen in there and see if we start
to see other degradations and
mostly we did we saw that the lab
atmosphere had a certain amount when you
remove that atmosphere you don't see it
it's argon based is very low in numbers
and when you add oxygen you see those
things go up a little bit and the
results were all statistically
significant
then we started to think well i don't
see it all growing down to acetone what
else might be happening
and this also tells us that our sample
preparation is critical to analyzing
exactly what's there so a big part of
analytical chemistry is how do i know
what i'm holding and how do i get it to
some sort of detection method that has
not altered exactly what i'm holding in
my hand and this kind of told us that
these residual solvent analyses probably
need a little work in sample prep the
injector temperatures in the gc the
methodologies of getting those vials
warmed up to put the volatiles in the
headspace all of those might have an
impact on the overall chemistry of
what's going on in the vial and that's
not necessarily representative of what
i'm holding in my hand or what's been
placed in my vape cart or other product
composition
and when you look into degradation i i
don't know if everybody might have heard
the talk earlier today about the
environmental chemistry that goes on
there's some pretty wild stuff that
actually happens to some of these
molecules over time under the right
conditions
and here's just a picture of some of the
pathways that go on in that regard
air oxygen other types of things can
catalyze those reactions certain
hardware inside of vape hardware or
metal catalysis might actually be a part
of that um we tried to add a little bit
of things to accelerate some of this and
we didn't see any great accelerations um
we think oxygen and the normal air was
the major culprit of these things but
there's still a little bit more work
ongoing before we're actually going to
publish all the results in this paper
but it does tell us there weren't really
these solvents inside of the you know
formulations that were produced or these
pure terpenes that we're getting it's
predominantly coming from analytical
methodology and i think that was an
important piece hopefully others will
start to adopt different analytical
methodology towards understanding how to
get good residual solvent results um
from compliance tests as well
and it made us start to think like could
we model uh potentially vape you know
hardware vape effluent streams utilizing
gas chromatographs so we is it a really
big giant vaporizer um in some sense
i've got a liquid that i'm going to put
into an injector it's going to heat to a
certain temperature it's going to try to
aerosolize or volatilize the molecules
that are in there and then they're going
to travel down the path and we can
detect them
and if you look at a you know handheld
e-cigarette it's pretty similar i've got
a liquid in there it starts to get hot
to a certain temperature air flows
through it and these molecules go down
an airway
happens to go into our airways but those
two things are pretty similar so i think
there's you know a glimmer of hope that
we might be able to model some vape
hardware in certain fashions or at least
glean toxicological perspectives on what
types of molecules may be formed in
which amounts from the breakdown of the
compositions that we're using inside of
these e-cigarette hardware pieces or
concentrates dabs or even other
inhalable products
and it's important to note this is
probably a good picture brad put this in
there i'm mostly vegan so he made sure
that we showed the steak to everyone
but you can all assess you know
different things change via time and
temperature so the hotter i've had my
steak on the grill the longer it's been
there the less rare it is the different
in color it is the different taste and
flavor and the different smells that i
get and all of those are telling us
there are chemical transformations and
chemical changes that are going on and
again it's the time and temperature
relationship so
it's important to note that gc liquid
samples what i place inside this you
know auto sampler isn't always what the
detector is going to be only looking at
my injector temperature may change
things and different chemistry may even
happen before it goes all the way down
the path to the detector
and it's important to consider that
that's also probably happening to some
degree inside of the vape hardware so my
cannabis extract my cannabis formulation
may be different than what's actually
hitting my lungs
to which extent i think is a very very
difficult complex and technically
challenging problem to answer
um i don't want to send alarm bells off
we've been seeing lots and lots and lots
of inhalation used for lots of time and
we don't see many many acute problems i
think the you know the number of valley
cases up to february of 2020 was only
around 2 800. um there are probably tens
of millions of folks that vape almost
every day so i want to keep the number
and relative perspective no one deserves
any of that harm so even one is an
alarming case
but it's not like we're seeing you know
tens of millions or hundreds of
thousands every day presenting with this
problem that would be a very different
scenario
unfortunately we kind of confound what's
going on with the chemical compositions
and the profiles by playing the name
game so we published
early on 2015 i believe it was
how your chemical profile on a flower
might not represent the the name so a
lot of folks will call something blue
dream or og kush it doesn't mean that
every one of those has the exact same
blue dream or og kush chemical profile
unfortunately
there is no nomenclature that's fixed
towards chemical compositions this goes
further when you even say that this
flower was what i used to do my
extraction
in this case it was diamond dust and
when that flower was extracted i have a
diamond dust concentrate so i think for
most of us
most general consumers the assumption is
well all the molecules i wanted just
perfectly went exactly over into the
concentrate because that's what i wanted
them to do
chemistry experience tells me the
molecules almost never do exactly what i
want to do ever
and here is a kind of a graphical
representation showing yes you pulled
some of them off but they're now in
different ratios they are in different
types you probably have isomeric or
oxidative things that have happened
throughout that extraction process
and there are prevalent pieces like this
no matter what your extraction process
is i do not have a perfect process to
remove only cellulose or only amino
acids and leave behind just the
cannabinoids and just the terpenes
exactly as the flower produced them so i
think you know we hear a lot of talk and
recently there's been a lot of talk
in california because the department of
cannabis control just released some
draft regulations talking about which
terpenes or terpene types ingredients
might be useful for inhaled products
and
a lot of folks thought that their
extraction for cannabis derived terpenes
meant that it was exactly what the
flower presented and that is
unfortunately not the case so it's
probably good that we've got greater
diversity but something to pay attention
to and something to know i can't say my
blue dream flower necessarily always
drives the blue dream concentrate
effects because those compositions are
very different
there are approaches that you can use
using individual molecules that will get
you to replicate the flowers profile in
a much greater fashion so with far
better precision and accuracy you can
drive profiles that look exactly like
the ones the flower produced you of
course have other flexibility that goes
along with that as well but in that case
you can say this is far greater
representation of what was on the flower
doesn't mean that any one of them is any
better than the other it just means that
this is an exact copy or as close to
exact as we can get today
of what the flower produced and if we
are trying to say hey we understand
these flowers we understand their use
and the patient populations that are
benefiting from them here's how we can
put those profiles into other products
such as inhalable products like
vaporizers
other concentrate forms or infused
products like tinctures topicals and
edible products as well
keeping those profiles consistent
standardized and highly scalable is what
is really important important to medical
patients in the medical population and i
think also to adult brands that say look
i have a consistent product so
consistency as we heard from the
cultivation efforts earlier today very
very difficult to come up with the exact
same profiles every single time
how do i treat a molecule as a molecule
and replicate that in a standardized
scalable fashion
using the individual components and
formulating them will lend towards that
type of approach and i think leads to
great scalability
and that is a good representation of
what the flowers produced
importantly we think it is kind of a
good collective time for all of us to
start considering inhalation safety
we know that the large bulk of the
dispensary shelves today are inhalation
products whether they are flowers that
are being consumed concentrates or vape
products right those things can comprise
the significant portion of cannabis
products today there are also some
unique benefits that are imparted by
inhalation products certain medical
patients and patient populations really
demand that type of rapid response they
demand that type of effectiveness and
they're not finding it from other
delivery forms so inhalation does offer
a unique route and i think it's you know
kind of a critical part for us
scientists to say how can i develop this
in a very intelligent way to lend
towards the lowest toxicology
perspective possible while delivering
standardized consistent products for
patients to benefit from
we all got started at least i got
started because of medical cannabis most
of california's forgotten the word of
medical of late most of the west coast
too but they are an important part of
this population they are still driving a
lot of the adult use store
sales and volumes and i really think
it's important that they are never
forgotten like this is important to keep
a very good quality product that is
standardized and consistent so these
patients can get that benefit and relief
that they deserve and that we all have
been fighting for and continue to fight
for
it's um i think important upon us today
to say let's come together and start to
talk about inhalation safety let's try
to educate regulators we can see in
different states that some of them
certainly don't know chemistry very well
or are not really understanding some of
the nuances that go with inhalation
safety
the food extract manufacturing
association had this problem
a while ago
they convened their own panels they got
together and they said let's start to
understand how we can assess the
toxicological profile of these extracts
that we're producing how do we know
they'll be generally recognized as safe
for use in foods at which levels and
it's important i think that the cannabis
industry understands that and tries to
model that it's also important that we
do not let happen
anyone consider cannabis to be just like
nicotine and tobacco they are very very
very different plants they have very
different uses very different chemical
profiles for importance and use and it
would be remiss to all of us if someone
says well let's just treat it like
tobacco
that would be a problem and we would
leave a lot of people in a bad position
that are looking you know to cannabis
for medical purposes
so a good start might be hey let's take
the information in the body of knowledge
that we know that was generated by
things like vitamin e acetate or things
that we've seen other studies with that
says let's not use those for inhalation
or these are the things that are found
in the cannabis plant we've been
inhaling and consuming them even at
combustion temperatures for a while
let's say that those things are pretty
okay and start here
because building this body of
toxicological work is going to take a
considerable amount of time money and
effort so we won't have this answer next
week even if we also decided to lock
ourselves in this room it will take a
lot longer than that but we have to
start somewhere and we can't start with
just some regulators saying i think this
makes sense
i think that's going to lend up to being
much more problematic and really trying
to unwind some of those things can be
very very difficult
so some of the key points that i want to
make sure everyone understands is the
compositions change with all of your
process steps so anytime i do anything
even if that's setting up my analytical
sample i might see changes in the
chemical composition that i thought i
was dealing with or that i put inside of
a formulation or a specific device
extraction changes them and heat is the
major culprit and heat accelerates
degradation with oxygen air and other
things that are floating all around us
it's very important to get your
analytical methodology right i think a
lot of current labs today don't have the
residual solvent methodologies super
dialed in that's why we're seeing some
of these nuances but we don't always see
a lot of products fail
for compliance testing but there's a way
to kind of tighten this up in a simple
fashion make it easy and
more robust and we'll get more accurate
understanding of what's going on
i think understanding aerosol testing
like the work out of strongens lab and
some others now that are kind of getting
along with this that field is advancing
and using gas chromatographs to kind of
understand
what we might see in these you know
heated effluent streams out of vape
devices or even via concentrate
consumption
and other inhalation means is very
important towards informing our
toxicological perspective and
understanding of which molecules might
be best on a permitted or prohibited
list
and again the name game still persists i
don't know how to solve this one yet
maybe someday in the shower we'll get a
good idea and we'll actually say like
this is a good answer
it's a complex problem it hopefully will
start to
get less
i'd say less problematic as things start
to be standardized and more consistent
if we can start with consistent
cultivation consistent processing
methods we should all be able to lead
towards more consistent products in the
end
and as i described there are a couple
approaches that might really help us
elucidate consistent formulations and
chemical profiles of those products
i thought this was a little bit of a
funny one but chemistry is definitely
not to be feared nothing in life should
be feared as long as you can understand
it um but you know i thought this was
funny until i was sitting there talking
to a legislative aide and a staff member
that were trying to write rules and
regulations around hemp and the novel
cannabinoids and the first thing that i
got after i was introduced by an
independent third party they said oh i
did terrible in chemistry and failed on
math i was told that there wouldn't be
much of that here so i'm like well delta
a delta nine delta ten and all these
other things i'm gonna start throwing
you are all chemistry so
other than giving you copy paste
language you know i don't know how we
can help but we have to have a
conversation it's not impossible to
understand but these things are what are
important when we're talking about what
can patients and consumers access what
might we be putting into the public
sphere what might cause harm or not and
we do
unfortunately not have a lot of
science-minded folks that are writing
the rules regulations or legislation
especially the legislation most of them
seem to be
english or legal majors um they are
fearful of the word chemistry and math i
can assure you i've seen it firsthand
but i you know try to gently offer
education and always available for
support and i think most of us
scientists are always happy to have the
conversation and educate so don't be
afraid of it it's not a bad word
chemistry is actually okay i've got my
little boy saying molecules already he's
under three it's fine
but understanding the world around us
and what we can get from that is really
the important piece of that and thank
you all for your time and attention
today i appreciate it
[Applause]
happy to take any questions
good luck no i'm just kidding um i get
this question a lot so how do you enable
a patient with just a minute or two like
what's the best way to go about it do as
much research as you can on the producer
and their consistency find certificate
of analyses they're supposed to be
available in most states by rules and
regulation you would be surprised how
hard it is to try and get those even
when they are supposed to be available
by rule
but you can if you are persistent so be
persistent do your research go find all
the cfas that you can and you can
probably pretty quickly assess
standardized you know standardized
product and process relatively quickly
if you start seeing numbers with wide
ranges
if it's at the same lab that lab is
probably consistently doing the same
thing they might be off the center of
the target but they're consistent so a
relative consistent analysis showing the
inconsistent profiles tells me there's a
lot of variability going on in the back
end um and then try through experience
and communication have you tried
different batches do you know like have
that conversation do you know have these
been consistent for you
um it's tough because we're all you know
variable every day right so even if i
get the same products i might need a
little more a little less from day to
day but through certificate of analysis
research and then ask a testing lab or
you know come back to the doctor and say
i found these 10 things what do you
think you probably can assess pretty
quickly not the producer or yes that's
the type of producer for me it's like
the best that we can do today so far
i i think yeah like it's so if i'm
looking for inhalable product or a vape
cart how do i assess that from a patient
or consumer perspective yeah what's on
the label what else might be going into
there um you know i'm not fearful of
synthetic or natural labels i think
there's a misnomer natural means safe
well ricin belladonna other things
they're all toxic poison ivy natural
totally not safe um what molecules are
being used in them are there any in
there that might cause concern have i
seen that from other states that's
pretty complicated and difficult i think
for most of the general population to do
but states are starting to require
disclosures on some of the molecules in
there i think there's a problem with
that where you start to read some of
these things you're like i can't even
pronounce them right there's they're too
big what does that mean if i read a
report it might really be off because
that toxicology report might be on the
pure substance and at high
concentrations and just that molecule it
might be bad but in a vape card it's at
a fraction of a fraction of a percent
and it's really okay the dose makes the
poison so i'd say you know consistency
of production you know are you seeing
the same effects if you used it from
batch over batch and what's on the label
and what do you know about it ask the
producer if they're trying to answer in
a very good fashion you could probably
feel more comfortable that they felt
confident but if they're like ducking
the question that's probably a flag to
say they either don't know or they don't
want you to know and you can probably
move on to someone else that would be
more transparent
[Music]
uh um our gc analysis on acetone was a
residual headspace um headspace solvent
analysis with gcms so there are
headspace files that were capped and
sealed placed in the headspace
autosampler warmed up to temperature
injected and then hit the ms and then we
could see acetone was like one of the
major culprits there are some other
things that you could see obviously the
ones that california's residual solvents
on the list that they look for but you
can't detect everything so that big
complex picture says there's all sorts
of other stuff that probably is present
but the lab's not tuned to look for so
when you see a small amount of acetone
yeah that's there and then in that slide
it was at i think 6.7 or so so that's
what that breakdown into but it broke
down to a lot of other stuff that you're
not detecting so we're gonna try to see
how much of the actual terpene is left
it's a little tricky experiment um but
that's how we got there
no we didn't do it that way no he didn't
have and that would be an interesting
one like if i inhaled and then exhaled
what did i catch out here well i what
did i keep in my lungs and bloodstream
too i could see maybe traces of some
stuff but my concentrations go down and
it gets harder you can hook up
e-cigarettes to devices um strongens
lab's done that we've done some of that
we say i've trapped all of the you know
vapor stream coming out of an
e-cigarette device or even a pre-roll
what do i see this way and there's a
couple of technical challenges with what
did i trap how did i trap it am i sure i
got it all is it stuck in a tube before
i got there you know how do i figure out
the entire mass balance like if i
started with 100 molecules of these and
it broke into 30 things how much of each
of those equals that 100 molecules you
don't always get there and it's a little
frustrating but it's because i'd
probably need five different detection
methods to kind of make sure i could
fill out the whole picture and that's
just too costly to do right now
sure
um
so they're the live rosin live resin
hydrocarbon extracts sauce batter butter
whatever you want to call it these days
co2 extracts any extracts composition is
different than the flour are they any
safer better they're all different right
so i don't know if we should use words
like safer or better i hear a lot of
folks like i think this one's better
great personal opinion thank you for
that maybe i could try this one or the
others and we'll see if i agree but
you're not telling me anything other
than your personal opinion for what you
think is better what's best is what's
right for the consumer and the patient
and what they get the best results with
which may be very different than what
that person thought was best
they produce different profiles some of
the live rosin or other things might
have higher
contents of other molecules like fats
and waxes depending upon how they
actually go down the process and not all
those processes are exactly standardized
or exactly the same so two different
producers even doing a live rosin type
of process may produce very different
things from the same plants depending
upon exactly how they do it
are they bad i mean i think they're
solvent-less so you haven't introduced
anything
you have a pretty good composition that
you're resulting to but that again is
different than what i started with the
flower and there could be things that
change terpene compositions in that
right so i've got pressure that's
similar to heat if i've done any sorts
of things that have tried to touch these
molecules they may oxidize they may
isomerize they may come into different
things so some folks we know took like
cannabis derived terpenes and threw them
through the analysis and you're like i
can see about half of what's here even
though i thought i saw a lot of this
stuff to start with on the flower
it's become a lot of other things that
are similar in structures so they're
probably isomers or other oxidative
degradings from that and it's you know
not the same are some of those allergens
sensitizers could they be irritating to
folks we do know that some of these
molecules may become ones like that but
we're not seeing you know everyone
present with tons of problems but you do
have some folks say i was irritated by
that that one bothered me um we don't
always know exactly why at a molecular
sense so again it's hard to say better
best or what's good or bad over which
method i think there's something for
everyone as long as we can consistently
produce it then we can start to
understand what might be right for which
types of consumers or patients
so um great question right it's a
vitamin estate bed we all know that for
sure are there others some states have
said mct because of lipoid pneumonia so
we know if you have like mineral oil
type ones really long chain fats and
fatty acids those might pool in the
lungs and you can't clear those
so you should stay away from things of
that type how long is that carbon chain
until you get there is a great question
mct you know if we're relatively
speaking mineral oil is like c40 and mct
can be like 9 to 12 or 15.
i don't know is that short enough to say
it's okay or is it still too long to be
a problem so i think the best approach
is saying what's in the plant how do i
use these things that people have been
inhaling and consuming before and try
and keep those in relative amounts that
are similar to the plant because i've
seen that be okay over the test of time
adding new things like that can be very
very tricky i think you know what's a
good solution to that we've seen other
states take out squalane and squalene
because they were concerned with some
cases of that
again i think it's going to be really
hard to say what's the best thing to put
in there other than what we've already
been seeing and could say hey this is
very close but you could say vitamin e
was fine and vitamin e acetate looks
very close and now it's not fine so
that's a very slippery delicate slope
and i think it's really really hard to
assess without a great toxicological
model which we really don't have yet
today so staying close to the plant
seems like the best place to start
sure
hi buddy
opinion of what
yeah so
um
are delta a products derived from cbd
safe or not and you know again with the
caution of what the word safe really
means so delta 8 i think is a fantastic
molecule it has a ton of therapeutic
benefits
maybe even a wider therapeutic window
than delta 9 because it has mitigated
psychoactivity for most folks but yet it
still has some obviously or we wouldn't
be talking about it
i think if you make that the right way
and you know all of your impurities in
that process it can be safe
is it currently being produced like that
out there today i don't think there's
many of that at all there might be some
but
i don't think that people are watching
what else is formed we've screened a few
of these things you see a lot of other
cannabinoid-like molecules that are like
there we don't know what they are
it's possible that you can have very
good clean safe delta eight products yes
i should be able to test them for heavy
metals pesticides residual solvents and
the gamut that we do for all the delta
nine products but that's not required
are folks actually doing that every time
if someone checking that i don't you
know i think that that's probably not
i think of the delta eight space
probably more like 2012 2010 california
you know where like everyone's kind of
doing whatever they want and no one's
really checking um there's some
laboratory efforts that say oh i think i
saw this but there's been a lot of
reports of well this folk this group
said there was no delta nine but another
lab looked at it and there was a
considerable amount of delta nine
because they were trying to say it was
legal to let that go where whereas it
really wasn't so i think the analysis is
probably not really on par with all of
those i think therefore i'm not seeing
all the other cannabinoid derivatives
that might be forming
um and i think you can do it very well i
just don't think there's a lot of that
going on yet today
for the terpene analysis no we only did
those in the headspace samples so we did
not try and put a pure terpene in like a
vape cart um or on a dab nail and try
and see some of that the strongen lab
did a little bit of that with mercene
and some other
pure terpenes or a model cannabinoid
composition
but we didn't do any of that work
directly ourselves putting a pure
terpene in a vape car is actually a
problem the viscosity is wrong and it
flies right through it most of the time
so they're not always built for that so
that's going to be a little tricky i
think
very good question yes
yep
so with a vape card does my chemical
composition that i actually have in the
cartridge change over time
yes it's very possible right because i'm
heating those things and what
temperature did i heat it to how hot did
it get there how long was it i think a
lot of us have probably experienced you
know the end of this one seems a lot
different than the beginning of that one
so you can taste it in some respects
that you know that there are changes
what are all those changes what did they
become i don't think that there's been
much of any study on that just yet but
that is important work to do because the
lifetime of that being effective in
terms of dosing and what you're
delivering to patients or are i for am i
forming
um you know bad compounds that i
wouldn't want to be inhaling in that
respect that certainly is a theoretical
possibility but i don't have any data or
information to share specifically on
that
right question though
sure
okay great question
are there any terpenes present in
cannabis that if i heat them too much
become carcinogenic compounds so we've
seen things become benzene that's a
carcinogen right so known carcinogenic
properties of some of those degradants
so yes technically the answer is yes do
we see those at exceedingly large
amounts that they could cause cancer are
they overwhelmed by the anti-cancer
properties of cannabis in general you
know i i don't think we're seeing a lot
of folks get cancer and dr tashkin did a
nice metadata you know met a study that
said we don't see lung cell carcinomas
in people that smoke cannabis so while
we're seeing these in the smokestream
you know carcinogenic compounds that
have formed via cannabinoids and
terpenes being thermally degraded
do we have a cause for alarm for causing
cancer
i think we would have seen you know a
lot of chronic cannabis smokers having
cancer of the airways the lungs and
other things like you see with tobacco
and we haven't seen that yet so they
technically form are they at large
enough concentrations now i can i can
certainly say the rat gets cancer when i
dunk it in a bucket of benzene but you
know if i have a two molecules floating
around it every other day does that
cause cancer for it it's a you know a
matter of dose that we get to in that
regard um so technically they do but are
they cause for cancer alarms i don't see
that just yet
maybe we'll go with the last one and
then i'll let toby get up here
[Music]
sorry i didn't hear the first part of
the question
ah that's a good one that's a good
that's a really good one um i probably
lost like more sleep over this question
than like any other cannabis question so
if i had infinite resources i was the
government oh my gosh
um well now i can dream right what would
we do about the naming game i think we'd
all have to start tagging a code you
know some sort of like large enough
you know sequence of code that it would
be always unique kind of like the
blockchain and say
this is what i meant by that and then
capture it what we can in a snapshot in
time to say well what did you mean and
later do i have any of it to kind of
fill in some of those gaps
would we see you know
possible groupings that come from that
and say cool we can say that this has a
little part of the code and then i can
call it whatever i want so i think today
a good step would be you know bob's blue
dream right it's the branded version of
whatever i wanted to call it so we don't
want to do away with all the lineage and
all the history that got us here there's
some nice elements of that and it can be
very informative to folks so you can't
just scrap it and start over but we may
transition to a place you know 50 years
from now where no one really knew what
blue dream was or cared much because now
we have new names that say this is what
it is how do we get there with this
bridge maybe it's you know this brand's
blue dream well hey when i had bob's
blue dream it was different than bill's
blue dream you know they both claim they
started blue dream they swear they got
the clones from the same guy and they
very well may have but their production
process and their nutrients and their
way they grew it and how they did it and
how they brought it to me in the store
ended up causing two different effects
so if i can brand and say i'm doing this
consistently and i call this my blue
dream i think that's a pretty good place
to start today
um and then if we like really said that
has to go to the place that can test the
daylights out of it store it so that if
we learn how to test them later we can
add those things to that info
that might be a way to go about it but
you'd probably have to be the government
with large resources and the ability to
say i can you know stockpile all
all this cannabis for infinite times
under cold conditions to do it
thank you though very good fun question
thank you again for your time
[Applause]
you