Hello everybody welcome so today we're
going to talk about total yeast and mold
if you are in the lab industry you're
probably very familiar with total yeast
in mold if you're not some of this may
be very new to you so I am going to do a
brief overview at the beginning
so what is total yeast in mold so when
we talk about total yeast and mold
testing we're talking about looking at
quantitatively the number of colony
forming units that are present in one
gram of sample or cfu per gram that's
how we quantify it when we report out a
result we say there's 3 000 cfu per gram
or 10 000 cfu per gram or whatever that
number may be and total yeast in mold
can include so many different species it
includes everything every total mold or
Yeast you can think of it includes so
aspergillus penicillin candida
sportabolis
fusarium and many more and that's one of
the complexities with doing total yeast
and mold testing when you're looking for
so many different things how do you know
if you're seeing them all and how do you
know if everything you're seeing is
dangerous or if everything you're seeing
is good what is the problem that arises
with total yeast in mold testing
so total yeast in mold testing in a
laboratory there's three primary ways
that Laboratories are providing total
yeast in mold testing the first being
culture-based plating methods and that's
going to be using an agar or a petri
film or membrane filter and growing
colonies they're going to take a sample
dilute it with a media add you know the
sample to the plate put that in the
incubator and then wait for it to grow
and see what happens and then they're
going to count those colonies the next
way is going to be qpcr methods or
quantitative polymerase Chain Reaction
methods and what that's going to do is
you're going to take the sample and
you're going to completely isolate the
DNA you're going to isolate both the
Cannabis DNA and the microbe DNA after
that you're going to use primers and
other mix that with that the primers
that'll look for both the Cannabis DNA
and the microbe DNA and then you're
going to put that on the PCR and it's
going to heat and cool and heat and cool
and it's going to replicate and then if
those microbes are present you'll see
this fluorescence and you'll be able to
detect and quantitate the amount of
yeast in mold present and finally is
going to be most probable number methods
and these are culture-based methods but
the principle behind them is slightly
different so you're not physically
growing colonies and this you're
actually looking at specific
characteristics so whether that be
turbidity changes or acid production and
you're using that to predict the amount
of cells that would grow so you're not
actually culturing it but it is in a
sense a culture-based method
so with this you run all of these
different experiments and you get tons
of different results which is the reason
for this comparison study and so first
off what we wanted to do was we wanted
to analyze cannabis samples using
different types of plates
um whether that be agar Petri film and
membrane filters plating is a really big
controversy right Labs you go to lab a
and you get a plating result of this you
go to lab B and you get a plating result
drastically different so why what is
going on there and so we wanted to be
able to compare these methods and assess
the reproducibility of the methods both
individually and then also against one
another and through this we were going
to also be able to determine how the
non-homogeneous nature of cannabis
impacts total yeast in mold testing we
all know cannabis is not homogeneous so
what happens if I take a one gram scoop
here and a one gram scoop here do I get
completely different results which
result is right did I get way more yeast
in mold in this scoop unless you Eastern
mold in this scoop so that raises
questions and then also to establish
true incubation times for each plating
method a lot of the different
manufacturers that produce these plates
make recommendations incubate for 48 to
72 hours well guess what if you're a
cannabis lab and you've been told by a
manufacturer you could incubate for a
minimum of 48 Hours chances are cannabis
labs are just going to proceed with that
because turnaround time is important
they need to get those results out even
though that method may need to go longer
and so we wanted to establish that as
well
so sample prep and design what we did
here was we took three unique samples
and these three unique samples were
weighed up five times and then we
pleated those samples at three different
dilutions and we used seven different
types of plates so four agars two Petri
films and a membrane filter and then we
also took a single aliquot that you see
here and we weighed it five times or we
had it weighed once and then we prepped
it five times and the goal of that was
to show the reproducibility from in one
aliquot so if you have one aliquot
theoretically it should have the same
amount of yeast and mold throughout so
we should get the same result for every
single one of those samples
so true incubation times let's talk
about that first so as I mentioned uh
manufacturers will make a recommendation
you know 48 to 72 hours 72 to 96 hours
but that's all they give you and so it's
the laboratory's responsibility to
validate that however Laboratories
aren't always the best at that or don't
really know how to go about doing that
and so that's what we did here and these
are the true incubation times we
established for total yeast and mold for
each of these and the true incubation
time was established as the point in
time when no new colonies formed and
instead the colonies only started to
grow they just got bigger so you'll see
on the next slide this drastic
difference between that 48 and 72 hour
and that's where we're going to focus is
that Petri film rapid yeast and mold
this true incubation time is 72 hours
even though the manufacturer
recommendations is anywhere from 48 to
72.
and that's what you can see here so you
can see here this top set of plates is
going to be the rapid yeast in mold
after 48 hours so with these samples we
put them in after 24 hours we pulled
them out of the incubator took pictures
put them back in for another 24 pulled
them out took pictures we did that all
the way up to 120 hours and you can see
there is a drastic difference between
the 48 hour and the 72 hour plate
results and based on this and then
reading those plates and attempting to
count those plates I mean counting the
48 hour plates is not easy and even when
you do count them you're drastically
under quantifying what that true amount
is we're looking at an average cfu per
gram at 48 Hours of only 44 000 whereas
by 72 hours we had 165 000 and I did
want to note here that you know past the
72 hours that average stayed about the
same we really didn't see an increase
which is why we established that as that
true incubation time
next is going to be the lack of
reproducibility we saw between plates so
here is going to be a drbc and a Sab Dex
plate and this is the same exact sample
prep so it's out of the same tube we
prepped it and plated it on the two
different plates and you can see for the
drbc we got an average of like 127 000
versus an average of 86 000 with stab
decks now if you're in the world of
micro you may say wait that's not that
different those are kind of duplicate
numbers but in the world of Florida
where our regulations are a hundred
thousand cfu per gram this is the
difference between a product passing and
a product failing so if a laboratory was
using Sab decks they would pass this
sample but if a laboratory is using drbc
they would fail the sample
additionally is going to be suppressions
at low dilution so this is the sabdex
plates again and what I want to point
out here is that 200x dilution and so
you can see that 200x dilution that
average is only about 25
000 across those and that's much lower
than the average we're seeing for that
1000x and that 10 000x and ultimately I
think it's due to over saturation
there's so many microbes present that no
more can grow however if you're using
this 200x it is going to drive your
overall average down so it's going to
take the average you can see if you
ignore it your average goes from you
know 61 to 81 000 it goes from 165 000
to 235 000 and from 86 000 to 115 000.
so the dilutions you use are crucial if
you are plating you need to be making
sure you're using dilutions that make
sense for your sample and for your
sample type
then we had the lack of homogeneity and
reproducibility so that sample that I
told you we took the one aliquot and we
prepped it five times out of the same
exact tube these are the results we got
so a hundred and ten thousand fifty
thousand two hundred and ten thousand
ninety thousand and eighty thousand so
all over the board you know this is
again the difference between for States
who have a ten thousand cfu per gram
limit this is all failing it's not a
problem but for States like Florida
where we have a hundred thousand cfu
gram per limit what do we do here what
is the correct answer is this product
failing or is this product passing
so conclusions for this portion of the
experiment are that you know the lack of
homogeneity seen in cannabis flower can
make it difficult to determine
quantitative total yeast and mold
results you may take a scoop here and
get one result the scoop there and get
one result it may not be due to the
method itself it may be due to the
sample and so how do we create a more
homogeneous sample in that sense also
the use of different agars or media can
lead to variations in the number of
organisms that can successfully grow so
certain plates have certain antibiotics
which allow certain organisms to grow
but other organisms can't grow and so
depending on what a lab is using they
may be able to skew those results and
some of them may not even be realizing
they're doing that they may just be
using what they've been told is you know
the gold standard to use for plating and
they do that and then now they could be
under quantifying those results also the
dilutions used during the plating
process can impact those spinal
calculations you need to make sure
you're working in the proper range if
you're doing a 100x and your sample has
a hundred thousand cfu per gram you're
not going to be able to grow all of
those colonies on a plate and you're
going to skew those results low once you
take that average and then the
incubation time for each plate type must
be determined prior to processing
samples all Laboratories really need to
go about this process they need to take
whatever plate type they're using and
you need to let it grow see what happens
establish that true incubation time
truly validate when those samples are
ready to come out of the incubator
and then also the use of internal
controls is something that I think we
should consider I don't know how to go
about doing this but I figured what
better of a conference to kind of say
you know this would be a great thing to
have think about qpcr we use an internal
control to make sure our extraction work
to make sure we did it properly the
chemistry side we use internal standards
to make sure things worked properly so
is there a way to implement something
like that into the plating process
with that we're going to switch to
talking about remediation of failing
flower products so with cannabis uh if
it fails for total yeast in mold there
or aspergillus there's a common
technique that is to remediate and
whether you're remediating that through
lots of different options but two of the
main options are going to be ozone which
is going to be known as it's a willow is
what the most common brand is called or
the rad source which is going to use
x-rays to remediate so it's going to
radiate the product basically use the
x-rays kill the yeast in mold
theoretically and then that will result
in the product being safe we see people
doing this and as a laboratory who runs
qpcr primarily people remediate their
product and it still fails and they're
not happy they said I killed all of the
yeast in mold and I said well I still
see the yeast in mold and they said
we'll switch to plating so we said we'll
look into it and that is where this
study came about so we in this we wanted
to analyze cannabis samples pre and post
radiation using qpcr both qpcr regular
and qpcr with grim reefer and Grim
reefer will remove that dead DNA and get
rid of whatever they may have killed and
then agar plates and Petri film we then
wanted to add an enrichment step to that
plating process of the radiated product
to measure cell viability so one of the
thoughts here is sublethal cell injury
the cells aren't actually being killed
they're just being injured and so if we
give them an environment that makes them
happy maybe they'll grow for you and
then you can actually properly
quantitate so we wanted to add this
enrichment step to kind of see what
happened there and then also we wanted
to look at the pre and post samples for
cannabinoids and terpenes to see what
that was also doing to the product
so for this experimental design what we
did was we took all of these lovely
different samples so we had pre-rad post
rad two weeks post rad four weeks post
rad six weeks post-drad and eight weeks
post-rad and I want to mention that the
pre and post router the same exact
sample the client literally took a
sample grabbed a handful of it out
before radiating it put it in the
radiate then grab more of it and gave it
to us but the two weeks four weeks six
weeks and eight weeks are different
samples they're just those time points
Outpost radiation the reason for doing
that is to see if you know after eight
weeks have those cells repaired
themselves and are now we're going to
have tons of yeast in mold growth
whenever we go to Plate this
so we took all of those samples we
prepped them in triplicate then we
plated them at three dilutions using
drbc and 3M rapid Easton mold and then
we also analyzed those samples via qpcr
and qpcr with grim reefer
and this is the average cfus that we saw
across the board so anything in red is
going to be those failing cfus in the
State of Florida so a hundred thousand
over a hundred thousand cfu per gram and
you can see that that pre-rad sample
across the board it failed even with you
know the use of grim reefer brought the
number down some but it still failed
plating you know three hundred thousand
two hundred fifty thousand three hundred
and thirty thousand and a hundred and
forty two thousand so it's very evident
that flower was extremely contaminated
not good definitely don't want that
flower on the market
um the post rad however you can see when
we ran qpcr on it we got 435 thousand
but then when we plated it we only saw
1600 and 1400 and this is without that
enrichment step so no enrichment step
these are the numbers that we were
seeing so drastically lower numbers
across the board so the theory of the
reason why you get higher results with
qpcr is because you're not destroying
the DNA but it's dead seem to make sense
but we still weren't convinced we're not
100 convinced that this product is safe
for human consumption and so that's when
we added this enrichment step and so
what we did here was and you can see
these little
circles that I've circled these are
little dots that are growing we don't
know what they are we don't know if
they're trichome interactions we don't
know if they're just particulate or are
they colonies that are attempting to
form but something has happened during
this radiation process and now these
colonies can't grow I don't know what it
is so I want to figure out what it is so
we took those samples put them in the
incubator for three hours and then we
plated them again and that allowed us to
enrich them give them that time to get
excited and get happy and if they were
alive hopefully to grow for us
and so here is the cfu averages after
enrichment so with no enrichment for
that pre-rad sample you saw you know
about 300 000 or so after enrichment you
saw way way higher numbers which tells
me that my enrichment process worked
that's why I wanted to enrich that
pre-rad sample is to show that if you
enrich it it's going to grow you know if
it's there if it's happy if it's in the
good juice it's gonna work and we were
able to show that with that but then
post rad you can see we did see a slight
increase in some of these samples but
nothing drastic nothing that would lead
us to believe that the product was
failing as far as if we're going to
Plate it however that doesn't mean that
these cells are not viable but not
culturable so are they still viable are
they still dangerous but can we just not
culture them
so looking at cannabinoids and terpenes
then is going to be our pre-rad and our
post rad flower here so to the naked eye
these flower samples may look the same
also these pictures may not be the best
however if you look at these in person
and you are looking at cannabis flour
all day every day like our team is you
get samples in that are radiated and we
can normally tell we're like this went
through radsource or this went through
Willow because they look almost bleached
they aren't as vibrant they aren't as
green and so what does that mean what is
that doing to the flower I don't know
but for a consumer they may never notice
they may never see the difference in
this and they may never be told that
their product went through rad Source or
went through ozone treatment
so we ran the potency in the terpenes
and you can see that the pre-rad sample
the average potency was 18.3 and then
post rad was 15.4 and then for the total
terpenes we saw 2.37 and then that
dropped to 1.98 and so when you
calculate the rpds between those results
they're about 17 for both so we saw a 17
RPD decrease after radiation does this
mean this happens to every single sample
that goes through the rad Source I'm not
sure but this is what we saw from our
preliminary investigation
so conclusions with this is going to be
that qpcr and Grim Reef for qpcr yield
higher amounts of total yeast in mold in
radiated cannabis products than plating
so we're definitely getting a higher
concentration what concentration is
right I'm still not convinced by total
yeast in mold is a pain it drives me
crazy but we're here to figure it out
right the addition of enrichment step
can lead to overgrowth in the
pre-radiated samples so you definitely
don't want to enrich your pre-radiated
samples however the post-radiated flower
did not yield a drastic increase but it
just makes me feel more comfortable if
there is something alive there if I give
it a chance maybe it'll grow so it makes
me as a laboratory feel a little bit
more confident in releasing plating
results and then any viable cells that
may be present in radiated flour do not
come culturable for at least eight weeks
after treatment so that's what we saw
there is you know we treated they were
treated eight weeks later we still saw
no growth does that mean they're not
viable again I don't have the answer to
that but I can say that I was not able
to culture them
the cannabinoid and terpene content can
decrease after a product is undergone
radiation whether or not this is an
outlier this is something that happens
every time this could also change based
on the amount of time it's in the rad
Source the amount of rad source that it
experiences
Etc so there's a lot of variables here
that in further studies we're going to
need to better control we're going to
need to have more information from our
client of exactly how much how long
they're being exposed to the X-ray what
rate of X-ray they're being exposed to
so we can kind of better pinpoint is
there a point where you're destroying
the yeast in mold but you're not hurting
the flower and then more research is
needed to determine whether or not this
remediation process is truly removing
all of the total yeast in mold or if
it's simply fooling the test so that's
the big takeaway here is is remediation
able to actually fix our product or is
remediation just figuring out a way to
trick the test
thanks for your presentation very
informative indeed as far as I know one
of the concerns health concerns of this
micro microbial contamination is related
to the mycotic scenes produced by some
of those species particularly fusarium
aspergillus I understand that
remediation might kill those
microorganisms but what happens to those
mycotoxins are are they also eliminated
so mycotoxins are interesting because
they're not a living species anymore
like the microbes so they're secondary
metabolites so with the mycotoxins when
you have a microbial and it starts to
break down you form the secondary
metabolite from our experience we can we
have seen that even when you extract
something if it previously had that
contaminant and it allowed it to form
we've still seen mycotoxins present so I
would say that it doesn't get rid of it
so you're still you're still having a
whole nother battle which is why that
mycotoxin testing is so important even
if you're able to eliminate the
microorganism mycotoxin is still is
remaining
it yes thank you
I'm sure that they're self-picking these
samples right
the the companies are self-picking the
sample right there's no state
for final product we do all of the
sampling ourselves so once the product
has been radiated if it's being sent for
final compliance testing it is already
in its package and we go out and
randomly select but for this experiment
they sent the sample but yes Florida
does Florida is very strict about their
sampling procedures it is there a
minimum or maximum to the lot size that
you get to pick from
is it mandated on the volume you know is
it 10 pounds did you actually pick that
sample from or is it you know 20. so
it's based on the batch size so we have
to take point three five percent of the
batch plus 10 grams for total yeast in
mold so you know you're going to take a
minimum or a minimum of 15 grams plus 10
grams so we're always as a lab bringing
back a minimum of 25 grams of flour 25
grams of flour from a maximum volume of
that would be from a maximum of about 4
000 grams and then after that it would
increase wow so as your batch size
increases once you reach that threshold
of the 0.35 percent you then have to
start collecting More Sample that's
that's better so I mean there's some
samples where we literally bring back
like 250 grams of sample
thank you
hey great talk
um I
have a well I'm curious about something
um you know when I buy my weed I don't
bring it home and soak it in a broth so
um maybe I do I need to care about these
like residual microbes I think I would
care more about the mycotoxins so with
the microbes the thing is is that's just
allowing us to culture them and to grow
them but standardly they're still there
that's just allowing us to quantify them
by adding them to that broth but yeah
but if they're that hard to culture then
they're probably I mean it seems like
they're probably less competent to
infect me too right
it's hard to say it depends on what it
is I mean if you have some powdery
mildew I don't think you want to be
inhaling the powdery mildew no no I
don't want the toxins or the residue
from it right but um uh when you um
when you measure these irradiated
samples like
I would love to see the error bars and
stuff because I like like we do this
with so much of our food radiation is
brilliant I've seen lots of data from
radsource and other radiation companies
I think a lot of people suck at using
the machines but um I think rad source
and radiation is used differently in
other Industries though it's not
necessarily it's used for shelf life
purposes rather than to kill
bad things yeah yeah yeah well and again
right just the fact that the critters
were growing in the weed that's the bad
part right like like and what they were
doing they've been crapping in my weed
right so that's why I don't want it but
yeah I I would find it hard to believe
that used properly this rad source is
going to do a significant amount I mean
I don't do much chemistry with x-rays
that's why that's what we're using for
and I think that's why more research you
know ultimately needs to be done before
we just put a ton of rad Source product
on the market is what is it doing to the
product make sure it's actually you know
solving the problem rather than just
tricking the test because there are
dangerous molds that could be present a
spurgeless could be present and rad
Source could allow that Colony not to
grow but the aspergillus then broke down
into mycotoxins that now you're inhaling
mycotoxins so there's so many different
pieces to the puzzle that I think that
the whole picture needs to be addressed