canoped is one of the largest public
databases for cannabis and hemp genetic
information
in addition to being a genomics resource
to the public community canopeda is also
where medicinal genomics customers will
get access to genetic reports for
samples that they submit for either
sequencing or genotyping
to date there are over 1200 registered
strains in canapedia
in this video we'll walk you through the
redesigned canopedia website and
highlight some of the key features
hitting the registered strain link at
the top will bring up a list of all
publicly registered strains in canapedia
strains are presented in a session date
descending order
you can toggle the order by clicking on
the arrow next to the sort by category
you can change the sort by category to
either grower or name
by clicking on the sort by category
and you can also toggle the sort order
of the other categories
on the right-hand side of search
parameters they can be used to further
refine the results feed on the left hand
side
for example click the add parameter
button
scroll down to thc eight percent
enter a value of 15
and then click the update results button
what you'll get in the return search is
every sample in our database for which a
chemotype for thca has been submitted
and which is greater than or equal to 15
you can also toggle the directionality
of the sort order with the arrows that
are to the right of the sort by thc
percent parameter
parameters can also be stacked on top of
each other to further refine the search
for example if we want to search the
database for anything with a thc a
percent of greater than equal to 15
but also
a cbd8 percent of less than or equal to
we just add that as an additional
parameter and update the results
note that the results of what is
populated on the left hand side has
changed to reflect these two parameters
combined
lastly we'll add one additional
parameter to further refine the search
so that we have any strain name that
contains the word lion
will update the results and the two
results that are found are the two
jamaican lion samples that are in
canopedia one is for cancer 90 and one
is for whole genome sequencing and we'll
look at those in a little more depth
we'll start by taking a closer look at
the whole genome sequencing report for
jamaican lion
the name of strain is on top along with
the unique identifier session dinner
canopedia database
some information about the submitter
sample name a session date reported
plant sex and the sequencing or
genotyping technology that was used to
generate the genetic report we've
introduced a lot more search
functionality into kanapedia
several fields in a canopy report now
have an embedded hyperlink
if you hover over these you'll notice to
the right of the term a search icon
appears
clicking on any of these links
will do a database-wide search matching
that particular term
for example clicking on the medicinal
genomics link
will give us all samples where medicinal
genomics is the submitter
whereas clicking on the gender female
link will give us all samples in the
database
where the plant sex was reported as
being female by the submitter
the rarity plot shows how common your
sample is compared to all other samples
that have been submitted to canopedia
a top heavy plot indicates that a sample
is rare whereas a bottom heavy plot
indicates that a sample is more
common the next section of the canopy
report chemical information for the
strain is presented
where this information is available
this information is collected from the
submitter at the time of sample
submission
the genetic information section of the
report reports this plant is being a
type 2 plant meaning that both the thc
and cbd synthase genes are intact in the
jamaican lion genome
to the right of this are several files
available for download that represent
the results of the whole genome
sequencing that was performed on the
sample to generate this canopedia report
the vcf4 variant call format file
contains genotypes for the 800 million
plus positions in the jamaican lion
reference
the annotated vcf file contains only
genotypes which differ from the jamaican
line reference
the annotated vcf file also contains
annotations showing which genes
overlapped the variants as well as any
details pertaining to any protein coding
changes that might be present
fastq files contain the raw sequencing
reads which come out of the dna
sequencer while the bam files contain
the mapped positions of those reads to
the jamaican line reference and what was
used to generate the variant calls which
are used in the analysis in a canopy
report
the plot on the left shows the
heterozygosity distribution for all
samples in canapedia and the line shows
where the current sample we're viewing
the report falls on its distribution
since this sample is a jamaican line
clone it's expected to be more closely
related to the jamaican lion reference
and therefore has a lower heterozygosity
percentage that falls to the left of
this distribution curve
a sample that's more distantly related
to jamaican line will fall to the right
of this distribution curve
breeders can use this heterozygosity
information as a proxy for assessing
seed line stability
a more stable seed line will have a
lower heterozygosity percentage and will
fall to the left of this distribution
curve
on the right hand side is the y ratio
distribution plot
scientists at medicinal genomics were
able to determine which regions of the
cannabis genome belong to chromosome y
by sequencing the jamaican lion father
by taking the total number of reads that
map to y
and then dividing that by the total
number of reads that don't map to y
you're able to calculate the y ratio and
take a distribution of this over all
samples in canopedia
the plot shows y ratio scores for two
separate distributions
in red is a population of known female
plants and in green is a population of
known male plants the line shows where
this sample falls in relation to these
two separate distributions
a line that overlaps the female
distribution is more likely to be female
and a line that overlaps the male
distribution further to the right would
be more likely to be male
the next section of a canopedia report
has next generation sequencing coverage
over key cannabinoid genes
the patterns of deletions in these genes
indicate the type of the plant
in type 1 plants active cbd synthase is
deleted and there's no next generation
sequencing coverage over the region
in type 2 plants active cbd synthase and
active thc synthase are both intact
and at type 3 plants active cbd synthase
has coverage over the region showing
that the gene is intact but active thc
synthase has no coverage over the region
suggesting that it's deleted
there's also a fourth type type 4 in
which there is neither coverage over cbd
synthase or active thc synthase
inactive cbd synthase is in close
proximity to the active thc synthase
gene is being tracked because of its
proximity to give a sense of the size of
the deletion
cannabichromine is another gene we track
in canopedia which may or may not be
deleted
one interesting feature of cannabi
chromine is that it may be responsible
for synthesizing thc in cases where the
thc synthase gene is deleted
this would be a good time to point out
the key differences between a can stamp
90 and next generation sequencing based
canopy report
a canstep 90 derived canopy report has
much of the same content as a sequencing
based report
the key differences are in the genetic
information section
note that only the annotated vcf files
are available for download as the other
file formats are specific to sequencing
technologies
deletions and key cannabinoid genes are
also presented and a plant type is
called based on the patterns of these
deletions however the nature of the data
necessitates that the information is
presented and analyzed in a different
way
each genotype called necan simp 90 chip
has a logo ratio score associated with
it
a deletion can be detected using these
log r ratio scores across multiple
variants in a particular region
the average log ratio scores were
calculated for samples detected as
having these deletions and samples
detected as not having them by using the
sequencing data
then the correlation of the log our
ratio scores and these averages was
calculated
a sample with a high correlation to the
average of the deleted samples likely
has a deletion in this region and a
sample with a low correlation likely has
that region intact
note that for canstep90 we also have
several y chromosome markers on the chip
the sex of the plan is determined using
the same process since a female sample
represents what a male sample would look
like with the y chromosome deleted
underneath the deletion plots is a table
that has the summary of deletions
showing the actual correlation scores
for this sample to the population that
has the deletion
and it has the actual cause whether
the deletion is intact or deleted and
for the plant sects whether the
sex of the plan is male or female
underneath the deletion summary are two
tables showing a summary of variants
detected in the sample
showing point mutations that are
predicted to have a moderate or high
impact on protein functionality and in
the first table we've got a thc cbd and
cbc synthase variants
underneath that is a list of variants
for 40 genes that are curated by
scientists at medicinal genomics thought
to play an important role in cannabis
genomics
so these would be important genes in
cannabis and
and mutations that might affect the
functionality of these genes
the variance table can be sorted on a
particular column using the arrows to
the right of the column header name
additionally there's a search box in the
top right hand corner of the table that
can be used to search any text contained
within the table and filter the results
based on that search
for example if we're looking for any
variants that fall on contact 700 of the
jamaican lion reference we simply type
contact 700 into the search box and we
only see variants on contact 700
likewise if we want to see only variants
which have a tc allele
we could put t
c into the search box to display only
those
a description of the gene can be
displayed by hovering over the gene
abbreviation in the gene column
there's also a unipro link which links
out to unipro
where there's more detailed information
describing this particular gene
in the next section of the canopedia
report we're showing you the closest
genetic genetically closest samples to
your sample
compared to everything else in our
database and we do this by taking a list
of high quality variants there's about
four thousand variants or so
that are
filtered with the high q qc values uh
high sequencing depth of coverage across
the reeds and ones that are found in the
population with a certain minor allele
frequency
we take those variants and calculate a
distance between
the sample and canopedia and everything
else in the database and then we rank
these distances to show you which are
the most similar and which are the least
similar and so on the left hand side
we're actually showing you uh the
nearest relative to jamaica jamaican
lion
uh which is the sample that we're
looking at in this canopy report
and it's based on every publicly
available sample in canapedia that's
what that's what you're viewing on the
left-hand side you will also see
any private samples which also you are
the owner of if you've elected to have
private canopy reports
now on the right hand side it's a little
different it's showing what we call the
base tree
and the base tree is a set of strains
that we have in our database
that for the purpose of calculating
distances we always keep the same
base tree and the idea was just that as
canopedia continues to grow
and
and some of these samples that are in
the database will continue to grow as
well we'll always have that stable base
tree that can be used and referred back
to
and uh and can be used to compare
samples to one another and have that
kind of stable comparison set that we
can use as as kind of canopedia grows
now beneath this we have
the opposite collection of tables which
is showing you uh what is the most
genetically distant strain from jamaican
lion
and similarly uh what are the most
genetically distant ones from the base
tree
and we have these plots that show the
sample of interest
as well as kind of
giving you a graphical representation of
what are the most similar and what are
the most distant samples to your sample
in this final section down here we have
the nearest genetic relative in the
philos data set on the left hand side
and the nearest genetic relative in the
lynch data set on the right hand side
now these are two data sets that we
downloaded
from ncbi it's publicly available data
and it's just some additional databases
that we've added for comparison purposes
so you can look at
for these public data sets which sample
is calculated as being the closest to
your sample and if you click on the link
you'll actually be taken to ncbi
to that particular record for that
particular
sample set
and you can get additional information
about
the sample by
exploring these these links on ncbi
now at the very bottom
we have blockchain registration
information now what is this
what we're doing is we're taking the
genetic data
the vcf file i specifically we take that
and we calculate an md5 sum for it which
is a unique identifier for a particular
contents of a particular file
you can take that unique identifier
which is called a hash a shaw sum hash
and
encode it in a blockchain transaction
which is what we do
and so the blockchain transaction id is
something that is submitted to the
blockchain
you can click on it
and it's a decentralized database that
medicinal genomics does not have control
over and it will store your hash sum
in the blockchain
in a decentralized database so what you
can do is if you ever need to prove to
someone
that you had a particular strain with a
particular set of genotypes
at a particular point in time
you can refer them to this blockchain
transaction
and the only way
to get
that particular hash sum is using that
exact file
that was generated as part of the canopy
analysis that's in
the canopy report so someone could
download that file
they could do their own hash sum of the
file and then they could reference the
blockchain
to prove that you had that strain at a
particular point in time
we also have the details of this
blockchain transaction presented in this
pdf file
which could be printed out and given to
someone presented to them via email
etc it's just a nice way to kind of
summarize the whole transaction
this concludes the walkthrough of our
canopy redesign
if you have any questions don't hesitate
to reach out our contact information is
on the screen and we'd be happy to help
answer any questions you have
thank you