thanks for inviting me to this
conference this was my first conference
so thanks you thanks to the organizers
for letting me present our research at
the University of Wisconsin Madison a
little bit about myself um I've only
been in the Cannabis space for maybe six
years um this conference has been great
yesterday yesterday I learned a lot of
stuff um I've been in the biotech space
uh for all my career so about 35 years
uh most of that in Private Industry uh
for 30 years and then I kind of came
back to University of Wisconsin where I
graduated from and uh directed a
facility that I'll I'll show in a few
slides that does um plant engineering
and editing of lots of different
species and today I'm going to talk
about the work we're doing in cannabis
and like Texas I'm from Wisconsin so
we're dealing with a Type 3 version so
I'll be interchangeably using hemp and
cannabis uh during the
talk okay so a little bit about um our
team at the Johnson crop Innovation
Center uh we're located off campus and
we're a facility that has about 50
people working at it we're kind of
almost like a small business um we have
our own production Discovery um plant
analysis teams Administration facilities
so it's almost a a unit uh outside
campus that that does this work um the
core hemp Team U myself Sean Kepler is
the faculty director of the site uh
Shelby Ellison is an assistant professor
working on campus and she does a lot of
the Cannabis breeding um and feral hemp
work uh on campus and then my team Cindy
Lucas and Jane they're all working on
the in the lab uh doing the
transformation and Gene
editing this is a a bird's eye view of
the center itself it used to be an old
Monsanto facility so Monsanto donated
this facility about 7 years ago um to
the university I directed the facility
for uh about 5 years and then I stepped
back and and came back to work on hemp
uh two days a week just because we had a
a grant for hemp um and I thought it was
just a fascinating plant it's really the
first time I was introduced to it um the
facility does transformation of many
different species um corn soybean uh
different different species for both
public and private uh Industries so they
can pay a fee for service we'll put your
favorite gene or knock out your favorite
Gene in any of these species and hand
you back to one seed and it's no no no
strings attached it's yours to do it
whatever you want to we also to do
collaborations uh and research
agreements as well if they're longer
term we were the first uh I think in the
world to staby engineer um heritable uh
cannabis and that was in 2018 we filed a
patent uh for our procedure um and it
was granted already and like I said we
have a dedicated team of of those folks
working on cannabis
research um y Hamp you've probably seen
this slide a million times but you know
some people call this a trillion dollar
plant um but not only for for uh medical
uses uh but Industrial Hemp uh there's
all kinds of uses uh for industrial hemp
as well uh Farm Bill legalized hempen 18
so that gave us freedom to really take a
look at it um because there's really
very little research done in the last 80
years on it um and then of course you
know the W the wreck use and the
medicinal uses uh even increase the
value of
that so I think really this is a a
disruptive time um for cannabis the
Cannabis industry uh I put this slide up
just to show that uh kind of the the
history of of putting genes into plants
you know first functional genes and
plants was back in the ' 84 um I was
working with a group on this as well as
uh some Monsanto employees and other
others in universities um that's just an
old southern blot showing T1 inheritance
um of a gene uh in a plant for the first
time then in in '96 that was kind of a
pivotal year as well where uh Roundup
Ready was kind of the first uh I'll call
it GMO plant that was widely
commercialized there was of course the
flavor saver tomato before that but it
kind of a failure uh but Roundup Ready
ushered in this commercialization of of
gml crops um brought in lots of noil
farming uh glyphosate resistant plants
um our group uh back in in before 96
worked on uh what you see up there is
that is the gene gun so we invented that
at a private company that I worked in um
and was electronic device that was used
actually to make that Roundup Ready
event before Monsanto uh purchased that
company and then in 2018 this is just a
a picture of uh our first transgenic
event um that's a T1 uh picture uh
showing red fluorescent protein this was
just a proof of concept to show that we
could do it uh progyny and the the red
plants in that picture um are expressing
a a red fluorescent protein whereas the
green ones uh don't have it
so a little bit about genetic
transformation in cannabis lots of labs
um have have published and and can do
transformation in in tissue culture they
can get actual transformation to happen
uh but the key the key thing is they're
they're most of them aren't able to make
it heritable or stable so they get it in
callous formation in Roots different
different parts of the plants but
they're not able to get a stable
transformed event um it's very
recalcitrant to uh tissue culture and
when I say tissue culture um I mean uh
embryogenic tissue culture so if you
have a callous uh form of the hemp plant
very hard to actually get a plant to
grow out of that callus to differentiate
into the
plant so one of the things we've done
since the 80s um at this facility is we
we focus on am meristem xplants so we
don't deal with callus or organogenic
organogenesis um we take a mature seed
we embibe that seed
overnight um and then we isolate the
Marist stems uh with the calans or with
the primary leaves on them so this is a
picture see the laser that's a picture
of what we're our starting material is
so that's your root radical um your
primary leaves there and then there's
the meristematic region there uh that's
that we're targeting for
transformation we've been able to use
both agrobacterium transformation and
the gun transformation for this we
choose agrobacterium just because it's
much more effici ient and
straightforward oops sorry um if you
don't know anything about uh Ager
bacterium transformation uh if you go
for a walk in the woods or in the town
you see plants with crown Galls so it's
these massive formations on these plants
that's basically a soil bacteria that's
infecting these plants naturally it
infects these plants and it has um some
anagenic genes that form this Crown Gall
so it's almost a cancerous growth on
these trees and scientists over the
years have hijacked this bacteria they
take out the genes that form that Crown
Gall the the cancerous genes and then
you can put in whatever Gene you want to
so whether it's a yield Gene an insect
resistant Gene hop latent uh mRNA
potentially um and that plant will
infect the cannabis plant and uh deliver
its genes to the plant and it'll Express
that
trait so we start out this is a an
agrobacterium plasmid we start out with
a plasmine that's located uh inside the
bacteria and this is what the bacteria
is going to deliver to the plants this
is where you put your whatever Gene you
want the plants to express and I'm just
showing you the the proof of concept uh
Vector that we used
whoops the proof of concept Vector we
used and I mentioned it had a a red
fluorescent protein in it um that would
be this uh TD tomato Gene it's called it
also has a gus Gene in it um which is a
gene that um if you give it a substrate
it'll uh it'll show a color of blue if
the gene is present in the plant so
these are just visual markers that allow
us to track you know did the plant get
transformed or or or uh
edited so those those embryos I showed
before uh those go through an antibiotic
selection uh we use spectamin as the
antibiotic and they get put on media
plates uh for about 3 or 4 weeks you can
see some bleaching here occurring so if
the plant is doesn't have the pomin Gene
that's spectinomycin will start to
bleach the plant and eventually kill the
plant anything that's Greening um shows
that that plant U may have the spec Gene
in it and it's probably transformed and
along with the spec Gene comes your Gene
of Interest T tomato Gus a yield gene or
whatever usually this this process takes
about 6 to 8 months going from uh
transformation or co- culture of the
agrobacterium to getting T1 seeds uh out
the
door this is our first t0 transgenic
event um I mentioned it had the blue
this blue gust Gene and we did some
staining and you can see this expression
of blue uh within the germline tissue of
this plant so we did we did this as a
preest to see um if it was transformed
and indeed it had blue in the germline
tissue so we were pretty positive that
it was a germine transformation
excuse me so a few statistics on our
transformation procedure um our
frequencies are in the single digits so
meaning if you take a hundred of those
uh embryo X plants we may see uh one to
five uh plants come out that are
transformed normally for soybean or corn
we see that in the 20 to 30% range so
we've got work to do to increase that
frequency but um it's very uh
repeatable um we've had success with
multiple cannabis genotypes and again
we're we're from Wisconsin so I'm using
CBD varieties I don't think this
particular procedure is going to be
genotype dependent I think we can do um
marijuana uh fiber hemp whatever it may
be uh We've made uh over 200 independent
events for private companies and
internally so it's again very repeatable
uh with whatever we're trying we've also
done Gene edits and that's what I'm
going to get to uh in the next few
slides and then since we're starting out
with a a uh embryo xplant we're not
starting out with a single cell we do
get chimeric events um anywhere between
10 and
20% and a chimeric event is just a event
that's not fully uh transformed in every
cell but it is a germine transformation
normally so if you take that that uh
plant out to T1 status it may not
segregate 3:1 but you'll be able to find
your true germ line transformation then
take it forward and it won't be chimeric
that's again I'll picture of our T1
progyny and some other examples of our
T1 so that was the T tomato we put a
gene called Ruby in uh Ruby is the it's
a a set of three genes that make beets
red so if you eat beets that's that's
the gene so we put that into hemp and we
get a plant that's totally red uh
compared to the null and this is an
overexpression um of that Gene then
we've made knock we made over
expressors and uh We've made uh some
other plants for private companies where
they're using evolved uh CBD synthes or
THC syntheses to see if they can change
ratios in in the in the cannabis
plant I probably didn't need this slide
but um normally we're dealing with a
variety we call Badger it's just it's
got um some some cherry wine in it it's
got some chardonay it's got some Electra
in it that's kind of the background
they are dious plants so we have to
feminize them or masculinize them to
make feminized seed in order to get uh
the gene to be homozygous uh in the in
the next uh Next
Generation so I mentioned our
frequencies are in the low signal digits
so we're doing a lot to try to increase
our our transformation frequencies at
the center we're trying uh different
selection agents so I mentioned we use
uh spectamin right now we're using
different agents we're using different
agrobacterium strains we're trying
liquid culture rather than a solid media
uh probably the biggest thing to try uh
for us right now as well as a lot of
other uh species that people are trying
are these morphogenic genes so these
genes elicit embryogenic responses in
plants that are recalcitrant to uh
transformation so things like Baby Boom
whel Leu these are all genes that a lot
of the uh big egg companies um have
looked at and are getting really good
results with especially with dicots or
especially with monocots and now
recently with dicots as well so we're
going to be looking at this as well um
yesterday they talked a lot about LED
lights uh in in culture I mean in uh
cultivation so we're looking at LED
lights also tissue culture so
pre-cultivation and whether we can
elicit uh better growth or different
responses directly in tissue
culture um media and hormone comp
components are always uh played with uh
for for probably the last 40 years so we
always look at those and then other
other Target tissues other than the the
immature
embryo so targeting um so after our you
know proof of concept was done we
thought about targeting different uh
enzymes or genes uh in the cannabis
plant and some of them some of the
obvious ones were you know the the
canabo pathway genes the turpine pathway
genes uh to look and see if we could
actually go and knock some of these out
to see if we knock these out in the
plant we got similar results that
they've done in yeer bacteria uh where
they've knocked these these genes
out um so one of the questions and and
it it was a controversial question for a
while but you know why do cbda type 3
plants make THC and medicinal genomics
did a lot of work on this uh and and uh
the the hemp plants that we use the type
three they don't have an active THC
synthes so the CBD
synthes um uh makes actually a little
bit of the THC so when you get your. 3
or point4 whatever percent THC you're
getting it's the CBD active CBD synthes
it's actually making that it's a
promiscuous enzyme it's very homologous
to THC synthes so that's what we
targeted uh in order to try to knock out
uh CBD
and this the reason we went after this
was back in 18 when the farmers uh or 17
when the farmers were growing their
first fields of of hemp and Wisconsin
about 25% of the fields uh went hot uh
they had to destroy their plants they
were saying you know we need a THC free
line um in the states that that get get
hit for that there are some CB GA lines
which is you know the mother of the
grandmother canabo of of that there are
a few lines out there in in 18 but not
too many
um the genetics of those lines are a
little bit questionable based on some uh
uh data that was done at the University
of Wisconsin there was also not in 18
but recently um GTR made a low THC line
uh that was high in in CBG as
well so we went after that cbda synthes
to knockout and we used this crisper
crisper cast system which they use uh
routinely in other
crops uh basic what you end up doing is
you design a guide RNA that targets
whatever sequence you want to knock out
that guide RNA sits down on the sequence
cast 9 comes in and and makes a cut at
that guide RNA um and then the plant
itself once it's cut it uh relates
itself just a non-homologous enjoining
religation uh event um and hopefully
when that religation happens you've
either dropped out a base or added a
base somehow you've disrupted that Gene
and that's that's how gen editing uh uh
works so we targeted that um the cbda
synthes in our Badger line um I'm just
showing a couple examples of what we got
out of that the first plant uh we we
sequenced um we had we had actually two
guide rnas that we sat down to try to
increase our chances of of it
working um the first guide RNA did cut
and we added a single uh nucleotide to
this sequence which would knock it out
and and make a non-functional but we
also had an insertion also at the other
guide site of about 177 bases um and
this came from the plasma that was
introduced into the into the plant so
that was the first
event the second event um the two guide
rnas cut perfectly at where they were
supposed to cut and in between those two
guide rnas the whole sequence just
dropped out so we lost that whole
sequence the sequence came back together
and again we have a non-functional cbda
synthes and you know if if we're if
we're successful with this we shouldn't
make any cbda in the plant and since the
cbda is responsible for the thca we
should not have any THC in the plant as
well so then we looked uh at hplc
results um this was done on I think uh
yeah 5.5 5 and 1 half week
flower and you can take a look at um
whoopsie
sorry take a look at the wild type uh
plants here here you can see the the
cbda uh is is high in these plants and
then there's a little bit of THC as well
which you know that's that's what this
plant would normally make the
heterozygous edit and I failed to
mention but when you make an edit um
sometimes you'll only edit one Al in the
plant not both alals so you need to edit
both alals in order you know for that
Gene to be knocked out so we went
through a round of selfing of that plant
in order to get a homozygous uh lines
Lin for this plant so we had
heterozygous Lions which just had one Al
knocked out homozygous Lions which had
both alals knocked out you can see the
heterozygous look very similar to Wild
type results and the homozygous edit
completely drops out the CBD um and the
THC and then the precursor which is CBG
elevates levels because there's nothing
pulling on it anymore so we have a high
CBG line um again these were only at 5.5
weeks uh taken normally this Badger line
is somewhere in the teens uh for for CBD
so we expect when we test this you know
at later stages we should be in the
teens for for
CBG um this line uh also we we applied
to USDA for non-regulated status um and
got that approved a couple months ago so
you can freely this is an edited plant
you can freely plant it uh out in the
fields without
regulation and we call it Badger G just
for where the badger
state um so next step for this Badger G
line we want to fully genome sequence it
uh we're bulking up feminized seed right
now so that we can get larger quantities
for people that are that may be
interested in it and again this is just
a high CBG line so there are other CBG
lines out there we realize um but back
in 18 this is this is what we were
after um there's companies uh hypercan
is a company that's interested in this
line uh they want to have a blank slate
to start with so a high CBG line would
be optimal for them to put in their
engineered cbda synthes genes so they
can play around with ratios of THC to
CBD um Penn State's interested in this
for animal feed so since it doesn't have
any THC whatsoever uh this it gets past
some of the regulation uh that some
states have for animal feed and then
we're crossing this line since since our
line is kind of an unknown this Badger
Line's unknown it's it's uh it's it's a
cherry wine based uh background we're
crossing this line with better known CBD
varieties like uh ACDC and some others
uh to get into a hopefully a a a well
more well-known Cult of our2
people and then um the other thing we're
going to do with this line is take a
look since we we have a lot of CBG
available um CBC is another minor canabo
that we've heard a lot of people are
interested in having a very high CBC
line so we think by using this line and
introducing either mutations to the CBC
or overexpressing the CBC C synthes in
this in this line we should be able to
make uh a 10% plus CBC
line so other ongoing research
um is uh that we're doing besides
cannaboids increasing flour and tri
Chrome production to try to just
increase overall
canabo levels uh biomass and yield which
is is with any crop uh
valuable uh flavor oids we're looking at
the flavonoid pathway to see if we can
increase maybe can flaven a can flaven B
that can be used in medicinal uh studies
fiber properties so Industrial Hemp uh
is up and coming uh so a lot of people
are asking you know what can we do for
for fiber um in hemp can we make more
uniform fibers longer fibers uh reduce
certain lignin in hemp things like that
so we'll look at fibers and then seed
and nutrition can we do anything with
seed so again you know I I I I find is
very uh similar to what they were
looking at in the 80s back for R crops
you know think about any trait you want
to put into hemp if it's if if you don't
think you can do it by breeding or
molecular breeding or it's going to take
too long um but this is a has
potential uh disease so I got sandwich
in between two hop Lon talks um and I
that's all I hear I hear a lot at this
conference um so hop lant is another
Target uh that we're doing uh it's been
shown to you know the RNA technology has
been shown in other species to work for
other viruses and viroids so we're going
to try to um attack that as well as
powdery mildew um so there are again
other species like wheat and and others
that people have been successful at
getting powdery milder resistance in so
we're going to try to do that in help as
well tpine profiles are another uh area
that people are interested in so
increasing levels of various Tarpin that
are desirable increasing Tricom
density um and maybe knocking out
certain turpins that people don't want
to have so you can customize your uh
smells or flavors or whatnot uh with
different
turbines herbicide resistance it's
always out there um I have larger
companies asking um that that are
looking at at hemp for paper um they
claim weed is a is a problem in their
large Fields so they ask about that
and then just a just a few uh slides on
collaborations that we have and these
were just press releases so that's why I
put them up um zal was a customer that
came out and put their uh photo seed
trait in hemp and they got an increase
in in biomass uh oil and then hyper can
this should say actually 2023 but hyper
can uh put their uh evolved CBD synthes
syntheses which are supposedly very
active and and produce more CBD uh in
the plant uh into hemp as well and they
saw an increase and kinoid
content um again hyper can uses a lot of
um uh x-ray crystallography they know
this enzyme inside and out they know
what mutations uh can make can can
change the cbda synthes to make
different ratios of CBD to THC so they
can customize that and I think the last
one on hyper cannons this was just their
data from their press release so showing
an increase in um uh leaves and immature
flowers in different uh cannabinoids
mainly the CBD and the
THC and I'm going through these pretty
fast because I'm running out of time uh
and then we're also looking again at the
CBC because there seems to be a lot of
interest in CBC so can we make a CBC
line that is 10% plus 15% plus uh for
the
community and this was this was kind of
hot off the presses I thought I'd throw
in there um we got this this result last
week it's very early it's just on uh
young leaves
but we targeted uh also an the OAC
enzyme which is olivetolic acid cyclas
um that's olic acid and gpp are the two
precursors uh to CVG so if you knock out
one of them the plant ideally shouldn't
make any any cannabinoids at all uh and
that's what we're seeing in this early
data for leaf data so our control line
makes um some um CV CBG cbga um and our
OAC knockout basically doesn't make uh
we're still looking at at these bars
here they're kind of right at the limit
of detection for our hplc so we don't
know if they're real or not but um it's
it's basically dropped out uh the CBG
out of this
plant so I I came to this conference you
know looking trying to trying to open
minds and trying to think about you know
what what traits are are out there that
people are very interested in looking
for collaborations uh Partners uh
anybody interested in you know uh
putting their favorite trade or knocking
out their trade in hemp can come talk to
me after the after the
talk and that's my last
[Applause]
slide
questions do you happen to have any
pictures with you of the early transfer
early
regeneration uh process you know once
you once you transformed these Mir
things
maybe you have some more other than the
ones I've shown yeah um just how it
looks like when it when they come back
from you know regenerate from that
little yeah I'm sure I could dig up some
for you we can yep
yeah hear
me screen great talk excellent work
yeah yeah so there a couple different
answers I guess um if you you know want
to knock out multiple multiple genes you
know just design your guide Ras to knock
out you know whatever Gene you want um
normally binary plasmas in aggro
normally you can make uh you know
probably up to a 30 KB uh vector and
have it stable um we've been playing
around and have had success with um a
new I I showed it up there on one of the
slides called it's a vector called
Gantry so it's it doesn't use a binary
Vector we uh we put the uh the genes
right in the backbone of the Agro and
deliver it through the backbone of the
Agro and we're able to make uh easily
over 40 KB uh in uh size plasmas to put
in so if we wanted to do overexpress say
a a multi-cistronic uh you know pathway
or whatever you could do it using that
Gantry Vector
y can you get yeah efficiency normally I
would say goes down just in general in
all species once you hit uh say 15 or 20
KB delivering that tdna size that's
where it just starts dropping off you
can still deliver over a 30 KB thing but
your efficiency of delivering that whole
thing is is going to go down the nice
part of the system is you know you put
your selectable marker on the left
border right so you you're you're sure
that the whole thing is going to go in
and read through the whole thing
yep and you mentioned that you're
working with different oxitop strains of
agrobacterium have you seen any
significant
differences yeah it's kind of early work
we're doing some lba4404 thigh minus
string or thyine minus strains the main
re the reason we're doing that is just
aggro overgrowth you know we're trying
to uh control the overgrowth in the in
the augur we use tattin we use carb we
use sep but every once in a while we'll
have we'll get this cropping of Agro
overgrowth that tends to lower
efficiencies um the thyine
minus I I think it's still out whether
they're uh as as efficient as other
vectors um I've I've seen certain cases
where certain um oxit Tropic vectors
don't perform as well
uh as in delivering TD n so you work
with LBA as opposed to like GB 3101 or
so the work we're doing here and I
mentioned LBA because that's kind of the
that's the oxit trro we have right now
okay um the work we're doing in cannabis
right now we've done uh gv3101 is is the
the one vector we've done but we mainly
use a a strain called 18r 12v so it's a
it's a uh it's a a k599 based or RI type
Vector um that was
disarmed so and we use that mainly
because it it gives us a little bit
better quality of an insert so we get
fewer potentially fewer copies going in
uh with with that particular thing
because it uses An rri
Origin okay thanks
[Applause]