good morning everybody so I've spent the
last ten years I've been a doctor now
almost 30 years but I've spent the last
ten years as a pediatric cannabis doctor
I also take care of adults when I
started my practice it was mostly adults
but I just wanted to share with you
these are all some patients of mine that
are using multiple different
cannabinoids to enhance the quality of
their lives and these include cancer
patients children with genetic diseases
children who have had issues since birth
and it's been really very rewarding
here's some other kids as well if you
could see the top middle photo this is a
little boy that was never supposed to
walk and he came walking into my office
this year so that's kind of amazing
the little boy all the way on your right
on the top said mama for the first time
at age six so anybody who's worried
about damaging little brains with
cannabis it doesn't happen it appears to
actually make brains move forward so the
conditions that I take care of mostly
are here treatment-resistant epilepsy by
far as the number one condition I see in
Pediatrics however autism is coming in
as a very close second unfortunately I
do see children with cancer most of them
are advanced cancers metastatic who have
been giving very poor prognosis and as
you can see the other conditions and one
of the things that's very important to
understand is that many of these
conditions have an underlying root cause
of endocannabinoid deficiency or
dysfunction some of the literature is as
bearing out that these children clearly
have an endocannabinoid deficiency and I
know there's going to be a talk on
autism but just in March of this year
Stanford University published a paper
where children with autism had
significantly lower Ananda mite levels
when compared to children who were what
we call neurotypical so when a child is
missing a compound in their brain that's
supposed to promote homeostasis
I consider it malpractice not to correct
that imbalance
here rationale for use again evidence of
the endocannabinoid system is root cause
despite a recent very recent just this
past Thursday there was a article
published in New England Journal of
Medicine about medical marijuana for
chronic pain and there was a pro and a
con and the con said we don't know the
safety baloney we know the safety
account of his ins of years show me the
bodies we don't see that
so certainly tolerated well by most we
don't see organ damage the only time I
really get concerned is when it's
combined with certain pharmaceuticals
especially in children with epilepsy no
question that the quality of life of
these children are being improved if
they respond and we do see like around
an 80 percent response rate which is
pretty good
certainly compassionate care end of life
now that we have tested medicine and
there has always been tested medicine it
just wasn't required here in California
but now everything that's on the market
is pretty is is compliant with testing I
don't have to worry anymore I can get a
batch result and I can see what is in
the compounds that the families are
using and most importantly with cannabis
medicine it's not a one-size-fits-all
you can customize treatment I will share
with you these are two children the
little boy on the bottom these are
siblings by the way and the mom sends me
these nice little milestone updates the
first day of first grade for Casey on
top and her brother started third grade
these are both children with epilepsy
and autism they had terrible quality of
life they're both on different regimens
and both as you can see are in school
and they look pretty happy doing really
well
I had this really cool animation where
when I click the button the little
circles came up but I lost that when I
converted this to a PDF so what I'm
using in in terms of cannabinoids for
patients is I am using everything that
is circled so I am using CBD extracts
THC extracts the raw cannabinoids THC a
CBD a we're also using just newly
available Delta eight THC for some
teenagers with anxiety
so all of these and and by the way some
other compounds are available CBN which
I haven't really used very much I
haven't found very good success maybe
other people have th CV is now currently
available in California access to all
the different cannabinoids is extremely
important I have some patients on five
different extracts a day multiple times
throughout the day some people take
certain cannabinoids in the morning and
some take at night but without the
ability to customize or to have these
available and you know I often get asked
to talk to families who are out of state
if they don't have access sometimes we
really can't get anywhere with a
condition so let's talk about CBD
extracts as dr. Michelle mentioned this
morning of course anticonvulsant and
that's been borne out in multiple
studies now we also know that CBD
extracts can help with anxiety and
aggression and si be a self injurious
behavior certainly analgesic my own
mother is using CBD for severe arthritis
pain that's been very successful for
three years she's been able to not take
any other painkillers neuroprotection
even in the patients that I take care of
like the children who may not respond
with a great result with epilepsy the
parents still want to continue to give
CBD to their children despite that it's
not lowering seizures they feel that
it's protecting their child's brain and
they're seeing that the child isn't
losing memory every time that they have
a seizure we also know CBD to be
anti-cancer and in general decreases
neuro excitation interestingly remember
CBD is a stimulant in low doses and it's
more sedating in higher doses and of
course this varies a lot of inter
individual variation but I have found in
in the autistic population that
sometimes the lower doses actually
aggravate behavior and as we go higher
in dose we can actually get an opposite
effect which is a more calming effect
sometimes that turns people off they may
try CBD for their child and usually in a
very low dose they see their child
escalate behavior and then they are
terrified to use CBD anymore
but remember these compounds are
biphasic so we're going to see an
opposite effect I like to divide the
CBD into two types of compound or kind
of categories high ratio CBD to THC and
lower ratio CBD to THC as you can see
I've listed some ratios those are not
the only ratios that we use but that is
just an example and the reason I do this
is because I find that people often say
oh okay I got some CBD well is it CBD
with a 1 to 1 or CBD like a 27 to 1
because if it's they're going to give
you different effects and you cannot
compare the two of them and if you don't
know what you're doing and you buy a one
to one ratio and you go home and you
dose it by CBD and you get stoned you're
gonna be a little bit turned off to that
if you're not looking for that effect so
I do like to categorize at least again
reading labels so that you understand
what is in the product that you're using
in children I've listed the five most
common terpenes that seem to be helpful
for both seizures and for autism Lyn
Elul pi9 limonene bethe Correia Flynn
and Marcin so raw cannabinoids have been
available now for a number of years in
California I find that both of them are
anticonvulsant in my clinical experience
anti-inflammatory and also in pediatric
patients this list of improvements that
we're seeing which is decreased anxiety
and proof focus better speech less
stemming in those children that have
autism better sleep better appetite less
aggression this is a picture of
Katherine Katherine came to me many
years ago she's one of my first
pediatric patients and when I gave her
CBD because that's what was available at
the time we had THC and we had CBD
extracts she did terribly she didn't
even last two weeks on CBD oil her
seizures were escalated she was on three
medications we thought maybe there's a
drug interaction that we weren't
accounting for but her family was
completely turned off to it and they
were not willing to even go and move any
further with it and about a year later I
noticed her name on my schedule and when
they came in the mom said you know we
tried two more pharmaceuticals and we're
not getting anywhere she was having a
significant number of seizures every
week and
this anxiety related she felt every
seizure coming so we call that an aura
and it would create tremendous anxiety
for her which then created tremendous
anxiety in the family and when she came
back to see me we had some new
information about THCA
and so we started her on that and she
had about 30% reduction of seizures and
complete resolution of what the auras so
the mother said the quality of life was
tremendously improved and when cbda
became available we added that into the
regimen and right now I'll tell you
she's 50% reduced on seizures she's been
able to wean off a very difficult drug
called anthe that's almost impossible to
wean off of and she's had no rebound
seizures from the weaning and in general
her quality life has really been
improved and again that's just on rock
cannabinoid she doesn't take CBD or THC
alright THC extracts you know I read
something about somebody saying that
children of course don't use THC no they
do and my practice they do I do find
that there it is an added anticonvulsant
effect for some patients I in fact have
one patient who the only thing that
works to stop his seizures is THC if you
are gonna design a drug for a child who
may need to be on this medication for a
long term THC may develop tolerance over
time so it's not the greatest but what
we found with this patient is that we've
got the seizures so well controlled that
we can back up a little bit on some days
skip a dose maybe take a break for a day
and then restart to try to keep the
tolerance down in general though the
child has no intoxication intoxication
he's at a pretty low dose but it's made
a big difference in his seizures I also
find THC to be very helpful when weaning
the pharmaceuticals AED stands for
anti-epilepsy drugs also what parents
will tell us and remember if your child
has an and amide deficiency or an
endocannabinoid deficiency giving THC
can help replace that deficiency and so
what we are seeing is improvements
reported in you know focus speech less
stimming better sleep appetite decreased
anxiety I find THC in general to be very
well tolerated one of the things I
explain to every family
is that every person has a sealing dos
and what we do is we start extremely low
and we titrate up if you if they see
their child starting to have any kind of
intoxicating effects we've now hit the
ceiling dose and the goal is really to
stay under that of course we're not
we're not looking to intoxicate children
so the low concentration products five
milligrams per ml and 10 milligrams per
ml everything and basically standardized
one ml syringe which is easy to measure
and give to a child I find allows us to
explore THC in very low accurate doses
with very little unwanted effects now
CBG is fairly new on the market CB G
stands for accountable Jarrell and I
have to thank a group called whole plant
access for autism and theirs they have a
poster and a booth so definitely check
them out I'm on their advisory board
there's a non-profit group that helps
families with autism there's over 8,000
families involved with them they pointed
out to me that CBG was out on the market
and there were some families using it so
I delved into the research and I'm not
going to go through it all since time is
limited but if can take a picture and
then take a look at these articles but
what's interesting is that CBG appears
to work at different mechanisms then
excuse me some of the other compounds
and what we're finding and let me show
you this slide is that they did a survey
of 35 families and as you can see the
dominant effects and these 35 families
of children with autism or mostly
beneficial so you can see 31 out of 35
and the children have better mood
increase in speech decrease in anxiety
increase in focus increase in social
interaction decrease in hyperactivity
increase in sleep better appetite
decrease in some pain that's kind of
amazing that when you look at the top
half of this graph you can see that the
dominant effects in this particular
group of patients is quite beneficial
and what we're finding with CBG is it is
an antidepressant anti-anxiety
definitely changes mood also works as an
analgesic and anti-inflammatory so I
have started using this in patients many
of the patients are combining it with
other cannabinoids and again I mentioned
this yesterday
at Q a that I attended in that
combination cannabinoids seems to be
very helpful for these children who have
such devastating illness in terms of
dosing CBG it appears to be fairly low
dose between 2 and 20 milligrams per day
it can be stimulating for some so some
of these patients are only doing it in
the morning because if they take it in
the evening they will stay up all night
which is of course opposite of what
we're interested in and there is a
report of a young adult that was shared
through me through this Facebook group
who had Tourette's syndrome and he
decided to try low doses all the way up
to about a hundred milligrams and he
found that he had complete resolution of
his tics between 25 and 40 milligram
dose so it's very interesting in that in
my experience with most patients with
Tourette you have to have a fair amount
of THC and he does supplement with THC
but in this way he might be able to use
both so he doesn't have to take as much
THC and so I got through it so I have
plenty of time for questions go ahead
good morning dr. goldstein thank you for
your work and your presentation is there
a suppository of information that helps
with Pediatrics weaning from certain
synthetics other sort of pharmaceutical
drugs or are you finding it more just
specific to specific diseases that
you've spoken about so in Pediatrics the
the drugs that were mostly weaning from
our anti-seizure drugs or sometimes the
children are taking either abilify or
respiratory
all of these drugs are usually very
difficult to get off of in general and
what I've learned is that you know
different doctors learn different things
there's no one absolute way in fact one
of my friends who's a neurologist said
he was taught a certain way in one
program and then he went to another
program and they taught him a different
way to do it so I do think it's really a
physician's preference in general I tell
patients
if they're especially if they're doing
well with cannabis medicine not to go
fast don't rock the boat
once we're actually seeing some good
results so I tell patients to to wean
ten percent or less over a period of
somewhere between two and four weeks to
do it slowly especially as we move up on
the cannabinoid treatment we can kind of
go slowly down there's no reason to rip
away drugs from a child who's actually
finally got some stability that's my
approach anyway okay thank you sure
two minutes remaining hi there my
question is about the CBG I know that
yesterday at the CME
talks that we had cannabinoids were
suggested in place and without THC so to
speak or for those that have
schizophrenia or bipolar and on that
slide CBG seems that it was also a
possibility for improvement of
antidepressant and anxiety do you have
any negative side effects for CBG with
schizophrenia or bipolar that you know
of right now so I haven't I've only
treated one bipolar patient with CBG who
was already a patient doing well on a
CBD dominant oil when we added in CBG
she felt that it was actually helping
her more in combination in terms of
complete elimination of the ings like
kind of paralyzing anxiety that she
still had breakthroughs with I have not
treated anybody with schizophrenia with
CBG but I certainly think it would be
interesting to try was that patient on
any antipsychotic medications now it
went on a patient who had already weaned
off all pharmaceuticals and was doing
well on cannabis thank you we've got ten
seconds body in your regimen and dosing
recommendations to children in your THC
verses THC acid one minute a how do you
really go about determining that spread
between the acid part and the THC
molecule right so you know there's a
huge inter individual variation
everybody responds differently
so in general I use the same kind of
motto that everybody uses which is start
low and titrate up and of course
remember this is out of pocket
Edinson and can be quite expensive so
what we're trying to do is find the
lowest dose to give the desired effect
so pretty much with THC I'm starting
usually at a half a milligram to a
milligram per day or per dose depending
on the condition and for THC a I would
say it's probably 2 milligrams or
sometimes even under that for a patient
with epilepsy thank you very much you're
welcome thank you everybody
[Applause]