foreign
[Music]
welcome to the can Med Coffee Talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
Minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing I am your
host Ben amaralt I'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the cam
Med conference
the cam Med 23 schedule is now live on
canmedevents.com check out all the
activities meals sessions workshops and
more that will be taking place at the
Marriott Marco Island Beach Resort May
15th through 17th
believe me when I tell you you do not
want to miss this event not only will
you get to learn from our oral
presenters who have been curated by our
esteemed Advisory board but we also have
four intensive professional development
workshops planned covering medical
applications of cannabis strategies for
fighting plant pathogens laboratory
compliance challenges and investment in
cannabinoid innovation
we also have a number of networking
events planned including Beach dinners
and open bar cocktail hours
if you have received your invitation to
cammed 23 register today to reserve your
spot and if you have not yet received an
invitation go to canmedevents.com now to
request one
Our Guest today is Akeem Gardner Akeem
is the founder and CEO of Canada in 2018
Akeem acquired an industrial hemp
license from Health Canada and began to
farm hemp as he embarked on his
entrepreneurial venture this allowed him
to meet with the University of Guelph
professors in the summer of 2019 to
begin the canned Flavin project
at can Med 23 Akeem will present
targeting glioblastoma Invasion and
survival with cannabis derived
flavonoids during our conversation Akeem
provides a preview of that presentation
as well as insights on the following
topics
what are flavonoids and how are they
different from cannabinoids and terpenes
the flavonoids that are unique to
cannabis also known as canned flavins
why canned flavins are not as well
studied as other cannabis compounds
Canada's method for isolating capturing
and concentrating these molecules and
potential medical applications for
canned flavins and how they may work in
combination with cannabinoids
before we get to my conversation with
Akeem I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor canirta
Canada is a pre-clinical biotechnology
company pioneering the discovery and
production of Novel
polyphenol-rich ingredients to improve
chronic disease prevention and Recovery
their research and Technology unlocks
the significant anti-inflammatory
antiviral anti-cancer and
neuroprotective potential of plant
polyphenols canerta aspires to improve
health outcomes promote longevity and
pull humans and animals out of the cycle
of chronic disease
to learn more visit canada.com
that's c-a-n-u-r-t-a.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Akeem
gardener
[Music]
good afternoon Akeem thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast thanks for
having me Ben excited to be here all
right and I'm excited to talk with you
because you are presenting at can mid 23
about research that your team has done
into using cannabis derived flavonoids
or canned flavins to treat cancer but
before we get too deep into that I
always like to start with the basics and
that might be especially true here
because I know that canned flavins are
not as well known as other cannabis
compounds so what are flavonoids or
canned flavins well we'll we'll start
with flavonoids and we'll get to the can
flavins in a second right but nice and
nice and sweet flavonoids are a class of
polyphenolic secondary metabolites found
in most plants so they're commonly
consumed in the diets of humans and
animals right we've been consuming them
since the beginning of time chemically
flavonoids have a general structure of a
15 carbon skeleton which consists of of
two fennel rings and a heterocyclic ring
and the key important differentiation
here is that it's a completely different
class of molecules than the more
commonly well-known cannabinoids or
terpenes that people are familiar with
from Cannabis hemp
right and so structurally they're
different how else are they different
from from cannabinoids and terpenes well
it
really the structure and and
I guess their activity and how the plant
uses them right
usually these molecules they have high
antioxidant properties the plant uses
them as part of their defense mechanism
they don't work on the endocannabinoid
system at least in the same way as our
cannabinoids and our terpenes do there
are different class of molecules and
that's what makes them unique for
exploration when it comes to people
exploring the synergistic effect of full
plant extracts in order to understand
this Synergy you need to be able to
understand all the different components
of the plant and that includes these
polyphenols or these flavonoids that are
there
great and now
how many different I mean I don't know
if you could put a number on it but how
many different flavonoids are found in
cannabis and are they unique to cannabis
are they found elsewhere in other plants
as well well just like much like the
cannabinoids right the flavonoids
there's a whole bunch of them and
they're found all across plant species
um all across the world right but what
makes cannabis hemp unique is that they
have very
specific or unique
flavonoids to them and this is where we
get to our canned flavins our canned
flavins aren't found anywhere else in
the plant life right and included with
the camp lavins are other molecules that
we might get to a little bit later
um still beans but benzyls that are
unique to cannabis hemp right now these
unique molecules are what we believe
adds to the high therapeutic effect of
the Cannabis hemp plant that humans have
experienced from the beginning of time
right why they continue to come back to
cannabis as a treatment for a variety of
different indications because
specifically in the synergistic profile
of this plant right are these novel
molecules that are known to help with
human and animal health
he
okay and now
are there certain canned flavins that
are you know more well known than others
that folks may have heard about before
well not canned flavins right because
again canned flavins are the more
specific molecule but flavonoids
probably yes right these are molecules
like the epigenous right
um cursor tin Resveratrol is uh more
recently well-known flavonoid because of
its um promise in regards to longevity
research right
Rootin was first isolated from oranges
in the mid 19 I think it was 1960s so
that was the first one of the first
flavonoids to be identified in the plant
matter so
there are more well-known ones but
flavonoids as a whole people aren't
really familiar with right they just
know to eat their fruits and vegetables
because they're good for the good for
you right
right and now so you mentioned a few
there
um are there flavonoids that are
currently being used as Therapeutics or
um for other indications
they're in a lot of exploration around
them right so again Resveratrol the more
most commonly known one
um has shown in different assays uh of
zebrafish and C elegans to be
have a lot of promise when it comes to
longevity neuroprotective properties
right but researchers around the world
scientists around the world and as you
know
most prevalent with natural health
ingredients in general there's always
the problem of translation and always
the problem of doing something with
enough specif specificity to be able to
get FDA approval as a registered
therapeutic but the work is out there
people are exploring it
um in fact in September I went for the
first time ever to the world polyphenol
conference and this is an annual
conference every year where people come
and they talk about all the different
signs from all around the world and the
researchers that's exploring this really
really unique class of molecules and
what they can do
interesting and now did I hear you right
is it difficult to really isolate these
compounds to really kind of study them
specifically
yes yes and especially when you're
looking at cannabis hemp yes right
more broadly when it comes to Natural
Health Products and um Natural Health
ingredients ingredients found in the
plant right there's a lot of challenges
about batch to batch repeatability how
do you know that this ingredient that
you get from one plant is the same as
the other plant so on and so forth right
so this makes um the exploration of most
plant-based molecules challenging in
themselves but when we look specifically
at Industrial Hemp cannabis right they
produce flavonoids at a very very
minimal
um profile in fact our can flavins so
when we talk about can flavins I'm
usually talking about can Flav and a and
b right and these molecules are found in
under
0.014 of the plant's biomass so they're
extremely minute extremely rare and that
makes isolating them capturing them
um very challenging it's part of the
reason why since their Discovery in the
mid-1980s there hasn't been a lot of
commercial or clinical work done on
these molecules they've mainly lived in
the world of Academia until professors
at the University of Guelph developed a
few technologies that allow for the
production of them in higher quantities
and it's these technologies that Canada
is the direct beneficiary of which
allows us to do the work that we're
doing today
okay interesting yeah I'm I'm kind of
interested to learn how you got
interested in canned flavins
um
what was it that attracted you to them
or what opportunity did you see there
well I got introduced to these molecules
by chance I was in the right place right
time
um and I was the lucky entrepreneur that
these professors at the University of
Guelph
um
chose to be able to partner with to
bring this forward right
um long story less Long right I'm not a
scientist by background or training
right
um I actually went to law school in the
United Kingdom from 2015 to 2017. after
graduating from the University of Ottawa
I did get my degree in Psychology and
philosophy there so some psychology of
the mind and how drugs affect the mind I
have some familiarity with but I thought
I was going to be a lawyer after but it
was really when I graduated from school
in 2017 and I returned back to Canada
and the legalization of marijuana
federally was amongst us I knew that
there was an opportunity going on in
Canada to be able to be part of this
emerging growing industry
um and an opportunity because we were
going to do it before the bigger Market
directly south in the U.S legalized
federally so I said to myself
um
um hey if I start now then I can be a
part of this movement of all the new
Innovations and everything going going
forward how can I get involved well the
hemp plant has 50 000 commercial uses I
like to say that's fifty thousand before
we add modern technology to it we're
really just now getting to understand
what this planet can do to accelerate
and create a more sustainable productive
world
so I decided instead of finishing my
accreditation to be a lawyer I was going
to use the money that I had from going
to school the line of credit to find
some farmland and start to grow hemp
and that's what I did I turned myself
from a law school graduate to a farmer
and I started to grow
um
no experience
um just a bright idea knew that this was
coming and I got my ass kicked on the
farm but what it did yeah it was it was
a crazy time but what it did do though
was it put me in a position of being a
king not the person with
just bright ideas Akeem the person who
was willing to work hard to see this
industry through right here in Ontario
and that ultimately led to a gentleman
from Omas omafra our ministry of food
and agricultural resources
to saying hey Akeem there are some
professors at the University of Guelph
they need some hemp they need a farmer
someone like myself to be able to do
some investigation on some of these
novel molecules that were there in the
plant and of course I was like wait
there's something else there outside of
the cannabinoids and terpenes send them
to my farm tell them to take all the
things that all the plants that they
want but I want to be a part of this
journey I want to know what's going on
and if there's ever the opportunity to
be a commercialization partner
um I'll prove it to you that I'm the
right partner to have and with that I
was able to show myself
um and I was able to show our dedication
the dedication of the team that we had
to this plant and that led them to
introducing us to all the amazing
possibilities around these unique
flavonoids the canned flavins and some
of the other molecules that we're trying
to investigate and explore right in the
Cannabis hemp plan
interesting so
is the is the technology here a way to
just concentrate the canned flavins or
is it um like breeding techniques to
have plants that produce more of them
what's going on here if you can even
share I'll Cheryl sure and this is where
things things get a little bit fun so
all of this started primarily with an
extraction technology right we have a
patented way of isolating capturing
concentrating these molecules out of the
plants of biomass and this is what we
started with but as we continue to grow
from 2020 when we acquired our first
intellectual property patent to where we
are now we also have two other ways of
getting to the molecules we also have a
growing production pattern a way of
enriching these molecules in the plant
matter right from the seed and we also
have an enzymatic biosynthesis
production platform a way of creating
these molecules in bioreactors purely
from scratch
now the combination of all these
Technologies give us a really really
interesting
um
commercial Advantage because not only
can we
now make these molecules purely from
scratch but we can also make pure and
authentic standards of these molecules
so that when we're looking in the plant
matter whether whether it be a grown
plant or an extract we can correctly
identify and label and say that there's
this much of flavonoid a b and c d right
that are there and this is what the FDA
and any regulatory agency wants to see
when you're bringing a natural health
product or a drug product to Market they
want to know that you can have batch to
batch consistency that they want to know
that you have clinically relevant assays
of what each ratio of these molecules
can provide and it gives us the ability
to not only bring these molecules to
Market in complex mixtures but also in
their pure individual forms and when it
comes to developing drugs and
Therapeutics this is where things get
exciting because now we can really play
around and say Hey What Can these
molecules do on their own what can they
do in combination and what can they do
against a variety of different
um disease States and therapeutic
indications
excellent so that's a good segue so
let's start talking about some of that
work
um so I know that the abstract that
you're going to present be presenting at
km at 23 it's looking at canned flavins
A and B
um so in addition to the fact that
they're you know alphabetically first
what was it about it again for Evans AMV
that were of particular interest
well well CAT5 and a and b are the most
well-known
novel flavonoids in the plaque they were
first identified in the mid-1980s and
when they were first identified by
Marilyn Barrett and her colleagues they
were found to have 30 times the
anti-inflammatory power than ASA the
active ingredient in Aspirin but also in
later in 2014 we learned that they had a
different mechanism of action than most
NSAIDs so they don't lead to many of the
GI issues the bleeding of the gut and
the ulcers that you get from our end
seeds
um so this led to the camp flavins being
at the top of the list of the novel
molecules that are in the plant and
that's where the researchers at Guelph
wanted to start their research
um but
um
I guess seguing to how we get from
inflammation to cancer we know that not
only do does many chronic diseases start
with systematic chronic inflammation but
we also know that
um some of these Solutions some of these
bioflavonoids right they have a host of
therapeutic potential that are
unexplored right now I'm an unexplored
with modern assays so one Professor uh
inventor of our patents Dr akhtar he
gave a colleague in his lab Dr Jasmine
Le long the can flavins to play with and
look at to say hey could these be
beneficial for nor protection for
neuroinflammation and Jasmine did an
initial screen to check and see might
they be and what Jasmine found was
actually the opposite expectation of
what he was initially looking for right
that these molecules were not
necessarily useful for neural
inflammation which we can talk about a
little bit later but they showed promise
of blocking an important receptor the
Trek B receptor tropomycin kinase B and
this led him to believe that
um
this is what this led him to believe
that this could be extremely important
in regards to a variety of different
um cancers including glioblastoma
multiform which is what our published
paper is on is about
great so so you mentioned the
anti-inflammatory properties of these of
these compounds and I know that you know
CBD is also credited to be a very you
know anti-inflammatory the way that it
acts on the
endocannabinoid system so
I was wondering how do those two how
those two compounds kind of interact and
is
and and I guess my question is
is CBD the only thing that's doing well
obviously it's not so maybe that's not
the right way to phrase it but is was
some of the anti-inflammatory uh effects
of CBD maybe
um inappropriately credited to CBD in
that the canned flavins were actually
doing some of the work too
maybe who knows this is some of the
excitement of the work that we have
um in front of us up here at Canada
the
interesting thing is that we know and we
know this the literature is out there
right that when you look at whole plant
extract versus pure isolated CBD there's
a difference of efficacy in the whole
plant versus the pure isolab right when
it comes to anti-inflammation anti-pain
and a host of other things right
so the real thing that we want to
investigate is when you start to break
down these components of the Pure Plant
extract what is each constituent
um responsible for and not only what are
they responsible for but how do they act
in Synergy with each other so
instead of having a pure CBD
anti-inflammatory or pure can Flavin
anti-inflammatory can you have a
combined CBD can Flavin
anti-inflammatory things that work on
different mechanisms that are
responsible are different targets that
are responsible for inflammation in the
body and then when they work
synergistically they're for the optimal
benefit of human or animal health right
this is where we know that some of our
work is going to start to open the doors
to researchers around the world when
they start to look and explore and say
what can these molecules do
um or why is the Cannabis hemp plant
doing what it's doing and
give them hopefully the data set that
they need when it comes to dealing with
regular regulators and getting um
Therapeutics passed and improved to go
to market
yeah no and that's a great point and I I
it it escapes me who who mentioned it on
the podcast before but they were looking
at you know different cannabinoid
concentrations for certain indications
and trying to isolate the the
cannabinoids to try to get the similar
effect
um and even maybe even using a
combination of cannabinoids but they
weren't able to see the same thing that
they could in the whole plant extract
and obviously their hypothesis was there
must be some other smaller compound or
compounds present there that they didn't
account for that's doing some of the
work and hey maybe that's the canned
flavins or maybe that's something else
that we haven't even found yet
this is where things get exciting right
I can share right
that um
there are about 15 to 20 other molecules
in the plant that we're pretty excited
about that
this modern standards of identification
aren't available to the masses yet these
molecules are there again arcanflav and
a and b are there in under
0.014 of the plant so we have to
concentrate so much to be able to get
these out in commercial or clinical
quantities luckily we found out we found
a pretty unique and easy way to do it to
do so to make it commercially feasible
but as we start to concentrate now we
start to get to look at what are some of
these other Peaks um that our hplc is
identifying and can we create standards
to identify these other molecules that
are there and when we start to isolate
these other molecules what can they do
on their own what do they do in Synergy
and how can each of these class of
compounds be best used to optimize human
and animal health
this is where we think that things are
extremely promising when it comes to
indications like inflammatory related
diseases cancers
respiratory diseases neuroprotective
um diseases neurodegenerative diseases
sorry I should say and then your
protective qualities of these molecules
and what the next 10 15 20 years looks
like especially after the rest of the
world starts to legalize one of the
things that again I'm a very fortunate
and lucky beneficiary of is the fact
that Canada decided to go first as the
first G7 country to legalize federally
that allowed for our universities to be
able to come to my farm take them take
the plant and say what's there we know
that in the U.S right now state to state
we have legalization and we're starting
to
get to the aspects of federal
legalization at least in regards to
research right now under Biden but as
this continues to open up it just allows
so many bright minds and people with
innovative ideas to come touch the plant
add their unique twists and Spins to it
and that's really going to push health
care and plant-based medicine forward
and that's one of the things that I'm
excited about being a part of
yeah we're excited about that too it's
one of the things that we try to create
an environment for at can Med is to
bring uh all all people that are working
on the plant together to share their
information make connections
um and kind of move this forward so
um so that's great uh but I did want to
ask you so you brought up again the
small concentrations that are found in
the cannabis plant so is it is the case
that a little goes a long way when it
comes to canned flavins that you don't
need a super high dose to get that
therapeutic effect
depending on what indication you're
going for
probably most most probably right and
this is what some of our initial data is
is showing us right now we have a suite
of a variety of different in silicone
and in vitro and early in Vivo data
animal data that's showing us um the
different areas of indications that we
should go after and we know the
concentrations and the ranges of how our
molecules work
the real key now is how does this
translate to humans right who are
um we're bigger right we need
um viral distribution of these molecules
in the bloodstream at the site of
actions to be able to get therapeutic
effect
can we do that with these rare molecules
we know that we can capture these
molecules at Commercial and clinical in
clinical amounts we have a variety of
different Natural Health ingredients but
also pharmaceutical ingredients that
will launch in the years to come to
start to get these ingredients and these
molecules onto the market but now it's
about now in our current investigation
it's
how do we get
um well and in the paper that we're
going to discuss and the interference on
track B and how that affects a variety
of different cancers how do we get our
mixture of can 5 and ABC
um to the site of the tumor to be able
to whether it be kill the tumor whether
it be to slow the spread whether it be
to work as an adjunct therapy so that
you need less radiation and less
chemotherapy to be able to help the
patients how does all of this work and
this is what we're really focusing on
right now in our research up at Canada
excellent yeah I know I'm glad you
brought that up because we're getting
towards in here we didn't even get into
the abstract that you're going to be
presenting we kind of danced around it
but let's
um
let's talk about it in more detail so
give me a summary or you know sort of
the main takeaway that you're that
you're hoping to to get across with your
presentation
so the main takeaway that we that we're
um hoping to get get across is that we
know that our flavonoids are can 5 and a
and b and they inhibit the activation of
the tropomycin kinase B tropomycin
receptor kinase B in primary cortical
neurons and this is very promising when
it comes to glioblastoma but other other
areas of cancer research as well like
breast cancer and pancreatic cancer as
well
we know we have doses that can disrupt
the downstream signaling of the track B
receptors they reduce the accumulation
of active activity regulated
psychoskeleton Associated proteins right
and they've been working in the
neuroblastoma cell line so now
um well at the at kanmed my hope is to
dive a little bit deeper into how we got
here
um to share some of the assays that we
did to be able to prove this and show
some of our more more recent work since
we published at the top of the Year from
Dr Jasmine the Long's Lab at the
University of Guelph
excellent and now you mentioned that
you're you know that your team you're
interested in other compounds you're
interested in other indications sort of
um what other things are you looking
into
um
as simple as put in I'll be very broad
here today because I do have a couple of
other well actually I could actually say
I think at cadmed you're going to be
able to hear from not only ourself but
Mr Hunter land in regards to what our
molecules can do in areas of
neurodegeneration longevity and health
span as well right this is an area
that's pretty interesting and
um in presentation with Hunter
um we're hoping that we can show some
pretty positive signs of what these
molecules can do not only on their own
but in combination with cannabinoids as
well
um outside of the neurodegeneration and
our anti-cancer promise I mentioned we
have some respiratory diseases that
we're looking at and the clear
anti-inflammatory angle as well so over
the in the years to come we're hoping
that we can continue to build up
momentum and show promise for our
molecules so that we can continue to
explore again just how effective and
useful these molecules can do across a
wide variety of chronic diseases for
both human and animals as well
all right you got a lot of work to do
so before I let you get back to that
work
um and Before I Let You Go I want to
give you the opportunity to share any
other
um resources that the listeners might be
interested to learn more about whether
it's your company or can flavins or any
of the research that you're doing and
then of course
um any websites or social media that
you'd like to share with the folks so
they can keep up with you please plug
away
awesome awesome awesome so our website
is canada.com
c-a-n-u-r-t-a.com you can find a lot of
information about what we're doing and
how we're doing it there also the
abstract that we'll be presenting at can
Med
um the main paper was published the
interference of neuronal track B
signaling by the can cannabis derived
flavonoids can Flav and a and b the lead
author the on that paper is Jennifer
Jennifer Holborn out of Dr Jasmine
luong's Lab at the University of Guelph
this was published in February in the
Journal of fidal Medicine plus if anyone
wants to read it there as well and you
can always reach out to me on LinkedIn
my name is Akeem Gardner I'm always
excited to talk about cannabis about
health and wellness and about what this
plant can do for the future so if
anyone's interested in diving a little
bit deeper I look forward to seeing you
at can Med 2000 and 23 and me just come
up to me say hi or reach out to me on
LinkedIn or on social media and we can
go from there
all right that sounds great and I'll pop
those links into the show description so
people can have an easy way to find them
and find you
so Akeem thanks again for taking the
time I think it was a great conversation
and I look forward to meeting you in
person down in Florida
I look forward to it as well Ben see you
soon
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Akeem Gardener check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and thanks again
to this episode sponsor Canada our next
episode drops March 15th that's two
weeks from today
in the meantime please do head over to
canmanevents.com and view our schedule
there you can learn all about the great
oral presentations and intensive
workshops that we have planned for Kim
at 23.
and if you haven't yet received an
invitation for cam med23 you can request
one at cammedevents.com
we are really excited about this year's
event and truly believe it has the power
to transform our industry through
collaboration and Innovation I sincerely
hope to see you there
but if you can't make it in person to
Marco Island we do hope that you will
continue to stay connected with us
through the podcast and through our
social media channels you can find us on
LinkedIn Twitter Facebook and Instagram
just search for Canada events all right
and that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and be sure to come back for the
next Kim at Coffee Talk
[Music]