[Applause]
i'm going to be the opposite of kyle and
here here and i need to bring the
microphone down some
um so as brian said i was i'm a
pediatric neurologist i'm specialized in
epilepsy and neurogenetics specifically
some disclosures i am a consultant for
coordination and i'm
also going to talk about some off-label
treatment in epilepsy
so the point of my talk is to try to
bring
together the bring together the
topics of epilepsy cannabis and genetics
and how to
use the data together to see how we can
cater
the treatment courses for these patients
so i wanted to do a quick jump through
the brief history of epilepsy and
cannabis
hemp was first known as agricultural cop
crop in modern taiwan in 8000 bc
but the first recorded use of cannabis
as medicine occurred in china
about five millennias later and over
time
uh it spread from china out west east
north
south unfortunately um the oldest
reading recording of epilepsy was in
ancient mesopotamia in 2000 bc but it
was viewed as a psychiatric disorder
possessed by demons type of thing
as you can see some of these drawings
and the treatment was not very good
going anywhere from leaching to burr
hose in the skull
so not exactly the most pleasant of
treatments
unfortunately we have progressed
starting in 500 bc thanks to hippocrates
who defined epilepsy as a medical
condition as opposed to a psychiatric
condition
and a greek physician galen a few
centuries later
started prescribing medical marijuana in
general not specifically for epilepsy
um going into modern times dr william
o'shonasi introduced medical marijuana
to western medicine including the
treatment of epilepsy so that was the
first recorded history
of medical marijuana being used for
epilepsy
um in 1850 bromide was the first
effective
anti-seizure medication by that was
introduced by sir
charles locka and since then uh we have
had many more seizure medications
introduced um to the point where we're
over 30 seizure medications now
including
1910 when phenobarbital was introduced
as the first synthetic compound
with the most recent being aption
so cannabis was added to the u.s
pharmacopoeia in 1850 as well but
unfortunately in 1914 the harrison act
defined marijuana as a crime and
subsequently following
california coincidentally was the first
state to
illegalize marijuana um
then dr rafael mccutchulin who we've had
the honor of listening to
um started researching um
medical marijuana and was started
isolating and synthesizing delta nine
thc
um and then in 1970 the controlled
substance act classified marijuana as
schedule 1
which basically illegalized it
nationwide
and that's where the problem started
marinol
did become fda approved in 1985 so that
started opening up some doors again
and then the cannabis receptors cb1
specifically was discovered in 1988 by
doctors howlett and devane
coincidentally in 1996 california became
the first state to re-legalize marijuana
and then the whole modern progression of
marijuana started medical marijuana
started in august 2000 2013 when sanjay
gupta
endorsed the product on cnn program
called weeds and highlighted the story
of charlotte figue
and gw started their trials soon
thereafter
so is epilepsy treatable i'm saying
treatable because most of the time it's
not curable we're basically putting
a band-aid on a symptom because seizures
are a symptom of the epilepsy which is
the disorder
as you see here this is a well-known
study from 2000 from
dr brody and for the first medication
works okay about 50 percent of
seizure patients become seizure-free but
as you get to the second and third drug
it's getting worse and worse to the
point where
the chance that when you're on the third
drug or higher it's only about a three
percent chance that you're going to
become seizures free so not very good
so about a third of patients remain what
we call intractable meaning failing two
or more seizure medications
so i think the best way to highlight all
this topic
is to go through some case presentations
and i have some videos that are slightly
graphic
um i try to choose more of the benign
ones but i think it really brings home
the point about
what these parents and these families
have to deal with um so
the first patient is mk she presented to
me at 11 years of age
her seizure started at six months with
of high fever after vaccinations
and then she had started having seizures
without fever at her initial evaluation
with me she had multiple seizure types
tried on multiple seizure medications
including oxycobazipine and lamotrigine
both are sodium channel mechanisms
um the ox cabazipima trilepto made her
seizures worse but then lamotrigine did
not which she's currently on as well
development was normal until about a
year and then she was subsequently
diagnosed with autism and was basically
non-verbal
and workup was essentially negative
including basic genetic workup and eeg
and mri changes that were non-specific
so i knew the diagnosis right away
hearing the story so i asked cordagen
to send the epilepsy next generation
sequencing panel she did come back with
a scn-1a de novo mutation meaning she
has dravet syndrome she fits that
phenotype
i asked them to rush it because the
epidiolex trials were just about to
close and i was running the trials in
orlando at that time
so i was able to get her in quickly the
importance of this mutation is that you
have to avoid sodium channel blocking
agents because it's a loss of function
mutation
in general though in the subset of
populations for some reason we don't
know yet and then we have to kind of
sort this out is they don't respond
adversely to sodium channel
agents but in in general you want to
avoid them because it can bring them
into status epilepticus
but she was placed in the epidiolex
child she had an immediate 50
seizure reduction eg showed background
improvement which is
unusual to actually get a change in the
background itself
and she was talking much more and had
much more improved eye contact
as an additional example i have another
patient exactly the same story
diagnosed before i saw her put in the
epidiolex child
she was non-verbal she was eating poorly
from day one we administered the
epidialex
as the mom was driving home she all of a
sudden spat out
mom i want food mom basically slammed on
the brakes and said okay
the first visit that she came back to me
i was also floyd she was
playing on her ipad which she was doing
before but i was seeing what she was
doing and she was actually spelling
words on the ipad which
completely floored me um dr davinski
kind of
went through this data already so i'll
just go look at it briefly as you see
here they did section out the dravet
syndrome
patients and they did have a better
response so there's a certain
subset of populations that is going to
respond better to the epidiolex
and these were the phase three datas
that dr davinsky already went through
so ja is another patient of mine he
presented to me at three years of age
with explosive onset of myoclonic
seizures so
basically jerking type of seizures he
also started having drop seizures atonic
seizures as well as generalized tonic
clonic seizures
and i kindly diagnosed him with dozer
syndrome um with dozer syndrome there's
no good treatment for it
some people say ketogenic diet some say
very good nerve stimulator but there's
no good treatment
he was having seizures so often by the
time
we tried him on certain medications he
was having seizures every seven to ten
seconds so imagine your life like that
there's no way
a child's brain can develop that way he
was tried on multiple medications
including ketogenic diet
he completely regressed he could not
walk he could not talk anymore he
couldn't even eat anymore
and his work up was basically negative
as well
so i wanted to show you a video of his
seizures
maybe
um maybe not okay um but basically as
you see his background eg's
very messy all those big generalized
spikes um he basically just
dropped or jerked every seven to ten
seconds and then he had those big
seizures as well
at this point i really had no more
options for this family i said well we
can try the vagal nerve stimulator but
the data is not very good on that as
well
i did send for genetic testing and he
had
two mutations come up one was a chd2
mutation which in the literature
had just been reported at a time
associated with severe myoclonic
epilepsy as well
however it was materially inherited so i
wasn't sure if that was the complete
answer but i kind of went with that
diagnosis
for the time being and mom was
asymptomatic so i wasn't sure
he also had a second mutation the
calcium channel cachna1a
which at that time i didn't believe
explained his symptoms because it's only
been reported with familial hemiplegic
migraine and episodic ataxia at that
time
but it was de novo meaning neither
parents passed on and so that was a
little unusual so i kept an eye on that
but so what we uh last year
uh this past december though there was a
few case reports with cachna 1a
associated with severe myoclonic
epilepsy so
i did talk to the parents about that but
i gave the parents the blessing they
they said that we want to move to
colorado and try cbd i said go because i
wasn't legalized in florida yet
and he after playing with a few
different strains few uh different
dosing we finally got him down to about
two to three seizures day remember this
kid was having
seizures every seven to ten seconds so
that was a huge improvement
um basically the when one of the emails
the family sent me was just basically
he's
they said he is back our little kid is
back he was
walking he was talking again he's
participating in regular classroom
settings
he's not quite normal but he's at least
you know being able to be integrated
into a regular classroom and he's eating
again
so this is him and as you see uh he's he
looks quite normal you would not
have known like a few months ago he was
having seizures every
seven to ten seconds so the
calcium channel mutation is interesting
because it works on the p and q type
calcium channels
now we don't have any seizure
medications that work on those channels
but we do have a blood pressure
medication that works on it called
verapamil
and that's the thing i'm going to try
them on next because i'm never happy
until the child's seizure free
so we're going to try this on the child
next um we actually have used for apple
meal in seizures before in the gervais
patient population and it has helped a
subset of those kids as well
so i'm excited to kind of see what
happens with him
um ec he's a six-year-old global delays
noted typical story bad
motor delays in speech became non-verbal
diagnosed with autism he started having
seizures
diagnosed at three and a half may sleep
mostly tonic seizures where you get
stiff all over
he had multiple um he's been on multiple
seizure medications basically he's tried
everything under the book
and he was having about 40 plus seizures
a day as well
yeah yeah the first video didn't have
that for some reason
so as you see here interactively meaning
between seizures he usually has a bunch
of spikes you don't see there but he
just has some background slowing
and then what he does is he drops and
then he cuts stiff and his background
just flattens and that's a typical
atonic tonic type of seizure
and remember he was having about 40 of
these a day
and just imagine for a kid that is uh
ambulatory this is not good because
they're falling constantly they'll have
to use a wheelchair they have to
wear a helmet he also had these episodes
of dystonia which
the previous neurologist kind of treated
him with baclofen it worked okay
since infancy also he had a lot of gi
issues cyclic vomiting
alternating constipation diarrhea
problems with weight gain
and also a lot of behavioral issues very
hyper very aggressive and that was
actually the main
concerns outside of seizures for the
parents um workup was basically normal
the microarray showed a
chromosomal deletion that i didn't felt
um fit the picture so i ignored that
so i also sent the epilepsy pattern on
him he came back to me with two
mutations as well
one is in the scn2a a sodium channel
just like sn1a but these
mutations are different because they're
gain of function mutations as opposed to
loss of function mutations
it was the novel so it wasn't inherited
by either family but i couldn't
so i couldn't completely toss it out but
he doesn't really present with like that
that most of the
all the scn2a kids present with seizures
under a year of age so unless the
parents completely missed it
um he doesn't quite fit that but i
wanted to keep that in my back pocket
the reason for that is
if he failed the treatment that we had
for him that i would put them on very
high dose sodium channel agents even
then in the literature those
that high dose doesn't get them
seizure-free but at least it helps them
but more importantly and this is a
diagnosis i thought about with him is he
had a
solute six eight a mutation
which is linked to x-linked creatine
transport
deficiency and this was inherited
through the mom
this is very important because as
opposed to creatine deficiency disorders
they don't respond as well
to the supplements um i did think about
these things um however
when a local lab gets an um order like
guanadino acetate they kind of freak out
and have no idea what they're ordering
and just order something else so i kept
getting the wrong thing so
i actually got these metabolic markers
four and a half months after i got his
genetic diagnosis and they were abnormal
they called me
and i said yeah yeah i already know okay
so on the left here is
mrs as you see this is the choline
creatine peak and that's what's normal
and this is the patient's as you see his
choline peak is much lower than what it
should be
his creatine peak is much lower than it
should be but this was important
information for me because it tells me
that he has some creatine going into his
brain
so there is some transporter function so
i said go ahead let's go ahead and try
this supplements
we put him on the supplements and he's
been seizure-free since his gi issues we
completely resolved
his improved energy his eg basically
normalized he has a few spikes here and
there but not like the bad eeg
background that i was seeing before
i repeated his mrs as well and there was
a 50 increase in creatine but
i couldn't go higher on his supplements
because if i go higher on his creatine
basically i
destroy his kidneys he however did not
have any improvements on cognition of
behavior
so the parents wanted to try cbd oil
unfortunately we did try that and he's
had no improvement but i was limited in
florida as well about what ratios i
could use
so as the laws open up hopefully they'll
be able to try other things
and the next thing would be try those
high dose sodium channel agents
but more importantly there is a clinical
trial in process with a creatine analog
specifically for these creatine
transported so
there will be no delays and diagnosis
with him once that trial opens i can
enroll him right away
and the mom was inherited because any
future boy she has that has a 50
risk of having this disorder
tc now is a five month old male he
presented at with
these episodes of behavioral arrest and
losing tone for 30-60 seconds which only
occurred during when he was sick
otherwise neurologically he was intact
in between episodes
and these were his episodes the eg
background is very normal
this is during one of his illnesses
and as you see he has good enough
strength to palm up but then he starts
getting wobbly
and then eventually he'll fall over and
he has a starter response not a seizure
and he just flops over the eg was normal
but the parents really wanted to know
what was going on and i didn't have an
answer for them but i said this sounds
like an energy
metabolism problem so i said let's send
for mitochondrial
unfortunately we did because it came
back and he had a solute 2a1 mutation
which enclosed for glucose transporter
one deficiency
so this kid got diagnosed at eight
months of age which is one of the
earliest ever for glucose transporter
one and it was the novo mutation once
again
coincidentally though they sent me this
video the same day i got the
genetic report back with these new
episodes
and basically he just has what we call
oral automatisms mouth smacking lip
smacking
and he kind of stares off so this could
be one of two types of seizures focal
seizures or absence seizures
but absent seizures really don't exist
in this age group
eight months of age with the exception
of glucose transporter one deficiency
so i got the diagnosis early before he
really became truly symptomatic um his
eg
consistent with absence seizures i
tapped him uh
and his glucose and ratios were low in
the csf it's immediately started on the
ketogenic diet and he's been free
seizure-free since um and has no
problems with his developmental
um he can also be enrolled in the
trihephthalon trial if he decides in the
future he doesn't want to do the nasty
ketogenic diet
but this is important because most of
these children don't get diagnosed late
in life i have several kids who come to
me at eight nine years old or older
they have these severe epilepsies global
delays movement disorders which is the
typical triad
of group one and by that time their
brains already destroyed and
irreversibly bleed damage so they're
they're
placed on the ketogenic diet the
seizures may improve but
their cognitive abilities don't improve
so would this be a case where
cbd oil may come into play and help
these children
is cannabis a reasonable option for
treating procedures we do know it has
anti-epileptic properties
it probably has has anti-inflammatory
properties that are also helping these
kids because these kids are seizing all
the time
their brains become damaged and
endemicus
so these anti-inflammatory problems will
help with that this is a map from
2006 in 2007 where these are the states
that were legalized we've progressed a
lot since then this is the current map
including georgia and virginia that were
just approved late last year and then
pennsylvania which will also be
pushing a bill through as well so what
do we know it's not a panacea
nothing is okay at least one strain is
not going to solve
every disorder and unfortunately this we
can't just have one drug company test
for
one ratio on one type of patient that
will take forever to figure this out
cbd is non-euphoric and non-addictive it
can be effective for many diseases
including many neurological disorders
side effects and ure spasticity
epidiolex for gervais syndrome
it is safe at least in the short-term
data but what other diseases can it be
effective for
we have a lot of anecdotal data and
small case series but very little
randomized double-blinded
placebo-controlled studies what is the
specific mechanism
and what compounds are needed there's a
lot of different compounds to cbd as you
see in the in the cbd pathway
microcannabinoids terpenes and so forth
different diseases will need different
ratios we do know need we
do know that and it's how much thc is
effective because we do know thc is also
pro-convulsive meaning it can cause
seizures
and what is the long-term safety data on
this compound
we still need a lot of studies so i just
wanted to end with a quote
by hippocrates himself people think that
epilepsy is divine simply because they
don't have any idea what causes epilepsy
but i believe that someday we will
understand what causes epilepsy and at
that moment we will cease to believe
that it's divine
and so it is with everything in the
universe and that's the case today
as we're finding the genetic etiologies
of epilepsies and can kind of cater the
treatment course
of these patients um it can affect the
outcome as with the glucose transporter
one
that diagnosis or basically save this
child's life and development
and then genetic testing can be helpful
as far as guiding if another treatment
is appropriate so for example that
glucose transporter one deficiency
you want to treat with ketogenic diet
first you don't want to play it out with
medical marijuana but we have kids that
has a cdk l5 mutation where we know
nothing works on these kids so why
mess around and wait instead of just
going directly to cbd and testing that
looking at responders versus
non-responders based on the metabolism
and the pathways as well as allowing
phenotyping of the compound to determine
contaminants
okay thank you for your time