[Music]
um in that
scenario um do they have similar kind of
therapeutic or you know similar effects
um because I know that in some cases the
neutral versus the acid they actually
have opposite
effects right so many of the targets of
CBD and cbda are the same they're
they're very similar and and so yeah if
you look at THC versus thca and compare
their pharmacology in the body very
different and when people take them they
feel very different um CBD versus cbda
is much more similar and so probably you
know one of the targets that's going to
be most important for for people that
are using this is the um the activity of
the serotonin receptor so they both can
kind of reduce anxiety and improve mood
via that serotonin pathway there's
there's been a number of animal studies
looking at the two um sometimes not in
the same study but two different studies
that have used the same model to
evaluate cbda versus CBD and you'll see
that they they can do the same thing
they both can reduce seizures they both
can decrease inflammatory pain they both
can uh decrease nausea and vomiting you
know there's there's a lot of overlap
there uh mechanistically It's usually
the same Target the the way in which
they're achieving these outcomes is the
same but the dosing is often vastly
different with cbda requiring a much
lower dose suggesting it as uh well what
we know from the animal studies is that
it has both better bioavailability so
take a dose more of it's getting into
the body and then it also has more
potency once once it's in the body you
know if you look at brain levels or
blood levels of these compounds that are
necessary to achieve their result you
need much less of it so more gets in and
you need much less maybe one of the
downsides is that CBD seems to last
longer in the body cbda you'll excrete
more quickly you might therefore have to
take it more often but um but a lot of
overlap there yeah and then kind of one
of the Nuggets that I picked up watching
your presentation from last year was you
showed some graphs showing that
cbda um is actually better absorbed when
it's part of a full plant extract that
that is that that I mean there's there's
findings and rodents you know we haven't
proven that for humans yet but based on
what we're seeing when people say you
know we get we taking these low Doses
and they're working really well and then
there is a human study that showed cbda
absorption through the gut was extremely
high it didn't test it like it did in
the rodent study on its own versus in
the in the context of a whole plant
extract but all the information we have
is pointing to to what you said that
essentially if you if there's a little
bit of THC or
CBG present with the cbda you might
absorb it or at least a rodent might
absorb like 15 times more of it with
just a little bit of THC or or CBG now
no none of us would have planned that
but I think a lot of us would have said
there is a pretty good chance that for
one reason or another taking this thing
in the context of the whole plant is
going to beat taking the isolated
compound you know and that that's the
lesson we've learned again and again and
again there's going to be exceptions to
that lesson you know in certain
situations but typically that is the
case and once in a while we know why
that's the case this is one of those
scenarios where we we think we know why
that's the
[Music]
case