[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben emerald i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
speaking of the canmed conference have
you gotten your tickets yet for
canmed2022
if yes then i can't wait to see you out
in pasadena this may for another
fantastic event
and if not what are you waiting for head
over to canmedevents.com now to get your
tickets
at cam ed 2022 you will learn from the
leading minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
and if you want proof of that look no
further than our keynote presenters
representing our science focus area we
have dr ethan rousseau presenting about
cannabis and psychiatry
representing our cultivation focus area
we have dr seth crawford talking about
innovations in hemp breeding
grace bandong our safety keynote
presenter will talk about building a
comprehensive analytical testing program
and finally dr bonnie goldstein will
discuss cannabis medicine for children
as our medical keynote
those presentations alone are worth the
price of admission but please go to kim
at events dot com to see the full
schedule
and if you want a preview of what you
can expect at kmed 2022 check out our
camed archive which is a searchable
video library of all the past canmed
presentations and panels find that at
cammannevents.com
at this year's event we are also
offering a full day pre-conference
medical practicum taking place on may
3rd
the medical practicum is led by dr
bonnie goldstein dr dustin sulak dr
kevin spellman and eloise
thiessen each of them will share the
latest medical cannabis research
including information on dosing drug
interactions and different product types
they will also share their clinical
experience they have acquired treating
patients with medical cannabis this
really is a must attend event for any
health care professionals who are
interested in recommending medical
cannabis but it's not limited to those
folks
anyone who is interested in learning
more about medical cannabis can and
should join us for this event head over
to kim at events dot com slash practicum
to learn more
of course if you can't make it to canmed
2022 we have a number of resources to
help you stay engaged with our community
and enjoy some world-class educational
content
you are already off to a good start
listening to the canmed coffee talk
podcast be sure to hit that subscribe
button so new episodes download to your
device automatically
second we have the canmed archive that i
mentioned earlier it's a searchable
video library of all the past kmed
presentations and panels that you can
find at kmedevents.com
while you're at canmedevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts that's the
best way to make sure you are up to date
on all the latest canmed news and
special offers
fourth we have our canmed community
facebook group which is a great place to
share and discuss news and topics
related to cannabis science the link to
that group is in the show description
and finally you can follow us on social
media we're on instagram facebook
twitter and linkedin just search for cam
at events
this episode we talk with dr punya
nachapa
punya runs a research program at
colorado state university that is
focused on understanding the
interactions between plants pathogens
and insect vectors and crops including
hemp
her team recently published a paper that
identified several different viruses in
colorado hemp samples most notably beet
curly top virus which is a pathogen
known to infect several different plant
species
in our conversation we discuss the
prevalence of beet curly top virus in
colorado hemp
how bctv compares to hop latent viroid
the bctv disease progression in hemp in
cannabis plants
we also talk at length about the only
known mode of transmission for bctv the
beet leaf hopper
we also get into strategies for
preventing bctv in keeping leaf hoppers
away and finally we discuss other
viruses and viroids cannabis and hemp
growers should be aware of
before we get to my conversation with
punya i'd like to thank this episode's
sponsor eugentec
eugentec offers smart analysis and
workflow software for endpoint
genotyping and qpcr pathogen testing
stop looking at every cluster or curve
let ai do the work and lab staff do the
review
whether you test for plant and seed
health or run studies for breeding or
crop science
fast finder will allow you to scale up
slash eyes on time on cluster calling in
genotyping automate pcr curve calling
and result reporting organize your labs
plates runs and studies and learn from
historic data to improve interpretation
speed and quality
for more information go to
eugentech.com that's u g e n t e c
dot com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with dr punya
nachapa
[Music]
good morning punya thanks for joining us
on the podcast
hi ben so great to be with you guys
yeah we're happy to have you here to
talk about a topic that's becoming
more top of mind for cannabis and hemp
growers that's viruses
yes plants get viruses too
you and your team have published a paper
in december that examined symptomatic
hemp leaf samples from colorado for beat
curly top virus which might be a virus
that listeners might not be familiar
with but before we get into that tell us
a bit about what you found and what you
published in the paper
so um i moved to colorado state
university in 2018 and
dr whitney crenshaw who had done most of
the work
on
characterizing pests complex complex
insect pests on hemp had um you know
alerted me to these virus-looking hemp
plants um in the field
um of course we didn't know anything at
that time it looked like you know very
typical yellowing and stunting um
symptoms and i was planning to go take a
look at it in the 2019 field season
but before i could do it myself we had
growers reaching out to my lab and the
plant diagnostic clinic here at csu it
was just an outbreak so of course we
went out uh dr whitney cranshaw came out
with us and it was incredible
the range of symptoms uh which i
published some of it in a short review
in outlooks and pest management
and the high level of incidents like you
mentioned 81 percent uh incidence is
just staggering uh you know in this new
crop
so it's pretty spectacular and spread
across
you know the western slope where we grow
most of the hemp here in colorado and
the northeastern area as well so pretty
widespread
and
my student who led that work judah
chiginsky we we continued to survey in
uh because the initial survey was in
2019 and 2020 it was limited because we
had another virus disrupting our lives
coveted
still we found in the limited survey we
found close to 100 percent bctv in hemp
wow
and then but last year i have some good
news for my growers um only only around
we think it was um it was very dry and
there was hardly anything green many
hemp growers didn't even grow much hemp
and the lack of you know green
vegetation may may have been one reason
for a lower incidence so it's been up
and down uh but it's definitely
you know it's this disease this virus
has been around for over hundreds of
years and other crop species so it's
definitely to show up in hemp again
so that percentage of um
of prevalence that you're finding with b
curly top virus now is that in
symptomatic leaves only or is that in
asymptomatic plants as well very good
question so you know in 2019 the work we
published in the paper was very targeted
so it was just the symptomatic plants
and like i said even that was
questionable because we'd seen such
range of symptoms
from curling to
something that we fondly call taco leaf
the leaf had completely curled up like
like a taco would all of them tested
positive for bctv so only in symptomatic
plants but currently we are having an
experiment in our greenhouse we're
working with this hemp genetics
developing company here in fort collins
new west genetics and we're screening
some of their lines and um some of them
are asymptomatic but test positive for
bctv uh using pcr
wow
and then
sorry go ahead please go ahead no i was
gonna say you know and then you've seen
our paper we we've had so many different
viruses in there right um and some of
them were healthy in fact the the sample
from larimer county uh that had um
cannabis cryptic virus was
healthy and beautiful as ever so
we really don't know the impact of these
viruses and the one viroid which is also
pretty important yeah i know that
cannabis cryptic virus it's no
it's no wonder why they call it cannabis
cryptic right it's uh
yes
yeah and i was gonna ask you about other
viruses too because you know i had
mentioned that it's viruses are becoming
more top of mind for hemp and cannabis
growers but the one that's that gets all
the publicity or gets all the notoriety
is is actually the viroid hoplite
thyroid so i wonder how does b curly top
virus differ from hot plate and viroid
how are they the same could there be
some sort of
um a case of misidentification people
thinking they have hoplite and thyroid
they actually have beet curly top um
your thoughts on that
so um
what's in we i'm just going to initiate
an um hop latent viroid project to do a
like you said you know better
characterization of it to help growers
but as the name suggests it's latent
right so it's dormant in the plant and
can go asymptomatic for uh you know
weeks to months is is my understanding
but then it causes the so-called duding
at least that's what the growers call it
where the flowers just don't flower and
are completely um
you know destroyed
um we haven't seen so in you know um we
detected hot plate and viroid in our
samples from two counties
and those samples predominantly had bct
symptoms had you know and coincidentally
they were infected um
with the hoplite and viroid or may it's
possible that the samples came from a
different plant and uh
because we had pooled samples you know
from from different plants in our um
sequencing so
um
i haven't first hand seen it but in
talking with a colleague in um
simon fraser university in canada
uh dr zameer punja who is a very well
known hemp a plant pathologist he was
telling us how predominant and prevalent
it is in canada with i think he
mentioned something like 70 or 80
percent
of um the cannabis uh being infected
with hot plate and vitroid in a study
that he had done
um you know so pretty staggering
how how it is so you know that's what
i'm that's the big difference between
bctv and hot plate and viral oil to me
but hoplite and viroi unlike bctv can be
transmitted mechanically right so you
touch an infected plant and then
and you have no idea that it's infected
because it's presumably asymptomatic and
you
handle a healthy plant and it gets
transmitted now with pctv
fortunately
we only there's only one mode of
transmission that's the beet leaf hopper
no other species of leaf hopper can even
transmit it to our knowledge
yeah it is it's it's just such a tight
evolutionary relationship just one
species and i work with aphids that
transmit viruses
like this potato virus y and there are
over 60 species of aphids that can
transmit the virus
but with bctv just the one so
that's really cool
and as far as we know it's not c
transmitted pctv
the cloud we're confirming that in our
lab because some growers
um
have that concern hemp growers
so that's the big difference right in in
some ways i think hot plate and viroid
because of the mechanical transmission
is you know spreading more rampantly in
fact we just got a
sample from a
colleague in
california
that
outwardly looked like bctv but tested
positive for both bc tv and hot plate
and viroid so you have this mix
infection and who knows what kind of
synergism or antagonism you know
multiple infections can have
yeah no that's a great point about hot
plate and viroid and sort of the unique
challenges that that raises another
thing to consider too is just you know
the clonal propagation of cannabis in
hemp as well right if you're if you're
taking a cutting from a plant that you
presume
yeah
is
not infected now you're handing a a bomb
to your
uh your colleague or your friend that's
going to be right
right exactly and
yeah and then who knows yeah the impact
on uh yeah
with you know crust uh prostate across
country movement and introducing these
pathogens
because it's not very well defined yet
as yet
you know seed certification or cuttings
right yeah or you know certified clones
too that are yeah
i mean
i know we ourselves in medicinal
genomics we're trying to develop pcr
assays to help people screen and do
things like that um so maybe eventually
we'll get there but um yeah it's still
very um
very early in that process so i want to
come back to the leaf hoppers because
that is really interesting i didn't
realize i i read in the paper that it
was you know the primary source of
infection but i didn't know that it was
the only source so
um
i'm curious more sort of about that is
it
how does that synergistic relationship
work
oh that's a great question so as i
mentioned you know the virus and the
vector um
the virus is only able to um you know
infect a plant via the beet leaf hopper
this one vector circular tenalis
and then and that's my training i'm an
entomologist by training so in these
fields in these hemp fields like you can
see in my background when we go over we
we use insect nests to sweep and there
we found around eight to ten different
species of leaf hoppers
and we tested each and every one of them
and only circular for tennelis
was positive for this exact same strains
that we were detecting in um
in our hemp sample so uh to date no one
has shown any other more means of
transmission of bctv there was one study
uh from iran i believe showing obesity
was seed transmitted in petunia but not
in
and it was very low uh transmission rate
but not in sugar beets or tomatoes some
of the other major crops that bctv
infects
so the the insect
picks up the virus from an infected
plant it's a phloem uh limited virus
right it's in the flow only in the floam
tissue of the of the plant so the insect
feeds on in the foam it's a foam feeding
insect sucks up the virus the virus
enters the insect gut
it does not replicate
uh as far as we know it just circulates
through the gut of the insects and then
comes and reinfects the salivary glands
of the insect and when the insect feeds
on a healthy plant usually they salivate
and that's when the
the virus particles of the virions come
out and infect the plant
now what's interesting is judith a
second part of her thesis my student
that led this work
she we're getting ready to publish
where we're showing that
virus infected insects actually have
better
reproduction better um life history
characteristics so you know when they
get infected they do better
um and able to proliferate more and
spread the virus more so the virus is
you know
uh manipulating vector performance and
this has been shown for other systems
but first time for bc tv
wow
so very intimate relationship yeah very
interesting
yeah that is interesting and
am i correct in maybe assuming that
the virus doesn't replicate via
mechanical transmission because
the the virus um you know is exposed to
the elements or whatever on the
instruments that you might be using and
it's not able to proliferate but then if
it's within the the gut of this leaf
hopper it's kind of more protected from
that is that safety now there are
viruses that do proliferate via
mechanical transmission you're right
like the most notorious one is tobacco
mosaic virus i mean that is um
so um
i'm not sure yeah there's you know how
that come this evolutionarily tight
relationship has come around with just
this one species of insect vector but
presumably you're right they are
um
you know
being um sort of um
protected
by the insect vector and then this
insect feeds on over 100 different plant
species
and able to transmit the virus to all of
these species now what's interesting is
we find that
the insects cannot reproduce on hemp
beet leaf hoppers
they can
and for that matter they don't do very
well on tomato or pepper the other major
hosts they can go maybe one generation
so the
females can produce one set of offspring
and then they just perish
so there's something um you know they're
not they haven't evolved with this um
plant uh potentially but
but they can they'd still do feed on the
plant and in in during that time it only
takes a couple of
hours for them minutes to hours to
transmit the virus
while they taste and they say oh i don't
like this too much this hosts too much
in the meantime they are transmitting
the virus
interesting so do the leaf hoppers not
particularly like the taste of of hemp
they don't feed on it as much they do
not in fact
more you know we
when we go looking for the leaf hoppers
in hemp we hardly find a handful but
then
in across in the surrounding fields we
or you know the ditches we see all these
weeds weed species
you know dandelion and kosher and
russian thistle that's where the leaf
hoppers are they really thrive on these
um bouquet of uh weed or buffet of
uh weed species and of course sugar
beets that's how we maintain them uh
in our lab
yeah that makes sense hence the name
right
yes
so
given the fact that it's just this
particular species of leaf hopper that's
spreading is this sort of a regional
issue and less of an issue with in other
areas
no not at all so in fact um leaf hoppers
don't even overwinter in colorado is
what we believe
it gets too cold for them we at least we
think uh uh some of our tracking work
has shown them that they
they are coming up from new mexico and
um arizona the population they
overwinter there and the more uh on weed
species again that it's more warmer
right than it is in colorado and once
those weeds dry down they are moving
northward so it's a huge problem
in
beet leaf hoppers and bctv is a huge
problem in peppers in new mexico
in arizona as well but most importantly
in california
bctv and
beetle hopper is a huge issue on
tomatoes and just devastated the tomato
industry you know some decades ago but
we have some tools and tomatoes
and i have talked to some researchers at
uc davis that have confirmed bc tv in
hemp they just haven't published it as
yet
yeah and i've also talked to some collab
some colleagues in oregon state
where again we have uh bc tv and beatles
and they've confirmed it in hemp as well
they just haven't uh published the work
so it's that at least you know
um western united states where most of
the hemp is grown it is
an issue
is it less of an issue in indoor
cultivation facilities
so that's what i'm trying to figure out
because one of the growers that that is
who is pretty convinced that it um it's
sea transmitted he thinks that he got it
in seeds uh not um clones
but i don't know if um a leaf hopper
came in and infected the plant or if the
bctv came in via the seeds you know it's
not 100 but even in our greenhouse
they're not hundred percent um you know
insect proof sure um they are pretty
they're bigger than something small like
mites or trips but um
i
definitely um be given that they like
like i mentioned you know this buffet of
um or a variety of plants they're more
likely to be an outdoor issue
and you mentioned i think it was when
you were talking about tomatoes that
there are some tools to sort of be
limiting the leaf hoppers um from
you know munching on the the crops so
what are some of the options for
preventing uh the curly top virus or
these leaf hoppers from infecting your
bro
so i'm so glad you asked that and in you
know um
given that like given that this virus is
only transmitted via via the hoppers
it's important for entomologists and
plant pathologists to work together
right but um and and this this is what's
helped the industry at least for
tomatoes um there are varieties and and
for sugar beets too there are varieties
that are resistant to the virus
um
they say it's between
low to moderate levels of resistance not
not extremely high
in
and tomatoes um they also use um
insecticidal sprays
yeah uh that you know but none of that
is an option for hemp growers in fact
and and that
that's okay but you know like i said it
only takes a few minutes two hours to
transmit the virus so timing is
important you know how are the growers
gonna know when the leaf hoppers are
coming in you know that's it's tricky so
what's worked for the sugar beet growers
because it's a huge problem in sugar
beets is uh systemic insecticides that
that's in the plant so you actually
in fact here in colorado and
our region
sugar beet growers have to buy
seeds sugar beet seeds that are coated
with a with the systemic insecticide so
when the plant
uh germinates the the
insecticide is in the plant
so that gives them the protection for
around
roughly around 50 to 55 days when the
first wave of the leaf hoppers are
coming in from the south and that
protects them but
none of that is an option for hemp
growers right in fact
that's where the issue is and my
collaborators from california the ones
that sent us that tissue we just
submitted a proposal trying to come up
with um management tactics for um hemp
growers
wow
and i wonder if we could talk a bit more
about sort of
once the plant is infected sort of
what's the timeline in terms of you know
how the disease progresses and does it
eventually kill the plant and just
totally wipe it out or is it more like a
hot blatant viroid situation where it's
just the yield and quality is greatly
reduced
you know that's such a good question so
like i mentioned our whole culture we've
got um cultures of beet leaf hoppers um
in the lab and we maintain them on sugar
beets and sugar beets just die in a
matter of um
a week to ten days because it's a
preferred host they just go you know i
wish you could come see our colony we
cannot keep up with
the pressure and how fast because of
course we're using a susceptible uh you
know line of sugar beets
now with hemp it's not that drastic
and i've gone to visit fields over weeks
and you can see the plant it still looks
pretty bad but not
dead yet and and that's one thing i tell
my growers you see an infected plant or
you suspect one that's looking infected
get rid of it so it doesn't serve as a
as a source so hemp lasts longer in fact
you know we're doing this um screening
right now
and um in several weeks months and the
plants look look
look diseased but not dead yet
eventually i i am sure they will
what we need to figure out and help and
its top priority for my lab is to see
how the virus affects cannabinoids and
the quality
yes
cbd but in particular
that needs to be done i um growers tell
me that the yield is reduced and the
flower quality is uh is poor
but we haven't had any actual evidence
of that
okay and and so i i heard you say there
so is the is the recommendation too if
you id if you identify an infected plant
just just pull it immediately
yes
definitely and then after my students
work we can tell the growers that two uh
dandelion and um
russian thistle
are top v you know there are some
specific weeds that they need to in fact
any weeds just get a surrounding hemp
you need to just get rid of it
yeah
yeah yeah i was going to ask about that
because you mentioned that you know
the leaf hoppers they don't prefer
hemp but you know they'll they'll take a
bite if they're kind of buffeting on
some other um
some other plants in the area so yeah i
was going to ask if it makes sense to
kind of make sure that there's a an air
that you clear the area around your grow
to kind of prevent that
totally yes definitely yeah
that's a that's a great idea too and
then another thing we do and you can see
in the in my background i don't know if
you can see very closely you know
growers use mulches plastic mulch is
right for
mainly for weed control
but there are some mulches research has
been done with aphids and other insects
there are some reflective mulches that
um you know
reflect light off and that prevents the
insects from landing on the plants so
we're trying to test that to see if
maybe growers could just switch it use a
different kind of mulch
uh that could then um
you know act as
weed control and also confer um other
benefits like reduce the pest landing
especially
leaf hoppers so some small easy things
that they can do
um to reduce
uh you know
infection
yeah
you know and i know that there are some
folks who with other viruses
are attempting tissue culture as a way
to
um
produce a new virus free variety has
that been attempted with anything that's
been affected with the curly top virus
is that not an option
so um we do have a tissue culture lab
here at csu and and we're trying and
i've given her you know our primer some
of our leaf tissue and rna samples
to develop
some diagnostic tools so then she can
test uh these tissue cultured plants but
i think it's very much in um you know
early stages not anything ready for
commercial um
you know
not commercially available but pretty
much once a month like just last couple
of days ago i got an email from
a diagnostic company one you know
wanting samples
um
from our study to develop diagnostic
tools but the issue is not all states
are allowed you know can work even on
hemp for that matter never mind
marijuana
yeah that is definitely um a challenge
that we need to navigate as we yes as we
explore these plants
so
i was wondering
i know that you identified other viruses
and viroids um in some of these samples
in your paper um
anything interesting there that you know
growers should be aware of or that maybe
you and your team are going to be uh
investigating the in the years to come
here
that's a great question you know my
department head uh
dr amy charkowski she told me one you
know when i was telling her about all
the viruses we found he's like you have
your carrier here you can just keep
studying this right and that's
and that'll that'll do it uh so yes of
course hot plate and viroid and um
there's a grower coming being bringing
me some
samples some plants infected so we can
figure this out and and actually there's
one report of
hop aphid transmitting hopleton viroid
so i want to look into aphid
transmission the other one that i i
think was particularly interesting in
our virum analysis is was a tobacco
streak virus
um
the reason it's interesting is because
it it has a worldwide distribution it
goes to it in fact several species and
trips transmitted and you know any any
grower in doing any kind of um you know
agriculture is where are familiar with
trips
highly ubiquitous several species of
trips transmitted and what's interesting
is our
sequences indicate that it's a new
genotype of virus or a new
isolate of this tobacco strict virus in
hemp
interesting so you know so
that makes it all the more
challenging
um
and tobacco stick wise goes to peppers
and all these other crops that we grow
here in colorado and definitely in other
places so i think that's that's an
interesting one but then you know you
think about cannabis cryptic virus and
this uh cannabis that have a mito virus
all of them i i have no clue what they
do and um
yeah
yeah go ahead we touched on it before
but were you surprised not to find
tobacco mosaic virus i was surprised not
to find but i i believe um
again talking to my uh colleague in uh
canada they have found tobacco mosaic
virus we did not yes he they did
um what was that the one i was going to
say oh and the other uh paper that we
just published last week
was
showing cannabis aphid it's a newly
identified aphid it's original to asia
we only discovered it in colorado
in 2015 a couple of years ago and now
it's one of the most prolific aphids in
um this potato growing region here in
colorado and
happens to transmit very efficiently
potato virus y which is the number one
virus that affects potato
uh crops so but we did not find potato
virus buy in our hemp samples
okay
it's possible
right yeah i think everything's on the
table huh yes hemp is just you know
changed the whole um patho system
no and i wasn't aware that folks had
identified tobacco mosaic virus in
cannabis and or hemp yet i know we have
a lot of customers asking us about it we
haven't been able to find it in the
literature so if you do have some
information we'd be definitely
interested in that
i can definitely put you in touch i'm
pretty sure uh he mentioned this
but it's no it's not published okay okay
yeah so um but i could put you in touch
with dr zamir punjah he's super oh yeah
oh i didn't realize it was doctor punjab
yeah
yes he's he's been a guest on the
podcast before has he now yeah so reach
out to him unless i'm mistaken but
you're right so that's prolific it is uh
yeah it's interesting that we haven't
found it yeah especially i mean again we
have a lot of customers who are
interested in it so i've done i've done
some research and you know interesting
to find out that it was the first virus
ever identified
and that it's you know it sounds like
it's very robust and can
um
you know can still be viable long after
it's it's been on you know other
surfaces so
uh tmv i i've even heard that it can be
on cigarette
uh exactly
yeah we had a customer mention that like
oh i don't let anyone who smokes go
anywhere near our plants and we were
kind of
thinking he was just paranoid but then
you read more about it and like no that
seems pretty prudent actually yes yes
yeah
so
winding down here um again i think you
mentioned some of the the things that
your team is working on and things to
come
um i won't give you an opportunity to to
share that again and if there's any
website or materials or social media or
anything people can connect with you and
stay up to date with the
with the work that you guys are doing
please plug away
oh that's great thank you so like i
mentioned we just um published this
paper on cannabis aphid um
being a vector for pvy what we're doing
now and this is funded by usda which is
so great that you know the usda has
removed these um
restrictions
against the crop which allows
researchers to get funded so i have um
good funding for um to work on pests and
the the big one we're focusing on is
hemperos it might it's almost a virus
it's microscopic so that's a huge one
that we're focusing on uh another usda
grant is looking at a more systematic
survey of
the virum across
different
growth plant phenology or growth stages
different cultivars to see you know if
there is some natural resistance
so that's one project that we're looking
on
um we're we're just our universities in
the process of updating our website so
we're but we were coming up with the
hemp disease website to have uh you know
um all of this information um updated
there but of course i would love to
connect with people on twitter i'm on
twitter uh just my name
nacho papuni i believe is the handle so
uh
yes
there will definitely be more things
coming and another thing lastly i want
to talk about um
sort of the
adaptive role of cannabinoids you know
there's research coming out about how
cbd has in some cases a negative impact
some cases a positive impact so we're
looking into that um
on insects with different mouth parts
like an aphid with a piercing mouth part
hemp preset mite that has more like a
little stub and a chewing mouth part
like corn urban or eurasian hemp porter
so we're trying to see how it affects
different insects that feed differently
so that's very exciting too
yeah that is exciting and you touched on
something we
probably should have talked about it is
uh resistance right i mean let's say
that you know pesticides and some of
these options aren't available to hemp
growers um identifying natural
resistance and breeding for that would
would definitely
be an option yes and growers you know um
of course we're working with new west
genetics and that's that's really great
when growers as you probably know they
are doing their own little breeding and
uh
you know developing their own varieties
and they swear
how one is more resistant than or
tolerant to another so i think that is
going to be key for hemp
given how limited the insecticide
options are
yeah absolutely
all right punya thank you again for for
joining us on the podcast um very
interested in learning more about your
work and everything i think um it's
going to be very important for for the
industry going forward oh thank you so
much ben any time when when i have more
more
or newer data yeah i'll i'll reach out
to you to come share it yeah thank you
this is so great to get the word out
there
absolutely thanks again
bye
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr punya nachapa
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor eugentec
our next episode drops march 30th that's
two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out the
canmed archive and join the canmed
community facebook group to stay
connected with us
of course you can also stay in touch
with us on social media on facebook
instagram linkedin and twitter just
search for kim at events
sign up for email alerts on cam at
events.com to stay up to date with all
the latest news and please be sure to
rate review and subscribe on your
favorite podcast app doing so helps us
reach more listeners
i do sincerely hope to see all of you
out in pasadena this spring but until
then stay safe stay healthy and please
join us for the next canbed coffee talk
do
[Music]
you