thank you and uh thanks for sticking
around for the last panel of the day of
course we're gonna be talking about
cannabinoid hyper and Mesa syndrome
today this is something that has come up
in the media quite a bit they say there
are no deaths from cannabis but
ultimately this is one of those things
where sometimes the complication
complications of cannabis use can result
in death and it is a really sad thing
that we see out there it doesn't happen
with very many faults but it is
something that is continuously coming up
and so we have some esteemed panelists
here with us today of course dr. door
who just gave his talk and Alice food
and Tom Poland I will do a bad job of
introducing these folks properly so I'm
gonna let them give them their own
introductions doctor or if you'd like to
start my current family physician and
for the last six years I was the senior
medical director of the cannabis program
of the Israeli faith good evening
everyone thanks for sticking with us
it's pretty late so we'll try and make
this short and painless for you and not
induce a mises my name is Tom fallen I'm
a board certified diagnostic radiologist
who has established a canvas canvas
medicine practice with a focus in
glioblastoma patients and I'm happy to
be here to talk to you about canvas
hyperemesis hi everyone I am alice moon
and I've been in the cannabis industry
for eight years and we are here right
now because I have cannabinoid
hyperemesis syndrome which means
basically cannabis makes me violently
ill so CH s is a condition to be
believed to be a side effect of frequent
and long term cannabis use and the side
effects include nausea vomiting and
abdominal pain so today I'm going to
tell you guys my story and hopefully
it'll inspire you guys to help me find a
cure for this
so I have been in the industry for eight
years and I when I was working at a
dispensary in 2015 I was writing product
reviews so I would consume edibles and
write about it so I was having about 10
milligrams of edibles a day and then in
2016 I started throwing up and at first
it was pretty random every few months I
would just puke and couldn't figure out
why I felt normal
and doctors couldn't figure out why
either they said I had acid reflux so I
changed my diet kept getting worse then
I stopped drinking alcohol even though I
wasn't drinking a good amount I thought
maybe that has something to do with it
and I didn't have alcohol for two years
and during that time I was getting worse
and worse to the point where in 2018 I
was starting to throw up almost every
day I saw a specialist who said it's
cannabis and I didn't want to believe it
I'm sure most of you don't want to
believe it because we know that cannabis
helps with not sure so how could
something that helps us with so much
also do damage so I said okay I'll take
a cannabis break but first I'm gonna
have my last hurrah so I went to a
five-course infused dinner and that
triggered my first episode of 14 days of
non-stop throwing up all day every day
now at this time I knew nothing about
CHS and I felt like I was dying I just
wanted it to end I didn't know what was
happening it was just throwing up over
and over and over and over even a sip of
water I was throwing it up now the
interesting thing with this syndrome is
the one thing that stops the throwing up
is hot baths or capsaicin cream on your
stomach now that's a cayenne pepper
based cream so I first tried this cream
not knowing what it was put it all over
my stomach and then my skin was on fire
so I was in excruciating pain but I
wasn't throwing up so it was like okay
what do I want to I want to have my skin
on fire don't be puking ultimately I
chose the puking because it was too much
and so then I was in the bathtub and
trying out the bathtub route and that
helped a lot but it dehydrated me as
well and the second I would get out of
the tub I was throwing up so I slept in
my bathroom on my bathroom floor for
many of nights my roommate will come
home and check to make sure I was even
alive I passed out in my front yard one
day because I was throwing up so much
that I couldn't hug the toilet and a
neighbor stopped by and said can I help
you and I just broke down and cried and
said I wish you could I wish somebody
could help me I don't know how anyone
can and you know I I felt like I was
dying everyone around me was extremely
scared I lost 15 pounds and so then I
quit using cannabis for three months now
people were saying they thought that
this was pesticides so after taking a
three-month break I said okay let me use
pesticide free cannabis try that and it
came back that time it only lasted four
days so not as terrible but still not
very pleasant then after that people
were saying CBD try CBD I'm sure CVD
will work for you right like it has the
opposite effect it'll it'll totally work
okay
I tried CBD and that ended up triggering
my worst episode yet it was on December
22nd so I didn't get to enjoy Christmas
or New Year's I threw up all day every
day for 16 days I had to urgent care
visits one at home nurse visit and
ultimately was in the hospital and was
in there for four days and you know my
ER doctor didn't even know the
difference between THC and CBD isn't
that [ __ ] ridiculous like excuse my
language but that is absolutely
ridiculous that an ER doctor wouldn't
know the difference so they can't even
you know know that cannabinoid
hyperemesis is real and in that process
I got two ulcers a hernia and a
bacterial infection now I'm proud to say
that I've gained 30 pounds since my
hospitalization and I think that really
speaks volumes to how much weight I lost
in the beginning of the year it was
extremely
Carrie and I was near death and I don't
want anyone else to go through what I
went through and what's pretty crazy is
I was looking to see you when was the
last time I had THC when was that last
episode and I realized that September
24th of last year was actually the last
time I had THC so I I think it's pretty
serendipitous that right now is my one
year anniversary of no THC now I want to
be clear that I was like one of you
before
cannabis is my life I love Mead so so
much it is my whole entire world I'm a
publicist in the cannabis industry
before I got sick I was going to three
to five events a week it's my life and
now I can't even be around secondhand
smoke so now I am determined to find a
cure for this
no one's researching it and I I want us
to figure it out so no one else has to
get this sick and so I can smoke weed
again
[Applause]
Thank You Alice also for sharing that
story it really kind of create a gift
some color to what we're dealing with
out there in terms of this condition I
do want to mention that there is not a
lot known about this condition currently
so I will advise that not all the
panelists have every single answer but
we're gonna do our best to tackle it
today with this discussion so I guess
I'll start with first question I have
for the panelists and that is so the
first cases of this started to emerge in
around 2004 and it's taken a while for
the medical community to actually
acknowledge and recognize this condition
in the first place so I'm hoping to get
some insights for our panelists as far
as why you think that is why is that the
medical community has taken so long to
actually recognize this condition I'm
sure so thanks again to Alice for
sharing her story it takes a lot of
courage to come to a conference like
this where basically people are
celebrating a certain thing and you've
had this terrible experience with it and
just you know to kind of confirm what
she's saying
I remember as a first-year resident in
Chicago
was the first time I ever heard of this
I had graduated medical school aunt
Alice's point had never even heard of
such a thing and I remember at Cook
County in Chicago where we doing my
training the ER doctors were you know
ordered to CT scan there like that's
gonna be negative we see this kid every
few months he smokes cannabis they CT
scans never show anything and of course
the tax payer is picking up that bill
he's picking up all that radiation for
something that we now know to kind of
screen for and look for in patients
coming in who endorse a history of
chronic cannabis use with this nausea
and vomiting so - Kyle's question the
first cases showing up in 2004 that's
correct
that was from Allen at Al in Australia
in a case of nine patients who endorsed
a history very similar to what Alice has
talked to us about and upon cessation of
cannabis I believe seven of those
patients had complete recovery and so
this was the first time this began
percolating the surface of the medical
consciousness does that mean that we
haven't had cases of CHS or so-called
CHS at least prior to 2004 no it does
not but of course in radiology we have a
very famous saying which says the eye
does not see what the mind does not know
so if you are you could be looking at
patients all day long who are throwing
up if you don't know that there's an
entity called cannabis hyperemesis
syndrome which involves trpv1 receptors
that we'll get into in cb1 receptors
you're not going to even know they took
me on your radar and another point we'll
get into is there's a second into the
call CBS of course is very non confusing
CBS CHS cyclical vomiting syndrome these
patients will typically have the exact
same presentation nausea vomiting
abdominal pain except that a good
percentage of them as well will also
endorse a history of migraine they tend
to be more a female than male which is
the opposite with CHS and then we don't
quite see the striking use of a hot
water bathing that we do see in CVS but
the reason I'm mentioning these are CHS
that are with CHS let's a Thank You
Ellis at the point being that there's an
awful lot of overlap and so
in fact one of the latest papers I read
from May of this year actually thinks
that CHS may be a particular subset of
CVS and so just bringing this up in the
context of this question because CVS was
known before 2004 okay so I think these
are some of the factors and then maybe a
final factor that people like to talk
about is this increase in potency we now
have concentrates and other forms of
cannabis that are you know ninety
percent THC and Beyond and that perhaps
this Bombardier receptors over time at
this level could potentially account for
the increase in prevalence of these
cases and also people are now admitting
to their doctors that they're using
cannabis um you know a lot of people are
afraid to talk about it so doctors
wouldn't even know like if someone's not
you know they just don't know so now
that states are legalizing and cannabis
is a hot topic and a lot of emergency
room doctors in like Colorado they know
about this now they're documenting yet
and there's been cases of this all over
the world I have talked to thousands of
people with ths all over the world
people have it it's just no one's
keeping track of it and no one's really
putting forward the effort to talk about
it I think the same as my colleagues I
tried since the morning to check the
numbers and I was you know number which
was a surprise to me with almost between
200 to 300 cases they take I mean all
the hospitals together in Israel but let
me refer to something because I would
like to see things in larger scale this
is only one of the syndromes connected
to cannabis
they are underreported we don't have a
good report system or about side effects
then when we don't have the system we
cannot publish results and the physician
does not know about it in a magazine or
so I really the beginning should be
teaching teaching physicians at the
incision again
and just to build upon dr. Dores points
it's a great point how we gathered the
data and how we're characterizing things
is very important so when we say
someone's a heavy user what does that
mean is that four times a week is that
twice a week these things matter and so
another point that I'll raise is that
the current Bible of Gastroenterology is
known as the rome 4 so in you know
psychiatry we have the dsm-5 which is
the Bible and that contains cannabis use
disorder the rome 4 contains CH s
cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome but
even that has an imperfect tool for use
and this paper that I just read from May
of this year suggests improvement upon
this so that when a patient has stopped
using cannabis for a period of six
months and has had complete cessation of
these symptoms they're proposing that we
use that six month period because their
own for didn't give any time period so a
patient could stop for a month and you
know not have any symptoms and then go
back on cannabis and then if symptoms
again so the point is that even with
this entity how we're diagnosing is and
who we're going to include is is
evolving all the time and it's as well
it should be because the major points
that if you've been off for a month that
actually isn't long enough to be able to
tell if you're going to have another
cycle so the proposal is that even the
room for criteria aren't good enough
that we need to be iterating on that and
editing as we go along
dr. Georges said since this morning when
he just did a few simple phone calls he
discovered that there's 300 people in
Israel that they have documented I am at
the end of this presentation we are
going to be going over and I have talked
to 200 people well I've talked to
thousands of people but I have
statistics from 200 people and we will
be going over the data that I have
collected and so this just shows how
widespread this really is and it's a lot
bigger of a deal than we're currently
acknowledging it to be so we spoke a lot
here about basically what are the issues
in terms of how people are identifying
this so because there seems to be this
kind of confusion among practitioners
is how to actually make this diagnosis
what would you say would be the best
approach to actually make a confirmed
diagnosis of CHS sure so I kind of spoke
about it in my prior answer but I'll go
to it again a modified version of the
Rome 4 is the best criteria we would
currently have so that requires that you
have a history of using cannabis for at
least one year that what they're
defining heavy user frequent use is
greater than four times per week there
they didn't give a defined time period
for cessation of cannabis and resolution
of symptoms so what then castithan I
believe the papers from from May of this
year is proposing is that you wait for a
period of six months after a cessation
of use or three cycles of hyperemesis so
if that patient would on average go into
a hyper Ematic phase every five weeks
then at fifteen weeks after cessation of
use you could now apply that diagnosis
retrospectively and the reason this is
very important if we want to get the
point out that someone shouldn't be
walking into the emergency room saying I
use cannabis and I'm throwing up and I
get relief from showers and then having
that label applied to them because what
they're finding is that a good
percentage of patients who have CVS the
cyclical vomiting syndrome and
psychogenic vomiting and other forms of
nausea and vomiting also find relief
from hot bathing not at the high
percentages that we're seeing being
reported in association with CHS but
certainly it is there so again I want to
harp on that six month and or three
cycles of hyperemesis that from the time
you've stopped and that brings us to our
next caveat CVS patients and CHS
patients up until they develop these
symptoms are RC CVS patients use
cannabis actually to treat their
cyclical vomiting and so they don't want
to stop and so trying to tell these
people to stop for a period of six
months what ends up happening is they
don't stop and maybe they don't tell
their doctor about it because they don't
want the doctor to get angry at them and
so this paper then goes on to talk about
how if the patient doesn't stop
and has used for greater than a year and
has used greater than four times a week
that a tentative diagnosis of CHS can be
applied in that case but again I will
point out that this paper was very much
in one case series where they looked at
when they applied Rome for criteria
retrospectively they found that a good
percentage of patients who had been
labeled with CHS in the emergency room
no longer fit the criteria for that
diagnosis one more consultation I did
today who was I as Professor Michelin
that is our guru and his his give such a
patient not THC I said I wouldn't
cannabis and it's just he is he knows so
much but this is something that people
don't know about it no people don't know
about this we're gonna we need to have a
chat with him I know he's not gonna
plane to it is real but we're gonna have
to have a channel for sure but yeah the
next question that you're gonna go over
was the treatment once we go get this
yeah so I mean we've made a diagnosis
now so what are the first lines of
treatment that you would actually
propose to give to someone who has been
formally diagnosed with CHS so capsaicin
cream on the stomach that helps that
relieve the symptoms
well that relieves symptoms for a lot of
people and then the antipsychotic
medicine algal that has had a high
success rate of stopping the nausea and
vomiting but the side effects of it are
so severe that the people I've spoken
with have all said they would rather be
vomiting because it's an anti-psychotic
it has caused a lot of anxiety
hallucinations and people don't
understand what's going on with them
because most of the time doctors aren't
explaining the medicine that they're
giving to them and so all of a sudden
someone's going through like this
feeling of psychosis in the emergency
room and they don't know why
so really the only thing is like for
people to stop using cannabis but an IV
and capsaicin and that would be yeah so
Alice brings up a great point with
capsaicin in fact some people you figure
this could kind of be diagnostic so you
come into the emergency room you endorse
a history of cyclical vomiting and using
cannabis and they rub a little on your
chest and abdomen if you start to get
better they shouldn't apply the
diagnosis right then and there but it's
kind of a presumptive a little bit
because as we're going to talk about
probably a little bit the receptor where
we were initially focused on was cb1 as
things have evolved and we've learned
more about this need for nosey cept of
heat above 41 to 43 degrees centigrade
and our the use of capsaicin we focused
on the so called capsaicin receptor
trpv1 and so that's why that can be
helpful but in some patients it's not
that's why I was mentioned why would we
give an antipsychotic such as
haloperidol common name is Haldol
because guess what our ondansetron
are a five ht3 drug that works in our
our chemotherapy patients famously does
not work in this case a Reglan our
metoclopramide which is another
medication that we will use for various
patients with nausea and vomiting
also doesn't work universally now in an
emergency room you know your average IDI
physician are going to try and go to
these things before they go to
haloperidol typically because
haloperidol can cause tardive dyskinesia
that famous lip-smacking and other
things that dr. Michelle I'm talk about
yesterday in his talk on schizophrenia
where he was saying hey we could use CBD
in many of these patients and avoid
these nasty side-effects and of course
the other issue being that some patients
develop this tardive dyskinesia from the
very first administration so you know ER
doctors don't take it lightly to
administer this but the other thing that
I will mention is that haloperidol works
so well that when it stops the nausea
and vomiting in this case as well that's
another sign that that's potentially
what we're looking at but again bear in
mind that six months three cycles before
you're applying that label which will
now stay with that patient for life
and of course I sorry I should all toast
famous to say biggest things Basics in
medicine get fluid into these patients
they are throwing up so the initial
treatment in the emergency room is IV
fluids
sometimes benzodiazepines to sedate the
patient to take them away from this
hellish experience they're having
getting fluids into them stopping the
emesis by any of the methods that we can
I've mentioned 5h t3 I've mentioned
dopamine antagonists haloperidol
so emesis is a very complex mechanism
and we will try any in all of our drugs
to shut it down and percent prevent
patients from going into acute renal
failure which has happened and acute
renal failure kills you again and so
just so you know there happens at CHS
but we can get towards that towards the
end you mentioned that been in the
morning and I wonder they dish in from
CHS must be because of the iteration and
I find it hard to believe in the 21st so
that not know to treat the iteration
unless those patient didn't come to the
hospital heard the problem dr. door and
this was a you know Alex parents and who
I'm sure is known and loved to all of us
in this room recently our last week was
publishing a case Mindy Anna where a
young guy had died with this presumptive
diagnosis EHS but it gets to a point I
talked about earlier when people had
associated cannabis with anti emesis you
coming along and telling them that this
very thing they were using is called he
didn't believe it his own mother was
there crying he kept on using and he
didn't believe it he tried stopping but
he went back to it
so I you know I don't want to blame
patients here but we're all humans and
it's human nature so that's why it's
important that we're having these
discussions and raising this awareness
and absolutely in the 21st century to
think that someone dies from dehydration
but unfortunately this is what happens
and some you know some people are afraid
to even go to the hospital and some
people can't afford to even go to the
hospital mean my urgent care visits were
expensive and
I have insurance you know is it this
syndrome has cost me a lot of money I'm
going to change the system so I do want
to ask about so treatment right so we
talked about different drugs that can be
used to treat it but we're also hoping
to understand what can we use otherwise
less supplements things like that what
what other activities can we use to
mitigate the symptoms of si-jess and
then also are there any types of
triggers that you've noticed of course
we know a cannabis is a trigger and not
just looking at the THC as Alice
mentioned she also had an episode with
CBD and there may be other cannabinoids
duplicated as well but specifically what
kind of triggers alcohol out there then
also what other types of strategies have
you been using to mitigate aside from
the drug that Tom had mentioned well one
interesting thing is running helps a lot
of people stop throwing up and there's
one reported case of somebody getting
rhabdomyolysis from running for 15 hours
straight 15 hours but he wasn't throwing
up and so I thought that was pretty
alarming so you know I reached out to my
network of people with CHS and we'll go
over the stats later but 20 people out
of the 200 found relief from running so
that is another thing that people have
found relief from some people are taking
vitamins I personally I don't have any
like I just I don't use campus at all so
that's kind of how I try to deal with it
and yeah just to build on what Alice to
say in case any of you were wondering
well how could running how does running
tie in to this this all gets back to the
TR PV receptor and what they think is
going on here is a cute aeneas steal
syndrome where basically you're having
dysfunction with cb1 receptors at the
level of the bowel and when you
put yourself under a hot shower and get
that 4143 degree temperature hitting the
TRP verse receptors which have been
desensitized they now open up and allow
you to feel the anti emesis or a normal
level of just functioning but
interestingly when they patients run
you're doing the same thing our I should
have said there is when the when you're
in the shower all of your blood is
flowing to your skin to release heat so
it's pulled away from the bottle they
think that the mechanism underlying the
running is that when these patients are
running all of their blood is now going
to their muscles and not to the bowel
so this cutaneous steal our enteric
steal syndrome and again this is all
hypothesis but this is the current best
understanding of why this occurs and as
far as triggers well there's a quite a
few foods that people can't eat if they
have CHS now not everyone thankfully
these foods don't affect me but black
pepper coffee and chocolate they have
naturally-occurring
cannabinoids in them and it can trigger
someone to have an episode of CHS some
people literally cannot touch black
pepper at all now imagine trying to go
out to eat at a restaurant and it's
trying to ensure that your food doesn't
have black pepper that's not easy yeah I
think those are the few the most popular
foods that are the triggers for it thank
you even there's no and of course that
makes sense with beta Coughlin's having
cannabinoid activity in black pepper and
as I was pointed out that cannabinoids
and cannabinoid like substances in
chocolate so Alice has mentioned you had
mentioned that basically if some of
these episodes were up to 16 days from
you and so even after sustaining any
type of cannabis smoke or an ingestion
those symptoms still continue to persist
so I'm wondering why is it that it takes
so long for these symptoms to clear up
do you guys have any insights as to why
that might be I think you can say it
better than I can I know it's THD just
you know it stays in your system it's
great life so the same reason that you
can get pulled over by a cop after not
having smoked for three and a half weeks
and now you have to submit to EU tox and
now it turns out positive is the exact
same reason that they
hypothesize this occurs for many months
are sometimes after cessation and why
they want you to go to that full six
month period or three cycles before
applying this diagnosis the lip
lipophilic nature of cannabinoids and
cannabinoid metabolites and that these
are being leached into the system at a
quantity sufficient to continue to cause
illness in these patients all right so
this is actually a question that I'm
very curious to hear panelists insights
about some folks on the internet seem to
be convinced that CHS is caused by the
use of pesticides on cannabis
specifically if identified neem oil as a
potential causal agent of CHS so do you
won't agree with this idea and if so why
are why not
hell no neem oil does not cause
cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome now I
know we're not supposed to say anything
with confidence because this is still
you know as we're researching it but
I've talked to people who have grown
their own cannabis and they have DHS I
tried pesticide free weed I have DHS I
it's not that the symptoms are simpler
but they're not the same pesticide
poisoning does you know it can cause
nausea but pesticide poisoning can also
cause seizures and issues with vision
it's not it's not pesticide poisoning I
I got it see you know I had an episode
from hemp drive CBD that I know was
grown without pesticides circular yeah
it's not in itself a family physician
and I like things to be seen through and
you say kiss I don't care I don't care
what is the exact reason I will treat
the patient the same intravenously and
some things against him and nausea and
at that point is emergency well as a
family or as a primary care physician I
don't care what was the exact reason in
the receptors the same the treatment
will be the same
yeah I would just add that we actually
also have cases of of CHS occurring in
patients using synthetic cannabinoids so
if anyone in the room who may not be
familiar one of the reasons patients may
choose to use synthetic cannabinoids
they may have jobs which require them to
get urine tested 50 percent of all jobs
in the United States require
pre-employment urine screening which is
ridiculous it's an entire industry but
suffice it to say that we have seen CHS
in those patients using these agonist at
cb1 receptors that may be even more
potent than THC and we have cases going
back to 2013 2014 from England and
elsewhere around the world and also to
Alice's point I know many cases here not
many cases but quite a few where people
were growers themselves and didn't use
neem oil and still developed this
syndrome and then finally Alice's point
dr. Ethan Russo as well has spoken about
this and how he really doesn't think
it's the neem oil because as Alice
pointed out they're not identical this
is not how many moil poisoning exists
are presents and when we have seen it it
doesn't persist for this period and
again we have seen this both in cases
where neem oil has not been used on the
cannabis and in synthetic cannabinoids
so moving towards how we get answers and
start to pick apart this a bit more what
approach that's been suggested to try
and further investigate this is to
sequence patient populations with CHS so
are there any different targets that you
think researchers might be interested in
sequencing to help tease apart what
genetic underpinnings might be present
in this condition I'll take that we've
discussed these beforehand so I
apologize for hogging the mic but two
things we know in CVS patients not CHS
patients we have found a gene the ry r2
gene and given that I just mentioned at
the outset of the talk that we think
potentially CHS may be a subset of CVS
we will certainly want to look at that
and see if that's a commonality amongst
these individuals who are reporting this
entity and also
cytochrome p450 enzymes that break down
THC and its metabolites are they somehow
different in this group are they slower
metabolizers perhaps these are all
targets that we would certainly want to
evaluate so moving to some of the
symptoms and what we see out there what
we're noticing is that hormonal
fluctuations in women seem to also worse
in the symptoms of their CHS do we have
any insights as to what is going on here
why this is the case
letting the doctor take this one again
dr. dork you want to just know what's
happening
we know that when women are getting
their menstrual cycle is when they're
having the most severe symptoms this is
a reoccurring pattern when I had my
worst case of CHS it was during my
menstrual cycle and so do you know that
we talked about again it's going to be
along the hypothesis thing where we do
know there's involvement of the HPA the
hypothalamic pituitary access the
hypothalamus is involved in thermal
regulation we think that's gonna skew
it's to do with the fact that even every
month woman's migraines their
fibromyalgia all of these things may be
worse in the para menstrual period
relating to the effect of estrogen
progesterone fluctuations we're again
hypothesizing that this is having some
effect on our homeostatic system our
endocannabinoid system but again this is
all just hypothesis at this point and as
Dustin Sulak had just mentioned in a
prior case you know we don't have great
data yet on cannabinoids and the sex
differences but it is certainly an area
ripe for exploration and investigation
and speaking of data Alice has been very
active in the community on social media
and she actually runs a couple of
different groups to support CHS patients
and people who are going through the
condition and she's actually collected
she's done a patient surveys so she's
actually gotten response from now 200
patients with CHS all through Facebook
maybe a couple other sources and not
sure if it was Jo about it so again our
social media business or
heavy metals talk it's a really useful
tool and so we're going to go through
some of those in just a minute or so
else I will let you think really slides
here so that should take you okay so yes
that is yeah I think elective data from
two hundred people now a lot of these
people they find me because I'm doing
interviews a lot I have spoken with
Business Insider Leafly Rolling Stone
and no small a few smaller publications
as well and so these people they find me
they hear about my story and then I
recommend these Facebook groups and
there's people who run other Facebook
groups as well it's not just me doing it
I can't handle all the emotional labor
to be honest so there are other people
that are helping do this and so out of
the thousands of people in these groups
I've collected data from 200 of them and
so so 75 people were using cannabis for
eight years before the symptoms began so
that is a high amount of people but as
you can see from that it kind of varies
of how long people were using we're
gonna move okay musical chair so I can
see better perfect and one thing I want
to point out with this data is there's
no consistency with anything it's all
over the place so out of how much people
consumed 55 percent used it multiple
times a day
27% used it actually all day long and
then some people used it daily and small
amount used it once a day and the age of
consumers buried with 50 patients aged
21 to 25 and then there is a variety of
other ages but the 21 to 25 was the
majority of the 200 people then location
where are all these people that I'm
talking to California had the highest
amount of people 15% next
was Canada 13% the New York Florida
Washington in Australia and then there's
a small cases reported throughout all
the states and then in Italy and the
United Kingdom as well and I think that
we are seeing these stats because these
are where this is where people are
figuring out that they have it these are
states that are legalizing and so people
are figuring it out versus the illegal
states that it's just it's not talked
about and people aren't using high
potency THC they're not using as often
due to lack of being able to get it so
then the methods of using cannabis the
highest amount of people we're using a
bomb
people are smoke out of her blah abang
joints blunts in a pipe smaller amount
we're using edibles 65 people out of the
200 we're using vape pens and 61 we're
using dabs so it's kind of all over the
place of how people were using before
they got CHS next up the symptoms as you
can see almost everyone out of the 200
had nausea and then following that is
the rest of the symptoms that were
occurring vomiting abdominal pain some
body pain diarrhea dehydration the list
goes on of awful things that people
experience with this syndrome what
provided relief hot baths and the hot
showers worked for 157 157 people
capsaicin cream 443 IV was very helpful
heating pads and ultimately sleep some
people were able to sleep through this
and try to get relief that way the
length of symptoms after stopping
cannabis use 22% went more than a month
of still experiencing symptoms before
they got better so imagine you stopped
using the one thing that you think helps
you with all of your nausea and all of
your pain and you stop using it and
you're not getting better
after a month you're gonna think it's
not cannabis so people will end up going
back to using it again so next
when asked if running provided relief
10% 20 out of the 200 of find relief
from running and then this is something
we hadn't talked about yet gall bladders
being unnecessarily removed since
doctors don't know about this their miss
diagnosing people and people are having
organs removed 16 people out of 200 had
their gallbladders removed and didn't
get better and then ultimately
discovered that this was cannabis making
them sick 16 people and then another 16
people their doctor suggested that they
have their gallbladder removed and this
is out of just 200 people that have
spoken to imagine how many people have
had surgery that they didn't even need
pre-existing conditions and this is
something that I find very interesting
is 48.5% of the people who have CH s had
anxiety and you know some of them were
using cannabis for anxiety and
depression as well so a lot of people
did have pre-existing conditions and I
think this might have something to do
with with this that our genes are I
don't know it's but the gun is the
second brain right there is more
serotonin in the gut job there is the
brain so that I could certainly play
into this is of course we know serotonin
is very implicated in anxiety
continue these people might be on
medicine as well and we don't know how
medicine reacts with THC I mean there's
not enough research at all so medicine
and the interaction could also play a
part in this we don't know
so in summary more research needs to be
done and that's that's that's it more
research needs to be done and that's the
point of having this discussion is so we
can bring more awareness to this topic
so that people do start to investigate
this a bit further I want to give a
thanks to our panelists for their
participation today
sorry there are knowledge with us and
now I'd like to open the floor to any
questions you might have for myself for
the panelist so where are we on the
sequencing of receptors in this family
such as trip a1 trip v1 c b1 c b2 etc
are we seeing potential polymorphisms
and those in this population that's
that's a great question to be quite
honest that work hasn't been done yet
and that's what we're hoping to you know
I was actually approached no later than
today to get involved in a project that
will be hopefully looking at these very
things so we're just getting around to
it now but really the trpv1 receptor and
to your point the TRPA receptor hadn't
been looked at the el puntal recently
people were thinking this was all to do
with c b1 but in the past couple of
years as the TR pv the issue has become
more prominent given the capsaicin the
showering baths the running now they're
just beginning to look at that but
certainly that's the next work to be
done so there's a whole vocabulary list
of these prep receptors right that we're
very much in vogue a decade ago they
kind of you know the field is the
neurobiology field has moved on because
it was well exploited it's the cannabis
field now that needs to come into focus
with this so as I said there's a there's
a large vocabulary in this to them and I
wouldn't necessarily just stop at a1 v1
Oh a hundred a hundred percent you know
the endocannabinoid system is
exceptionally complex and there's so
many things you could focus on but I
think these are good starting points and
certainly to look at the rest of the TRP
receptors as well and I'd also like to
point out I'm pretty sure this is the
first DHS panel to ever happen this
isn't a topic that is talked about at
all and so we are just now starting the
conversation and just did two quick
statistics I'll trade you the overall
instance in Colorado of seeing patients
present for nausea and vomiting
0.07% this is the small issues to put it
in context but it's a very important
issue particularly if you are the person
suffering from it or you know someone
suffering from it the other thing to
point out after the legalization of
cannabis in Colorado the following year
they saw an 8% increase in presentations
to the emergency room for nausea and
vomiting so again it's only 0.07 percent
of all of their visits but they did see
that uptick so you know we owe it to
ourselves to remain intellectually
curious and to ask these hard questions
since the trpv1 receptors are involved
as anybody looking into using CBD a to
stop the symptoms so no one is looking
into anything with DHS um let me just
make that clear is no one is doing
research at all Canada has allocated 250
thousand dollars towards the research of
CHS but that is not going to start until
next year no one is putting too much
focus on this because there's other
things going on in the industry and
people don't think that this is a
widespread problem so while we think it
has something to do with the trpv1
receptor we can't speak with certainty
we don't know I will add I'm aware of a
friend of mine in Canada who's looking
very closely at the TRP family of
receptors and at this thing that Alice's
point this is more nascent knowledge and
more nascent direction but but certainly
there are people already beginning to
look at this quite heavily because
mechanistically it explains what's going
on much better than the cv one
predominant theory which didn't explain
why only certain subsets of patients
develop this there are patients who will
use cannabis every day of their life and
will never develop this so what we're
really interested in finding out is who
is the cohort why is it that certain
people and with regard to CBD a as well
I think the patients after they go back
and try CBD and have this 16 day
protracted period of throwing up are so
like I'm done so any pick anymore any
pick I've tried and I almost died so
it's certainly a great question
thank you two questions actually
one about sedation you mentioned that
that helped or at least sleeping out do
you think sedation over a period of time
actually decreases the length of the
attack or I realize go ahead maybe I'm
not tryin sir completely
do you mean to put a patient because of
vomiting under full anesthesia and to
live in death for several days or weeks
well I'm not quite sure of a sedation
comment that the other doctor made will
range exactly but might presume that as
you sedate the person at some point they
stop vomiting yes that's right
now there's degrees of sedation and all
that yes true my question was more along
lines of if sleep helps and sleeping
bills or whatever does it actually or do
you think it could compress the kind of
lessen the severity of the attacks like
sixteen days might shortened or whatever
potentially I mean I think it's a great
question basically you're asking if
someone comes in we have a hundred
patients and we sedate them with some
benzodiazepines
is there a length of protracted vomiting
shortened somehow improved by the
sleeping it has a great question I don't
think anyone has really looked at that
but certainly something to keep in mind
and I will something that just came to
mind as I was talking again Ryan Moreno
who's a pretty prominent talk
psychologist emergency room physician
and other physicians have recently
started proposing keeping a registry on
cannabis given the how much of the
United States is now legalized cannabis
and in Canada as well so toxicologists
who are emergency medicine fellowship
trained experts in drugs are now going
to be keeping a database and asking the
same questions every time so that
hopefully in five years from now we will
have much more dynamic data sure the
second question had to do
at what level won't you have in the tag
what level stimulates another one like
micro doses for instance at what level
does that kick off an attack or I mean I
think Alice mentioned that just
secondhand smoke would do it
does anybody have a clue about that so
it varies from person to person there is
no consistency for you know I was just
consuming like five ten milligrams day
maybe smoking half a joint and to me
that's not a lot to someone else that
might be considered a lot so as far as
using again and getting symptoms again
it completely varies for each person
usually after taking a break people can
consume a little bit over you know a few
months and then the symptoms come back
so people do try to use it lightly well
I mean also lightly it depends on who
what they think but there is there is no
consistency and one of the slides that
wasn't included analysis talk today but
I certainly encourage you when she
releases all of it to check it out
because it's really fascinating but in
that one of the slides that wasn't shown
fifty percent of those 200 patients were
able to go back and use cannabinoid
products again at least per their
reporting how much of that was true was
it really 50% was it more like 30% and
the other 20% did get sick that they
didn't tell us but at least fifty
percent are saying that they were able
to introduce cannabis or cannabinoids
after a certain period of cessation
there now where the money is
what was that period of cessation what
were they using what did their genetics
look like do they really have CHS were
they a CVS cohort that stopped for a
period and were given that diagnosis so
these are all fascinating questions but
even in talking to other pretty
prominent cannabis clinicians at this
event they have been noted that the same
thing and I would also make the point
that some people believe this only
occurs to recreational users who dab and
whatnot and that is not the case we also
see this in some medical patients who
may only be using for as little as a
couple of years in some cases before
this develops and to follow up on that
so you said people do go back to using
but from my dad
people after taking a break did the
symptoms come back it was 50% of people
who start using again their symptoms did
come back so 50% just to clarify that
50% of people who took a break and then
start using got their symptoms again so
that's hundred people out of 200 and
that alter rates the person that the
other 50% may have been cyclical
vomiting syndrome where they went and
smoked again and they didn't have the
issue and that's kind of what this
latest paper by then Kath asan is
getting at that we really want to be
careful here in disentangling these two
entities and in prospectively applying
this label of CHS just about at one
point in you asked about second-hand
smoking I don't believe that that will
give the patient enough amount to
influence No well you and I can go sit
in a room and you can smoke a joint and
watch how sick I get the next day
because it can make me throw up I went
to a Snoop Dogg concert and that was a
mistake so I encourage you to smoke a
joint around me so you can see what
happens because I am that sensitive to
it now and trust me I wish this wasn't
true because I love cannabis so much and
I can't go to these events
this means a certain point maybe there
are some sensitive persons individuals
it's always been like that but mostly
second-hand smoking is not effective no
- thanks Tom young from San Francisco
Bay Area
a patient who was pretty much a
recreational user he was 19 years old I
inherited him actually but he was also
the suffered a traumatic brain injury
about a year and a half tho and so I've
been a little liberal as far as not kind
of lease on his use you know because it
had sort of a mediated a lot of his
anxiety and insomnia symptoms but for
the last three weeks so actually almost
a month he's been waking up every
morning with this exact same syndrome
and you know I've urine tested him
I have quantified his cannabis use I've
checked you know all the usual stuff you
know
including thinking it might be a
gallbladder very unusual for young 19
year old man but I guess my question is
what would you suggest algorithmically
or you know in a differential where I go
with this at this point I mean he needs
to take a break
ultimately and you know I think it's
something I didn't touch on was the fact
that I have had every test done on my
body possible to make sure that nothing
else was wrong with me
so I encourage you to look into other
things too and not go straight to it's
cannabis but I have been poked and
prodded over and over and over so that
way I knew it wasn't anything else that
was happening there is prevalence of it
being in the morning when people get the
worst symptoms and I don't think we
touch base on that question but it is a
very common thing with people who have
CH s to feel it the worst right when
they wake up and Tom do you want to go
into explaining that or just cortisol
okay so when it's time to get up in the
morning the Sun coming through your
window causes your body to produce
cortisol it's why we see more heart
attacks in the morning we are think this
is going to be due to a leeching effect
from the release of Adrienne excuse me
from the release of cortisol basically
causing the leech of whatever retained
metabolites and cannabinoids are in the
system again just hypothesis but that
would be the leaving hypothesis so yeah
he needs to take a break needs to cease
cannabis use for a bit to see if it was
that because if he continues to use then
it could get worse if it is cannabis and
you know I'm not a doctor and so I'm
just saying from what I've seen that
it's best just to take a break the other
thing I would talk about which is
mentioned in a lot of the literature in
wanting to bring this entity to the
Klint to the public's consciousness is
that these patients run up seventy
eighty ninety one hundred and fifty
thousand dollars worth of medical bills
when they could just have stopped
smoking they are getting CT scans they
are getting ultrasounds sorry Alice
and I I'm a radiologist I love the
business keep it coming but you know
like really know okay we where I come
from an art and you have to be
practically dying to get medical imaging
in this country
I've got abdominal pain run through the
tuba truth the CT scanner that's a
problem when a 24 year old has now had
eight emergency room visits and eight CT
scans and that didn't then develops
lymphoma twenty years later these tests
are not innocuous so in error or benign
so I would simply say you know if you
smoke cannabis BRR use cannabis a knee
capacity cannabinoids
be honest with your physician if you
can't be honest with your physician find
a new one ask for cannabis after having
such side effects and in cysts or
enemies then I believe that that is some
kind of addiction and they must be
treated in other direction I've spent 40
plus years as an emergency physician and
Alice have to apologize for not knowing
anything about cannabis for 35 of those
years I've seen an evolution though it
seems like if you come in with nausea
and vomiting and you so much as smell
the flower
yeah there's now cannabis hyperemesis
but you know I thought I had a handle on
there's a first time I've heard that you
actually have to have recurrent symptoms
with CBD which I'm surprised I presumed
that you know the association with the
high frequent use which because we down
regulate our endocannabinoid system we
basically get a dysfunction acquired
dysfunction and and so we develop these
symptoms and that's also why things like
the capsaicin you know working on other
receptors which again CBD works on the
trip receptors why did it cause was
recurrence symptoms so I definitely have
a little more theory about you know what
is that dysregulation in the
endocannabinoid system there might be an
underlying cause of this little syndrome
yeah so first off thank you for your
longtime service in emergency medicine
and you
it's better to come to cannabis late in
life that's never come to cannabis at
all so thank you for that but what I
would say there is why the focus is that
what they think is going on at the TR PV
receptor is they think it's been
desensitized where we know that it
responds to acids with a pH of less than
6 cannabinoids nociceptive heat at 41 43
degrees and capsaicin and the idea is
that when the cannabinoids can no longer
tickle that receptor Argueta to provide
a certain tone of anti emesis that the
patients have figured out how to
self-medicate or how to self treat to
achieve this and even in the case Alice
was describing where the gentleman
developed rhabdomyolysis from running
for 10 or 15 hours in the hospital they
have to ask him you know to stop running
in place and there was another case
where a patient in the hospital the
nurses would ask him to come out of the
shower so they could evaluate him so
this will just tell you that when the
dysregulation goes awry at this receptor
these patients will do anything to the
point where they're coming in with
third-degree burns self-induced from
staying in the shower or bath for
protracted periods I'm not sure if I
really have a question or not but it may
come out like an hour like 10 minutes
before the panel started I introduced
myself to Alice and said hi we have a
mutual friend by the name of Kristin
Yoder who is on LinkedIn and Kristin
Yoder
was someone who actually brought this
particular topic to the forefront of the
cannabis community a few months ago and
boy the backlash of people in the
cannabis community instead of coming
together and being loving there was all
this really are you sure isn't it in her
head are you sure was this that
poisoning whatever and people were
really not very supportive so I'm here
to support you Alice on your journey I
know it has not been easy
I think yeah you're welcome you're
welcome and I really appreciate from the
bottom of my heart how grateful I am
that you are so vulnerable and willing
to be so courageous to the group here
today no matter what the size is what
matters is moving forward and getting us
out to the people because there are
other people who are suffering and sadly
god forbid if you have this syndrome it
doesn't sound like it's a wonderful
thing but it sounds like there are
options and alternatives and I just
wanted to also say that I had my
gallbladder taken out but and when I saw
that I'm like oh my gosh I really wonder
but nevertheless like I said I really
don't have a question I'm here to
support you and thanks for everything
thank you and I would like to just give
a few final statements that the person
she mentioned is one of my best friends
who has my back on the Internet
I do get a lot of hate for talking about
this syndrome
people have accused me of working for
the feds people say that I'm trying to
make cannabis illegal and I'd like to
remind everyone that alcohol is still
legal so this isn't a movement towards
getting cannabis out of the hands of
people I am a hundred percent pro
cannabis I fully believe in the power of
the plants it helps so many people every
day this is just an unfortunate side
effect that happens you can have too
much water and you can have too much
cannabis and so I just want to get to
the bottom of it and hopefully you guys
can help me do that thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
want to say thank you again to our
panelists and thank you all for
attending
Kent mid 2019 and enjoy the rest of your
evening thank you