well I'll begin by thanking Kevin and
Doug and the organizers for the
opportunity to speak it's nice to be
back here I was at can med I guess a
year and a half ago or something in
Boston and it was a lot smaller than
this so it's great to see the growth the
growth in the cannabis area in general
so we're switching gears from earlier
talks which were focused on on humans
and medicine and and disease states to
the plant itself and so I've sort of
tailored my talk to speak specifically
about genomics I'm not going to talk too
much about the plant other than to say
you know this is an amazing organism
that we're talking about with cannabis
it's used it's has been used for
thousands of years maybe going on 10,000
years by humans for very diverse
purposes so there's no other plant
species I think that humans sort of
access widely that is both a source of
food and the you know that pile of hemp
seeds that I show on the slide source of
fiber so there's bast fiber in the in
the stems of cannabis that is very you
know high tensile strength and used for
clothing and fishnets and it's and of
course it's a medicine because that's
what we're talking about here today and
by medicine I mean you know it can
actually treat disease or alleviate
disease but it's also a drug it's a
social drug and the picture on the
bottom left which I sort of scooped off
a paper that Ethan Russo published a
while ago is actually a shamans grave
from western China think it's something
like 2700 years ago that this individual
was was buried with a whole bunch of
grave Goods and something like 740 grams
of dried cannabis flour so this is a you
know a plant that humans have have
already utilized going back that far for
it's it's chemistry like THC and other
cannabinoids so what my lab is done for
for a while now is is really focused on
cannabis as a producer of unusual
chemicals so my my trajectory as a
researcher was from trying to understand
cannabinoid biosynthesis so the the
biochemical
pathways by which cannabinoids are
formed actually I'll go back one and
that led more and more to be involved in
genomics and in in 2011 I was part of a
Canadian team that published the first
cannabis genome it was actually the
first medicinal plant for which a genome
was was known there was about 22 other
plant genomes known at the time but
these were things like weed and cotton
and soybean etc cannabis was was really
a medicine in it
it's a genome that's pretty standard
it's about 820 mega base pairs so not
not huge but relatively complex and we
actually sequenced a cultivar or what we
were in the day calling a strain called
purple cush that we we obtained the
leaves for the the sequencing from a
medical cannabis patient in Vancouver
British Columbia who was growing it for
himself so it wasn't you know a big sort
of corporate Enterprise at the time and
he gave or donated a handful of leaves
that we isolated the DNA from so that
has been an extremely successful project
at the same time it's it's commits very
incomplete the genome is fragmented it
gave people the raw materials to do
further analyses but it's certainly not
finished but in in today's talk I'm
gonna highlight a couple of areas that
we've actually what we've used the
genome for and I guess where I'm trying
to go here is that you know sequencing a
genome is one thing it churned out a
bunch of data you make it available you
you do a lot of computational work but
it's really the raw materials for other
science so one of the things the key one
question number one that we tackle both
with the genome and and before that was
trying to figure out how cannabinoids
and torpedo formed in the plant so this
is you know how does THC acid or
cannabidiol ik acid or Mir seen or beta
carry awfully and on the terpene side
how are they actually made what are the
genes that control their production and
the way we did that was was actually
twofold one of them was one approach was
to focus in on the plant structures that
make cannabinoids so these are the
glandular trichomes that are found on
the female floral tissue so female
flowers are the
by the the flower that people smoke or
extract they're rich in cannabinoids and
the reason they're rich in cannabinoids
is because cannabinoids are not just
made in the leaves or in green material
they're actually made in these little
disks of cells that are underlying a
resin droplet on the top of a tri coma
trichome is like a microscopic hair I
mean you can see it with your eyes but
it looks like a little bit of a sort of
shiny crystally thing on a plant surface
we took those those cell types those
specific cell types of trichomes and
analyzed the gene expression in them
using DNA sequencing technology that was
available in the day and we were able
together with a lot of classical
biochemistry a lot of you know that sort
of grunt work that grad students are in
in the lab at midnight doing to really
figure out all of the enzymes and the
genes that encode those enzymes that are
present in the cannabis genome so we
from the sort of basic building blocks
of plant metabolism down to the finished
end products that an audience like
attending can met here is interested in
things like cannabidiol ik acid which is
the precursor to CBD now we know how
those are formed and that was really the
power of genomics the in in particular
cannabis chromatic acid CBCA which is on
the bottom right of the of the slide
there we actually didn't look at the
trichomes we analyzed the genome in its
entirety to find that enzyme so that was
one sort of success story we similarly
and I've heard that voice of the time
limit the voice of God so many times I
actually drop slides from my talk today
but similarly we've done biochemical
work using the purple cush genome to
figure out how the terpenes for which
cannabis is well known as well how the
terpenes are formed what are the enzymes
that make terpenes and we ended up
having basically all of the metabolites
that are labeled I'll not slide though
the major cannabinoids like cannabidiol
ik acid can bridge or aaalac acid THC
acid can of achromatic acid and the
Manger monoterpenes
and these are the compounds that Ethan
Russo was talking about
well things like Betty carry awfully and
mere scene and pining we have all of
those enzymes and that's from genomics
the other thing we did with our genome
is is moved away from the biochemistry
for which my lab was sort of established
and really focused on the evolution of
the plant
what is the Jeannette genetic structure
of cannabis and by genetic structure I
mean what are the relationships amongst
all these different types of cannabis
that we have so we know that drug type
cannabis and hemp are different I heard
various conversations around CBD from
hemp and CBD from cannabis it's the same
plant it's the same species they're
inter fertile so cannabis the drug form
whether it's called marijuana or
cannabis or drug type cannabis and hemp
are grown and and really bred for
different purposes so hemp is a source
of those seeds and fiber for which I
sort of showed in the first slide while
marijuana or drug type cannabis is for
the production of cannabinoids like THC
and CBD but they're very they're very
similar sort of morphologically
certainly hemp is a lot more sort of
scraggly looking plant if you drive past
the hemp field and we have about a
hundred thousand acres of hemp grown in
Canada each year it's not as sort of
pristine beautiful crop like you see in
a modern medical cannabis production
system but they're the same plant within
drug type cannabis of course we have
this sort of you know this canonical
classification which I actually think is
is is probably not that meaningful but
the classification is that drug type
cannabis is divided into indica style
plants or type plants and sativa type
plants indica type plants would be sort
of shorter stockier broader leaflets and
with a more of a sedative or sort of
body stone versus sativa taller sort of
lanky or more open flowering plant
narrower leaflets and with a sort of
stimulating or cerebral effect and this
is what you know
you're in a dispensary in Vancouver
where I'm from or going online in
California or wherever you are people
classified drug type cannabis marijuana
type cannabis into these types and they
also describe a third type the hybrid
the mix of the two so that that's sort
of how we think about cannabis broadly
and then of course we have this kind of
this crazy chaotic world of cannabis
strains or cultivars or chemo bars white
widows Sour Diesel Jack Herer Kevin dog
what-have-you these are these have been
sort of I would say haphazardly named in
many cases by the people who sprouted
the seed or got a clone from their buddy
and really enjoyed and gave it a new
name so what we tried to do with our
genomics work was used genotyping that
is the ability to sort of analyze the
the genetic differences between
organisms using a scan sequencing
technique so we didn't sequence every
single piece of DNA in in the plants we
we scan just sort of the sort of high
points and we got 43 samples of DNA from
from hemp types an eighty one drug type
or marijuana type samples and we
analyzed them using a technology called
genotyping by sequencing and what this
gave us was a dataset of about 14,000
single nucleotide polymorphisms or snips
these would be individual genetic DNA
code differences between those samples
and this was in what I say we this was
in collaboration with a population
geneticist at Dalhousie University named
Sean miles and then we crunch that data
that oh really the problem moves away
from a plant problem or DNA sequencing
problem into a statistical problem and
and what we used was or at least as we
visualize the data here shown as a
principal component analysis we found
that there was one group that sort of
upper right-hand group in green that was
the heme type they were very broadly
separated from drug type cannabis which
suggests again you know they the banks
he backs up what we already know they're
grown for different purposes they might
have even originated from different sort
of gene pools but within the drug type
we found some
relationships but it was a sort of a
larger more spread-out group and then
when we dug in more closely what we were
trying to do was correlate what we
called the reported ancestry so the
percentage of indica our percentage of
sativa as described by the grower or the
seed company that provided the sort the
sample with what the genetic type said
and the r-squared the correlation
between reported ancestry and genotype
was 0.36 so it's a you know low to
moderate correlation in other words
there wasn't a lot of evidence to
support genetic differences between
indicas and sativas as they were
described by the people who grow those
plants so I think what were what we're
sort of exposing here is you know the
inaccuracy of that indica sativa
dichotomy but what I don't suggest is
that it doesn't mean there's thought
they're subject not subjective
differences between cannabis types
people clearly see that whether it's
medical or recreational use and there
are more sedative types and more
stimulating types but it's just that the
genetic identity and then the also the
ability of the grower or the process or
the dispensary to give you information
around that is not not really unfirm
footing so I'll go back one slide what's
next for cannabis genomics I think what
we're going to see now is a movement
towards using genomics to fast-track
breeding we've had this you know
wonderful plant it's widely grown
probably every continent I'm not sure
about Antarctica but I'm sure someone
has tried to to cultivate it there but
it's been really kept out of labs you
know in universities governments larger
corporations its improvement has been
limited to this sort of underground
breeding world which has has to be
applauded for its these amazing success
in increasing THC levels and bringing
CBD back but it hasn't solved some of
the problems things like you know
powdery mildew is a widespread fungal
pathogen outdoors continues to be tchau
in different latitudes really what we
need is a genomics to accelerate crop
improvement and so I just just to finish
my talk I sort of highlight three areas
where I think this kind of new wave of
cannabis science driven by genomics is
going to to move things along for our
both our industry and for the use of
cannabis one is its a potential
resolution for this strain chaos problem
in the sense that you know we need trust
in the industry we need more predictable
effects for patients and consumers we
need a better understanding at a purely
scientific level of how cannabis evolved
so I think by applying more genetics
getting more samples doing more in-depth
analyses we're probably going to be able
to link you know a name and I think
humans are always going to want a name
they're not going to want a list of
chemicals they're gonna want a name you
know whether we have Merlot grapes and
we have Honey Crisp apples and we have
Dalmatian dogs and we name those things
and I think we're going to continue to
name kanima's but we need some genetic
identity that backs that up as I
mentioned before genetic markers are
going to accelerate breeding things like
flowering traits disease resistant
traits specialized chemistry's I heard
th CV mentioned earlier CBG I mean we we
want to drive towards breeding and
providing plants that have chemistry
that helps patients also has
recreational properties that are
desirable three minutes the last point
and I think you know this is already
being worked on in the industry is that
you know we we have sort of generally
sort of two tools or have had two tools
in planned improvement one is
traditional breeding the other is
genetic modification now we have a sort
of a third way which is genome editing
that's using specialized and
revolutionary techniques called CRISPR
casts and related approaches to actually
make changes in genomes whether it's an
animal genome or a plant genome towards
a desirable outcome and I think you know
now cannabis is finally sort of coming
out of the closet as an organism that
that labs can work on we will see the
application of this technology
fairly soon is a GMO or not I mean the
EU says one thing in North America says
something else so it's a bit of a debate
but I think this is coming as well and
with that I'll end and there's time for
questions I'll take some thanks there's
microphones for questions in the front
of the room please step up if you have a
question yeah I think you need to go to
the mic at the hi John thanks for coming
today I wanted to find out more
specifically what kind of markers what
low sigh you are beginning to find
disease resistance for instance and
possibly the autoflowering traits one
minute yeah so you know I partly now a
lot of my work is more of a commercial
nature so I'm sort of a bit hesitant to
other than to say you know flowering
time control is a key area that we're
detecting in in our work and disease
resistance specifically around botrytis
and powdery mildew I think are huge
drivers of crop maybe not lost but loss
of value so we're working on those two
as well actually there's no GMO I mean
like but in terms of CRISPR I don't
think it's GMO because the changes made
those genome editing technique is the
same thing that would happen naturally
with with mutation or you could induce
it with a chemical or radiation so I
think it's safe to say it's not GMO in
terms of the idea that we have GMO
cannabis already
there's no GMO cannabis I mean may exist
the lab but it's not something that's
that's out in the in the wild in terms
of production or anything so I don't
think we have to worry about that yet