[Music]
welcome to the caned Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
ameral I am the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and proud member of
the team that puts on the camed
conference all right just a few
reminders before I introduce Our Guest
for this episode first be sure to
register for the canmed 24 Innovation
and investment Summit before the early
bird deadline of December 1st that's
only one month away if you can believe
it we just announced last week that
Golden Eagle Partners will be returning
in 2024 with their Capital markets
Workshop that will cover topics related
to to investing in cannabis
Innovation the session was a big hit
last year with representatives from
several top
companies it's a great opportunity to
connect with them as well as potential
investors you can learn more at CET
events.com and be sure to register
today we are also accepting abstract
submissions for oral and poster
presentations at Ked 24 so if you have
new or novel research related to
cannabis science medicine cultivation or
safety testing we want to hear from you
I put a link in the show description
where you can learn more about the
abstract submission process and you can
submit your abstract there as well the
deadline for that is November 18th so
get on it and good
luck Our Guest today is Bill Graham bill
is the founder of microcone tissue
culture a company that provides tissue
culture kits Consulting and training to
cannabis
cultivators with Hands-On expertise Bill
retailed and distributed hydroponic
supplies sourced grow lights globally
created bioice nutrients designed fresh
filter air quality systems and
simplified micropropagation cloning
creating microcone tissue culture kits
in
2005 during our conversation we
discussed the basics of tissue culture
tissue culture as a propagation
alternative to cloning how mother plants
can lead to pathogen infections and loss
of
vigor combining tissue culture and qpcr
testing to eliminate pathogens such as
hop and vroid and much
more before we get to my conversation
with Bill I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor cambium
analytica cambium analytica provides
analytical product development and
quality assurance services for the
Natural Foods Botanical products natural
pharmaceutical and dietary supplement
Industries cambam is a leading research
organization that is focused on
leveraging its expertise on drug
Discovery and Method development to be a
research partner of choice for new
Innovative companies and the burgeoning
Botanical medicine
spaces their focus on applying analy
iCal techniques in combination with
sensory product development and consumer
research is driving advancement in
natural product quality and Innovation
learn more at cambium analytica
tocom all right without any further Ado
please enjoy my conversation with Bill
[Music]
Graham
good afternoon Bill thanks so much for
joining us on the
podcast glad to be here all right so
let's talk about tissue culture and I
know this is a a propagation method that
you've been evangelizing for for quite
some time and with the emergence of
hlate and vroid and other plant
pathogens it seems like now more than
ever tissue culture is top of mine for
many Growers so so let's dive into it um
and let's talk about what tissue culture
is and what advantages that it may have
over the cloning that a lot of Growers
are doing now so um so let's start with
that so give us a high Lev view of what
is the tissue culture process and uh
we'll take it from there oh happy to uh
ordinarily tissue culture is going to be
practiced in uh in four stages uh and
then incidentally I might just take this
opportunity to kind of tell everybody
what tissue culture is in especially as
it pertains to plants and very simply it
is Hydroponics with sugar so we're using
the same nutrients we've got some uh
special amino acids uh usually there may
be um hormones to give it Direction uh
but uh what makes tissue culture special
from the Hydroponics that Growers are
already doing is going to be adding
sugar uh to give that
energy source directly to the plant
sugar can be directly absorbed by the
stem and uh and and surface tissues
without roots um to provide that energy
so we can make plants from pieces that
would be too small to uh clone very fast
themselves however because it's sugar
everything else wants to grow on it and
that's when you start seeing the scalpel
and forceps and the HEPA filter and the
laminar hoods and the pressure cookers
all those things are to be able to make
the growing medium clean the plant
handle it uh and grow it so that uh the
fungus and bacteria and those things
don't get back onto it um but uh given
that uh tissue culture is fantastic for
being able to make lots of uh brand new
clones from a a a sterile uh Source once
the plant's clean and it's growing in um
it's growing in the jar so the four
usual steps of of tissue culture are
going to be uh introduction
multiplication uh rooting in culture and
then rooting back out of culture but you
uh you probably already know that I've
kind of made a little special version of
that uh to make it easier for for
Growers and to make it more effective
for uh a lot of our producers right so
at a completely high level what we're
talking about is using small pieces of
an established plant to make new copies
of a plant so not too dissimilar from
what you would do with cloning just with
much smaller pieces right oh yeah yeah
and in fact it's funny I'm actually
calling it tissue cloning because we're
using tissue culture to clone uh and um
and that's kind of part of my uh the
shortcut that I've made up and that is
to um uh top veg plants uh taking a two
or three centimeter uh cutting off of
the top so that the plants will branch
which is valuable for indoor growth
especially um and this is primarily for
our our vertical Growers but works for
anybody who uh is raising plants uh
indoors and vegetative growth but that's
uh but that's putting a uh a tip cutting
directly onto rooting medium which is
sort of a a shortcut of the usual uh
four
stages right so you're taking so a lot
of Growers they're they're topping their
plants like you said to kind of widen
them and give them more of a bushy look
so you're actually being able to make
use of that by putting it into a a
rooting media and and kind of create
copies now with that not be a good
material to use for cloning
traditionally uh it actually makes a bad
clone because there's uh so much
concentrated branching in that piece uh
and um to take it as a clone length
you're usually throwing away you know
four six even eight good nodes uh which
is all growth um that we don't want to
get rid of uh uh typically when a veg
tray which is about 96 or 100 plants
when it's when it's growing
um everybody in there is essentially a
clone but some are going to be more
vigorous than others uh and the
technicians are going to look at it and
say okay we have enough lower branching
that we are going to remove this much
material off the top of that plant uh
and leave you know is it going to be
four five six sometimes eight limbs
whatever their number is uh but that
piece has to go and they're usually just
pinching that to trash pinching it
compost uh uh and so what we did is I
was like you know I I'm in the facility
already to do collection they're always
sending me to the mom plants to do it
but I prefer to go to the veg plants
because immediately we can tell which
ones are strongest just based on figure
and number two is uh that it's already
being done uh so you know this is
material I can take that doesn't
interfere with any other uh cloning or
um propagation going on in the facility
and then it turns out that we could turn
it into an actual strategy to produce
all the plants that that the Grove needs
and in fact improve the crop um quickly
uh by selecting on Vigor and that's
where things get really
interesting right so I mean you touched
on a good point there
so with your system you could
potentially do away with moms and just
do all of your propagation off of your
veg plants is that right yes I am mom's
mom plant's worst enemy uh you know but
but you know I totally get it you know
um what's really kind of funny is how we
got here because I of course ran the
retail shops man made grow equipment I
and we used it so I got to be the grower
equipment maker and really Mom plants
were a a means to an end it got us by
you know as a grower myself I never did
my did Mom plants because it was a waste
of P tensi light uh I can get if I'm
producing all the veg plants I need for
my grow then I really just need like two
or three flowering rooms um so that I'm
producing veg plants every two or three
weeks so I've got all the fresh material
I need to cut from and you when I was a
a college Gardener uh I was using side
limbs for that work funny enough that
was exactly the same time I got into
tissue culture and it was going to be
20s something years later I'm not dating
myself uh that I started realizing wait
a minute this material that we're
proving off the top actually makes a
great clone and if we're taking it from
the very best veg plants then that Vigor
which was expressed in the veg plant it
was cut from carries over into the new
plant that that uh um culture is going
to
produce and we're able to we're able to
get all the plants back uh over two uh
pruning Cycles so if I've got a tray of
100 veg plants I need to replace I can
take about 35 of the best tops first and
then seven days later go back for
another hundred or so so that we can be
selective and in eight weeks those tops
going into culture were going to be the
plants that are being topped again so
we're able to short the whole uh
selection cycle down to um eight weeks
and and you can see none of that
involves a m plant H all right I'm not
sure if I quite followed that all the
different stages and the different mul
so topping the plants to make the new
plants that all that ultimately go back
to
veg okay so so walk me slides while
we're talking say that again go ahead
I'm pulling up slides while we're
talking so I can actually throw these up
if we uh need them oh yeah absolutely
that that would be great so
email yeah you could do that or uh yeah
you want if you want to do that I could
pull it up that'd be cool would it kind
of show the different um you know yeah
it's got a picture multiplication steps
there it does it does but uh very simply
it just kind of shows a veg plant being
topped and then that going into a a tube
um on rooting medium which will uh grow
about three or four times its original
Mass um because that's what's happening
when this cutting is in the tissue
culture tube so if we've taken a a a 2
or 3 cmet cut and put it onto um rooting
tissue culture media
the uh sugar is absorbed immediately
right through the surface of the stem
and that cambium that green growth
tissue just underneath the surface is
going to be turning that into uh starch
complex carbohydrates it's turning into
stored energy wood it turns it into wood
and you can see it get fat um
unfortunately I took all of my last
clones to um Rhode Island with me and uh
and didn't bring any back uh I can run
over and grab one um from show the other
day but it's got a little spoilage on it
but anyway the bottom gets fat uh with
all that stored wood and it gets lumpy
uh because of the influence of rooting
hormone so these shortcut Ro uh tissue
cuting are root ready to root into plugs
in about three weeks so I'm using tissue
culture as a cloning tool without how
many different copies can you get from
one
plant well if we were doing the straight
micropropagation where one cutting would
go into a jar and it uh would uh branch
and grow on a on a multiplication
hormone that is going to be the class of
called cyto which are the opposite of uh
oxin which are rooting uh those plants
will usually grow to um if we're lucky
enough to get them to Branch uh to like
six or seven um new uh 1 and a half
cimer node cuting in the period of like
five weeks and that would make that many
new plants you start doing an
exponential uh multiplication on that um
and uh you're going to have you know we
can have thousands uh in the case of
regular horiculture uh I can tell you
for a fact that a couple of plants can
turn into tens of millions because uh
that's what I did with uh citrosa
deriums if any of your Watchers have the
uh the mosquito repelling geraniums in
front of their house uh and everybody
recognizes them those actually came from
these hands in 1992 because that was my
project when I went when I was hired to
work at AGR starts uh hired from college
to return to college um with a special
one-year project and um uh I did start
with just a hundred cuting from the
original stock plants and those are the
parents of all of the citrosa plants
that anybody has ever grown in North
America since
1992 wow which has to just be in the
tens or even a 100 million plants by now
wow so are those all propagated through
tissue
culture they now funny enough the plants
they sent me were in 8 inch pots from
Holland which is really interesting
because this was a plant that was
supposedly developed by somatic
hybridization the process was supposedly
to take this scented uranium and grass
of China strip all the cell walls off
make the little naked stells stick
together um regrow some cell walls and
then encourage those to grow in culture
and become uh a uh a duranium that had
this uh citronella oil in it um however
that it would you know very much a
tissue culture
tool however the plants I got were in
pots and so that was when I first
suspected that they were not actually
from tissue culture uh and the second
was when I got a mosquito bite when I
was in a a greenhouse of like 200,000
plants
uh but I still encourage them because
they're really pretty and they smell
great and I still have them all over my
house but that's that is tissue culture
as far as a few plants making many and
and that's where we really stand today
as an industry most of the people who
have used your you are using your
products uh especially the um uh hlvd
testing uh are testing plants that are
going to be dedicated moms and I totally
get that um we try to encourage that to
um
uh to to get away from moms and to try
and do a lot of this work off of veg
plants for the reason that um we kind
there there's a disease cycle involved
with Mom plants that is unique to
cannabis indoor cannabis um and that is
that you know the plants are the Petri
dishes for everything we're trying to
get rid of good or bad and uh things are
shared um in innocuous ways I mean it's
really hard to move the around and clean
the tools every single handling and most
grows uh you know are never going to be
that disciplined so anyway even just air
exposure in the same grow facility
everything we're worried about grows on
cannabis and the oldest plants are going
to be the most exposed and as your
testing reveals so often is that plants
that show no out outward symptoms uh can
contain thyroids fusarium uh Bettis
aspergillis uh any of the things that
we're really worried about and of course
they are the source of all the new
plants in the garden and so I the tissue
culture shortcut helps break that
because the plants that will become the
new crop will have to grow inside of a
sterile tissue culture tube for at least
three weeks in which case if there's
anything there that doesn't belong uh we
can usually see it by eye and of course
you know um the medicinal genomics gives
us tools for being able to uh PCR test
that uh and know that the material in
the tube itself is also uh is sterile
you know just in the course of the 3
weeks but uh that's that's a good start
we can label it as a negative and then
follow it afterwards uh and test it
several more
times if you're anybody familiar with uh
segra or any of the uh companies doing
uh tissue culture services to clean
plants uh they will be doing the exact
same things propagating the the plants
and testing over and over again you know
they they usually look for at least
three negatives um uh from subcultures
before they kind of give guaranteed um
vroid free uh back to the customer and
then it's what does the customer do they
grow another mom plant they started all
over again they put Mom in the same room
as all the other mom plants uh the
technicians still have the dirty tools
even if they're cleaning there's risk
and we just want to kind of break all
that besides if I can turn a mom room
into a flower room I've just made a
grower you know a little bit more money
sometimes 20% and then if the crop gets
better from just Vigor there's another
20 30 40% from doing nothing else except
selecting on Vigor which incidentally is
why we don't have corn that looks like
this anymore someone went in and said
hey that one look that one looks a
little better and that's what they grew
next year no and you make a great point
about this you know the moms being a bit
of a Petri an incubator for all these
different diseases and and it makes
sense they're older plants um and
they're constantly being exposed to the
air and the elements because they're
continually having their their limbs
lopped off so um sort of breaking that
cycle seems to make a lot of sense and
one of the things I I did I had the
pleasure of seeing you present at the
Cannabis science conference uh just
recently and another thing that was
brought up during that talk was this
idea of genetic drift um yes which also
seems to be sort of um a problem that
emerges from using mother plants so
speak a bit about that oh uh this is
actually one of the things that got uh
the kits popular the first time is
because there are a lot of fantastic
Growers and especially Legacy Growers
who have been growing uh plants for 10
20 years or so I mean these are their
trademark strains but what's going to
happen in that much time especially
especially if it's you know recycled
indoor growth is it sometimes happens
that the plants are just not yielding
like they used to they're not behaving
like they used to they're not yielding
like they used to but we know it's the
same plant because you do the DNA
testing of these things well so you know
what that comes down to is epigenetics
which is going to be the expression of
the genes uh so they're there why aren't
we seeing them and why aren't they their
very strongest and there's usually a
couple of things uh they can usually be
stress related um because you've got a
really nice indoor environment the light
comes on at the same time the
temperature is great everything is
wonderful if we lived in spas I don't
think we'd look quite as fit as if you
know we were outside um you know uh
taking care of the land like uh our
ancestors right um though it'd be worth
it uh but uh genetic drift is going to
sort of just be like the plants sort of
drop off of what they used to do tissue
culture is a great little Tool uh for
that because it kind of brings back
juvenile growth it tends to strip off
some of the
methylation um that has occurred on that
DNA uh in um in those nice environments
and frankly we try to do a two-prong uh
approach anyway and that is for any
grower that's experienced genetic drift
uh is to uh try to raise uh some of the
plants vegetatively outdoor in the
outdoors in the summer um for you know
like six weeks or so for that
multi-spectrum Sunshine uh the hot days
the cold nights we can even simulate
some pest attack uh with um harpon
protein um and and and material like
that you know possible real insect
attack uh wind all those things like
that that uh are actually
stimulation to the plant uh we had
several um uh lectures during cannabis
science uh about stress and so on like
that so I tried to put the two together
and of course we are going to take uh
tip cuttings from those outdoor plants
put them into bleach water which is sort
of our conduit getting plants into
culture and that is our quarantine to
moving outdoor material back into the
growth space plant cuting go into the
chlorine uh we clean the tools every cut
which is how we are able to uh take that
small piece of tissue and um uh put it
into a solution that's not only cleaning
the surface but preventing uh vroid or
any other pathogens from moving between
plants and another one of the things
we'll catch up on before we get out of
here will sort of be uh the strategy of
taking small pieces to um uh hopefully
eliminate to hopefully take material
without thyroids and
pathogens yeah so I mean no time like
the Pres let's get into that now oh
shoot this is where we've been using
your kits this is where uh this is where
the um upcr H has been um I beg your
pardon that was mostly for our
chromosomes but uh using um uh your
vroid detecting um PCR has been
excellent because we're using such small
material and we can get smaller I mean
two to 4 cmers is a good working size
for new users because the plants that
begin to root are a good size to go into
a rooting plug and and begin creating
the new plants quickly which is what
Growers one um but you know as we teach
in like our our master class is that you
know we'll go down to 1 cmet half
centimeter pieces we can keep going
smaller and smaller because this is the
cool thing is once you've got a simple
setup and I don't know if your viewers
can see you know what's behind me but
I've got a simple laminar Hood which is
not even really necessary uh and a
lighted Shelf with a HEPA filter and
this is my grow chamber um but we are
able to uh once we've got tissue culture
media prepared we can do plants of all
sizes but anyway the the premise uh I
have really just written into a proposal
for research paper is that there the
material the tips are always outgrowing
viroids or anything systemic so all the
growth is coming from the very tip I
mean less than a millimeter of the very
tip is the future growth of that entire
limb uh and even before vascular tissues
are produced so the vroid and and so on
will move either in the vascular tissues
or in the intercellular uh intercellular
space between the cell walls and the
cells themselves some will pass into the
cells and some will be shared with the
cells next to it because that's kind of
how how cells communicate but not
quickly it's all passive and as long as
that tip growth is vigorous that passive
exchange is not necessarily fast enough
is there viroid in the cytoplasm in that
brand new GR growth and and some of the
work that zir Puna um especially as we
saw canmed uh was showed in his
presentation is that uh viroids and uh
systemic pathogens are not uniformed
through the plants you he had that one
slide of a plant he goes left side has
vroid the right side does not it was all
the same plant and where was I my hand
was Sky High back there in the audience
I was like let let talk about that
because that happens on on on idual
Limbs and the more the plant grows limbs
uh the more likely that's the case and
um and especially the vigorous ones so
it kind of one thing sort of led to
another uh in all of that but your stuff
comes in because we can take uh a
cutting a small cutting and uh actually
save a piece of the bridge tissue which
would be uh the stem tissue going into
that cutting if I take a 4 cimet cutting
I can use bottom centimeter for a
thyroid test and the upper 3 cmers uh
are being clean to go to culture and if
we've got your tools for working on site
at that at that location at that moment
we can know before that plant is even
cultured if it uh was uh negative or
positive on the test so that's kind of
an interesting one that I talked to uh
we we talked about it can Med and I
talked to Kevin uh is uh exploring the
use of bridge tissue for uh um uh PCR
testing of viroid because we shouldn't
need much especially now that you I saw
that you guys have tests with infinitely
small uh amounts of sample like we can
actually just stab the actual cutting uh
with the tip of a um a micropipe pet uh
no cutting no cutting needed no washing
needed so I'm really looking forward to
getting into that because we can now
test the piece that's actually being
isolated and grown to be the next crop
negative lives mean a lot more if we
know that it's trapped inside of glass
going get a whole out of it well yeah
and so a lot of the talk about using
tissue culture to S sort of create a new
copy that's that's free of hlvd had
always been about meristem tissue
culture which I think when you were
talking before is that very top tip um
which you're hoping that the virid
hasn't had a chance to get to yet but it
sounds like you were just describing to
take a a larger cutting but then test
the bottom of it where it had met the
the larger plant to see if there's
anything there and if that's clean you
assume that the rest of the cutting is
clean as well do I have that right we
yes and it is totally assuming um and
and it's not necessarily 100% we can't
test every cutting uh you know because
if I need if I need 100 veg plants and
I'm doing 135 cuts to get it that's a
lot of expensive testing but that's why
it's called sampling we will do stum
along the
way know I've got we got a whole
strategy for this uh that kind of
involves you know weaning the vroid out
of the crop gradually um but by
gradually it can be 20 or 30% a cycle
and those Cycles can be eight eight or
nine weeks apart um if you guys if you
want to know a little more about that um
yeah yeah but you know what we've gone
on because I do this for big Growers and
I did it for myself interesting Enough
by the way everything that that I kind
came up with that we shared was
developed for fusarium first so when you
all sent your uh sent uh your first um
uh PCR test uh around um with Kyle uh
way back when we were doing gender
testing but you asked right away they
were like oh what's the next test we
would need and I said fusarium because
at that moment I had a massive fusarium
problem at my place and so we did this
really to eliminate fusarium but the
premise is exactly the same and
incidentally it's turns out to be ideal
for a vroid as well because they sort of
tend to travel and move the same ways um
but uh you know if you're 100% trying to
eliminate uh vroid uh in one shot that's
where we would take like those half
millimeter Marist stems and that could
take a long time to grow a new plant but
you can but what I discovered was that
uh on a plant that we might have uh that
might register positive because it was
it because of where the tests were taken
it was taken at Leaf WLS you know where
everything that the penate leaves all
come together or down in The Roots uh
and those are uh either vascular
intersections where traffic seems to
slow and so they accumulate or of course
the roots are a sink you know everything
kind of goes down there and stays put um
as a testing company you want to find
the greatest concentration of vroid so
that you can get the uh result that yes
this plant has vroid in it it but funny
enough I go to that exact same plant and
do my stuff off of the tips especially
if it's if it's been cloned um and it's
on the table and we've got viger's
growth if we select on
Vigor then and this kind of goes down
the type of uh research that Kevin's
doing is that we might have uh plants
that are naturally resistant we might
have a strain of the vroid that is
particularly weak we might have any
number of circumstances that just kind
of mean that vroid is not necessarily a
problem not only in this particular crop
but in this particular tissue if the
tissue is vigorous that's our sign and
you know we've kind of assumed just
making up a number is if we had a a
positive plant uh made into 100 clones
uh vegetative clones and we start
selecting on Vigor on those uh that
taking time tops we're maybe uh taking
off 20 or 30% uh that are absolutely
vroid free because the viroids would
have not caught up with that tip growth
um but eight weeks later those same
plants are now uh are clone donors so
the plants from the two test tubes that
we topped are the veg plants being
topped again and we do the same
selection on Vigor and now we take off
another 20 or 30% thyroid free so if we
start at a a hypothe 100% we can go down
to 80 62 keep going like that uh pretty
much uh at the end of the year um we're
in the low single digits getting smaller
and here's the thing is most of the
Growers who have thyroids as your
testing reveals are living with it
anyway so we just try to strategically
make that the very best growth that it
can be and besides selecting on viiger
seems to make the entire crop uh perform
better anyway mom plants as Growers are
using today have been selected on Vigor
anyway but that was eight months ago by
doing it at eight weeks we can do that
six times a year you know remember if
you're trying to do breeding experiments
um you got arabidopsis for plants and
fruit flies you know if you want insects
because we want those Generations you
know flip them right which is another
culture trick by the way is we started
doing um we started harvesting amateur
embryos uh um fertilized embryos uh at
like two days so we fertilize a bud then
dissect the flower and pull out the uh
the fertilized embryo um and can put
that on culture as well it's smaller
than it's great but you just put it
right over the same medium you little
less sugar a little less hor no hormone
um and uh and give it time and we can
make plants from that the value being is
by just touching the tip of a scalpel to
that little embryo we can get our DNA
sample for that entire cross so then we
can run it through PCR uh and be able to
see it uh our is our marker pattern um
the desirable cross that we were looking
for because that's how that goes is you
do a cross and your seeds still go all
different ways and uh know there's going
to be a good deal of testing but we can
test the seeds for the genetics and then
from culture uh turn those into whole
plants after that selection wow yeah all
right this is this is where we work
together so well yeah veered off into
whole different I don't want to do what
you're doing but I want to I I want to
keep sharing what we do you know
absolutely walk them right up to the
edge and then you take them from there
excellent no and I want to go back to
sort of this this process of continuing
to propagate to kind of get ahead of hot
plate and hyid and so as I understand it
so is the idea being that like like like
zamir had had shown in his in in his
presentation that the plant typically
gets infected it goes down to the roots
stays there for a little while and then
it kind of proliferates throughout the
rest of the plant so is the idea being
that like you're trying to catch those
tips before the vroid has had a chance
to get there and then you're kind of
constantly it actually M and down so
even if it's in those limbs some of it
moves down the down tends to go down and
stay down it could of course carry back
up because the um xylem uh which will go
back up to the limbs uh is especially
active during uh it's active early on
for you know water and um and nutrient
salts so of course it's the primary car
carrier for those in uh flowering
especially in cannabis it gets
interesting because we have a a new
shunt and that is that uh stored sugar
uh the wood and and and carbohydrates
we're talking about in The Roots and
stems begins to mobilize again so it'll
take complex carbohydrates and turn into
the simple sugars again and start
sending those up the xylem which is when
we suspect that the uh vroid is going to
be carried up as well you know because
you know sugar relatively large
organisms it's obviously metab uh
metabolically driven um and uh we
suspect that vroid is involved somewhere
in uh gumming up the metabolic process
um but uh it's first of all we're doing
an AEG when those things would not be
moving
anyway number two is just uh that all
that growth is coming from the tip it's
like trying to chase a rocket if you're
in its uh in its in its burn stream you
know it's going to be
hard you know what was what was that
very tip growth yesterday is now
centimeters or inches higher tomorrow
that's incredible and considering we're
talking about uh things that are just
shared passively
uh cell to cell and um uh when you get
up into growth that high and then those
brand new vascular tissues is they are
often missed is how it goes and this is
where the testing comes in yeah because
you know I I've done this for a while
and we were sending in Te uh testing
from tips uh and we were getting so much
more negative material and what's funny
is you guys as a testing agency were
saying oh well you you should either mix
all of those samples together or let's
go for these other high concentrated uh
tissues which is great again for
identifying the presence of the vroid in
the garden I would almost go ahead and
say it's there and if it wasn't vroid
it's something else um but you know
let's uh if we start doing it off of
tips there is the uh greater likelihood
uh that given the plant assuming the
plant had vroid in it at all that we're
using uh material that's so new uh and
as has grown so vigorously that it is um
vroid free and if we take that cutting
with clean tools now the part about this
I had mentioned is that to take that top
off your hands have been cleaned in
bleach water your tools have cleaned in
bleach water I actually have a a vinyl
apron with bleachy sponges in it and
three sets of tools and gloves uh so I
can do that and of course from talking
to zamir he said yes Spyro can live and
bleach as well but not well and not for
a long time so we you know it's the best
we have right is to use that you know
let's we're not going to ask for trouble
we're going to do our best to eliminate
it but that will be cleaning the plant
cleaning the tools and then taking
another cutting but that's it uh if I
can I want to take my sample for the
test from this piece on its way to
culture that's it right and so if I'm
hearing you correctly so if I'm a grower
and I have a plant that tested positive
for H for hot PL and viroid and maybe
we're assuming that we were looking at
one of those High concentration areas
maybe like the roof or one of those so
we know that there's vroid there but I
think from what I'm hearing is yes
before you throw it away you might want
to search for a spot on that plant that
doesn't have the vroid take a cutting
from that and then try to use tissue
culture to create a vroid free copy yes
yes thank you and you know um yeah for
sure I would and above that would be you
know taking like a hundred or something
copies
uh in testing as many as as you can
afford so you can have a representative
sampling you know again Growers don't
need to freak out because you know
viroids in plants are shared by plant
juice it's only juice to juice that's
going to make uh problems which is why
we clean tools uh you know think of it
like HIV or hepatitis um you know you
can you you can touch the plants with
your bare hands um you can move pots
around and stuff in the room when the
leaves rub each other it's not
necessarily spread spreading um and we
don't know so much about like the the
sucking insects uh aphids um spider
mites so on like that you know we those
things should all be under control
anyway but uh um the idea is that I
would take like aund and something
cuting and select off of vigor and do
the testing on as many of those as you
can afford so we have a representative
group if out a 30 test we get 10
positives or 20 um you know we'll keep
the good 10 and the other 100
uh that we go because you're still in
business these are the plants that made
you um uh tens of thousands of dollars
Just A Week Ago we'll go ahead and grow
them again always keeping things clean
between uh handlings but then you know
we'll test the next round two where
hopefully we'll see you know 12 or uh 12
or so positives and then the next time
fewer than that so uh you know always a
valuable part of it and I would
recommend you know testing at least 20
of every uh 130 or 40 plant batch so you
have a representative sample right and
so this is a process you've used you've
used in the past and it's been
successful yeah yeah this is one of the
best parts about it uh it's why I call
them buggy guys all the time is uh um
kind of coming up and saying hey I'm
doing this thing different and
strategically working out ways to um uh
make sure that we have a suitable sample
you know for uh for the
testing excellent no we'd love to do an
application note or a case study with uh
some of your success stories I think
that would be a a great thing to have on
our website and share with our potential
prospects too so if that's something
that you're interested in we could do a
nice nice co co-branded uh um document I
think that'd be awesome okay I'll uh
I'll I'll send it to you as I go I just
put in another um uh 800 words yesterday
so oh excellent it is I I I will get the
research done because this is still
we've seen it on site but you know
science is science there's a method and
we're going to do it properly besides if
I do enough of these I may finally get
that degree that I've been seeking for
30 you know it's crazy I would have had
a cannabis degree you know if it
existed 169 credits under Graduate
University of Florida would not leave
school first I was growing so I could
pay for those credits and um and they
were only 99 bucks each so State schools
awesome uh but um uh you know everything
everything was really kind of cannabis
horiculture molecular biology related
you know it's just one thing right after
another I was like oh this is cool they
made me leave and I tried to get a
graduate degree but no one was going to
take me because they didn't know what I
was doing that's how it went and I
really just couldn't marry peas or uh
beans or corn or something like that you
know uh to get in on with somebody's
good graces right talk to the we about
it we can't get you that degree but uh
we we might be able to get you up on the
caned stage if you if you publish that
research or if you send that research to
us so uh it's a it's a decent
consolation prize I
suppose I I might I also promise to
share a copy with Max Jones um maybe we
can wrap that all up everybody's in this
game together all right Bill Before I
Let You Go I want to give you a chance
to share any resources that the
listeners or the Watchers um might be
interested in to learn more about uh
your process and some of the research
that you've done and um of course plug
away with any other ways that people can
get in touch with you uh learn more more
about what you're doing oh I definitely
appreciate thank you uh um I I post the
uh I post all the um Graphics uh links
to the videos at microc clone. comom um
we have the videos on YouTube under
microcone 100 uh Instagram is microcone
100 I believe uh uh Twitter x uh
microcone Facebook Facebook microcone
it's microcone everything and I try to
post uh um little bits and pieces
everywhere um so you can sort of build
the story but the website is the uh the
the very best uh direct resource and my
email is Bill micron.com
um and uh and uh I'll uh um put up uh
resources such as my um uh appendix or
the um the index of the research that we
followed mostly uh zir punja uh some of
your early stuff on um on viroids and
detection distribution um and uh uh
anything related to the um uh to the uh
shortcut propagation excellent excellent
yeah and I've and before when I was
getting ready to to talk with you I did
watch some of the videos of the process
and you make it look very easy is it as
easy as you make it look because I think
maybe in my mind and maybe other other
people's minds too like issue culture
seems like a very kind of daunting
process that you know you have to be
super clean and super precise but um
like I said you make it look very
easy uh yeah I mean when you if if
you're going to be full-on professional
and you've got you know 100 200,000
invested in it we'll put up you know the
um uh the doors and the pass keys and so
on but genuinely the whole idea is to
learn start successfully get all the way
through and we do this in that little
lunchbox kit you've seen me carry um we
have prepared medium in um uh the our
starter process usually works with like
an instant pot or a uh a stove top
pressure cooker uh to sterilize media
our transfer area is as simple as a
plastic storage bin um and we work in a
little shallow saucer the plants are
cleaned in chlorine water our choice
chlorine is going to be uh sodium D
chloro uh cyanurate um uh pull shock
really it's 99% um
uh dissociative chlorine so it's free
chlorine uh and it evaporates so I love
it because we can work in it without
rinsing and that's a big deal and we can
make it stronger but we will clean the
plants in this solution and I'll
actually put a puddle of it in the
saucer so that as we're dissecting the
plants um nothing is getting on there so
that gives us a still air box and then
lastly will be some sort of a clear grow
area um where we can have lights on a
shelf and a HEPA filter running nearby
to keep the air clean over there so the
pressure cooker in the kitchen a pH
meter and some mixing tools and um a
real simple transfer area I've done this
at trade shows I do this in hotel rooms
I have generally sterilized media in the
microwave right next to the waffle maker
in the morning and put plants in that
Medium before the afternoon we might
have a little more incidents of
contamination because it's all brand new
but that's usually for Learning and the
crazy part is is we still will end up
with like 50% clean plant
that the grower will transplanting into
plugs three weeks later that's the whole
idea is that tissue culture is a grower
tool they can use in the simplest area
and can always expand it's absolutely
scalable uh my I've got Growers who are
up to over a thousand clones a day who
started with the same instant pot that
I'm talking about right it's really just
a way to get their feet wet and get them
comfortable with it and then you can
scale up from there that's it that's it
excellent that's the idea yes take the
intimidation out of it it's a Growers
tool we're Growers Growers innovate look
at what the hell we did when growing was
illegal you know look at what we made
work the grow lights you have today you
spoiled youngsters um you should have
had it back in my day walk to school
uphill both ways um is that you know we
we made stuff from what we had I was
like street light Warehouse light
whatever you got we took it apart
rebuilt it so that it became a Growers
tool and we had to make that stuff work
because you were not necessarily going
to theore store to get the answers you
need and you were working in the middle
of night so they weren't open anyway and
tissue culture version of the same thing
but go to microc clone. comom you can
see everything that we use um and uh and
get started for you know less than a uh
300 bucks get you a whole kit and uh my
um commercial people can usually get
started for less than a thousand and
train several people and I'm available
for Consulting uh by Zoom or on site
excellent Bill uh oh a pleasure talking
with you uh seems like there's a lot of
opportunities for us to be working
together so excited about that uh thanks
again for taking the time and can't wait
to see you down in uh in Marco Island
for camid yeah I just got my discount uh
code from
Brandon I'll see you next year all right
get that ticket before they sell out
thanks Ben all right won't wait till the
last minute like last time you and
everybody
else just want to make you
sweat a great one man you uh say hey to
everybody over there I look forward to
seeing y'all again all right I will do
cheers
[Music]
night I hope you enjoyed my conversation
with Bill Graham check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and thanks again
to this episode sponsor cambium and
analytica our next episode drops
November 15th that's 2 weeks from
today in the meantime head over to
canmed events.com now to learn all about
our canmed 24 Innovation and investment
Summit which is coming up next May if
you like what you see and I'm sure that
you will be sure to register before
December 1st which is the deadline for
our early bird
rate also if you're interested in being
a CED 24 presenter you can submit your
abstract the deadline for that is
November
18th also I invite you to follow us on
social media we're on Facebook Twitter
LinkedIn and Instagram just search for
CET
events also we would appreciate if you
would rate review And subscribe it
really helps us reach more
people all right that's it from us stay
safe stay healthy and be sure to join us
for the next canmed Coffee
[Music]
Talk