[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben emerald i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
speaking of the canmed conference have
you gotten your tickets yet for
canmed2022
if yes then i can't wait to see you out
in pasadena this may for another
fantastic event
and if not what are you waiting for head
over to
cammetevents.com now to get your tickets
at cam ed 2022 you will learn from the
leading minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
and if you want proof of that look no
further than our keynote presenters
representing our science focus area we
have dr ethan rousseau presenting about
cannabis and psychiatry
representing our cultivation focus area
we have dr seth crawford talking about
innovations in hemp breeding
grace bandong our safety keynote
presenter will talk about building a
comprehensive analytical testing program
and finally dr bonnie goldstein will
discuss cannabis medicine for children
as our medical keynote
those presentations alone are worth the
price of admission but please go to kim
at events dot com to see the full
schedule
and if you want a preview of what you
can expect at kmed 2022 check out our
camed archive which is a searchable
video library of all the past canmed
presentations and panels find that at
cammannevents.com
at this year's event we are also
offering a full day pre-conference
medical practicum taking place on may
3rd
the medical practicum is led by dr
bonnie goldstein dr dustin sulak dr
kevin spellman and eloise
thiessen each of them will share the
latest medical cannabis research
including information on dosing drug
interactions and different product types
they will also share their clinical
experience they have acquired treating
patients with medical cannabis this
really is a must attend event for any
health care professionals who are
interested in recommending medical
cannabis but it's not limited to those
folks
anyone who is interested in learning
more about medical cannabis can and
should join us for this event head over
to kim at events dot com slash practicum
to learn more
of course if you can't make it to canmed
2022 we have a number of resources to
help you stay engaged with our community
and enjoy some world-class educational
content
you are already off to a good start
listening to the canmed coffee talk
podcast be sure to hit that subscribe
button so new episodes download to your
device automatically
second we have the canmed archive that i
mentioned earlier it's a searchable
video library of all the past cammed
presentations and panels that you can
find at kmedevents.com
while you're at canmedevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts that's the
best way to make sure you are up to date
on all the latest canmed news and
special offers
fourth we have our canmed community
facebook group which is a great place to
share and discuss news and topics
related to cannabis science the link to
that group is in the show description
and finally you can follow us on social
media we're on instagram facebook
twitter and linkedin just search for cam
at events
this episode we talk with itsak kurek
ceo and co-founder of canformatics
itzhak and his team are measuring the
effectiveness of cannabis-based
medicines using biomarkers so far they
have identified dozens of cannabis
responsive biomarkers that can be used
to objectively quantify the
physiological impact of medical cannabis
treatment and provide a tool for
investigating the metabolic pathways
affected by medical cannabis and cbd
their pilot study looked at patients
with autism spectrum disorder and was
published in the journal of cannabis and
cannabinoid research in december
during our conversation we discussed
details of the asd pilot study the
benefits of using biomarkers versus
self-reporting
the bi-directional nature of cannabis
and the endocannabinoid system
the importance of whole plant full
spectrum medicine products
how the focus on thc potency stifles
medical research and the challenge of
doing proper medical cannabis research
with limited resources and available
funding before we get to the interview i
want to thank this episode sponsor
cannabis patient care
cannabis patient care magazine is an
educational resource for patients
medical professionals caregivers and
advocates on the latest research
benefits and treatment options medical
cannabis provides for a variety of
illnesses
learn more at cannapatientcare.com
okay without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with dr itzak
kurek
[Music]
good morning itzhak thanks for joining
us on the podcast
hi good morning thank you for inviting
me
for this podcast
yeah for sure
so
your team is taking a novel approach to
measuring the effectiveness of cannabis
treatment by using cannabis responsive
biomarkers and we discussed this topic a
little bit when bonnie goldstein was on
the podcast a little while back but now
we have you here to to dig into the
details a bit more so
maybe the best place to start is for you
to tell the audience about the autism
spectrum disorder pilot study that your
team has published
so
we
had an autism disorder pilot study in
which we
it was the first time that we as a proof
of concept
showed that we can detect a cannabis
responsive biomarkers in saliva of
children treated with medical cannabis
children with autism treated with
medical cannabis
the idea behind that is that we take
we identified metabolites that responds
to medical cannabis treatment
and
analyze the change of those molecules uh
and in that way we
we can see if those molecules change
towards any physiological range which we
determine
in a
in a group of
typical developing children
and that way we can quantify first time
the impact of medical cannabis treatment
excellent so
tell me a bit about how did you
determine which biomarkers were of
interest and how did you determine what
an optimal range would be
okay that's a great question and and and
to begin with we we are lacking of uh
medical
scientific data about cannabis uh
in the literature typically when we
start a biotech company we're looking at
solutions that exist at medical
scientific paper any medical information
that we can have on that topic in uh
cannabis will
very much beyond behind actually those
those
knowledge so we have to discover those
biomarkers first or
before discovering even prove that they
exist
so what we do we we use technology
called mass spectrometry
which analyze metabolite in saliva we
separate the metabolite again through a
a
liquid chromatograph that's the
technology and we have
we we we scan for about 1500 molecules
once we look so we look at those
molecules before medical cannabis
treatment and after medical cannabis
treatment and identified in that case in
15 kids we identified about
a 400 molecules that change
before and after
now we analyze those molecules the way
we analyze those molecule
we first of all determine that we are
interested in molecules that
exist at least
at nine children out of the 15 so at
least nine children has those molecules
and they change
now we want we we want to compare them
to as you mentioned to the physiological
range physiological range we determine
by a
typically developing children
with the same boys to girls ratio and
the same age as the
studied group
and we we
look at we average
the value of those molecules at that at
the typically developing group
and determine the standard deviation
and in a
rule of thumb
one standard deviation is the
physiological range
so we call it a z-score
and z-score mean how many standard
deviations
the
children with autism
away from the physiological range if you
if a child is above
a 2 or below 2 standard deviation that
means that his value is not in the
physiological range
if it's over four standard deviation
it's
significantly uh
in away from the physiological range and
we use our in-house algorithm to analyze
all the samples from all the children
and see which one of them were
far
before the medical cannabis treatment
and they got closer to the physiological
range
after the medical
cannabis treatment we choose after what
we call peak
at the time of each parent
reported that that the optimal time that
they see a reduced symptom
in these
children
so that way we identified about 65
uh new
cannabis of the first ever cannabis
responsive biomarkers that shows a move
towards the physiological range in
children with the autism
okay
so it sounds like so you started with
identifying the f
1500 biomarkers and then i narrowed that
down
to the 400 that are actually affected by
cannabis and then after
you know comparing the data from
from the children with autism and the
the other children you narrowed that
down even further to the 65 that are
um have some implication for
autism spectrum disorder and are
responsive to
cannabis treatment do i have that right
correct so so this is still temporary
because we need to increase the data
in one way to have a manageable number
of biomarkers but more important right
now we still don't know within those
biomarkers
which biomarkers are more important
and which one of them also which are the
biomarkers that associated with uh
symptoms or with phenotype of autism so
we still need to rank them and that
comes with
more with once we increase the study
we need to rank those biomarkers and
determine which are the most important
uh biomarkers
yeah so interesting
so one more thing
when we did the analysis one rule that
we had
was that uh each biomarker that we look
had has to exist in all the children
all the typically developing children so
we cannot
because sometimes you don't detect a
biomarker because of the level if the
levels are too low
you cannot detect the biomarkers but we
cannot do it with the control group
because we need to make sure that that
biomarkers is relevant
right that makes sense
so so you said
you kind of hinted into the next phase
of this study so so what is that what
where are you gonna where are you gonna
take this
so as a startup we are in the
fundraising it's always money and
funding
but the idea is that now we are
taking those biomarkers and the study
and increase it to about 200
people
it's gonna go beyond the six to nine
year old children we're gonna have
adults
a
more
variation with the medical treatment but
it's still under control of medical
cannabis treatment and 200
participants will allow us to narrow
down to about 20 biomarkers those 20
biomarkers
would be
in a way our first service once we rank
them and have those biomarkers also it's
important
for us to determine what is the
physiological range so it's going to be
and now there will be
more typically developing
participants to
make sure that the physiological range
could change between ages
gender
er sometimes even a
different ethnic groups so it all comes
with in i mean
the big picture it's how we're moving
toward precision medicine or
personalized medicine and and and
biomarkers are a part of this huge
a precision medicine model
so
we are
expanding it to that 200 and from there
once we have those values we can start
actually provide recommendation
for a patient that being treated with
the medical cannabis
either through a doctor or a
parents that do it without the doctors
we we can provide
how
the impact or how well the medical
cannabis treatment works the next step
after if we think about it probably
within once we have about a thousand
participants or between thousand to two
thousand participant
we can
actually start predicting
and i think that's the beauty of the
system it's once we can look at the
pre-dosing we look at saliva before
medical cannabis treatment and decide or
recommend a certain
product or treatment the idea of
conformatics is to
provide
a range of products so a
patient or families could use either
edible or tincture we we will provide
both recommendation
to a product
right so so the goal is that you sort of
do the saliva test you get a profile or
so almost like a fingerprint of your own
biomarkers and then based on that
connect with a product that's that's
going to work for you correct
correct exactly it's it's almost like i
mean the idea is
when we go to a doctor
and we do a blood work and we see uh
we see
a
i would say
glucose at blood blood glucose or we see
cholesterol and the doctor has a range
and based on that we know
if we need the treatment or we we don't
need the treatment and if we need the
treatment typically the doctor
knows
how much what type of treatment for a
certain
[Music]
range
a patient need
yeah and that's a good point too that i
i wanted to talk about so so you've
identified the 65 biomarkers that you
know have implications here and you know
you mentioned that we don't really know
which ones are the most important but
i'm i'm curious are you seeing that the
cannabis is
sort of at least bringing all of those
into some sort of homeostasis and i
guess that's that's the question i
wanted to ask was you know we've talked
to other medical professionals on the
podcast and they always talk about how
cannabis has this biphasic effect where
you know it can upregulate or down
regulate based on your you know whatever
your deficiency is um wondering if you
see that in your results as well
yes so i think the most interesting
biomarkers the first one or the most
significant that we found and that
basically with the algorithm
was a
a naa which is
n-actual aspartate aspartate
and that biomarkers
i think
in probably 12 or 13 kids out of the 15
change
but the change was a
four or five kids it significantly
decreased
at the same time we saw changes in about
four or three kids that it's actually
increase
and that's very rare
it's very rare because we typically
use kind of beta blockers we use
pharmaceutical treatment which are
reducing in general we know how to block
and reduce things it's very hard to
increase things and with cannabis we see
naturally
increases
of molecules or decrease
now when we
analyze this molecule actually in the
literature there is disagreement because
some
studies showed that molecule without
not in the context of cannabis but just
as a biomarker for
autism
some claim that it's extremely high and
some claims were that it's a low
we saw both in saliva none of those
study were in saliva we sold both in
saliva but we saw that the increase to
the physiological or decrease to the
physiological range happen from both
direction
wow
yes
yeah and that's that's interesting and
you know it's interesting you bring up
the difference between sort of candice
and
traditional pharmaceuticals one of the
other things that we commonly see with
traditional pharma is you know sort of
this idea of one compound one target
but
you know as we're seeing here where we
have multiple targets or at least we
think we do with these different
biomarkers and we have cannabis that's
affecting these multiple biomarkers it
has multiple compounds within it how how
do you start to unravel that whole
gordian knot of all different things
so i i like the quote from uh dimarzo at
1998 about
the endocannabinoid system and he said
he described it as relax eat sleep
forget and protect
and so we see the wide range of
activities or functions of the
endocannabinoid
system
so to begin with
treatment has a multiple effect
and we cannot take
and
not only autism most of the medical
condition that we're dealing with or
solving with medical cannabis are
typically complex medical conditions
and it
it's not so it's hard to
see that it's a one target one a
compound will will fix it
you need more than that it's not like a
single shot
treatment
and i think cannabis has this potential
because of this
large collection of active ingredient
we still need to know which active
ingredient do what and also what are the
dosages that we need to take
but that's the the beginning that's the
starting point
in our study with
i would say with being very careful with
the limited data that we have we could
see that there are
at least specific biomarkers or cannabis
responsive biomarkers that responds to
thc
a specific one that responds to cbd and
that's the majority that we saw a
biomarkers that response is specific to
cbd
and few that
responds to cbn
so
due to the small sample size and
not huge variation in the treatment we
could
only
at that point
see those
changes and as the data goes
increase we can get more and more
information about other a cannabinoid
the change but
definitely
it looks like full spectrum or
multi-component
will have better effect than a single uh
dose or a single active ingredient
right yeah so you you mentioned those
cannabinoids did you see any um
any indications that terpenes are
playing a role
no we could not get into that resolution
because i think
most
i think most of the
children
use terpenes
so
it was very hard to er
the reason we can
typically we can
see the differences is if we have a
changes
in product a or
in children we detect changes in
children that not using thc for example
so we can compare the samples and
identify
we could not get to that resolution yet
but but terpin i mean they should work
and they should help because first of
all we know aromatherapy helps
and we know terpenes have chemical
characteristics that help a
a
soluble solubilized membrane and
allowing
thc or cbd to enter in the cell
they also
working as anti-inflammatory
so
it's a treatment by itself i i think
it's just an add-on
and
to the cannabis
um
curious were there any patients that
were using
because you mentioned you know full
spectrum medicine were there any that
were using sort of isolated compounds or
isolates or was it pretty much across
the board uh full spectrum medicines
so some of them use isolate but it's a
combination so
you get at least three four
a
different
active ingredient
also often you see a
full spectrum
and then
add on another thc or cbd
uh but there were at least a i think
three or four active ingredient
one case there was only
one
active ingredient
uh
but again
we're talking about
autism which is it's a it's a
spectrum
so we cannot also it's a very it's a
complex medical condition and it is a
wide range of a
different type of autism
yeah that yeah that makes a lot of sense
so i'm curious about
i mean so
we've talked about how you know full
spectrum products are are the way to go
especially with these kind of
multi-faceted
uh disorders
um what about
on the cultivation side what sort of
diversity should we be encouraging
cultivators
be growing in order to address some of
these um these kind of multifaceted
conditions you have any thoughts on that
yes it's interesting i i started my
journey with cannabis i came from the
agricultural biotech world and i thought
that a
the way to go is to improve
the strain and and i came with ideas
that we bring from from that world how
to do it
and it seems to me that there is a race
for thc
right
and and and and the less for full
spectrum and once we start in a plant
once we start to
breathe towards thc
i think we're losing
all the other uh
active ingredient because the plant
becomes a machine
only for thc so all the energy all the
metabolic pathways everything goes
to thc and we believe that
especially now we don't know we don't
know which active ingredients are
working better for any medical condition
we just know that there are hundreds of
a
hundred of active molecules of
cannabinoids in the plant the capacity
of the plant to
synthesize uh those cannabinoids is huge
and we we're still talking iron
interestingly we we're still talking
about a plant that was already
domesticated probably for 10 000 years
so if we would go to the origin if we
can find the origin of those
plants they probably have even higher
capacity or more
diverse compounds to produce it we start
domesticating them to one direction so
even
we can think about medical conditions
that we're trying to
[Music]
use now
for like like
cancer i would say maybe it's a good
opportunity to go back and find
other
new
old molecules or molecules that exist in
the origin of those plants
so i think i i think that
yeah we're losing a huge advantage
because it's becoming more uh
therapeutics more
more uh
more like pharmaceutical and farmer
knows how to do a single molecule in
very high purity very reproducible and
probably cheaper than any other
industry
yeah absolutely and we've
we've had a guest on the podcast before
who
um
their company can actually train yeast
in order to create cannabinoids so
i mean with that in mind if if thc
really were the end-all be-all and that
were the holy grail then you could just
you know
feed the precursor to the yeast and have
it pump out thc but um i think i think
you're right there's a lot more
therapeutic potential in the plant with
all these other compounds
and i got to imagine one of the at least
one of the challenges in sorting that
out is the fact that
there are a number of compounds that
we're not even testing for right now and
so it could be that there is a lesser
cannabinoid in low concentrations
because we also see that as well that
low doses can be very effective
that could be doing a lot of the heavy
lifting here that we're we're just not
seeing yet
absolutely and and that's one of the
advantage that we uh
encourage uh producer processors to work
with us because we first of all we can
see with biomarkers one of the things we
can see the
full picture
while when we do a observation or
self-evaluation
it's really a portion it's just the tip
of the iceberg so
a person cannot
report how is inflammation or how we
feel is inflammation or or or
or a
dysfunctional mitochondria so so when we
when we
using cannabis responsive biomarkers
with full spectrum or different
combination or different extract we can
start see
what
compounds help
which of those biomarkers
and that allow us really to dissect the
the response and create or even
custom-made a product that help pain
help anxiety help
hail als all those products can help
a different or more specifically for a
medical condition that now
don't exist or
don't don't work or not optimized
yeah and that's a great point and i have
to imagine too that in a lot of cases
for patients it's difficult to
find consistency in their products as
well they'll they're finding they find a
product that works for them
they use it for a while then either you
know that product goes away or they have
different source material for for a new
batch and then um you know it doesn't
work as effectively where i think that
you know if we have more studies like
this to really identify what those
compounds are and how they're actually
moving the different biomarkers then you
know that's a real strong indication to
those cultivators and those producers
that you know these are the types of
products that we need
correct
but but that
again it brings us to
where we started it requires r d
and it requires a
cash or finance it requires funding
and
by the end of the day
we'll not always know how to produce
those molecules because we don't
understand how the plant does them so
some of the one of the reason that i can
see inconsistency is because we cannot
replicate the condition the condition
uh
to grow the plant
and to always get those uh
exact molecules and and some of them
what we call minor cannabinoid there is
a reason
why they're minor because the plant
doesn't make enough uh whatever it makes
it right now for those conditions is
good
and so we need to learn also it needs to
come also from the the plant side and
understanding
how to grow plants or how to stress the
plants these are stress molecules that
produce when the plant is stressed so
how to stress the plant
in order to get those
a
cannabinoid out and to get
consistency
in those minor
well yeah no i hadn't
i hadn't thought of that that
that there might be um certain stresses
or certain uh things that we can we can
do to the plant to kind of coax its
production of these minor cannabinoids
that's
interesting
yes i mean we have to remember the the
cannabinoids the
plant doesn't make it for us
it makes it to deal with the
uv
or it makes a deal it deals with it
deals with the
insect uh
sometimes pollination
uh it depends on the plant and depend on
the
on the molecule but there are needs uh
during stress uh sometimes it's drought
uh
all kind of
plants don't work so when they're
exposed to to stress
whatever they have in their
in their arsenal that's what they can
fight with so that's why the the genome
is big
and and they create much more many more
a secondary metabolite like cannabinoid
so and we don't know and and that's a
basic science it
that we don't have
and companies uh
typically don't do it it comes from the
academia but right now there is no
funding
for this type of studies
yeah that's the unfortunate place we are
right with the um
with the legal framework the way it is
it's really kind of
hamstringing us on on what we can we can
find out about this plant but you know
thankfully there's there's folks like
like you and others who are attending
canmed who who are doing the work
um and sharing their their findings and
hopefully we can all advance this
together um
and make the best of the situation that
we have
it's uh yeah and that's why uh
the way we can informatics
does it we publish and we publish the
first paper about the cannabis
responsive biomarkers should be pretty
soon i hope a second paper coming
uh which we use a little bit of
we use a different
separation method and identify another a
group of cannabis responsive biomarkers
mainly from a
from lipid
and we're going to do it with any
medical condition that we're working uh
will try to publish as much as possible
because i think it's between companies
and producer processors right now and
in the whole industry
uh generate the knowledge uh
and
try to share it because everybody's
going to benefit from that
i
i agree with you and i guess that's a
good segue if people want to learn more
about the work that you all are doing or
if there's a way to um either sign up
for updates or follow you on social
media anything like that please uh plug
away now and um i'll put links to
uh all those resources in the show
description as well so people can easily
find them
this is your queue for informatics.com
oh yeah and in our case in our case it's
obviously conformatics.com
uh
the there is a link for paper and a also
a short video about the technology
and a
a subscription that we are
keep announcing our
findings so these are all
kenfomatics.com
excellent those are great resources
all right uh i want to thank you again
it'sak for joining us on the podcast um
and i look forward to meeting you and
the team out at canmed uh this may
thank you very much
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr itsak kurek
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsor cannabis
patient care magazine
our next episode drops march 30th that's
two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out the
canmed archive and join the canmed
community facebook group to stay
connected with us
of course you can also stay in touch
with us on social media on facebook
instagram linkedin and twitter just
search for candid events
sign up for email alerts on cam at
events.com to stay up to date with all
the latest news and please be sure to
rate review and subscribe on your
favorite podcast app doing so helps us
reach more listeners
i do sincerely hope to see all of you
out in pasadena this spring but until
then stay safe stay healthy and please
join us for the next canbed coffee talk
[Music]
you