good afternoon or I might even say good
evening I'd like to thank Doug and and
Bonnie goldstein and the organizers of
the conference for inviting me to
moderate I'd also like to thank the
remarkable panel that has agreed to
share their knowledge with us today I'd
only tired cardiologist who first became
interested in cannabinoid oncology
when I saw Mara Gordon show brain scans
from patients with brain tumors who were
treated with cannabis and had
well-documented shrinkage of the tumors
when I saw those images I knew that's
what I wanted to do Mar was kind enough
to teach me her method for approaching
patients with tumors
I saw many patients many patients were
able to shrink their tumors and many
were able to achieve no evidence of
disease however I saw far too many
patients who failed to respond to
cannabinoid antineoplastic therapy about
a year ago dr. Betty Mary gave a talk to
the Society of cannabis clinicians and
this presentation stimulated me to
reassess the therapeutic cannabinoid
protocols that I had been using I'm
gonna can I mention your names down and
just sort of wave your hand to introduce
yourself when I say your name I thought
what you correct so I'm afraid when I
was asked to moderate this panel and
select the panelists I thought that we
would learn the most by merging the
intellectual capital of the best
researchers dr. Mary dr. Sanchez dr.
Russo and
nation's doctors herdin rather &amp;
Goldstein an aspect of dr. Murray's work
also dealt with the use of various
solvents and so I wanted Dustin Mahon
the CEO and chief executive chief
science officer of Indo can alabs in
Colorado to show us extraction results
of several chemo VARs with multiple
solvents laboratory work that we have
available in this country we don't have
mass spectrograph since dr. mary has as
at his disposal dr. Goldstein and dr.
Hagen rather will share their experience
first hopefully speak to their failures
as well as their successes in using
cannabinoids in the treatment of cancer
then and then mr. Mahan will show us
some comparisons of various cultivars
and multiple solvents with that
background we will then begin asking the
full panel the questions detailed in the
panel description I hope you have all
those you have those at your disposal
now otherwise I'll be reading them as we
go and and the objective of the panel is
to learn how we can better apply
preclinical research to improve patient
outcomes so with that if if you would
start please dr. goldstein
good evening everybody
so I'm gonna talk about my experience
with mostly pediatric patients that I
treat with cannabinoid cannabinoids for
cancer
remember cancer is a term that we use
that encompasses a whole bunch of
different diseases and as dr. Sanchez
and dr. Murray's research shows that we
can have breast cancer we can have colon
cancer but there's still subtypes and
they may not respond the same way so
it's a it's a very difficult complex
question when you're approaching
patients that come into your office and
are asking for help a few of the
concerns with Pediatrics is that they
are same chemotherapies are being
recycled over the years of very few new
treatments for these kids also
unfortunately pediatric cancer only
receives about four percent of all
cancer research money so there is 96
percent of the cancer research money
goes to adult cancers and so that's also
kind of hindering research I will tell
you that also what I'm finding is that
when parents come in with their children
one of the biggest concerns is my child
may survive but what is the quality of
my child's life going to be down the
future is my child going to get a
secondary malignancy from radiation is
my child going to have cognitive
impairment from chemotherapy and
radiation is my child going to have
cardiac disease and I was preparing for
this panel I actually read about a
gentleman who's doing research at
University Hospital in San Antonio who
he himself is in his forties and he is a
cancer survivor and he is in his 40s had
has had severe repercussions from the
chemotherapy he's had a cardiac arrest
he's had strokes and so he is actually
studying what chemo does to those who
survive from childhood cancers and he
says it accelerates the aging process
and if you've seen some research in the
last couple years about cannabis we know
that it can help actually kind of
reverse aging as well so when I have a
patient that comes in with cancer of
course I go through a history physical
exam I talk about with the family what
their goals are with cannabis therapy
for some of them it is just symptomatic
treatment because they're on a protocol
that may give them very good survival
some of them want to add cannabis as a
adjunct antineoplastic agent and so I
often discuss both treatments with the
families many of them do opt even
they start with symptomatic treatment
many of them as they see that their
child's responding really well then they
come back and say you know what we want
to up the dose we want to start giving
our child more cannabis to see if we can
try to kill it increase the chances that
our child's going to survive this with
children I use all the cannabinoids we
were there obviously the research that
dr. Mary and dr. Sanchez are doing is
very helpful but still to this day we
don't know what combinations are going
to kill which cancers so as we're going
to discuss I think other panelists are
gonna probably say the same thing I have
found that combination treatment is
clearly the way to go I usually use five
different cannabinoids and once I heard
me speak yesterday so CBD THC THC a CBD
a and C B G I try to use as many
different preparations and also from
different companies because then I can
be sure that they're probably going to
be grown a little bit differently
they're going to hopefully cover a lot
of the different compounds right now I
kind of look at this as you know
somebody comes into a hospital who's
really sick and you do not know what
let's say they know they have an
infection but you don't know what they
have he may send a culture and you cover
them with what we call broad-spectrum
antibiotics till you can narrow down
what's going to work and that's kind of
how I approach this broad spectrum using
multiple different compounds to try to
see what will work and I start low dose
and we titrate up of course always
concerned about side effects if there's
going to be any I will tell you children
because I have taken care of adults with
cancer too children tolerate
cannabinoids way better than adults they
have they don't drive a car they don't
go to work they don't have to make
dinner so they kind of go with the flow
many of them
I will tell you the parents will tell me
there is absolutely no side effect and
their child goes from being sick on
chemo or side effects of radiation I
have one patient it went down from about
90 pounds down to 57 pounds post
radiation and she's gained it all back
just from adding cannabis in so children
really tolerate cannabis well and
in my experience I am seeing just over
the last few years that more and more
patients or parents are bringing their
children to me earlier in treatment
rather than waiting until they've been
told that there's no other treatment
many of them want to help their child
get the but of course the best results
so that's all I have to say I don't know
if there's anything that you want to add
Joe you'll have a chance to oh to weigh
in later okay just one other thing Joe
did ask me to talk about like possibly
the patients that don't respond so
sometimes people get to my office so
late like unfortunately had a child show
up on a Wednesday and the child died
Friday that's obviously not enough time
to be able to intervene although the
family didn't even have time to get oil
I've had other patients come in who
clearly it's towards the end and I don't
think that it's going to reverse
anything but certainly quality of life
at the end of life so that the child's
out of pain may be eating a little bit
baby boy playful certainly makes a
difference for these families there are
a few cancers that have I've not got
good results with DIPG if you've heard
of that it's a very rare brain tumor
unfortunately we have not gotten very
good success one of patients who have
leukemia seem to respond really well so
of course it also depends on the kind of
cancer in terms of response and also
what at what stage they are when they
get to me thank you
well I wanted to first thank the or the
organization for the opportunity to
participate it's wonderful to get
together with our colleagues from around
the world and meet new folks in the
field I've been a cannabis doc for a
long time I started my career about 40
years ago on a commune in Tennessee
learning about cannabis as medicine but
cancer wasn't part of that at that time
wasn't until I opened my office about 20
years ago up in Sebastopol California
that I began to see cannabis cancer
patients on a regular basis at that
point there are somewhere in the range
of 8 to 10 percent of my patient
population came with cancer and since
that time really in the last three years
this demographic has changed drastically
to where now they're about 30 to 40
percent of the patients that come in to
see me are coming because of cancer and
mostly asking for treatment that may
mitigate may help in the in slowing the
progression of these tumors that's a
huge difference and I think those of you
are are going to see the same kind of
demographic in your practices I have
seen some amazing things over the years
and some of the first ones were smoking
a small amount of cannabis on a daily
basis to see a Glee a glioblastoma never
recur for eight years for nine years I
might add before that point that the
patient stopped smoking cannabis and he
had a full recurrence of the tumor
within a year I've also seen a
neuroblastoma disappear after UCSF had
given up on him and they sent him home
and said comfort care we don't have
anything more to offer and then he too
as a nine-year-old began to smoke a
little bit of cannabis for pain relief
and within a couple years the tumor had
disappeared malignant melanoma is
another case where I've seen them
disappear
these tumors disappear in multiple
patients over a period of time and since
these other tumors had a carcinoma other
people with glioblastoma and really
multiple tumors have done well but
saying that I also have to say the
majority of patients with cancer don't
see this kind of response of course I'm
not controlling for either the cannabis
or for the
treatment protocol I might advise a
treatment protocol but I have no idea
what they're gonna do once they go out
into the back to home and try to find
these products so approaching a patient
with cancer I think is very important to
just be and as you know the ethical
approach is to say look I expect that
we're going to get treatment benefits in
terms of symptomatic cures or
symptomatic relief you're going to have
a better appetite you're gonna have some
pain control you're gonna sleep better
your mood is going to be better the
anxiety is going to go down nausea and
vomiting are going to be controlled we
can expect that in most all patients who
use cannabis at all but whether or not a
tumor is going to regress that's a whole
other thing and you know it's looking at
the work of dr. Sanchez and dr. Mary and
others before who have really led us to
say well you know it was McCallister's
work of seven years ago eight years ago
who said hey THC and CBD work together
better there's a synergy of these
molecules so this has led us along the
way to being directing patients to some
at least hope that we're gonna find a
combination of cannabis cannabinoids
that that may work best so at the least
I want symptomatic relief at the most we
may get lucky and be able to treat a
cancer really effectively and slow the
progression or in a rare case see a
tumor disappear but for those patients
that come to me and they're already
chronic cannabis smokers I say look you
know it doesn't really look good because
this tumor has developed in in the face
of a regular use of cannabis and we can
certainly try high-dose therapy and we
often do that so that's getting up into
these gram quantities that have kind of
gotten known as the Simpson Simpson oil
and that protocol of taking a large
amount of cannabinoids
I can't attest to any results for that
but people are at least trying it
we also are still faced with the issue
of people come in and say what is the
best strain for me to treat this cancer
and we simply do not have that
information yet
we're close as we can feel the research
coming I know people are gonna be
looking for THC and CBD and CBD and from
this point on they may also be looking
for compound 3 3 118 B you know that
they didn't say the right one right
[Laughter]
okay I'll scratch that out of my notes
so method of administration I think is
very interesting because we do know that
a puff on cannabis has a very high blood
level for a short period of time and it
was the great work of Donald tashkin
sitting in the front row who taught us
that yes this is in it does provide some
injuries some irritation to the lung in
the Airways but we're not going to be
causing COPD and emphysema and
significant alterations in the pulmonary
function studies so you know I don't
discourage people from smoked or
vaporized cannabis as a method of
administration otherwise if we're going
to be treating cannabis treating with
cannabis we tend to look to the to the
oral forms in order to get the big doses
that we think might be necessary again
some of these cases that did so well
earlier 15 years ago in my career as a
cannabis specialist were very small
amounts in many cases and so I don't
know if we're way over acting to be
giving graham quantities of cannabinoids
we may be but there seems to be
information that we don't really fully
understand yet and that would be markers
of the tumors that would give us some
clues as to what tumors are going to
respond best to what cannabinoid
profiles dosing in frequency this is
tailored to meet the patient's needs it
really has to do with what kind of tumor
we're doing dealing with if it's a
slow-growing tumor and they just want to
come in and have an idea as to what to
do it may be a small dose of
cannabinoids at bedtime that's
sufficient if we want to ramp it up we
might give a big dose of of CBD in the
daytime even twice in the day the
morning in the afternoon and have a more
sustained blood level so now you can get
up into hundreds of milligram quantities
of CBD rich full plant extract cannabis
oils if they
tolerated the THC in their product then
fine I think it's probably a good idea
until we learn better but for a bedtime
dose I'm really encouraging people to
use a combination of THC and the other
cannabinoids acid cannabinoids I think
are certainly a value too and I do talk
about the green green cannabis as well
if they have friends that are growing
put those buds in a blender and and have
them on a daily basis if they possibly
can the duration of action is different
because of these p450 cytochromes that
are a little different from patient to
patient some people are gonna probably
be adequate with a dose a day and others
may need three doses a day in order to
optimize or maximize their cannabinoid
therapy so I'm excited to be in the
field I do the best that I can and I'm
really relying on these colleagues of
mine in this field to guide us as to
what might be best in the future and
it's one thing to grow them in a lab and
kill cells in a laboratory on a petri
dish and quite another to be able to do
it in vivo in people that are dealing
with these cancers so that's more or
less the way I'm approaching cannabis
therapy of cancers and I'll welcome the
opportunity to answer questions if they
come along thank you thank you my name
is Dustin Mahan I'm the president CEO
and CFO of ICI labs in Denver Colorado
last two years I was out in the crowd
with you guys watching these great minds
up here I mean I'm so humbled right and
how did he apply here with this panel
that I words can't say enough of how
thankful I am to dr. Joe and all the
people that can met here cannabis has
saved my life and it has fascinated me
ever since I jumped into the to
understanding it I did a quick
experiment here to try to help help the
panelists and understand a little bit
more
go gotta go back
which way am i okay so we are extraction
experts at Colorado in Colorado we use
hydrocarbon extraction as methanol
extraction I did use a lab white label
to do some co2 extractions for me here
so there's still much more research that
needs to be done from the cannabis plant
on what things do what here but we
wanted to focus specifically on the
cannabinoids and terpenoids cannabinoids
and turkeys have shown largely they have
a significant impact on cancer cells
there are far too many variables right
now to validate really a best
classification for solvents however this
experiment will provide information on
the best solvent for specific
applications like total cannabinoid
potencies or efficiencies right now we
have an inability to test all of the
great things that my friend here gets to
test with cannabinoids and turkeys but
it leaves us with probably more
questions and we have answers but this
is as far as we've gotten we really need
a lot more research so the few things
that we look for out of the cannabinoid
extraction or from extraction of
cannabinoid plant is going to be
efficiencies so how much of the
cannabinoids and the terpenes did we
pull out of the plant material as well
as potencies so how pure is the
concentrate that we get out of it
the other thing that I like to look at
is the decarboxylation rates you know
the plant grows in their raw acidic
cannabinoids and certain extraction
techniques actually will activate those
cannabinoids so the different variables
that I tried to accomplish here we're
gonna be using a quick wash versus a
soak which is going to be plant material
on a quick wash is contacted and very
minimal exposure time trying to increase
the period ease but you're gonna
sacrifice some efficiencies versus
soaking the plant material where you're
contacting with the solvent for
prolonged periods of time trying to pull
as much of the cannabinoids and
Terrapins out of the plant material but
understanding that you'll probably pull
some
impurities as well so we took two
different chemo VARs of cannabis we took
the high THC strain and a high CBD
strain here we ran them through several
different methodologies of salt of quick
wash and soak with five different
solvents and we had the cannabinoids and
terpenoids tested on the starting plant
material the concentrate as well as the
ending plant material so we used propane
and butane we used ethanol and then we
did a subcritical and a supercritical
co2 extraction one of the major
questions that I get is how much solvent
is left over every state in the that's
legalized to set some sort of residual
solvent level even the United States
pharmacopoeia set a residual solvent
level that they could have in
pharmaceuticals however I'm a huge fan
of leaving that you should really not
have any residual solvents left over in
your product and I have proven and it is
possible to remove the solvents from all
the different methodologies that I've
shown here so it's a quick you know test
that we get in Colorado from rm3 a lot
of n B's up there I could flood your
inbox with n DS but I think we can all
agree that it's it's very possible to
get all your solvent out of there
so the different cultivars I used the
first one this is my THC strain this is
our alien rock candy somewhere in about
6% terpene content 22% cannabinoid
content to your cannabinoid test from
the alien rock candy and then my
spectrum strain spectrum is a very high
CBD strain we grow it out to a little
over the point 3 percent THC mark but
it's used heavily in Colorado as a hemp
strain so our M 3 distant testing for us
and the things that we were able to
figure out well we wanted to look at
what solvent extracts Tobel total
cannabinoids with the highest potency
here so on the THC heavy strain we found
that supercritical co2 actually tested
at the highest purity at eighty five
point three three percent propane quick
wash which is you know
minimal soak time which makes sense we
hit eighty three point eight one percent
and the butane quick wash at eighty
three point five nine percent on the CBD
strain your propane and your
supercritical flipped but they're pretty
negligible in in potencies they're at
eighty one point eight and eighty one
point seven six and then the propane so
came in eighty one point zero one so the
way I looked at for highest efficiency
isn't necessarily how many grams you
pulled out of there but how many
milligrams that you pulled out of there
so multiplying your grams by your
potencies there and on their heavy THC
stream we found that the butane quick
wash came in at the the highest
efficiency and ethanol soak right behind
that which again with in point one
percent so pretty negligible and the
propane quick wash came in right after
that on the CBD strain we had a really
really great extraction with the ethanol
soaked supercritical co2 came in after
that and then a butane quick wash as far
as terpenes go propane quick wash one
out on both sides there the ethanol we
had a soak for THC and a quick wash for
the CBD and then the ethanol quick wash
again for THC and a butane quick wash
for the CBD and then as far as the
extraction efficiencies propane again
looking really good for your terpenes
coming in ethanol and butane right
behind that so the only thing that I
really recognize in the testing for
decarboxylation rates was that it was
the co2 process that tended to
decarboxylase the plant material now I
understand there is specific ways that
you can run your machines we ran these
on a very commercial very standard
supercritical subcritical and we saw
that supercritical across-the-board
decarboxylase both THC and CBD about 60%
the interesting thing though on the
subcritical run is that your THC in your
spectrum THC jumped about 20% and the
CBD jumped 40% however the
or the THC in the CBD strain jumped 40
percent but the CBD in that spectrum
strain only jumped 2 percent so i
theorize that it's actually the
different pressures that are extracting
in that subcritical the difference
between subcritical and supercritical
being the pressures that our subcritical
hit high enough just to activate the THC
but not enough to activate the CBD so is
there really a best solvent I think what
we have shown is that each solvent has a
unique ability to do something different
than its counterpart we have shown that
there are some better than others in
specific categories but and we've also
shown that there are far more variables
and extraction that are still to be
found out I think that the fact that
every body and every cancer is unique
that a combination approach is
absolutely necessary and far more
research is needed thank you yeah I
should have told you can we turn the
screen off for now so so with that
background what I'd like to do is is is
is ask some questions of the panel dr.
Hogan rather alluded to how to sum the
ratio of THC to CBD how do we know when
when to give more THC are there
situations where we want to give more
CBD than then THC how do we learn if if
how do we decide how much of each
cannabinoid to use anybody
in a situation like that if I were asked
that question by a patient I would try
to go to the literature and see what
Christina or daddy or Manuel Guzman has
done previously that indicated that
there was a preference for a particular
cap cannabinoid or whether there
actually had been combinations tried
before additionally I have the benefit
of having a large network of friends
that I can ask about this kind of thing
I would additionally look for any
synergies that might be present in the
turpenoid literature but as we've seen
sometimes it's not not so clear but
first thing is to see what has been done
or what even might have been known
historically and what history tells us
that a lot of treatments of tumors in
the past were with what appeared to be
raw cannabis whether it would have been
CBD a predominant or THC a dominant and
as we find out in the last year from
another group in Spain Nadal at all that
THC a is a peep or gamma agonist so
that's a nuclear receptor that affects
gene transcription and may have a very
prominent role in treatment of cancer
but that still needs to be investigated
further thank you why I might might add
that one of the techniques that I have
been attracted to is that that we know
from from dr. Sean McCallister's work
that CBD down regulates the ID one gene
and the ID one gene is associated with
tumor growth and and metastasis so if
there's if if if searching the
literature shows that a particular tumor
routinely our level of ID one be a
good indication I spawned for me your
mics breaking I know how often how how
how often should the THC be taken in my
experience it's easy to give the
majority of the THC at bedtime because
the patient can sleep through the psycho
activity but dr. Goldstein referred me
to an article of patient with with
lymphoblastic leukemia who expressed
blast cells that were not curtailed when
the THC was given twice daily but when
it was given every eight hours the the
blast cells fell so so I would like to
ask the question of the panel how often
should we give the THC and when I can
tell you what I do so for most of my
patients again with children it's a
little bit easier because they're
they're usually not losing function that
most of us would not want to give up by
driving a car you know functioning if
the family expresses to me that they
want their child to still go to school
and to function well at school I will
have them take THC in the afternoon when
they get home from school and then in
the evenings if it's a child who's not
going to school which as you know if
they have cancer many of them are not
attending school I usually recommend THC
every eight hours along with the other
oil CBD and the raw cannabinoids and now
I've added in CBG as well I'm probably
and I tell people this I'm aggressive
and I often over treat but I'm terrified
to under treat to be perfectly honest
because again children tolerate
cannabinoids very well and I find that
really the only downside is on is the
cost at most families if we're getting
somewhere with with the cannabinoid
treatment I don't if we actually can get
to a point where the cancer is gone we
can back up and go to more affordable
doses so again much of it if they're
very small it doesn't cost that much to
give a fair at high dose but in general
in children again THC I often recommend
that every eight hours we don't have a
lot of clinical really very few clinical
trials
to really hang our hat on how long the
cannabinoids are going to hang around in
any particular person with Jeff's
experience with patients just smoking
and getting results certainly we know
that when you inhale it's not doesn't
last in your body a very long and
certainly not at high doses so it
certainly has to do a lot with the
sensitivity of the tumors as well to
exactly what they're taking I would
concur with dr. goldstein
if I can get a patient to take a THC CBD
balanced medication in three times a day
I'll encourage them to do that if it
doesn't work into their life plans if
they're going to pick up the kids at
2:00 in the afternoon then take the CBD
in the morning and reserve this THC for
later in the day so I I do encourage
that often right from the start I in
California under the under the laws that
we have today
I tell people right from the get-go you
you need to start thinking about growing
your own medicine the cost of these
molecules have gotten so expensive
maminta are gonna be taking a dropper of
dropper full of cannabinoids three times
a day and I say no you're we're talking
about a bottle of an ounce bottle of
cannabinoids a couple times
cost is absolutely prohibitive in this
kind of dosing so I really encourage
people to talk to friends and consider
growing their own medicine again
multiple cultivars I think are very
important and the opportunity again to
get acid cannabinoids into the mix I
think also is really valuable thank you
so I want to say something maybe to be
the bad boy on this panel we don't know
that's the truth okay so the answers
here was how to give cannabis that the
patient will be comfortable we're not
treating a patient how to patient to be
comfortable we want to kill the cancer
so when a physician give chemotherapy is
not an saying if you can drive or not
drive
we don't know every answer will be good
as the other answer we don't we don't
know what the patient needs to get we
don't know if it's accumulating the
tumor so in the mice I can tell you that
they see accumulation of cannabinoid in
the tumors it's like stuck there is it
this true for patients do we need THC in
the evening do we know it CBD in the
morning the truth that we don't know so
every answer will be as good as the
other answer Kristine Sanchez and me
like the scientists we know that we cure
every types of cancer in minds so it's
not true for people so there is a huge
gap between killing cells in the plate
killing tumors in the mice and treating
a person's and the correlation so far
that even if we learn about it in the
mice we won't know how to treat the
patient before we'll do real clinical
trials checking this kind of thing so
the truth in all these conferences
people are coming and asking what we
need to give the patient first of all we
don't know really that it's working we
are assuming we hoping and even if we
know we don't know what to give them
that's the truth that we can't run
around it thank you
[Applause]
how did
so I have another slide I have the slide
from your from your most recent paper in
nature and and and what you showed which
which is impressive and and so important
and I'm so thankful that we have this
that you compared you compared 36
cultivars versus 94 cannabinoids and you
can see from from this top part of of
the other of the chart that that there
are different cannabinoids in different
cultivars and they're all over the place
and
and also you I stole this slide from
your from your patients out of time
presentation in May and this this shows
that this shows six different different
solvents and this this this confirms
what what
Dustin found so the the solvents here
the this the first six down here are the
same as the six across the top and here
are two cultivars extracted with six
different solvents and what we can see
is for example if we're looking for for
CBC bgv
we're not going to get it in this
cultivar with any any solvent but if we
take a cultivar that has that has that
cannabinoid we can extract it with with
only butane and carbon dioxide not with
ethanol which which many of the fun
extracts are made with so so for for me
it's pointing in the direction of making
our medicine with multiple cultivars
extracted with multiple solvents in
order to get all the cannabinoids now
dr. Mary showed us in his presentation
this afternoon that there were a few key
compounds that were necessary to kill
the cancer so I'm wondering if you would
comment on the the
benefits or potential benefits or lack
of benefit of of making these
combinations of multiple cultivars and
multiple solvents yeah I'd like to take
that one initially for me it's easy
there are only two possibilities ethanol
or co2
I have little confidence and the ability
to totally purge of these other solvents
many of which are toxic additionally
there are a lot of people out in public
that think that they can do a home
extraction with butane and they blow
themselves up in the process is the
story I told on Monday that the safe
ones are ethanol and co2 extraction
obviously for the latter you need some
very technical equipment but I I just
don't see the place for the others
myself ethanol is just as flammable and
I've seen very big fires for methanol
just throw that out there yeah I don't
recommend the patients do this at all
but I can add something I completely
agree with Ethan and we have to keep in
mind that we are talking about patients
that take this medicine on a daily basis
several times a day doing very prolonged
periods of time so if you have a tiny
little bit of something that is below
detection limits in your sophisticated
equipment but if you accumulate that a
little bit of something three times a
day every day for months for years that
tiny little bit becomes something
important so I could be with you so I
just want to say it for my defense first
of all it's like hitting the experts I
don't remember these figures it's a long
time ago but second this is academic
work and this is not coming to treat any
patients and for sure that there are
solvent there which are poisoned just to
showing the different solvent create
different extracts it doesn't I don't
want nobody to treat with these solvents
patients
and I think what Christian and then like
the people here said it's extremely
important when you're doing extract you
need to think about the solvent what is
left with the patient and regarding your
questions so when you are mixing
different cultivars you diluting
compounds so it's true that you have
higher variability but you're diluting
the compounds and again I don't have the
answer what is good and bad to the
patient I just know what is the action
that we are doing and what is the result
and I think the physicians here have
much much more experience how to treat
the patient sobani and we don't we were
far away from knowing you know in this
we just showing the complexity and how
how much we don't know but we have good
answers I guess so so dr. Lisa would you
would you think that that combining co2
and alcohol extracts might provide
better patient outcomes possibly but
again you know I'd want to see some
evidence a rationale behind combining to
get those specific components so I say I
want to say something about fire and an
ethanol when I started to do extraction
I look to to find a method in PubMed
it's usually where scientists look for
evidence and there was no good way to do
the ethanol extraction so I went to
YouTube's
first of all I I thought that I'm the
first one there doing extra ethanol
expert extraction without the two-second
the guy said the most important thing
when you're doing the extraction don't
smoke
thank you
and wondered since you used ether in
your lab did anybody go to sleep I used
ether yes
the first solvent it's it's may explain
why this student was very slow so so one
of the one of the things that intrigued
me from from dr. Sanchez's recent paper
was the the lack of emphasis efficacy in
in adding back the terpenes now she she
added back five terpenes two of those in
in dr. Russo's publication on on
antineoplastic terpenes only two of the
five were designated as as
antineoplastic little rule and alpha
humulin so what that triggered in my
mind is when we talk about the entourage
I've always thought of the entourage
being the terpenes but I'm wondering if
it's not as much or more so the minor
cannabinoids that make up the full
entourage and and and what I was
thinking about in the combining the the
extractions from multiple cultivars and
and with multiple solvents was enhancing
the entourage if you had compounds that
were not present in one cultivar you
could bring them into play and and and
and even though it's it's diluted if you
standardize for THC and CBD its diluted
but but maybe maybe in that that slide
that the last presentation the small
amount of CB GA was what made the
difference and maybe it doesn't take
very much maybe it's a catalyst rather
than a
a true act activator of anyway I
appreciate your comments on that you yes
please sure it's an intriguing question
one of the things I noted when I read
Cristina's paper from her group was that
there was no detected limonene limonene
e actually has had observed activity at
least in vitro and in breast cancer
there was a study done in humans of
high-dose limonene in breast cancer
unfortunately it didn't read out and my
impression of that was while they forgot
the cannabinoids so yeah certainly when
I thought it did relate to minor
cannabinoids and again given what
Cristina said in relation to my question
I'm really I have a strong hunch at this
point that THC a is responsible for the
difference from THC alone so I want to
comment about the terpenes I think we
all think the terpenes are important I'm
speaking by myself so I think the
terpenes are important but I know even
mine what are you thinking and I'm quite
disappointing so one of the first thing
that we're doing in the lab when we see
phenomenon would cut the terpenes out to
see if it's affected and except for
sleep disorders that we have a mice
model for sleep disorders that we do see
the terpenes important in epilepsy in
the cancer models in the other models I
didn't find that they are important so
every time that we cut them out it
doesn't affect the phenomena which is
extremely disappointing for me but these
are the results for now so again except
sleep disorder I didn't find anything
that they were in the mice model and
then with the cell model that there
Turpin's was very effective so that's
the results
so so a quick question yes him a
legitimate source of CBD in
antineoplastic protocols I didn't but I
didn't get the question I want to know
if we can use him it's very difficult
for some patients in Europe to get to
get high CBD cultivars for their
medicine it's virtually impossible I do
some consults from Europe or worth
patients in Europe it's also difficult
in many areas in the United States to
get ac/dc and and and other high CBD
cultivars and I'm wondering but but hemp
seems to be much more available and and
I've looked at some of the the lab work
on on the lab analyses of hemp extracts
and they there are some that do have a
rich terpene profile and have
substantial amounts of CBD and I'm
wondering if that is a a potential
source of CBD maybe however I think
they're going to spend a fortune in the
bargain given the kinds of prices I've
seen you know a lot of this is a
byproduct of prohibition let's be clear
you know the there are better ways a
dedicated what we'd call drug keema var
that's rich in in CBD is likely going to
be preferable plus with a hemp extract
so-called generally we're not talking
about any significant amount of THC and
for most tumors that's a necessary
component right right
I'm just thinking about the the the CBD
component what I've seen from a lot of
CVD extracts is that in a raw CBD
extract and ethanol extract if you will
is that you can see THC get into the 3
to 5 percent range on that which for
some patients I've seen some really good
responses to that one with some of my
cancers but like you say it's still kind
of out there I would like to have a lot
more THC but for those people that don't
have access to anything better I can't
see the harm and I think it could
actually help and and and so a follow-up
question on that is we've heard a lot of
talk about CB g + CB GA at this
conference and it looks like it is
turning out to be a useful cannabinoid
that we ought to include in our
antineoplastic protocols and would help
be a good source of CB g years and CB g
a wave one strain in the lab that have
17% CB gene without tips in CBD almost
at all like 0.2 CB t 0.4 CB g yes THC
and this is a very potent strain so you
see that there are cancer that being
affected by that there is in the
epilepsy model it's affecting like there
is many models affected then again I
don't know if it's just CPG but for sure
this strain is very very potent strained
for many things and I believe that CB
G's as potent as tits in CBD it's
usually not in high percentage but I
guess again my belief that T it's in CBD
is a little bit covering for the others
but if you eliminate them there will be
other cannabinoids with high affinity to
the receptors and they can be very
potent if they will be in the percentage
of the states in CBD in
as we and we usually see them so it
might be that there are other what we
call minor cannabinoid that if there
will be in high percentage have higher
affinity to the receptor so we call it
affinity of an avidity how much it's
binding the receptors and we see that
there is minor cannabinoid with very
strong activity on the receptors and
just amount I believe that in the
cultivars and then they think that
people are doing we will find more and
more strains that have different
cannabinoids that are expressed there is
already like THC v strain with 10 and 11
percent of THC v which is extremely
psychoactive people think that that just
eight sees psychoactive to achieve is
also very psychoactive but we will see
more and more cultivars with different
cannabinoid expression and different
effects I already I already see that
people think that they can send
everything to my lab in FedEx and they
are right so I see a lot of things I've
because of my work with children with
autism and families of course searching
for products that might help their
children I've learned about a couple of
CBG actually three CBG products
available here in california two of them
are very very low THC so can be sold
across state lines is kind of under the
hemp but we've gotten them tested at
multiple labs and they one runs about
50% CBG with about 2% CBD and I can't
remember what the THC it was very very
low and one of the other ones I'm
waiting on lab tests and then one is a
sublingual tablet that you can get in 3
milligram amounts and we've have that
pending right now in a lab test so CBG
is becoming available I'm sure there's
going to be more products on the market
if you're interested in using it and
there is some an article and maybe Joe
you can share that with people the
article that
talked about CBG for colon cancer yep
I'd like to can you here with me yeah
you can in right now so you you said
that you you suggested the patients
throw a couple of buds in their smoothie
in the morning to get the raw
cannabinoids there is there is a pretty
extensive literature for the raw
cannabinoids that the CBG a has I think
I found five articles showing that it
had benefit for breast cancer doctor
Mary has shown some experience with THC
a and and prostate cancer but in in in
your slides when you when you showed
that in one of your YouTube videos it
turned out that that THC a also killed
the glioblastoma cells in in in vitro if
not next to next to the the
decarboxylated THC the THC a was the
second most potent cannabinoid so
there's also literature on CB GA and and
and and there's paper sawn on colon
cancer with with with DHEA and and CBG a
and so I'm wondering if we should
include raw cannabinoids in in a formal
way in in our cancer protocols so so I'm
just envisioning that that since they're
not psychoactive the patient could take
the the CBD and raw cannabinoids during
the day and take a big dose of THC at
bedtime and get all of the get a really
full
entourage of compounds to fight the
cancer and and I would like to here's
the can the panel is response to that
yeah great share it around so so
throwing a few buds into the blenders a
pretty good way to do it if you can't
make the oil and and there's not many
many products available in the
dispensary that have a full complement
of cannabinoids so I want to say two
things yes there are cancers that been
affected by the acid form of the
cannabis and I don't know if it's the
acid form or other terpenes I didn't
they sect it yet to know the major cell
lines that we checked were more affected
by the Decker box elated but there are a
few of them in prostate cancer is one of
them and being highly affected by the
acid form we need to remember that the
acid form is the native form and if they
on the plant so the plant not creating
they it creating THC and there is a
logic to think that there is a role for
that you know in animal receptors if
it's kind of defense or attract
mechanism for the plant and but usually
they are less potent than the active
form like the decarboxylated from that
at least in our results if the patient
can eat cannabis like that it's not
affected so the is-8 and said why not so
I want to say like you you same thing
that are more related to two United
States in Israel we don't have a problem
of the amounts of the plant the patient
they are not paying for that it's not
related to a price the pain fixed price
doesn't matter how much they are getting
they can get 600 gram and months or 2
grams a months it's this
amount for them we don't have a problem
of CBD cultivars they can choose so
every girl will have at least one high
CBD cultivars and they can choose and
can have it so all of these problems we
don't have it just we don't know what is
good to give them but if we know it was
available for the patients so do you
routinely use the THC a now with
recommended to patients with prostate
cancer my patient have four legs and a
tail I'm not a physician
I'm routinely tried checking it in my
lab on this the models that I have I'm
not I'm not offering your patient and
I'm trying to avoid it I think you know
people that are experienced and
physicians should take these decisions
one minute can I make a quick comment
sure sure so I think ultimately you know
there's a huge amount of research that
has to be done including clinical trials
and one of the biggest problems of
course is the schedule 1 status so any
chance you get to try to talk to any
politicians if you're if you know people
we have to get it D scheduled so that we
can do the research period we live in
chaos where CBD is still a Schedule one
drug if it comes from a pharmaceutical
company just recently now it's a
Schedule five but how do and then
there's a patent right on THC by the
government for neuroprotection but yet
it's still a Schedule one so that it's
utter chaos and that has to get sorted
out but ultimately having the science
that that dedi and
and Christina are doing is so very
important but at the same time what
we're being warned about over and over
is not to take their results and then
apply it to human beings because that is
not that that's not linked it's the
initial findings what we're seeing is
sure maybe it it definitely helps in
breast cancer cells in a test tube and
then also in mice but again remember
we're missing clinical trials for Jeff
and I that tree human beings that come
into our offices we offer the best that
we can there is no one protocol that's
going to work for everybody I I had the
unfortunate well I guess it's a mixed
experience I've seen two teenagers with
the same exact stage for osteosarcoma
it's very similar stories one young man
the family was very motivated they took
high-dose oils and that young man
survived and he was diagnosed at age 14
was probably not going to make it till
17th birthday and he just turned 20
about a month ago but at the same time I
had another case referred from the same
oncologist who the family came and I
gave a very similar protocol and they
just had a really hard time giving the
oil whether a psychosocial situation or
the child didn't want to take it and
that boy died so there there's you you
you can't conclude very much other than
there is certainly a chance and what
we're seeing I know dr. Hagen rather
night better quality of life
maybe extension of life for certain
patients and certainly an ability to
give somebody some hope and to move
forward despite the diagnosis of cancer
and sometimes very devastating cancer
diagnosis but at the same time there is
no one magical protocol that seems to
work for everybody
despite the fact that you may have the
same cancer or the same type of cancer
you have to remember that we're still
very early in the stages of this and I
don't think that I'm sure a lot of
people came to this panel saying well I
want to know what to take or what to
recommend to my mother-in-law but at the
same time what I'll tell you is that
there's no reason not to try if you sir
if you certainly have an advanced cancer
or certainly if it doesn't look good for
you because we are out of time but if
you want to take one question from the
audience will be we can we can do that I
want just to say that there is few
clinical trials in Israel that running
now with cannabis and cancer there is
like three weeks seems some like there
is one on glioblastoma and thank this
data that will come from there we start
to give better hints and I totally agree
the Bonnie that you know you can
conclude for the mice and from the cell
lines how to treat patients but I think
from these researchers will be better
and I admire these physicians that treat
the patient and and take the advantage
as they said it's not toxic and there is
no it's even if it's give a little hope
to the patients were see you all for in
your own way pointing out what we don't
know which I think forces us to zoom out
and use more of a Systems Theory
approach when it comes to working with
patients what I didn't hear and I'm
wondering if some of you could comment
on would be cautions or
contraindications from using cannabis
and patients that say might be doing
immunotherapy or based on some animal
data that just came out this month from
Lopez Valero at all showing that CBD may
reduce the efficacy of tamoxifen decay
shion's to offer I can make a comment so
when a patient comes in of course
they're required to supply me with the
list of medications that are taking
including and in chemotherapy or any new
immunotherapies one of the things that I
find helpful is that you can call a
pharmaceutical company they're always
open to questions and if you ask them
have there been
of course drug drug interactions with
anything like CBD is usually the big one
that we find interactions and for some
of my patients if they're on a
medication and their oncologist wants
them to take that sometimes I'll tell
them you know you can take low doses of
cannabinoids to try to mitigate side
effects however it may not be in your
best interest to take high doses of
cannabinoids right now if it's either
going to clear that drug out of their
system quicker or actually allow that
drug to accumulate and create toxicity
so we have to be very careful because
the vast majority of patients that are
coming in now and I'm sure Jeff can say
this too are choosing treatment they're
not coming at the last resort like it
used to be maybe about five or eight
years ago most people that are coming in
are actually coming in fairly early and
so now it's created this review of all
medications because many of them are
interested in combination therapy and
that's why it's important that
especially now that there's legalization
in our state here in California that
someone over 21 doesn't self-medicate
while they're on a oncology protocol
because they could actually make
themselves toxic on medication doesn't
have the round of applause for our panel
[Applause]