[Music]
welcome to the canmed Coffee Talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
mindes in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing I am your
host Ben ameral I am the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
camed conference well the list of names
participating in camed 24 continues to
grow we have now added our first batch
of poster presenters to our speaker page
so I encourage you to check those out at
canmed events.com while you are there
you can also check out the canmed
archive which is our searchable video
library of all the past canmed
presentations please also while you're
there sign up for email alerts so you
can stay stay up to-date on all things
related to the canmed 24 Innovation and
investment Summit we still have a few
more announcements up Our Sleeve so do
stay
tuned by the way ticket packages are
still available for camed 24 go to camet
events.com to learn all about the
different packages that we have
available and read about all the
amenities that come with them and if you
want to learn more about what makes
canmed unique and unlike like any other
Cannabis Conference check out the link
in the show description our marketing
team put together a great blog that
highlights all the ways that canmed is
unique my guest today is AEM Gardner who
at canmed 24 will present effect of can
flavens on mitigating motor neuron
disease AE is the founder and CEO of
canera he is an Innovative entrepreneur
with over 5 years of experience in
industrial hemp Enterprises
he has a proven track record in leading
high performance teams that work across
multi-channel platforms and
strategically aligning profitability
with sustainability and economic
development in
Ontario during our conversation we
discuss the minor molecules found in
cannabis that canera is investigating
for
Therapeutics cana's process for
evaluating indications for can flavens
and
polyphenols how the diverse molecules in
cannabis make it a great therapeutic for
a multifactoral disease like
ALS the potential for can flavens and
polyphenols to be used as an
anti-inflammatory neutraceutical and
more before we get to my conversation
with theem I want to thank this episode
sponsor the American cannabis Nurses
Association acna is a national nursing
organization whose mission is to advance
Advance excellence in cannabis nursing
practice through advocacy collaboration
education research and policy
development founded in
2010 acna continues to work on providing
their members with up-to-date cannabis
information and resources to care for
patients who use cannabis join them
today at cannabis nurses.org and be part
of the
change okay and without any further Ado
please please enjoy my conversation with
AEM
[Music]
Garder good afternoon AE thanks so much
for joining us on the podcast oh thank
you for having me here Ben excited to be
back looking forward to canmed 2024 as
well yeah it yeah no it is great to have
you back on the podcast and as you
mentioned you're returning for canmed 24
you did give a great presentation at
canmed 23 about the researcher team
performed on using can flavens to treat
gleo blastoma and I'll put a link in the
show description so people can can check
that out and as we said you're coming
back again this year to share data
related to how can flavens again may
help treat patients with motor neuron
disease but before we dive into that I
was checking out your website at
cana.com before we jumped on and it
seems like there's a lot of activity
going on there so why don't you catch us
up on what you've been working on since
last we
spoke awesome awesome awesome yes as you
can see we are very very busy bees up
here in Toronto doing a lot of research
on these minor molecules found in the
plant not only the can Flavin but other
penol flavonoids still beans Spenzo
that are there in cannabis Industrial
Hemp as well and as you know and as we
know with right with all Botanicals with
the cannaboids all these molecules they
have um um multi-targets they work on
different aspects of the body to do
different things in various diseases so
over the last year we've been really
really trying to narrow down in on our
research on the applications of what
these molecules and ingredients can do
on their own and in different
combinations and how do you actually get
products out of these Botanical uh
Botanical drug candidates but also
neutral that can go to the market much
sooner and help people out in a quicker
in a quicker period of time excellent
okay so I heard you mention there's some
additional molecules that you're looking
at because last time we we we focused on
the canned flavens A and B last we spoke
so I'm curious what these what these new
molecules are we did and and um but I
yeah I can't remember if I said it last
time probably didn't but at canera we
really want to be the company that you
go to when you think anything cannabis
hat polyphenol related so in these
polyphenols and in minor concentrations
in the plants there are groups of
crenelated flavonoids which would
include the can Flavin a can Flavin B
and others it would include still beans
b benzil b benzil are ingredients like
canine cannabis still beans
um so still Beam with benzil and other
ingredients as well that have yet to be
characterized all in all I think there's
about seven or eight molecules that have
been identified in literature but
there's no validated standards to be
able to identify these at a consistent
basis and they are very very small and
very very small concentrations in the
planet so we are working on multiple
ways of um enriching xats for these
ingredients then being able ble to
isolate them purify them and then test
them all out for their bioactivity that
way when we're putting combinations
together we're sure we can be or make
better um guesses or
hypothesis
hypothesises about what these
ingredients can do when it comes to
treating both humans and animals in a
variety of different health conditions
excellent so you say small
concentrations how small are we talking
well if we look at the can flins the the
lead ones these ones are the ones that
we can get most reliably and these ones
are found in under
0.014% of the plant biomass on average
everything else is less than
that wow y so we we really have to and
the first patent that we designed or the
researchers at the University designed
was a way of specifically concentrating
then identifying isolating and then
purifying all of these molecules so that
when we're doing hlcr NM or whatever or
whatnot um Mass speec we actually know
what's there we can identify the various
molecules that are there and then we can
develop standards for these molecules um
with our biosynthesis technology as well
awesome so with the plant making such
small concentrations is that the best
way to produce these um molecules or do
you have some other sort of uh process
for that well the best way for us to at
these molecules right now is extraction
the beauty of our extraction process is
it's a commercially feasible way of
again concentrating isolating and
purifying so that we can get these
molecules in the future there may be
another way that we um come up with we
have a couple of other methods under
investigation right and again like I
said this is what we ultimately want to
be known at known for ater being the
ones that can get these molecules in a
reliable fashion at the standards or at
the level with the characterization that
the FD or any other regulator around the
world wants for Botanical ingredients
Botanical great no and I know a big part
of what you do at canera is you
investigate different um indications um
that might be a good a good Target for
these molecules um and again like I said
I was looking at the website and there
looks like there's a lot of different
things you're looking at so I'm curious
how do you decide which condition
um you want to investigate and sort of
what's your process for sort of um
evaluating
these well as a halfway joke right
partly ask chat GPT hey we have these
molecules they have these sort of um um
end PLS in activity how might they be
able to help right that's a halfway joke
because um we do use AI environment
informaticians to help screen our
molecules and give uh um us information
for where we think this might be most
applicable um one of the things that we
know that our ingredients do very well
is they target the inflammatory related
path and we know that chronic
inflammation um systematic chronic
inflammation is related to a wide
variety of diseases usually everything
starts as that slow burning continuous
inflammation goes undetected then it can
turn into cancer into neurod
degenerative problems into
cardiovascular problems so on and so
forth so where we start is we look at
okay um what areas of disease or what
other indications are related to a
inflammation um even if inflammation is
the primary um driver of that disease do
our molecules hit other targets that are
related to that disease for example in
our cancer program for Goma we found
that our molecules also hit Tre B so
that we were able to go down that
pathway but then really what I try to do
is I try to find a key opinion leader
someone who's used to doing the AC mic
or pre-clinical or Discovery work
required to be able to validate the
ideas the hypothesis that we have so in
Canada we are very fortunate to have a
wide variety of um
universities um with a lot of
investigators with the government
programs that can fund um student
research so that professors with the
oversight can lead a PhD or a master
student or even sometimes undergrad stud
students to do a series of experiments
for us proof of concept experiments for
us that will give us the information we
need to deductively reason and say yes
this is what we want to do or this is
where we think we have the highest
chance of success or we can turn this
around in a reasonable time because from
this batch of experiments and work
previously done we can FastTrack this
into the clinic which we're trying to do
with our first asset our lead asset for
motor neuron dises ALS great okay so
that was was going to be sort of my next
question is you know which one of these
indications is sort of the furthest
along or closest to actually doing
clinical trials and it sounds like it's
um this ALS motor neuron um application
mot neuron dise I I think so right EXC
over the last year we've learned a lot
about ALS monor neuron disease we've
learned a lot about how the cannabis
plant has helped people suffering from
neurological ailments um um since the
beginning of time in a variety of
different cultures and again leaning on
the experience of Dr Ethan Russo our
senior medical
advisor and what the work that they did
formerly at GW Pharma we know that
cannabis can help in severe neurological
diseases neurod degenerative diseases
and ALS BTO neuron disease is an area
where these patients they need help a
lot of them use cannabis right now to
help manage their symptoms but they
don't have something standardized and
the practitioner doesn't always know
what the patient is using even though
they can come into the clinic and say
hey we're using cannabis we feel better
we're eating more so on and so forth so
our goal is to be able to leverage all
the work previously done along with some
of the new work that we're doing right
now to be able to move this forward into
the clinic and really help a patient
population that's looking for answers
that's looking for um help that's
looking for a better quality of life and
really deserves to have it excellent and
now
um the therapeutic that you're sort of
evaluating is that a like a single
molecule um therapeutic or is it sort of
a combination of of different compounds
what does that look like so generally
speaking when we evaluate um our Assets
in any indication we put a series of
different candidates in there so we will
put like um highly purified single can
can Flavin cany we'll put cany extract
and then we can put combination extract
in there and see what performs best um
based on the mixture the cocktail
mixture the um almost Entourage or
synergistic approach right now based on
the work previously done and based on
again being a student of Dr REO we know
that in the clinic for humans it's
probably not going to be a single
mixture a single ingredient that has the
best opportunity to help these patients
it's going to be a cocktail mixture a
cocktail approach not dissimilar to how
these patients are getting treated right
now but we can talk about that a little
bit later um as I was saying we put
together a series of um different
molecules found in the plant at various
concentrations at safe concentrations
that we believe can be delivered to
patients chronically on an everyday
basis that can help them manage their
symptoms that can improve their quality
of life and might also be
neuroprotective as well um and help them
with survival so we think that we have
something that can be disease modifying
now we just have to continue to go andov
it great and so and so where are we at
now and I mean maybe let's how about a
little preview I don't want you give
away too much because we want people to
come out to the event but um what what
are you looking to present at at
caned so I CED I we have a series of
again previous literature that's been
done but also some unique exper
experiments that we've recently done to
validate that our combination actually
does work how we think it's going to
work so I'm really excited to share some
of this information share again the
process that we went through from
looking at all the things previously
done to adding our unique twists on it
and then showing uh what the result is
and how we got it to work in our favor
excellent excellent and now you touched
on it before um when you were talking
about ALS like what are sort of the
Therapeutics that ALS patients are using
now um and you know why is yours
potentially a better
solution so um well I'll start first
really quickly with what is ALS right
sure yeah and ALS is a pretty severe
neurodegenerative disease right it comes
in a variety of different forms it's a
really complex disorder where a lot of
things are going are going on people
don't really understand why um patients
get it why they um as soon as they get
it they're two to three years usually
until uh to mortality um they usually
assum when they get it they end up in a
wheelchair they have to have tubes to
help with their feeding right really
really rapid progression and debil
dehabitation U motor neuron disease um
right
now because of the complexity of ALS
again
even though it was first discovered 150
years ago there's no cure to me still
right and it's because of the complexity
of what's going on in the CNS and in the
motor
neurons
so most recently um and I think as of
today there's four slash I think and uh
metosin becomes the fifth um drug that's
approved for the treatment of this
disease but the thing about all these
different treatments is none of them
extend survival in a meaningful way none
of them cure the disease none of them
help manage the symptoms and because ALS
is so complex between Patient to Patient
there's so many different gen IR
irregularities and different things
going on um right now practitioners they
sort of prescribe to the patient in this
cocktail approach here take all four
treatments right and all four will maybe
help you um on your
journey so what we aim to do do instead
of having to have the patient have um
four or five different treatments to
help them we aim to put all the benefits
of the cannabis plant and the various
different ingredients in the cannabis
plant into a single or a monotherapy
that they can take on a day-to-day basis
that will not only help them address
their various different symptoms their
pain help them sleep better help them
with their hunger and their appetite
help them with um um keeping on muscle
mass um but also improve their quality
of life and then potentially be neur
protective as well and extend their
survival we think we have a sort of
all-in-one approach and this is where we
get to benefit from the multi the
multiple applications of the cannabis
plant and all various indications we
don't need one thing to do one thing
very well when you're dealing with a
complex disease like ALS you sort of
need the poly phological approach and
this is where we get disadvantage plus
the an advantage of having our superp
poent anti-inflammatories and our C
flins in this m stream excellent
excellent no and you mentioned so the
current medications they they don't
relieve symptoms they don't extend
lifespan there I think there was another
thing you said they that they're not
doing so what are they
doing well they help right um um but
they don't cure there's no cure for alsc
right we don't really understand what's
going on and again each of these
medicines they're designed to
specifically do one or another thing um
help with patient um subpopulations of
ALS patients that have um one disease
modification off or another right but
they don't help in
a broad spectrum if you would call it to
the broader population right and none of
them none of them address the symptoms
like we know we can address the symptoms
with cannabis that's why ALS patients
even if they're taking a medicine one or
the other they'll still often smoke
cannabis or have a A tinure or have a
topical or something like that to be
able to help them with the symptoms that
they're also suffering
from EXC so this is where yeah this is
where we think we can come in and we can
really help because again we know things
like cannabis helps with spasticity it
helps with muscle spasms cramps the pain
the fatigue depression nausea so on and
so forth um and we know that with
cannabis you can have these benefits
have an improved quality of life without
a host of a whole bunch of other adverse
effects excellent yeah and it sort of
seems to kind of illustrate you know the
difference between cannabis medicine
approach and a traditional farmer
approach right is like Pharma is is like
you said typically focused on you know a
single molecule for a single um
indication um which it sounds like is
what's being used for ALS now but it's
not really effective because it is such
a
um a
broad uh disease where it's it's not
sort of a one-sized fits-all and that's
where something like a a cannabis might
actually be a better approach because it
it can help in so many different ways it
can be if you can deliver it with the
CMC and the pharmaceutical standard
right um in Pharma they do do
combination therapies like I mentioned
they still use the cocktail approach for
ALS they have four proved diseases a for
ped medicines sorry that can help treat
one aspect or another of the disease and
then they deliver it together together
in the combination approach but the
easier way to get it approved um because
you have to do the clinical trial
because you have to have the CMC and be
able to produce it consistently every
single time right it's to have one thing
that does one thing very well get it to
Market and then let the practitioners
prescribe it or use it to help their
patients this is where again um our
learnings from those that have done it
before those that have done it at the
pharmaceutical standard with satex and F
dialect we get the benefit of
understanding how do you make this
happen how do you make this happen with
Botanical mixtures how do you make this
happen with Canabis and how do you and
once you can do that from a a production
weight from a clinical trial weight from
a bat toat repeatability rate then the
patients get all the real benefits that
cannabis can offer in a standardized
consistent method yeah I mean the whole
consistency thing that is one of the
greatest challenges with cannabis
medicine for sure
um so another but another challenge with
cannabis medicine is of course the cost
um so I'm curious and maybe it's way too
soon to tell but like how would the you
know the cost of this type of
therapeutic sort of compare to uh kind
of the standard uh ALS
treatment probably a little bit soon to
tell right yeah a lot of that's going to
come uh come after we finish our full
scale up our CMC and have the cost of
good Souls but the thing is is once you
get it through the clinical trials once
you get it uh approved by Regulators
then the payers the insurance will pay
for it right and the nice thing about
this is that it's not just res
restricted to a medical cannabis program
when you get it approved as a drug you
can cross Interstate lines and the big
insurance companies um can pay for it
not only in the US but also this is the
approach that will take in targeting the
payers and getting the payers to approve
reimbursement all over the
world excellent no I know you're up
there in Canada which is a little bit
different than the us because you do
have a federal medical cannabis program
up there um so with the path to getting
the payers to um reimburse or or pay for
um this therapeutic is it an easier path
up there than the
US probably I'm not going to say easier
because again we're not going to go down
the medical cannabis route to start
we're going after pharmaceutical right
got it so we'll go the same route as
traditional Pharmaceuticals like GW uh
Fara did with epid and satex to get full
reimbursing but that's not to say that
we don't have a fallback plan if we have
to go to a fallback excellent always
good to have a fallback plan ex um and
in what concent you we mentioned before
um that these are in very low
concentrations in the plant um at what
sort of concentrations are these um
these compounds effective is it um a
little goes a long
way well again
different dosages for different
indications and our ALS formulation is a
combination of a variety of different
things including our can FS so in the
ALS formulation we don't need a lot of
can Flavin a to or B to work um to help
the patient because it's not working
alone right versus another indication we
may want more of it because the can
flavins might do something better than
uh a tarpine or another cannaboid for
that example right or the can fibs might
even just work better all alone instead
of in combination for a different type
of disease so it really depends on what
we're talking about and who we're aiming
to help and and I'll also say it also
depends on the physical makeup of the
person for example um we have some of
our extracts right now um are pilot
skill extracts they're not on in the
market yet but I consume them right but
I'm 65 240 my mom isn't 65 240 so where
my mom takes one one um tincture one
droplet one tincture full of our extract
I have to take two or three to get equal
therapeutic dose so this is some of the
complexities about cannabis and about
humans and about making Pharmaceuticals
because all of us have different genetic
makeups different physical makeups right
what works for one person might not work
for the other so sometimes you may have
to titrate up to your dose find your
maximum tolerable dose
and do what works for you yep absolutely
yeah that's it's the standard that's
that's what um Bonnie Goldstein and
Dustin
and Ethan Russo of course talk about and
they'll be talking about again this year
at the medical practicum so we're
excited about that so so you said that
you you take um one of your extracts um
daily or is that just for kind of
General Wellness
or well for General Wellness and I can't
put something on the market that I
haven't put through the ringer myself Me
and My Husky Sky we're conera 1.0 taste
testers if Sky loves it if I'm okay then
I feel good with everyone else so um I
do take it right now for general for
General Wellness also um I'm currently
our longest um safety study our
long-term safety study because I've been
taking it since day one right and wanted
to make sure that again no stomach
issues no nausea no Adverse Events right
I feel really really fine the other
thing that I can say about our extract
one of the things that I've come to
found is um the other day I hurt my back
in the gym and it was a crazy day I was
deadlifting I was deadlifting angry you
should never deadlift angry because
that's when injuries happen and I
learned it the hard way but it was very
interesting because when I tweaked my um
the muscle in my back um I still had
range of motion I knew I was hurt I felt
that I was hurt but I could still move I
could still get through my workout
versus traditionally um or if I well
traditionally I'll say my back would
lock up so
after that injury happened I remember
the next day the next two days I was
taking my extract again I was like I
slept okay I woke up my back didn't lock
up I wasn't super sore I'm like this is
weird but is this in my head right
because I want our extract to work more
than anyone but I'm like I definitely
know I'm
injured um and then u i remember me and
my mom we were sharing a bottle at that
time so I left the bottle at home and I
went to my fiance I st spent the weekend
at my fiance I woke up Saturday morning
and I hadn't had the extract and I'm
like okay I'm starting to feel a little
bit more tightness in my back right but
I'm okay right I still have my range of
motion I can get in and out of my car
stand up sit down okay but then the
Sunday when I woke up my back was locked
I was like this is completely messed I
can't believe this is what my back was
going through this whole time I don't
know what's going on I called my mom
immediately M I'm coming home to take
the rest of the bottle right now sorry
you can get from the next batch because
there's no like I couldn't every time I
was getting up sitting down it was so
tight I had to like you know you know
when you're injured and it's really
tight you have to like slowly but surely
bring yourself down and then um no lie I
started to take my extract again at the
usual dose and then again the next day
and the day after I was still hurt but I
had my range of motion I can get in and
out of my car without thinking twice
about it I was like this is actually
like really Illuminating because if um
I'm 33 right now but we know that as
people age as um they get more chronic
elments more arthritics so on and so
forth that they're going through things
like this I think that an extract like
this can really help really help improve
quality of life really help them just
manage the symptoms of whatever they're
going through and that was um the first
real time where I was like okay I know
what I read I know what I'm seeing in
the experience exper experiments but now
I actually felt it in my own body about
the power of this extract the power of
the enriched extracts and what it can do
wow no so that's that's some power
powerful anti-inflammatory there huh it
was it was definitely helpful and again
ever since then I'm like nope Mom we
have to wait for the second I have to
have a bottle with me at all times
excellent all right um so in in kind of
winding down here I did want to kind of
check in with you too because we
mentioned at the top that you spoke last
year about using can flavens for G
blastoma um I'm wondering what's
happened uh on that front since then um
is that is that also kind of moving
along the uh um the
pipeline so slowly but surely cancer is
very difficult and tricky sure alss
complex as well cancer even more right
um we're still continuing that project
is still going on at the the University
of walf we're actually getting ready to
do a series of organoid studies and not
only for G blastoma breast cancer and
breast cancer metastasis studies as well
because again we know that our molecules
have the track B activity plus their
antiinflammatories these are still being
done at a pre-clinical phase the
challenge that we are going to have
right now is I really need key opinion
leaders and people who can help us do
the work at the next phase I'm not a
practitioning doctor
uh a practicing doctor I'm not a
principal investigator in the
traditional right right and I don't see
these patients so really for us U the
next phase of work that we need to do
once these sets of experiments um are
complete is finding someone who's
interested in looking at uh future
alternatives to cancer treatments small
molecule cancer treatments and taking a
look at the data that we have and having
the experience and the knowhow to be
able to help us take this forward
excellent we have some we have yeah we
have some ideas about about um other
areas of cancer that we might be able to
help in like things like cancer pain
which are inflammation related but when
it comes to things like again Leo blast
brain cancer um breast cancer we really
need people um from the community from
out there in the rest of the world to
help us Mo those things from excellent
well I do know an of an event that's
happening in May where there's a lot of
uh clinicians uh who might be able to
help you out so oh 100% for sure last
year all the feedback and the people
that I met at canmed were awesome um and
a lot of interesting leads that I am
very excited to follow up on this year
to be able to show okay now we know that
we can actually do x y and z now can we
actually and we can actually produce
more now what are the next steps to
actually getting this one step further
down the line excellent oh happy to
Foster those relationships for sure um
no I do actually want to Circle back
about you know your story about sort of
using the extract as a as an
anti-inflammatory and sort of as almost
like a a preventative or General
Wellness now is that another line that
you're pursuing as well as um sort of
making this available to uh to folks to
to take regularly or when they deadlift
angry yes
so hopefully this year um sometime
between Q2 and Q3 we will have an
extract ready for launch in the US
markets we have a group that we we've
been working with in Oregon shout out to
F soil um they we've been able to
transfer our technology to them they've
been working on scaling it up um now
we're at the last step on making sure
that um our excipients uh our excipients
and our ingredient stays in excipients
in the carrier oil that we have our B
moding and our labeling all worked out
and then we will be launching this in an
e-commerce type of a way so very very
soon we're right around the corner this
isn't a high concentration can Flavin um
extract product but it is an enriched
polyphenol product the camp flavens are
in it in more of an amount than any
other product that's on the market as of
today it's not at our full Botanical
drug characterization level yet but it
doesn't have to be as a neutral and as a
health and Warmness prodct
so for us again the most important thing
is going to be getting this into the
hands of people who need it the most
allowing these ingredients to start to
get into their um daily consumption
patterns um allow to start to accumulate
in the body and do what it does well
even if could be at a more of a
nutriceutical health and wellness
everyday level and for those suffering
more from severe chronic disorders
will'll continue to do our clinical
trial research our batto batch um
production and our scale up so that we
can serve them as soon as possible
they're are wow that's great that's
exciting um I mean I I personally I take
cbda every day or after all my workouts
so I'd be definitely definitely be
interested in uh checking out your
products once they're out
there um all right AE winding down here
I did want to give you an opportunity to
um plug any additional resources that
you think the listeners might interested
in learning more about the the topics
we've been talking about and then of
course uh your website social media
anything like that please plug away
awesome so for anyone who's interested
in learning more always feel free to
reach out to me on LinkedIn or on my
email it's just a Keem ata.com on our
website in our Journal area so cora.com
Journal we have a bunch of different
resources there including um um new
literature or new data as it comes about
um we look to post it there and it
usually goes on Lin but what I would
ultimately say is to come to canmen 2024
canmen 2024 was very important for me
last year I'm learning about where the
state of cannabis research is meeting
all the different key opinion leaders
and the P people who are treating
patients suffering from a variety of
different things of cannabis and also
allowing us to tell our story so I was
very happy to be able to get on that
stage for the first time last year
really excited to follow that on with um
more actionable items this year and
continue to grow a relationship with the
whole CED Community that's what I would
say about it excellent we appreciate
that and we appreciate you AEM and look
forward to seeing you down in in Marco
Island I look forward to it as well
thank you very very much for having me
here today Ben please stay warm because
in Canada it's cold and wet we're up in
the Northeast it's not much warmer where
we are but we'll do our best looking
forward to
best I am as well thank you thank you
very much for your
[Music]
time hope you enjoyed my conversation
with AEM Gardner check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and thanks again
to this episode sponsor the American
cannabis Nurses Association our next
episode drops February 21st that's 2
weeks from today in the meantime please
go to Kat events.com and check out our
speaker lineup and our poster presenters
while you're there sign up for email
alerts to get notified about all our
event
announcements you can register for your
ticket package through a link at caned
events.com as as well and be sure to do
that as soon as possible because our
tickets are limited this year also be
sure to follow us on social media we are
on Instagram X LinkedIn and Facebook
just search for canmen events and lastly
we appreciate it if you would rate
review And subscribe to the podcast on
whichever method you use to consume us
all right stay safe stay healthy and be
sure to come back for the next CED
Coffee Talk
[Music]