[Music]
welcome to the cbag Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I'm the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on the camed
Summit okay we just announced our first
round of poster presenters who will be
sharing their work at the camed 25
Innovation and investment Summit this
June in Puerto Rico you can read all
about each of them on our speaker page
at canmed events.com along with our
confirmed oral presenters and panelists
who will be participating in the
Cannabis genomics workshop and the
compliance testing Workshop
you can check out the caned practicum
instructors as well and don't forget
that doctors and clinicians can earn six
continuing medical education credits by
attending the
practicum all the details are at camed
events.com be sure to sign up for email
alerts so you get all of our
announcements delivered directly to your
inbox and please subscribe to the
podcast so you don't miss an
episode oh yeah and don't forget to
register to join us at
c25 we've gotten a great response on our
early bird promotion which did expire
last week but there are still great
ticket packages available we'd love to
see you in June check out the details
again at camet events.com
our guest today is Israel
gaspin Israel is a Visionary
entrepreneur engineering scientist and
the founder of zentella a company
dedicated to transforming cannabis
research through advanced
neurotechnology and
AI under Israel's leadership zentella
developed the psychoactive effect level
metric an Innovative eeg-based measure
capable of objectively assessing
cannabis products psychoactive
potency by combining wearable EEG
technology with Aid driven EEG analysis
the pel metric provides cannabis
producers researchers and Regulators
with a non-invasive and costeffective
way to quantify product effects and
maintain quality control at K at25
Israel will share results from over
10,000 EEG scans of consumers using a
wide range of cannabis products in his
oral presentation titled cannabis
affects research driven by EEG
technology and machine learning
during our conversation we discuss how
zella's wearable EEG technology got it
start measuring drowsiness in truck
drivers the unreliability of consumer
feedback surveys with regards to
cannabis product
effects how the peal metric was created
to measure the unique psychoactive
effects of
cannabis how EEG data can be applied to
objectively measure the quality and
effectiveness of cannabis products
Beyond Simple cannabinoid
percentages research findings that show
THC percentage and plal percentage are
not directly correlated and
more before we get to my conversation
with Israel I'd like to thank this
episode sponsor the dent
Institute with more than 300,000 patient
visits per year the dent neurologic
Institute ranks among the largest neuros
science centers in North
America its 24 subsp specialty clinics
often treat the most challenging
neurologic conditions including but not
limited to migraine chronic pain ALS Ms
Parkinson's dementia and
neurooncology with their mission of
advancing Neuroscience the dent
Institute established a cannabis clinic
in 2016 to Aid in the treatment of these
chronic conditions seen throughout the
Institute you can learn more at Dent
institute.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Israel
gasperin
[Music]
good afternoon Israel thank you so much
for joining me on the
podcast hello pamin thank you very much
for having me here happy to tell you
more about um our technology Cella and
uh sharing all of this information with
your audience yes I'm excited to talk
with you today about this wearable EEG
technology that your team has developed
to measure the effects of THC in the
user brain so let's start with what
inspired you to develop this
technology yeah thank you um so I think
I was thinking about the about this the
other day and the the main inspiration
to build this technology was in 2016
when the Canadian government was in the
process of legalizing a recreational
Cannabis consumption and the lack of a
test to object itively determine if a
person needs cannabis in or
not at that time we were building this
technology to detect drowsiness and
while driving and and we wanted to help
truck companies to keep their driver's
alert so they were telling us about this
um upcoming legalization of Canabis
consumption for non-medical purposes and
that they didn't have a way of detecting
cannabis impairment and that the current
way which is
analyzing and detecting concentration
levels of THC in saliva urine blood or
breath there didn't exist a test to
analyze the brain of of drivers so we
were like okay that's the aha moment
when we decided to Pivot from detecting
drowsiness while driving to detecting
cannabis impairment while driving
and in that way help uh multiple markets
to better determine if a person is or
not impaired because that's the biggest
the biggest issue the we we we all know
very well that THC remains in body
fluids uh for many hours days or weeks
post impairment or experiencing the its
effects and and that that leads to
inaccurate determination ations about
being impaired so that was the main
reason that inspired us to to build this
technology and once we build it we
realized that
the the need for this type of brain wave
analysis was even bigger and Beyond the
the safety and law enforcement
applications and that other application
was for research to better understand
the effect and the quality and efficacy
of all of these Innovative products and
you know breeds and strains that the
market is developing and uh that's how
all started wow okay so so really to
start it was to try to determine how
impaired a driver was yes exactly the
the the Ontario brain Institute and the
Ontario Center of innovation two two
Ontario uh government
organizations fully funded us to to to
develop this technology and that's how
we were able to build it because I hope
you will appreciate and your audience
will appreciate that in
2016 nobody really but not many were
familiarized and and Believers of the
potential of artificial intelligence
specifically when it's applied in brain
data so the government was the one one
that believed in this you know potential
crazy opportunity to you know complement
the current investigation process of
cannabis impaired driving determination
and they were the ones that funded us to
to build this technology build it to a
commercially L level kind of uh uh yeah
a level of commercial viab viability and
then conducting independent trials to
prove that AI
can do this type of brain wave analysis
at a way faster and more cost- effective
way and accurate than a neurologist or
neuroscientist doing it individually or
manually right so so that's how all
started oh so interesting so it's an AI
component as well absolutely that's the
the the main differentiator and the
uniqueness of our approach by the way
because EEG technology is not really new
it has been used for more than 100 years
but in the medical space neurologist
neuroscientists EEG technicians
certified EEG technicians have been
using it for you know more than 100
years the problem is and in fact we we
came to this conclusion and realized
that that's the main reason why EEG
technology has been inaccessible to
several Global non-medical Market
because when you require a neurologist
and neuroscientist and EG Technologies
buil for medical applications it becomes
very expensive very complicated to use
very slow and that makes it not
commercially viable for all of these
type of markets that are also conducting
some type of human research not
necessarily clinical or therapeutic but
it's more about understanding what is
the state of of individuals to make
better decisions in terms of safety you
know law enforcement product testing
product quality testing Etc yeah no no
and it's it's a great uh technology for
that application especially because as
you said the concentrations in the blood
or saliva they can last for much longer
than people are actually affected we've
we've had folks on the podcast talking
about those challenges before um so
that's a that's a great
advancement absolutely uh Benjamin and
and and if you think about it is the
exact same problem that we have when
it's about measuring the quality of
cannabis products right now now finally
I think the industry has kind of uh
gained more awareness about the
problematic that
represents a uh you know judging and
determining the quality of a product
just by the THC metric yes it's it's
very well known that you know that
doesn't necessarily determine the
quality and efficacy of a product to
create an intended psychoactive effect
or other type of effects it's not only
about THC it's overall if you think
about it it's a complete change of
Paradigm in terms of measuring product
quality I I think that we will always
continue measuring the quality of
ingredients and and accurately
determining the concentration levels of
those ingredients in products and plants
Etc but another big big thing is
determining its quality to the deliver
the intended benefit to the consumer and
I think we that's our vision and the
reason why we exist that analyzing the
brain in a fast cost effective and
objective and scientific way is is the
is the approach to really determine in a
new way what what consumers are
experiencing and and measuring it in a
reliable and scientific way so it's it's
accepted by all the stakeholders because
I think that's the other big challenge
that we have seen you know there are
many solutions but I think uh coming up
with a solution that all like the main
stakeholders of the industry will accept
I think that that's the actual
you know uh event that needs to happen
someday in order to become a new
standard and that's what we are kind of
attempting to do long term no and you're
right I mean the industry really needs
sort of an objective way to evaluate the
effects of these products we make the we
make the comparison all the time to
alcohol but where're cannabis is really
different from alcohol is that you know
is the experience you know you drink
alcohol I mean maybe maybe you feel a
little bit different when you drink
tequila versus beer but for for all
intents and purposes that's not what is
differentiating your products right it's
more about the flavor or things like
that whereas with cannabis The
Experience can be very important so
having an objective way to maybe measure
that or show an effect is very important
absolutely Benjamin and and you know in
fact I think that it's it's it's an
undefined
unexplored space like we talk about
cannabis effects but there are probably
hundreds of effects that created by
cannabis and different cannaboids etc
etc and and and I think that you know
just differentiating them alone it's
it's something that we have never ever
done you know in in in the entire
history of humanity and I think that now
I think
that the the implementation of EEG
technology with machine learning and
science Etc is giving us the opportunity
for the first time to come up with
universal and
scientific and measurable definitions of
what they cannabis effect mean and and I
think that that's a one of the most
exciting opportunities to me to see you
know what is the potential of this
technology for that and and just to get
back to the point of subjectivity here
which is the the big matter that we have
been dealing with is that because of
this huge variability you know this huge
array of effects that cannabis creates
it's it's very um subjective and and
easy to provide different type of
feedback which is what it has been
happening with consumers right I I might
take two milligrams of THC and I I could
start feeling the body high and random
and uncontrollable thoughts which is the
the head high and another person might
feel strongly relaxed just with two
milligrams two milligrams of THC and
they might score in the drug effect
questionnaire a a high level of oh a
strong cannabis effect but these are
completely different effects so that is
the unreliability of just simply using
or getting a
consumer feedback if it's not
standardized and objective so in that
scenario and with your technology are
you able to see different areas of the
brain lighting up on those different
people who are experiencing different
effects absolutely Benjamin so the the I
I think maybe it's important to provide
a little bit of context to your audience
about the the the approach that is used
with machine learning and artificial
intelligence compared to the to the
current traditional appro approach that
has been used for more than 100 years
the current approach is all based on
neuroscientists and neurologist doing
very deep and clinical analysis of how
different regions of the brain are
stimulated by substances and there are
tens of papers explaining how cannabis
and other drugs and other things you
know uh impact your brain functionality
and the specific regions of the brain
Etc
but this analysis has hasn't been
standardized because of the complexity
of just simply detecting a specific
changes it's it's a like a complicated
combination of patterns or changes
happening in multiple regions of the
brain
Etc Ai and machine learning is based on
having large data sets of information
that you reliably know what they mean so
in order to build this technology we had
to conduct large scientific human trials
approved of of course by independent
ethic research boards and that that was
how they we use the funds that we raised
to build this large data set so we were
we were conducting manually and you know
carefully under control the scenarios
human trials where we were observing and
controlling how study subjects were in
taking cannabis and we use multiple
approach approaches to reliably
characterize the type of mental
cognitive or emotional state that they
were
experiencing so and and and and
Associate that to which of those are
related to or uniquely created by
cannabis and which ones are just altered
by cannabis for example emotions
emotions maybe cannabis might make you
feel more more more happy happier right
that you know that that state is
universal is not necessarily to Canabis
but getting back to the point yes we
have built these huge databases that now
are enabling us not only to generate the
pl metric the plal or or psychoactive
effect level metric is a specifically
designed to detect this mental state
that is making you experience unique can
of psychoactive effects like the body
high the you know the head high and you
know this famously called the hter
effect Etc but also you know the AI that
we are building is only is also helping
us to develop other metrics that measure
for example what is the relaxation state
of a study subjects and based on that
now also quantify how cannabis or
specific canab dos or a specific
products or specific amounts of a
product will impact that relaxation
state does it help you to relax or feel
sleepy or actually stimulates you to the
point that you want to be you know
mentally active and socialize and do
this this kind of stuff is is basically
the equivalent of the IND and sativa
thing is which is another meter right
that exist in the industry so it AI for
EEG analysis is measuring
multiple types of cannabis
effects and so are all those different
effects are they all sort of combined
into that peal metric no that that's a
great question right now we are the we
are building different metrics for for
one specific reason H Benjamin for
example the relaxation or energy or
sleep
effects these are mental States
Universal mental states that are not
necessarily and only impacted by
cannabis they are also impact impacted
by alanine and melatonin and herbs Etc
caffeine energy drinks Etc so we
strategically build these other metrics
as Standalone and Independence because
now we are also helping not only the
Cannabis cpg Market but other wellness
and health cpg markets that by the way
have the exact same problem that the
Cannabis cpg Market have their products
are marketed by clinically proven
alanine and yeah so so what like how did
you prove that the PO the the way you
mix a certain amount of Healy anding
with other active ingredients or
non-active ingredients
and and use a specific drug delivery
method and the format Etc the way it
will be consumed how do you prove that
that is the most effective way of
delivering an intended effect and and
and these other metrics are not only
helping cannabis for relaxation energy
or the Sleep effects are helping all all
these other wellness and health cpg
markets interesting all right so that
plal that is a specific effect for
cannabis
exactly that's exactly right excellent
excellent so I'm curious I was hoping
you would share a bit about the kind of
the findings that you found like what
were the different products that you
were testing and comparing to each other
and sort of what stood out or what was
surprising to you absolutely and and I'm
very much looking forward to presenting
this work in detail at canth 2025 in
beautiful Puerto Rico uh but but it it
is a
huge it's just a huge database of
product effects that we have been
accumulating Benjamin uh from different
type of different product formats
consumption methods and and consumption
amounts and different type of consumers
that have consume the those type of
products but we have been doing a
studies with for example with with back
slabs we conducted a partnership with
them in order to study the psychoactive
effect levels of live rossing you know
oils that are
vaporized versus distillate thhc ER Bots
and and uh you know one of the biggest
takeaways of that is that thanks to our
metric we were able to show you know the
quality and the famously called anash
effect that creates having you know a
live ring product which which you know
for those who don't know it It's a
combination of you extract all the
ingredients and properties more than
ingredients all the properties that are
in a plants when you squeeze it and and
get all of Thins and several minor
canabo THC and all of the other kind of
chem chemicals in that plant versus just
isolating THC with through distillation
and and coming up with that an oil just
with THC so what what this is sugesting
is that you know live rossing uh or at
least the way this company built it is
creating a stronger psychoactive effects
than just distill atic alone
interestingly both products suggest that
they have between 92 to 93 96% of THC
but the actual quality of the experience
is significantly different and this is
very important to them because then now
Brands like PS are now are also using
this type of data to educate consumers
and highlight why a live ring product is
a high quality product a premium and
more expensive product than the the
still THC alone so so that is one but we
have been doing a lot of research with
strings like you know joints that have
you know flag work that have 15 or less
percent of THC versus 30% of THC we have
been doing research with beverages that
have two or 2.5 milligrams of THC and
quantify how that psychoactive effect
level changes based on consuming 2.5
drinking 2.5 of of THC 5 milligrams or
10 milligrams of THC we have also been
doing research about what about changing
the consumption pattern of a drink
because you can have a beverage in 10
minutes and that will be a completely
different experience the onset time and
the potency of the experience will
change than if you are just sipping it a
10 milligram THC beverage you know you
are sipping it over an hour how that
changes the psychoactive experience and
I think that that will continue helping
a lot with consumer education and and
you know helping helping them to make
inform and responsible ER consumption
decisions so they can maximize the the
pleasant experience of cannabis and
minimize the
unpleasant effects which is they are
real and is the elephant in the room
that many don't want to talk about it
but the reality is that also you know
managing and minimizing the the you know
negative effects like paranoia and
anxiety Etc is is critical and right now
to the best of my knowledge nobody is
really helping consumers to do that and
I think that is potentially the Holy
Grail to you know just you know invite
many curious you know people to to try
Canabis have a great experience and then
adopted as a as another alternative than
alcohol or I don't know other substances
or problems interesting
so is that sort of that paranoia anxiety
that negative effect is that a metric
that you can actually
measure that is exactly right Benjamin
and and you know it was so interesting
because when we started to build this
technology and start conducting research
we didn't really know uh many things
about cannabis effects but I vividly
remember when some very frequent and and
daily cannabis consumers used to tell me
you know what you know I I can you know
smoke a joint but and I can do as many
Buffs as I want or you you you need for
the research but there is a point where
I just don't continue getting
higher it's it it flattens and it
doesn't change anything else but what we
found out with our EEG technology and
also at that time administration of
psychological tests proven to
characterize your mood
the biggest take away was that yes at a
certain point study subjects didn't feel
more higher and with our EG scans and
the pl psychoactive effect level metric
we showed and and obtain objective
evidence that the pl the psychoactive
effect level they were experiencing was
the same whether you were having I think
around six to nine Puffs I don't
remember the exact number or 11 to 20
something pffs same psychoactive effect
level but what it was changing was their
the their mood
changes the first group was experiencing
Serene and positive effects like feeling
more Serene where whereas the other the
other group was feeling
anxious and and so so I think in an Med
World which I think it will happen the
sooner or later I think that the strings
will be sold and and with this
information that will indicate how many
Buffs you should intake according to the
properties of that strain and
potentially according to the profile of
consumers in order to maximize those
pleasant effects and minimize anxiety
and paranoia and all of those unpleasant
effects interesting okay so just going
back so so what is the plal actually
measuring if not um sort of mood and and
that sort of thing it's just how
um impaired a person is what what is the
PO metric yeah exactly it's basically
measuring a specific and
unique brain w alterations Associated to
the specific psychoactive effects of
cannabis
or THC or these other canabas related to
the psychoactive effects like feeling
the body high the random uncontrollable
thoughts and the the head high all of
these effects that
are I don't know if they are therapeutic
to the best of my knowledge but but but
they create this like nothing else to
the best of my knowledge creates that
type of specific effects and and that's
what the PL metric generate you know
measures H the other metrics that we
have now measure other type of effects
like whether you are feeling more you
know energized or more relaxed or sleepy
Etc excellent okay cool and now I see
the is that the device behind you back
there exactly it's it's it's a it's our
own wearable device and and the reason
behind because somebody asked me why the
heck did you build your own device if
there are so many in the market and I
was like well for for the specific
reason that there is nothing that really
works for this type of research that we
are conducting for non therapeutic and
non medical applications it's it's it's
just about mood effects and and cannabis
effects Etc and in order to do it you
need to make it very cost
effective very straightforward to use
you don't need to be measuring the head
like the head of the study subjects and
from here
measure X number of you know centimeters
or whatever in the 20 the 1020 system we
converted all of that into basic
standardized you know um indicators to
apply the device so quickly and easily
so anyone and anyone I mean food
scientist product Developers my team and
I who I'm not a neuroscientist either
are able to use this technology and and
collect EEG
data for this type of scientific
research excellent so you know
researchers they could develop their own
sort of their own
trial that is exactly right benjam me we
created some let me call it standardized
master EG research protocol that has
been approved by H Canada and have been
approved multiple times by different
independent ethic research boards but
the beauty of our standardized research
protocol is that it enables our partners
because we don't only do research in our
lab we are implementing this technology
in other labs and research hospitals is
that they can customize you know this
this protocol they can typically what we
do is EEG recordings before the
intervention or consumption of a product
and then after the consumption of the
product so after the after consumption
recordings are completely customizable
you can do many EEG scans or recordings
right at the beginning the first 30
minutes if your objective is to capture
the the onet time as accurately as
possible think about as resolution right
the more samp the higher the resolution
to see how that evolves but also you can
do it you know you can just record the E
of a study subjects and map that product
experience for up to 30 minutes or 45
minutes or one hour or three hours or up
to five hours Etc right you you can you
know customize that according to the
needs of the needs and objectives of the
company or research organization that is
conducting research in this in this
field yeah and I have to imagine this
being you know Ai and machine learning
the more data that folks are generating
it's just going to feed into the system
and just improve it
correct exactly Benjamin it's it's just
it's just like snowball because the more
data we collect the more AI will
continue learning and and and I think
that we will get to a point where the pl
metric will not only measure you know
the high and you know how strong is that
effect Etc it will it will also tell us
what type of high you are experiencing
are you experiencing the body high or
the head high or what hallucinations I
don't know Etc I think that it will get
to that level of accuracy and even
better I think that it will get to a
point where we will be able to personal
it so imagine that at a certain point
and I want to be one of the first ones
to say it because I really think it will
happen is that these devices will become
you know gadgets for consumers where you
will be able to wear it it will read
your brainway and will know who you are
what type of what type of brain you are
and based on that you will tell this app
hey you know I I want to relax today
okay you are this type of brain you want
to relax these are the type of products
that you should consume and this is how
you should consume them I I think that
that that would be the one of the late
latest stages of adoptions uh of
adoption of where e g technology and AI
for for this type of consumer package
good markets like personalized
recommendations of product used to
accomplish and experience yeah I mean I
can definitely I can definitely see a
future with that I mean I I wear my
Apple watch I track my recovery and all
that to inform when uh if I should work
out or not so um it definitely seems
like uh that's a
possibility totally Benjamin I I you
know to I mean we believe in this 10
years ago and that's why we continue
doing this because we want to be
somebody needs to do it and we want to
be one of the first in doing it and I
just really think that is um nobody has
built the databases that are required to
unlock the potential of artificial
intelligence to help us you know make
this type of brain analysis to
understand cognitive emotional or mental
states of people and and and I think
that this is just the beginning of many
other applications this technology as I
was sharing with you was built for
safety and law enforcement
I I I just realized 10 years ago or
eight years ago that cops were not going
to use this technology right away first
because it's a little bit of removing a
little bit of their you know power
because it's no longer you giving your
expert opinion it's still subjective
though it's now you know an objective
assessment and I think it was very
controversial at that time to prove that
you could have the see in
saliva and and our EEG show that your
brain WS are not altered anymore so our
PE reviewed publication show that this
evidence could eliminate up to 50% of
inaccurate accusations of being impaired
or not being impaired just because of
the amount of THC in Sal or whatever so
I I think that the you know these new
neurot Technologies not not only Centras
maybe others will be adopted by several
other non-medical markets that continue
you know depending on subjective
assessments of uh people right so but
it's a very very very exciting a time
for for everyone who is in these spaces
yeah yeah and when you talk about
impairment too like would it would it
work for alcohol like to correlate
someone's blood alcohol content to how
effective they actually are exactly you
know in fact I think that right now our
our perception of impairment is a little
bit I don't know if limited is the word
but but maybe it's not you know fully
aware of what impairment means and you
know you could be driving and you are
impaired because you are in Shock you
are hyper stressed you are extremely
tired you are extremely piss because
something happened to you and now you're
driving so aggressively you know you you
may be Dr you might be high with
cannabis you might be you know high with
so many other substances so I think
that's why I was mentioning building
these
databases directly Associated to all of
these states is what it will unlock the
law
enforcement use of this type of
technology to Better h you know to
improve safety on our roads and and you
know it's it's it's not we haven't
forgotten about that market but we just
believe that is just the tip of the
iceberg and it's it's a longer term
application I think that just for pure
you know cannabis effect research for
you know educational purposes to help
Brands you know prove you know product
quality and differentiate their products
is is just an ontap Market that is right
there and and that's what we have been
doing in the last three years yeah I
know and when you're talking about like
sort of personalizing it and having you
know one of your own for sort of your
personal use like I can imagine you know
if you were wearing something it's
probably be a different device but
you're getting ready to write a an email
to someone it kind of triggers like you
might be a little too upset you might
want to on it before you write that
email exactly Brokers right hey wait
wait don't invest it that you are super
excited be more you know objectives
think about it come back exactly like
measuring that type of emotions will
enable many other markets to make better
more accurate more informed decisions
about so many other things right all
right Israel so so wrapping up here so
you mentioned that you're coming to CED
25 in Puerto Rico this June and we're
very excited to have you so you're going
to be presenting this this data and
sharing this information I'm just
curious what folks are you interested in
connecting with there um you know maybe
this is a good time to kind of put out
there who you're looking to connect with
so that they can come down and meet you
absolutely we are I'm I'm very much
looking forward to H you know uh
connecting with other researchers and
product developers and and food
scientists and and high quality Brands
all of those you know licensed producers
that are building truly Innovative and
high quality products I I am very much
looking forward to meeting with them and
presenting our work because I I really
think that one of the biggest challenges
that the entire the global cannabis
Market is facing is saturation and
undifferentiation and and right now the
consumer is not aware of that and they
don't believe in words but what we have
been doing in Massachusetts which I will
be presenting is about the way we
helping all of these companies to
differentiate their high quality
products regardless of their canabo
properties and and leverage that to
really transform the way they develop
products they test them and also they
take them to Market and educate
retailers and consumers to really
differentiate their brands and their
products and I really think that that's
the future of cannabis cpg and I'm very
much looking forward to connecting with
other you know uh companies that really
appreciate this scientific approach to
innovate and differentiate their
business excellent well you will be in
the right place all right one more thing
before I let you go I want to give you
an opportunity to share any additional
resources that the listeners or viewers
might be interested in in reading more
about to learn more about the technology
and and the things that you're
developing and of course website social
media anything like that please plug
away absolutely I I think that the the
the the best way to you know bring you
up to speed is to connect on LinkedIn
that's the platform I use to share news
share some of the highest and most
exciting results that you know as soon
as we complete the studies
Etc my name is Israel gasperin H you can
find me on link linking with my complete
name also you know our website
centr.com but most importantly if you
look for peer review Publications using
the name of our artificial intelligence
the
cognizer cogn cognizer cognizer because
we have a breath analyzer Etc this is
the cognitive
analyzer calyer uh you can find our PE
reviewed
Publications that you know prove and
explain and elaborate the the
objectivity accuracy sensitivity and
specificity and applications of this
technology for multiple times of uh
human research or investigation so I
think that that could be a very good
introductory uh kind of content that you
can gain to to to get more context and
and hopefully when we meet in uh at
canmet we can have more insightful and
and interesting conversations excellent
I will put links to all of those
resources in the show description so
people can easily find it um Israel
thanks again for taking the time it was
a great talk and looking forward to
meeting you in person down in Puerto
Rico in June that sounds great Benjamin
thank you again for having me and having
this very exciting conversation and
looking forward to meeting you in person
as well
[Music]