about four years ago I had the pleasure
of meeting Lucy with her daughter and at
the time she was 89 years old and had
been diagnosed with advanced stage
dementia her dementia was so advanced
that she was incomprehensible with her
speech she was falling every day and was
now becoming a safety risk in her own
home and the facility where she lived
was requesting that Lucy be moved into a
memory care unit Lucy had a 40 year
history of multiple sclerosis and
migraines and insomnia she'd been using
dilaudid and gabapentin along with
ambien that louder how's that I was
hoping how's that all right yeah you
missed a really good story the end so
Lucy had a 40 year history of multiple
sclerosis migraines as well as insomnia
and she'd been using dilaudid
gabapentin and ambien to manage her
symptoms when I met with her daughter
who had durable power of healthcare and
Lucy Lucy didn't even engage with me she
couldn't focus her speech was
incomprehensible we decided to focus on
her pain and sleep I started Lucy on a
one-to-one 2.5 milligram THC and two
point five milligrams CBD capsule twice
a day and 10 milligrams of a one to one
at night within three months we were
successfully able to get Lucy off her
gabapentin her ambien and her dilaudid
and she only needed to take her high
blood pressure medications she became
alert and oriented she lost 25 pounds
she stopped falling she was sleeping
through the night and for the first time
in 40 years Lucy did not complain of
pain she had such a remarkable recovery
that her daughter was successful at
getting her diagnosis of advanced stage
dementia removed from her medical record
about six months after taking cannabis
the med tech came by one day and knocked
on her door and said Lucy I have your
marijuana and Lucy said I don't take
marijuana her daughter who had durable
power of healthcare was able to make
that decision for her but hadn't had
that conversation yet and so that opened
up the conversation and Lucy realized
that she did get her life back and so
she started to become an advocate at her
facility talking to other residents
about the use of cannabis for their
symptoms fast forward three years later
Lucy was turning 92 she was originally
from France and her daughter wanted to
surprise her with a trip to France for
the first time in 50 years and so Tania
called me and she said Eloise
how do I travel to France with moms
cannabis and I said you don't she said
what do we do and I said well we should
probably take her off of it and if her
symptoms return you may need to consider
pharmaceuticals so we did and within a
week her symptoms started to return and
she was placed back on gabapentin and
within ten days on gabapentin her speech
became incomprehensible again and she
started to have multiple Falls the
daughter was clearly frustrated took her
off gabapentin and sent me an email and
said I am gonna just mail it ahead of
the time to the hotel and hope it makes
it and I said please don't tell me that
I don't want to know that you're
smuggling drugs into France and she
laughs and then a week later I got the
email that said the eagle has landed
my name is Eloise Thiessen and I'm a
board certified adult geriatric nurse
practitioner I have a clinic in Walnut
Creek with a physician dr. David Ferrara
where we now treat patients who want to
use cannabis as a treatment modality
I've seen close to 5,500 patients and
within those 50 500 patients you'll see
here what I'm going to present today is
some of the data overall the average age
of my patient
about 76 they're primarily female at 85%
they've never used cannabis before and
as you can see they don't want to smoke
it and they don't want to get high and
more recently they asked me not to gain
weight or get the munchies so one of the
things that I recognized as a clinician
was that there's really no way for me to
collect cannabis data I looked and
looked for an electronic health record
that would help me put patient
information in there and start to
provide me with some feedback on my data
all of this data that I collected here
was by me going through manually
handwritten charts that patients had
filled out and then I was fortunate
enough to find a company that is working
on some data collection and they came in
and looked at about 220 of my chronic
pain patients and you'll see that the
the numbers are much different than my
overall patient population I have about
34 percent of females are coming to me
specifically for pain and about close to
50 of them are male and you'll see that
17% is blank because what we realize is
that it's not a mandatory field for them
to identify their gender so that is
definitely something we learned from
there is there any way you could get my
powerpoints a little bit bigger on here
I don't I don't need the notes after all
would you mind please because I can't
see it's funny I usually tell the joke
when my picture comes up because
patients asked me if that's my daughter
rude
apparently cannabis doesn't help with it
gray hair nor does it help with baldness
but apparently you can put it in your
attic where okay some other trends that
we identified here were whether or not
patients had any previous experience
with cannabis and in my pain population
of these 220 patients we found about
almost 35% had no previous experience
they weren't currently using it
and about 48 percent had at least tried
it at some point and again we have a
blank area because we realized that it's
not a mandatory field and these are some
of the different pain categories that
they identified so you'll see most
patients coming to me or cancer my
background prior to cannabis was
oncology so it's natural for patients to
come see me for symptom relief related
to cancer treatment a lot of them
identified it as chronic pain or other
diseases that were causing pain like
Lyme disease or lupus stenosis was also
a big category the different routes of
administration although 62 percent
weren't currently using it to treat
their pain the 37 percent that we're
using it most of them were using
sublingual followed by topical and then
ingestion and inhalation and when I do
my data collection I do do a full review
of symptoms so sometimes patients will
come to me for chronic pain but through
that review of systems I'll actually
identify other ways that cannabis may be
helpful for them like mood improvement
sleep anxiety many of them identified
cardiovascular issues so I have a lot of
patients who have high blood pressure we
know that as we age blood pressure rates
can go up I do have a lot of patients
with atrial fibrillation other
musculoskeletal issues urinary issues
again I have a lot of females so
typically that means they're having
incontinence respiratory issues like
coughing or shortness of breath so
chronic pain is definitely something
that we're all probably going to
experience as we age although the
statistics say that about one in four
adults over the age of 65 will report
chronic pain by 2035 and right now it's
costing us about five hundred and sixty
billion dollars per year and direct
medical costs lost productivity and
disability we also know it's one of the
most common conditions in older adults
65 and up with 40% of them reporting
chronic pain it's more common in females
and patients over the age of 85
and when people have chronic pain
they're also likely to suffer from
depression anxiety insomnia isolation
and falls and here's our current
pharmacological recommendations for
geriatric patients this is our standard
of care we start them at acetaminophen
or Tylenol and that's usually for low to
moderate pain we have quite a bit of
evidence it's high quality of evidence
to demonstrate that tylenol or
acetaminophen is safe and effective for
chronic pain although we have to be very
concerned about potential liver toxicity
in this population then we move into
NSAIDs or your ibuprofen your
anti-inflammatories again these two are
available over-the-counter and we have
quite a bit of evidence high amount of
evidence to demonstrate that and seds or
anti-inflammatories can be effective we
should only be using them for short term
use though because the long term effects
especially in anybody over the age of 65
can be things like decreased kidney
function increased risk of atrial
fibrillation and gastritis or
gastrointestinal side effects I can't
tell you how many patients I have that
are using tylenol and ibuprofen just
over the counter without the direction
of a clinician our physician because
they think it's safe if the
acetaminophen or NSAIDs are ineffective
we can go to tramadol and when I was
doing my research I found this
incredibly interesting that the quality
of evidence to support using tramadol
and geriatric patients has not been
reported but we're happy to give this to
our patients especially because we want
to avoid opioids oh I guess my updated
slides didn't get in there okay there's
an error on the bottom there you'll
notice we have tricyclic antidepressants
that can be used for neuropathic pain we
also have anticonvulsants like the
gabapentin which can be used for
neuropathic pain and we have low to
moderate evidence in those medications
but again they seem to be widely
prescribed when I'm meeting with
patients safety considerations in our
anticonvulsant should be peripheral
edema
neuropathy and then of course opioids
right which we're using for moderate to
severe pain but the quality of evidence
is low and we have safety considerations
you know as tolerance sedation but of
course death is the biggest safety
consideration and then there's cannabis
which is not currently on our
pharmacological standard of care for
geriatric patients or any patient right
now at the quality of evidence is high
not i GH we have quite a bit of you know
we even know that the National Academy
of Sciences recommends cannabis for
chronic pain particularly neuropathic
and spasticity in safety considerations
dizziness sedation potential
hallucinations but we all know we heard
this earlier this is dose dependent we
can control these side effects much
easier with cannabis than we can the
pharmaceutical options and with opioids
we know that we're now experiencing
we're seeing about a hundred and thirty
deaths per day and when I started to
observe in my clinic is that with the
CDC guidelines were changed in 2016 they
changed the practice guidelines because
what they noticed in the literature from
2004 and 2009 not the literature when
they looked at overdoses from 2004 to
2009 they saw that those as prescribed
at 48 and that Mme is morphine milli
equivalent dosages between 48 and 98 per
day was where they saw the highest rate
of overdoses so the CDC came in and said
let's lower the morphine milli
equivalent to 50 milligrams a day and
not to exceed 90 unless documentation
supports higher dosages and just to give
you an idea of a morphine equivalent
that's about 510 milligram hydrocodone a
day so what's happened is that
clinicians physicians are coming in and
starting to reduce these dosages based
on the new CDC guidelines but they're
not really offering their patients any
alternative right so it's not a surprise
that in states where they have access
that patients are looking to cannabis as
a potential solution for their pain so
as a clinician where do you start if you
have a patient who's taking 50
milligrams of hydrocodone a day
what's that THC equivalent what we did
is we looked at the literature we know
that there's five milligrams of THC can
be about as effective as 30 milligrams
of codeine so we went in to an equal
analgesic chart and crunched the numbers
so that you can get an idea of some of
the potential max doses of THC that a
patient may need to replace their
opioids depending on how much they're on
I'm not aware of any literature that
demonstrates CBD as an equal analgesic
so usually what I do in my practice is
add in CBD to help decrease some of the
unwanted effects of THC and cannabis use
among seniors has increased tenfold from
2007 to 2017 and I'll often go to other
talks where I hear people tell me that
it's a myth that seniors are the
fastest-growing demographic of cannabis
users I disagree most of my patients are
75 and older they never used it they
never even smoked a joint in college or
high school so they really are new to
cannabis and they're seeking relief from
things like anxiety pain insomnia and
there's a lot of barriers for them
access a lack of guidance and education
the stigma of cannabis I currently have
a patient I've been treating for the
last three years who was homebound as a
result of her back pain and since
starting cannabis she's now able to
travel again with her husband and get
out of the house she got her life back
and she comes and sees me every year for
a checkup and I said Kathy have you told
your adult children yet that you're
using cannabis and she said oh no Eloise
I spent my whole life telling them to
say no to drugs
I said Kathy they have to know you're
doing better right aren't they asking
you what's different she said yes and I
said what do you tell them she said I
tell them I do alternative things
that's how deep the stigma is for her
the shame is for her she won't even have
these open conversations with her adult
children and of course the cost you know
I'm from California we've seen an
increase in the price as much as 50
percent for some of these products so
what I wanted to do was dive in deeper
to the data that I had of course because
it's all handwritten I have to go in
manually so I picked 50 female patients
who came in and they were suffering from
chronic pain they also had reported
anxiety depression or sleep issues and
of those 50 patients 33 of them were
cannabis naive the average number of
prescriptions they were on was about 3
when we had one patient who was using it
as many as 8 then about 10 patients were
using 5 or more of these 50 patients we
identified 11 of them that had insomnia
or sleep related issues either as a
primary or secondary diagnosis we also
had 36 patients who had a chronic pain
as a primary secondary diagnosis now
again remember if somebody comes in and
sees me for a sleep issue I may identify
that their sleep is not they're not
getting quality sleep because they're
having pain issues of the 36 patients 16
of them had osteoporosis 15 had
neuropathic pain sorry about that
boom can you hear me if I step back a
little bit okay and about four patients
had other conditions pain conditions 19
of these patients had anxiety or
depression as a primary or secondary
diagnosis and the other day a secondary
diagnosis included migraines tremors
Parkinson's disease Lyme's disease and
cancer out of those 50 patients only six
patients reported no improvement with
cannabis so 44 out of 50 felt that they
got some effects or relief with cannabis
thank you five of them used a cannabis
tincture and one of them used a cannabis
edible of the patients who experienced
improvement this is just a little bit of
a
shot of the different types of products
they were using most were using an
account of his tincture a lot of my
senior patients prefer that route of
administration it's easy for them to
titrate they have a lot more control
over their dose and their experience 3
of them used a can of a cannabis
vaporizer only 13 of them had multiple
routes of administration and some of us
who have experienced pain or helped
people with pain know that sometimes you
need multiple methods to help control
the pain and 9 other had single routes
of administration or products like a
topical a tablet or a capsule and when
we ask them whether or not a clinician
provided treatment plan was effective
for treating the primary secondary
diagnosis as I said 44 out of 50
responded yes we went ahead and looked
and see to look at the hours of sleep
that patients reported prior to starting
cannabis and on average of 35 patients
is about five and a half hours and after
starting cannabis they were reporting
increased sleep of about 6.5 hours again
where they weren't necessarily coming to
me for sleep but we did notice over all
that sleep improved I think we've heard
that multiple times this last two days
as well and before pain their pain score
before cannabis was six point nine and
thirty two patients afterwards was three
point nine and I really just want to
highlight right now and take an
opportunity to highlight the role of the
advanced practice nurse and nurses in
general I haven't heard many
conversations about nurses in the last
two days and I want you guys to know or
three point nine million strong
[Applause]
in North America alone numbers-wise we
outnumber physicians five to one you're
missing an opportunity here in the
industry by not engaging nurses right
and if you look at the data that came
out of California for nurse
practitioners we actually have lower
rates of preventable hospitalizations
readmissions emergency visits when
compared to physicians patients are more
likely to receive education and
counseling from nurse practitioners than
they are from their physicians and were
less likely to prescribe opioids for
pain so we're ready we're ready we have
the American cannabis Nurses Association
and the incoming president the 1,300
members and 48 states and our mission is
to educate collaborate and advocate so I
encourage you all to know that we are an
ally we're looking for strategic
partnerships because it takes a lot of
us to get together and collaborate and
when I look at the research that I have
right now in the ways that I want to
improve here are some implications for
research that I would like to see now
how do we engage patients to maintain
follow-up appointments to help them
eliminate pain medications and achieve
success
for me the biggest barrier is cost they
have to pay out of pocket for my
appointment and the cost of medicine and
then any follow-up appointments they
struggle with the cost of the
medications the fact that insurance
doesn't cover it they can get their
gabapentin sometimes for 50 cents for a
month's supply right how do we compete
with that when a tincture can be $70
before regulatory taxes that may last
them a couple weeks and can we measure
success rates when patients are working
with clinicians directly versus going
into a dispensary first what I have
found when I would do speak with people
in the industry particularly producers
or dispensaries they often tell me that
they're spending anywhere from 30 to 60
minutes in a new Senior patient who may
be coming to them about cannabis so
again we have this opportunity here to
engage with clinicians help reduce that
amount of time
that maybe some of the staff is spending
answering questions for their patients
and get them on the right track right
away because if we can find their
medicine they have to take it daily
sometimes multiple times today so this
is where we want to be focusing on is
medicine for these patients okay I
actually have a little bit of time for
questions um I think I have about eight
minutes if anybody hasn't yeah I don't
know if there's a mic there's a
microphone in the middle and if anybody
has questions about the data our data
scientist is here because I don't speak
that language I was wondering when
you're to expand a little bit further on
engaging nurse practitioners and
obviously possibly educating nurse
practitioners so Illinois is just coming
on to be you know adult use recreational
so I'm not really sure if there are any
networks that are already established in
Illinois and if not what would or what
or how would you do would you say to
create this type of a network yes so we
do have the American cannabis Nurses
Association we do have members in
Illinois and actually a couple of them
are nurse practitioners so by joining
the organization you do get that network
I'm in that opportunity to see what
they're doing and there's lots of
educational opportunities I can talk
about offline with you so that you can
you know start to get thank you yeah I
just got a quick one I'm dr. Gillian
Smith a pain physician where did you get
the slide about the Oh me cannabis
conversion like how did you come to that
which one were you talking about the
Ami's and then the cannabis my charts
yes oh oh we did that we what we did is
we looked at the the we took the data
from five milligrams of THC can be equal
to 30 milligrams of codeine and then we
went in and looked at at a standard
equal analgesic chart with codeine and
hydromorphone and oxycodone and
hydrocodone and we did the math where
did you get that five to thirty I can
give you the reference
I don't have it off the top of my head
but yeah it's there's some literature
out there okay the five milligrams yeah
that'd be great thank you
yeah you're welcome this is what you're
talking about right okay yeah I was up
there wasn't it oh it's on my screen I'm
sorry I'm like what are you guys talking
about
okay thank you so much i pyrius if you
could give some clinical tips and pearls
of how do you start the process with the
older adult mm-hmm
that's a great question I'm fortunate
enough to have 45 minutes with each new
patient and really I have them fill out
a pretty thorough health history
beforehand and when they come and I want
to know their goals because I may look
at their thing and think oh they're
coming here for pain right but they're
really coming here for sleep and of
course low-and-slow
the education helps them to feel less
anxious about it because they have a lot
of misconceptions and I usually ask them
not to what are your misconception or
what are your what brought you to
cannabis are you concerned about
anything you know you hear that euphoria
and I loved how dr. Sulak addressed it
today because often I'll say it apace
you wait to feel better more relaxed
more communicative with your spouse you
know and they're like well yeah I'm like
well that's the euphoria from cannabis
right so they start to come around with
education and they get less scared about
proceeding so I'm a physician in
Maryland and I work with a nurse
practitioner thank you
and I'm a big fan of nurse practitioners
yeah so don't don't everybody go
crapping on doctors no no it's
collaborative
we need not all cut from the same cloth
you know one comment and then a question
my comment is that I have a similar
practice cohort to you a lot of elderly
patients all fearful of getting stoned
and my main concern in them is on
unsteadiness on their feet and fallings
I'm very cautious about dosing my
question is why have I forgotten my
question it's not cannabis related it's
not that I'll check with you offline
it's like being gone sorry yeah and just
so you know that they don't call it dope
for nothing the average dose that most
of my patients are taking is about 2.5
to 10 milligrams of cannabinoids so it's
pretty low and I support the concerns
about falling yeah okay great yes I my
name's Thank You Eloise my name is John
Calvert I've had the privilege of being
in the cannabis industry going on nine
years right now and I've also had the
privilege for almost two years and
working with this wonderful lady up here
you're amazing yeah Louise my question
is this and first a statement everyone
that's in this room and everyone has had
the privilege of listening to Raphael
and Sulak and all these wonderful
speakers here the baseline is education
and the challenge is that I have is my
business and our company is really
getting the word out there and so Eloise
is all about education it's her middle
name
it's your initial article yes so and it
takes dedication beyond that anything
yeah you're shaking your head you damn
well bet it takes education but it takes
a commitment you sign on for a first
some sort of a seminar it's over in an
hour but you sign on to take a webinar
series that lasts four hours it takes
tremendous dedication so elbow using
your experience past experience and
going forward can you list what you
think are the top three mechanisms the
ways that were waving the magic wand
whatever it is what do you think the
baseline and how to get the message out
thank you oh great that's like a huge
question John you could have sent it to
me ahead of time to sound intelligent I
think it's about collaboration and
coming together and I hope that I didn't
come across like we don't need
physicians okay good because I'm very
aware of that and sense
I think we need all all of us together
whether it's the the growers the bud
tenders the manufacturers the clinicians
we are all here to help patients and we
have to really continue to plant those
seeds because not everybody's ready
right and then we come back and water it
a little bit and then we come back and
water it and eventually the results are
going to speak for themselves and people
will naturally like we're seeing now
gravitate towards it oh well we'll take
off mine because we have nice people in
line two seconds mm-hmm yeah yeah yes of
course I think it's money well spent we
can talk about it offline too and and
you can see that I don't know if I'm
managing this well sorry how about we go
here hi hi thank you so much for working
with older people yeah thank you um my
question is about cannabis and how it
might help dementia hmm
in our experience cannabis really helps
dementia but I'm not a doctor I'm just
the family caregiver turned advocate can
you tell us your experience working with
dementia yeah well the role that you
have is really important so don't say
just Thanks yeah I mean because dementia
is a very challenging disease as you
know and it's another presentation I
could do I'm really fortunate in
California to work with assisted living
communities that will dispense cannabis
under a written order by the physician
and myself I'd like to get a list of
those people yeah so I have about three
dozen patients right now who are using
cannabis for their agitation anxiety and
it's dramatic the results that we see is
it a large dose or small dose not two
milligrams of THC for most yeah not CBD
a few times a day it depends but yeah
anywhere from 1 to 4 times a day
awesome thank you so much yeah you're
welcome mm-hmm I have 17 seconds I
really final offer okay what route of
administration is this based on that's
oral okay oral through the gut or
tincture well my experience this is my
disclaimer here I find that most
oil-based tinctures follow the pattern
congestion so yeah through the gut
alright thank you guys so much for your
attention
[Applause]