we're gonna jump in to a different topic
here we're gonna change gears a little
bit and dive into genomics here so for
those who weren't here last year last
year we had the great joy of presenting
really one of the most complete cannabis
references completed to date now there
have been a lot of cannabis references
generated over the years and we've
generated some and many in this audience
have as well and they've been very
difficult to read mainly because of the
complexity of the genome it's very
polymorphic and it's very 8e rich so
when we finally got and assembly put
together with with Pacific Biosciences
it was really a joy of you know a day of
joy because we had not really seen what
all of these cannabinoid genes look like
in relationship to one another so today
we're gonna shift gears a little bit and
not talk about just that one reference
genome that we built but we're gonna
talk about 42 more of them that we've
since done since we started on this last
year so this was funded by a
cryptocurrency there's a talk that we
did last year describing how this was
done it was a five month grant that was
voted on by over 4,700 individuals
around the world to contribute some
cryptocurrency to this project is
actually sequence a cannabis genome and
this required about five months of
effort and in 60 days from being funded
we put the first assembly from Pacific
Biosciences up on the web at I think it
was a 600 and this like 60kb and 50 now
you're gonna hear a couple terms
throughout this talk about how you
monitor and assess the quality of
cannabis genomes and 50 is a measurement
of the average length of the context
sizes and you want these things to get
to be about the size of chromosomes
ideally that is rarely ever the case in
fact the first chromosome assembly for
the human genome just occurred last
month on I don't know one of the smaller
promos ohms and it's taken us like 19
years to figure that out because the
sequencing technologies really just
can't handle some parts of genomes so
this after we put this public we quickly
put up a preprint to get the data public
for everybody else after after the
August release and I think this one had
a even more contiguous assembly and that
n50 number was out to past three mega
bases now the other term you can hear us
talk about in terms of monitoring these
genomes
is a busco score which is an evaluation
of how many genes you should have in the
genome that are seen in all other plants
and if you're missing some of those
you'll probably have some completeness
issues okay so we were seeing these
genomes run up to a 97% busco score
which is a great in silica way to tell
you that your genomes getting close to
being done but really the the nail in
the coffin is when other people pick up
the data and measure it with different
techniques and come back with very
similar numbers and so I think there's
some probably members in the audience
that were involved in this wonderful
work on the proteome where they took
cannabis proteomes or measured them via
mass spec by doing a metabolite profile
and from there they were able to get
peptide signatures they could map to the
Jamaican lion reference and they were
low and behold finding that the Jamaican
lion reference produced the most number
of peptides that matched their proteome
data and then Reggie and his team with
Keith Allen at steep hill also grabbed
the Jamaican lion reference and then
annotated all of the terpene synthase
genes and recently published this paper
in PLoS about some unique features of
the terpene genes that we now know about
it so what's novel in the cannabis
genome is that many of the terpene
synthase genes have very long introns
this can be a problem if your assemblies
are somewhat fragmented because you
won't be able to piece these genes
together in the correct order or
orientation these are 55 in the terpene
synthase chains that they studied these
cover the monoterpenes assess quote
terpenes and i believe even some of the
diets were Keynes who are still digging
into the triterpene x' which we're gonna
touch on a little bit later in this
presentation but there's great work here
demonstrating that there is
co-occurrence or Co expression of
certain terpenes like human and
beta-carotene and they're probably
coming from the same genes okay so with
that said if you want to study the
terpene synthase genes you really have
to look at the chloroplast genomes
because half of the pathways inside the
plastic genome and to do that with
Pacific Biosciences sequencing you you
really need very high coverage and long
reads to do this
these this is a depiction here of what
looks like ten different chloroplast
genomes that are in the plant now we are
expecting to find one and now two of
these I think we can rule out that
they're actually nuclear genomes sorry
right there these are what are known as
nups there's a lot of transfer of DNA
from chloroplasts to the autism
and as a result you have to itemize
which ones are actually in the autosomes
and which ones are actually in the
organelles because the ones in the
autosomes are usually silence with
methylation so we do be doing a quick
scan on these to look at the depth of
coverage we have across those contexts
and then how much methylation is
actually present on those contexts so
that we can decide whether these are
organelle euro or silenced autosomal
copies of them but this does bring us
back to some questions about the nature
of chloroplast genomes we're always
taught in biology class that these
things are circular but the reality is
when you have sequencing capacity of
this power you capture these organelles
in the process of DNA replication live
and so you what you end up finding is
not just a perfect circular genome but a
bit of a Hydra where these when these
things are replicating there all of
these photo competent branches coming
off the circle that have certain
polymorphisms and then that we need to
keep track of the reason we're paying
close attention to chloroplast genetics
here is that if you look through a lot
of the genome engineering that's going
on in plants the vast majority of the
yield improvements are coming out of
modifying the photosynthesis pathways
moving things from c3 to c4
photosynthesis or modifying parts of
this of this genome those are seeing 50%
40% yield increases in a variety of
different organisms and so we really
have to understand the chloroplast
genome to get yield right and to get the
terpene synthases done correctly as well
and this gentleman Arnold been - had had
put out - a wonderful paper showing that
genomes really aren't circular when you
when you when you when you put them
under a microscope and we're seeing the
same thing with the single molecule
sequencing so how do we do the
methylation well this was done with New
England Biolabs now the thing about
cannabis is it's very hard to study its
methylation patterns because a lot of
the single the single molecule
sequencers out there aren't trained to
look for these methylation patterns
they're much more complex than human
methyl owns and so we're still resorting
to an older technique known as bisulfite
sequencing which converts the genome
anything that has a non methylated
cytosines it's converted to a thymine
alright so your genome then gets peeled
into two different genomes and it goes
from 66 percent 80 into 83 percent 80
this makes it really complicated to read
with short reads I think only about 50%
of the genomes mapable once you do this
but nevertheless you can still study
some of the genes and understand what's
going on with methylation so New England
Biolabs developed this methylation kit
that
is has less bias in the process of doing
this assessment and we deployed it on
five different tissues from the plant on
female flowers female seeded flowers
male flowers leaves and roots so that we
get an understanding of what's going on
throughout this process and the most
interesting thing that's that pops out
at you when you look at differential
methylation throughout the genome is
methylation in the Edisto gene so the
intestine gene is what makes the hemp
seeds so nutritious all right this is
the globular protein that gets made in
the hemp seed and if we want to feed the
world we need to understand how to hyper
express this protein well what's
interesting about the expression of this
protein is you can see that it is
differentially methylated in seeded
flowers versus female flowers and that
makes sense once the the female flowers
get seeded they start making seeds so
they turn the ax destined gene into high
gear
they hypo methylated take the
methylation signals off and let gene
expression occur when they want to shut
it down they methylated and this
silences transcription so we can see
these methylation patterns and they're
beginning to correlate with the
messenger RNA sequencing the other gene
you need to know about if you want to
feed the world is the THC gene alright
this is one that stimulates people to
eat particularly in cancer scenarios and
we can see similar methylation patterns
there where the male flowers have these
little red bars here and there those
things are effectively methylated and
shut down and the blue bars up here are
signifying bases in the genome that are
under methylated or unmethylated and so
transcription is turned on so we can
look at just the methylation signals on
the DNA to understand what genes might
be active and which ones are inactive
plants have different methylation than
humans as I mentioned before there's CPG
methylation there's CEHD methylation in
there CH h methylation and this means
the patterns a little bit more complex
to to read them what we see in human
genomes and so what you end up seeing if
you look at just flowers like male
flowers versus female flowers you see a
vast array of differential methylation
signals between the genomes now if you
move over to female flowers and female
seeded flowers this picture becomes a
little softer because there's less
differences between the genes between
those different biological events and if
you actually categorize them for ones
that are statistically significant the
genes that pop out are things like a
Destin and some of the cannabinoids and
face genes like
see so the methylation patterns are
giving us some picture of which genes
are on and off and it's a very sort of
simple survey that helps compliment
anything you do with RNA now that does
bring us to the RNA side of things
there's before jump on there there's a
500 to 700 different sites that are
hyper or hyper mo fellated with very
strong p-values that we're paying close
attention to and combing through but you
really want sequencing information of
the RNA to understand what's going on
here and so there are these great new
tools from Pacific Biosciences that
allow you to sequence an entire RNA
molecule 50 to 100 times over as a
single molecule to get better than
saying or data to annotate genomes like
this this is something known as ISO seek
and when we do this what you're seeing
here is the lap the number of laps that
we're getting around the molecule we
turn these molecules into circles and
they run like a gerbil on a wheel with a
polymerase measuring incorporation and
you can read this molecule over and over
and over again with these sequencers to
get very high accuracy and what you're
seeing down below is the average
transcript length that's in the genome
so some of them are getting out to be 5
KB genes which is quite long and you can
see the average in there is around one
to two thousand bases long what this
does it gives us a picture of all the
different isoforms that are in the
genome so an isoform is a version of a
gene any given gene can have multiple
exons and those exons can be
differentially spliced and when they're
differentially spliced they create a
different RNA molecule so each gene can
have two or three different RNA
molecules coming off of it that's what
we call an isoform and interestingly
enough the male flowers have more
isoforms and the female flowers and
we're in a habit of getting rid of these
things as fast as we can find them but
we might find some very interesting
biology in there that give us some pause
on that on that genocide so what else we
can find from this is we can take these
RNA molecules we can then map them to
the reference genome and then identify
where all the genes are in the genome
and so we can annotate the genome and
what we're seeing is around 27,000 genes
that are female gene models and this
gives us an underestimation of the exome
size inside cannabis as well it's about
44 mega bases of exome there's 35 mega
bases of this that are coding because
parts of exomes can be utrs and there's
121 mega bases that if you include the
intron so this is bigger than the human
exome yet the genome
about a third of the size of the human
genome so it's kind of an interesting
adaptation that we're seeing in cannabis
and of course if you're gonna do this in
females you have to do it in males we
just saw that males have more isoforms
and so what we've done it's taken all of
the RNA that we've done from those five
tissues and map them against a male
assembly that we now have and we can
identify that there's even more genes
that are active in the male genome this
thirty to thirty two thousand of those
genes and about four thousand of them
that are that are differentially
expressed in the male this also helps us
decorate the y chromosome we can see
parts of the Y chromosome now that are
about 80 mega bases that do not
recombine with the X chromosome and
about 30 mega bases that is still
recombining with the X chromosome so if
you're gonna build any sex tests you
want to put it in the region of the Y
that does not Rican by Nando I show you
run into some trouble likewise another
paper great paper came out from the
worst burn laboratory doing more mass
spec on cannabis genomes and we soaked
up those fast day files and compared
them to the more recent references we
have in 98.8% of the mass spec data is
detected inside the genome now we have
the advantage of being able to amplify
RNA so we can pick up more really low
incident events it's very hard to
amplify proteins and so it's not
surprising that the protein systems are
not finding all of the peptides are
finding about 40% of what we see in the
genome but there's a very high overlap
with what they do find is being real and
so these can be very complementary tools
because you can pick up like oscillation
and other signals with with the mass
spec data okay so let's let's look at a
couple examples here's and here's a gene
that has been studied heavily by
Jonathan page called the the pile
transferase gene it's involved in taking
a live italic acid and converting it
into cannabic erikak acid but it can do
it in two different ways and the plant
predominantly is making this form CB GA
but what we're seeing in the genome is
that there are several cases of tissue
specific expression of alternative
isoforms where we see two exons skipped
in the female flowers and three exon
skipped in the male flowers we don't
know what that means
it may have some may play some role and
giving us some alternative synthesized
cannabinoids it's that's something yet
to be yet to be resolved now there's
some other things people always ask is
what other genes are being Co inherited
with the cannabinoids right these
cannabinoids synthase gene clusters have
been shown
have very low recombination between them
so it makes you question what's the
linkage disequilibrium with and what
other genes are coming along for the
ride on those haplotypes well this is
the cannabic chromium synthase gene
cluster there's eight copies of the gene
all directionally oriented in one
direction and on the boundaries of this
of this gene we seem elect in expression
and we see angkeran expression these are
genes that are known to be involved in
pathogen defense that seem to be going
along for the ride with cannabic roaming
that's kind of initial little story the
THC synthase story is even more
interesting and that what you see
flanking THC s in the genome are
transpose aces these are enzymes that
copy chunks of DNA and shuttle them all
over the genome and it's probably the
reason why we have a cannabinoid gene
expansion inside of cannabis these
transposons are probably cutting it and
pasting it everywhere they can but also
within this same cluster are
differentially expressed cannabinoids
and face genes that we don't know what
they do these are getting differentially
expressed in different tissues and this
particular one shocked us because it
actually has an intron it most
cannabinoids synthase genes are believed
to be one exon very easy to study when
they start having introns then they can
alternately splice and give you more
common at Oryx and on isoforms and so
that's the first time we've seen in
intron inside of a functional
cannabinoid sensation at least one
that's getting expressed and in frame
what we see genome-wide is about 90 of
these different genes that have pfm
designation as a cannabinoid synthase
genes so there's a lot of genes to to
comb through here this is one that stood
out on the the CBDs con take this is
what's known as the self-incompatibility
protein that's used to prevent plants
from self pollinating all right so if
you have an obligate out crosser you're
gonna probably want this gene so you
can't self yourself now this is probably
a historical remnant of the hemp lines
which were known to be malicious but
once we move to dioecious plants those
things become obligate out crossers and
we don't know what the function of this
is but it's only expressed in male
flowers it may be may be very helpful to
understand what if we want to understand
hermaphroditism because hermaphroditism
is is probably linked into this into the
split now what you can see here is is
that this self-incompatibility gene is
tissue specifically expressed only in
male flowers and happens to be right
next door to CBD a s including a bunch
other novels and face genes that are
differentially expressed as well in a
very tissue specific manner so we have a
lot to do to understand the complexity
of the cannabinoid synthase genes and we
can't just be looking in female flowers
to find it we're gonna have to be
looking at at multiple tissues to
understand this so in speaking of that
we have to also look at the male genomes
the male x x and y chromosome so the
largest chromosomes in cannabis and the
Y the Y is actually larger than the X so
what's on the Y chromosome well what we
did is we took the RNA off of the male
flowers mapped it to the female
reference genome we have in the reads
that didn't map to the female we would
then map back to the male genome to tell
us which ones were male specifically
expressed and that gives you a hint as
to what parts of the genome are in fact
the white chromosome because none of
this stuff matches to the female genome
however female genomes can also have a
lot of structural variation in there so
this doesn't necessarily tell us that
this is all Y it tells us it's either Y
or it's in a structural variant in the
female genome then we're going to touch
on structural variants in just a minute
but this does give us a list of over 118
megabases of
target genome that is differentially
expressed or only expressed in the
male's compared to the females and
there's a lot of gene content in there
as well that to pay attention to now if
you really want to resolve the Y
perfectly the right thing to do is to
sequence three genomes what's known as a
trio a brother a sister and their
offspring is what we chose to sequence
here so it's a bit of an inbred cross
and when you do this you end up with
fairly routine and 50s over a mega base
in all cases we did not do any
optimization here we basically just
purified high molecular weight DNA put
it through this equal to platform and
out pop 1.6 mega base and 50s as a
comparison of reference point the human
genome a project went down to the White
House to celebrate 500 KB and 50s back
in 2000 and we're still waiting for
Donald's invite to celebrate this one
but I'm suspect it's coming anytime soon
but all of the all of the busco scores
are easily above 97% with just using a
single method so this is actually really
reassuring because in the past to tackle
genomes like this you'd have to deploy
five or six different methods to really
to really kill it and that's coming I
think coming to a close soon so this is
the actual family of other Jamaican
lines that we've sequence the rest of
these we hit with a short read platform
known as aluminum
and what you're seeing above each one of
these genome pictures here is a coverage
map across the BTB d allele the genes
that we just went over from that are
coding for the cannabinoid synthase
genes if you look at the coverage map
across those you can predict what
cannabinoids did the plant is going to
make alright and that that can be seen
in this little diagram here we can
detect with this tool that's on canopy
dia whether it's gonna be a type 1 type
2 type 3 or type 4 plant just from the
Illumina sequence coverage profiles
alone if they have an active THC allele
we know that's gonna make some THC if
that's in combination with a CBD gene
that's not even in the genome we know
it's a type 1 plant when all three of
these contacts are present we know it's
a type 2 plant
when only the act of CBD contexts
present and there is no THC contador the
CBD s inactive we know it's going to be
a type 3 plant and when none of them are
present it tends to be a CPG plant so
just looking at the coverage Maps alone
we can sort out it's it's its chemical
expression at least on those three
cannabinoids the other thing that you
want to do is compare this to other type
3 plants so Chris grasa is here and
presenting later later I think today or
tomorrow on a genome that's a type 3
plant a hemp line known as CBD rx and so
we like to do is always align the
reference genomes that we have is to
make Alliance what other people have
found in other states and other
jurisdictions to see that we come to
some level of consensus on this and
we're beginning to see that with both
the male and female genomes what you're
seeing here is a continued to continuous
alignment of our genomes to theirs and
you see these diagonal lines those all
represent the chromosomes the 10
chromosomes that you see in cannabis and
so we're beginning to get genomes that
now share a lot of a lot of content now
the next thing that we did is we took 40
genomes and sequence them with aluminum
now these are shorter reed systems that
can't get you to the whole genome and
they can't get you all the structural
variants but they can get you to all the
snips and the small insertions and
deletions in the genome so this year is
a histogram of the number of variants
that we see between the lines the
jamaican lion genomes are here and
they're usually 2 to 3 million variants
between those siblings but when you get
up into comparing those to hemp lines it
jumps up to about 12 million variants
all right as a perspective here the
human genome is going to have a part of
tenth of the number of variants that
we're seeing here per cannabis line
there's about a variant every thousand
bases in human there's one every 90
bases here in cannabis so there's a
tremendous amount of diversity here that
we have to comb through we also have
some sense of the insertions and
deletions from this data the data set as
well but what you can do when you have
the RNA data layered on top of the
genome is you know where all the genes
are so now you can take the variant
information and ask well how many of
those genes are broken by those variants
do we have any like frameshift mutations
do we have any stop codons that are
disappearing do we have any any start
codons that are changing and you do this
with a program known as sniff PFF it
looks at the heart of the impact of the
variants so we just went through and
asked how many high impact variants do
we have per cultivar because in humans
those numbers are really low in plants
like cannabis there's over 2,200 high
impact variants per cultivar so we've
got a lot to understand about what this
type of diversity actually actually
means you can also take all of this
sequencing data from the Illumina
platform map that all 40 of the genomes
to the male reference and what you see
here are 40 genomes lined up top the
bottom here these top ones are male
genomes and we're looking at the density
of coverage across all of the contexts
in the genome and it what's interesting
is the females have none here the red
means there's no coverage or at least
twofold less coverage than an average
and the yellow is twofold or greater
more coverage than average and so
instantly from a picture like this you
can identify all the contexts that are
present in the male's absent in the
females present at half the coverage in
the males and double the coverage in the
females that tells you X and y so now
we've got a list of all the genetic
content and the genes that are on x and
y so we can begin to understand what
things are really related to
hermaphroditism
a couple of interesting genes that pop
out on the Y we have some flowering
low-side we want to pay attention to
there's a cow cone synthase in there
there's a trichome gene involved there's
a downy mildew resistance gene that's
involved in there so a lot of activity
and the Y we don't want to ignore that
but the other thing that popped out of
this data completely accidentally was
with three of the genomes that are in
there from Colorado seeds this is an
interesting cross they've done that
that has some some some interesting
properties I'll say but what was
interesting about this is there are
these three hot spots that this to us is
a copy number variant when you see
something really bright yellow on this
map it tells you it's been replicated
and without knowing that this plant was
powdery mildew resistance we called them
up saying hey we have regions of your
genome that are amplified and they
happen to map to a gene that is powdery
mildew resistant in hops what do you
know about this plant I said well that's
interesting this thing it never gets
powdery mildew would surrounded by it
all the time and we want to know more
about that we weren't even looking for
this and it just jumped out by looking
at these these coverage maps so that
might be an interesting marker that we
want to track as we breed it into other
plants okay so let's touch on structural
variants I still have some time on
structural variants so many of you may
be familiar with snip chips sniffs are
great for looking at single single base
pair variants maybe some of the small
end else but when you want to look at
things that are up to 50 base pair
insertion and deletions you usually
migrate to something like an Illumina
sequencer those are great at getting
some of the in Dells up to about that
size once you start getting larger than
that it's very difficult to ascertain
them with short reads you need long
reads to do this and the important thing
about doing this with long reads is that
the the vast majority of the variant
information in the genome is usually the
structural variants they're not very
frequent in terms of their incident rate
but they happen to contain large chunks
of DNA in almost entire genes so you
really need to pay attention to the
structural variants and and get on board
with some of these long read sequencers
what you're seeing here is a graph of
that the the variant size and the
cumulative percent of a percentage of
them that that they make up in a genome
and so you can see that there are a
tremendous amount of variants that are
large like 10 KB in size and encompass a
tremendous amount of either regulatory
elements or genes and humans what you
see is around seven of these per
megabase and then this jumps order of
magnitude when you get in the maze
there's about 70 of these per megabase
and you can see that the short read
systems have a very low sensitivity for
picking these things up and so you're
blind to these if we're only using the
Illumina sequencers when you put in 20x
coverage on these with these long reads
you see them all and it becomes a really
interesting story that is represented
here here we can see over 17,000
heterozygous and almost 10,000
homozygous deletions in the male
our almost an equal number of those of
insertions likewise the offspring there
has a similar number of deletions and
insertions in the in the histogram of
the size of these things is down here
below so there's clearly some kind of
repeat element in the genome that's
jumping up and around 10 KB as being
inserted and deleted inside the genome
this makes you question what the heck is
in this stuff if this is just one inbred
cross in a trio and there's this much
stuff jumping around this is like an
eighth of the genome in structural
variation this is extraordinarily
plastic when it comes to come it comes
to a genome and it's not necessarily
containing boring things we're seeing
terpene synthase genes that are in these
parts and these structural variants in
the genome
alright so TPF 17 is a bit immersing
gene and we also have other TPS 10 and
TPS 30 like or perhaps making alpha
pining and delimiting not oh and in the
terpene landscape a single gene does not
make a single terpene one gene can make
multiple terpenes and there can be
multiple copies of that gene may
contribute asain terpene so just by this
beta mersin being dropped out doesn't
mean it doesn't make any mercy there's
other genes that will probably have low
compensate for that but we also see this
in the triterpene nobody is measuring
for tri terpenes right now in the labs
we need to be looking at these things
because the flavanols are in there and
people are publishing on how the can
flavin genes are in fact having an
impact and pancreatic cancer and in pain
yet it's a molecule that the plant makes
that we don't track likewise these other
triterpene seem to have some interesting
characteristics as well and we think
we'd love to see those getting into the
analytical chemistry labs now we're
tracking all of this stuff in a web site
known as canopy dia and what this system
enables is for people to sequence
partial genomes or complete genomes and
put the data public or hold a private
depending on their need but it allows
you to compare that genome to everything
else we have in the database so you can
get a phylogenetic tree of what it's
related to and what it's the most
distant to and how heterozygous it is
and how backcross it is and we can also
scan for the BTB d allele to know if you
what type of plant it is and whether
that's gonna step on any intellectual
property that's out there but all of
this is linked into a a blockchain
system so that then time stamps and the
notarization czar uneditable by us if we
disappear your data still has links into
a blockchain that is distributed around
the world
old and your time stamps cannot be
changed by anyone at our company now
this is we're starting to integrate some
genome browsers into this as well so
people can kind of peruse their genome
next to this is down below this is what
the 40 genomes snip variant file looks
like theirs looks like there's almost a
snip at every single location throughout
the genome when you put this many
genomes in there but if you zoom in it's
not that it's not that it's not that
sparse but nevertheless it can be a very
helpful tool for for analyzing your
genome and now since the data up there
is public there's been over seven
publications that have just scraped data
off of that site and published their own
analysis of it so that it's been
thoroughly vetted and it's it's growing
every day so with a few minutes left I'm
just going to touch on what you can do
what applications can you do with genome
structures like this and sequences like
this well we first thing we started to
do was to build a fingerprinting tool
that only needed 16 snips to identify
cannabis strain and we want it to be 16
snips that we can do it on a
quantitative PCR instrument in an hour
we don't have to necessarily send it out
to a sequencing lab we can we can
basically get parentage information from
16 wells at a 96-well plate inside that
system that we've built we also have
that CBD and THC allele so we can
measure the BT VD allele on a plant with
a genotype and in a PCR well now which
is quite nice and it also makes you want
to think about doing RNA a PCR can you
do qpcr and RNA of the terpenes or the
cannabinoid genes to understand at what
stage does development are you getting
hyper or hypo expression of those genes
and then we're beginning to work on
viruses as well there's some great work
that was published by dark art nurseries
recently on the hops Layton virus so
we've made an assay out of what they
discovered and we also did a half's out
of lettuce chlorosis virus that was
published in israel recently and threw
in a third one known as CC v1 so you can
start to track the actual viruses that
might be spreading through the
population and then two other things
that we're playing around with is some
work with arbor where we're making
different panels that can capture a
thousand genes or 50 genes at a time and
sequence those so that people can take
more bite-sized pieces out of the genome
and analyze them this current one has
the synthesis in face jeans and the
Edisto genes I think they have a booth
here describing this panel that they've
built and a lot of that was built off
the Jamaican line references and we're
also making multiplex tools to measure
the micro
that are in the plant and down below
there is just a five color Aspergillus
assay for tracking things in in
California and then the final thing
we're just toying around with this
really early is pollen traps there's all
this problems with pollen floating on to
open v open field cannabis farms right
now and so we are trying to do here is
quantitate the amount of male
parliaments in the air and the amount of
THC Laden pollen that's in the air with
these $50 pollen traps that you can
throw in the corners of your property
and see if there are a lot of pollen
that is blowing in that might be
destroying your grow in the next couple
years so a lot can be done with genetics
and I want to thank all these people
that helped us do it
- really kicked off the snow mulling of
this and then PacBio was pivotal in
providing that the technology that could
sequence these genomes New England
Biolabs did a lot of the methylation
work and some of the sequencing work you
can work on the Novus seek and we've
done some work with phase genomics and
the other parties here to actually piece
the genome in some more contiguous shape
and then all of these people were
required to make this happen it really
does take a village and a tremendous
amount of collaboration as dr. Mutulu
was saying so with that I want to leave
a few seconds here for for questions if
possible and if not we will roll over to
the next section which i think is a
panel thank you
[Music]