[Music]
using potential chemical elicitors yes
um to kind of I guess mitigate some of
the negative effects of hlvd so please
tell us more about that yes so um
chemical elicitors or synthetic
elicitors also called plant growth
Regulators as the name suggest it's a
chemical that mimics plant
hormones so it's essentially giving the
plants a little boost to get their
defenses going and this is not you know
I didn't come up with this idea uh um
we've been using it in Plant Pathology
and in entomology research as a way to
trigger plant defenses give them a
little boost to get it get it
activated uh you could also think of it
as a way to Prime the plants and and it
can protect against diseases and
pathogens because naturally plant
hormones or what we call phyto hormones
are doing this but they're doing it at a
at a low level so that you know the
plant can um devote all the resources to
the different functions we want to give
it this boost so it can get activated
and the reason that I was interested in
this research is because cannabis and
hemp can be considered organic U
production systems right because the um
the repertoire of um insecticides and
pesticides are so limited right all we
have and so there are only a handful of
products we don't even know their
efficacy and it turns out that these
chemical elicitors are actually
registered oh for use so that's that's
one of the reasons we went um we were
interested in this and so our idea was
to just boost the plant's innate
inherent immunity to better defend uh
the viroid and so prior to
infection um no we didn't do it prior so
we infected the plant and um a week
later so we got the plant um going with
the infection and then a week later we
sprayed these elicitors and then sprayed
every week for up to three weeks and
then subsequently I think at the fourth
or the fifth week we took uh tissue and
analyzed for hlvd levels using qpcr then
left the plants grow go to flowering and
then did the canabo analysis so you
could we we debated should we do it um
spray first then infect or infect and
then
spray uh we decided to do and I uh
decided to do um the former because so
we we got clones from infected plants so
they were already infected um ready to
go cuz that's probably a more n we
figured that's probably more of the
natural situation the plants are already
infected excellent and so what were the
results oh my goodness so you you know
this already and this is how it goes
with research it's never yes perfect
result always more questions to be asked
offs right yes exactly but it's it's
great um we did two rounds of it and
we're actually getting ready to to do a
third round so the results were mixed
bag but very interesting what we found
was yes indeed certain phyto hormones or
chemical elicitors reduced hlvd levels
interestingly they also increased the
biomass um you know the yield of the the
plant which we were excited about but go
to look at the flow production and canab
oid levels and it was and are the major
ones like CBD and THC was actually
reduced I'll tell you biomass like
almost 50% for salicylic acid the
biomass increased 50% yeah compared
compared to infected yeah no they're all
infected compared to so the control was
ethanol because that's the solvent
salicylic acid dissolved in in ethanol
the biomass per plant was 88.3 gram and
in the salicylic acid sprayed it was
like
15% 15 grams oh wow yeah so almost
double almost double because these
elicit these phyto hormones also cause
the plants
to cause cell division in delay cense
and essentially giving it better overall
health excellent so I'm just picking
salicylic acid said uh they all look
pretty much the same some of the other
ones I'm saying
brassinolides was 12.8 gram compared to
eight so a little less than 50 so let's
look at
um umid we can again pick salicylic acid
TBD this is in micrograms okay so THC or
THC a was ,00 microG gram per gram in
the control in
ethanol and in sa it
was
1300 microgram per gram
30% so a third so if basically 100%
increase in biomass yeah but a 30%
decrease in th yes in thca interesting
interesting yeah but not so interesting
because guess what just after we did
this in this is a this was a twoe study
from 2022 just and he graduated uh in in
fall in Fall here comes a really nice
study and I can talk about that showing
that in fact higher levels our goal was
to cause induction our our the aim of
our study you know because we were kind
of going blind was we want to make sure
the plant the these um Pathways in the
plant salicylic acid or what what have
you was uh was turned on so we we went a
little high on the dosage and then a
paper came out saying higher dosage can
reduce can abono whereas a lower
dosage so since that paper came out we
are now we've got to fine tune the the
rates it's not so over applying it can
improve um reduce hlvd levels and um
biomass but does not have the same
impact for canab noids which is
important so you got to fine tune this
and so we're redoing um that experiment
it's already started and I should have
some new data uh for Canin excellent
[Music]