[Music]
welcome to the CM Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I'm the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and proud member of
the team that puts on the camed
conference first off I do apologize for
the lack of quality in the video here if
you're watching us I'm actually on the
road at a conference so I'm in a hotel
room with my fake background here um I
hope it's not too much of a distraction
it's only going to be for this intro and
for the outro the actual interview is
going to be the same quality that you
know and love but wanted to acknowledge
it right off the top okay just a few
reminders before I introduce this week's
guest
if you're listening to this episode on
the day it's released then I'd like to
remind you that the early bird deadline
for the canmed 24 Innovation and
investment Summit is this Friday
December 1st yes Friday December 1st is
the last day you can purchase your CED
24 ticket at the lowest price available
you will save $300 off our full Summit
package which includes access to the
medical practicum industry workshops
oral presentations poster present
presentations networking events meals
and a three- night stay at the JW
Marriott Marco Island resort with all
the associated
amenities head over to camed events.com
now to register and I hope to see you in
Florida this
may also our camed Advisory Board is
reviewing the abstract submissions we
received for oral and poster
presentations and we hope to be
announcing some presenters very soon you
may have already seen that we announced
that the capital markets Workshop will
return for camed 24 led by Golden Eagle
partners and we are also going to have a
special nursing panel on Sunday May 13th
you can learn more about both of those
sessions at camat events.com and while
you're there be sure to sign up for
email alerts so you can get those
announcements right to your inbox my
guest today is Dr Carla Gage Carla is
assistant professor of weed science and
plant biology at Southern Illinois
University Carbondale where she received
her PhD in plant biology with a focus in
weed ecology in
2013 in short Carla is a weed expert but
not in the weed that you smoke but
rather the weeds that you pull her
research focuses on using integrated
weed management to control and suppress
weeds in midwestern us rotational crops
including corn soy be wheat and now hemp
during our conversation we discussed
what negative effects weeds can have on
hemp which weed species are threatening
to hemp herbicides that are approved for
hemp and the threat of herbicide
resistance integrated weed management
strategies such as crop rotation cover
crops chaff lining plastic coverings and
more and how feral hemp varieties may
have traits to help breed for more
resistant hemp
varieties before we get to my
conversation with Carla I'd like to
thank this episode sponsor Rare Earth
genomics Rare Earth genomics Texas is a
partnership formed to accelerate hemp
research and produce critical tools for
the farmer re's mission is to increase
the likelihood of a successful Harvest
through genetic analysis and rigorous
Environmental Testing of vigorous
cultivars reliable data sets analytic
tools and stable germ plasm are core to
the program success for the farmer is
the goal you can learn more at rareearth
genomics. okay and without any further
Ado please enjoy my conversation with Dr
Carla
[Music]
Gage
good afternoon Carla thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast hi good
afternoon yeah it's such a pleasure to
be here to talk with you today yeah I'm
excited to talk with you today about
weed control in outdoor hemp now we've
covered other plant pathogens on the
podcast before hop L and vroid pow
mildew pythium Bettis all those things
and even got into pests before with
russet mites spidermites Etc but never
weeds so this will be interesting um I
suspect that's because so much of
cannabis cultivation occurs indoors but
I know that the majority of hemp
cultivation is outdoors and after all
hemp and cannabis are the same plant for
all intents and purposes so be fun to
dive into this so let's start with the
basics what are the negative effects
that weeds can have on
hemp yeah well with any CR right uh
weeds can directly compete by uh taking
resources that the crop needs uh
resources like nutrients uh water space
um so there's that direct form of
competition but there are also other
indirect things that happen um for
example um cannabis can exude some
biochemical substances that can
interfere with the growth of other
plants potentially uh that's something
that my lab has been looking at but
weeds do the same same thing right so a
weed that's competing with a crop plant
may be releasing biochemical compounds
or having other effects on that plant
that are Beyond just the direct
competition for
nutrients great and now I know that hemp
can be grown for all different sorts of
things fiber um grain seed um and of
course cannabinoid Rich flour so are
there different considerations there for
how weeds can affect the crop for what
the crop will be used for
yeah so it's pretty amazing to look at
all the different um crop morphologies
meaning that if you're growing for each
of those different Commodities the crop
that you're growing is is going to
probably look different uh for example
if I'm growing a fiber crop that plant
has been bred over time to grow uh
directly upright to not Branch very much
uh and it's planted very densely
together in the field so for for weed
competition that would be a very
competitive crop and if it gets
established there should be relatively
few weeds coming up below that crop
canopy and you can contrast that with
how um Dual Purpose uh crops are grown
so those would be crops that you would
Harvest for both seed and fiber
potentially and those are typically
shorter plants they're a little bit more
branchy and uh they're spaced out more
in the field so there's more potential
for weed competition below that crop
canopy and then of course the most
sensitive type of cultivation to to weed
competition would be the CBD floral
biotype where you know those plants they
are branchy you know they are uh they do
take up a lot of space as they grow but
they're planted at um a pretty good
distance from one another and then you
have to do some weed control around them
whether that's you know uh black plastic
mulch or other organic mulches uh there
has to be some other type of weed
control tactic because the crop itself
is not going to suppress weeds as well
so yeah depending on what commodity type
you're growing the the weed control
problems are are can be dramatically
different yeah and are there any sort of
numbers around like weeds can affect
your your yield by X percent yeah so
actually that is such a fascinating
question and that is uh really one of
the things we're trying to determine
with our research uh in 2019 there was a
a publication that came out it was uh
basically a review of of all the global
literature looking at hemp cultivation
and uh in of the P of the Publications
that were reviewed uh weeds were either
neglected not even mentioned in the
Publications or they were mentioned as
inconsequential to the yield so that
brings up a a a really good question
right I mean we we know that this should
be a competitive crop hemp is uh is a
nitrophilous species meaning it should
be able to um you know uh accumulate
nitrogen and use nitrogen very
efficiently and uh could probably
outcompete a lot of other plants but um
the key seems to be uh getting it
established because even in our own
research we have seen a good number of
crop failures when the weeds come up
before the hemp or at the same time as
the hemp and uh and and then you know a
lot of times we don't even get a a good
hemp stand you know we see the weeds and
not the hemp so we know that competition
is a problem yet um the effects have
been
inconclusive and one of the things that
my lab has been working on um we do have
some uh some funding from the USDA as
part of a a larger multi-state project
and uh we've been looking at uh at what
is the called the critical weed-free
period in hemp and and all crops have
this uh sort of the theoretical concept
where you know if you can control the
weeds during so many weeks initially as
the crop gets established then you can
maintain uh you know reasonable yields
by the end of the season so there's this
critical period when uh plants are are
more sensitive to competition and you
have to to Really take care of the weeds
during that period of time well we were
looking at this and uh there were
students in my lab that were weeding
hand weeding our hemp flots uh at
different intervals throughout the
season so some of the plots were not
weeded at all you know we planted the
hemp and and walked away basically and
then uh there was a there was a
treatment that was only weeded for a
week and then two weeks and three weeks
and so on and there was one treatment
that was weeded for the entire season um
so we were all a little surprised when
we did a preliminary analysis of the
data and we found that statistically
there was no difference whether or not
we we didn't weed the plants at all or
whether we weeded for 80 7 days which
was the entire season wow exactly
that's that's what we thought as well um
we could see a little bit of evidence
for um heavy grass competition so we
could see that the plots were had where
there was a lot of grass uh competing
around um those were our 14-day weed
weed treatments but but we could see a a
hit in the overall biomass uh with some
of the competition but it was just
amazing that statistically there was no
difference
so so we're now in our second year of
that study and we'll be um doing a more
um detailed data analysis and we'll be
looking at all the different yield
components because that was just a rough
look at overall biomass of uh fiber and
Dual Purpose crops so um so yeah it's it
seems like um it's one of those crops
where if it gets a head start it's it's
fairly competitive interesting yeah so
timing is everything yeah it is it is no
but so just want to make sure I heard
that correctly so the amount that you
weeded whether you did none at all or
you weeded throughout the whole thing it
did it didn't have an effect on the
overall yield at the end it didn't on
the overall biomass that was produced
not looking at quality of fiber or
amount of seed yield so just overall
plant biomass now there may be
differences for each of those components
right because plants will uh in that's
it's an investment strategy right so um
they may have been investing in growth
and in structure and putting less into
seed production for example so uh now
that we have two years of data I I hope
that we're able to sort of tease apart
any any of those differences but um and
and now we do have of course we have a a
pre-emergence herbicide that's labeled
as well so if uh if Farmers want to grow
hemp now there's there's more um
more tools available to give the hemp a
head
start okay so that was going to be one
of my questions are there approved
herbicides for hemp H this is recent
yeah so there is now a pre-emergence
herbicide that would do hopefully um
what we're talking about and and give
the hemp the Head Start that it needs
for successful production um it's it's
not um there are going to be some
challenges for the weeds in our
geography not all of the problem weeds
are are going to be well controlled by
this herbicide but it's more than we had
before um so for Farmers that are um you
know accustomed to growing corn and
soybeans in herbicide managed systems uh
the the goal would be to see this as
another crop potentially in rotation
with those crops uh one of the reasons
that we have so much herbicide
resistance besides just the the sheer
amount of herbicides that we use um it's
because we have very simplified
rotations in our agricultural system
systems so if we could put more crops in
rotation with corn and and soybeans then
our Pest Management challenges would
would change and we wouldn't have um
such dominant weeds
theoretically right okay so a few things
I want to make sure that I that I touch
on with that question so the first one
you said do it was specific to your
geography so are there Regional
considerations here for for weed control
in hemp yes there are um you know some
species are not not uh uniformly
distributed across the United States
there are certain geographies that have
uh different problems um I think across
most of the the midwestern U cropping
region the amaranthus species are a
problem if you're familiar with
amaranthus seed it's it's basically
they're plants in the same genus as that
food crop that have become dominant
agricultural weeds and they've evolved
resistances to multip multiple
herbicides that have become a critical
part of our crop production systems so
um as they evolve very quickly we're
losing some of the herbicide tools that
our Farmers have relied upon and uh and
something there's something very special
about those weeds so those amaranthus
weeds are dous meaning that they are
males and they are females and they have
to cross-pollinate to produce seeds and
those are the only species in our system
that are what we call rver weeds that um
that are evolving herbicide resistance
so quickly so the genetic exchange
between those plants is in a sense
driving Evolution and genetic variation
and uh and of course the the plant that
we're introducing into the system you
know this is our first dious plant as
far as I've worked with that is a crop
species now and does that bring with it
other uh
challenges well potentially right
because uh hemp is the uh it's the
original weed
right the name yeah so uh you know we
have in Illinois a victory hemp left
over from World War II era that still
grows in the ditch Banks and roadsides
around agricultural Fields um so it's
still it still exists it still is
persistent so um that's another uh
another research question in the fields
where we're growing hemp for a crop you
know uh we're going to have to manage
those volunteers as we rotate into other
crops so how how easy is that going to
continue to be are we a are we going to
be able to continue to manage hemp which
is very susceptible right now to the
herbicides that we use so right now yes
yeah I'm I'm glad you kind of brought up
the the ditch weed that um is still out
there is that and is that a weed for all
intents and purposes for if you're
growing hemp could that potentially be
an issue issue um well it depends right
if you're growing floral uh CBD hemp
then
yes that is an issue for you in your
product quality um and potentially for
uh for other crops as well but I think
more importantly it's it's um it's
important to consider that as a
reservoir for very important genetic
traits that might be useful for future
Crop Production those plants have
existed for uh you know decades
successfully in these areas they are
tolerant to the environmental conditions
that they're being exposed to and to the
ecological interactions so so that
shouldn't be dismissed um I don't think
they should be devalued I think that in
the future they could have a very real
um a very a very real um contribution to
Future breeding
programs that's well that's actually
very interesting um I don't know if if
you're aware but here at mical genomics
we do um sequencing on cannabis
varieties temp varieties things like
that to help readers kind of identify
these traits I don't think we've ever
had any um ditch weed or any of that
that we've actually sequenced I know we
have some land race strains that are
kind of from other parts of the other
parts of the world but I don't know if
we have any that are um that are native
to the United States that would be
that'd be really interesting I'm gonna
I'm gonna bring that up to the CSO right
after this yeah yeah that would be um
you know in Southern Illinois we have a
very heavy soil type and and uh we find
that it interacts with our heavy spring
rainfalls so there's a there's a period
during the initial part of the Season
where you know we do have ponding in our
soils and you know it's it's really
difficult for the early planted hemp
crop to survive because it's it's not
very tolerant to um you know water
logging so uh that's where you know
maybe there is uh there's that trait
that exists in one of those weedy
populations that would allow it to
tolerate heavy soils a little bit better
so yeah those are the types of things
where you know I I do think there's a
lot of value in looking at those feral
populations that still exist interesting
okay all right so back to herbicides we
talked about that there are some some
approved or an approved herbicide that
that recently came online so um I know
that hemp is a bio accumulator so are
there considerations with that and using
like a an herbicide that it might you
know kind of accumulate in the in the
crop um yeah and I I guess I I'm
probably not the the best to talk about
herbicide tolerance levels uh so
residues in crops um I I yes I I do um
agree that hemp can be a
bioaccumulator um I guess the the type
of production that we're looking at um
I'm really more interested in seeing
fiber production so in that case um
anything that's bioaccumulated could
actually be a benefit if you use it for
remed ation purposes then uh you could
lock away those chemical compounds that
the plant takes up in in hempcrete um
you know into structures that are not
going to be degraded and released in the
future so so in that case um that could
be a benefit a beneficial characteristic
of that crop plant interesting you need
to be careful for other um food based
commodity types right for seed and
especially for floral uh production
yes um definitely and I know I think too
that there must be concerns also if
you're growing near other crops that
some of the herbicides that are maybe
used on those crops could drift into
your
Fields yeah and and we have seen that a
bit um herbicide drift has has been a
concern especially in some geographies
um we see that uh that hemp is sensitive
to some of those herbicides and uh in
some of the preliminary preliminary work
that we've done um we haven't seen a
huge yield impact when hemp is drifted
upon by other herbicides so again that
that does go back to the need to
establish herbicide tolerances and
safety levels on hemp depending on what
it's going to be used for in the
future and so given that you know hemp
was was banned for so long until kind of
the farm bill a few years ago kind of
open things up and so how far behind are
we in in researching you know uh weed
prevention and
hemp well
um really far behind yeah um yeah so
there's there's not really a lot known
as far as hemp's competitive ability um
I'm working with a colleague here at SIU
uh to to just set up some um species by
species competition studies just to look
at you know some of our most problematic
weeds uh put them in different numbers
growing with different number of of hemp
plants in in pots in the greenhouse and
just simply look at the impact of of
that competition at different densities
on that Target hemp plant uh so it's
just the the things that just a lot of
things that we don't know um in my mind
you could take pretty much any uh
publication that's been done in soybeans
you know looking at weed control and
probably redo that and it would be
completely novel and hemp uh so there
there's nothing but questions right now
uh very few answers
and we do have two herbicides actually
so
thein yeah ethol Florin is the
pre-emergence compound and then there's
a postemergence compound um which is
quizalofop or aeru is the trade name but
it's only a grass specific compound uh
so you can you can spray it across the
top of the hemp plants and uh and at
least kill the grasses that would be
competing but it's not going to impact
the the broadleaf plants that are
growing and competing with the hemp so
so it's but it's a you know it's
something right it's a it's a full
herbicide program a pre-emergence
compound plus a post-emergence compound
that that Growers are conceptually
familiar with working with and now are
herbicides the best tool against weed
control or are there other other options
they're the most commonly used Tool uh
it's partly as a as a um result of the
sheer number of Acres that our our
Farmers manage um you know if you go
into organic production for example
you're relying um either on tillage to
control the weeds up until a certain
point until you can't till anymore
without hurting the crop or you're
heavily Reliant upon uh cover crop
species that would suppress the weeds
and uh there is a potential to see cover
crops used in hemp production um I know
there have been some pilot studies that
have been conducted and uh you know the
cover crop literature is well
established that
you know you can suppress some of our
most problematic weeds with a with a
good uh cover crop that accumulates
enough biomass and that's really the key
is giving that cover crop the chance to
accumulate the biomass it needs and the
cover crop's not going to compete with
the hemp well you would uh you would
terminate it uh typically uh the way
that cover crops are grown ahead of corn
or soybeans um corn is a little bit more
sensitive so you terminate the cover
crop typically um before you plant the
corn uh soybeans are less sensitive and
some Growers are going into this this
program where they plant green meaning
that they don't kill the cover crop they
just plant the soybeans directly into it
and let the soybeans emerge and then
they come back and kill the cover crop
and again it's just going towards
accumulating the biomass uh there has to
be enough biomass for that cover crop to
suppress the weeds so they're just
trying to give the cover crop a little
bit of extra time after planting so
something Sim similar would have to be
done with hemp where uh you would kill
the cover crop and uh and we have a uh a
roller crimper planter where we can
terminate the cover crop by basically
mashing it down and creating a mat of
residue and we'll plant the crop into
that and clear spaces for the crop seeds
to emerge but then between the crop rows
we rely on the cover crop to suppress
the weeds interesting um so what other
what other tools are available to kind
of help control weeds yeah so uh again
going back to using hemp in a rotational
strategy um that's what I meant to
that's what I meant to come back to I'm
glad you excellent well I I think
there's a lot of potential because um
the the work that we've uh that we've
done that my lab has done um has shown
that some of our our our driver weeds
the most problematic species don't
emerge well from hemp residue so uh
there is a system in um in management of
other crops called chaff lining and uh
you can think about a combine moving
across a field and harvesting soybeans
for example so the combine is collecting
the soybean seed and then out the back
of the combine all the residue the crop
residue the stems uh all the other
material is being deposited back on the
field well um Australian Farmers came up
with this really neat system where they
take the finest particles of that crop
and they funnel it into a line in the
back of the combine and not only is it
the the finest particles of the crop but
it's also the weed seeds so they deposit
the weed seeds in this crop residue it's
this this pile of biomass in a line um
and if you have Precision planting
technology then you make those lines
after every crop in the same place every
year so you're always putting your weeds
seeds back in a line in the field and
then you know the the great thing is
they're they're going to be there so
that you can do other management
practices on top of that line you've
concentrated them it's not that you're
uh preventing them from germinating so
much uh but hemp on the other hand if
you were to use hemp in a chaff lining
strategy uh and look at the biochemical
properties of the hemp biomass there
might be the potential to suppress the
germination of those weeds because of
the the biochemistry of that crop plant
does so so that's one thing that that my
lab has conceptually looked at and a way
that I think hemp could actually be um a
positive
um a driver in um creating a more
sustainable rotational
system interesting so if I followed
so so you're kind of having all the
waste from from the previous harvest in
these lines and that includes the weeds
and the seeds and everything um and
typically those weeds will germinate but
with hemp they don't so what we found in
shaft lining systems in general we had
hoped that the seeds would Decay more
quickly because you're putting them in
in biomass where microbes are going to
be working harder right uh but we don't
see them decaying we actually see that
that biomass protects the seeds and they
can remain viable for longer
so that's not what we' hoped but at
least we can show that we're
concentrating the seeds in one location
if we concentrate them in hemp biomass
then then yes we do see a suppressive
effect of the hemp mulch uh I don't know
how long it will last it depends on you
know the amount of rainfall and and
microbial action so rainfall and
temperature would be major drivers of
that but um but yeah there's the
potential to get a little bit of added
benefit uh from compression of those
biochemicals found in hemp potentially
interesting so so going back to corop
rotation would hemp be a a good
candidate crop to be rotating with your
your soy soybeans or your corn or or
things like that oh I think it's still
unknown um so some of the Corn
herbicides may be a little bit hard on
hemp if you rotate uh from corn to hemp
um so that's uh that's something that
we' we've seen observationally but um I
haven't really Quantified
um so there can be some rotational
issues potentially but um it goes back
to you know if you really got the hemp
established you could get a really good
uh suppressive year where you didn't
have a lot of weeds germinate and that's
a form of Seedbank control right for
these uh summer annual plants that are
problems uh that are weeds in our in our
corn and soing systems uh their strategy
is just to produce seeds right if a
summer annual produces seeds then it's
it's basically one uh for that year uh
so we could possibly reduce seed
production if we can get a suppressive
stand of hemp and then any seeds that
are produced could be lined in a chaff
lining system potentially um but there
are a lot of uh questions as far as
rotational strategies you know um I
think it's unknown as far as the number
of pathogens that the crops may share in
rotation and I'm not sure if we know
which crop should follow which right now
you know what the best uh temporal
rotation really is so um I know there
are other people working on that so
hopefully um hopefully one day we'll
have an answer excellent uh what about
mulching or plastic covering um does
that does that help as well absolutely
yeah um that's one of the the more uh
common ways that I see um floral hemp
produced in our local geography is with
um plastic mulch of course that in
itself can have some environmental
sustainability implications um but any
sort of material that could be mulched
with so even an organic mulch material
that could suppress the weeds that would
be very helpful as
well excellent and in my research I I
will confess I am not a cultivation
expert but uh what is integrated weed
management so so that is uh that's the
um the focus of my lab
actually yes
GL
I we do a lot of work with herbicide
resistance and uh and I study herbicide
efficacy and the way that we should use
herbicides in our cropping systems to
control weeds but um if you look at the
evolution of herbicide resistance and
the increasing cases um it's very clear
that we're putting herbicides under a
lot of pressure uh so herbicid or weeds
are evolving herbicide resistance uh I
mean really faster than we can create
new herbicides at this point so
integrated weed management is the idea
that you um you should develop a more
Diversified strategy for weed control
and you should put more pressures on the
weeds besides just herbicides right it's
the same thing with uh you know um
microbial resistance to antibiotics it's
the same type of selection that's
happening so if we can put in um cover
crops and uh and harvest weed seek
control tactics like chaff lining like I
was mentioning um you know if we can
build an
ecologically um robust system where we
have uh seed Predators you know insects
in the field that are eating seeds uh
and we can you know capitalize more on
some of these ecological interactions
that are happening um then then that
integrated system you can still use
herbicides but you're putting less
pressure on the herbicides and you're
probably um at some point you're
beginning to slow the evolution of
herbicide resistance right yeah it seems
like herbicides are really the the
short-term solution but with really
potentially severe long-term effects
well you know and it's uh it partly goes
back to the need to be um you know
financially sustainable in the short
term and um you know learning to manage
other tactics like learning to manage
cover CR in the system it's like in a
way learning to manage a whole new crop
right so you're increasing the
complexity of the system whereas
herbicides are a simplified strategy but
they're um they come with a prescription
you know when to apply them you know
what to apply and uh and you're
relatively guaranteed to some degree a
success um if you do things in the right
way and when you start adding all of
these other tactics in then uh some of
the interactions become less predictable
and that means that the yields can be
less predictable and for a farmer who's
maybe not as comfortable financially it
can be very difficult to take those
risks so um so there's a lot to the
conversation as far as um you know the
adoption of more ecologically based
practices um it can be really risky for
some
people yeah no and that's a great point
and especially with hemp too I think um
a lot of people got into hemp production
particularly for CBD um assuming that
there was going to be this huge market
for it and then uh there was kind of
over production and the the prices
really fell through the floor so
definitely a
consideration yeah and for our Growers
here locally there there are a lot of
folks that are interested in in growing
fiber and um and potentially seed crops
but you know the market is still not
there to support them so they can
experiment on a small scale but there's
not going to be a you know a lot of
potential for that that return on
investment right now
yeah no I that is definitely the case
and I mean not to put you on the spot
and if if you don't want to answer this
we could certainly cut it out but um why
do you think that other types or other
Commodities associated with h really
haven't taken off yet it really has been
focused primarily on the
canabo yeah you know great question um
it's it
seems like it's kind of a a chicken and
the egg type scenario right I mean in
order to have a market that's built
around a commodity you have to have the
farmer that's going to produce it well
in order for the farmer to produce it
that person has to have a place to sell
it after they produce it so it's I think
more of a question of establishing some
of these basic uh Market initiatives
across a large scale right so you if
you're a processor if you want to
establish a processing facility that
means you know two years ahead of your
facility you're already reaching out and
Contracting up to a th Acres of
production with local Growers and then
you're working with them so that they
understand how to grow the crop and
you're providing some agronomic oversite
while you're building your facility and
then everything comes online and then
you have your Growers contracted and you
have your product coming in and then you
just continue to build capacity after
that so it's it's not it's it's not just
like building a facility and then it's
it's good right you have to have a
knowledgeable grower base to go along
with that to for that to be
successful got it well that is a great
answer so all right so winding down here
and you you've touched on it already but
I want to give you another chance to to
talk about so what's next what what are
you working on now and what can we
expect to see in the future yeah so
we're continuing to be part of a large
scale cul of our trial where we're just
planting different cultivars all across
the US and different geographies uh to
see what the um you know uh genetic by
environmental impacts are for each
cultivar so ideally uh you know I hope
that we can identify some cultivars that
do really well in Southern Illinois and
kind of expand our our grower options
here um so that's one of the things that
we'll continue to do and then uh we're
wrapping up our critical weed-free
period and uh um management study that's
funded by the US ta so uh within the
next year I hope to have all those data
analyzed and and published so that's
something to look for and then uh You'
mentioned cover crops I hope to
establish a couple of pilot cover crop
studies just to see what that looks like
because we've never really experience um
experimented with planting hemp into
cover crops at least not yet excellent
that sounds great um also want to give
you a chance to share any other
resources um that you think that the
audience might be interested in if
they're interested to learn more about
we control and how sure well um the
resources are still being developed so I
hope that those will be shared more in
the future but uh we do have a growing
cannabis Science Center here at Southern
Illinois University Carbondale so there
are some resources on the Cannabis
Science Center web page and you can see
what our diverse faculty group is is
doing and how we're coming together to
study
cannabis excellent all right Carla well
this is has been fun uh it was a great
conversation um excited to see some more
results of what you're working on and
hopefully see you up on the the can mid
stage real soon that'd be great yeah
thanks so much thanks for having me
[Music]
today hope you enjoyed my conversation
with Dr Carla Gage check out the links
in the show description to learn more
about the topics we discussed and thanks
again to this episode sponsor Rare Earth
genomics our next episode drops December
12th that's 2 weeks from
today in the meantime please do go to
canmed event.com now and sign up for
canmed 24 at the early bird rate that
deadline for the early bird rate is
December
1st also I invite you to follow us on
social media we are on Instagram
Facebook Twitter and Linkedin just
search for CET events and lastly please
rate review And subscribe on whichever
platform you use to watch or listen to
the podcast we really appreciate
it all right that's it from us stay safe
stay healthy and please do come back to
the next C Coffee
Talk
[Music]
n