[Music]
welcome to the can med coffee talk
podcast my name is Ben emerald
I'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and I've been part of the kid
med team since our very first event in
2016 at Harvard Medical School I'm also
the host of the can med coffee talk
podcast where I will be talking with
many of the people who will be
presenting and can med 2020 and Pasadena
this fall so join me as we get to know
the leading minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
we will get into the important work they
are doing to drive this industry forward
and provide a preview of what you can
expect at this year's can med 2020 of
that speaking of KM ed 2020 tickets are
on sale now we are running a special
promotion on our full conference ticket
for just $420 you will get access to two
days of oral and poster presentations
are expanded exhibit hall coffee and
lunch stations networking events and
more that 420 dollar price is only
available through April 20th but don't
wait until the deadline get your tickets
today and cross it off your to-do list
and if you're interested in presenting
it Kim at 2020 you're in luck we are
currently accepting abstract submissions
for consideration for aural and poster
presentations go to kin med events com
for more information about the abstract
process and the kinds of abstracts our
advisory board is looking for all right
now that the shameless plug is out of
the way I have two more things to ask
first hit the subscribe button on your
podcast app so new episodes will
download to your device and second head
over to Ken met events dot-com and sign
up for email alerts if you do you'll be
entered into a drawing to win two free
tickets to a VIP dinner so thank you for
checking out our preview episode of the
kid med coffee talk podcast and be sure
to come back April 1st where we welcome
our first guest
Kevin mckernon CSO of medicinal genomics
Kevin is going to talk all about the
exciting research he's done into the
cannabis genome including the Jamaican
lion reference the 40 genomes project
and a lot of other things so we look
forward to talking to you that bye bye
for now
[Music]
you