[Music]
um all right so I was wonder if you
could kind of just like take me through
the process of creating a new strain um
like are you selecting the plants with a
specific trait in mind or are you just
taking two plants Crossing them and kind
of seeing what comes out and then
following the trail from there how does
that work yeah so I mean each strain is
different um I give you an example um I
brought back a a cut from AK-47 of AK-47
from a family farm in Durango Mexico um
we got it back um and got it initiated
we then crossed it with a very popular
Michigan strain you've probably heard of
it Oreos um but to create our new strain
uh which we called cream 47 we had to
take the Oreos get it to an F3 and then
we took our AK-47 which we knew is a
land race train and we did that initial
upfront cross when we do that cross when
creating cream 47 we had a list of
markers we wanted to hit we wanted to
hit high triome density we wanted the
bag peel to be there we wanted some of
that creamy kind of Oreo um flavor to
come over from the Oreos uh in that
cross so in some cases it's doing a stem
rub on the male in some cases we're
looking at internodal spacing you know
do we want a indicia dominant plant do
we want a sativa dominant plant do we
want a true hybrid um and then we're
also implementing like I said before
which genotypes and which plants are
most resistant towards certain uh plant
pressures um so I mean it's hard to give
a breeder a a rundown of an exact
formula for what our targets are um but
it's always changing I mean for each
strain we have a different goal um we
just developed a strain push OG which
our goal for that was to be very drought
resistant uh very very drought resistant
and to be a light feeder so yeah I mean
it's hard to nail down exactly what
we're looking for for each strain but
bag appeal because of the way the market
is right now and the things that are
trending in the industry bag appeal is
always a box that we have to check
because at at the end of the day the
grower needs to like what they see in
the canopy and the consumer needs to
like what they see in the bag yeah for
sure so now when you you were talking
about doing the initial cross with uh I
think it was the F3 and then the land
race and then so how many different
seeds are you popping how many plants
are you sort of evaluating and sort of
how does it scale from there yeah so I
mean if we're doing if we're hunting
through seed we're doing about 200 um as
I told you before we're a small indoor
craft sealed facility uh where we're not
Outdoors we're not in a greenhouse we're
in an indoor sealed environment that way
we don't have any worries of any
cross-contamination or uh foreign pollen
coming in that we're unaware of um but
for what we were just speaking about the
F3 and then you're taking the land race
AK-47 once we make that cross we will
hunt out about from maybe 200 seed um
we'll do that because of the stability
with both lines we're working with all
we need is about 200 seed to find that
genotype that we want to then sterilize
um again we we use um axillary node
culture so we're actually doing a micro
splice taking that node sterilizing it
and then getting it into vitro um and
then depending on how quick we need to
make seed for our new line it might stay
there for a year it might stay there for
two years um and then we're we're
pulling it out when we need it excellent
so that upfront stabilization before you
were putting it into uh tissue culture
makes it so you don't have to to hunt as
many that's right that's right awesome
[Music]