[Music]
great so could you walk us through the
process of of tissue
culture okay uh sure I'm going to give
you a very brass tax uh very basic
explanation of the tissue culture
technique and also I have some um images
for both our research and also some
cartoony ones that are a little bit
easier to see if like the screen small
like they're just watching it on their
phone so uh the basic T process of
tissue culture is first you do a
selection of M of
materials that you select a plant and
you select the tissues in question and
then you
[Music]
um then you take and
oh we'll pull up this cartoon so you'll
take um a cutting from those tissues and
sterilize them this is so that you only
are dealing with the plants that you
wish to deal with and not of of any of
the pathogens or any of the other
materials you're specifically getting
you're only selecting for like say for
instance you only want Marist stem which
is like Bud tissue or you only want Leaf
tissue so you just get that and then you
uh plate the tissues on a media that has
um these cell signaling compounds that's
those compounds that I said beforehand
were like the plant saying hey look this
happened you need to do this so it grows
into um a mass of these Undeclared
majors of cells like undifferentiated
tissue called callus and then you take
and you start giving it signals to say
like hey I want you to make roots or hey
I want you to make this compound or hey
I want to make shoes and for in this
micropropagation slide um what you're
doing what this is doing is we're taking
uh some of the body tissue converting it
into callus and then converting that
tissue in that callus while we're making
the callus grow over and over again
we're also telling it to make more plant
babies now you know that's the cartoon
version um these are some of the
research pictures they might they might
not necessarily be as clear so this is
this is an example where that upper left
the white tissue that is that was some
cuting that I took off of a a
economically threatened plant and we
grew a whole mass of that tissue
normally that amount of tissue would
take about 2 or 3 years to grow because
it's it's it's a perennial this was
grown in months and then we convert
those tissues into a special subtype and
start making plant babies uh that's one
example um this is um this is from our
lab currently uh we're working with um
some of our partners and working doing
some work for them so I took some cuting
off of one of their mother plants and
then did a then selected for tissues
plated very small tissues and these guys
what they start doing on that little
jelly media that they grow that they
they in they grow they reproduce they
grow they reproduce they get bigger they
reproduce and more and more and then as
they get to a certain size they start
throwing shoots off and then we cut the
shoots off and you know propagate cut
the shoots off propagate until you get
basic this is probably a little bit more
easy for the the audience to see so so
that's like the basic process of tissue
culture
[Music]
a