hey everybody thanks for having me I
want to thank Kevin mckernon for
inviting me here I am the former UI UX
tech lead of - core group incorporated
I currently advise multiple blockchain
projects
if you've ever downloaded a Shutterfly
photo book
I am listen as a patent inventor on that
particular project I'm involved I was
involved in the FedEx print online
application that allowed you to upload
documents to FedEx and pick them at up
pick them up at a FedEx Office location
basically what I'm saying is a developer
and have been focusing on front-end
development for most of my life as a
professional I discovered this I the
reason I share this is because I want to
let you know that I've been involved in
the in the in the software industry and
cryptocurrency I believe is the next
evolution in software and I love to see
the cryptocurrency industry in places
like this a little bit out of place a
little bit kind of why is this guy here
kind of feeling
I love being that guy and I want to
introduce you and invite you into the
next evolution in economy that's going
to happen I believe that events like kin
med and sponsorships and things that the
medical genomics is doing on the -
blockchain are just a sample of what's
coming in the future economy I call it
the fractal ization of niches the
blockchain is going to touch every
single aspect of our society in some way
shape or form and if you haven't
understood this yet and you've just
heard about this thing called Bitcoin or
you're wondering what - is doing here
let me explain to you what I think is
going to happen first the information
that we have been giving to
organizations like the government
Facebook Google all of these things that
invade our privacy in ways that we don't
really understand at a very basic level
the ways that they invade our lives and
collect the data on where you had
breakfast this morning
what hotel you stayed at what your
current your credit number credit score
is you know your bank account balance
how much money you make who you work for
who your friends are what your friends
buy what you buy what you buy for your
friends all this information is being
collected on us
- believes and the - ecosystem believes
as an ethos that privacy is very
important that's why a lot of people
think that - is a privacy coin which is
it kind of is it offers privacy it's
always opt-in privacy
now that's just one of the things that -
is doing what you get with that privacy
is the ability to treat a digital token
a scarce digital token as cash it's as
good as cash you can exchange it at
places like cannabis stores and nobody
has to know that that's what you're
spending your money on because you can
opt in to a private option this is why -
is here - the - masternode network as an
organization and I should say at this
point it is a legal legally recognized
Association the - Association of
masternode owners is listed as the
beneficiaries on a New Zealand trust
that is administered by a Swiss
organization that has the the Swiss
excuse me switch administrator that is
legally bound to protect the interests
of the beneficiaries and again the -
masternode owners association of
masternode owners which is an
association of random people anonymous
people throughout the world who own -
master notes and I will tell you what
that is if you're not aware in just a
minute this association of master note
owners is the beneficiary of this trust
and the Swiss administrator is bound to
work on behalf of that beneficiary with
regard to the assets what are the assets
currently -
- poor group incorporated and - ventures
which hasn't quite listed yet but - core
group Incorporated is a Delaware
corporation that currently employs about
70 people roughly about half of whom are
developers charged with the duty of
improving and sustaining the -
masternode network the - master dote
network is a protocol it's actually a
copy of Bitcoin with improvements it
works just like Bitcoin if you know how
Bitcoin mining works you put a node on
the network you mind on the network use
spin hash cycles and you can earn tokens
on the network if you add to the ledger
if you add the next block to the to the
ledger
that's the blockchain the chain of all
the transactions that happen on the
network this network is public open
source and censorship resistant meaning
you can send money to anyone in the
world and nobody can stop you this
basically makes you your own bank it
removes central banking from the
equation of issuing money and managing
money but it does put you in the
position of having to take
responsibility for all the things that
banks and governments do in terms of
issuing and transmitting money to people
around the world the nice thing about
this is we get a little bit of our power
back we are empowered to control our
financial futures by managing our funds
in a way that nobody can stop us nobody
can tell you that you cannot transact
with this person and nobody can stop
your your account from functioning at
any time as long as this public open
source platform continues to exist which
it has for about three years just on the
- masternode network the Bitcoin network
has been going about 10 years now and
the reason that I believe so very
strongly that cryptocurrency is going to
in fact disrupt every single industry on
this planet is because we've already
seen I have been privileged to see three
instances of such disruption in my
or lifetime of 42 years first time
happened when I was nine years old with
the PC revolution when my dad would not
buy me a strobe light and in my nine
year old angst I learned to code basic
and turned that IBM PC Junior into a
strobe light god damn it and I was very
pleased to have done that and I realized
as a nine-year-old child that that was
going to change the world
empowering a nine-year-old to turn a
computer into a strobe light means that
anybody in the world with a computer can
do a lot of very powerful things a lot
of very powerful calculations a lot of
interesting things both in terms of
graphics and as we've seen here science
and academics and education worldwide
the next time it happened I was running
a BBS a bulletin board system when the
internet came about and I told my
parents that they needed to invest in
FedEx and UPS because of your box store
in the world it's gonna disappear and
everything's gonna be shipped around the
world I mean how else you gonna get your
products well now I'm seeing that soon
enough we'll be able to fabricate them
off the black blockchain and they'll
just have corner locations where you
just fabricate whatever you want to
fabricate give it about 20 years I
promise you it's gonna happen so this is
what I think is going to enable be
enabled by these blockchain systems this
this exchange of value that has come in
in this quarter quarter century of this
information age as we're currently
labeling it is now going to include not
only information and media and
connections and social aspects of our
society but now we have an exit strategy
from the centralized banking and
government controls over value we don't
need to have borders on our value we
don't need to ask for permission to
exchange value and soon enough we won't
need to ask for permission to trade many
many billions and millions of dollars
worth of value and perhaps even the
dollar won't be the denominating factor
of the future that's what I think is
gonna happen
and I would like to make sure that
everybody know is that this is happening
because we right now are in this 1% this
very small population that are becoming
aware of cryptocurrency 1% of the world
which means the value that exists on all
of the cryptocurrency networks which is
currently around 200 to 250 billion
dollars depending on how you look at it
happens to be close to about the same
amount that the Federal Reserve drew
down beat on its balance sheets between
September and October of this year what
I the reason that I share this is that
there is an immense amount of value that
is out there in various organ is a
various situations of value whether it's
gold or many hundreds of claims to that
gold that sits on top of gold in bond
markets or banking industries and things
like that
that will very likely be subsumed into
the script of currency market and the
reason that it's going to go that way is
because the blockchain offers a public
open source ledger that anybody can
confirm whether or not value has been
transferred just like a retail cannabis
business who wants to accept something
of value in exchange for their goods and
services that's why we're here and the
interesting thing about this masternode
network this - masternode network is
they vote on what to fund they vote
every month on whether or not to pay the
salaries of the core team they vote
every month on whether or not to support
events like can med or to support the
etching and hashing of the new genomes
that medical genomics discovers - a
public open source repository that will
be available for as long as the network
exists these are the things that I think
are for the public good these are the
things that are going to attract people
who believe that they should have should
be more empowered financially with their
own data and attract themselves to and
opt-in to this this new economy that I'm
hoping that we can build together and so
the reason that I'm here
is to say if you want to build this
future with me if you want to assist
Doug and medical genomics and excuse me
I said Doug Kevin Doug has been helping
me a lot at the event today and medical
genomics in this process of bringing
data to a public space of bringing value
to ourselves of removing the controls of
the system of control that the current
banking and and government institutions
offer us and empower ourselves to
exchange value among one another and
exchange information among one another
and create public open source
repositories that are censorship
resistance to change and manipulation
some of these things are going to be
wonderful for us a scientific journaling
mechanism is it's going to be wonderful
I don't know exactly where that project
it's at but that's that's gonna be a
wonderful thing that's gonna be added
and I want to help build this I went all
in when I read the Bitcoin white paper
in 2015 which I recommend that you do
it's a very interesting kind of
financial political statement once you
read it and if you're at all involved in
software are capable and understanding
some of the principles that are in this
document you'll see that the intent of
the thing is very simply to say look we
don't need these banks anymore and we
don't need governments in the business
of printing money because we have
another option here and we don't want to
centralize that control in any entity
because as has been demonstrated
throughout history whenever whenever we
centralize that money and power into an
entity they typically abuse it and it
attracts corruptible people and those
corruptible people often end up
corrupted and once you have a system of
corruptible people you it's it's a
difficult situation to exit and so I
realized that that Bitcoin whitepaper
offered an exit strategy to humanity
that we never had before and I want you
all to see this help see how this
cryptocurrency movement of whom only 1%
of
the world is aware right now of which
only 1% of the world is aware right now
we can start to bring this into our own
lives as I have now one thing I will
warn you at this point never if you are
looking at cryptocurrency as an
investment only invest what you're
willing to lose now
me when I started investing in the
cryptocurrency industry I very quickly
realized that most of my life I had been
living paycheck to paycheck so it really
wouldn't make a whole lot of difference
if I just went all in with my crypto and
my job so I started earning everything
that I had in crypto and I said moved
everything out of the Fiat system now
that's me because I'm okay losing
everything because I know that I can
start from zero and that's okay now if
you're there with me I will help you but
if you're not there and you just want to
dabble a little bit come visit us at the
dash booth at the exhibitors Hall
tonight or tomorrow I think we're gonna
close up early tonight but tomorrow I'll
be there all day come talk to me we'll
set you up a wallet we'll get you
transacted at least once maybe you can
get one of these nice - shirts and you
will have received your initiation into
the cryptocurrency industry just that
simple now I'll tell you at this point a
little bit of context Bitcoin was the
first it's ten years old since then
there have been thousands of crypto
currencies and tokens that have been
created if you're not aware - is only
one of them but by measurement of market
capitalization - has always been in the
top 20 since it's been introduced into
the system and the whole market has
fluctuated quite a bit if you're if
you're not aware it peaked as a markets
almost to a trillion I think it got to
about eight hundred and seventy eight
billion in market capitalization for the
whole market in December January this
past year and now again we're down a
huge percent almost 60 70 % down to two
hundred billion I think it even got
lower for a little while just to show
you that it is a volatile market so if
you don't have the guts for that
volatility don't again don't invest but
watch this watch how it happens if you
want to transact if you want to gain
your privacy if you want to gain control
your own finances pay attention to
what's going on in the crypto
cryptocurrency space three minutes so in
summation pay attention - is just one of
thousands - is not the best - is just it
just happens to be my current favorite I
will jump ship if I think - is not doing
what it should be doing but you if you
want to learn more and start to get
engaged in this space certainly check
out the crypto show.com also on a
co-host of that radio show which is
broadcast on Bloomberg AM radio in five
different cities San Francisco Houston
Phoenix a couple others I always forget
but let's check out the crypto show calm
let's talk Bitcoin calm you can listen
and learn about what's going on in these
cryptocurrency spaces come visit us at
the booth I'll be happy to talk anything
that you'd like about cryptocurrency
software development again I advise a
number of blockchain projects I advise
merchants on how to build ecommerce
systems and I'll be happy to help you
and one interesting note that I should
mention I do not work for a particular
company - is the first decentralized
autonomous organization of which there
are many now but as a Dow were all free
agents every one of us who is working at
the booth is only believing in an ethos
and we are not paid to be here I was not
paid to speak here I was just
enthusiastic and wanted to get this
message out to as many places as I can
and there's a lot of cryptocurrency
conferences happening and I personally
prefer anything that has nothing to do
specifically with cryptocurrency so
again I want to thank you all very much
for having me here I'll be available for
questions and I love to talk about this
stuff forever so please bother me