[Music]
explain a little bit more about the
methodology behind your uh toxicological
risk assessment that you're
performing yeah that's a great question
so toxicological risk is a component of
the the unique um Hazard risk of each
ingredient coupled with the exposure
level so I always like to describe this
in terms of alcohol most of us are all
very familiar with alcohol so for
example ethanol that is the compound
that has the inherent risk in
alcohol and so we understand the
toxicity of ethanol then you compare
with with the exposure level so for
example one glass of wine
you're probably going to feel totally
fine um you'll wake up the next day feel
totally great go about your day no
problem so that is a very low exposure
to ethanol so the risk is very low but
then let's say you know after I do my
presentation I'm really excited I'm
going to celebrate and I drink a whole
bottle of wine so that's a much higher
exposure and while I'm drinking that
bottle of wine I might lose a little bit
of balance right I might say things that
I think are really funny but maybe not
be so funny um and then the next day
when I wake up I'm probably going to be
very dehydrated I might have a headache
but ultimately I have a really great
breakfast and by the end of the day I
feel totally fine again so the risk
between you know a glass of wine and a
bottle of wine is a little bit higher
because we're doing we're getting
exposed to a higher level of that
ethanol so that's the idea behind a risk
assessment because nothing and I mean
nothing in this world is 100% safe so
it's really important to understand the
inherent risk of that individual
component but then also to understand
how much of that component how much of
that ingredient can a consumer be
exposed to without having any risk or
without having any like you know the
risk is at a negligible
level so the methodologies that I employ
here at true
turpins um includes surveying all of the
publicly available data on each
individual
ingredient compiling all that reading it
understanding the
conclusion and then I perform a set of
calculations which is very standard in
toxicology um and so these calculations
do things for example if it was a study
with a rat we need to understand what
that means in a human so I do a
calculation to put it into the levels
that a human would be exposed to then I
need to put it into the exposure of a
cannabis consumer right so I understand
how much is a cannabis consumer vaping
every single day how much of this
extract are they being exposed to every
day so that's a really important
calculation then once I get that calcul
or once I get that answer from the human
exposure
level I apply a set of uncertainty
factors or safety factors they're
sometimes called so what that means is
we found this limit from a study where
there was no Adverse Events to the rat
but we're not 100% sure if a rat is
totally equivalent to a human so we're
going to apply this uncertainty factor
which brings this No Effects level down
let's say 10 times so now it's 10 times
smaller limit so it's going to be more
conservative limit so we can be more
confident that that limit is not going
to cause harm to our cannabis consumers
in the final product so that's kind of a
brief overview of you know what a
toxicolog risk assessment is and how I
perform that excellent excellent so in
your example with alcohol you were
mentioning how ethanol is sort of the
the compound um that can cause harm I
guess for like of a better term so when
you're looking at
[Music]
a