[Music]
them of like what is genetic engineering
what is gene editing and sort of um you
know clarify th those sure sure yeah so
so genetic engineering um is is I guess
is kind of defined as moving a gene from
one species to another so for instance
if I maybe if I give an example
so back in the mid to late '
80s uh the papaya plant was basically
being decimated by a virus called
ringspot right so the all the Hawaiian
plantations were were being devastated
at the time and they couldn't breed in a
a good resistant or bring in a good
resistant line so the University of
Hawaii and uh Cornell I believe
identified a Gene um not from papaya but
a a gene that would be resistant to the
papaya ringspot virus so they put that
Gene and this was actually with a gene
gun um they put that Gene into Pap into
a papaya plant um and and found out that
yes indeed that plant was resistant
fully resistant to uh the ringspot virus
so that since that Gene didn't come from
papaya that's an example of a GM or a a
genetically modified organism right so
now you know I don't know if you you
knew or people most people don't know
that you know most of the papaya plants
that we've been eating since uh the late
80s are GMOs um but it's it's it's you
know that one particular Gene that gives
it resistance to that papaya disease
excellent another example maybe you know
is is a purple tomato that came out
recently last year uh they came out with
a purple tomato that was another uh
genetic Ally modified tomato that was
made through agrobacterium
transformation but it just put basically
in genes that uh were anth thein genes
and so they're making purple
tomatoes excellent and and on the on the
flip side Gene editing is is a little
different because now you're basically
just removing a little bit of sequence
or or adding sequence that's already
there into the existing cannabis plant
from its own genome so you're not
bringing in an external Gene you're just
either you know cutting it and deleting
a few bases or bringing in a gene that's
uh that's in cannabis already to give it
a different different trait okay so
that's the main distinction then
engineering introducing genes from a
different plant editing is um just
editing the existing genome in that
plant yeah and I guess a way to look at
it is the way that that um I guess the
FDA USDA look at it is is um if if the
plant can be made by normal breeding um
because through normal breeding you know
when you take two plants two cannabis
plants together and breed them there's
going to be a lot of shuffling of
different genes and amongst you know
amongst their genomes so if it's if it's
something you can make through normal
breeding which editing is because you're
just um you know taking out or adding a
few bases of its own genome then they
consider that editing
and yeah
[Music]