[Music]
with that said Ed what inspired you to
create high science specifically about
cannabis and why
now you know uh back in
2018 I had acoustic Noma surgery and if
anybody knows what that is that's a a
tumor in the brain uh that's connected
to uh your basically everything and
after surgery I spent 33 days in ICU and
had some
issues uh and the medicine I was on I
did not like uh I also believed when
they did the the surgery was I don't
know 10 12 hours whatever it was uh they
said it was easier to remove it was more
cystlike uh than the tumor uh and I
believe that when I found out I had this
this uh problem I just smoked a lot of
weed because I heard uh it was great for
cancer and tumors and blah blah blah the
list goes on so I smoked a lot of weed
and uh I believe that's what made it uh
easier to remove the doctor doesn't
think so but that's medical versus a
cannabis guy and uh I had this idea for
a show and because I wanted other people
to understand what cannabis was all
about uh and managed to through a friend
meet uh the infamous David mckellop uh
who's now my partner and I don't know
what I would do without him uh I think
we make a great team uh and he asked me
do you really think uh we could do this
and I said I do David and he goes who's
going to own the IP and I said you and I
uh we're not going to sell it to a
network uh we're going to do everything
ourself
and he said let's go uh he comes from
the television world and uh we sat out
on a road to find the most
incredible
OG entrepreneurs in the Cannabis
industry from medical geonomics being
the top lead scientists in the country
and around the world uh to the little
guy that produces seeds uh we wanted to
really
showcase these incredible entrepreneurs
and the incredible work that they're
doing with this plant and I gave all
these puzzle pieces to
David and here we are getting ready to
launch the show today the
27th uh eight weeks David took this and
built one hell of a beautiful puzzle
this show is going to be great not only
informative educational entertaining
it's all right there excellent yeah and
David tell us a bit about your
background and what got you involved in
the project you know I'm I'm a I've
spent most of my life as a television
programmer I've headed up uh programming
departments at the National Geographic
Discovery Channel uh history A&amp;E I ran
A&amp;E as the general manager um so I've
spent most of my life producing programs
um everything from uh Deadliest Catch at
Discovery to Storage Wars Pawn Stars and
uh Duck Dynasty at history and A&amp;E um so
I you know i' I've been doing this most
of my life um when I met Ed you know I
had I kind of left the network you know
you you you can't program a you have
there's a certain limit to what you can
do in terms of your age and everything
so it's time to let the other people
come in in program but I had a great run
and loved what I was doing um and you
know I was looking for my next thing so
when Ed approached me I was skeptical to
be quite honest with you you know to me
it was like oh you know am I
allowed to say that um is that
um that um I'm not gonna just sit here
and do some kind of Stoner show you know
that's just not what I smoked the I
smoked some weed when I was a kid in
fact we when I was growing up we
actually smoked weed we didn't really
drink I never even drank until after
college um but anyway I started to meet
some of the people Ed had rounded up in
this group and I started to do some
research and I suddenly realized
wow um people's perception of the
Cannabis industry is still squarely in
this idea of a of a recreational drug
and the government and big
pharmaceutical companies would love to
have you think that but what we soon
discovered where Ed had shown some light
and I did some Discovery is that quite
the opposite I mean up prior to the to
World War II cannabis was the go-to
treatment for up to a hundred different
alements it was also the main treatment
for pain before aspirin so we began to
discover that the relationship of human
evolution and cannabis evolution is
tightly bound and it's somehow gotten
lost you know I have my theories on why
a lot of it probably is people don't
have patents on it and been trying to
make a lot of money off of it but anyway
so I thought you know what I'll take
this I'll take this on you know we
didn't have a lot of
money uh but we had a lot of passion and
someone like Ed and we met some of the
people and the characters in the show
and we worked hard and we all chipped in
we didn't weren you know we weren't
paid this was kind of a uh it became a
passion for me and um because I know how
many people can benefit from it and the
most important thing is is that people
there been lots of stories about people
overdoing it or going into emergency
rooms and that's because there there's
no information there's no one there's no
trusted source of information the
government doesn't want to tell you
anything pharmaceutical companies don't
want to tell you anything so people are
basically finding out for themselves how
many gummies it takes and that's a
disaster you know an
uneducated population is not going to
really be able to fully Embrace what
cannabis can do for the human body and
since no one else is going to do it Ed
and I decided that we're going to do it
and the first step in this was to create
the high science TV show which is going
to be an anthology Series so this first
series is we're following a a family of
investors but our
third uh we could be doing something
totally different but the goal here is
to educate people at the same time and
have a and have a lot of fun so that's
how I kind of got involved in it
excellent
[Music]