foreign
[Music]
Coffee Talk podcast where we talk with
the leading Minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I am your host Ben amaralt I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the can Med conference
we are now officially three months away
from the cammed 23 Innovation and
investment Summit which takes place May
15th through 17th at the Marriott Marco
Island Beach Resort in Florida
believe me when I tell you you do not
want to miss this event not only will
you get to learn from our oral
presenters who have been curated by our
esteemed Advisory board but we also have
four intensive professional development
workshops planned covering medical
applications of cannabis strategies for
fighting plant pathogens laboratory
compliance challenges and investment in
cannabinoid innovation
we also have a number of networking
events planned including Beach dinners
and open bar cocktail hours
if you have received your invitation to
cammed 23 register today to reserve your
spot and if you have not yet received an
invitation go to canmetevents.com now to
request one
my guest today is Dr Marcus Robin
Marcus is President and chief scientific
officer of delic labs a licensed
cannabis and psilocybin research
laboratory focused on extraction
optimization analytical testing and
process development
Marcus has been in the Cannabis industry
since 2014 and has held several
executive positions in analytical and
production companies his research into
process optimization and analytical
methods has been recognized with a
number of awards and he has become a
trusted advisor and mentor to multiple
startups startup accelerators and and
organizations including can Med
at cam mid 23 Marcus will be presenting
the topic of birds bees and buds how to
talk about cannabis and how to label it
correctly
during our conversation we discuss some
of the issues with current cannabis
labeling as well as some potential
alternatives
more specifically we discuss how THC
percentage is miscalculated the fact
that only a fraction of the THC in
cannabis flour is actually consumed
how joint architecture affects the
amount of THC the smoker consumes
why the ABV percentage in alcohol and
the THC percentage in cannabis are not
one in the same
and how establishing a standard unit of
cannabis products May shift the focus
away from THC percentage and towards
things like Aroma terpene profiles and
flavor
before we get to my conversation with
Marcus I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor juvealife
founded by Pioneers in the science and
business of cannabis and guided by a
team of Highly acclaimed medical
professionals juva life brings
unprecedented depth of knowledge in the
science and medicinal effects of
cannabis
they're vertically integrated approach
allows juva life to carefully oversee
every aspect of development from
cultivation to Consumer with deep
expertise in research testing and
efficacy
it's an approach that enables not only
quality and consistency of product but
most importantly it assures accuracy and
legitimacy of testing and research data
learn more at juvalife.com that's
j-u-v-a-l-i-f-e.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr Marcus
Roggin
[Music]
good afternoon Marcus thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast yet again
thank you for having me yet again
all right so you have a problem with
cannabis labeling you've written several
articles on the topic and you're going
to be presenting about it at cam med23
so let's let's get into it what is wrong
with the current way that we label
cannabis
a lot uh and uh you have to come to the
event in Florida to like hear all about
it uh but here I will give you a a quick
uh summary of it
um before I give away what is wrong with
it
except everything uh let me explain
where I come from
so I came to the Cannabis industry out
of University just finished my postdoc
in chemistry
um and I've no personal background in
cannabis so I came to it new and fresh
and
so I I might have looked at things a
little different and it's like not
that's why normal normally people would
say oh that's the way it's always been I
was like why do you do this and so I
started asking things uh with my main
research field of cannabis extraction
right that's where most of my work comes
from but it then also dawned on me at
some point
that the way cannabis
um is labeled
um is mathematically wrong so that's how
it started because
um you see on on flower labels that
there is a total THC value or a total
CBD but effectively every cannabis
cultivar nowadays is just pure THC so
total THC and um total THC is made up of
the natural produced THC asset that's in
the flower and then THC that that
happens after decarboxylation which
hasn't happened yet in the flower but
it's the compound you get when you smoke
and you want because that's
incontoxicated and instead of labeling
this is how much THC is in a THC acid is
in there but people want THC people came
up with a total THC number because
there's a weight difference between THC
acid and THC so therefore they are
correcting this
and when I was explaining this to my
fellow researchers who really have no
background in cannabis and just uh
students at the University in British
Columbia at UBC
um
I stumbled over the point realizing that
the weight correction is done
for the THC acid weight loss
but not for the weight loss of the
sample
so it's mathematically incorrect because
you're forgetting the denominator
the best example is if you take pure THC
acid Crystal like a pure THC acid
Crystal you would normally think yeah
that's pure THC right THC asset THC is
like it's Purity it should be there for
100 THC or total 100 total THC
but by the mathematical formula it would
be
87.7 total THC which makes no sense
right how can a pure compound not be
pure
right
and and so autonomy you're forgetting
this uh denominator and you're not
correcting for mass and so I wrote about
this but when I then started thinking
about this does that have any influence
I realized
the whole industry
sells its products based on one number
total THC
unfortunately yeah aside from Total THC
being mathematically wrong and I find
this as a scientist interesting but I
think the general public thinks uh geek
uh or nerd and moves on
the general public should be interested
in the fact that cannabis is just sold
as one number it's total THC
and yes that's what the customer wants
but that's also what the we educated the
customer about
right
and there's a strong reason why that is
because THC was the is the main
intoxicating compound and it was like
the first one we could test for so we
saw it we made a number we bred for it
we focused everything on it
but
if you take parallels to other
Industries
alcohol is not bored by
the alcohol number in it
because if the highest number of alcohol
is what you are after then every time
you go into a wine store to buy
something you walk out with a bottle of
vodka right
and we should all drink ever Everclear
and
and the U.S shouldn't drink any
Budweiser
or Pop's Blue Ribbon because German bee
has more alcohol and I generally can't
understand why you wouldn't why you
drink American Beer not German beer but
that's a different story
so
this focus of total THC
is preventing the industry from
building on its
um
aspect of flavor like the there is the
intoxicating aspect of cannabis but then
there's the connoisseur the high quality
the the craft cannabis that everyone
talks about but then you only sell it as
such THC right it's like so
that was my my internal
conflict
um that then made me think about how
could we correct that
right no
and it's interesting too I mean when you
mentioned that it's just the way that
it's always been and you know people
might not be questioning in it
um I'll be completely honest I hadn't
actually really considered
the way that we're reporting THC potency
um until I started reading through what
you've written getting ready for this
interview and I hadn't actually
considered what that percentage actually
means but when you think about it and
the parallel to I think alcohol kind of
drives this home
at least in my mind you could tell me if
I'm wrong but you know alcohol by volume
kind of makes sense right if it's eight
percent then okay I'm gonna drink this
liquid and you could calculate what
percent or what volume actually of
alcohol I'm ingesting but when it it
when you see THC percentage on a flower
you're not just eating that flour you're
you're burning it you're decarboxylating
it it's it's sort of a different method
of ingestion and is that part of the
problem as well is that you know that
percent number isn't actually
you know telling you what you're
actually going to be consuming
you're absolutely correct so
um
that's my advantage I have my own
research lab so I can actually test and
measure things
so
for the last few years we are doing
smoke research so we have a robot that
smokes a joint we can put therefore a
joint or a vape cartridge to this robot
and then capture what comes out and we
can measure puff puff and for the whole
joint
and
we we recently did studies on seeing if
the the particle size of the flower
that you put into a joint so if you if
you break up a flower Bud into big
chunks or really fine powdery chunks
right
does that make a difference in the
inhalation of THC
and it does if you have a fine powder in
your joint you inhale double the amount
of THC
for the first few Puffs then you do
for large chunks so one millimeter was
five millimeter particle size
so and it's the same flower
and then in addition the small particle
The Joint Burns quicker and then the
large particle
the burns slower and you get more Puffs
out of it so overall you inhale more THC
for the large chunks
when you smoke the whole joint but if
you just take one or two Puffs then the
small particle size is the right one so
this notion I buy a I buy a pre-roll
joint with 25
THC is better better in air quotes
because it gets me higher than a 19 th
total THC joint
is wrong because the architecture makes
a big difference right a particle size
packing density we also looked at water
content and how that affects it right
and
and so having
a percentage number for an inhalable
product that is burned
um doesn't really make much sense
because it doesn't directly correlate to
how much you inhale and also side note
when you smoke a joint
you maybe get 20 percent
of all the THC that's in the joint so if
we say that a joint has a hundred
milligram of THC in that flower
and you smoke it you inhale 20
milligrams of THC
wow over the course of it the rest is
destroyed
um goes into the room
sticks to the paper we haven't found
every single milligram of THC yet where
where it goes but not all a substantial
amount of the Cannabis of the THC that's
in the Cannabis joint doesn't make it to
your mouth
interesting
and then we could also discuss if you
inhale it does it actually reach your
bloodstream
it's more biological question and and
part of the ideas that we had for for
different uh ways of labeling it but uh
when we are talking
about how to labor cannabis better and
my position comes from
having done the math having done the
the chemistry experiment actually
measuring stuff
um and and so I think I can
speak from presume Authority saying the
current way is wrong
right
and now if I understand correctly so if
I have you know I have 25 flour right
and I roll one one gram joint with very
fine particles and another one with
bigger chunks and I consume both
entirely right
in different sessions I'm sure but I'm
gonna get a different amount of THC from
one versus the other just based on yes
how the particles are wow yes
and so and that's just joints right what
about you know if you're using a
um a bowl or a bong or a vaporizer are
those all you know
different
very likely but we have sofa only done
research on joints and vape cartridges
oh fun fact a vape cartridge and a joint
are about the same amount of THC per
Puff
okay
so it's not that the 90s on the particle
size though right
there are error bars on everything so
they are within the same area so it's
not like you inhale one milligram for a
joint and 10 milligrams for a vape
cartridge you inhaled somewhere between
half a milligram to two milligrams in
both cases depending on the the flower
the mill size the oil the hardware but
it's it's somewhere in the same region
and is that independent of what the THC
percentage is of the flower
yeah
yeah so we tried different we we bought
different pre-rolls you can buy in the
store and we made some from our own
flower uh stock in the safe and and this
yes there are factors of one or two two
or three in in air so like half a
milligram versus two milligrams but uh
when we think in scientific terms we
normally think in orders of magnitude so
is it one ten hundred right that size
steps and it's all within the the one
problems so really that percentage
difference that you see you know in
different products it doesn't really
translate in terms of
you know in actuality no and it's not
and an important part it's not directly
correlated so it's not that the 19
flower gives you less of a buzz than the
25 percent
flower
because architecture again joint
architecture and in under joint
architecture I go particle side packing
density water content
um paper uh mouthpiece right everything
wow um and that also means that the
around 20 percent THC flour
and the 90 percent
cannabis oil
from a vape cartridge still gives you
the same amount of THC per puff so all
the politicians that say that joint that
that cannabis is getting too strong
[Music]
they see oh 90 Vape cartridges
but then the Vape cards gives you
the same again per puff because if you
smoke a whole whole Vape card that has
like 400 Puffs on it
um
that is going to give you a bigger bus
or a total amount of THC but
I would say that very very few people
can smoke a whole Vape card in one
sitting okay yeah well I know they
exists
but I I would say that more people can
smoke a whole joint than that they can
smoke a hole
yeah and I mean and so what about the
whole idea that at least anecdotally
people who may have may have used
cannabis back in college or high school
and now they're coming back to it and
they buy something from the dispensary
and they think wow this is way more
potent than I remember it being
that might be the case that might be the
case I'm sure there's an inflection
point if you have like three percent THC
versus 20 THC I I go with that
um
and I'm not old enough to be those
in college back then
theoretically I went well effectively I
went directly from college to cannabis
so I can't really say
and I actually never smoked myself so
really difficult
but there's also the aspect that you
lose your
um your tolerance when you're losing
your tolerance to THC or to cannabis in
general it takes about a week maybe 10
days
of not consuming at all to lose most of
your tolerance to the drug
so the kids that might have in college
dabbled with a few joints so therefore
where regular users
and have built up a tolerance and then
don't smoke for 30 years they lost all
the tolerance so is it just the I lost
my tolerance or is it really stronger
and and I leave other and let others
decide on that yeah that's a fair point
and we didn't have I mean at least when
I was in college we didn't have
laboratory tested
um cannabis either so we didn't I mean I
have no idea what the percentage was of
that back then so it very well could
have been three or five percent who
knows
um
so I think we've done a good job kind of
establishing what's wrong with labeling
at least and this is only just in flower
and I know you have you know comments on
the tinctures and other things too but
so let's let's talk about what ways we
could we could do better or some ideas
that you've had
yeah so my my base uh base thought is
don't sell it as the high number of THC
but you still need
to inform about the amount of THC
present
right
because that the regulator requires that
right so there needs to be a THC warning
unit there is package sizing
particularly in food and tincture
settings
so
um
if you sell it
package it by THC
uh amount but
make it in a way that it's just
a given like a bottle size
let's go to just we we will switch
between cannabis and alcohol a lot
um so if you think about beer beer
always comes in the same volume
right it's the same bottle size so you
never really think about bottle sizes
you only think about oh today I just
want my own beer
um or if you're buying a wine like there
are small bottles and large bottles
right do I want just a wine bottle for
myself or do I want a wine bottle for
the whole table right so you buy the
different size bottle but otherwise you
don't think about the volume
so can we turn THC into a volume thing a
package size thing your standard size
because that yeah standard size so that
would allow us to to
say yes there's THC and you're buying
the intoxicating part but let's now
focus on all the other cool things that
I'm in our cannabis product so that
you're like we got away from the THC now
let's talk about all the other things
that make our flower
better than the the rest in the store
and if you in Canada you can't do
advertisement you can't do fancy
labeling but you can inform about
testing
so okay so my I have two proposals for
for the THC question and that would be
either we take the idea of alcohol
the standard drink
so you would have a box
or a jar of flour
and in that jar it's not a gram or an
eighth but there is one or two servings
of THC hmm so at that point it becomes
unimportant if the flower is 19 or 25
percent
because you always have the same amount
of THC in there
um and how we then Define the serving
size
um that can be we in the industry could
come up with an idea or work with
regulator on that
because we already have a serving size
in edibles
depending on which country or state
you're in that might be five milligrams
10 milligrams per serving
so if we think about that the standard
joint right now is one gram flour and
has 20 THC so let's say 200 milligrams
of THC
would be our serving size so we just
package each jar that has then 200
milligrams of THC
um and there therefore there might be
one gram or one and a half grams or only
0.8 grams of flour in there depending on
the concentration but you know that when
you consume this you theoretically
had the same amount of THC
And if every box from every supplier is
100 or 200 milligrams of THC you can
then start thinking
how about we by the one with the the
fruity terpenes or we buy the ones with
the with the skunky flavor which which
comes from thials
um or we do this from the local uh
grower so you can move away from THC and
think about other other things
because the Cannabis industry always
talks about the Entourage effect and all
the other flavors and then salsa that
talk to THC so like
let's try to like put this all together
and like do a con
consistent marketing messaging
yeah and so it so if I if I understand
your point here like if you had a
standard serving size then I mean if you
had a 25 flower versus a 10 flower there
would be more actual biomass in the 10
right because you would need more of it
to reach that right ribbing size
right
okay right but
um it's similar to a uh to to be a wine
out and and vodka
you already know that the serving size
of beer is bigger than a shot of vodka
right so again that you are you're
supposedly consume the same amount of
alcohol
yeah a drink is a drink is a drink
yeah well you might be able to down a
vodka bottle quicker before you feel
full or intoxicated and then you have
consumed more alcohol but that's a
different
story
luckily
THC inhalation is very very quick in its
intoxication so over consumption is less
often
issue there
I understand it is an issue for
unexperienced users on the edible side
right that's why we have serving sizes
there yeah
no that's a good point
no and I think you know the the
correlation again to alcohol makes sense
when you're comparing beer versus wine
versus a spirit although
um what about craft beer in the fact
that you know some of these beers are
getting up to like nine percent alcohol
by volume so like the whole idea of you
know I drink one Budweiser and I feel a
certain way versus uh you know a one of
these craft beers that's nine percent is
that more of a a an apt comparison to
what we're seeing with cannabis in the
the differences in the percentages there
no because then Budweiser would have
gone bankrupt if that would be the case
because that's what currently happens to
all the
cannabis producers that can't make a
flower over 20 mm-hmm
right so people are buying a Budweiser
not because of the alcohol content but
for another reason
I think I'm not lying they buy it for an
alcohol content otherwise the the
alcohol-free Budweiser would be selling
uh massively
true but I'm just saying if the one like
like we see in cannabis the kind of the
sole determining factor of quote-unquote
quality is your is your THC percentage
that's not the case in alcohol or else
Budweiser wouldn't be the most popular
I'm German so I find it difficult to
find quality in American BS but a
different story so I said popular not
better
the
alcohol user
or alcohol consumer is aware that there
is more to the drink than just the the
alcohol number
and therefore craft beers that go to
nine percent or there's some Stark beer
in Germany and Scotland where they have
gotten over 30 alcohol content yeah
they're using freeze drying to do that
it's very laborious but again
if you if you want a craft beer with
more
um
then you might do so but
that might be more a question of do I
want
a wine
or beer of that alcohol content then
saying I just want to drink
five glasses of beer today do I take
butt or the nine percent craft beer I
think that's not really the question you
have there it's more your you are
considering what
flavor experience you want to have and
and that might include this craft beer
of nine percent or you pick a white wine
versus a red wine
um and their people people go and and
consider flavors and actually wine might
be a better example than beer because
a Budweiser is a Budweiser it like
tastes the same everywhere it's always
the same but in in wines we already know
that different years have different
different years from the same wine
producer have different flavors and and
they are priced years and and not not
surprised years
and the the the variety and variability
of of flavor experience is priced into a
wine
and people seek that out
and that's what cannabis is we the
Cannabis industry has an impossible task
on trying to make a consistent product
that tastes the same every time right
and has the same THC content every time
so why not give up on it and think about
it more from the craft or Craft brewery
or the um the wynyard approach
yeah
no I mean it's something that's come up
time and time again on this podcast was
the whole is the whole idea of
the
laser focus on THC percentage is you
know doing a disservice to the industry
just for the reasons that you said that
you know people aren't concentrating on
the flavors the Aromas
um or even just you know how clean the
smoke is how you know Pleasant it is on
the pole or anything like that it's just
THC percentage and you know perhaps
having a standard unit like you've
outlined is a way to sort of level the
playing field
right
and the regulator
on the edible side
prior to regulations there were
chocolates with like 420 milligrams of
THC or or the thousand milligram THC
chocolate bar like the this like oh we
we put a gram of pure THC into the
chocolate
these were these things existed
and then the regulator came and said
like no
do it in a in a package size and and
then the industry can adapt I I find it
annoying when people say oh don't do
regulations
um people are like Industries or
products adapt to pressures and uh it
might even
make for a better product
yeah so I I could assume we are early
enough in this industry
in this legal industry and in the US
it's still not legal
uh in Canada it is uh and in Germany
medical is but they're thinking about
regulation so I think we're really early
enough to maybe do a concerted effort by
the industry
or n and or the regulator
to say
package size
hmm
THC is package size not THC percentage
but THC package size
yeah
and and you have to have different
package sizes for different different
product classes you can't you can't say
that the same amount of THC should be in
a joint than in a vape card
we are going to run into issues there
and
uh and then this would allow us to think
about all the other
benefits or so that that cannabis has to
offer to the consumer
yeah no and I think you're right I think
you know edibles
you know like you said that has been
regulated to be kind of more of a
standard size and I think you know
tinchers the way that that's measured or
the way that that's labeled that makes a
lot more sense too right it's the amount
of milligrams that are in this volume
um makes a lot makes a lot more sense
and we we saw a standardization there
that right it's like normally like what
is it 40 milligrams per milliliters or
so and you have like 100 milliliter per
bottle or so right it just
someone has standardized itself and and
that is because you you can measure the
THC before you formulate it into the
product right into the chocolate into
the oil right you can measure that
um so in in cannabis flower where you
can't control it as well you just have
to get away from the weight and just say
well we just the weight of the biomass
and just like two different ways go away
from the ounce and the the eighth and
the gram and just say package size of
that many milligrams of TLC and like
like we had talked about earlier so much
of
what is eventually going to get into
your body is going to be dependent on
what method that you use to ingest it
right right whether it's a joint versus
uh anything else yes and and you are
absolutely right and that is actually
the the alternative
um way of labeling that I that I propose
so there's the alcohol side right
package size that many milligrams of THC
per per package like a standard drink
like a standard unit
um
but it doesn't speak to how much THC you
actually get into your system or how
intoxicating that is we know that that
uh
Edibles hit you harder than flour
because the THC is digested first in the
liver and it forms the 11 hydroxy THC
which is more intoxicating so you get a
bigger Buzz
um
and we talked about that joints
depending on the architecture deliver
different amounts of THC to the body so
therefore even the same same flower
depending on how you make it would
deliver different amounts of THC so if
you go by package size you would have
the same package size but different
effects right
so therefore
I thought of an alternative but a little
but more complicated way to presenting
so not the presentation is not more
complicated but the
finding that number is more complicated
um
did you take your multivitamins this
morning
um not a multivitamin but I do take
vitamin D okay so uh how many how much
vitamin D did you take this morning
um I believe it's 1 000 IU
right you took a thousand uh
international units of vitamin D so how
much milligram was that
I don't know
you don't care that's okay because the
international units are built to give
the same effect independent of the
formulation
to the user
and it's a it's an arbitrary measure
that is not translatable from vitamin D
that you talk to vitamin C that others
might take or Vitamin B or whatever
other multivitamins they take so the
international unit doesn't care about
the amount you consume it cares about
the biological effect
and so you see where I'm going with this
mm-hmm
so
how about
we do a really really complicated long
and expensive study on figuring out how
different cannabis products and
formulations and consumption methods
affect the body
and deliver the same and then try to
find the the right amounts per
formulation to deliver the same amount
of THC to the brain to get the same
intoxication or yeah to deliver DHC to
get the same intoxicate so you see it's
way more difficult to yeah to do but
they have done it for vitamin d and
vitamin C and so on so it like it can be
done but I'm not a biologist or medic uh
a doctor so I actually don't really
understand how they do it I just know
that it's being done
as if we sorry but there are a lot more
variables in cannabis right because of
the different cultivars the different
modes of administration and all that
sort of thing yes and so that's why I
had to offer two ideas because you can
shut down an idea early or I invite
experts in that field to come in help
with comments so I might just have
pushed
the stone I hope that others help
rolling it along excellent so
um if you then say now you if you have
to figure that out you could now say now
we sell cannabis as
thousand IUS
and then you can say the chocolate is a
thousand I one piece of chocolate is a
thousand IUS
one dropper of that tincture is a
and this one joint is
a thousand IUS
at that point
and from that we know that it's
different milligrams for the texture for
the flower and for the chocolate
but the end consumer doesn't need to
understand now milligrams milligrams per
milliliter and percent weight
percentages
the consumer only needs to remember one
thing I use or standard unit or whatever
you want to call it
I wanted to call it standard Buzz uh but
or unit of buzz but I I leave that again
to other people
and so the end consumer only has to
remember that there is one kind of
measurement or or numbering
and that that user
if they are new they are advised to take
a thousand
yeah uh and if they see that was a bit
much then they might realize after the
second or third time like 500 is there
preferred number
and for uh experienced user they might
go to five thousand
units
[Music]
but they then can switch from a join to
a to a cookie or to a gummy
and know that they get the same Buzz
they don't have to retry trade every
single time right
and it's in the nutraceutical Realms
that I use so this standard unit of
effect in cannabis would also be in this
semi-medical effect and that uh arounds
and that's what what medical amariana
was the trail barriers are for the
legalization the medical effects and it
would help with a self titration of the
product
excellent
all right Marcus I know I'm already over
the time that I I promised I would keep
you it's a fascinating topic and I think
it's going to generate a lot of good
discussion at can Med yeah I hope so too
but before I let you go
um I'm already going to provide links to
the articles that I know that you've
written on the topic
um in the show notes but if there are
any other resources that you would like
to share or that people can read up more
kind of on this issue please please let
us know right now and then of course any
social media or websites that you'd want
to plug uh please thank you very much I
I do all in one
um our website uh is nowadays
effectively uh
suppository a depository for all our
Publications presentations podcasts
white papers basically all the research
we do we publish on our website and that
would be
deliclabs.com
insights so Dalek Labs delay comes from
psychedelics because that's our current
company so d-e-l-i-c
l-a-b-s.com slash insights
excellent
all right Marcus thanks again and I look
forward to seeing you down in Marco
Island yeah I'm looking forward to it
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Dr Marcus Roggin check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and thanks again
to this episode sponsor juva life
our next episode will drop March 1st
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime head over to
canmedevents.com now to check out our
preliminary speaker list in details
about our professional development
workshops while you're there if you
haven't received an invitation yet you
can request your invitation for the
cammed 23 Innovation and investment
Summit we are really excited about this
year's event and truly believe it has
the power to transform our industry
through collaboration and Innovation I
sincerely hope to see you there
but if you can't make it in person to
Marco Island we do hope that you will
continue to stay connected with us
through the podcast and through our
social media channels you can find us on
LinkedIn Twitter Facebook and Instagram
just search for Kim at events all right
and that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and be sure to come back for the
next can Med Coffee Talk
[Music]