[Music]
um I did want to ask you about um the
Women's Health Initiative at mind uh
it's mentioned in your abstract as
something that you guys are looking into
or sort of expanding into um so please
share about that and sort of what what
conditions you're looking at there yeah
whim or the Women's Health Initiative at
mine I just wanted something that was
catchy where I could say not just a whim
um so you know over a billion you're
always with the puns I try I really try
um over a billion individuals are
affected by things like gynecologic pain
in this country it's largely
understudied this is an underserved
population for a million different
reasons and there are lots of reasons to
explore the potential application of can
cannaboids in these conditions for
example we did a number of survey based
studies these were my first real survey
based studies I had done a little bit of
work in this area before but it come in
with um per menopausal menopausal and
postmenopausal disruption and things
like um cannabis or cannaboids we did a
survey study that was a bit of an
adjacent clinical um uh investigation
individuals who are using a commercially
available vaginal suppository for uh
menstrual related dysfunction and we now
have our very first uh project that's
funded to look at women with
endometriosis using a whole plant full
spectrum product that I made for folks
with endometriosis and related pain so
there's a lot of interest here and
people are using these products the
problem that I often hear about is
patients will tell you you know I don't
know my friend used this so I figured
I'll just try well wouldn't it be great
to actually have data that could help
individuals be informed about what
products they should and maybe shouldn't
be exploring I don't know just a thought
um so that's that's I think a a rather
exciting area again endometriosis is is
one of those conditions that so many are
affected by so many are affected by yeah
and the number of symptoms is rather
staggering when you really start looking
at the data and so if you can improve
the quality of life and you can reduce
discomfort and increase people's ability
to sleep and be less again either less
anxious or have less pain or all of the
above why wouldn't you
try no it's interesting you mentioned
endometriosis we did have a presenter
last year uh who talked about that and
it was sort of more exploratory of you
know could cannabinoids potentially be a
good treatment option um and it sounds
like now you're actually investigating
that so that's that's fantastic there's
every reason to think so given the
relationship between the endoc canono
system this endogenous system you know
chemical and receptors throughout the
brain and body and the and the
gynecologic system right so again when
we think of the ways that we're all sort
of wired why wouldn't you try to harness
the most powerful things that you could
that are potentially less invasive or
less quote disruptive to other things um
you know if it isn't likely to do a ton
of harm and could potentially help I'm
all for trying to see what what we get
excellent
[Music]
a