[Music]
give us an overview of what they are and
what their role is in
cannabis yeah Ben absolutely so uh tpin
themselves are not unique to cannabis so
these are small molecules that are found
in essentially all plants at least all
plants that I know about what makes them
kind of unique for can is there's a lot
of them in cannabis more of them than
there are tend to be in other plants
like hops or or pine or whatever and so
what is a turpine a turpine is a small
simple uh molecule like it's small um
very aromatic very small very Hydro hydr
phobic SL lipophilic it's a small
molecule and it we've sort of known
about these molecules for many years
because as you just said they add to The
Taste and Aroma of the plant and so you
have something like you know even if you
don't know what tpin are you kind of
have still experienced them so you you
smell that fresh lemony smell from a
real lemon not the not the stuff that
comes in a can and you know that's
that's deliming right that's a that's a
turpine you smell that smell coming off
of hops that's Alpha huming uh you know
the pine tree smell that's beta pining
and so on so you've all experienced
tping even if you haven't run across
that term before and so in terms of what
they do in cannabis yes of course they
add to that unique Aroma and flavor
although um
parenthetically they actually are not
what give cannabis that real skunky
smell so we've actually isol or weed
were not the ones that isolated our
collaborators isolated that compound
called penal thol working with it
separately it actually has different
activity than either the Turpin or the
canono but just kind of a side note
there so it's not exactly that skunky
smell but some of the other taste and
Aroma elements of the plant are from
these tpin and so of course for many
years now people have been looking we
sort of knew that it did this taste and
Aroma but people suspected that these
have had therapeutic and pharmacological
effects going back some time and so
those have been under active
investigation in the literature and um
and then what as also as you suggested
that people have suggested that these
turpins contribute to the Entourage
effect the idea that the tpin might
somehow combine with the canabo to give
you an effect unique to the plant that
you wouldn't get from either one
purified alone and so there were sort of
all these ideas floating around there
had been some studies particularly in
pain suggesting that tpin could relieve
pain even clinical studies had shown
this uh but there were some real
limitations in the literature and the
there still is no solid evidence whether
or not the Entourage effect actually
occurs in like a a cannabis extract that
you yourself are taking or smoking or
whatever and so we kind of surveyed this
landscape and about 2020 is when we
started our work in this we said okay
you know there's a lot of suggestions
but not a lot of hard data so let's
drill down and figure out what these
molecules are actually doing rather than
just kind of throwing around ideas and
uh so we started by isolating the
turbines and studying each one
individually rather than as you say
combin into this kind of this mix of
this extract so that we could really
figure out which each one does alone
before we start you know at looking at
them in combination and so we published
that initial work in 2021 showing that
the turpins have what we call a canaba
mtic effect that they they behaviorally
they look like a canono although they
are not a canono and their ism is a
little bit different than a typical
canono but nonetheless It produced some
of these same effects in animals like uh
you know sedation the kind of the couch
lock or couch high that you get um
catalepsy decrease in body temperature
uh pain relief and so on so it had these
had these effects and interestingly in
terms of the Entourage effect when we
combined the turpine with a canono a
synthetic canono we got a higher impact
than either one alone and that's kind of
what got us the most attention in 2021
was this idea that that you could comb
that have that trines were having this
effect and that the effect could be
greater when you combine them with a
cannaboid and so that's what really got
our journey started in in this
area excellent um so how do turpins
interact with the human body um
particularly in relation to
pain yeah so that is still you know
really a big unknown question right not
completely unknown so there have been as
I mentioned clinical studies other
studies showing that the tpes relieve
pain so even like say a study where they
would give a Lin to um laboring women
like women in labor giving birth and it
show that they had this benefit and
there other studies looking at chronic
pain patients and so on give the turpine
you see this benefit but there's still
even when you know that there's still a
lot of unknown questions first of all
like we all know that turpins have a
strong smell and we also know that
humans have a strong placebo effect uh
when they're exposed to what they think
is a medication like I haven't seen any
well-controlled studies that suggest
that the turpine effect is separate from
the REO effect and mechanism is also
unknown right we don't know how this if
it is relieving pain how it's relieving
pain and that's something we try to
tackle in our own work by first of all
working with mice who do not kind of
have this this expectation that a human
being does they they don't know and
furthermore we were injecting the
turpine so they couldn't get like that
Aroma or that smell to sort of confound
the effect and then looking at the mice
and then also figuring out mechanism and
diving in and figuring out exactly what
these are interacting with and at least
in mice we now have data that suggests
that these tpin are stimulating The
cannaboid receptors in your brain so
sort of the the known cannabinoids that
are going to be or sorry known cannaboid
receptors that are going to be
stimulated by drugs like THC and also
your endogenous canabo that your own
body produces uh and we also know that
they can bind to and activate a receptor
called the adenosine a2a receptor and
again this is one of those targets all
of you know about even if you've never
heard that word before because that's
the same dra or sorry the same receptor
that's targeted by caffeine so we've all
stimulated or inhibited our Denine a2a
receptors whether you know it or not
because we we do it through caffeine and
we found that the turpine stimulate at
least in the mice this receptor to
produce a strong pain relief in a
chronic and neuropathic pain interesting
all right
[Music]
a