[Music]
so what were some of the most surprising
things that you found in that
analysis I think that the first thing
that c our attention was that we
initially expected that the Y jeans to
show more specific expression in some in
samples from male
flowers but only a small proportion of
the genus on the white chromosome are
expressed exclusively in the male
flower while many other genes are
expressed in samples from other chesus
including those from female
Bloods ER so searching about that uh I
see that this butter can be explained
by some researchers indicating that only
a small proportion of the white
chromosome is unique with the majority
being shared with the X
chromosome so uh but it's still a thing
that need more deep
attention um another notable finding was
uh the clustering of the Tricom samples
because as you know troms are where the
synthesis and storage of the medicinal
compounds are in the plant and we
observe that the triom
samples showed um very similar
expression profiles regardless of
chemotype indicating that it's likely
that only a small number of Genies that
differentiate these
chemotypes but again it's something that
need more deeper um
interpretations wow that's surprising so
so you're saying parts of the Y
chromosome can actually be found in
female
plants yeah a Genus provenance from the
the Y region also have expression in
other teur including in female um
cheeses in the case flowers interesting
[Music]
a