well first I'd like to thank the
organizers of can Med for so graciously
and generously inviting me to once again
be part of their annual conference Ken
met is one of my absolute favorite
conferences and I'm so sorry not to be
able to join you in person this year but
with that I will talk about what's in
your weed assessing the impact of
individual cannabinoids on clinical
outcome measures
now as I don't really have to explain to
this audience cannabis has been part of
ancient civilizations with references to
its use spanning thousands and thousands
of years in fact it was part of our U.S
pharmacopoeia in 1850 doctors could and
did prescribed cannabis it wasn't a
recommendation for use or a
certification for use it was a
prescription or any number of
indications or conditions or symptoms
that patients had
through a series of events it fell out
of favor in 1937 and by 1942 was pulled
from the U.S pharmacopoeia and in 1970
it was placed in the most restrictive
class of the newly created controlled
substance Act was classified as a
schedule 1 substance but it remains
today schedule one substance
since 1970
um when cannabis was declared a schedule
on substance California was the very
first state to re-legalize cannabis for
medical purposes in 1996
1996 I make this point because by the
time my own state had legalized cannabis
for medical purposes and you can see in
that timeline how different states sort
of followed California's lead but by the
time Massachusetts legalized cannabis
for medical purposes in 2012 there was
still absolutely nothing in the
literature with regard to what I would
call the long-term or longitudinal
impact of medical cannabis
um that surprised me pretty much
everything we know about cannabis comes
from studies of young primarily healthy
recreational Cannabis consumers in fact
my lab has been studying the impact of
recreational cannabis use for decades at
that time and I was quite interested in
understanding the potential differences
in those using for recreational versus
medical purposes so I scouted the
literature figuring there had to be
something and I did find some studies of
acute administration of some products
for medical purposes but nothing that
looked at Patients or subjects pre
versus post
nothing that classified or characterized
cognitive performance or really even
clinical change as a primary outcome and
nothing but followed patients over time
nothing at all so in 2014 I established
the marijuana investigations for
neuroscientific Discovery program or the
Mind program at McLean Hospital
so this is really the first program of
its kind and it's dedicated to looking
at the long-term impact of medical
cannabis use on things like clinical
State cognitive performance Sleep
Quality of Life conventional medication
use where applicable measures of brain
structure and function and related
measures pretty much anything we can
think of right the program uses
longitudinal observational
cross-sectional survey and clinical
trial models and it supports projects
designed to examine custom formulated
novel cannabinoid-based therapies for a
range of symptoms and conditions we
examine major and minor cannabinoids and
their impact on clinical and cognitive
outcomes and the ultimate goal here
really is to be able to harness
therapeutic potential while minimizing
risk and harm related to medical
cannabis use
so our very first longitudinal
observational study again longitudinal
observational study not a clinical trial
observational study
was designed to actually set the stage
for for other types of studies but this
study really looked at clinical State
cognitive performance mood sleep
conventional medication use all those
things I just mentioned to you and
individuals who were interested in using
medical cannabis before they began their
treatment measurement this is a very
important point so here are folks with
berries and Sundry indications and
conditions who are interested in
exploring medical cannabis use for
whatever indication or condition they'd
like but we've seen them before they
begin using okay we then follow them
initially we had very ambitious goals of
going out to almost one full year which
we thought was a lofty goal we have now
extend that several times we now follow
patients out to three years because
generally once they're enrolled they
don't want to stop
which is wonderful so we see them for a
baseline visit before they begin using
and we see them again at months 3 6 12
15 18 24 and now 30 and 36. uh we also
talked to them every month with regard
to their medical cannabis use and other
things they can use medical cannabis for
any indication or condition that they'd
like pain sleep mood anything and their
choice of products those products are
ultimately assessed by an outside
laboratory more on that in a moment the
assessments that they complete at each
of the time points those what I call the
Milestone
study visits so again Baseline three
months 6 12 Etc they consist of things
like clinical ratings where we're
looking at pain mood anxiety sleep
quality of life and anything else I can
think of
um very detailed uh information
regarding their medical cannabis use so
really detailed fine-grained information
individual level data
um the actual products are using product
type frequency amount Source cannabinoid
constituent profile Etc conventional
medication use because we're looking at
potential change over time measures of
cognitive performance and of course when
we can a multimodal neural Imaging
protocol that allows me to look at their
brain structure and function and all
sorts of other things so it's a pretty
comprehensive longitudinal observational
study
in order to be considered eligible for
this study people have to be over the
age of 21 and have a valid certification
for medical cannabis use or plan to use
products that don't require
certification this whole landscape has
shifted slightly since the legalization
for adulter recreational use
but back to the certifications they can
be for a range of indications as I
mentioned we didn't limit this first
study to any specific individual
clinical cohort we weren't sure how many
people we would get they have to be
candidates naive or have no regular
consistent use of cannabis over the past
several years and they have to be
negative for THC at Baseline
we also had a group of control patients
so these are individuals who have
similar conditions and indications as
our medical cannabis cohort but who are
not interested in using medical cannabis
at least when they sign up they're not
we've lost several people in the
treatment as usual group to the actual
treatment group over time not
surprisingly
so in 2016 we published our first paper
I was asked by a journal to get at least
10 patients from Baseline to their first
longitudinal assessment which was three
months I think we published on 11. again
we looked at these folks before they
began using medical cannabis and three
months after they had been using and
what we found was really quite striking
we found improvements on some measures
of executive function in clinical State
and a reduction in their use of
conventional medications use the reason
that these findings were so important at
least in my mind was that again we'd
spent decades looking at the impact of
recreational cannabis use on target
performance and clinical measures and
measures of brain structure and function
and generally I will work in the work of
colleagues across the country and
throughout the globe had suggested that
individuals especially those who began
using early on in the developmental
trajectory when the brain is still
vulnerable
um had decrements in certain aspects of
cognitive performance for example
measures of executive function we didn't
necessarily see those same patterns of
people who began using lighter a very
important distinction but so here's this
first study of medical cannabis patients
over the course of three months showing
no decrements in cognitive performance
but improvements so we expanded that
study and actually ultimately and I
should say that that first study got a
ton of media attention and I think it
was in the top five percent of all the
uh studies referenced in metric we uh
published I think in 2021 on a cohort
that we followed over the course of one
year this was uh 54 patients followed
over the course of a year again before
they began and then at 3 6 and 12 months
and once again what we found were
significant improvements on some
measures of executive function and
clinical State over the course of their
12 months of treatment we also found
that measures of verbal learning and
memory generally remain stable so no
decrements first and foremost what we
see in these studies is no decrements in
cognitive performance or clinical state
but improvements very very important so
this study has continued and now I'm
going to show you data from a larger
sample
so this is a data set of 67 medical
cannabis patients who completed a
Baseline and at least one follow-up
study
and you can see on the left hand side of
the screen that these folks are about 46
years of age so let's just say beyond
the period of neurodevelopmental
vulnerability these are not kids or
emerging adults right they're
predominantly Caucasian they have a
higher than average IQ at almost 120 and
they're well educated 16.54 years of
education as a reminder 16 years of
education is analogous to a college
degree duration of cannabis abstinence
so they've been abstinent from cannabis
use on average for 20.3 years that that
makes sense since most of the time if
these folks have had any history of
cannabis use it's a remote history of
use in high school or college
what are they using cannabis for what
are they interested in using canvas for
when they first enroll well the top
three indications really Echo what we
see across this country the top three
spots in this country and really every
state generally fall between pain where
anxiety as numbers one and two and then
sleep so in this cohort it's anxiety
PTSD then pain then sleep then there's
mood and attention and other what's
other inflammatory bowel disease chronic
migraine headache as I mentioned we also
have a pilot group of treatment as usual
patients with similar conditions but who
are not using cannabis so we also looked
at those folks over time
in terms of some of the assessments they
get these are self-report rating scales
in terms of looking at mood anxiety
sleep pain and quality of life and I
wanted to just highlight what some of
these are they're the profile of mood
state of really really common measure
all of these are very very common well
validated measures here we're looking at
total mood disturbance we also do the
back depression inventory very common
measure of depressive symptoms for
anxiety we have the back anxiety
inventory and the state trait anxiety
inventory again classic for Sleep our
primary outcome measure is Pittsburgh
Sleep Quality Index or the psqi for pain
we're looking at the numeric rating
scale the pain distress scale the pain
Disability Index and for quality of life
I'm going to show you data on the hoop
calls again this is a subset of what's
actually administered so first taking a
look at our cohort over the course of
one year in terms of mood what we see
again total mood disturbance of the
profile of those state is on the left
and the bank depression inventory is on
the right but overwhelmingly what we've
seen is that patients report significant
improvements in mood related symptoms
between 3 and 12 months after initiating
medical cannabis treatment the grain
line is our medical cannabis patients
the blue line is our treatment as usual
folks and what you see is a
statistically significant Improvement at
each time point for the MC patients we
do not see this change and treatment as
usual patients okay that's true for the
TMD and the BDI
when we turn to anxiety which is a very
a very special area of focus and
interest in my group once again we have
the back anxiety inventory on the left
and the trade scale of the STI on the
right
patients once again report statistically
significant improvements and symptoms of
anxiety between Baseline 3 6 and 12
months of treatment the treatment as
usual folks those folks on the blue line
that's the Blue Line there do not
demonstrate the same pattern no
improvement
looking at sleep patients are generally
reporting improved Sleep Quality between
3 and 12 months after initiating medical
cannabis use a statistically significant
Improvement at each of the time points
in the medical cannabis Patient Group we
do not see the same in the treatment as
usual
in a subset of patients these are folks
who are using medical cannabis
exclusively for chronic pain conditions
what we see here
is over the course of three to six
months patients with chronic pain report
significantly decreased ratings of pain
on the numeric rating scale the pain
distress scale and the pain Disability
Index across the board here okay again
the green line is the patient's blue are
the treatment as usual folks
statistically significant improvements
over the course of a year in the MC
patients that we don't see in the
treatment as usual folks are you sensing
a theme because I am finally with regard
to quality of life and this is the hoop
wall physical health on the left and
psychological Health on the right what
we see are significant improvements on
some aspects of quality of life
specifically here for physical and
psychological Health we actually didn't
see any change in Social relationships
or the environment subscale Sports those
remain pretty stable over time
for psychological and physical health we
do see a statistically significant
improvement over the course of one year
of medical cannabis treatment in the
patient group not in the treatment as
you should so
pretty interesting uh I mean I think
it's fantastic to see that overall
people are getting better but it
certainly raises the question what's in
your weed what might account for the
Improvement and how can we find out
what's in your weed how do we best do
this once again I turned back to my
extraordinary lab and we were able to
create a step-by-step metric that really
quantifies estimated maximum possible
cannabinoid exposure it's called can
account and it's an improved metric for
quantifying estimates of cannabinoid
exposure the increasing array of
cannabinoid-based products contain
various amounts of different
cannabinoids and other constituents
existing methods are pretty limited
though and none at all account for
actual cannabinoid content of the
products that patients or consumers are
actually using so we created something
this metric
basically considers things like the
actual individual cannabinoid
constituents frequency and duration of
use the amount used and the root of
administration or mode of use all of
these things are incredibly important in
figuring out quote what's in your weed
and what might people be exposed to over
time
so
um this is a just a slide showing
cannabinoid constituent information and
how you get it on the right side what
you see is a laboratory analysis that
breaks down again a cannabinoid
constituent profile how much of each of
the constituents is found
medical cannabis product samples are
basically sent to a third party lab for
this kind of profiling again it
quantifies the amount of individual
cannabinoids if actual product samples
are not available for testing or if
patients are unwilling to partner with
even a tiny amount for testing which so
far has not been a problem thank
goodness you can rely on dispensary or
supplier certificates of analysis if you
have to and also you can use product
labels
um not preferred given the very known
and very obvious issues with product
labeling accuracy so what you really
want is to get a sample of the actual
products that patients are using and
have an outside lab analyzed that's how
we did it so as an overview of can
account and I won't belabor this too
much you can pull the paper it's really
really helpful step-by-step guide
but basically we're querying patients um
and and you can use this with
recreational consumers as well for
people who are interested in figuring it
out
um you're asking questions about product
type frequency amount or magnitude use
and duration of use and again then we
get this laboratory assessment we
organize the data and then convert the
data into what I would call preferred
units for the calculations so we might
convert for example things like
percentage to milligrams per gram
um or millimeters to gram
um we also account for conversion of the
acid form uh to the active forms right
that's really really important and we
calculate exposure generally in two ways
you can use one or both of these one is
the discrete use approach so patients
report frequency and amount of the
products used each time so how much and
uh and how often they're using each
individual product or they can report
the total amount of a product used over
a period of time so for example I might
say to a patient so you bought three and
a half grams of X flour how long did it
take for you to go through that how did
you use it Etc so those are just some
examples can account this metric can
actually be used to estimate exposure to
any cannabinoid not just THC and CBD
which most people spend a ton of time on
but the miners as well as long as the
cannabinoid content is known and derived
from what I would call a reliable source
that's really really important
um this is just a quick slide that shows
you how you calculate exposure for the
discrete use approach versus the total
use approach but this is all detailed in
the publication and all of this is just
a way of getting to what I want to show
you which is the what's in your weed
Factor but again
um you can actually some cannabinoid
exposure for each route of
administration so for example you have
folks who are using roots of ventilation
they're smoking and they're vaping you
can sum those you can also some for
example anything that was an oral
Administration or mucosal or a
skin-based product some have asked us
whether they can sum exposure across
product types you certainly can
um I don't necessarily recommend it
because it doesn't account for different
bioavailability across product type and
root of administration we all know that
right the ways in which we use these
products and individual product types
are not all created people but back to
our own sample of patients so this is a
bar graph that basically illustrates
exposure to Delta 9 THC and cannabidiol
or CBD at three months and at six months
and what you see so THC is the dark
green and CBD is the minty green what
you see um immediately is that between
Baseline and three and Baseline in six
months our patients are being exposed to
significantly more CBD than THC
this is perhaps not surprising because
generally our patients are very clear on
not wanting to be high or altered in
fact what they say is Dr Robert I don't
want to be messed up I can't uh sort of
be checked out during the day I have a
job to do I just want to be able to
sleep through the night or I just want
to be able to take a walk with my
husband or remember my kid's birthday or
something that's what they tell you
they're not looking to be high so very
often they're choosing products that
have an array of non-intoxicating
cannabinoids very often rich in CBD
so to examine the unique contributions
of THC and CBD we actually conducted an
examined correlations between these
cannabinoids and outcome variables so
clinical measures and here's what we
found relative to Baseline following
three months of medical cannabis
treatment
irthc exposure was actually related to
improvements in pain severity as
measured on the visual analog scale and
the numeric rating scale and pain
related distress you can see that in
these graphs right so higher THC
exposure and you know greater
Improvement we didn't see any
relationship between higher tat exposure
and mood or anxiety measures so what
happens at six months
relative to Baseline at six months of
medical cannabis treatment th exposure
is no longer related to any measure a
pain or mood or anxiety so we saw it at
three months we didn't see it in six
months really really interesting
especially when we consider what's
coming next
with regard to CBD or can have a dial
relative to Baseline after three months
of medical cannabis treatment higher CBD
exposure was actually related to
improvements in mood we see this in the
Palms total mood disturbance score the
back depression inventory and anxiety
measures so both the trait and the state
measures we also see it in terms of
improvement on disability caused by pain
so the the pain Disability Index very
very important that's three months of
treatment
at six months of treatment now what we
see is higher CBDs exposure continues to
be associated with all of those measures
so we have that the total disturbance
and BDI and the anxiety and PDI scores
ircbd greater Improvement on all of
those measures and now we also have an
association with improvements in pain
severity as measured by the numeric
rating scale and pain related distress
so at six months we see the same
improvements with CBD on mood and
anxiety and pain pain distress and
that's uh now we're seeing pain severity
and pain distress also improving with
CBD very very interesting
as I probably don't have to explain to
this audience given some of our esteemed
folks in the uh in the audience I'm sure
um minor cannabinoids often exert a
major impact and although we need more
work in this area we certainly have a
fair amount of evidence suggesting that
some of the so-called minor cannabinoids
termed only minor because of the amount
within which they are present in
chemomars they can have a major
therapeutic effect so for example
cannabis Gerald or CBG has been shown to
exhibit anti-tumor antioxidant and
anti-inflammatory properties and is
often tattered as being neurogenic can
have a chromine or CBC
hypothesized have anti-inflammatory
antibacterial antifungal effects and
also shown to increase viability of
adult neural stem regenitor cells thcv
or tetrahydroconavivarin shown to
inhibit some of the negative cognitive
and physiologic effects related to THC
Administration it may also be
neuroprotective and that's just the
beginning so much more so the question
is what about the miners
well when we looked at the minor
cannabinoid exposure uh in our
population what we see is is certainly
um a range across the board with with
CBG and the acid form CBN CBC and thcv
but it raises the question of what's
what's in their weed what's in the
product so we did an analysis of all the
products submitted by our patients to
look at the presence of minors and what
we found this is all of the capitals let
me be clear not just them either this is
everything and I'm going to pull out the
miners so first and foremost when we
consider all of the constituents 82
percent of the products submitted had
detectable CBD 70 almost 71 percent had
detectable Delta 9. and really right
after that the next step Canada or CBG
at 58.8 percent and cannabochromine CBC
at 54.9 so well over 50 for those two
after that you have the acid form of CBD
you have CBN or cannabinol thcv Etc so
very very interesting right in terms of
what's in these products
so in more than 50 of the samples we
found CBG and CBC so we conducted
preliminary analyzes to look at the
potential relationship between these two
cannabinoids and any potential change in
clinical outcome what domains are we
looking at once again pain mood and
anxiety
and here's what we found
increased exposure to CBG and CBC were
both associated with lower distress
related to pain if you look on the left
that's CBG and the pain distress scale
on the left hand side significant and on
the right hand side that's CBC and the
pain distress scale so really really
interesting right we're not necessarily
seeing relationships between CBG and CBC
and actual mood and anxiety measures in
fact we didn't we looked we looked again
there's no relationships that we found
in this preliminary analysis between CBG
or CBC and any specific mood or anxiety
measure instead we're seeing lower
distress related to pain distress
related to pain
so let me summarize what we see so far
in a longitudinal observational sample
of medical cannabis patients the
clinical data are clearly showing areas
of significant Improvement between 3 and
12 months of treatment after initiating
their medical cannabis regimen
we're seeing improvements in measures of
mood anxiety sleep pain and quality of
life
their treatment regimens contain vastly
greater amounts of CBD relative to THC
we get that by using this great metric
can account and actually quantifying
exposure to individual cannabinoids over
time we're not guessing we're not taking
their word for it we're actually
quantifying it accurate estimates of
cannabinoid exposure using can account
or this metric will help clarify the
impact of cannabinoids on treatment
outcomes and hopefully generate more
accurate risk benefit ratios we're
desperately in need of it we need
something to help us
we also saw improvements related to THC
and CBD exposure that were very
different
when we consider pain we saw reductions
in pain associated with higher THC
exposure at three months but we did not
see that same relationship at six months
we have three months most associations
between pain and CBD exposure were noted
at six months and with regard to CBD we
did see improvements in anxiety and mood
with higher CBD exposure at both three
and six months that seems pretty
consistent so very different responses
to these two primary cannabinoids when
we think about them right before we get
to the miners when we consider the
miners we saw that the products that are
being used by our patients do contain a
range of minor cannabinoids more than 50
percent of all products analyzed
contained CBG or CBC
we did see significant relationships
between the minor cannabinoids and
measures of pain specifically for CBG
and CBD CBC exposure we saw a
significant association with reduced
pain related distress pain related to
stress so clearly we need additional
studies that look at specific
relationships between the so-called
minor cannabinoids and the major
clinical impact they may have and what
subtle nuances they may actually confer
so again pain related distress is not
necessarily the same as pain reduction
so really really interesting and
important area of Investigation
so next up I just want to touch on
mindful activities and the fact that we
do a lot of custom formulation we're
currently conceptualizing and
formulating a number of additional
cannabinoid Blends optimized to treat
various conditions and indications these
are whole plant uh derived full and
broad spectrum products hemp and
cannabis based and basically I create
study products that are high in
cannabinoids that are typically
considered minor but which demonstrate
tremendous clinical potential in some
cases this is for some of these studies
we're interested in examining the impact
of terpenoids on a number of
biobehavioral measures as well terpenes
of course are the essential oils that
give cannabis is characteristic scent
and flavor profile neither THC nor CBD
have a center flavor that's the
terpenoids they themselves have their
own biobehavioral health effects and I'm
actually currently optimizing some some
terpenes to ultimately address specific
indications and conditions which are
really exciting so we have a number of
clinical trials designed to assess
efficacy and safety of custom formulated
full and broad spectrum products and a
number of inds or investigational new
drug approvals in hand I'm very very
excited we're looking at moderate to
severe anxiety in a number of cohorts
anxiety and agitation and Alzheimer's
related dementia mood and anxiety in
patients with bipolar disorder that's
kicking off this month anxiety and pain
in patients with glioblastoma with a
very exciting exploratory aim of
potentially slowing tumor growth
and of course we now have a new study
focused on chronic pain and that's
actually taken
um a fair amount of work in terms of
optimizing some of these lesser-known
cannabinoids or terpenoids
in addition to considering THC and CBD
content again we're optimizing products
with regard to the miners and their
terminally contact so I would conclude
by saying we have an unprecedented
opportunity to customize and optimize
cannabinoid-based treatments for our
patients which has the potential to
transform patient care and medicine as
We Know by harnessing therapeutic
benefits of cannabis while also
mitigating potential risk and harm
based treatments may very well be the
answer for countless individuals for
whom conventional medication doesn't
provide adequate symptom relief or
produces unwanted side effects both of
those things unfortunately result in
lower rates of compliance in our
clinical cohorts so we have to do
something right and with this I would
thank you for your time and tell you
that I couldn't do any of this work
without my extraordinary team I mean
extraordinary team as well as my various
team collaborators and tell you that if
you have any questions I'd be delighted
to answer them contact me at grouper
mclean.harvard.edu you can also check us
out at themineprogram.com lots of
exciting things so much to be excited
about
of an amazing amazing rest of your
conference again can man is an
extraordinary experience and I wish you
all the very best stay safe