[Music]
so I think to start it would be great if
you could tell us what inspired you to
undertake this study of cannabis and
focus on developing a gene expression
database okay um well I would say that
the recent changes in the regulation of
cannabis use and cultivation around the
world have opened up opportunities to
research with the species to be
condensed more broadly so this has lead
to a rap increase in the amount of
information available about
cannabis so including earna sequence
data and however these data are often in
the RO
form uh meaning that the while the ear
A6 sequence files are available in
public databases for example uh without
proper futuring and Analysis they aren't
very
affirmative so and addition to this um
not all of this um data are linked to
published scientific studies so this
this is where the idea of the Cannabis
expression Atlas came in uh the goal was
to create a database that translates the
earic data so it's speak um transforming
R sequence information into easy to use
and refined data to anyone interested
in great so you're you're you're
Translating that data to make it more
useful yeah excellent um so one thing
noticed when I I was reading through the
the abstract in the paper is that you
chose to use the Jamaican lion reference
which again near and dear to our heart
at medicinal genomics uh our team is the
one who who put that together so how
does that reference benefit the
study um well um during my Nisha
research I realized that there was no
consensus about uh which reference
genome to use in cannabis research so
this made me want to look further
to available genomes for these species
to choose the most suitable one for
using our
study so I found that most of other
genomes came from female plants and were
from type one or three
chemotypes and that's mean that's when
the JAMA genome called my attention
because first it's a type two her so
which means that has the both gcas and
cbdas gen active and additionally both
male and female plants were sequenced
and the researchers from the medic
genomics had identified a Rion
corresponding to the Y
chromosome and this is uh a key feature
compared to other available genomes
because
which uh as I mentioned are all from
female plant so using this genome as
reference uh allow us to enrich our
database and identify Express terms for
why chromosomes and genes for example
and which can be very useful for helping
researchers to better understand sex
differentiation in canis for example
[Music]
a