[Music]
so what are um some of the signs that um
Growers should be looking for to in
order to sort of identify a problem
before it you know snowballs out of
control you know um one thing that I
always try to have Growers do is Empower
their staff because a grower is only one
person and there in any given facility
there's thousands of plants possibly but
you have people that are looking at
those plants every single day Empower
your staff to come to you they don't
need to be an expert necessarily but
they know when something's not right if
that plant looks different than it did
yesterday have them come tell you and
then you can figure it out you know it's
it's one of those things that if you
don't allow your staff like I don't want
you to have your staff think that
they're making a mistake you know what
I'm saying like a lot of times people
will not go and tell the head grower
that something's a Miss because they
don't want it to come back on them like
oh well then you did this type of thing
Empower your people to say like if there
is anything that's off let's figure it
out you know if this plant looks
different than it did yesterday if it's
got purple stems if it's got stippling
on the leaves if the you know turgidity
is gone and the leaves are starting to
curl down if they're starting to curl up
like anything that just looks a Miss
allow your how do I put it like you
don't necessarily have to have a team of
Master Growers you just got to have a
team of diligent people and as long as
there's one person on staff that you
know can say like okay there's an issue
let me go see it like most facilities
have one maintenance guy that fixes AC's
it's not on everybody to do it so if you
have one guy that's responsible for
plant health and pathogen mitigation
when somebody finds something he can say
hey I got to go tell Ben what I just
found and you know it could be that they
topped it funny it could be that it's
hlv it could be that there's an actual
issue going on beyond that you know but
having the ability and that
communication between your team is
Paramount uh because those are the guys
that are in the trenches so to speak and
you know you got to empower your team to
let you know what's going on because
again the head grower is only in one
spot at one time and having the ability
to have a team that can relay real world
information to you uh you know very
quickly helps a lot that flag system
that I was mentioning a little bit that
really helps a lot because a head grower
can stick his head in a room and count
Flags in 30 seconds and that's a great
way to you know also track progress if
we had 10 red flags last week and this
week we're down to five then what we're
doing is working you know we need to
continue on that process that we have
implemented if we were at 15 red flags
this week and last week we only had 10
then we need to switch it up because
it's getting worse and so it's it you
know communication is I think the most
important part of integrated Pest
Management to
me yeah the communication definitely
seems important and like you said it's
it's a culture right and um so how
common is that the culture in in
cannabis cultivation like is it is it
becoming more of a thing
I see more and more operations becoming
more and more regimented in terms of how
they do things and whether it's state
regulations that have kind of
facilitated that change or people just
realizing that they have to run leaner
because the market isn't what it was um
having the ability to educate staff and
you know get them all on the same page
and Empower people I think is the way
that the successful grows are going if
you punish your employees for trying to
do their best they're not going to want
to work for you
[Music]
a