[Music]
I'm excited to talk with you today about
this wearable EEG technology that your
team has developed to measure the
effects of THC in the user's brain so
let's start with what inspired you to
develop this
technology yeah thank you um so er I
think I was thinking about uh about this
the other day and the the main
inspiration to build this technology was
in 2016 when the Canadian government was
in the process of legalizing a
recreational Cannabis consumption and
the lack of a test to
objectively determine if a person is
cannabis inert or
not at that time we were building this
technology to detect drowsiness and
while driving and we wanted to help
truck companies to keep their drivers
alert so they were telling us about this
um upcoming legalization of cannabis
consumption for non-medical purposes and
that they didn't have a way of detecting
cannabis impairment and that the current
way which is
analyzing and detecting concentration
levels of thhc in saliva urine blood or
breath there didn't exist a test to
analyze the brain of of drivers so we
were like okay that's the aha moment
when we decided to Pivot from detecting
drowsiness while driving to detecting
cannabis impairment while driving and in
that way help uh multiple markets to
better determine if a person is or not
impaired because that the biggest the
biggest issue the we we we all know very
well that THC remains in body fluids uh
for many hours days or weeks post
impairment or experiencing the its
effects and and that that leads to
inaccurate determinations about being
impaired so that was the main reason
that inspired us to to build this
technology and once we build it we
realize that that
the the need for this type of brain wave
analysis was even bigger and Beyond the
the safety and law enforcement
applications and that other application
was for research to better understand
the effects and the quality and efficacy
of all of these Innovative products and
you know breeds and strains that the
market is developing and uh that's how
all started wow okay so so really to
start it was to try to determine how
impaired a driver was yes exactly the
the the Ontario brain Institute and the
Ontario Center of innovation two two
Ontario uh government organizations
fully funded us to to to develop this
technology and that's how we were able
to build it because I hope you will
appreciate then your audience will
appreciate that in
2016 nobody really but not many were
familiarized and and Believers of the
potential of artificial intelligence
specifically when it's applied in brain
data and so the government was the one
that believed in this you know potential
Grazy opportunity to you know compl the
current investigation process of
cannabis imper driving determination and
they were the ones that funded us to to
build this technology build it to a
commercially L level kind of a uh yeah a
level of commercial VI viability and
then conducting independent trials to
prove that AI can do this type of brain
wave analysis at a way faster and more
cost effective way and accurate than a
new Ro ologist or neuroscientist doing
it individually or manually right so so
that's how all started oh so interesting
so it's an AI component as well
absolutely that's the the the main
differentiator and the uniqueness of our
approach by the way because EEG
technology is not really new it has been
used for more than 100 years but in the
medical space neurologist
neuroscientists eag technicians
certified EG technicians have been using
it for you know more than 100 years the
problem is and in fact we we came to
this conclusion and realized that that's
the main reason why EEG technology has
been inaccessible to several Global
non-medical markets because when you
require a neurologist and neuroscientist
and EG technology is built for medical
applications it becomes very expensive
very complicated to use very slow and
that makes it not commercially viable
for all of these type of markets that
are also conducting some type of human
research not necessarily clinical or
therapeutic but is more about
understanding what is the state of being
of individuals to make better decisions
in terms of safety you know law
enforcement product testing product
quality testing ET
[Music]