[Music]
to all of that I'm sure there are some
people watching or listening who aren't
familiar with CHS so can you give us a
rundown sure so this is a condition that
was first published in 2004 in Australia
um based on several cases Within index
case going back to
1996 now what's interesting is usually
when something's reported for the first
time you have a real evolution of the
description however they kneeled it
pretty much from the start so what they
were describing was a situation in which
uh chronic cannabis users uh developed a
syndrome in which they had nausea
vomiting abdominal pain often cyclic
that seemingly was relieved by hot water
bathing and some of the patients
involved would spend hours in the tub or
the shower um to try and relieve
symptoms um so uh this gradually has
become more frequent either
ascertainment has improved or uh what
many of us think is that has become more
prevalent over time with the greater
prevalence of H potency cannabis
materials and this seems mainly tied to
THC but we should point out that it's
really an issue with any CB1 canabo 1
receptor Agonist because the problem has
also been described in people who are
using some of the
synthetics uh the high potency synthetic
CB1 Agonist in total absence of cannabis
usage uh so clearly that's the problem
um there have been other people that
thought or would like to attribute this
to pesticide exposure but certainly
people get this even with organically
grown cannabis um and like it or not
cannabis is the culprit
here okay um so these bouts with
vomiting now as I understand it this
isn't just sort of like an acute
response where you know you kind of have
one episode it this is this is going on
for quite some time hours sometimes days
yeah that's an important distinction
anyone can get sick from Cannabis if
they have exposure all of a sudden to
too high a THC level so I I think many
people have had the experience of uh
using a vape for the first time or
having an edible that was too powerful
and actually getting sick so this is
part of part of the problem it's sort of
counterintuitive to people because
everybody knows that you use cannabis at
least in low dosages to treat nause and
vomiting associated with
chemotherapy so it doesn't make sense to
people that you can have
this reaction that seems illogical
however it's very consistent with what
we know about canono that they have
what's called a basic dose response
curve not a break that down it means
that a lot of the canabo will have one
activity at a low dose and an opposite
activity at a much higher dose and so
that explains how people can get sick
from THC acutely but that's quite
different from CHS canabo hyperemesis
syndrome because that is a Subacute a
chronic problem where people um will
have these increasing bouts of attacks
of nausea vomiting and abdominal pain um
and uh basically they go on until they
abstain um as we'll get into there are
treatments for it but uh they're a
little um different than what we'd
expect as
[Music]
well
a