[Music]
and then took a few years off but now we
we're excited to have you back um in
your presentation we'll share data from
several clinical trials that you and
your team are performing as part of the
Mind program so that's probably a good
place to start tell us a bit about the
Mind program why it was founded and how
its 10 years of research have led you to
this point sure well first I will say
this I'm delighted to be heading back to
Canad this year and yes I was part of
early early caned meetings and thought
and still think it's um really one of
the best meetings there there is um and
I think it's a great opportunity to
interact with people from lots of
different areas um related to cannabis
and cannaboid based um work so the Mind
program did just celebrate its 10
anniversary which seems odd to me um I
will tell you I spent several decades
looking among other things at the impact
of recreational Cannabis on different
aspects of function so cognitive
performance and clinical outcome
measures of brain structure and function
you name it and we had done lots of
different studies again looking at the
impact of recreational cannabis and when
Massachusetts was on the precipice of
legalizing medical cannabis I scoured
the literature I thought let me see what
do we know about the long-term effects
of medical cannabis because as you
probably know cannabis was Rel legalized
in this country in 1996 in California
and despite that interestingly enough
there really was nothing in the
literature nothing at all about
long-term effects of medical cannabis
use I found some evidence for certain
types of studies that looked at you know
sort of a a quick and dirty if you will
um assessment of cognition as part of a
different kind of very short type of
study but nothing that was longterm
nothing that followed patients over time
and certainly nothing that looked at
cognition or clinical outcomes as a
primary focus and so I launched
marijuana investigations for
neuroscientific Discovery or the Mind
program with the singular focus of
looking at the long-term impact of
medical cannabis use and at the time I
think a number of people were sort of
like well you know you can do what you
you can try to look at these folks over
time but these are primarily
recreational people who are really just
looking for a legal way to use cannabis
and I I first and foremost I would say
that that was absolutely positively
untrue I knew it then and I can now I
can really point to you and say
absolutely it's it's not true um so it's
been an extremely important um program I
think it's still the only one like it in
the country and it's home to what we
call a number of Firsts we were the
first ever to do long-term assessment so
we look at patients before they begin
using medical cannabis and that's really
important so people have different types
of indications or conditions whether
it's chronic pain anxiety or mood
disruption sleep disruption you name it
but we look at them before they begin
using medical cannabis products then we
follow them over time they use any old
products they would like to use and we
have those products analyzed by an
outside lab so we know quote what's in
your wheat um that's because it's not a
clinical trial and I'm not controlling
what's given to them but then we can of
course look at their exposure to
different cannaboids over time which is
incredibly helpful in the meantime we're
looking at primary outcomes like chronic
pain like mood like sleep and then of
course measures of cognitive performance
and thankfully measures of brain
structure function quality of life Etc
and I think that again some of these
firsts that mind um has has sort of been
fortunate enough to to put on the map um
should be really
just what I would call the beginning of
the story right this is just the tip of
the iceberg so yes we're the first ever
to look at long-term outcome and
cognitive performance and first ever to
do IM
first us to do some of these clinical
trials all of which are informed by
these long-term observational studies
they tell us the directions that we need
to focus on patients have always been
our greatest source of information they
lead the way we follow them which is a
little backwards in terms of medicine
right it's not usual but we do it um so
it's been an incredibly rewarding time
um and I think the program is
unbelievably um helpful and now has
really expanded so it's um it's been
it's been a great Journey so far great
so you mentioned there was a lack of
long-term studies how long are we
talking so in terms of the types of
longitudinal studies that we're doing
yeah so if you look at the literature
again we were we were looking at
legalization here in Massachusetts in
2012 and there was nothing in literature
our first studies were designed to look
at individuals up to one year and again
I had a lot of people say good luck
they'll never stay well uh we have the
opposite problem which is that once we
begin looking at people over time and
establish relationships and people come
in and we have these very comprehensive
assessments they're interested in
staying connected so we started off
looking at outcome between Baseline and
3 months 6 months 12 months and every
month um our team contacts them and we
get an idea of what they're using how
they're using frequency magnitude all
that stuff but these in-depth
assessments at the Milestone visits then
we went out to two years then three
years now we're following people all the
way out to five years which is amazing
amazing so that's really
lucky excellent
[Music]