first what is this so this was a real
mystery it was first described in 2004
in Australia in eight patients but the
index patient first one that manifested
symptoms was cleared back in 1996 so you
can imagine going eight years with this
mysterious illness that nobody could
treat um they nailed the description
because what they've said um now uh
years ago is exactly the description of
the syndrome today which is a
combination of nausea vomiting abdominal
pain and hot water bathing behavior and
this was among people who had no
knowledge of other people being
similarly affected so it wasn't a matter
of one person saying hey if you take a
hot shower you'll feel better so this is
associated with cycles of of nausea
vomiting abdominal pain