so I got a call from a lab in Florida
and they said that aspil terius was
showing up in all of their samples
including the negative control after
talking with them I learned that a
recent batch of R&amp;D samples had tested
positive for aspir gillus terius I
speculated that possibly the samples
were so hot that the aspergillus was
able to sporulate and contaminate the
entire lab cleaning up contamination in
a lab is no small task and so I flew
down the next day to in we wiped down
every surface with 10% bleach including
the floors pipets benches and any
equipment in the
room at one point I was on my hands and
knees scrubbing the floor when our sales
account manager walked in and he really
got a kick out of that after several
rounds of cleaning and running blank
samples to check if the mold was still
present we got a clean
result the lab thanked me for going
above and beyond but I was just doing my
job