okay
this is a re-recording of an emerald
emerald
conference 2020 a that i gave at an
agilent seminar
so this is a topic that's going to cover
um a broad
array of information regarding the
cannabis genome so there is some work
here related to a pre-print that we just
published
we're going to go over some of that
there's also some work here that's not
in the preprint
that describes how to potentially
breed for particular hemp genetics okay
so right now there are some usda regs
out there
and they're pretty challenging to to
address right now because they're very
strict in terms of levels of thc
um and we're finding that thc and thca
can be leaking from a lot of other
cannabinoid synthase genes and we're
going to try and address how to track
those genetically
and what implications that has for
pathogen response because
eliminating some of these genes means
you eliminate some neighboring genes
which happen to be
pathogen response genes and in some some
of the cannabinoid genes
we're going to touch on that but
um to give you some um some back story
here
this actually uh was a project that
started um
a long time ago a couple years ago june
uh
2018 actually we started this with uh
with a grant that we received for
cryptocurrency and actually was
snowballed
by a foundation medicine sequencing
report
for my father and i explained some of
this
at a at a pac bio seminar at pag
back in january when we're going through
a bioinformatics seminar there
um there's a probably recording that
floating around as well
but we had a sense of urgency this
because this foundation medicine report
was actually a mutation of a tumor from
my father
it was a prostate cancer that they
biopsied they sequenced the biopsy and
found that he had a b raph
k 601 e variant that's an amino acid
position in the b raf gene and when you
have that type of mutation
they recommend akt inhibitors
akt inhibitors that foundation medicine
was confident with
um of course we googled akt inhibitors
and cannabinoids and up comes all types
of hits on how cannabinoids are
um are potent akt inhibitors
and our father was interested in using
those anyway due to the fact that they
were addressing the nausea and the bone
pain that nothing else seemed to touch
so
um so we had a sense of urgency on this
project um and that urgency was
underscored in the manner in which we
uh funded this this is one reason why we
truncate this long title uh
into a uh speed wheat as being an
abbreviated version of all of this uh
scientific mumbo jumbo we have here in
the title but uh
knowing we couldn't jump to nih to get
funding this quickly
um we turn to a cryptocurrency known as
dash uh dash is a fork of bitcoin
technically a fork of litecoin which
which uh forked off a bitcoin but uh
nevertheless its code base is very
similar
uh the only thing they changed is they
decided to create a treasury so that as
a cryptocurrency grew
and they issued more of these coins to
the miners
they could reserve some of those coins
into a treasury that people could vote
on
as to how to distribute those coins now
who votes well
there's another set of masternode owners
in the network that if you hold a
thousand of these dash
and as a proof of stake of your
ownership the network you get a dividend
of um i should say dividend you get you
get you have the ability to vote on
on these actual uh how to use this
treasury
so the masternodes are responsible for
helping distribute some of the coins and
making sure that the
the instazon works and they and they
they have to keep up a node that's fully
functional and fast that can relay
uh messages or transactions very quickly
um so the the master domain owners get
some of the rewards
of the block awards the miners get some
of the block rewards and then there's a
treasury and only the masternode owners
can um vote on the treasury
they have to have at least a thousand
dash piece anyway long complicated story
this cryptocurrency is interested in
solving banking problems in very various
jurisdictions in the world and one of
the markets they're interested in is
cannabis and they figured
having a really good cannabis reference
is going to help with seed to sale
tracking and it's going to help with
building a good blockchain for that
industry so
they funded this um the crazy thing
about getting crypto funded by dash is
that every month your funding can
disappear
um so we were granted a five month um
grant uh it was probably roughly in the
70 or 80 thousand dollar range but the
currency is so volatile it probably
ended up being about a third of that by
the time the project was over we we
actually refunded a time period where
the cryptocurrencies were going down
quite a bit
so every single month we had to refactor
our plan as to how we're going to
sequence this thing because the currency
would change on us and there's one month
we nearly got voted off
um so it does it does change the pace of
science and you can see some of the
stuff that's been posted
um on the page is a cryptocurrency
funded genomics page of menstrual
genomics that we'll talk you you know
walk you through how this project
progressed and every every single
experiment has been logged in every
single experiment negative experiment is
up there as well
so all your embarrassments are online um
okay so how do you get this published in
five months well it's really hard too so
what we did
uh is we put it up on a preprint server
uh and then
invited people on the internet to review
it we put out a bounty a 500
bounty for three reviewers to be
selected
based on their credentials we put their
credentials online so everyone can see
that they're not uh they're not our
friends
um and uh 500 upon completion if they
completed the review in seven days
all of them were completely reviewed in
seven days right so this is a really
fast way to get a review done
some people call it bribing uh we don't
think so we think there should actually
be a price signal in peer review so that
a market can develop and that really
good reviewers will get paid more than
bad reviewers and
that it would become a uh you know
almost an industry or market for some
people so
um uh you know stipends like this
actually give people priority to work on
these things and one of the reasons peer
review is broken is that no one has a
priority to do a well or to necessarily
do it quickly it's all done on charity
right now so
this is a way to cut out some of the
journals and just do pre-prints and
and bounties but nevertheless it's
controversial and we weren't going to
end there we just couldn't get this
thing through a normal peer review
process let alone get the genome
sequence in a five month time frame so
we opted to do this approach
and we have since followed up with a
more traditional approach where we're
taking
that data and of course 42 more genomes
and putting it through bioarchive and
in the traditional peer review process
so okay there's a lot more data in this
and this is the day that we're going to
go over in this presentation
uh this this this actually represents an
entire trio that we sequence a trio
is a sibling a set of parents in their
offspring okay so
mother father offspring in this case the
mother and the father happen to be
brothers so it's an inbred
trio and the offspring is uh happens to
be
a male and it ends up being i think the
offspring in this case is a type 3 male
so with that
we've got five tissues of iso seek also
done
on on the jamaican line mother okay the
the
the strain that we're sequencing here
the cultivar or however you want to call
it is a
uh is jamaican line uh the tissues
um that we're sequencing with isoseq
this is important to sequence rna
in order for you to annotate the genome
you want to sequence the rna from
multiple tissues
okay now we chose to take approach using
single molecule sequencing to read that
rna because single molecule sequencing
reads the entire
rna piece in one go you're not trying to
assemble the answer of the transcript
with a bunch of short reads you just get
one long read that goes across the
entire rna in fact the reads are so long
now they lap the rna
multiple times they turn these rna
molecules into circles and the sequencer
reads it like a gerbil on a wheel over
and over again until it gets it right
um so the best annotations in the world
are done with isosec right now
all right that's the method of choice to
annotate a plant genome so we did it
across five tissues
we did four tissues with a methyl seek
program
or or protocol known as emc from new
england biolabs
we then did 40 whole genome shotgun
libraries on illumina these ones were
barely amplified and the reason we took
very care
exquisite care to keep low numbers of
amplification cycles in these libraries
is because we want to look at copy
number variation and if you start pcr in
your libraries before sequencing you
lose resolution and copy number analysis
and we didn't want to do that so
all of these libraries have have have um
umis on them which are which are these
uh these
indices almost like a dna barcode that's
put on so that you can do
you can do molecule counting and and
detect pcr amplification bias
uh and you can also remove it but you'll
see in the in the paper we didn't
actually even need to use the umis just
by using three cycles of pcr there's a
very very uniform
coverage across the genome and we know
that because we compare the coverage of
this illumina method to what we have
from pac bio which has almost no
coverage bias
we have done some phase genomics work
and some ont i'm not we're not going to
touch on much of that in this
presentation we'll save that for a later
one that's a more complicated topic
all in all this represents about four
terabases of sequences in ncbi it's 40
times larger than any other cannabis
submission that we can find
i'm certain that that that landmark
number is going to change in time as
i've seen a lot of
data getting queued up to go into ncbi
but nevertheless it's a very large
change in the landscape of of cannabis
sequence information that's now public
this is now public in the koji genome
browser it's also public in ncbi
and you can read this uh paper here at
bioarchive this is what we're going to
be touching on
okay so a little bit about terminology
all right so
when you're sequencing genomes there's a
couple techniques that you can use but
there's three in general that you
probably heard the most about
you've probably heard about illumina
often often um abbreviated as il and
then
there's nanopore and there's there's a
couple different flavors of pact bio
this pack bio continuous long read
which is running the molecule as long as
you can not lapping it at all and you
have
a much higher error rate that way and
then there's pb
or pac biome ccs which is a circular
consensus sequencing that's the gerbil
wheel that's when you run it over and
over again you get really high accuracy
and only recently could they do this on
20kb molecules and we're going to touch
on some of that most recent data toward
the end of this
that's what's known as hi-fi sequencing
the graph here on the left is just
demonstrating which techniques
give you the most accurate genomes and
that's pb ccs
hands down this is the gold standard
nothing touches it there's there's
exciting work coming out of
oxford ganapor and illumina but they
don't have the accuracy yet and so
they can be a bit challenging for
assembling plant genomes um they can
help scaffold though they may play a
role in scaffolding some of the
cro the um the context together um okay
we're going to touch on a few of those
things uh going forward
okay so here the methylation maps and
the messenger rna maps were done for
these five tissues uh the roots didn't
seem to want to cooperate with us for
the methylation map but we did manage to
get some rna out of the roots first for
sequencing
um and a couple you know interesting
stories here's the adestin um
gene that you can see across multiple
different tissues having different
methylation patterns and this makes
sense because the intestine gene
gets turned on when you make seeds this
is the protein that makes hemp seeds so
nutritious
this is the protein we need to
understand if we want to feed the world
this is a really important gene cannabis
that you barely hear spoken about
um but uh you can see we have rna
transcript differences over here um that
are tissue specific and we also have
different methylation patterns and uh
why do we care well methylation is a
sign
that genes are getting turned off when
things are hypomethylated or red
when they um sorry hypermethylated when
they're red hyper meaning having lots of
methylation patterns it silences
transcription and you don't get rna out
of it
when things are unmethylated it begins
to turn on transcription
and you end up getting rna off of it so
methylation's involved in turning genes
on and off and so
it's always good to see correlations
between the methylation patterns and the
promoters of genes and the rna
transcription that's coming off of it
okay so a bit about rna so we take these
molecules of rna
and we clone them into a circle or we
put what are known as smart bells on
them
which makes a double strand of dna and
then you put smart bells or dna loops in
the end of it so when the polymerase
latches on with a primer
it starts lapping this molecule peeling
it apart and running around and around
them a circle this is known as circular
consensus sequencing
and the rna molecules are getting 50 to
100 laps now this is
running the sequencer that had
remarkable read lengths and as a result
we
could lap these things so many times
that we're getting q30
q40 dna that means dna sequence that has
1 000 one to 10 000 error rate
um here's the size of the of the rna
that we got out of tissues
um and then you can see the the number
of um
of genes that were discovered in the
process what we call these high quality
isoforms
um so any given gene can actually make
multiple isoforms because genes
have introns electrons and those can get
shuffled in various ways when it makes
an rna
the rna can choose to read every single
exon in the gene
and then afterwards it may get spliced
by the cell where it rips a couple exons
out or skips a couple exons and shuffles
them around
but that all happens in splicing the rna
so when you start reading rna molecules
you see
all the iso forms from a given gene and
on average there's probably about three
isoforms per gene
this is just demonstrating that if you
look at this curve here
based on the number of isoforms the
number of reads
as we sequence more reads we begin to
saturate the isoform discovery but you
will notice that this is not yet
saturated from any tissue so i would
expect if we double down on sequencing
here or sequence some more tissues we'll
discover more
genes than what we're going to describe
here but this is one of the first
surveys
um so the female genomes that are over
27 000 genes
the exomes larger than human that's up
at 40 almost 44 megabase exome
the exome includes on uh utrs
which are basically uh untranslated
regions these are regions that
include the promoter and can include
some of the terminators
on the genes and then all the exons that
actually
code for stuff from the first methionine
to the last start the stop codon are
known as cds those are coding sequences
all right so the exome includes the utrs
and um the coding sequence and it only
includes the
the internal exons all right now this
stuff is um
scattered or defragmented all over the
cannabis genome if you will
across 121 megabases so very large
introns as well
the genes are are easily disrupted with
structural variation
keith allen published some work
encourage people to look at this is
looking at a bunch of the terpene
synthase genes in jamaican lion and you
can see the different families that are
out there the family a b and c
terpene synthase genes and the fact that
they're um
seem to have long introns in all of the
family
genes there's in one particular gene
family that has longer
introns than the other and he's
correlated this with some of the
chemical data that they're seeing at
steep hill
okay now the male is very interesting
because the male is bigger the male has
another 100 megabase it's a tire an
entirely new chromosome the y chromosome
that the females do not have uh and as a
result of this we're seeing about 4
44 male specific genes that brings the
male gene model
in this plan up to 32 000 genes and
about 80 megabases
of this is why specific and about 30
megabases is what's known as
pseudo-autosomal y
the pseudo-autosomal region of y still
crosses over with the x so the genes
that are on the y
that can still cross over with dx are
important because those are traits
male-based traits that can make their
way uh
and and into into the x chromosome all
right now the the
the why specific sequence are if the
genes on that section well it's not
gonna it's unlikely you're gonna find it
breeding into your population unless
you're keeping males around all right
now
how do you assess whether these genomes
are done well the best
peer review is actually other people
utilizing this data in publications and
you saw that with keith's work and you
see there's another paper here from the
oarsburn laboratory that actually
ran mass spec not on jamaican line uh
even though this this image up here
makes you think
they ran on jamaican line what they did
is they got ms spectra of peptides off
of the plants that they worked on and
then they mapped those peptide sequences
to the jamaica line reference
and they're finding jamaican line to
have the most complete reference
we know that from just looking at the
assembly statistics we're going to go
over that a little bit
as to what assembly statistics do you
look at in order to evaluate the
completeness of genome but the other
thing you can do is you can do an
intersection which is what we've
shown down here in this venn diagram
which is that 98.8
of the mass spec data we find
corresponding homes for those in this
dna sequence information the jamaica
line genome
now they discovered 12 000 peptides this
is probably the first time they did it i
wouldn't be surprised if that number
rises in time as they dial up the
sensitivity of the instrument
or or survey different tissues um so
they're only seeing about 40
of the peptides that we see throughout
the entire genome but that's actually
pretty good when you think about
how many genes are actually expressed in
any given tissue it's rarely more than
that
so they're probably capturing every gene
that's present in the tissues they
surveyed
and if they survey more tissues their
number will probably soon match what we
see complete in the
in the jamaican lion genome mass spec
data brings other information
it brings oscillation signals that we
don't have in the rna it is so it's an
important tool to
complement the data that we've got um
okay uh that being said
the the rna data is probably more
sensitive um it is we can get single
molecules of rna sequence very readily
and i'm not as familiar with the
sensitivities in the mass spec but i i'd
be
i imagine it'd be challenging to get
down to single molecule levels with the
complexity of the entire proteome but
maybe that's possible
okay um so how do we start decorating
these chromosomes we don't really have
chromosomes right now we have an
assembly that has um
contigs which are just basically long
contiguous stretches of sequence and of
course those contexts are usually going
to break when you hit the centromeres of
the genome and the telomeres
because those are the ends of the
chromosomes in the middle
sometimes if you're really good at this
you can get through the centromeres
they're just now getting through the
centromeres on the human genome after
i don't know 10 how many years is that
now 20 years of trying to finish it so
um only recently have there been tools
to do tip to tip or telomere to telomere
assemblies and we're starting to do that
with jamaican lion
okay so decorating um the male let's
figure out what the y is what you do is
you take the male flower rna
those iso secretes you map them to the
female
reference right and then the reeds that
don't stick to that reference you map
back to the male
that decorates the regions of the male
genome that are unique to the male and
have no
home in the female this is probably the
part of the y chromosome
you might be seeing down here which
doesn't cross over with x anymore
this region up here the top part of it
the smaller part is believed to still
cross over with x
this one if we want to decorate it um
this is what we do
and this gives us the information that's
down here
and when we do this we find
regions of dna that amount to about the
size of a chromosome
65 contigs and one of the largest
contigs in the genome there's about 427
bosco genes in here which is interesting
so busco is a tool that we use to
measure the completeness of genomes
uh and it's um it's there's around
there's just over 2000 genes in the
bosco data set that they believe should
exist in all plants and you want to find
you know over 90 of those in fact
jamaican lines finding around 97
of those genes are in the jamaican line
reference and that gives you a sense as
to how complete the genome is
okay but some of those are on the y
which is kind of interesting
um uh unclear whether the duplicates are
not they might have counterparts in
other parts of the genome
but that's that's something to know
now the other thing to take note of is
this process isn't perfect right there
could be structural variants that are
novel
in the male genome that aren't male
specific they're just not in the female
but they're on one of the autosomes
and we'll touch on a few of those and
those would make it through this process
all right so this
this is a combination of both what is
male specifically expressed and also any
novel structural variations particularly
inserts that could be in the male genome
that would make its way through this
that aren't in the female all right
and we have a way to solve that the way
to solve that is with a whole lot of
whole genome shotgun sequencing which
we will touch on in a bit okay so let's
back up and talk about
uh how you build reference great genomes
well uh the best tools today are using
pacific biosciences tools um there's
also some oxford nanopore material
working out there
uh we're not fond of it at the moment
because of its error rate and
the cannabis genome being so repetitive
makes it really expensive and
challenging to assemble genomes with
zero rate there are attempts to try and
polish that aerate with the luminaire we
have found that to be somewhat faulty
uh just due to the fact that you really
can't error correct ont data
in regions that aren't mappable with
aluminum you get too much
too many reads that pile up in that
region and you don't really know where
they came from and so your error
correction is really a mirage
so we stick with the highest quality
long reads we can get and that's with
pac bio
so here's the dash funded female genome
this was then crossed with a male
this offspring was actually selected i'm
sorry it was a female
this offspring was selected because it
was a runt we were interested in
genes or deletions that might impact
yield and so we selected
one of the offspring that looked like it
was having trouble growing
and turned out to be a real stubborn run
with hyper hyper branching and whatnot
okay so we did we did tons of sequencing
for those who don't know this is like
200x coverage of one of these genomes
this is 150x coverage of these genomes
right we absolutely
hammered these things with more sequence
coverage than you would ever need
for a couple reasons one we didn't
really know how big the genome was going
to be
most other genome projects to date were
still below the one megabase and 50
number which meant they were broken and
not quite mature
most of the dna assembling people out
there in the world want to see one
megabase or greater and 50s to call it
in the megabase club and we're pushing
up to three and beyond
you'll see some later data pushing up to
five and eight
now this is really the most important
metric is
how long these contigs are
how deep they've been covered and with
what accuracy you have in the raw data
because
this is the information you're going to
look for single nucleotide changes in
that are going to make an impact on
protein function and make an impact on
evolution
we measure almost all of the selective
pressure by looking at these these
changes in snips
and you want those to be extraordinarily
accurate and the longer this gets
and the better these busco scores get
that's a sign that you're coming to
completion on the genome and that you're
doing it with
um with the largest number of
the most contiguous genome that you put
together now there are some other
genomes out there
that have 750 kb and 50 and they've
tried to
glue some of those contigs in order and
orient them
into a scaffold by using some linkage
information and breeding and that's an
interesting approach
the only challenge is the linkage
information that people are
are utilizing is coming from the
illumina sequencer which has really
short reads and the reads don't always
map very effectively
and so there is some confusion over what
the chromosome names are right now
in ncbi and we're hoping we'll be able
to address that with some of the data we
have here
okay so in addition to doing that trio
with pac-bio we then busted out an
aluminum sequencer
and and sequenced another 40 genomes and
in that 40 genomes was the rest of the
family
okay so uh one of these jail number five
which turned out to be the runt of all
these
uh was sequenced with back bio the rest
of these well it was and also got
resequenced with aluminum
now what you're looking at here we've
described in our canopy tutorial this is
the sequence coverage
over certain genes in the genome type
two plants have coverage across
all of them type three only have
coverage over cbd synthase
we don't have any type ones in here we
have mostly type twos and type threes
okay type ones would have only coverage
over thcs and phase
all right we also did an outcross um so
we've got some sequencing information on
on not just sequencing a cross between
an inbred pair but we also outbred it to
blueberry cheesecake
and we have some of the offspring of
those as well so
an interesting tree okay so now if you
look at the 40 genomes we sequenced and
you take those alumina reads and you map
them against the maternal reference here
you can see the number of snips that
we're seeing
compared to the jamaican line reference
so we're getting you can see the number
of snips up here is in the in the 12 to
14 000 range this axis of the insertions
and deletions they're highly concordant
with the actual
single nucleotide changes and you'll
notice all these type ones are you know
about
10 12 maybe 16 million steps apart
uh but when you get into the jamaican
lion family it tends to dip
and that's because these are all closely
related so of course they have more
similar genomes to their parents than
they do to anything else and so these
map that have really really
um producing very few snips
all in all we ended up with about 58
million variants in here
these are all mapped with dragon and
paragraph parabricks two different tools
for doing
hardware acceleration for sequencing
mapping um
and we kept these all down below five
cycles of pcr
with uh as we mentioned before so when
you have those pcr cycles done
at a really low number of cycles you can
count on the coverage information in the
sequencing to give you patterns
of of deletions and insertions what we
call copy number variations or c and v's
and what you're looking at here is a
collection of all the cannabinoid
synthase genes
i'm not going to say all but the ones
that we've curated to believe matter
and and of course these are all the ones
we found in the reference the jamaican
lion reference okay if you do another
reference like cbd or x or
purple kush they might have other
cannabinoid synthesis genes we don't
have right i mean just take a look at
this map you'd be a fool not to think
that because even looking at
this through the lens of jamaican lion
all these blue areas
are lines cannabis varietals that have
deletions in certain core genes that are
certain cannabinoid synthase genes so
all this blue space you see is just
gone cannabinoid synthase genes that
aren't in those genomes the red ones
have two copies and the the purple stuff
are haploid there they have like a
single copy okay so their mother genome
might have the deletion there but their
father genome has it
so you can see there's a tremendous
amount of copy number change here over
these genes and so we'd be a little bit
naive to think that if we surveyed other
cannabis genomes
that there might not be a longer set of
these genes
that the jamaican lion genome is
actually missing a few that we don't
know about all right
this is the reason why we believe it's
important to do a pan genome because
when you view all these genomes through
a single lens of jamaican lion
you're only going to see all the genes
that are in jamaican lion
in in the other genomes but you're not
going to see the gene content that is
novel to the other genomes that jamaican
lion doesn't have
okay and that's a very big number is
what we're anticipating and
and uh we'll show you that in a slide or
two forward when we look at structural
variations which are a similar form
of variation um okay on the right hand
side
are 82 different genes involved in
pathogen response
these are kitinases thomatine like
proteins or tlps your heroes
call them for short and then mlo which
is a mildew
loci that's been tracked down in hops
why did we pick these well these are
just genes in the literature that we um
families of genes and literature that we
know have been tied to powdery mildew
resistance in hops
and we did have some powdery mildew
resistance information from a couple of
the growers
the green lines down here are powdery
mildew resistant and the pink ones
aren't
and of course what do you see as uh in
the heat map like this you get a little
bit of a correlation
that all the samples over here seem to
have a pattern that's different than the
ones that were here
and maybe that is what is driving
powdery mildew resistance in these
so um it's a whim uh it could be that
all of these samples are jamaican lion
not all of them but a lot of them are
and that they just happen to have a
shared ancestry
and that this pattern of different tlps
and mlos
is just an artifact of their ancestry
and has nothing to do with resistance
well
what was really interesting to us is
that a few of these samples that
proven to be extraordinary powdery
milder resistant and aren't related to
jamaican lion
have a copy number amplification on some
kitinases
and likewise there is a thomatine-like
protein
that has been amplified in these as well
and i can't see this very clearly here
but we'll show you which one that is
going forward
but we took a couple of these genes that
were amplified
and seem to have have the most extreme
copy number
changes and clone them and the way you
do this is you've run a pca analysis i
don't have the pca in here but if you
run a pca analysis on this
the genes that stick out as having the
most signature in the pca analysis
are what we chose to clone and and to
express um now you also want to look
upstream
right so the cannabinoid precursor genes
are probably playing a role role in the
magnitude of cannabinoids they they're
not going to dictate whether you make ch
cbd or thc but that might dictate how
much you make
and there have been previous copy number
amplifications that have been described
by
john page on aea1 and we might have some
of that here in this
in this if i read this correctly and
there's a couple other ones that have
deletions
so we're keeping your eye on some of the
precursors that may be involved in um
uh in modulating the amount of
cannabinoids and the other thing we're
looking at
are the the trichome by refringement
genes which um
may be playing a role in trichome
develop in shape or size but we don't
know we're just kind of looking for
a lot of consistency in here in this
part but then you get down here and some
of these genes look like they might be
differentially
modulated um or have different copy
number and maybe playing a role in
trichomes
um so there's there's just a really rich
set of information here
and we by no means that we thoroughly
mind this data set we've put it public
because we think having millions of eyes
look at this is going to be more
productive than having it rust between
our own servers
um so um that being said we did we did
comb through the rna
data um to try and hunt down what
which of these genes should be cloned i
mentioned before we did a pca analysis
that
that populated a couple candidates after
we had those candidate genes we asked
the same question as well are those same
candidate genes that the pca pulled out
from a copy number standpoint in the
genome
do they also have a lot of rna being
expressed so these are the cannabinoid
synthase genes
these are the different tissues and you
can see that we do have
we have some expression but it is pretty
much zeroed in
on having expression that is uh
tissue specific for only a couple of the
genes in fact the can have a chromie
gene seem to only be expressed at least
in this jamaican lion plant and in the
males
that may not be true in other plants
i've heard of cannabi chromium getting
expressed in female flowers but it's
just not the case with jamaican wine
at least the time point we we harvest
the these uh this rna
you look down here at the actual
kitenases the tlos
are the tops and the mlos and you see
much different picture
a handful of genes here that just don't
care they're not on at all but you get
down here and there are some heavily
expressed genes in fact the most heavily
differentially expressed gene in the
genome are the kitinases
that was a red flag to us in fact
they're not expressed in the roots at
all
and we think that's because the roots
want to communicate with the rhizal
with the mycorrhizal and the fungi
environment in
underneath the soil it doesn't want to
use kitinases
that destroy microbes that could be
doing nitrogen fixation for it however
everywhere else on the plant it's
expressing chitinases galore
and we just confirmed some of this rna
sequencing information with some of the
methylation information
to zero in on which one of these kinases
we're going to clone and this is the one
that got cloned and is sitting on place
with fusarium as we speak
there's some methylation patterns in
here that we were
combing over this is what they look like
actually when you bring them up in an
igv read viewer or genome browsers you
see all of these
blue regions and these red regions that
are being silenced
okay so now that we have these enzymes
uh these targets the genome what do you
do you take that gene
you cloned it into a coli and you
express it
and you get the coli to make lots of
this protein and then
if you're smart about this you put a
little his tag on the end of the protein
this is
four histidines which happens to bind to
nickel very readily so when you're done
making this protein
you can bind it to a nickel column rinse
it off and hopefully still have active
peptide
when you come off this this process
doesn't always work perfectly because
the tag sometimes alters the protein
sometimes
the e coli glycosylates the protein
differently than you'd expect
in the plant sometimes it doesn't fold
correctly in the plant so it's a bit of
a gamble
and we got quite lucky on this gamble
after we
got this cloned and expressed we took
the protein and started putting it
through
beta-glucanase assays these are assays
that that have a fluorescently labeled
insoluble beta-glucan molecule that
after it's digested
it's soluble so you can monitor the
digesting capacity
of a thomatine like protein by putting
it through this assay
for a set period of time you put a
little bit of enzyme in there and if
it's good at doing its job it will chew
up that insoluble glucan that's
that's fluorescently labeled and the the
fluorescent molecules that come off that
that digestion process
are now smaller sugar units and now
they're soluble so you can then spin
down the insoluble fraction and then
measure the absorption that's in the
supernatant and you get a measurement as
to how active your enzyme is well
we have some activity from the enzyme
that came out of beta glucan that's so
that's very exciting and we've been
comparing this tlp
enzyme to some other uh
chitinases and um i'm sorry kitinases
and some other
enzymes from a snail actually the snail
one is
uh is quite active um
you can see some of that repeated over
here we're playing around with
uh tlp that came out of the inclusion
bodies of e coli versus ones that are
cytoplasmic
versus a couple of the other of the
other blanks
and we want to see is that there's a
high signal here this is the um
the positive control is what happens if
it's perfect and you want the signal to
almost reach the positive control
all right so um we're getting the most
expression from tlp here and from here
this one went through dialysis to change
the buffer
but when you apply these on to plants
what you want to look for are now here
are the jamaican lime plants that have
the enzymes natively expressed and
they're not getting powdery mildew
despite having been placed it's in a
in a tent surrounded by this guy who has
it all over him and it doesn't seem to
transfer even if you take them and put
the put the
the leaves side by side we don't get a
transfer there are transfer protocols
described by dr punja
uh he has some protocols with certain
amount of humidity you put these and you
should get transfer from from one to the
other
now the other thing we do outside of
these assays is we grow
some of the endophytes from the plant on
actual petri dishes now we couldn't do
that with powdery mild
powdery mildew over here because powdery
mildew is not it's an obligate biotroph
there's no way to culture it other than
on a leaf so
um we are working on foliar sprays and
we do have some photographs of applying
this um to the plant and there does seem
to be some decay of the um
the powdery mildew when you put enzyme
on these i don't have those photographs
in this presentation
but they'll be posted they've been
posted online before um
but what you're looking for is you you
take this technique where you put these
tabs
of watman paper you have to sterilize
them of course right next to the colony
as it grows out
and right as the colony begins to touch
those tabs you start adding in
the amount of enzyme to see if if the
enzyme retards any growth
and here's the blank which is the
vehicle control that this enzyme's in
and it seems to not do much
20 micros microliters of tlp didn't seem
to do much on its own
you add in a little bit of two different
flavors of this enzyme
and you start to see it turn blue and
you put in a kitinase and a tlp here and
you can really see an impact here this
line of blue and the cheese
this is a type of penicillium that you
find in blue cheese and you can see it
starts to give you that cheese like look
where the blue is starting to change
color
uh and there's and there's an
indentation on his honest growth in
advance
well we did the same thing with fusarium
and aspergillus
and the aspergillus didn't seem to make
a big dent but we only did it with the
top we're trying to get more
kitenase so we do it with both and we'll
see if the the cannabis kitenase
actually
fights fights it back a little bit
better but with fusarium what you can
see
here is that in the high in the medium
side
of this experiment we're getting all
types of disruption of growth in fact
the pigment
is changing this this discoloration and
pigment has been published before when
you add
any type of miticide on here that or
mycocide that might actually
kill fungi the autofucerin expression
turns off in fusarium and so you lose
the pink pigment as you're starting to
kill it
so that's a great assay to show you that
the enzymes actually have some
functionality
so we think we've got a good model for
powdery mildew resistance in jamaica
line
we don't believe that we've nailed
powdery mildew resistance for
all cultivars because when you see this
many genes involved in pathogen response
there's probably
you know a dozen different ways to skin
the cat and there's probably convergent
evolution where we see
other plants have copy number
amplifications of other
proteins that we're not paying attention
to or
that just aren't necessarily amplified
in jamaican line and those may in fact
be another source of powder melody
resistance in other plants so
we can't claim that this is the powdery
miller powdery mildew resistance gene
for all of cannabis i don't think that
will be the case i think we're going to
find multiple different modes of
of resistance as we go forward
nevertheless we do have tools
that can help monitor this while you're
breeding to know whether your relative
number of
genes is going up or down in the process
of breeding you certainly don't want to
breed yourself into a corner
where you're missing some of these genes
now
i do want to go back to tell you why
that's important
this area here in the cannabinoid
synthase
map here where you see full-blown
deletions for a very large section of
the genome this is actually the cannabi
chromium
cluster okay there are eight cannabic
chromium genes in here
it's labeled as inactive thc synthase in
ncbi and that's because when they first
discovered this they noticed it didn't
make a whole lot of thc but
it's believed that it could leak some if
you take these genes
cbd thc and cbc and you clone them into
yeast and feed them precursor under
different conditions they will
promiscuously make multiple cannabinoids
each enzyme itself is not a pure
chemical reaction okay it has off-target
effects thc synthetics can make little
cbd synthase
cbd synthetics can make little thc
synthase and cdc
is believed to be able to make both the
others as well although it's less
documented
um so what else is carried along in this
deletion well this deletion
also carries on it's contag 756 down
here and you can see anything labeled
with contact 756 that's blue is in that
deletion and these genes
happen to be nip 1 tps1 pip 1
npf 1 rmt and spa
these genes are all involved in pathogen
response okay one of them is an
aquaporin receptor the other one is like
a gibberellin receptor all right this
this is stuff we can't like
uh these are important genes that are
really close to the cannabinoid
that can have a chromium cluster and you
can see the deletion
has a variable stop point for each one
of these cultivars
not all of them have the deletion
stopping at the same point
so there's some heterogeneity in
the three prime end of this deletion
that you might want to track because uh
it's very easy for you to breed for a
cannabi chromium deleted plant
if you want to lower some thc levels and
maybe your type 3 plants
you just search for one that doesn't
have this and cross it and if it's a
type 3 plant
and you crossed across you'll be okay
you'll notice a lot of type 3 plants in
here actually have the cbc so a really
easy thing to do is maybe cross it with
some type twos
that don't and see if you can lower your
thc levels
notice a lot of type ones have it as
well not all of them but a lot
some of them have at least half but
these guys have a have two copies of
canva chromium synthase or kind of train
wreck and i think the other one is
citrix
or black 84. um so there
we see them more in uh in the hemp lines
than
in necessarily the thc lines but these
full-blown deletions
are homozygous solutions are really a
sight to see
this is another reason why naming the
actual chromosomes is going to get
delayed because
a two megabase deletion of this size
would confuse you as to whether you were
chromosome 5 or chromosome 6. the
chromosomes are usually numbered by
by size okay
if one of your chromosomes happens to
have a two megabase solution well it's
going to confuse you as to whether it's
chromosome similar size okay so pathogen
response
in cannabinoids these are important gene
copy number events to monitor in your
plants i'd recommend you sequence your
parent lines so you know you have and
then
um you can probably aluminum sequence uh
and even maybe do panel sequencing or
snip chips
on the offspring to lower costs but you
probably want your parents
done whole genome scale so you know what
you're dealing with and you know what
what cards you've been dealt
okay now let's get on to the real hairy
part of the presentation
so um one thing you can do with these
very long reads
is you can begin to ask between the trio
how many structural variations do i have
how many times do i have a long read
from the sibling or from the offspring
that
looked like looks like it's got a large
deletion or a large insertion in it
these are called
structural variants now structural
variants sometimes can also be
a little bit different than a copy
number variant although a copy number
variant is a subclass of a structural
variation copy number events tend to
increase or decrease the copy number of
the dna
there are such things as balanced
translocations and
and inversions in the genome where you
you know two chromosome tips swap
copy hasn't changed but their structure
has
you know same thing is true with a
balanced deletion or an inversion where
something just flips on you copy number
hasn't changed but it's order and
orientation
the genome has okay those tend to
structural variants are a larger class
where c and v's are just a subset of
them
all right
so when we do this we see 17 000
it's a heterozygous deletions and 9 000
homozygous deletions
in the male flower and and the offspring
has even more
um so this is actually a tremendous
amount of
variation that we're seeing uh in fact
it looks to be like it's over an eighth
of the genome and includes some bosco
genes
all right so if there is this much
structural variation going on an inbred
trio
now granted i think this might be an
extreme case even though it's an inbred
trio i think the selection of the runt
has caused some of this that this thing
was probably an unstable genome
and so we have a really high structural
variation map right now
but um it's quite surprising that it can
happen in just a matter of 12 seeds one
of them is a runt and we have all the
structural variation that's that's quite
remarkable
likewise all of the illumina data on the
other 40 genomes supports lots of copy
number variation so it kind of implies
this isn't really unique to our
situation here
that there is in fact a lot of genome
plasticity in cannabis
uh to give you some perspective the
human genomes have like seven events per
megabase
in sv and uh they have maybe a similar
number of events but they tend to be
much smaller they're only one percent of
the genome
all right we're upwards to twelve
percent of the genome so this is a much
harder problem in cannabis than human
now um so that makes you think how can
you pick a single reference well you
really can't
but if you're forced to pick a single
reference there are some criteria that
you should think about
in picking them um at the moment if you
go to ncbi it will probably graduate
anyone who's dared call chromosomes and
cannabis and a couple people have tried
and as a result the three genomes that
are in there and none of them agree on
the chromosome nomenclature all right
and i'm not surprised that's because i
think there's still some chromosome
misassemblies that are going on but
there's also probably lots of structural
variation between the biological samples
that make these things
very difficult to discern one chromosome
from the other so
eventually we'll be no getting the
nomenclature right in these based on
what genes or what tend to be in which
chromosomes and probably not stick
get get so hung up on the size but at
the moment
we've got a bit of a chromosome mess
going on in there
now in light of that the chromosome
scaffolding information doesn't really
hold a lot of quality information when
you take contigs and you link them
together with linkage maps you don't
have a real quality score
on what is that scaffold made of it's
just an association that we think this
content is next to this one
but you can't put a probability on it
right whereas the
the sequencing information itself you
have quality scores at every single base
that you can put a probability of
correctness on so that's the underlying
data that's most important and you want
to make sure that that data is the most
contiguous as possible
you can easily play some shell games in
sequencing where you report
really large scaffolding and 50s but
they're based on chromosome or on
contents that are extremely small and
those tend to be very poor
poorly constructed genomes okay the
other thing you want to look at are the
bosco scores you want to make sure those
are as high as possible you also want to
look at how much depth of coverage the
genomes has and
as we've shown you um we we tend to have
much higher coverage than anyone who's
ever made a stab at this before
100 to 200x coverage is not
traditionally getting done
so there is uh there's far more raw
sequence data
on um on jamaican line than there is on
anything else that's in there
okay we also have some some high c data
that we can use to call chromosomes
however when we've done that we've just
realized that our chromosomes disagree
with theirs as well and so
we've got the problem of the fourth
watchmen where we're not adding any more
um we're not adding any more contiguity
necessary to the equation we're just
adding more confusion so we've opted not
to put that data public until we get it
done on a couple different technologies
so that we can really confidently call
what the chromosomes are in
in jamaican line and they still might be
different than what we find in the other
lines just due to biological diversity
but nevertheless um we don't want to add
to the chromosome confusion at the
moment
so okay what are the other things that
are key to making a gold standard
reference well
you want to get both a male and a female
genome
um sequenced because we just showed you
the male chrome
the y chromosomes the largest
chromosomes you gotta have a why in your
reference all right
the other thing you want to do is get a
trio because you need to to train your
genotypers right now
the genotyping software out there has
all been written for human which is
expecting a variant every thousand bases
and we happen to have a variance every
50 bases in cannabis
and those genotyping tools all need to
be retrained and the way that you
retrain them
is to sequence a mother father and an
offspring what's known as a trio
so that you can segregate sequencing
errors and confirm
whether or not they exist in the parents
if a sequencing error is found in one
line and doesn't exist in the parents
it doesn't pass a mendel check that
makes no biological sense you
flag it as an error and now you can
count your errors
versus all the genotypes that you have
that have mendelian concordance between
the parents
this mental check thing is very
important for for gauging genotyping
accuracy and it's only been done to date
on jamaican line
okay the other thing you want is a type
2 plant something has both thc and cbd
genes in this you don't you do not want
a type 3 plant as a reference because if
you sequence
a genome for a client and you map it to
a reference that doesn't have thc
synthase
and you fail to detect that their plant
could potentially make thc synthase
then the criminal negligence charges
that the usda might throw out the grower
are going to roll uphill to you
so no sequence provider chip
manufacturer
or or or tool provider
in the space wants to touch a reference
that doesn't have thc synthesis in it
because they have to be able to detect
whether the reference has that that's
probably the number one thing in
cannabis you've got to detect given
there's criminal negligence for 0.5
thc or higher got fthc as i mentioned
before you want the longest reads the
most recent chemistry
the deepest coverage and we've got that
with sql 2 and with hi-fi data we're the
only one who's done a cannabis genome on
hifi data the data is already public
free use it you also want to get your
rna
annotation from the same genome that you
assembled many of the other genomes out
there are taking
rna sequencing from other plants and
applying it to theirs to call the genes
that's noisier you get all the different
you get different snips involved you get
different structural variations involved
and
it's harder to do gene annotation with
the different organisms
uh or different plants rna it's really
much better to get it from the
the plant that you sequence the genome
from and we have that with jamaican lion
we've got methylation information and on
top of that
more cannabis data is mapped to jamaica
line than any other cultivar there are
47 whole genome shotguns now in the koji
genome browser with bam files
that's after mapping so you don't have
to remap the data and we've also loaded
over 50 strain seeks in there and
there's another 300 on their way
so this has two genomes that are
certified in koji the male
and the father are the i'm sorry the
mother and the father
um and the offspring's up there as well
so there's a trio up there
in in koji for you to work with okay now
let's go beyond this let's actually take
this to
doing better assemblies um so since we
put all this data out this is stepping
into stuff that we haven't completely
published yet
although the data is public for you to
use it's not been put into paper yet
um this is what's known as a can
assemblathon um something happened uh
this year
that was a bit of a paradigm shift in
dna sequencing
all right pac bio finally got the read
lengths out to 180 kb
which meant that they could lap a 20kb
molecule nine times
and in doing so they can get q30 data on
20 kb molecules
no one's ever had that before and that
completely changes the way that you
write dna assemblers and so all the
leading dna assembly people in the world
realized this and immediately rewrote
their assemblers
three new assemblers came out this year
we have something called hi asm from
henley at the broad
he's one of the more prominent um
software
authors for a lot of the stuff in the
field he wrote a bwa in a variety of
great tools
um sergey korin wrote canoe which is one
of the more popular dna assemblers out
there he rewrote that specifically to
handle pak bio's new data form because
he was so excited about it
great conception at um pac bio has also
um re-rigged the falcon assembler to
better handle this data and jason chen
who was a former author of the falcon
assembler
rewrote an algorithm altogether called
the peregrine assembler that takes a
completely different assembly approach
knowing it has accurate data and you're
going to see some of that it's quite
remarkable
so what you're seeing here is just
different stringencies applied
in the assembly to try to phase the
genome you can start to peel
the mother and when you do a assembly
like this all of the reeds from your
genome get assembled and your mother and
father
reads sometimes for the same chromosome
gets stuck together they get collapsed
and the job at the end of assembly is to
phase those or split them apart into
mother and father
lines and that can be challenging if the
mother and the father genome are so
similar that they don't there's no
differences upon which to split them
or or if they're hyper polymorphic they
easily separate into two unique pieces
of sequence all right
so in order to do this you set different
stringencies of
uh of of this is called the minimum
percent identity
uh to actually purge and split these
happel takes and this is just greg doing
eight different or what was it one two
three four
five six seven eight nine nine different
assemblies on falcon
uh there's a ton of compute power put
into this slide um to give us
um different types of assemblies you can
see some of the ones like the 99.9
purged are giving us six mega 50s and
you can measure the amount of duplicated
genes that you see
in the busco um score to get us a sense
of how well you're purging a lot of
these jeans
and how well you're splitting the
assembly um but anyway
uh this was all done on what is known as
hifi this is the latest chemistry from
pac bio we got early access to it and
they uh did a single flow cell and got
400 giga sequence out of a single flow
cell 180 kb and 50 reads and we gave it
20 kb
molecules so we got 30 gig of ccs data
this is about 30 x coverage across the
genome
now what's different about this now that
you have really accurate reads
you can play some games you don't have
to do an n squared assembly where you
map every single read against every
other read you can do something that's
known as
a paired shimmering approach which i'll
leave you to go to jason chin's
work on the paraben assemblies to how
this thing works but because this
algorithm scales not n squared but n
times the coverage squared
you can actually pull this off in a home
computer so i was able to assemble this
genome
on my home computer in seven hours i've
never been able to assemble
a cannabis genome on a home computer
he pulled it off in much in much less
time he's got a better computer than i
do
um here's here's an example
30 gig going in um this is hi-fi data
again
this is the most recent pac bio data
offer sql 2.
he assembles this in uh in 71 minutes
ends up with a record-breaking uh four
megabase and
n50 it's the best one we've ever seen to
date
um and he tunes it a little bit further
and pushes it out to eight megabase with
busco scores over 97 percent
71 minute assembly all right this is a
remarkable time to assemble
normally these things take a week or two
on a 500 cpu cluster with a terabase of
ram
all right this is a hundred to a
thousand fold faster
than what we're doing right now and from
a cpu standpoint
i think it's actually a thousand times
faster from a cpu standpoint because the
the um the high canoe assembly took four
thousand cpu hours
and this one was i'm sorry it's a
hundred fold it's 100 faster but it
being 100
faster means we can actually de novo
assemble these genomes
faster than we can map 200 million reads
to them this so this changes the way
you think about genomics if the if the
assembly of a cannabis genome is now
computationally more effective with pac
bio then mapping 200 million short reads
to the genome
you start to switch plants you scent you
basically do de novo assembly in your
parents so you don't have to worry about
structural variants you can get all
those nailed and then you can aluminum
map to your references you make your own
personal references for your parents
we can help you do that um and that way
um you're not playing a guessing game
with what genes are there and what genes
aren't there
okay well the other thing that popped
out of this was the cbd and thc in one
conjugate that's never happened before
that's kind of cool
um you can see them scat this is the dot
plot so this is the repeat pattern
that's around these genes and it's
absolutely remarkable it's like this
crazy fractal
um that you see and um in fact
here's another view of it oh uh here's
another view of it you've got
all of this different uh repetitive
material right as you come through this
um
region there's five copies and one
contig and four in the other
um so totally phased across many many
megabases we've got them
both uh together now we know their
distance um
that's pretty cool that's never happened
before um
now that being said like i mentioned
before
um you probably don't know who these
artists are if you're not of a certain
age but this here is millie vanilli uh
who are busted for lip syncing and
that's kind of what read mapping
is and we've tolerated it in genomics
because it was so affordable and cheap
but now the price of long reads are
coming down and you can get large reads
you really should just move on and do de
novo when you can
at least on your parents all right so
i'm gonna be like this guy who
from the looks of his eyes is probably
into cannabis um
but this is the math here on the
assembly time
uh since you have 20 kb reads you only
need 1.5 million of them
and since you have more accurate data
you really only need like 50 next
coverage but we did 30.
um this ends up being a
much much smaller number uh than taking
200 million reads
uh and having to deal with 60-ish
coverage any more coverage for the
shorter reads
uh you end up having to deal with a lot
more computation this way so
fewer reads to map and the fact that
we're not doing an n squared algorithm
here if this were n squared it'd be it'd
be 200 million times 200 million that's
a lot of computation
or 1.5 million times 1.5 million still a
lot of computation
it's really only the square of the
coverage that we're dealing with which
is a much much smaller number
when you use this peregrine approach
it's still early with peregrine
and we're testing it out the other thing
one of the other assemblers that sergey
korn updated was called
high canoe high canoe is uh
one of the more popular assemblers now
and the remarkable thing about haikai
canoe is it pumped out a 5.2 megabase
assembly in this assemblathon and a 97.4
percent busca score which is
remarkable but the thing that gives us
the most faith that this is probably the
best genome ever assembled for cannabis
is that the telomeres are perfectly
resolved telomeres are the end of
chromosomes that have like the same
sequence for very long stretches in fact
you can see this repeating pattern down
here
and it goes on for one half kb here 3 kb
4 kb 5 kb 7 kb
and it doesn't end it ramps all the way
out to 26 kb
43 kv i mean i've never seen a 43 kb
repeat before in my life because
sequencers just couldn't read them it's
really remarkable
and the fact that we have 17 of these
now means that in the first attempt the
genome
sent out a pro we should have gotten
about 20 chromosome telomeres
the fact that three of them are
collapsed is going to be probably pretty
easy for us to resolve what you'll see
is there are subtle differences
in these telomeres and what they link to
is different
so you can get a 20kb read coming in
here
that bridges out here and has one or two
snips in the telomere and you can link
another high quality read to it and
extend it and this is how we're getting
out to some of these 43kb telomeres
um now why am i so excited about
telomeres there's not a lot of
biological information in there i mean
the molecular clock is probably in there
your clones are probably getting shorter
and shorter telomeres as you age
but the reason why we're so excited
about seeing telomeres is that when you
get
perfect telomere assemblies it's usually
a sign that the repeats internal to your
genome
are all resolved perfectly as well
because they're more divergent than
telomeres telomeres are a simple
sequence repeat that goes on for a long
period of time they're very difficult to
start
they usually are assembly knots in fact
when we look at a lot of the genomes in
ncbi right now they're
they don't have telomeres you do see
some internal telomeric sequences
which makes you think some of the some
of the chromosomes might actually be
inappropriately fused together
so you get a telomere sequence in the
middle you can find that that's also
naturally found in plants so you don't
really know what to do with that
information but
uh when you have assemblies that pop out
beautiful telomeres like this you have
much more confidence the rest of the
genome has its repeats in order as well
all right now what do you do with all
this information well what we've been
doing with this information is designing
really good
qpcrs to pick up yeast and mold and many
people skip this step they don't bother
sequencing the host genome and this is
the pain they have
here's a group that made a microarray
system where they put all these primers
in the microarray and everything in
yellow hits cannabis
so they didn't bother they didn't bother
to scan cannabis references as to
whether or not the primers
were going to hybridize to it imager
calibration
negative control hits it all right
aspergillus flavius
niger these things have some homology
now it's not the whole pro but it's long
enough
of a sequence of the probe to probably
interfere a little bit
some other pcr primers that amplify the
material have these problems too
they filed six patents in 2018 on this
they since told us that they no longer
use these primers so
they spent more money on attorneys
making bogus patents than they could
have spent on sequencing the genome
likewise you can look at another set of
primers that came out of
a group in europe and this group is
pivoting also into the space in the food
industry where they've never had to
worry about a cannabis background and
are just kind of arrogantly plowing in
assuming they don't have problems and lo
and behold you sequence some of the
amplicons that come off of their total
yeast and mold primers
and what do you hit you hit cannabis 28
is ribosomal dna well that's not going
to work
that means there are cannabis plants out
there that your primers amplify and
you're always going to be failing
someone for some level of yeast and mold
these are also polymorphic so they may
get amplification on some
cannabis and not other strains so you
might get some strains that just look
like
it works on and you get you always get
mold on and other ones you don't and you
blame it on the plant as always having
mold and really you just have some snips
in your in your 28s and 26s
ribosomal regions and it appears as if
the plant always has mold when it
doesn't
the other thing you shouldn't hit with
yeast and mold primers are insects this
insect in particular is a spider mite
so if your primers had spider mites
you're going to fail a lot of stuff that
doesn't have mold that you think has
mold because it's hitting spider mites
spider mites are gross i don't want my
canvas either but your test should be
accurate it shouldn't hit stuff if it
hits
insects god knows what else it hits
right it's going to fail
for a lot other material that's not on
the fail list
now with this we can also go through
canopedia i already have some videos on
canopedia
so i'm going to plow through this
because you can review some of the
canopy
information in the kanapedia tutorial
but i do want to
point out this promiscuous dna or
or thc synthase thing that's going on
here here's a type four plant
um thc cbd knockout still has thc
still has thca still has cannabi
chromine
we don't have the sequence of this plant
but i wouldn't be surprised if this has
a
chromium cluster and might be leaking it
doesn't have a cbd gene so this thc is
not coming from cbd synthase
none detected all right so that's why
you want to be paying attention to what
types of genes you have in your genome
and also read this paper zerbel's great
paper where they clone these genes and
they demonstrate they can make different
cannabinoids under different conditions
and they actually chart out all the
different point mutations in the gene
that starts to change these ratios
we track those in those types of
variants in in canopy
and this is what you want to look for
this is a variation map across thc
synthase
and here's one across cbd synthase um
never mind this this is an
error that the thing burped up in
annotation it doesn't actually have x
introns and cbd synthase but
nevertheless these are all the different
snips that we found and those snips you
want to do is correlate them with the
ones that they found as causing
a decrease in function and that may help
your breeding program
now our current strain seek panel does
in fact hit
cbd synthase i'm sorry cbc synthase it
also hits
cbd and thc synthase this is 323
different strains examples
this is the sequencing coverage across
them you can see a crater is down here
on the samples that are cannabic
chromium negative and if you pull some
of these out of canopedia you'll see
they don't make any cannabi chromium
down here they're cannabinoid chromium
negative plants
um that's a good sign that means that
cbd synthase which it is making isn't
making off target can have a chromium
not that it would matter but um you know
it's just nice to know that that
there's some specificity there in one
direction um
anyway we use this to track uh people so
you don't have to sequence an entire
genome to get to this answer we can help
you breed the cannabinoids with
just a panel um it's a little bit
cheaper that way but um
contact us if you're interested in there
if you do get your data sequence with us
there's a wealth of data you can compare
to we have four terabases of sequence in
a public genome browser that you can
load your data in and view it and
annotate it privately
against the backdrop of all that public
data and it's great information like
this in here this is actually
what you're looking at are the different
exons that you're seeing there in pink
with the lines connecting them and so
you can actually look at alternative
splice signals that you have
they're not really any present here
maybe that one um but
uh you can see the different rna that's
getting expressed in different regions
of the genome
and uh gives you information on on how
much you actually have per tissue which
is kind of informative
and you can make other um tools we do
have a 16 snip panel
that you can use to do seed to cell
tracking with it gives you enough
certificate enough
enough information um that you can pin
down a strain in a gross ballpark and
this actually feeds right into canopedia
because we have
6 500 snips in there across all the
strains that we aggressively monitor and
these 16
key into that so that we can plug into
canopedia from here
and we can also read the btbd allele and
the xy marker off that assay
we're building virus assays we're
playing around with some other
expression assays as well
but all of this is predicated on having
a really good reference
on top to top that off uh we do have
five
color aspergillus assays now so nigeria
terious flavors and fumigatus are all
done in different wavelengths in one
single tube with a fifth
color for the cannabis control there's
more enzyme the kids are more sensitive
than before
and we have them worked working out um
with uh some of these can work out with
a live debt essay you just have to be
careful what channel you put the control
for the live debt assay in
but anyway this is uh this is a new kit
that's out that greatly simplifies
aspergillus testing in the field and we
know our primers don't have
hit all these other extraneous places in
the genome because we've got more genome
sequence than anybody else we know how
to make primers as a result of that
and that means you can make primers that
do this this is a beautiful site to see
you take your primers apply them against
all these different organisms and
demonstrate that they do not hit off
target
that is really key so our aspergillus
all four of our assays have been
screened against all of these organisms
this is part of an aoec
inclusion and exclusion criteria and
we're in an aoec process of validating
this now
all these people help pull this off
takes a village um it is really an honor
to work with a lot of them
um they have been they've been just
tremendous aids and
and uh get it it's just diverse it's
diversity in terms of the the expertise
you have here
experts in gpus with people who know
about methylation enzymes and single
molecule sequencing and even some block
chains that really leads to a
kind of a fun day at work every day so
um and then these people
directly have been contributing to
various aspects of the project um
a lot of folks here missile genomics
have put in long hours making all this
stuff work
uh with that crazy grant structure we
had and um
and dash has been uh you know a great
partner in funding all this
uh and then all these folks as well who
have chipped in over the years so
thank you and hopefully that is within
time