[Music]
I think most cannabis consumers by now
are familiar with turpins and sort of
the role that they play in uh the
experience the smells and you know even
the actual experience of consuming but
as you point out in the paper that tpin
are only telling a a small portion of
the overall story and that sort of some
of these attempts to classify cultivars
by their top Tarpin um weren't really
working so speak a little bit to that
yeah so I mean if you look within the
study we we were trying to measure a
broad variety of exotic cannabis
cultivars everything from as sweet and
fruity as possible get something that is
dark berry something has tropical notes
something that has weird Citrus notes
like Tangi but also prototypical
and you can look at some of the Exotics
and some may be tropical and others may
be dark berry and they have a lot of
either lemon or one of these major three
turpins but they don't smell the same
and when you go to the Savory front like
GMO and other Savory Exotics they also
have similar top turpins but their
overall Aromas aren't anything close now
that doesn't mean that the the tpin
don't impart any flavoring r at all in
it wasn't part of the research
publication itself but we did some
studies in our lab just to see well what
would happen if we stripped all the
turpins out and did just everything else
right what's this going to smell and
taste like pretty weird um straight up
it didn't didn't smell and taste like
cannabis was unbalanced it had a very
weird non-descript experience that was
just very just unpleasant it's not until
you have everything there that it has
all the balance of what the plant
intended right you have all the
everything basically in Sy and working
just harmoniously together to give it
this full experience because if you
strip out that core base of what makes
cannabis unique and even though it's
like even though lemoning may not
correlate to Exotic specific nature it
doesn't mean it has no impact to the the
flavor and Aroma of cannabis that we all
know and appreciate um and so having it
all there is super important but it's
not the defining features of what makes
exotic it's a it's required to give it
that full experience but it doesn't help
to find that exotic note a lot of that
coming from those Esters these other new
compounds we discovered in this specific
study right so it's almost like music
where you know maybe your terapin are
your drum kit and your guitar and your
bass guitar but it's really sort of the
you know synthesizers or the other sort
of instruments that you're layering in
on top of that that makes it sort of a
unique musical composition 100 per. it's
it's exactly how we started to explain
to a lot of the customers and our sales
team we've been working with when we try
and bring this complex chemistry and
bring it to it layers down the way to
explain it is just like that right if
you have a symphony and you strip out
your string quartets your strings or
your brass you're still G to have music
but is it the same no right it maybe not
like tping they are absolutely needed
but they're not that the most only thing
representative of all Roma right that
would be that's where again the study
came in to show that hey Turin yes they
have importance and value but there's
more we haven't been considering as an
industry that play a significant role
that we should start looking
[Music]
at
a