[Music]
um so why do you think that you know
they haven't been studied as a
therapeutic uh really to this
point well they have somewhat and there
are a lot of papers out there I don't
want to short anyone right or kind of be
insulting there are a lot of papers out
there um but they were still limited
right so it's like we're going to take a
A turpine or tpine extract we're going
to give a certain amount to patients and
then we see the pain relief but for
whatever reason I don't fully understand
why those next steps weren't taken like
what are the side effects what's the
what's the pharmacokinetics you know
what's the minimal dose that we need to
be effective um you know and really like
formalize and systematize this
investigation so you could really turn
it into something um I'm just
spitballing here I don't have any
evidence for that but like one of the
reasons could be because it's generally
regarded as safe maybe you can't get a
drug company interested in making a
product because you know you can't they
can't patent it um and that's where I've
been work all the companies that I've
been working with in this space are all
smaller companies right that that care
about cannabis that care about turpins
they're not looking to be fizer maybe
that's why they're the ones that are
willing to tackle it and maybe that's
why they haven't been tackled in the
past with some of the larger the larger
you know groups and it could also be the
possibility that funding has been harder
to come by I don't really know no so we
were able to get funding from this work
from a portion of the National
Institutes of Health the N uh called the
national Center for compliment and
Integrative Health the
ncci so kind of a sub subpart of the ni
and they had this program where they
were specifically interested in looking
at Turpin and minor cannaboids and so I
will say that just in general the
Cannabis field cannaboid field has grown
a lot recently you know the last 10 10
or so years all of that has grown
funding's become more available people
are becoming more interested and then
some of these minor components or or
understudied components of the cannabis
plant like tur beans and the minor
canabo those have also been growing very
strongly as well with that interest so
maybe the time is just here
[Music]