[Music]
why Aromas are so important to cannabis
and why they're important to you and
your team at
abstracts yeah so cannabis Aroma is
really I mean they're really responsible
for driving that consumer experience so
when consumers are purchasing whether
that be concentrates vape pens flower
pre-rolls um they may be buying these
based on how they like how it smells and
tastes right and to understand more
about why it smells the way it does and
tastes the way it does we want to
understand more about the chemistry
behind these Aromas and the
understanding this research is really
important to us as a company because we
have an extraction facility um obviously
we create flavor and turfing blends for
various customers but also just really
were curious to see like why does I mean
we understand why OG smell skunky and
gassy but why now do GMOs smell garlicky
and savory why do Zid and runts and all
the other Exotics tangies smell fruity
tropical gassy oranges like where are
all these smells and Ras coming from and
can we start correlating the chemistry
to the human sensory aspect because and
as a company when we start we working on
this for about two three years now um
before he published it but really was
around like I think November 2022 we
started seeing regulatories um agencies
come out with new regulations stating
that cannabis was not fruity or sweet or
um Savory right we've seen this in
California and this isn't this isn't
anything malicious right this is just
because there was no data and
information showing that out in the
marketplace testing Labs couldn't really
test for it and there was no public and
so we knew we had all this data inous we
working towards this publication like
hey we really need to tell the story
right and show people that hey there is
more to the plant then we may understand
at this time that we know why it smells
and tastes grapey right why does GDP
have that grape note why does Blackberry
Kush have those dark berry notes we
understand the chemistries behind this
and this is empowering um important
powerful information not only for
Regulators people doing cultivation
genetic like breed genetic breeding um
extraction the whole Gambit of the
industry could benefit from having this
information because then you can
utilizes to better improv products and
consumer experiences and when you look
at Publications like Addie Ray and Ethan
Russo's publication they're looking at
they show that the consumer experience
it how much how good that experience is
for the consumer how positive it is was
correlated to how positive they perceive
the aroma to be right so understand
understanding more of this is going to
help give better experiences to not only
existing consumers but new entry
consumers coming into the industry who
may be interested to try
cannabis excellent yeah I'm glad you
brought up Edie Ray and her um her study
there she was a guest on the podcast
I'll put a link to that one too people
can really go down the rabbit hole um
but yeah that was really interesting
where yeah she would have folks on the
study smell different types of cannabis
and how how how good they thought they
smelled and then actually consume it and
kind of rate their experience and saw a
correlation where if you like the way it
smelled you tended to like the
experience which was pretty pretty
powerful 100% right I mean it it just
going to show that understanding more
about why it smells and tastes the way
it does is super important for whole
wide ranging um different product types
and our understanding of this industry
and trying to again empower consum
consumers to make more educated
decisions and get better experience of
the products right I mean a lot of
people who've been either in the
industry or consumed cannabis a lot of
people have bad experiences and bad
stories right maybe if we have more
education and more understanding of
what's going on we can avoid those
circumstances and those those bad
[Music]
experiences
a