[Music]
we have a lot of conviction that we can
find a therapy that not only deals with
the symptoms would actually attacks the
source of the problem through my own
personal research on cannabis I found
that there's women in particular have a
high concentration of endocannabinoid
receptors meaning that they are
particularly receptive to the medicinal
properties of the plant and I've read
tons of anecdotal data and research
published by universities that cannabis
does help with endometriosis and
endometriosis is tissue that forms very
simply put it's tissue that forms on the
a delay of the uterus which causes very
painful periods and can cause
infertility why is women's health
important it's a no-brainer to me we're
more than half the world's population
we're your caregivers we're the
caregivers our children are our spouses
of our parents our grandparents if we're
not going to take care of ourselves then
who will what we as women fail to
realize is how much power we truly have
right now we are undergoing a seismic
shift in women's personal and
professional power by 2020 women in the
United States are gonna control 22
trillion in u.s. wealth we don't need
anyone we can fund our own research we
can push forward products and science
that actually benefit us we women u.s.
women are the biggest consumers on the
planet even if you're not working you
decide what goes in the cupboards what
goes in the kitchen when to when and
where to make the doctors and dentists
appointments we are the caregivers it's
time to put our money where our health
is
[Music]
you