we really appreciate everybody joining
us to discuss the ten cardinal
parameters of plant health and vitality
our intention is to share some
information that we researchers and
other industry professionals in our
ecosystem have collected and applied to
large-scale cannabis cultivation
facilities to minimize cultivation risks
and maximize genetic expression as the
title of our webinar suggests there are
ten parameters that work in Symphony to
produce an end product that contains and
preserves all of the secondary
metabolites which consists of
cannabinoids terpenes and flavonoids
that are a value for recreational and
therapeutic cannabis products the
structure of today's webinar will
consist of a 30 minute presentation by
Jesse Porter inspires cannabis business
specialist and Robbie batts inspires a
chief technology officer with that I'll
pass it off to rob to kick us off
today's talk is truly inspired by dr.
Bruce Bugbee presentation at the CGC in
Niagara Falls in late 2019 his
sectioning of the main inputs into nine
cardinal parameters is something that
brought us to the realization that all
the systems of plant growth are
intertwined in a way that it's
impossible to focus on one without
having an impact on perhaps several
others so why do we have ten and the
esteemed dr. Bugbee has nine well dr.
Bugbee was specific about his nine
parameters being environmental only we
are humbly adding a tenth which is
microbes because our conversation is
specifically general plant inputs around
cannabis we exceed its impact on the
high dollar value of the cannabis plant
and we would be remiss if we did not
include them we find that when most
people talk about growing environments
cannabis they're most often looking for
that nugget of wisdom as it pertains to
VPD and many of you probably joined for
just that reason
well we don't blame you it's a topic we
take most seriously as a company that is
built on a backbone of temperature and
humidity control equipment and
controllers we're going to do a deeper
dive shortly but to set the stage let's
talk about it right here
VPD is vapor pressure deficit it is
water vapor pressure deficit and our
business that inspire has become control
of this very important metric are
designing efficient systems that control
track and trend the metrics this is
amazing things happen when you get it
right and we've seen some less than
desirable things happen when you get it
wrong we take our job humidifying and
conditioning the air very seriously
because there's someplace for water to
move from inside the plant to outside
the plant it would be impossible for
plants to thrive and at the end of the
day that's car business now it's almost
a true it's important to both leaf
temperature control and the
photosynthetic process amongst other
things but the real understanding that
plants only use a small fraction of the
water you give them is the start of a
deeper understanding to environmental
controls sea water is pulled through the
roads up the stem into the leaves and
would otherwise have no place to go
except for the fact that there are tiny
pores on the plant called stomata
through which the water can escape now
these pores are mainly where co2 enters
the plant oxygen gas leaves the plant
and also the water that entered the
plant through the roots as a liquid
evaporates out into the environment now
in order for the liquid to evaporate
into the air the surrounding air must be
below the saturation threshold of water
taking a closer look at the picture on
the Left you're going to see again and
again and again in this presentation you
can see that there is a substantive
cavity just on the inside of the stomata
the entire gas exchange process I
mentioned in the previous slide well
that happens here and if the surrounding
air is moist there's a good balance of
co2 entering an h2o leaving the plant if
the surrounding air is too dry relative
to inside the plant the co2 has a hard
time fighting its way upstream from all
the water vapor leaving the plant now
that that's out of the way
let's talk about the interplay of all
these variables in the context of plant
vitality
Jessie take it from here hey thanks Rob
great information there I think diving
into the parameters of plant influence
there are wonderful reference points for
understanding the interactions that
maximize the plant's vitality and
directly influence BBD east cardinal
parameters work synergistically to
create the ideal cultivation environment
and as we collect more data we might
even uncover more parameters of
influence hormones maybe I don't know
but for now we'll talk about 10 many of
which you're probably familiar with
light humidity temperature co2 and air
flow and then down in the root zone we
have temperature again nutrients
microbes oxygen and water that are all
major influencers in plant health but
what plant right cannabis sure but
understanding the genetics and breeding
history of a cultivar and have
significant influence on our
environmental set points
speak on genetics it's very easy for me
to show you pictures of beautiful
strains autumn izing expressing unique
traits and losing their oils but I think
it's even more powerful to share a
concept from robert c clarke and his
book marijuana botany as you can see in
the diagram phenotypes are the byproduct
of genetics mixing with the environment
makes sense right
strains are bred to thrive and are
uniquely adapted to the environments in
which they are created so whether you're
growing a maple leaf indica from a
reputable seed breeder a land race
Vietnamese black you picked up on
vacation or a handful of beans from a
friend it can be very helpful to
understand where they came from and how
they were bred in order to let them sing
if you think you're trying to create the
perfect conditions for your genetics you
should first consider the habitats
associated with the genetic origin and
then follow the environments in which it
was developed in order to get the most
out of your phenotype so what genetics
considered let's take a quick look at
light and its powerful and dramatic
interaction with the other plant
parameters in order to maximize
photosynthetic rate and your lighting
investment right it's important to
harmonize temperature co2 levels and
ppfd while thinking about your lighting
source as you will see later they are
separate VPD charts for LED and HID
lighting this is because HID lighting
emits radiant heat which impacts the
plant and leaf temperature as a result
the same plant will prefer a lower
temperature room for HID for maximum
production and a higher room temperature
in an LED room maximizing the
photosynthetic rate of cannabis requires
a keen understanding of the relational
set points associated with your lighting
choice
mentioned there's also relationship
between light and co2 we know plants use
light energy to convert co2 and water
into sugar and oxygen its photosynthesis
right but we also know as light
intensity goes up the amount of co2
utilized by the plant does to co2 is a
plant food that passes through the
stomata and is necessary for the
photosynthetic process and the amount of
co2 assimilation is directly related to
the accumulation of plant biomass so
when you consider parts per million of
co2 you should correlate that to ppfd
and the stage of plant growth as the
plant transitions from clown to veg to
flower co2 can be increased alongside
light intensity in order to maximize the
plant's development but what good is co2
if you can't deliver it to the plants
effectively right air flow has a direct
impact on how co2 is delivered to the
stomata it also affects the leaf
temperature influences to model
reactions microclimate management and
VPD in cannabis plants the stomata is on
the undersides of the leaves so the most
efficient way to deliver conditioned co2
rich air is up through the canopy and
directly to the undersides of the leaves
now as air passes the leaf surface it
has a drying and cooling effect it
should be accounted for when determining
room conditions in leaf tab airflow
considerations are also imperative to a
successful harvest as it can break up
canopy overlap contribute to cultural
control help mitigate odor it can even
impact drying and carrying employee
health and overall IPM strategy airflow
also plays a part in successful
regulation of temperature and humidity
and on that note I'll pass things back
to Rob who can talk about what happens
when we get hot and wet
thanks a lot Jesse and as far away's
does almost a decade trying to
understand the interplay of temperature
and humidity and its influence on plant
metabolism you know it turns out that
when water evaporates from inside the
substance
evany I talked about before it has the
same effect as sweat leading a person's
skin it'll cool to plant down and make
the environment around it more moist now
the rate of which this happens is very
important because the leaf is a somewhat
narrow band of temperature where the
chemical process of processes are most
efficient fishing chemical processes
inside of the plant mean higher yields
and higher revenues so if we measure
this for a plant it should be easy
enough to just set the room temperature
to the leaf temperature we want right
and bingo increased yield unfortunately
that's not the case although some days I
really wish it was that easy
instead all sorts of variables affect
leaf temperature and leave temperatures
almost always not room temperature now
it's not exactly easy to measure this
effect because leaf canopies are not a
single temperature as you can imagine
and in fact in fact they vary even
across a single leaf now in practice the
room is easy to measure
we set up an array of aspirated sensors
inside or close to the leaf canopy and
take our readings like to understand the
leaf temperature most often we use an
indirect measurement via for example a
thermal imaging system now it's
important to remember that the primary
heating source for a plant is the
radiation that is absorbed by the leaf
and this comes from primarily two
different sources now in a room lit by
HBS length we have the lights themselves
that are throwing infrared photons into
and through the canopy essentially we
have a source of heat similar to a
microwave heating their leaf from the
inside out
now most LED lit rooms don't have this
energy source to maintain the correct
leaf temperature we have to bring heat
to the plant by elevating the room
temperature around it and the walls and
the surfaces provide some infrared input
to heat the leaf up and for the will use
convection and warmer air inside the
room to keep that leaf in a narrow band
I mentioned before now this might be a
topic of a webinar in and of itself but
if you want to jump ahead
maybe hop onto Google and study the
Bowen ratio now this defines the amount
of energy of some outputs and heat law
patient to the transpiration process
now speaking of which remember when I
told you before that we need some sort
of lower moisture environments but
plants can transpire and the water can
move to the plant well that's true but
let's talk about humidity and in
different context let's talk about the
pests that thrive in humid environments
now we're going to be showing you some
tables later indicate a good humidity
relative to temperature for different
stages of growing environments and
growing rooms and this might lead you to
believe that anywhere inside those
ranges is good for plant health that may
be considered true but for the most part
inside of a room where we are moving off
in hundreds of gallons of water through
the air we have to be careful not to
give the pests a place to thrive now
it's widely understood that humidity has
a direct impact on the things like
powdery mildew and botrytis keep in mind
the general rule of general rule of
thumb is the one of the room the higher
the likelihood that even a small
outbreak of these pests can become
unmanageable and a revenue destroying so
whatever what about the plants now and
the effect of humidity on them when we
look at this leaf cross-section we have
to remember that in order for the plant
to use and move water we need to have a
humidity level outside the plant that is
less than inside this if this difference
is literally sucking the water through
the plant this difference is VPD now
it's actually a fairly simple task to
get an appropriate VPD chart if you know
just three of the things I've already
mentioned get yourself over to the
website you see in the bottom right hand
corner with your room temperature your
room humidity and leave temperature in
hand and voila you can generate a VPD
chart for almost any type of growing
environment assuming that the chart is
drawn for whatever plant you're growing
with but don't forget lighting type
affects how the chart is drawn the chart
below might be the kind of chart you'd
use in an LED lit room and this is the
kind of chart you would find if you're
using an HP S or C mhm lint room
intercept the corresponding good areas
of transpiration have changed well let's
make things a little more complicated as
you can see
from this chart on the right-hand side a
player will photosynthesize less and
less as the VPD increases that is as we
make the environment drier but as we
decrease the VPD make it more humid the
photosynthesis will increase but so does
the ability of a pathogen to thrive
there's a balance in there somewhere and
understanding that is going to be really
critical to understanding how you can
maximize the plants in your facility now
remember I told you that leaf
temperature is not room temperature and
then we had to use different types of
measurement systems for both types of
temperatures well let's see a really
really complicated this can get when we
look at a 15-hour leaf and room
temperature trend in one of the rooms
that we've put plants in as you can see
here things change dramatically if I
wanted to take a look at just this
differential you can see here that the
difference between the leaf temperature
and the air temperature changes almost
minute by minute the peaks on the left
and right hand side indicate areas when
the lights are on and the value in the
middle is when the lights are off in
this specific room if you're trying to
manage VPD with a static chart on the
wall you might have a hard time now we
use control systems and produce control
systems that can measure temperature and
humidity and plant temperature across an
entire range of time from the beginning
of the plants being moved into the room
to the time the plants leave its with
these sensors and controllers that were
able to measure the moisture removal
from the room every single day and feed
that information back to growers who
might find some useful nuggets out of
that what I'd say is we can see that the
plants transpire more when the lights
are on and that's the blue bar on the
right hand side at night they transpire
less and in fact most that moisture is
particular moisture loss by adding the
blue and the red bar up we can tell you
with pretty good certainty plus minus 5%
exactly how much transpiration is being
sent through the room now if you're
going to start off by trying to control
room humidity and VPD you're going to
need to size your equipment appropriate
we use the equation on the left hand
side as a starting point based on the
data we've taken from rooms and we
suggest you do as well
well that's enough about temperature
humidity Jessie why don't you take it
from here and talk about room
temperature and the rest of the
parameters you got it thanks again Rob
so temperature is also a major factor in
creating a healthy root zone when it
comes to the root zone I think it's
really important to consider the media
and its role in root zone thermal
regulation for example we know that soil
holds its temperature differently than
rock wall and if you're thinking about
an aeroponic approach it's going to be
heavily influenced by water temperature
and room conditions a root zone temps
play an important role in nutrient
uptake and root exudates production for
example studies show us that root zone
temps higher than 77 degrees inhibit the
uptake of calcium and other nutrients
and a root zone that is too cold will
slow chemical reactions and less than
the plant's ability to capture nutrients
a highly accomplished colleague of mine
would say finding the sweet spot for
your genetics is about determining the
temperature that balances enzyme and ion
concentration in the root zone for
maximum uptake I like to say it's like
Goldilocks all about finding the right
porridge and when it comes to
for your plants we know there are many
different nutrients and delivery
techniques available to the cannabis
cultivator
many of us even have our own secret
recipes despite that one thing holds
true for every successful nutrient
regiment it's directly connected to
transpiration might seem like a
stretched first but when you think about
how mobile nutrients are moved by the
planet and immobile nutrients are moved
through the transpiration process it
becomes more clear in order to maximize
your plants uptake of immobile nutrients
you must maximize the movement of water
through the plant otherwise the
nutrients will never get where they're
supposed to go we can collect some great
information on transpiration and plant
nutrition first we can test the
nutrients available in the media and use
that as a baseline for comparing leaf
tissue analysis from new growth and old
growth on the same plant if we discover
immobile nutrients lacking at any stage
of growth we can assume we miss an
opportunity to maximize transpiration
and nutrient translocation
now oxygen is another very important
plant influencer we know oxygen is
something that your plants give off
during the process of photosynthesis but
oxygen in the root zone also plays a
critical role in roots breathing
chemicals interacting and good microbes
breeding now if the media becomes
compacted or the roots grow in an
anaerobic condition the roots will
suffocate chemical reactions will slow
and your plants growth will - an
anaerobic root zone is also a breeding
zone for pathogens that will negatively
affect plant health oxygen water and
temperature all interacting factors we
know that cold water holds more oxygen
we don't want to put ice water on your
roots right it's about balancing this
knowledge with your media choice room
conditions plant stage and other factors
to make sure oxygen is allowed to
function most appropriately oxygen also
helps us create an environment where
good microbes thrive and pathogens don't
there are many different microbes on
this planet that directly influence
cannabis one example Rob mentioned
earlier was the botrytis that's all
around us and preventing conditions for
it to take hold involve appropriate
dehumidification integrated biological
filtration air flow considerations and
proper staff training but there's also
good microbes we should think about
managing beneficial fungal colonies will
thrive on plants roots in an oxygenated
environment root zone fungus like raizou
faggus irregularity vies sugars -
bacteria as a reward for making
nutrients available in the rhizosphere
sounds relatively simple but managing
protozoa and nematodes micro arthropods
fungi and bacteria can be a real
challenge when oxygen levels are low and
fungal and bacterial pests begin to take
hold instead it's more about creating an
oxygenated rooting environment where
good microbes can maximize nutrient
uptake emulate growth and protect
against pests and pathogens good and bad
microbes like bacteria virus and fungus
and
controlled if the appropriate
environmental conditions are maintained
and when it comes to thinking about an
IPM strategy every good IPM plan starts
with cultural control which prizes
prevention over attempted eradication
filtering the air creating right air
pressures optimizing air flow
considerations appropriately
dehumidifier and maintaining conditions
that are unsuitable for pests is
cultural control the ability to
precisely control your cultivation
environment limits IPM applications
limits labor hours and it gives you the
ability to change conditions for a short
period of time in order to increase the
efficacy of an IPM application for
example we're using the humidity for a
certain IPM application to be more
effective we're dropping the humidity to
control a fungal spread either way
environmental considerations are
imperative to the success of any IPM
plan an application strategy and
speaking of success water management is
paramount to cannabis cultivation there
is no life without water right and
Leonardo da Vinci said water is the
driving force of all nature I like this
quote because I've heard the taxicab
water analogy before water is the
vehicle that picks up all the nutrients
and moves them around water is the
driving force for cannabis plants both
internally and externally water delivery
must be treated to avoid the development
of pathogens like Pythium and
temperature of the water must be
considered as a lab an impact on root
zone temperature and oxygen holding
capabilities oxygenated water will help
the root zone grow and aid in beneficial
microbes growth and appropriate water
pressures will maintain and maximize
plant growth nutrient utilization and
phenotype expression and we all know
that water in the room is humidity that
needs to be managed appropriately in
order to prevent things like powdery
mildew from destroying your crop instead
we suggest you apply the knowledge that
you have about vapor pressure deficit
and use water to maximize your plants
expression in biomass
and with that let me toss it back to
Brian Jesse Rob excellent work very very
nicely done at this point we'd like to
answer some of the questions that came
in from you all here at the top one of
our attendees asked is airflow different
than HVAC yeah I think that's a really
good question and I think when you think
about airflow considerations for a room
sometimes we've separate them from an
integrated HVAC approach but when it
comes to conditioning the air in the
room and redelivery it to the plant
they're tied together specifically I
like to think about air flow as you know
breaking the boundary layer and
recreating some outdoor environmental
conditions that put some you know subtle
pressures on the plan and remind them
that we are mother nature when it comes
to the bigger HVAC conditioning aspect
it's about removing the water that
doesn't need to be there and controlling
the environment in a way that we're
filtering biological pathogens and we're
cleaning the system and that we're
maintaining the temperature and humidity
set points in a space so while I think
they're both interconnected there's
definitely a multitude of different
approaches we take with each one
I'm sure lab can add something there too
yeah can you hear me guys we've got you
great so what I like to say to that is
if you're going to be looking at air
flow inside of a room most likely it's
going to be two separate systems that
handle the conditioning of the air and
the dehumidifying of the air and I
wouldn't rely on those systems to get
the air just where it needs to be inside
a very dense canopy inside the room if
you were trying to do that you'd have
ductwork everywhere and frankly these
rooms can be quite busy and you're just
going to need some way to get air into
the room and then from the room itself
or in a general cavity of the room
out into the canopies in a way that's
not going to impede the ability of
people to get around the room get in
between the rows etc etc but yeah
Jesse everything you said was correct
and they're definitely very much
intertwined excellent thank you guys one
follow-up question related to air flow
is what are some good vertical upward
through the canopy air flow options as
far as brand and style
well what your shameless plug you know
oftentimes we don't see anything that's
being done inside the rack and the tray
to bring air flows through the canopy
and so we're often sourcing these and
providing them ourselves
so we supply them I think the most
integrated system out there is probably
the vertical air solution system and
that does a pretty good job now I think
the question was from the bottom up
especially they only go from the top
down at this point but yeah I think
there are a number of options out on the
market you could reach out to us and
we'd be happy to tell you all about them
and guys just to piggyback on top of
that I saw a quick question come in
about you know the effect that
delivering this air to directly to the
stomata on the undersides of the plants
you know is that a potential stressor
and I think this comes back to a couple
of things it comes back to data
collection and real world application
absolutely if we apply too much air flow
too fast we can affect the stomata
negatively we can get it to close we can
slow the plant's metabolic rate so when
it comes to this air flow delivery it's
really about making sure of two things
that the air is the appropriate
temperature in humidity so its condition
and also that the rate of air flow the
actual velocity in which it's delivered
to the plant
I think our study shows somewhere around
a meter per second it could be wrong on
that but we've done some in-depth data
and studies and just to show or just to
get an idea of how much air flow we need
to apply to that leaf surface to
positively affect the plant to break the
boundary layer and deliver that co2
without any stressors without any leaf
curl without any negative reactions to
the environment and it's just key that
that air air is conditioned and you know
delivered at the right velocity to avoid
that kind of stress hopefully that's a
little bit of insight on that that
concept Thanks thanks Jesse makes sense
another question I have here is the VPD
and transpiration continue as a plant
process as a plant process post-harvest
so this is Rob here I think that the
transpiration process does not the
transpiration is that full cycle the
water enters through the root system up
to the stem and then out the stomata of
the leaves at some point when you've
trimmed the plant is harvested in that
process stops there are no more roots
there's no more water going through the
stem you're going to start seeing water
leave the plant through the stomata or
through that ticular membrane on the
leaves themselves that is very much
VPD dependent now it's not a VPD chart
you would use or find on the website I
showed you before but it's very much
dependent on how much humidity is in the
room the temperature of the room and the
temperature and moisture content of the
leaves and those two things will play
off each other those two or sorry four
things of the two subsets from the plant
and the room those things will play off
each other and dramatically affect how
quickly or how slowly that plant dries
and further it will affect the
consistency of the drying so many times
we see a harvest lose so much value in
the drawing incurring process because it
was dried inconsistently it's crusty
outside on the bud and a really moist
interior that's just perfect for
pathogen growth and that rate of air is
going to strip apart all the value
you've put into that plant to that point
mm-hmm yeah sounds like a great segue
into our next webinar more
come another question here can you
provide a recommendation for maintaining
soil temperature and large fabric beds
yeah I think I think what we're really
talking about here is no understanding
the process of break down in those beds
what I'm thinking of what I'm picturing
here is a no-till kind of approach where
people are trying to maintain beds or
even just a soil recycling system where
people are trying to sort of maintain
the temperatures in those beds and
obviously we know that there's a pretty
significant influence from the airflow
and the temperature and humidity set
points you know how they're going to
impact that soil but I also think it's
important to sort of think about the
chemical breakdown and the nutrients
that you're going with if you have a
soil based program and you have a lot of
really good organic inputs that are
continually breaking down and you have a
lot of microbial activity there's going
to be a good chance that you have
wonderful micro climates this way we're
talking about micro climates in a good
way in that soil structure that allow
certain fungal and bacterial colonies to
thrive and spread their wings and sort
of encapsulate those roots and protect
them from some of the environmental
threats I also think it's important to
think about water temperature a lot of
times we don't think about that delivery
temperature and if we deliver water
that's really cold to a cold root zone
when the lights are off you know it's
cold on cold on cold and if we can
deliver the water at the root zone after
the lights have come on we have a little
bit of warmth in that room we have a
little bit of process going on in that
plant and if the water is warm enough
but not too warm again back to that
Goldilocks porridge we can use that to
sort of maintain the soil temperature or
any media temperature for that matter as
well hopefully that provides a little
insight there Barnett I like to add a
little something to back when we were
doing work in the
some industry large soil beds were kind
of a de facto standard for growing
mushrooms inside of a cold wet darkroom
and so maintaining those bed
temperatures is pretty important and
some of the methods they use there and
I've seen some of this in the cannabis
industry people attempting it anyways
would be to use basically piping a coil
piping a radiant floor type system
underneath the bed
you could put cool or hot water through
it and end up with a temperature control
scheme that way and we've also seen
people attempt to use phase change
material kind of novel they'll find out
the time to get into it but we've tried
to see them use phase change material I
can't tell you how well it worked out I
can find out for you and the person who
asked the question No right thank you
very much Steven I see that your hand is
up that you also have asked a question
I'll try and and ask your question here
shortly if you have more questions or
follow-ups I can also bring you our live
to chat with us so just let us know on
that the next question I'd like to ask
is indoor agriculture is very energy
intensive what are some ways to be more
efficient with HVAC and are there any
sacrifices that are made to plan
performance as a result boy just show me
a soft one there I guess you know to
inspire we've designed and built some
very efficient ways to diiie humidify
the air the challenge is one of being
able to use the energy you're putting
into the system in a novel way in
standard G minification systems they do
that by using compressor energy to
reheat the air after they've cooled it
to that temperature where you get all
the moisture out we and some other
manufacturers in the industry go a step
further and we will move the air from
one spot to the other inside the air
handling unit in a sense in essence pre
cooling the air before hits the cooling
coil and using that same room energy to
reheat the air back up and effectively
we get 30 to 50% less compressor energy
there are other very very sophisticated
ways including desiccants to increase
the energy efficiency of the whole
growing process but see but you know
beyond all that making smart light
choices will probably help drive the
efficiency of the facility and also we
know that LED rooms which are much
warmer have a much easier ability to
deity much easier ability to
dehumidifier that air using less
compressor tonnage so those factors all
combined and from one to the other we
can see energy use 50% you know an
efficient building compared to a
standard building a legacy system that
was you know being built a designed I
guess even today but usually we saw them
mostly you know five years ago or so
then answer your question I hope
equation I believe so
but the second part would be are there
any sacrifices that are made to plan
performance as a result of the the more
energy-efficient process there can be
but that has more to do with the choices
you make in general if you don't have
systems that can modulate and that can
handle the cool times at night versus
the hot times during the day and those
transitions in between its the
modulating equipment if you're not using
it that's where you're gonna find the
challenges it's one thing to sort dumps
I'll get it but if you don't have a
really effective gas pedal lead on a
dump truck or an efficient Prius then
you're not gonna have a really good
chance controlling those systems and
that's where the sacrifice comes in I
mean the plant health will really suffer
if you give those pests a place to
thrive if you're not doing the right
thing for the root zone temperature etc
I got it I like that analogy very cool
ok I got a question here from another
attendee temperature humidity and air
flow conditions can vary widely within a
room is there an ideal room size for
optimal quality at what point does an
increase in room size jeopardize plant
quality you guys have any sort of these
general ideas around room size
all right yeah I mean I think that let
me take a stab at this Rob and you can
forward I think for the most part you
know as we've all transitioned to larger
scale cultivation facilities we've
started to sort of appreciate the
smaller room size for isolation purposes
and you know prevention of spreads but
at the same time you know if you
accurately and adequately understand
your watering rate and you have an
appropriate mechanical system you can
have a much larger scale to me it really
comes down to a couple of things it
comes down to you know working with your
engineer and really understanding the
inputs and thoroughly vetting them and
appropriate planning but it also sort of
comes down to CFD modeling and
computational fluid dynamics is
something that you know I wasn't too
familiar with until I really started
looking at these larger scale rooms and
it wasn't as simple as hey we're gonna
put a fan every six feet
you know this rule of thumb for
traditional legacy growers was still
applicable but we needed to take those
inputs and sort of take them to a
data-driven science level and by doing
the modeling we're usually allow we're
usually capable of determining you know
how many air exchanges we're gonna have
you know per per couple of minutes or
you know where that air is gonna flow
the potentiality for dead spots and and
as a result we can adjust our mechanical
influences and cultural control in that
space to make sure that we are
controlling the space as a whole a lot
of times traditional techniques are
let's let's put up some HVAC let's put
in some pocket dehumidifiers and let's
blow air all around the room and I think
what we're talking about is a recipe for
microclimate and without the appropriate
planning and the appropriate data
collection it's really hard to get all
those things on the same page and
actually manage the envelope as a whole
but Rob you have you have something you
want to add to that
well you busily stole my thunder dare
you yeah say the exact same thing you
know anecdotally we see rooms 2,000 to
3,000 square foot and
and they might go one or two tear we've
seen since 40 rooms but like I said
gently without modeling you can't really
no modeling gives gives us a sheet that
says what's the average dwell time of
air inside of a room it's one thing
design to design a room with an HVAC
system that's going to do a certain
number of air changes per hour but you
know even then unless you can prove to
me that we've gone in model the canopy
like they're doing the wind tunnels use
those same formulas and applied them
into the rows and the racks of the
Cannabis themselves through the CFD you
know I just I don't I don't believe it I
need to I need to see it to believe it
yeah modeling has helped us for sure
great
all right questions are coming in guys
thanks thanks very much
for for the the level of engagement here
another question here from Eric Studdard
saying I do energy studies of indoor
cannabis facilities and you've seen a
lot of variety and how much
dehumidification is required during dark
flower flower dark periods the strain
type has the most significant impact on
dark period transpiration Wow great
question I go I can tell you that you
know we catalog every room that we
design and go back to verify how much
moisture is being taken out of it like
you saw on that graph during our slide
we can measure the transpiration rate
down to the minute the instantaneous
transpiration rate of the room we have
yet to catalogue it like strain so it's
probably gonna be the next thing we go
and look at now our rooms are generally
designed on day one to handle a wide
variety of plants so we don't want to
limit a grower or a facility to a
specific strain on day one and then you
know six months later market conditions
change etc we always advise using
standard rules of thumb and going just a
little bit bigger than that for your
room dehumidification design but that
being said I can't wait to go back and
look at that data
very interesting I'm curious to know
great hopefully that answers your
question Eric thank you again I've got
another question here from Jacob Hickey
are there any fundamental strategies or
differences in maintaining the ten
cardinal parameters in rock wool
substrate well I think that that's a
really good question and obviously
[Music]
that's that's an interesting
conversation for a parameter but your
media choice is definitely going to have
some impact on how you deal with it over
the course of time and how your plant
grows so I think when you think about
the ten cardinal parameters you know the
importance is understanding the synergy
and how they all interact and how they
work together and the same thing goes
for your media choice for example you
know if you're using rock wool media we
know that initially that rock wool media
tends to have a very high pH you know it
could be it could be very high it could
be somewhere around eight it could be
even higher than that so in
understanding that and first
appropriately treating the rock wall to
get to that right pH is a step that you
need to take because of your media
choice in order to facilitate all those
other parameters interacting a microbe
growth the appropriate water retention
the right you know root growth that
leads to plant vitality you know the
same goals same goes for every media
choice that you have they're all going
to have you know slightly different
considerations another one might be
something like you know using cocoa and
we know that you know cocoa has a
tendency to bind nitrogen over a long
period of time so if you're recycling
your media over years that's something
very important to consider you might
actually have to add more additional
nitrogen to that to that product because
you have a cocoa beast media and then
when you start to mix media's and build
your own media's and build soil you have
all these other interacting factors as
well some of them are buffers force
success through that mixture just by
creating more inputs and more
opportunities in the root zone but
absolutely there there will be an impact
because of your media choice sort of
mentioned temperature as well so in a
cloning environment you have all these
little rock wool cubes sitting around
and if you're blowing too much cold air
past the environment they're gonna pick
up that cold air they're gonna be
sitting there without roots growing and
that's going to dramatically impact your
ability to get roots quickly but if you
think about that and you raise the
environmental conditions and deliver
warmer air to that root zone that's
oxygenated that will have an impact on
you know initiating root growth faster I
think this is probably a topic for a
much deeper dive but hopefully that's a
little bit of insight and the answer is
absolutely yes it's great thanks Jesse
another one here I hear a lot about
Bruce brute-force HVAC are there any
other options to consider
yeah absolutely
um I'll take this one yeah I've been
stood the technologies before for
dehumidification and how to make a less
energy-intensive growing operation
there's a number of dehumidification
technology you know we call them in our
products at coil runaround loop there's
an air to air heat exchanger around the
same cooling coil mechanism that we
talked about before there are liquid and
dry desk in systems that can be used
well we talked when we talked about
brute force we're specifically talking
about the use of a commercial air
conditioner that takes the room
temperature and humidity air and brings
that all the way down past that dew
point that's required to maintain the
room condition and that takes a lot of
compressor energy compressor energy 70
to 80 percent of most air conditioning
systems we try and reduce that using
that air to air heat exchanger system or
a coil runaround loop and we've also
looked at dry and liquid desiccant and
they might be they may do a very good
job too frankly we haven't found much
luck but you know it's all about system
design and thoughtful approaches ahead
of time absolutely
excellent piggybacking on that question
in a region where outdoor temps can get
below negative 30 degrees Fahrenheit and
humidity in the 20% range will this
affect indoor conditions of an enclosed
facility and wood concrete floors affect
things as well yeah absolutely
I can tell you for sure that an unfilled
most over the second question lap or
first a concrete floor we've seen it in
rooms contributing humidity into the
space almost 50 percent of what the
plants were doing at different times of
the stages of growth especially that's
the problem in drawing rooms so if
you're going to use a concrete floor
your best chance to combat that and not
have to over dehumidified moisture
inside your space that's not coming from
your plant is to seal it off use an
epoxy seal if the rest of the room is
sealed going back to the first part of
the question if the rest of the room is
sealed and it's still very well and the
pressure is controlled appropriately
then outside temperatures and humidity
don't actually have that much of an
influence that outside air that's being
brought in for ventilation purposes if
it's being brought in and we recommend
it should especially for pressurization
and pathogen control and biosecurity
well then there should be treated and if
it's too dry it should be moisturized if
it's too hot it should be cooled down we
don't want to bring in air into a room
that's not conditioned in any way shape
or form so we're not to manage that it's
an engineering equation and at the end
of the day again we recommend sealing
rooms so that we have the best pressure
control possible if only for biosecurity
reasons that person can feel free to
email me afterwards and I'll do a much
deeper dive but yeah sealing a room we
find in most facilities we go into we
just don't have that much influence even
the hottest desert areas of ambient
conditions considering the rooms
themselves are rooms inside of
facilities so they don't have a solar
load and there's very little thermal or
humidity load inside the facility itself
right
thanks Rob circling back on the on the
medium the question of a medium are
there any specific issues that inspire
can address as an aeroponic system of
being utilized yeah I mean I think when
you think about aeroponics and the way
that we're controlling the root zone we
don't have a buffer other than water
right we're delivering a fine aerated
nutrient mist to the root zone at
periodic intervals and water is being
delivered through tubes and bucket
systems that run throughout the facility
so when it comes to understanding the
importance of that water temperature
because it lacks a buffer you know we
really need to control the oxygen levels
and water and dilution of that of that
delivery mechanism so when the water
runs through the systems and the pipes
get hot and cold those are going to have
influences on the water delivery in the
root zone so in an aeroponic setting it
becomes of critical importance to
control the ambient temperatures to
control the room temps and make sure
that you don't have dramatic spikes but
you can stabilize the delivery of that
water throughout the entire propagation
period is that does that make sense yeah
that's great thank you it looks like we
have time for maybe one more question
here I'm circling back on the concept of
drying rooms which again will take a
much deeper dive on with our next
webinar session the question is have you
found an accurate way to estimate pounds
per hour water loss of product in dry
rooms on an hourly basis based on
product mass volume percent moisture
content and/or VPD in turn being able to
accurately size the dry dry room HVAC
system and control properly through the
drying process great question I can say
that
on so I would say that yeah absolutely
we have just like he saw in that graph
with red and blue bars we can watch
product in a room lose water weight at a
certain pace based on the effective
temperature and humidity control of that
space so starting at the beginning if we
can control the temperature of the
humidity to the customer's desired
requirements that means we are removing
the moisture that's coming off of the
plant after the harvest at a specified
rate but we use sensors that are
accurate enough and a verified miss with
weighed product in the field weight over
time to know that our air conditioning
system feeds back the moisture removal
rates from the product itself so we use
our air conditioning system controllers
to tell the growers and the harvesting
team how much water is being lost on a
pound per hour basis not being fed we
know that water starts at a certain
moisture content and the customer
typically wants a targeted moisture
content at the end of the drawing
process what we do is we look at that
difference in pounds of water coming out
of the product and saying how many days
do you want that product removed how
many days you want that weight removed
and usually we end up with a number
that's seven to ten days you can make it
go faster than seven to ten days by
heating up the room but you're probably
going to do negative things to the plant
you can slow it down and really
essentially slow down the plant drying
process these are all things that we
play with and it all goes back to really
good sensors on the equipment that's
doing the dehumidification and knowing
from that exactly how that moisture loss
is being handled terrific all right one
one more question
and we're going to have to sign off here
in respect of everybody's time for any
of the questions that we didn't answer
please feel free to reach out to us
directly and we'd be happy to talk with
you more
the final question
here is do you think recirculating
molecular filtration equipment proto
mitigation has a negative effect on live
cannabis in the space so that will
question one more time circulating but
do you think recirculating molecular
filtration equipment such as activated
carbon for for odor mitigation has a
negative effect on the live candidates
in the space oh that's a pretty good
question I can tell you that we talked
about
VPD which is what when we talked about
it in this context it was water vapor
pressure deficit I can tell you that
there's also a vapor pressure for other
products inside the cannabis like the
chip beans themselves that if you've
removed them you may end up causing a
deficit of the token in the air which
would have a detrimental effect of the
tripping on the plant which is going to
evaporate into the room now how much
carbon filtration do you have to use
inside of a room to drop the vapor
pressure down of a terpene to affect the
plant don't know the answer to that I
can tell you that most times researching
it in air even going through a carbon
filtration scheme in fact it's only the
air that's being injected out of the
room in the facilities we design that's
going through carbon filtration so the
answer may or may not be yes I don't
think using carbon filters in your
recirculating air stream necessarily a
good idea the pressure drops are high
there's all sorts of other things that
there's a really good impact your bottom
line in a facility that's not into that
question I hope I did answer it I got
the purse can reach out to me if they
want Jesse give anything to add alright
I think that was really good I think
when it comes to you know recirculating
and it's it's better to to make a really
good stab at trying to do it right and
you know necessarily think about the
minor implications that you might have
for that recirculated air we know that
stale and stagnant air is going to be a
health issue for people and plants in
the like and just like you mentioned as
far as an integrated system it's
probably looking more like some sort of
capture fill
like a murder 13 followed by some sort
of secondary treatment you know whether
that's UB or photocatalytic oxidation or
something like that in order to make
that recirculation past or it makes
sense for a long period of time the
replacement on those carbon filters can
be really tricky as well you know you
might run them for a couple of cycles
and then not know if they're full and
not know if you need to throw them away
and maybe not be able to accurately
determine that so I have my concerns
with carbon as well but I think you
touched on that Rob we really just sort
of use it as the exhaust odor mitigation
and we do some pre-filter before that
for the integrated room system excellent
excellent
all right everybody looks like our time
is up we'd like to thank you all again
for spending the last hour with us and
we look forward to having you
participate in future events hope you
all have a great day thanks everyone
dancing thanks everybody