from an investor's standpoint think the
most surprising thing was the the amount
of capital that was being poured into
Canada and the amount of capital that
Canada was pouring back into the United
States I think the last couple of years
the expectation was that most the deal
flow is going to be dominated by the
private equity firms here in the US the
guys had large pools of capital they put
together specifically to back cannabis
based businesses and they thought that
their competition for deal flow was
largely going to exist between private
equity funds what ended up happening is
that after some of these Canadian
companies ended up with you know
sometimes billions of dollars of capital
is sitting there they're creating
special opportunities funds and those
special opportunities funds we're now
competing for deal flow and they also
had the advantage of being able to use
their paper as when I say their paper
their stock as a way to purchase some of
these companies
so from an M&amp;A perspective so much the
deal flow went to the Canadian
businesses and then there's also
Canadian businesses that are formed
specifically for the purpose of
acquiring US assets you know companies
such as cantarella tea which is now
called origin house or c21 or i anthis
those companies start coming to the US
and using a combination of cash in stock
to to put together large portfolios of
US businesses and I don't think that
anyone in 2017 expected how much capital
come out of the Canadian market that way