in 3 2 1
we are live ok thank you for joining us
everyone we have here we go
Kevin Joey is entering the room Chris
Anderson is entering the room and that
is me Peter so very so Jason what we
were talking about earlier is kind of
like can you talk about the evolution of
kind of your grows and your gross style
from like when you first started growing
I assume it was not at a commercial
legal commercial scale so was it was it
in the garage was it outdoors was it up
in the Humboldt area was it outdoors it
was in the mountains you know we call
them grill it grows you know he did hike
bags of dirt chicken shit whatnot up and
down mountains and you know item as good
as we could and you know it was like
that for four years and then eventually
we started moving indoors I mean the
evolution is kind of started at a slower
speed and it's just sped up to a whole
different world now I mean it see
everything that's going on yeah you know
I was really young I was I started
working you know it's still be grown I'd
be growing really grows with my dad and
you know patches out in the middle of
nowhere and you know doing construction
with him for a while and it eventually
moved on to just work in big indoor
scenes and you know learn how to grow
both both ways you know the technology
wasn't there so you know we weren't
doing testing and we didn't know near
the science we just you know we were
taught from our parents and we knew I'd
agree oh no we
to grow the plant and uh you know when
you have Kevin here because I mean a guy
his brain works there mean he knows so
much more on on this you know all the
descriptions organisms and all that but
yeah we sit there and I could tell how
to plant as you know I just always kind
of fed it the same I'm a ball go to fed
it but I know how to go intuitive
intuitive yeah you basically learned
with your dad right and and was this in
like the 80s the I mean you don't look
that old well I'm 40 yeah I definitely
remember you know starting to work with
him when I was around you know eight
probably you know I was probably picking
leaves and I was about six you know so
yeah I was really young and you know it
was a whole different world we were
super freaked out just because you know
we did a camp flying over a house
multiple times and landing at her house
coming in our house we dealt with all of
that I've already you know told these
stories a lot and you know it's kind of
I really love to talk about it as much
anymore is good to let the story out at
first and now now we're kind of past
that we've you know we went from doing
these you know just just back down like
said we'd grow you know 10 to 20 pounds
sell it for four to five thousand
dollars and you know we were really
really we were really poor family back
then but life was just great so if we
didn't need thousands of pounds
we just we needed just just what we
could live on it was a whole different
type of growing you talked a little bit
about that what you were growing back
then what types of cultivars and strains
and how that's of all oh my gosh I mean
Tod we call it you know your pop we go
seed we we
we had seeds from friends every
neighbors we all traded seeds it wasn't
there wasn't so many strains I mean and
as we know a lot of these strains have
there's been one strain you know crossed
a thousand times now there's just so
many strains it's crazy to watch happen
even when I was in my teens growing you
know indoors there is still probably
four or five strains and you know that
that's evolved just it's it's amazing to
watch it and it's it's exciting honestly
I mean for me I love the plant I love
growing right now I'm growing seven
strains and six green or seven strains
and six greenhouses that I've actually
never even grown before up ten strains
six greenhouses and seven of them I
don't even know exactly what they're
gonna do I've seen the final product
through other people but you know it's
really exciting to see because there's
just amazing you know there's these
people out here what do they call it
Kevin just the genetic the people are
you know all these there's lots of
people like you know growing up stuff
let's say see junkie right now and
lemonade and you know there's all these
that they're incredible there's and you
know so you know the evolution of the
strains changing is just crazy to me
it's it's how do you decide what you're
gonna grow do you take what's available
are you making proactive choices like
this year well let's say this year I
mean I'm sticking with stuff that I know
people will like I mean the Green
Lantern seemed to be really good it's a
very very potent strain seems to be this
day and age people really like hi Katie
that's like what they're going for they
I want to see these numbers from 25 you
know personally it's not what I love but
that's what they really like out there
Green Lantern is a very special strain
because it floors you it's doesn't have
tons of flavor
it gassy and grown and cured perfectly
because it does have like you knows
about half of G in it but uh these other
strains you know let's say like runts
it's a very popular strain but its taste
amazing and I mean when I smoke it as
lots of like the purple Urkel's like
flavor that was one of my favorites um
back in the day um what's the cherry
what's a cherry one Kevin give you out
on there
what's that you look at cherry pie yeah
the cherry pie the cherry pies in lots
of these and I was one of my like you
know so I'm kind of going with I always
will grow no G because I love to gassy
oh geez I love that just the dominant
indica it's it's I say Oh G is queen I
mean that's what you say it's it's all
these people always love oh gee I love
our G but I do love flavors I have this
uh so I'm citrus I'm growing and it
tastes like an orange it's a very
citrusy flavor I did notice you know
let's say normal club last year a lot of
the flavors that talked you know that
we're up there in the talk were were
more exotics and you know so it's it's
weird certain places I mean as we know
it you know East Coast loves the gassy
flavors they love the Sour Diesel they
love the oh geez I mean I mean that's
just coming from a producer person that
produces marijuana you could use know
where it goes and that's what they love
but it seems like it's turning into more
of a exotic type of like out there and a
high THC so between both of those you
know I look and see what the public
really likes what I what I like just
kind of roll the dice on a lot of it and
hope that it you know I don't know you
kind of learn a strain I could tell oh
gee exactly when I flip it how big it's
gonna get I know what to feed it I know
everything about it so when you pick a
new strain it's a whole different thing
you have to pick you know you don't know
when you flip it if it's gonna let say
skittles one year do that I flipped it
it grew one inch and then sorry buddy
they were tiny
you know let's say the runts you flip it
it'll grow it'll double its size so you
kinda have to learn strains it is risky
to switch and grow a bunch of different
strains but I really like the variety
I like having um I know I'm growing
great strains because like I said the
people that made new genetics I mean
they're crushing it and so I'm not
really worried about it being good I
know I could do the quality I mean I'm
hard not super worried about either so
you put that together and it should be
fun and it makes it way more interesting
than growing all oh gee I did that for
last not last few of you before probably
four or five years in a row just all oh
geez so that's a people wanted cool
beautiful plants love it but you know we
need more we need like you say I believe
we need to fall for me I'm in girl weed
like I said it's really like really
grown weed since I was probably about 12
and so the excitement in it for me is
definitely seeing new strains brand new
strains of getting the feedback from the
consumers and I mean that's what it's
about that's really what I was hoping to
talk about a lot on this is we really
need to educate the consumers and that's
that's you know that comes from
you know the dispensaries Chris redwood
roots you know people going out there
and getting are about they're telling
our stories knowing where the herbs that
they are buying comes from where that
money that you know who they're
supporting what they're putting in their
bodies you know all of that comes back
to educating the consumer and if we all
work together like podcasts like this
you know and get the word out and let
them know you know they they buy it from
a family-run farm or you know we support
a small community basically they help
support a whole village and I mean
that's really what's happening you know
and that's what keeps our little town
going yeah I I think I mean you're
talking about education and I think it's
interesting that you you do have to
balance kind of growing hype strains
versus maybe stuff that you and your dad
grew or your neighbors grew that you
really loved but doesn't have the
hightlight like when Chris has to go
down Chris were you just down in LA
think he's on the 405 right now I'm
actually I just hit the valley down on
the five I just came down the grapevine
you're in those you're in SoCal right
now so like in terms of when you're
interacting with shops and bud tenders
and owners and purchasing decision
makers you know telling the story of
something that's not a hype strain but
that jason has been growing or any of
your other farms have been growing for
decades and as you think is amazing but
the kind of general public is like
that's not the hype strain that I'm
looking for
they just haven't smoked it yet but yeah
I'm actually not currently our major
focus is on moving a lot of bulk product
we are not servicing a whole lot of
dispensaries at this point in time we've
kind of regrouped and and honed in our
whole strategy on this
you should too instead of you had a
vision of covering all the bases and
full vertical integration and all the
whole nine yards and I still feel like
that is something that's out in the
future potentially however we've we've
really honed our whole process in
business and financial model into first
mile distribution and procurement and
and delivering that product to other
brands and distributors across the state
more more so than retail at this point
we are redirecting a whole lot of our
energy here in the next 2 3 4 5 6 months
back to the brand and retail and getting
shelf space and and having those
conversations with bud tenders and
buyers and and and that education that
Jason speaks of is absolutely over
important but how do you get the mass
consumer base to swap up the fluff and
the vapor of all these designer strains
which are chronic crucial I like smoking
all of them - for sure I just like P o T
ha what's wrong with that you know
whatever happened to the posturing I
love the evolution I love all the
genetics the evolution to me is is is
more based on medicine and the evolution
of genetics and and breeding and and the
unknown medicines that can be unlocked
in that evolution is super crucial of
course we all like the flavors and the
high and and the terpene profiles and
all that stuff work you know I think
most we all what we all enjoy all of
that stuff however I did see the
evolution of cannabis and the medicine
part is what gets me really excited and
I'm obviously not a doctor or a
scientist but there are doctors and
scientists out there pushing the
envelope and you know so that that's
exciting to me so I I want to do we got
what I like about this is we have plenty
of time to dive into some of these
topics so I don't have to gloss over
them
I want to get into kind of the evolution
of each of your like the many pivots and
twists and turns you've taken and kind
of your current line of thinking but
let's sit let's stick with kind of
cultivation and stuff like that Jason
give me an example of something that you
like to smoke that you don't see out on
the market or think that people
necessarily appreciate I'm Chris or
Kevin her well my dad has the seed
strand he's working on for a while it's
called Supergirl and I mean it it's it's
amazing it's completely pretty much done
by September
I mean buds are giant which you know
when you bring a bud you know this big
and it dries this big it's people don't
love it in a bag you know the bag
appeals not crazy but it the high is
amazing it's you know I mean I still
have when my dad shows me his weed and I
look at it you know I know personally on
the market it's not this purple nug that
looks like it's dipped in sugar but it's
amazing you smoked it and it's like you
know I mean he grows 15 plants you know
and he put so much time and love into
him he's smoking you could just taste it
it doesn't hurt your throat the high is
amazing it's clear and you know it's
great I mean so basically it comes out
to its you know it's like you say the
hype a lot of that weed is amazing like
I said I do I love smoking grunts I mean
it's taste really good ice cream cake I
mean who could say it's the most
beautiful looking plant
I mean it's purple it's amazing but it
tastes okay get a little flavor then
it's gone the highs okay but yeah you
know my dad has some seeds that you know
we pop and we actually he grows a few
plants so it's all rather smoked some of
that than some of these other strains
because it just tastes great looks not
quite there but yeah it's called
Supergirl maybe one day we'll have to
bring it out
talk about your your because when we're
talking before you were talking about
playing with some new products since
then specifically roots organic and so
can you talk about your setup like you
said you have seven greenhouses are UN
pots or you and raised beds or you time
in raised beds I mean I love growing
organically I have changed so many times
and anyone around here that says they've
only grown organic is pretty much full
of crap I mean when we were younger we
didn't know shit you know we put
Osmocote on the bottom of it they the
ground in the middle of nowhere with
drip lines I didn't know I use bro more
you know I'm at least two literally dip
our hands in avid like we didn't know
any of this stuff from your younger and
so I would do that evolution of just
using whatever I was taught for years
GHP
you know lots of different stuff I mean
it wasn't good I'm not gonna but when
you don't know any of this you're
younger you're just trying to produce
and get a certain amount of yield and
you know for your boss and make everyone
happy you're just listening to people
that's what you do as you learned you
know and I mean obviously my dad wasn't
happy with any of that that's for damn
sure but uh as we evolved you know I
definitely started going back and do
I've always the raised beds or pots you
know I have planted you know auger holes
right into the ground but you know we
just use you know the usual the worm the
chicken shit
you know the basics lots of bat and
stuff like that and you know you know
I'll tell you right now is if you say
you know everything and growing then you
know then you're never gonna
you're never gonna aren't gonna move on
here can you get better what you do and
I've always listened I learned and
advice from other people and in this
industry it changes so much growing but
the knowledge has changed so much and
this year what I'm doing you know last
year we tried certain things you know
and and I liked it it worked
good but I have some friends that you
know we were childhood friends roommate
baby just quickly can you talk about
some of the things you tried last year
and kind of what I use a lot of MOCA use
doctor hurts and chicken shit and phone
real and I'm saying into my dirt I'm n
my beds really tough with all kinds of
great nutrients so my bands have enough
stuff and I my first work honestly I
probably barely need to feed it but then
I start powering on all kinds of
organics you know last year I did try
some new stuff with green grow and tried
some of their products I had a I got
really lucky I had a really good friend
I fish with Oh have a good friend it
fish with that that is a tea guru and
last year is my first year to really
learn how to do tea which I still don't
know shit
honestly I'm not number 10 like I did
but I know what to put in because what
he told me because I listen but I know
what to put in you know and in these tea
and they brew tea for the whole run and
so talk about kind of some of the things
he tried to drill into your head in my
head it's basically how long you breathe
key it's what you put in the tea
everything you put in take somes 24
hours some 32 hours I mean it goes on
and on it's the amount I mean people
right there's tons of books on this
probably I mean I'm just saying it's
evolving there's too much for me to
learn in a year so he he gave me his
recipe and that was mostly for the
grouse stage so I use that my plants
grew they look like celery they grew so
fast my starts that were in five inch
pots were I mean it was like I mean they
grew like bean pulls away I've never
seen nothing like it
I was really excited and then when it
came to the bloom stage he didn't really
give me that so then I had to start
digging I started going with some green
grow I started going some root stuff
they have this turkeys and this
bounty bounty makes teas and sigh sorry
I mean you could go in the stores and he
can buy premade teas for a lot of money
or you could buy just you know the right
ingredients I spent $200 and I still
have stuff from that and at the end of
last year I could tell you right now my
yields were down and my quality was up
so I mean you you could smoke and I was
told this from a few the judges you
could smoke the joint all the way down
to the bottom of the roach and it still
tasted good and I I think that was from
the tea honestly and so now this year
what I was trying to do is like I was
saying with the roots is these are two
really good long time old friends I've
known them my whole life
you know they're their new gene Oregon
they're in a whole different area and I
remember them coming here cuz they had a
gross tour is mostly like a fish store
back then
and so they came here probably 12 to 15
years ago and they sat down and they
were just tripping on all the weed grown
here and just how this you know are
basically canvas culture we live in and
I was we were thriving and they won't
you know they're excited about it and so
to me it was really special about it
we all went all the way around and we
met right here and said let's work
together why are we not working together
and so one of my best friends which he's
like one of the main guys he produces
their products he is a genius he talks
to me and I don't understand half the
stuff you saying
but basically helping me with this
organic recipes and you know I'm using a
lot of their products around it is I
mean it's fun for me it's a whole new
thing I've new strains of new product
and you know that's a lot when you know
what you do you know how to do it and I
know I'd be fine doing what I've been
doing for the last ten years
you know I say that because I've
switched so many times the last ten
years I'm just drawing with you know the
regular
greedy incised it's a lot to really do
that in trust and other people
especially when I have some of the eyes
on me to to grow really quality product
so but anyways so now I'm doing a whole
new different feeding regimen I'm using
the same dirt I'm adding a lot of the
same stuff to the dirt and I'm used it
doing a lot these a lot of new strains
and it's besides out and he said
intuition of knowing okay well my plant
looks like there's too much nitrogen in
it you know I could I could tell that
before I sent off to him to the lab
because when I read tests we've never
never tested my weed once I never tested
my dirt it all just started happening
now you know we didn't test for THC we
smoke the weed you got really high high
THC you know it wasn't it's just one of
these things like coming from me and I
mean I can see you know Kevin and Chris
it's like this is our life we've been
doing this our whole life so you know
people were ahead of us on the indoor
game like that you know co2 and this and
that
yes yeah - we had big old diamond lights
you know we you know big old bulbs and
it did we're behind the technology but
we all its inner it's our heritage it's
what we've been doing we know how to
grow we know the plant so we don't even
need all that technology you know so we
get actually we're so lucky that I can I
could skip around and I can grow other
food that I personally know is good and
do it in the same way that I've kind of
been doing it and I have a feeling it's
the turn out good and I mean right now
my crops look amazing I mean I've stocks
that are giant which sometimes sometimes
scare me because the Giants stock at a
depth plant isn't always the biggest but
right now it's starting to stack and
everything is looking really really good
yeah it's just you know for me it's
excitement you know and you know winning
cups and all that that's definitely
fired me up having you know one of my
best friends in the world Chris watching
him his business
watching so many of my really close
friends take this this journey we're on
right now and run with it you know cuz
you know it wasn't really it's kind of a
half half split around here probably
even less probably a 30/70 of people
that went the way that we went and you
know really it was a pretty scary scary
move that we did you know go from
outlaws to you know be out in the public
and Beyond The New Yorker give
interviews and you know tell your life I
mean it definitely wasn't easy so I'm
saying all of this type of stuff is what
is getting me excited and keeping me
going and this this way I mean I I love
the plant I love growing I'm a very
small scale farmer still and that's fine
with me you you know I mean I'd rather
do quality over quantity any day of the
week you know all day all day so you
have a big ol filing cabinet behind you
is that for all your paperwork you have
to do now there's so much paperwork it's
yeah that part of the game now you're
gonna bum me out
see now you're crying I'm dressing a
part of the conversation leave metric I
wanted to hire someone but my wife
wanted to take that on well it's not the
best thing for a relationship is metric
they'll tell you right now but yeah the
county the paperwork we had a hard three
years and you know right now we're still
battling and I mean I've up stuff with
the county that I've been working on for
three years straight the easiest stuff
you would think would be like let's just
get it done and it's just not done you
know so yeah the paperwork is a
nightmare but we're all starting to
settle in and figure out where we're at
in this game and how you know how it's
gonna pan out and we know that hey we
are essential right we know that I mean
it's amazing right now you know and
what's happening in this time and not
people love wheat and
it blows my mind right now seeing how
much weed is out there and the demand
for our weed is just as high as ever you
know and that's you know like when I
scroll through Instagram and you know
I'm looking pretty much everything on my
Instagram is weed because you know let's
let's really follow and you'll come
across giant green houses that are you
know I don't know can I don't know were
they 20,000 square foot green Alice's
maybe even bigger with just lights and
this not I school right through that I
don't even I don't care about that I
look at like a plant and some small farm
and you see little veggies around and
just a beautiful bud and that's what I
want to look at I mean the rest of its
just like Rose a weed I don't really I
don't care they're probably feeding it
tons of salts and crap and it just
doesn't really mean anything to me and I
know because I know what's the best and
that's really what comes back to the
consumers it's not fair a lot of them
don't know what is what they're smoking
what they're putting in their body out
there you know are you doing what to
turn to your idea - I didn't today a lot
of people you know that people come up
here you can set these up you put like
you go all year round like I need a
break and I have kids I have a life I
wanted education I wanna know life's
fast you know I got a 16 year old and 11
year old and yeah I don't need to go
around all year this is this is plenty I
mean we've been doing it like all year
our whole life I mean we grow indoor and
your outdoor indoor outdoor
indoor/outdoor so to be able to change
get rid of the indoor throw keep on you
know growing beautiful full Sun and you
know with our climate it's just it's
it's worked out great you know I mean
laughs you never know what the weather
is gonna hear last year we probably
could have done a third round it's you
know stay beautiful for longer but it's
fine with me man it's it's plenty of
weed and you really have to put all your
energy into it if you really want the
product that
want to give to the consumer I I'm
looking at the chat on YouTube and a
brass Sakhalin said I'd go as far as
this a bag appeal is set Canada's back
with bullshit breeding goals so Chris
can you talk about like you know you're
you're on Jason's farm a lot can you
talk about kind of I mean I know you you
hung up the cleats as a grower so I want
to talk about nice so what do you what
do you what are you running at home
right now then let's see I've been
playing with I got a bunch of genetics
that I actually like years ago and then
I got up this crucial og seed from this
dude up in Harris the prodigy up - so
I'm like 25 years ago one of the dudes
there's like 10 people that claim they
brought it up there whatever wherever it
came from I don't care I'm not a an OG
ajita
that actually ended I planted it is a
back seat and that being a male so I
started pollinating all these different
genetics with that one male that I got
so and then I've been pulling mammals
out a lot to pollinate stuff every year
but so there's it's six different six
plants six different strains they're all
like crosses of this og there's a got a
fruit loop seed from Johnny
Casali I got an XJ there's a milk and
cookie seed that hyleri from LA gave me
at San Bernardino High Times cup like
four years ago
there's a train rub purple Oracle train
Red Cross it's stupid stupid stupid fire
I'm gonna start to trickle these out
next year they're starting to stabilize
finally so should be some good stuff
coming out but uh last year I grew my
first 12 pounder haha
see ya get into the in terms of or what
were you asking about Jason's farm
you've watched him so what
what have you seen with kind of the
evolution of his journey whether its
cultivation style or running a
professional small operation or well I
really really really am stoked he
transitioned over to teas I did I made
that move myself seven or eight years
ago and then I haven't been growing much
or for the last few years but it went
from spending however much money on
plastic bottles for it'll full of
fertilizer to 50-pound bags of
amendments into a brew tank and the cost
of goods dropped tremendously terpene
profiles shot out the fucking roof so
I'm a I'm a firm believer and auntie's
and I'm super stoked jason has trans
transition that direction for sure man
I'm all over the place though III
unfortunately I would like to spend more
time with Jason on this farm but I mean
I've been there three or four times this
year and and I what I can say is that
his crop this year looks phenomenal
so whatever the hell he's doing this
year is good so that the roots organic
decision and that relationship is has so
far proven to be a good one and you know
I really appreciate what you said Jason
about the honesty of where we've came
from in terms of our practices out there
in the hills and all these people up
here up and so on and humbled and in the
Admiral Triangle trying to be all
righteous about organic and stuff which
we should be now at this point and we
should be pushing that and we should all
be growing organic but anybody like
Jason said that claims that so they've
been doing for forever is a bunch of
crap so we're all learning we're all
evolving we're all trying to be better
people and do better things we were
young and dumb and trying to make a
bunch of money and it didn't you know
though not everybody was that there's a
lot of conscious you know earthy people
up there the
have always been that way and didn't you
use blue juice grow more and spray of it
or and they didn't do that but there's a
big percentage of people up there that
certainly did so I appreciate the
honesty and the candidness there and the
again were were we're here the standards
our face ourselves in the mirror about
our our prior lives and how we can
improve our current actions in this
world jason has kids you know he's going
to leave this farm to his kids and so a
piece of property is super important to
him and keeping it clean and and then
like he also said that you know I
believe the education to consumers for
sure some of it certainly should be
pointed as Jason said towards what are
you putting into your body and if
consumers knew I think a lot of them
maybe they just don't care they're
eating McDonald's anyway you know so
maybe the most consumers don't care but
the ones that do we don't grow enough
pot to feed all the consumers anyway
so let's find those consumers that do
care because there are enough of them
that do care they just don't know where
to find us yet they're they're finding
us slowly but surely but so anyway
Jason's farm is absolutely beautiful
it's been incredible to watching the
evolution of him as a businessman and
and community leader and a farmer as
well it's not just the cannabis
evolution we're like you know we're
growing up and gotten our eyes and
crossing our T's and becoming real real
life businessmen which is a cool thing
to you know we're stepping up to the
plate as a community on that level so
and Kevin certainly been leading that
charge absolutely no hot air they're
like you you took it seriously to the
professional level from the get-go when
this 215 kicked I kicked off and a large
percentage of the people I know weren't
into that yet and in fact believe I've
always believed in the medicine but
we're anti any kind of regulation or
legality
so the fact that he took the initiative
and became a leader in our community and
in the cannabis community and and has
been driving a major driving force and
that is super inspirational to me and
and you know I felt like I kind of
stepped out of the closet pretty early
and so huh but Kevin was in that shit
ten years before me so kudos to that for
leading the charge and kind of opening
the door for the rest of us you know
they lived that old life to be
comfortable more comfortable maybe not
comfortable but a little more
comfortable stepping into this new life
so it's it's an exciting time for for me
and for for us man I really believe we
made the right decision and decisions
heading this direction I just believe it
with every fragment of my being the
indicators currently are proving that to
be so what when you say this direction
do you mean going into the legal legal
market okay so yes sir so given that all
three of you are long-term cultivators
and operating in in the joyful
California legal cannabis system Chris
you were when we started touching on
business you were talking about kind of
the wholesale or the bulk so can you
talk about the evolution of your vision
from like because at one point you were
growing and you decided entering a legal
market that did you were you growing
when you first entered the legal market
absolutely and what stopped me from
cultivating is the police coming to my
farm know I had a collective I had a
patient base the Mendocino County was
dragging their feet in their ordinance
in place and
so I focus all my my energy on my
commercial piece of property in Benton
bow and my distribution retail
manufacturing nursery permit permits
that I filed with Humboldt County for
that piece of property and kept on
cultivating because I had a patient base
and a collective and I was feeding
patients medicine men see no County then
finalized their ordinance and I didn't
have the bandwidth to do it all and I
was focused on the Bembo property and I
really little I mean like 4,000 square
feet little and I'm at the very very
very very very very northern tip with
Mendocino County knowing what they would
have to fly over a drive-by to come to
my house where I live how's my
grandparents built and they decided to
drive two and half hours from Ukiah with
35 people to bust my 4,000 square-foot
farm driving by acres and acres and
acres of illegal pot with no collective
or patient base so fuck you Mendocino
County and fuck you fucking fishing game
for doing that what what year what year
was that the reality is it I honed of
skill in over this fucking crazy life of
finding the silver lining and the silver
lining in that was that I didn't go to
jail and I focused 100% of my energy on
my commercial piece of property in Bembo
and getting this distribution thing off
the ground and if I wouldn't have done
that I would still be spread out I would
still be all over the place I wouldn't
have focused I wouldn't have honed in on
something and so that was the beginning
of the honing and the evolution and the
or the whatever
you want to call it from that period to
now has been keeping my ears wide open
listening sponging watching not talking
and seeing what all these other entities
were doing and the mistakes they were
making and having conversations more so
for intelligence with really big
investors and and listening to them and
and having them kind of guide and and
say well Wow and maybe you should do
this or maybe you should do that so
maybe you shouldn't do all that maybe
you should do this one thing and do it
really well some investors conversations
will know that's the right thing to do
you need 10 mil today you need 20
million that million isn't enough you
need 20 million right now let me force
it down your face you need to grow fast
and all I got to say to that is that's
the wrong strategy and slow steady and
organic has proven to be the way for
redwood roots I'm not saying that any
other way is right or wrong for anyone
else but I know what's worked for us and
you know we still have our eyes on
retail we still have our eyes on
delivery we still have our eyes on
maybe nursery certainly have our eyes on
processing as a distribution company we
know how crucial processing is any-any
and i saw that coming two years ago I
just haven't had the capital or the
funding or the bandwidth to get ahead of
the game but I saw this second coming
years ago I knew exactly where this was
going and but you know we don't have to
listen to anybody tell us what to do or
where to spend our money or how to grow
we get to do that on our own
and at the same time as listen to what
other people have to say in their
opinions of where we should go and what
we should do but at the end of the day
we get to make our calls and make that
decision for ourselves so sorry I'm kind
of rambling now but hey Chris talk a
little bit more about the economics of
bulk versus branded or retail and what
you're seeing out there both gets
farmers paid immediately if they're
working with the right distributor ha
some distributors not so much so retail
is brutal it is fucking brutal it's
cutthroat it is people are straight
Corporate America America modelling
under pricing to get market share and
putting little guys at trying to put
little guys out sell an $8 fucking AIDS
fuck you ain't the way to fucking play
and just so we know like what we're
talking about how many forms are you
like distributing for and getting their
product out there for probably this year
we sold product from 120 farms the next
year I bet it will be 240 and I assume
you started with kind of the farms that
were all your friends like a Jason and
you're fulfilling a need for him because
what what I've seen and you know a lot
of friends who are up in the hills or
wherever it's like you're at the total
mercy of some distributor who just
doesn't give a shit about you who's then
gonna take your product and bring it to
a shop that doesn't give a shit about
you and you know you don't have the time
to get off the farm and so to have
somebody who I'm talking about the two
of you who you've known for a long time
who you trust who's out there trying to
do right by you must be I mean Jason
that must be a godsend to have Chris as
someone you deal with rather than you
know random distributors
cold calling you and wanting to strike
deals I mean 100% it's like you said I
mean the wholesale market is easy you
know it's it's easy to get paid but you
know we really I got really lucky you
know obviously to get my name out the
way I did I mean it started with Kevin
at the golden tarps 2017 you know I got
the win there with the Green Lantern and
it started rolling from there
so yeah the wholesale works for anyone
and it's quick it's you know you saw
your weed you get some so and so they
get to claim your wonderful grown herb
and put on the shelf as theirs and you
know that's that's great I mean you get
paid and you know your family gets gets
the eat and it all works but it's really
about making the right decisions and
it's when you don't know what you're
doing you know I don't really want to
put out too many names out there but
it's like when I first won the Cup and I
went with you know
well corner let's just say you know I
don't have much bad to say about him but
I didn't really know you know I've Chris
my best friend you know he's doing his
thing and I was so excited you know I
was like oh my god maybe I could get out
there this is really happening I didn't
know what what route to go I was more
acting on excitement and and you know so
I had to learn right and you know I did
a little thing with them and honestly it
was great
they didn't be right but I wasn't
feeling it I didn't feel it my sword I
felt my heart didn't really make me feel
great
what made me feel good was showing up
the Emerald Cup this year with a bunch
of my best friends that I personally
know our amazing farmers and what they
do is real and who they are is real the
product they produce is is the best that
I mean I've seen my soul right there I
already won our booth was fucking
amazing we had the best group of people
and
so yeah I mean happens some I mean doing
this journey with Chris we both talk B
both when this all started unrolling you
know one of my things I was tripping out
Mike welcome girl weed my whole life
like dad was gonna weed his little life
I mean it's just this is our life
this isn't we aren't just jumping in we
aren't 2017 we started what we this is
our life and I started feeling like oh
my gosh this balls rolling what's
happening we're just going to all get
pushed out of our fucking heritage it's
gone you know and and it was scary but I
knew there was something deeper I
remember one of the first days sitting
around with Chris was coming up with
this redwood roots and we're all
deciding if we were gonna sign like
basically these affidavits with the
county and a lot of people said if we
sign this or that we're gonna get fuckin
we're admitting everything and we're
gonna probably you audit it and go to
jail you know I mean we didn't know what
the hell is going on so basically you
know go through this journey and having
friends like Chris to be able to console
in and talk in and then obviously work
with is a blessing
I mean without them I'd feel alone and
know like I said I'd have a lot of
friends that feel different about all
this you know they want the whole other
route and you know I still hope the best
for them you know I don't I don't ever
want to see somebody go to jail for
marijuana ever and I hope everybody stay
an outlaw you do fine it's nothing wrong
with that I feel for me the position I'm
in I feel like I was meant to be in this
position I feel like Chris was meant to
be in this position and there's a lot of
other people and our that were meant to
be in this position um you know I'm
excited to work with Chris I went he
basically watching him like you know we
were I was still growing weed I was
still making money I was surviving I
mean I watched him give up everything
and basically go deep deep in the hole
and work his ass off and had so many
people not believed what he was going to
do was going to really work out
I didn't believe it I fuckin knew he was
gonna do it because you hear him talk
it's like you have that passion that
drive you know that will to not give up
you're gonna win you're gonna make it
and so I'm not surprised how you know
where he is or what he's doing and I'm
so fuckin happy he is where he is
because he is helping out so many
farmers so many families and I mean
we're talking people that were there's
so many people that were with these big
corporations like you said the guy
handed millions of dollars and all my
god is great well who are they calling
now my boy you know they're calling him
up you know come help us out and I
guarantee you know getting paid from a
community a small business a family-run
business
it feels so much better than getting a
check from cement corporation it really
does and you know it's like I said it's
hard I still and I still have things
going on here and there where it's like
it's just the right decision or not the
right decision because I do want to stay
relevant you know I do want to be out
there and have my name out there and you
know there's a lot of these big
companies that will help that happen but
at the same time you have to kind of
work with with you know wait what your
heart and soul but what you feel good
about you know I mean I'm I'm 40 I'm
growing weed my whole life and I've been
blessed you know you're doing a job with
something you enjoy your whole life I
mean what more could ask so at this
point I'm just gonna keep you know
trying to you know I I'm not I've
relationships also with humble Fran you
know there's another group there's
another small business you know it's
like staying local keep you spreading my
love out there you know given we did
this person that person is great and I
mean Chris kind of went more to the
wholesale thing which I wanted to do
some of but to keep the ridge line name
out there and keep it growing I need to
be on shelves and I'll tell you like he
said it is a cutthroat game it cost some
it's money I'm finally getting my first
jars out this next month and it's been
like a year and a half
thousands of dollars so so you were you
are just bringing your brand to market
no no my brand I've been co-branding
with everyone you know okay you have
Ridgeline with all kinds of people but
actually make some of my own jars which
I'm still I'm gonna do these jars oh man
they are beautiful but do you have one
I'll show ya but I'm gonna actually get
to drop this special jar with my my
buddy Chris and we're gonna do that pie
next month and so to be able to you know
because I could still make it but he has
the connections and he's doing the
legwork and so you know for me to be
able to grow the weed put it in the jars
that I design give it to one of my best
friends and he gets to go out and
distribute it to people and make people
happy and I mean it just it's a
beautiful thing so how many pounds are
are you produced do you think you'll
produce this year you know I'd like to
say I like to tell you right now
whenever anyone looks my greenhouse and
says man that you're gonna kill it how
much is that uh you know I do not
project I know the average I mean let's
just say a thousand somewhere in there
but you'd never know rowing weed you can
look at my stuff right now it's the most
beautiful greenhouses but growing parts
easy for once those bugs start throwing
once they start swelling Oh
how does Aurora greenhouse for the
projections going yeah exactly
oh all of a sudden there's a fucking
storm it's like let's say last year all
of a sudden there's a storm oh shit
beautiful bud start molding or all of a
sudden you have a fence or rust it might
sir you know we as farmers we're dealing
with all kinds of shit that nobody out
there knows oh your readings good who
reads bad they don't realize that there
is tons with all these new strains we're
getting these strains from
different parts of the state come new
bugs new diseases and big fucking no
hammer you you know I just having very
close friendlies three beautiful
greenhouses had to throw them all out
for force arienne well I mean this is
we're talking a silent killer this is a
sport you can't see this is I mean this
is a basically a corona of of weed so we
go through a lot of shit as farmers when
you want to I would hope I hope to get
you know average out of a 80-footer I
mean you you always want to get a pound
of foot you want to get 80 pounds I'd
like to get 145 a greenhouse you know I
mean the max I usually do in a 20 by 80
is around 137 to 140 so I mean that's
kind of you know I know my max I know
what I want but you can't it's it's not
about what you want in this game you
just got it you got it we aren't working
indoors we aren't working with you know
co2 s and air conditioners working with
the climate or you know we're working
like we're outside there is there's all
kinds of stuff outside to ruin a farmer
quick so we just have to knock on wood
do our best and grow the best we can and
I'm yeah you know I think as it right
now
it's looking good and that's you know
now I'm just waiting for these buds keep
swelling and hope all these fucking
weird genetics I'm running turn into
some big old buds and not some killer
little purple dime-sized nug you never
know never know so of what you'll
harvest this year what percentage of it
do you think will go into your your
branded product versus all coal sale I
mean I definitely I like to make a leaf
but at least you know yeah like I like
half of it you know at least and you
know it's stuff like I don't know I mean
I definitely look at what looks the best
I mean I want the best
me to open up my jar and look at that
bud and be like wow that is a beautiful
weed you know I mean I literally I'll
never forget when I when that first big
drop happen and I'd these people waiting
for some of my weed and forever writing
me on Instagram and it was in those flow
con jars and then he sent me this
picture he opened it up and these little
shitty nurdles of weed were in this hand
and I was just I wanted to drive to him
and hand him a bag of weed like so
basically I want I want the best if it's
my half assed lookit so what's funny is
someone on the chats that I tried Flo
Connor wants blueberry muffins from
Bryce line and it's smoked like it was
stored in a car for a year no no to say
about that because they they do grow
some good herb but you know if you over
by you herb and you know got the door
and it's in a little jar for a long
fucking time well the Crosley excuse me
that daughter in there them cussing away
but yeah let's get here good yeah no I
mean you know it's kind of that comes
out also to the distributor you know you
hope a distributor is gonna put a
beautiful mug in a jar and not put some
disc crappy little buds in the jar
because these consumers are paying a lot
of money and I'll tell you right now
that money is not barely any of us going
to us okay you know if there's so many
middleman you know the state there's so
many middlemen that you know there I
feel for how much of consumers have to
pay for a quality product it's not fair
and it's not the growers reaping those
those benefits not even probably ten
percent of it honestly Chris you're
primarily focused on bulk now sore are
you gonna be bringing Jason's product to
this hit his brand his CPG brand product
to market or are you gonna stay focused
on bolt like
you're gonna mix it up do a little of
both no I said before we're
transitioning a pretty good chunk of our
energy back towards retail in the brand
both redwood roots brand and a very
limited select group of farmer brands
like Jason's Ridgeline we just got we're
very honoured at the opportunity to to
work on a very small level with the
farmer farmers cut which is I think
Emeril grown coops I believe it's their
their new brand but Daniel Stein from
Bryson forest mARMS Happy Days KC O'Neal
and then I'm down Elm Farms I'm up in
the Grass Valley area are the three
first kind of flagship farms that are
participating with the brand but it's a
co-op grown the the packaging is just
fucking beautiful it's like a kind of
like a not hand scissors trim but
literally like hand leaf trimmed buds in
a half ounce jar and then there's a
couple other farm brands son love farms
we got some pot of his in jars already
green light farms 7:07 we've got some of
his herb audience of jars we have a
bunch of conversations going that have
been going now for quite some time
see it's planted year or two years ago
even with some of these conversations
but some collab projects some collab
projects for some news Hughes for
Redwood roots some some concentrate
lines some tincture some tincture lines
South health and wellness lines we're
going to be ramping up the brand redwood
roots brand and start starting to get to
retail here over the course of the
summer leading into next fall we're
looking at our strategy is is hone in on
a very limited small number select group
of shops that are already representing
brands like ours that are willing to pay
the price let the consumers come get the
pot and then it'll spread slowly and
organically from those kind of retail
locations and then we can spread out and
go from there but I we feel like we're
not going into every 12 dollar wholesale
eight to spend
three and trying to get into 600 shops
we're gonna try to get into 50 shops and
they're all going to be high-end high
price shops it will pay the price to get
these farmers the money they deserve and
let it grow slow in organic we'll have
some some budget skews to get into those
other shops they don't want to pay what
we want to you know pay that the price
that we want to charge so we'll have
some some budget outs half ounce eight
smalls Duff trim
you know the whole pouch idea
everybody's going after the small shit
now it's what I see and what I'm hearing
is concentrates have lost their muster a
little bit our live residents still the
thing but there's people like raw garden
that are pushing it out for $10 a gram
or some crazy shit so there'd it's that
that market is it's all over the place
it's super fucking difficult to put your
finger on it and even even contemplate
where it's going whereas all these other
SKUs are a little more settled I feel
like at least for right now and so we're
we're definitely going to go back after
retail for sure and Jason's Jason's new
jars are the inspiration to get back at
it and that the booth that the Emerald
cup that we had in the you know eight
out of the ten top winners are people we
represent 13 out of the top 20 winners
are people we represent so to to let
that opportunity slide it would be
fucking lunatic so we we have you know
we got a bunch of urban jars right after
the cup and did a little launch locally
and got into Sonoma area blah blah blah
and and then the reality is that you
know bootstraps grassroots that's a real
thing we don't just have a bunch of
capital to do it with to do it all
we just don't and our margins we're
making a little bit of money selling
bulk wholesale and and again able to get
these farmers paid real quick and and
the money they're asking in and so that
keeps the boat floating we
bill and I've always believed that shelf
space in the brand is the long game and
that wholesale getting farmers paid and
getting up just giving us the ability to
to survive this hurricane and hunker
down and and and just like Jason said
keep the brands relevant on some level
but I mean ridgelines not going to be in
every shop in the state that ever he
doesn't grow enough pot you know even if
he put his whole thousand pounds in his
jars that's gonna get into maybe a
hundred shops if you want to service
those hundred shops all year and once
you get into a shop you don't ever want
to lose that shelf space so there's a
lot of farmers with brands that think
they're gonna go do it and build it and
I hope the best worm but I don't think
it's a good strategy for them at this
point in time I think it's it's way too
competitive they're slotting fees still
out there there's no farmers that can
afford a slotting fee are you kidding me
so I still know that the brand is the
long game but we we also just need to
keep our community alive and and
surviving these times and so I really
believe that we're still in another wave
of hunkering yeah we're gonna go to
retail but we're not going big it's not
time to go big yet it's just not it's
time to hunker and fucking settle and
hone in your processes and your
procedures and your team and just get
fucking Titus fucking all hell and then
you can keep going to battle with these
big fuckers because that's what it's
really about we got ten people on our
staff
we're buying new vans we're hiring more
employees we're not firing 40% of our
staff and selling our vans and we're
gonna continue to grow slow and steady
and pick the right partners and be super
fucking conscious and careful about what
we do this is our money we're not
playing with somebody else's fucking
money this isn't R&amp;D money out of some
bench
capitalist fund that's literally
$200,000 of R&amp;D money that could just
fucking vanish and they don't give a
fuck this is our fucking life all of our
lives not just me not just Jason there's
a community of people up where we live
and I'm not just so um I'm not so um
centric there used to be this soem thing
it's like we're all the same people in
the Murrell triangle all of us are the
same we're all trying to make it we're
all trying to survive doing what we love
to do we just want to stay where we live
where we love you know now I'm rambling
again but so you know Chris one of the
themes that's come through in in in
almost all the discussions we've had
lately is that in the in the current
environment smaller operations companies
they're maybe a little more flexible or
better able to survive than the larger
ones with more overhead what do you
think about that well like I said we're
hiring on staff and buying vans and
expanding slowly but surely and I all I
hear from those bigger entities is
implosion implosion implosion left right
left right one after another so I don't
think those companies are all gonna
vanish those big guys but I don't know I
think there could be there's a big shake
I'm going on I don't I mean some of
those companies are so big they're just
they're gonna somebody even bigger than
them is gonna buy them and just throw
more money at it and I mean yeah I don't
know man I just I feel like it's the
proof is in the pudding about how to you
know how to get where you're trying to
go and it's just this this market is too
unsettled it's it's no one still know
anybody that says that they know what's
going to happen I'll punch him in the
throat because they're just wrong they
are in any business model when they
don't know what's going to happen unless
they have money to throw away out it is
going to just go crazy big and
it's just not the right thing and so
we're very genuine and real about our
grassroots nests and who knows maybe
we'll take investors I'm not trying to
say we'll never take an investment or
partner with the venture capitalist firm
or some corporation Patagonia is a
pretty cool corporation you know what I
mean there's cool there's good people
doing good things out there in the world
with their with their business so we're
not in any hurry to go there and it
would certainly have to be the right
partner but for right now we're we're
pretty we're pretty not comfortable
comfortably uncomfortable maybe it might
be a right way to say it I'm very
humbled and I'm this is not me but I'm
really confident in our community and
where we are today and what we're
bringing to the table I am I'm really
confident I think you know we've been
talking about interstate international
forever but there's a generation in
SoCal which is the biggest market in the
world as we know it doesn't even know
what Humboldt County is or where it's
from or they're no triangle no never
care and they don't care and those are
not our people the further away from
Humboldt County you get the more
Humboldt County has a name because you
asked somebody in Australia cannabis you
ask somebody in Spain you got somebody
in fucking China they're gonna say
Humboldt County that's what they still
say and so there's plenty of high-end
consumers across the world an interstate
that will pay us the price point and get
you your money Jason and Kevin and so
it's slow steady let's sell the book
let's get you paid let's keep the
fucking boat floating let's get the
brands relevant let's be really slow and
cautious and steady and by the time
interstate international opens we'll be
sitting pretty and we'll be ready to
fucking crush well so that gets
through the Appalachian conversation
which is uh which is happening right now
so what for the three of you what are
your I mean obviously to say it's it's
grown in Humboldt is one thing but that
doesn't guarantee anything so do the
three of you put any weight on the
concept of Appalachian when when
Appalachians personally came into this
concept right I have a kid named Lou
Bruner working for me who was a
brilliant young dude and he had done all
this extensive research on how
Appalachians add value and so when I got
to talk to senator McGuire at my office
and we had a conversation and said hey
how do I help you in in your area and I
said listen for what we need long term
we need some kind of certification that
says organically produced because USDA
won't give it to us and we need an
appellation of origin so that we can
start to have brand value because our
regions like even even not just humble
but like Santa Cruz Grass Valley
Trinity mando humble we're all known for
producing really high quality cannabis
and it may not be important in
California but it sure the fuck is
important outside of California and so I
had this opportunity to speak to him and
that was really the initial conversation
of our operations with politicians and
Maguire watch that shit and so what
happens next as we get into the whole
Appalachian program and the
international canvass Farmers
Association starts to really go at it
and they start trying to form all the
pieces and now we've had all these
different hearings that we had our
moment to make comment the origins
Council achene Coleman got heavily
involved in it because they're they're
far more developed in their in their
direction of how they want to apply it
but for us the long term the value is
priceless and people argue about it
because they say no one cares but that's
not true that people do care and it's
just that when you look at your market
as a neighborhood market then that's not
we were selling where we're trying to
have a global market and Humboldt County
has a global market ability just like
the other regions I mentioned and so for
Jason and Fatah
you know Jason's internationally
recognized as a cultivator and and and
the one thing I gotta tell you to write
is that what you gotta remember is my
mom was a brilliant scientist and she
said to me there was a quote from
Einstein but it said that intuition is
the is the epitome of all genius that
it's the ultimate expression of genius
the scientists have to study what people
do to understand it but they don't
necessarily create it and so you're a
really good representation of that and
many of people like you in Humboldt
where your career knowledgeable that
transcends science because ultimately
how the fuck did you went back to back
cups if you're not good right so-so and
you got you got dudes at Noble County
and Trinity and that's the cultivators
to understand especially young common
top cultivators because you have to
believe you can make an impact you have
to believe you have a chance you have to
believe that within the world of
cannabis you could be somebody too
because our desire was always to live
this life forever and as we go into this
new phases that everything seems to be
so doom and fucking blue because all the
cats that are coming in with buckets of
money but that doesn't mean the customer
wants the product and so appellations
are things that protect brand value and
like Toph was saying none of us
I'm only 20,000 square feet right so
I'll never put enough jars it enough
store to be in other stores where I'm at
but I never intended to I wanted to be
able to put the jars in the places where
they were most desired and I wanted
people bill appreciate that product and
and as a group we're under an umbrella
where Hubble County farmers and our
individual Appalachians will help
dictate expression to the consumer of
say a gentleman's ship that he chooses
comes out this way we like it and Toph
has other farmers and he grabbed some
calves stuff does this it'll become a
recognition like all
azar people just don't walk around
blindly they do in modern cannabis
because they haven't had any time to be
able to practice playing and by and in
these legal markets but as time goes on
it will and you're 40 I'm 54 but none of
this stuff is really for me my time was
in 40 year prior when I was in the paint
this is for my kids so like it's easy
for me to do this shit now because I
know what I'm doing it for I'm doing it
specifically in further my region
further my crew further my children and
and that's the part that appellations
has the value and it's the part that
that cultivators have to understand that
humble County Mendo Trinity these are
regions where people been doing this
multi generationally and they have a
feel for the product that science has to
understand it doesn't mean that a
premium agronomist isn't a brilliant guy
and they don't do phenomenal work but
you you you have to understand that
aren't science is separate and that arts
art and so what you see is a lot of art
and and that's where this Appalachian
stuff comes into play and before I
forget too when we were talking about
trends and heritage strains you got to
remember that the cats are to buy an
herb now did the smoked cigarettes they
smoked fake pens so their flavor
addicted and so they they're at their
introduction to consumption of small
bubbles was flavored vape pens that
never happened in the whole history of
dope smoking tobacco and forms of
tobacco with it with it with the
interconnection between smoke right so
this group that comes in now is all vape
pen so what they want is flavors because
that's what they know they don't they
and then it's the trend goes by we'll be
able to reintroduce him to the earthy
things that were pop when we used to
just grow herb but until until this they
get saturated with their desires being
fulfilled to make them happy with what
they could soo-min a vape pen that's
what's gonna be the trend because all
the fruits all the citruses all that
shit all the stuff coming from oil that
changed people's profile of what they
wanted to smoke and need because it was
so fucking intense in the mouth that
they became disappointed and
and so they had to start steer the
profiles in the flour into that
expression to get the customers to come
back in the flour but that's a trend
that's that'll tattle turn around over
time too and that's why it's important
to Bank varieties where you're going to
hold the genetics so that you can go
reintroduce them into the market when it
comes time but right now like I used you
as an example the other day about
heritage strains didn't speech Russell
look if people gave a fuck now and Jason
killed it what the white runs right why
why did that win when it was heritage
people judging it so there were people
that you know Swami judging it Swami
seventy fuckin seven his birthday um he
smoked about as much air as anyone on
earth and he was uh he was a really a
fat ik you know champion of your variety
because he said hey the quality was just
fuckin superlative that's that's the
important part is that transition should
change the regional influence has an
impact and us as a cultural influence
has an impact and all the regions around
California and and and for me anywhere
in the United States and globally if
your area produces something equality
and the people are minded to produce
something equality take advantage of
what we did here in California with the
Appalachians and start to protect your
brand for globalization because
ultimately it's going to have a value
and if you get your hands into it before
someone makes it impossible to you do
better on a community level and that's
what we need is because we are a
community that's the thing is all these
regions people know each other you you
worked off a handshake for years and I
was everybody I know handles a couple
hundred million fucking dollars in cash
that ran through their fingers over
their houses in Korea so when I talk to
these guys in the modern world about
money and business I look at them and
I'm like fuck an ATM card in your pocket
and go cash looks like so it it makes it
hard to have a conversation that makes
sense because they look at all of us
like fuckin Stone Age but we were
actually really competent at the old
business and our understanding what
people like in cannabis is pretty
accurate still you know and and that's
that's the point that's why I said it's
nice to be on the show with you and be
on top because I know
both you guys cuz you good dudes and you
also about you shitting about your
community that's as real as it can
fucking be so do you think someone like
Jason needs Appalachian - I mean
Appalachian is kind of more rigorous
than obviously you know he's in southern
Humboldt or you know wherever someone's
based like it he's already do that
filing cabinet behind Jason has CDFA and
then if he wants to do the organic
comparable he'll have another filing
cabinet for that and then if he wants to
be Appalachian you know origin control a
southern Humboldt specific region he's
gonna have a third filing cabinet as and
how many what's the square footage of
your cultivation is a small as a not raw
garden sized operation it is worth it it
is worth it for you because if you take
a look at our wine moves we put wine in
the right market it's worth five times
more than it is in a regular market so
stuff coming out of Napa sells for four
hundred and now for five hundred in
China because it's got a fucking
appellation on them it's it's about the
long term and the thing is that we're in
the beginning of a process that will go
on forever and so I wish that I was
younger so I could like write this shit
now but I know that I'm doing it for my
kids so that when my children are older
they have a farm that has a specific
impact because ultimately Indore is so
simple even though there's and I argued
about Appalachians for Indore because
you want all cultivators to have a
chance to benefit but ultimately the
outdoor expression in his situation and
then his hand on it combined with
genetics is his thing and if he was the
same as everyone else so why does he
keep on fucking winner
so it's it's one of those things where
the end result answers the question it
says that he's doing something different
because he's running something that
other people had that cut other people
use that dirt other people use
shit but his environment coupled up with
him and the genetics and his choices and
how he operates makes something that's
absolutely exquisite
that's the value so I actually on that
point Chris you you you work with how
many farms like I said currently we've
we've sold herb for about 120 130
farmers this year so far
so you smoke a lot of weed from a lot of
farmers so can you talk about something
that maybe two different farmers grow
the same cut that you've noticed just is
different based on where they're based
can you give a concrete example you know
not all these farmers that are using
each other's formulas and sharing
feeding regiments and whatnot but at the
end of the day it's I think both of
those things are coming into play it's
not just the appellation but yeah the I
mean I don't even I can't even really
think of any specific examples just bump
off the top of my head but I can tell
you that I've seen a lot of the same
cuts from the same nurseries growing
different farms that come out looking
what a different they smell different
they look different they smoke different
so it's Appalachian I think comes into
play what it's grown in what they were
sprayed with what they're fed with how
they cured it how long did they cure it
what temperature they cured it out how
long has it been in a turkey bag was it
in Turkey bag was it in a cardboard box
was it in was it stored underground was
it stored in a garage with no insulation
at 70 degrees there's a million things
that come into play with when it comes
to what that consumer is tasting or how
they're feeling so yeah I've seen it all
over the place for sure it's super
interesting it's very fascinating for
sure yeah so that tells me that that
appellation is going to be really
difficult which we know it's going to be
it is and then it's going to be
localized and really specific so Kevin
how do you think it's gonna work out
what do you think it's gonna look like
on the ground at the end of the day we
don't we don't have the the final regs
in play but the bottom line is that if
you're because what Chris was talking
about that's all part of Appalachian to
Appalachian is is is location process
and we're part of the process but it's
processed genetics and location and
processes all those things we talked
about so say say you're in an adhesion
and what we're saying is that our our
curing process is longer when we take
more time we make sure that the plant
the the product after cutting never goes
over 65 degrees so we don't flare off
any monos and we don't oxidize the
product that's holding stability we talk
about the speed that it moves through
the system and and how it's never
transferred unless it's preserved in
quality that's the stuff that we learned
from all these other countries that did
Appalachians where they figured out how
to refine the process to look who's
absolutely rock tight for them and it it
it doesn't mean that everyone is going
to get paid from it but what it does is
that it creates the upper shelf you have
to have the upper shelf because the
higher the upper shelf it brings every
other shelf up below it but if the top
shelf is ten bucks
you fucked if you down below that but if
the top shelf is 50 bucks there is some
room and what it does it starts to allow
you to create exquisite markets and then
normalize markets and then both markets
because everybody deserves good grass to
smoke but when you're talking about work
that required an ungodly amount of
fucking labor you're selling a Maserati
you're not selling a Honda they're
different Honda is a beautiful car - but
Gupta didn't stitch the leather seat in
it so when it comes to us with the
Appalachian how it rolls out is is the
boots like I like about it is that
they're actually taking their time and
the groups are putting arguments
together that are trying to lessen the
these so that it's not so expensive to
begin one and it's not so expensive to
change one and that we're creating
variability in the genetics that were
using so that you're not tied into a
specific thing because y-you had the
data from the monks so remember I sent
you an email where I laid this whole
thing out and study in the shipping
years and I'm not an Appalachian expert
but what I care about is how do you take
their ideas and use it to assist us in
what we're doing and not follow it
verbatim because cannabis is not wine so
it has to have its own criterias and the
the idea that it's something that brings
value to regions that have historical
relevance and that the impact is genuine
and is like I said it creates the upper
shelf and it allows you to start to
validate outdoor cannabis in a way
that's speeded because we know from
consumption point of view that the
thickest richest greasy as shit is
coming from outdoor so indoor is a
smoother and it is usually because of
that diurnal swinging temp and the fact
that they stabilized methodology and if
you're running it as a organic indoor
you're getting a really premium product
but if it's regular salt grown it's very
similar and so you don't have these
subtleties and nuances as much the
cultivator themself as influence but not
like the specific regions within
California than that influence and I
think that once you start to create this
as long as it's not too onus on the
operator where it's too much paperwork
and too much money then over the course
of the next 15 20 years what you've done
is you started to first legitimatize
cannabis as an ultra craft product to
fit and all the extra lines of all the
other craft products because everyone's
consuming it but now you just have to
call it that and then what it does it
starts to create the value for all the
small far more over time as long as we
can hold our properties like that's the
hard part for us is how do you maintain
the land and how do you maintain the
family integrity to get to that point
where we're going to get paid and we
weren't paid before now we're going
through this transition and with
actually okay I'm feeding my kids I'm
not rolling in the fucking paper like I
used to but I'm also happier than I've
been in a long time because I know I get
to go run the farm so like this is a
busy Beauty to being legal in a way that
it's not about you man it wasn't about
me tripping on the game it was that I
looked at my kids and realized that by
the time they get older our whole life
will be gone and so what do we do and so
to me the Appalachian is the key to move
this forward and if we just study how
they came about it was wine where the
monks the monks were the ones that
figured out the best processes and they
figured out the best locations because
they were funded by the church so they
didn't have to get paid making wine they
had to have it for mass so everything
that we have on Great Dane is really
from the Franciscans and so they figured
out where everything knew best and how
it grew best and what was the impact of
the soil and the air and the environment
and the elevation on that grapevine we
don't have that amount of data but begin
in it and that's that's the point is
that it has to just be flexible enough
to let you get involved without too much
money flexible rules to begin so that
it's not too exclusionary from the
beginning and then have an ability over
time to adjust and refine so then fits
the needs of the farming community and
the customer and now you got some real
shit so isn't it like Jason has that
information but innately like yes he has
it intuitively intuition right intuition
which is it which man I went to Russia
with my son right my sons a world-class
weightlifter so I get invited to Russia
to go to the Russian Sports Institute to
get him studied and I'm at the Sports
Institute the fucking smarter sports
scientists in the world and they're
filming this athlete I said what are you
filming him for he goes we're trying to
understand what he does so that we can
explain to other people how they should
do it and I said you can't create that
and they said no we can never create
what we do is we analyze research
determine how they did it and try to get
someone else to copy because ultimately
Cree
in his creation that's the art and
that's really what I think like Jason
and a lot of the guys Chris worked with
an including Chris own situation he's
intuitive isn't intuitive Khosla because
that's he's building his business by
himself
so that's intuition and that's I think
it's imperative to put that out because
all young cultivators all young artisans
and all crafts have to realize that if
you feel like you got a skill when you
touch it it's genuine chase that shit
because that's the brain and your body
fucking tied into your spirit and that's
where Wonder comes out and that kind of
stuff it it's valuable to him because
his location and his ability and his
choices make that value so that when it
does it allows us to kids down the road
to be able to have real estate that has
a value so that they have security they
have heritage you know we don't pass
anything down anymore in society
nobody's passing skillsets from
generation to generation and
appellations you look at these farms in
in Italy in France is stuff you're
talking four hundred years of people
passing a farm down do you know what the
most profitable fucking business on
earth is per person is a winery in
France and they're generating office 600
acres over a billion dollars with like a
hundred and twenty five people that's
the best of most bowl and a slough
cretons business on the planet for that
number of people working it so when
someone says this ship doesn't have a
value at that opposite extreme it most
definitely does and we may not have the
ability to produce six hundred acres in
that form but in our niche markets we do
and once you start to get the public to
understand what's produced they can
start to put in orders and you have tree
buys we even have auctions on the
batches so that when you have a vintage
year when the when the when the
Assessors come in and say these are
primo crops you start to get bids I
don't think anybody has any idea what
possibly were people are talking about
$2.00 grass and I'm like in the wrong
fucking business you're not selling
Timex watches
Rolex watches so just quickly I asked if
people have questions and then it
exploded so let me start catching up for
these questions but the one that
everyone wants an answer to is Kevin so
everyone's basically asking can you ask
Kevin if in Skunk projects is still in
the works it is it's still in the works
and a couple times what I did is I I had
gotten ill a couple years back and I
just didn't expect that the I was out
when I was in a coma
but I didn't expect that it was going to
fuck me up so badly and slow me down and
I couldn't really do I could go to work
but I couldn't do all my extracurricular
projects and by the time I kind of got
healed back like this was two years ago
so - I feel great now but man it was
like I had aged like 115 years and I
couldn't move the project forward I just
sat with all the material and I kept
everything alive but by the time I get
back to being healthy I'm in a new
business model with my operation and so
what I did is I took all the genetics
all the seed stock all the parental
stock and I licensed it to another
company that I'm connected to so that I
can have them do the actual sifting work
and breeding on it and then I can go in
and help them with selection because on
the inside what's that which company
don't you want to know me to be able to
utilize their operations that are larger
to do the sifting and the hunting but
otherwise it was going to have to keep
sitting on the weight and I thought I
was going to get to use the farm but
when you start to run your numbers on
the farm and you find out how much you
make really working on the farm you
realize that every square foot you farm
has to be operational so all the way I
behaved for decades which was R&amp;D all
over the place and testing shit running
shit once we get into this new system
it's a fucking tracking nightmare and
it's also financially impossible on your
farm to play hunt and chase when you're
having to tag and identify every one of
these plants that have been bashed and
it's a fucking nightmare and so I just
said hang on so it's not going anywhere
and I'm not tripping because old
I wasn't trying to be first to the
market I just knew that I could access
material that I had myself and I knew
that when I threw some feelers out into
the world to see if did anybody have any
stock from the late 70s I was able to
get it when we tried to open those seeds
up a couple years ago the technology
wasn't refined enough and so we opened
them government pop we still didn't get
them to extend so now the hormonal basis
is better and I know we're going to be
able to do some good embryo rescue on
and start to pull some of this old stock
that I acquired because it wasn't just a
hunt the you know the road killer but
he's obsessed with roadkill but like it
was to hunt and era because like when I
got to California in I'm gonna get
California 87 that was this it was just
so much good pie and it was all coming
from all over the place but it was just
rich and diverse and interesting and
it's it's my roots that's my heritage
strains and so that was the whole
purpose of the project was to pull this
stuff out and it'll happen but
legalization kind of slowed down the
ability to use the tools like I used to
use and then I unfortunately got really
ill and almost fucking diagnostic so
it's it's it's there it's just not being
able to be focused on on the forefront
right now I think everyone was happy
with that answer so getting back to what
we're just talking about with
Appalachians or relevance Appalachians
for all three of you so this is from Don
Jose how long does it take to adjust a
strain to a specific area environment so
Jason can you talk about some genetics
you've run and maybe something you've
noticed like three years into running
something versus the first year of
running that okay interrupt that one
second because I wanted to go back to
where he's just talking about the Rd and
me and my dad we love you know cross
pollinating making strains I mean that's
one of our favorite things to do
together and
I have some you know amazing genetics
I've took the green lantern I've crossed
it into these og you want these strains
these ice cream cake strains other
fruity strains and I want a girl more Oh
I mean I've even popped a bunch of the
seeds and now I'm sitting there going
you know where I put them you know I
could only plant six six plants for my
personal so you know like you said it's
like there's so much out there we want
to try but you almost have to leave it
for those people that are dedicating
their full space to that and then I
wanted to go to the Appalachians real
quick just because I felt like I've been
in Appalachian forever as a kid from
humble he's you know I've been lucky
enough to travel a good amount
everywhere I've ever gone if I well you
know were you from homo County oh you
grow wheat and yeah that's what all I've
been told my whole life and so you know
when you know I've been offered honestly
by places in Santa Barbara you know to
grow Ridgeline hey we'll do a few acres
of light depth for you you know I'm like
no I mean I want Humboldt County on my
brand you know where I'm from I don't
want you know somebody to buy my smoked
that's grown and Santa Barbara or you
know Salinas or whatever in another
another area so I feel like the
appellation thing is pretty real and
like I said I feel like we already are
in our appellation and I want homel
County to be on every package you know
produced in Allentown tea that I sent
out there to consumers getting back to
the question you asked that's a hard one
I mean I guess I'm figuring out right
now I'm growing a bunch of strains that
I personally only seen endure you know
I've only seen us so I'm gonna know a
lot more I mean hopefully to get back to
this after this first you know season
problem or this first round you know
late July and I'll know what these
strains are doing I feel like if you are
you know a good grower you know you're
doing
you're gonna grow good herb no matter
what but you know like I said every
strain is completely different and you
you do have to learn a strain you have
to learn its tendencies some mold some
grow way faster and others some like
more nitrogen so you know they all are
different I don't know a specific strain
it can really put my finger on that yeah
you know it was easier before a climate
change started to becoming more
aggressive because like what Don Carlos
is asking is it's like how long does it
take for them for the plant to
acclimatize to a region because
epigenetically that the plant is plastic
in its genome which means it can
suddenly adjust suddenly gently' adjust
over time to fit the environment better
because it's an organism that wants to
survive just like your your body is a
plastic living body that the genes can
modify and move so that you're able to
constantly pick up information and that
way you pass that information downstream
so when people talk about reading
projects you know you're looking for a
large chunk of time because every year
that you read you chose the best ship
that survived that season so it picked
up the genetic information of
survivability for each one of those
years and when you have a gene pool you
know within the gene pool you have
something that's going to make it and
with and it used to be like just even a
few years back remember we had the
drought right so there was like five or
six years where you weren't getting rain
until like fucking December and humble
and so anybody that was doing
developmental work during that time for
Humboldt County built things that
finished way later than they should and
now you're going into a situation where
we're getting rain again come November
or you should get it back in and the
development of things that went along
that timeframe and no longer applicable
so I think when it comes down to is if
you're trying to develop stability in a
line in an area it's really a measure of
time from swings so you need to take a
look at what you're working at now in
terms of environment
we then go back X amount of years to
when you began and you'd be able to get
an idea of what did you do your
development in environmentally and I
don't so I don't think there's a set
answer of like you know three runs and
it's acclimated seventy two generations
of reading and it's good it's really
about selection and desire for the
market combined with what worked
environmentally a lot of work being a
breeder two minutes oh hey it takes so
much time I mean I guess if you want to
take plants and throw them in door and
make them be their thing quit but I mean
it's you know it for me it's a year you
know every time a lot strain is okay
well extra yeah this one is near that
Supergirl that my dad has you know it's
I don't even know this house train wreck
in it he's been doing since you know we
were all grown train wreck so what does
that fifteen twenty years ago and now he
has it for its finishing you know at the
end of August early September you know
so just like you say but it's not really
a strain it's more of us evolving the
strain you know with the climate but you
say it so yeah it's it's a lot of work
that's why it's nice you know I mean I
like that's one of my favorite things to
do is you know breed is is being a
breeder but now like you said we have to
we have our square footage and the more
strange you put in the greenhouse with
all the metric and all the paperwork
it's headache yeah it's a nightmare and
a batch testing oh it's gnarly but
that's why you know kind of I want to
see what strains are gonna come out the
best in our area so yes I'm taking a
risk right now growing so many different
strains like we know you know a lot of
them growing they've proven themselves
indoor time and time again I guarantee I
could probably I guess I can't guarantee
that because you know they're endure
strange but I know I'm gonna grow them
pretty damn good and we will see they
don't come out good it won't grow them
again we don't know what they're gonna
they're gonna react in this climate we
have you know today today is 85
100 tomorrow's g5 and we're gonna get it
into rain so this is an indoor facility
in Arizona is the the kind of global
warming weather stuff going on really
affecting you guys right now like is it
just all over the place in terms of like
you you used to have predictability I
mean obviously you'd have something
happen in a season that was unexpected
but you had expectations it seems like
now you just don't know what to expect
every single year I mean really we grill
full-term plants in the summer full-term
we go indoor in the winter and yeah you
know Dex really only came around I don't
know what you think 10 years ago I mean
really fully started hitting so yeah I
mean it was just kind of the way it was
a 20 20 years one thing it's a you know
that was her life is this that we would
just always it was full-term plants we
grow all summer long and then the winter
comes you'd go inside so yeah it's the
weather is completely unpredictable the
almanacs on it said it's gonna be a
wetter May but you know we did like I
said last year we've got a whole nother
run it it didn't rain forever it was you
know we're into October there's no rain
yeah I mean the year before we had a
gnarliest storm ever and we had weed
molding everywhere so you know working
with the climate is a whole different
game but at the same time working with
the Sun and the vironment weed is I mean
it's way better I guarantee it's you
know it's getting the teenage seeds
gonna be higher it's I mean just
everything about some girl weed is
better so I just want to say that as a
consumerist and a patient which is
always how I'm experiencing these
conversations
what I want to hear in order to make
that bridge be a successful one to get
from here to there so everyone survives
and there there is what I've heard today
I can't even begin to tell you that
Jason in particular because you're here
is able to integrate everything all
breathable this fucking shit you have to
go through the regulations and the
metric and this integrate that into what
you've been doing traditional and
otherwise and now legal and still
maintain the integrity of your process
as a consumer who does care that the
product is clean and only cares about a
future that has craft cannabis in it
right I like I like all cannabis but
that's the future that matters right and
the business model is there if you can
make the bridge right direct to consumer
and all of that that's what I want to
hear that's exactly what I wanted to
hear that you're able to maintain that
so I just went with that like they said
slow and steady wins the race you know
there's been there's so many people
moving in and they want to just throw
tons of money and build out and do all
this crazy stuff and they have no idea
about growing and you know and elements
and the climates and you know I I'm not
trying to go crazy
I just keep focusing on what I'm doing
and you know I'm proud of what I do you
know there's there's always gonna be
Coors and bud
Budweiser Coors Light Budweiser but then
when I drove through Sonoma a few months
back and there's just lying it is
brewery I said you know what's that line
for ask my sister and she said Oh piney
beer I'm like holy shit you know there's
a line two mile down the block and you
know so I mean what I'm good now is
you're always bill to buy that that
random shit and you know it's still
gonna get you high it's you know but is
it gonna make you feel good you know
clear nice thoughts you're gonna be able
to you know go out and smoke a nice
joint at the end of the evening and just
feel
you know you can feel the difference of
a nice fresh outdoor but I mean some
people some people like to drink Opus
one some people like to drink France
yeah there you go yeah am i feeling
about this is selfish man you've got the
knowledge you have the genetics you have
the things we want to survive we're
blessed man I'll tell you what you know
I mean especially with this whole
lockdown thing we got people tuning in
from around the world there are a lot of
people saying it's 9:00 a.m. and they're
waking and baking watching this and they
appreciate it so so safer 9 ask any
experience with rebadging Kevin have you
done a lot of reading and what you're
going to find is the more determinate
the plant wants to fly where the harder
it is to pull it back so determinate the
flower is always upper latitude plants
so stuff is equatorial stuff this long
flower and Hayes's and Cambodians a shit
like that that will come back relatively
easily because it's almost always in a
semi vegetative state but if it's
something like a broadleaf man actually
takes time and so what I would do for
people is I go up to the hill and they
say look we screw this out as a seed
this fucking plant supernatural we don't
know what to do with it and so instead
of trying to clone the flowers which
works sometimes but a lot of times you
end up rotting it in the Train it
doesn't work you take it like you know
40% of the canopy go off and then I dig
up the plant put it in a burlap fucking
bag like a tree and then you bring it
into a indoor and set that thing off
under 24-hour light because you have to
be able to get that hormonal reversal to
go back into juvenility and all you got
to do is as it dries out just don't
overly feed it with heavy nitrogen just
enough so that it's in a positive so you
you're if you're
if you were driving it through a PK push
in the finished flower you need to reset
that and go back into a higher nitrogen
level and be patient and I've had plants
take up to almost five and a half months
to revenge and people would come in they
see this ugliest-looking thing you ever
seen in your life because all the bugs
are rotting off basically and dry and
falling out and then all the new
helicopters come out and so the point is
that if it's valuable enough take your
time and be patient it doesn't happen
overnight if it wants to turn quickly
you can do it in a month and you can
pull a cart off but like I said I had a
I had to kill a plant I got out of
somebody from another location that was
phenomenal and I held it for him but it
took me over five months to be measured
so I rather keep copies of the plants
that I'm testing and clonal form to make
it easy but sometimes you know you just
one of them things you run a plan it
turns out to be the best thing you have
seen in your life
don't fucking smoke it take the top
forty percent off the rest of the plant
dig it up with the shovel and get two or
three your friends to put it into a root
bag and then tie it up like a tree and
bring that shit into a building and set
it up it's worth the time because
ultimately like with with what we're
doing all of us have seen herb that's so
much better than Eddie the herb was
smoking right now we don't have it
anymore a lot of these newer strains are
so unstable that you know I mean the
seed strains we have there's a little
light show and or just a little weather
change also they'll hurt me out they're
not proven but revenge is something that
you can do just by patient and 24-hour
light not excessive food levels it's
normal let it slowly come back over time
because really what you have to do is
going home oil change yeah
hormonal shift is though is the key part
you want to get to get it back to come
from senescence the juvenility following
up on on what kevin was talking about
about future consumers being like coming
from the vape world does that mean that
maybe they might be like into sauces and
hash and
concentrates things like that so I'm
curious Jason I didn't do you grow for
hash for other stuff is that a part of
what you're doing as well well you know
if I definitely did some fresh frozen
last year it was amazing I used some of
my smalls this year we did some sauce to
Humboldt brand that turned out really
really good
I definitely don't grow for that you
know I like I said I take a little
amount you know maybe to enter the
Emerald cup maybe so I could actually
have some personal smoke and for me and
my friends or whatnot but uh you know
like you said this malt could do
anything they're versatile you don't get
that much for them and I definitely
don't want them going to my jars so yeah
I don't go for it but I definitely enjoy
you know I'm good with about one dab in
the evening you know right before dinner
I'm not I'm not wanted is hit him all
the time I like smoking joints man
honestly here's my question are you
are you as versatile in your business
model as you are in your cultivation for
instance if you attract more people to
your brand by having other products out
there and eventually they make their way
to your flower which is where you want
them to be isn't that a good thing is is
like is that a nod we have to make to
where the markets go it's amazing that's
exactly where I want to be if I have
amazing fresh frozen or a sauce maker or
somebody that wants to do a
collaboration with me I'm down with it
you know I'm open with collaborations
because I grow a good weed I have no
idea how to how to make oil sauce fresh
frozen you know I I'm old school hash
you know I could make hash you know I
don't know that so and I don't pretend
to yeah I'm open to any any type I
believe it definitely helps a brand to
have multiple products come out of what
you grow that good the only way that
you can hold the product to showcase a
season is in a concentrate form because
flour breaks down just due to the fact
that it's got too much organic matter
right and so a small amount I think of
stuff that we make should always go into
some form of concentrate being a
traditional hash but even if it's enter
in in a BHO extract where it was diamond
and sauce that shit'll just sugar up
over time but if it's held cold and you
open a 34-year jar up it's still rates
and so I think that that's the only way
that you can kind of take people back to
let them see what the seasons were like
so that you get to show them this this
progression of time and that's what
that's what's cool about it by holding
concentrate form is that you
you just get to kind of go back in time
and say man 2017 was a fucking epic year
look at the look at the oil the herbs
long gone but we still have some oil
left and we'll break when I the farmers
are on saw in the freezer Frenchy you
know he was always saying you can hold
that for time and I think that that's
something that that it's important too
because otherwise nobody gets to see
what the farm did in the years prior and
you can kind of help people understand
the changes in environment and in your
development as a cultivator by what the
product smokes like in that oil form
it's if it's it's not it doesn't have to
be so fuckin difficult because
ultimately we're all smokers who want to
share good smoke with other smokers what
is it like we're disconnected from the
dope game we're born in the fucking dope
game and what you want to do is have you
embrace it with us what I mean now that
we're not fucking criminals and being
persecuted and hung up on the fucking
Street it's a lot better because now for
the first time you could really get
people to get caught up in let's enjoy a
good pot together it's not anybody
smarter or better it's just that we're
all fucking humans who have that
commonality so let's talk pricing a
bunch of people we're asking if you guys
seems like prices are going back up so a
couple questions like we talked to Chia
Rodriguez from our kana flower or
Mendocino generations and she was
talking about how two years ago
everybody was calling her for trim
because they wanted to turn it into
extract and nobody really cared about
the flower now she gets no calls for
trim they're all for flower so I guess
let's start with like GN yeah it was so
you're selling bulk so obviously like to
tell us where prices have been going for
flower and trim and then Jason you do
have what are you doing with all the
extra like the trim from your farm is
that worth anything right now or what's
kind of your model for using the whole
animal bones and all 100% I would say
it's more like a year ago every phone
call that I got where I need 10,000
pounds of trend a week I need 10,000
pounds of trend week all day every day
every phone call those same people
including Humboldt County manufacturers
they were manufacturing centric and
distillate centric are all now pink
their flower distributors they don't
want they don't even didn't even cut the
manufacturers don't call me for trim
they call me for flower so is completely
swapped around in all those big farms in
central Cali Central Coast and a bar a
lot of that pots going to manufacturers
so that market is saturated more than
flower it is brutal they can't sell the
flower they can't sell their flowers so
fucked up they are got to send the
flower how to concentrate it's so booked
you take any shitty weed you turn in the
oil you can put some bullshit Terps in
there and then some person it tastes
like fuckin candy and it's still dis
shitty weed you know the big brands in
the state that have been shopping in
that in those areas that we were just
discussing
are hollering out us heart and they want
to fill their jars with our herb and
they'll pay and it's transitioning as we
speak today in this moment prices for
trim or we're selling trim for averaging
probably $100 a pound still today it
went down and then it kind of got went
back up a little bit it was in the 50 60
dollar mark about six months ago and now
it's back up into the 80 to 120 probably
averaging about a hundred for us I don't
know what's going on off there for other
people that's what's that's what I just
see all day every day
we're so empowered and that to the
farmer right now in between a thousand
and fifteen this depends on what it is
and where it's grown and quality and who
was going to I see it I see it the price
actually continuing to go up for the
next 30 days I think we might see a 16
we might see an 18 I think come July
August it's gonna get back down into
where we're at currently today and then
I think you know fall is gonna be what
it is we'll be back down into the 800 mm
category and we're not gonna sell pot at
that price unless the farmer makes us
what when was the last time you saw 1800
you know it's probably no five years I
can't even they can't tell you the
prices have been so all over the board
and you know who would have thought it
and definite could all sudden make the
places go up all the sudden we have a
everybody wants to chill at home and
smoke weed and you know I I'm doing the
same things I I what you're asking me to
afford to you know what the Tramp is
yeah we wanted to do something with
everything we have so yeah we want to
sell all of it there at the time we used
to throw shakes head up the hill didn't
matter and then all of a sudden it was
worth of time yeah I mean like you said
people wanted shake them nobody even
wanted but so you know I think there's a
there's something for all
all of it definitely the littles they're
versatile pre-rolls you know he rolls
are great you know I definitely make
sure to sell every bit we can I mean
it'd be nice to make papers out of the
stems if I had the right people to do it
I'd love to do that as well you know
there's a lot of good product I mean I
was picking leaves the other day and I
mean they were so big and juicy I was I
wanted to juice these leaves and you
know I've never done that or I've never
drink the juice from them but they look
so great so yeah there's lots I could do
with you do you ever make canna guards
no no what is that once miss smoking
it's their role in a it's cool looking
but they smoke like shit man and gives
Polly you make up yeah you make a pot
leaf cigar but the problem is it doesn't
fuck it
tobacco's Molly no yeah you may have wet
then you heart it hardens up and
couldn't look any cooler but I've never
had one that I enjoyed smoked very moody
on traditional paper smoker I mean for
pricing though right now like because
they've been swell chin down on all the
the hot operations street prices
exploded and so I mean I think run to
moving it like 32 from end or just you
know a month or two ago I have someone
tell me 38 five down in the city right
now so I can heard those numbers and
fucking years
yeah so what I know is that you're
you're gonna see some changes in price
and what fucks us in California is that
there's not enough storefronts and too
much large production so as an
overproduction situation it doesn't
reflect the reality of cannabis because
we only have you know 1,500 stores so
when you open this shit back up and now
you have stores to move herb into the
pricing will I think rise up again but
like Chris just laid out he's seeing the
cycle right now there's some there's
huge build outs so when all these giant
build outs happen well that's definitely
gonna make the market you know kind of a
little bit but that's why Appalachians
humble our brands that's why we have to
stay who we are
because I mean those those big those big
build outs are still they're gonna grow
well they're gonna grow they're gonna
grow killer Coors Light weed you know
yeah
be great for that but we you know if we
keep educating the consumers and they
know what we're growing you know and
they know that we are they sell they buy
my weed it's gonna be great it's gonna
be you know it's grown organically well
not only that the money I get you know I
coach baseball I'm part of lots of
things in southern Hummel well this
money helped my community go not only
what they're smoking it's where that
money's going and you know what that
money is helping out it's helping out
schools you know we donate you go to the
basketball gym so you see our farm names
on the gyms you know so it's it's a it's
a lot more it's a big it's a big thing
and that's what I feel this whole legal
market not only are my kids safe from
having the house raided like that so
many times as a child you know but now
my kids you know basketball team has
Ridgeline farms on the back you know I
could put really harms banners
everywhere I could I'm always me and my
family have always been great you know
supporters of the community but now we
could actually have our brands out there
and it really makes our children proud
and you know like like Kevin said you
know I'm doing this for my kids you know
and that's really it I'm doing this for
the community I want southern humble to
thrive oh with emerald trouble and we're
all triangle to thrive you know but uh
you know we we we use Humboldt County
this is our heritage this is what we've
been doing our whole life this is what
our family our parents our grandparents
I mean this is you know this is the law
there's a lot bigger picture going on
right now and you know people like you
Peter you know put up there I hate
things like these I wish it is Kevin is
amazing speaker but why I'm doing this
is so the consumers can learn who we are
when that we are real people
and we're not just about money or about
our
communities and we're about you know
given the best ur know the best ur you
know to the and giving it to the people
Cheers
oh yeah the beautiful daughter right
there but we love when kids and animals
come on so you got both right now
so Kevin Kenton right
so Kevin you you planted this year right
yeah yeah and I realized here too i I
was gonna skip the season because the
the the lysis shit was such a freak show
and all of a sudden I pulled the annual
and a company hit me up and said hey
would you be willing to run a run for us
so this year though I already have my my
annual renewed and so I'm my farms fully
ready all the soils detailed props have
been put in and I'm just waiting to go
in the ground when this last of this
little weather bumps and then I'm gonna
run like I said I just run a full term
and for me that's that's just really
because that's where I wanted to be as
an older guy I wanted to go back to what
herb was to me when I was young so I've
been through the whole fucking game
for as a grower I wanted to do an
intense season and then have the rest of
the year not that I'm excited it's gonna
be great yeah and and awning for your
own brand or you're gonna label it or
just sell it bulker what's that well
I'll do a two things actually I'll Co
brand with the company so the company
will have me on their label for their
product because I'm growing the product
from them and then I wanted to also grow
something that wasn't in their catalogue
for myself because you mean you're
growing their genetics
yeah grown their genetics and then I'll
produce it they'll produce their product
for them and then I'll get recognition
on the jar which are you allowing a
savior that is yeah yes it's for the
cookies
okay so I'll also I'll do work for the
cookies and it's a good contract and
what it does it allows me to be able to
have surety on the business
it I need the stability to cover the
actual business and then what I'll do is
I'll take about 20 thousand square foot
awful 4,000 square foot off and I'll do
that myself and I have something that I
really wanted to run that just as an
outlier freak and I just said you know
this has to be produced just because I
got a seat in the market and then once I
produce it I'll figure out how to move
it into the world from there but I just
know that I need to grow it on the hill
because the quality of flowers per line
and it's got numbers that are ridiculous
I under your own brand name yeah I'll do
it out of my own brand name so what's
the brand name you know what's the brand
my brand sport right out okay surprise
is your store still open it's open right
yeah I think we just officially opened
up the coffee shop the tourist area that
we opened up the whole thing we got a
smoke alarms going in this summer so we
have a full outdoor lounge going in
legal slope lounge and the circle where
we turn our store in to a drive-in keine
so you are no built-in retail outlet for
your own brand I do I do but which is
cool are you gonna carry a Ridgeline but
I don't handle any of the inner
transactions I can preferred you to the
buyer team yeah I can't always many
people he's the Fuhrer you man I try it
makes it it used to be a lot different
because at one time we ran everything
ourselves because that's how the
operations work but as you go forward
with all this new shit it's just not
that way anymore and so the only thing I
have full control over what I do is the
farm and so this is it'll be nice
because I can do business that's
business and then I can be something
that I want to produce myself I love the
flower yeah the flower yeah it's great
having them out of school and
coronavirus me
been a nightmare for them in a lot of
ways but the happy kids in the house
it's just been great we're at the river
yesterday and we're gonna probably go
take off and hit the record amaro I got
some cool blog shit we got on the rapids
with but a lot of it is just as a
producer you have to do things that that
you know will make money because you
have bills to pay the County charges be
twenty thousand whether I harvest the
buck or not the state charges me
fourteen thousand whether it harvest the
buck or not
so that's fourteen that's uh what's that
thirty four thousand right there right
then I got another 5k going out to let
water board most of the shit so you're
looking at like almost 40 grand coming
out of your pocket whether you make a
dollar and so 40 grand is almost taken
home like 17 so if you make 70 K you'll
take home around make 40 mm so that's a
$70,000 year job and Emmanuel in the
time so a small portion of the cannabis
on the canopy can be me so that I can
kind of enjoy being my stout and then
the other part is good business and I
don't mind growing their varieties
because the stuff that putting out is
highly marketable and my business
dealings with the company had been
nothing but good you know I have no
complaints it's been straight normal
solid business and that's what I would I
needed when I you know got involved in
this stuff so we just had a Los Angeles
retailer on whose vertical and also
grows and has his own branded product on
the shelves including his own and I hate
to bring up the dreaded T word taxes but
he said the taxes in California are so
fucked up that it makes more economic
sense now for him to bulk his own flower
rather than put it on his own shelf and
it sounds like he's you're in the same
oh yeah the retail the thing with the
store is that stores give you access to
people if you if you're if you do a
store if it's not in a geographical area
where you get phenomenal traffic you
have to make it very streamline so when
I laid out my storefront it was the
designed to handle quick traffic through
the facility and have minimal staffing
but intelligent people behind the
counter and you know I mean like I think
some of my favorite stars I've have been
to is like dockside up in Washington
so dockside in Washington is really well
done stores where they got a customer
service level it's phenomenal and the
layouts are incredible and the fucking
experience is phenomenal and so I I got
a chance to check out the dockside
operations and I was so impressed but I
realized that they would not work for me
at all here because of what where we're
at and what we're going through and so
the store is something that gives you
access to the public it helps you
understand what's moving through distro
it's like a window and but it's not
whether the profit is it pays for itself
pays for the investment costs to build
and it pays to the employees it creates
an ability to have a license that's in
continuing but you know for me being a
farmer especially because I actually run
my own farm so I can send myself the
laborer so I get I get to pay myself
labor and then I get to make profit for
my company and because I was always a
person who loved to grow pot being
outside for long hours in the Sun I
don't see it as a punishment so like you
know for me I mean I'm a blue-collar in
New England and so like the work thing
isn't a problem I actually like what I
do a lot I like it so much I've done it
my own fucking life so it's there's like
a dual benefit where like I get a good
paycheck as a worker and I get to do
what I love but the store is more of a
matter of building supply chain
components and it gives you a really
good window but man for people that have
stores and areas that you know are going
to be impacted by cold but heavily in
terms of financial situations look pity
these poor people because you don't you
don't want to see anybody fail I don't
take Glee and seen anyone get the shit
kicked out of them really like I know
you know sometimes you might deserve it
but if I celebrate it too much it means
I'm fucked up and so I try not to get
caught up in that
and so what I know is that with us as
operators each license has its own
pitfalls and they they all have a plus
and a minus and you have to clearly
identify what that is before you get
involved in it so you can understand
that if you're gonna put that into your
portfolio it has to cover itself and it
might not make money but it's a supply
chain component that lets you have a
different type of strength in your
business and I mean who ever would have
thought we had to do all this shit like
really like the complexity that we're
going through to survive is mind-bending
and it's people say well that's business
but I'm like I've been in business for a
long time no other business you have to
do this much weird shit it's crazy so so
wait with use you said it was twenty
thousand square feet and 16 is going to
the cookies collaboration yeah roughly
probably like 15 because I'm not really
gonna pull one of the benches out
because I didn't get a chance to do the
work on that lower bench to prep it like
I was doing the others and I just said
it out sometimes you have to make sure
when you're doing the labor that it's
workable and it's not important to fill
the whole canopy always at the same time
and that's where like the Canadians the
best examples of Canadians I got a
million square for the greenhouse they
should have ran like a hundred thousand
square foot and instead they ran a
million square foot and they only could
move 50,000 square feet so it's the same
with what we're doing is I'm filling up
the quantity that I can control myself
with a single worker and so out the 24
is going that way 16 could potentially
go to the cookie but probably more like
14 so I'll pull 2,000 right out of the
canopy this year and not run it because
it when I started laying out my time
schedule on the work I realized that I'm
not dialed in enough to cover another
2,000 square for the labor but but so
women cookies are you running their
genetics or your genetics no their
genetics remember I
I have the nursery that supplies them so
all of their all their breeders feed the
nursery um I'm involved with my old
nursery is a new nursery but now it's a
single client nursery and it it puts the
genetics that the proprietary farms the
farms that catch the first release of
the lines so there's the humble
population group which is forearms and
Humboldt County that are going to work
producing product for cookies and then
other farms within California that
produce they all come get the genetics
from us at the shop and so what what we
do is we just produce what's needed that
would work well in our environments so
that it reflects well on the on the
brand itself so it's not a bad deal as a
cultivator because they don't want to
feed you shit that won't work they want
to feed you stuff that works so that you
have an ability to put their product out
and stuff that they're doing on the end
or render stunning it's just that when
you put it on the outside you know you
get a fuller richer expression and the
steering of the choices are based off of
because remember we have a test facility
for that stock too so the cookies test
facility for outdoors behind the one log
so we have a full light that greenhouse
at an outdoor next to the nursery that
does the R&amp;D for a lot of these projects
so I'm not involved in that into the
sense of the iron D component oh then
come by and smoke with some of the wheat
the one log team is which isn't bad
you get court bit too much shit you
drown timewise but the point is that
it's a thought-out process because what
they want to be able to do is create the
sun-grown lines around the state to
highlight sun-grown production and then
to find the varieties that shine in
sun-grown best and then let the things
that shine and endure be best because to
say that people don't like indoors to
say that you'd be wrong it its desired
by two different people and they're the
education isn't to get people to leave
indoor and go to outdoor it's to let
people know there's various grades of
cannabis and that all the time when you
experience enough of it you'll be able
to find your own balance of what you
desire and where it's grown or how it's
grown but the point is to curry
the best product and all the
environments so that indoors well done
mixed lights well done outdoors well
done
the grass is good grass right so with
have they guaranteed like will buy X
volume from you or is it kind of a more
fluid relationship no it's it's what
what the way you work it out with this
will be the way you work it out with any
of these operations that provide you
material is that y'all you'll produce
the material you'll give them an
estimation of how much you believe is
gonna come off your farm based off your
your square footage and your production
methods and at the end of the season you
do a quantification testing to find out
are you clean because before they take
the product into the system so you do a
pretest pretest comes up it gives them
an idea that you have no heavy metal
issues you have no microbial issues and
no no other banned substances in the
product and then it also gives them an
AB annoyed level so they can get an idea
you do an estimation of your yield and
you can give it to them on since I don't
have my own processing facility what I
do is I pass it on to a processor but I
can tell them I have X amount of bucks
flour and they can do the calculations
on what they normally average on from
box to finish so say I have 400 pounds
bucked we might say that comes out to
260 pounds finished that'll give them an
idea broken up offer your metric
configuration tags because remember this
is all track and trace and then that
product moves into the chain so as long
as the products at the quality that they
want it moves and that's how it should
be with cannabis like any AG product
where there's no such thing as you grow
it for us we take it off your hands even
if it's shit so like that doesn't work
like that because who would who would do
that in business right so there's always
an incentive for the farmer to make sure
they do a good job because this way the
product moves and if a brand is willing
to work with you as a farmer is your
responsibility as a farmer to make that
brand look good
regardless who it is I don't give a shit
if it's the littlest distributor to the
to the biggest company as the farmer
your obligation is to farm the damn weed
and do your best job and when we do that
we do a good job and so I don't mind
growing other people's products and I
know in the future as the Appalachians
come in we'll start to stabilize what we
actually produce and run in these areas
so that customers can get the same
product a couple years in a row my only
problem with flippin varieties
frequently is that you don't get the
repeat by next year on the same product
unless where's it coming from it's not
coming from you and so I think that as
we go forward and you have enough
producers producing enough cannabis on
the bulk level we'll be able to go back
to not happen to chase the strain to
shore and work with things that shine on
our property
I only produce a thousand pounds a
thousand pounds moves into the system
and that's what I produce every year so
it's like saying I'm going to produce a
thousand cases of wine that's what I
produce that's just how it is and we can
use all their agricultural models to
understand how that works and it doesn't
help us in a congested California market
but if I'm looking down the road it most
fucking surely does because what I'm
building is a quality market because
don't tell me people don't like no shit
I mean people can drink all the fucking
blood wise in a run but I haven't had a
canned and that shit in a long time and
I don't drink a lot of beer so but if I
want a beer I go get what I like and if
I met someone's house they offered me a
Budweiser and chill now drinking juice
I'm not going to turn it down but the
point is you don't ever see me go to the
store and buy a 12-pack of this shit so
I know that if I'm not saying on every
consumer but people kind of operate
pretty similarly we just have to create
a level of production quality that is
seen by all our craft regions so that
people start to understand the craft
herb is good and then they can start to
find regions of products that they like
and things that shine in certain areas
and the main point for all of us in
production sales manufacturing
processing is to is to try to build a
steady rely
business model it's based off of paying
the fucking people back that the product
firm just do the goddamn business and
that way what it does is everybody
trusts each other because you've got
fifty five fuckin contracts but if I
don't trust you I don't give a shit
anymore I don't want to deal with you
and we really went back to what we used
to do way back in the day where we kind
of looked at each other said we're both
here for the long term yeah we both
fucked up we lose money yeah now we can
do business and that's something that
resonates to the customer because what
it says is we're here for the fucking
long term and we're willing to fight for
that and that means we care it's not
it's not on a portfolio sheet of I have
a weed farm I'm in we business that's
great are you are you a dedicated
producer you'd like Chris is a dedicated
purveyor so he was a producer but now
he's a purveyor he looks to find the
things that are quality to put into the
market
jason is the creator of these things
like the it's a chain without each
person doing the best doesn't work it
had Kevin this can do you mind can I ask
a question and just say fucking I don't
have the answer for you obviously if you
can't answer but yeah yeah how do you
how do you and cookies determine what
the price point is on your pot next year
in that contract you know it if a lot of
it works off of your the when you're
when you're going through a supply chain
that with all the processes or controls
they know how much the product has to
cost in order for those touch points to
make money through the chain for them to
so you get an idea and the whole point
of like the appellation situation just
like the farmers reserve is to bring up
higher attention to a product it starts
to allow for you to have a little higher
pricing for the farmer because the
actual untrimmed I'm a little less
trimmed and a bigger container saves you
money on packaging and trimming so the
way you approach the final piece has to
be backwards from the retail because
ultimately people are saying pounds is
gonna go for a hundred bucks and I'm
like well it cost 160 just to grow the
fucking pound so how can I sell it 400
bucks if it's
sixty-two grow it's impossible I got
fucking taxes the taxes are more than
the prices people quote and I'm just
like it's impossible the taxes dictate
the price through the chain and then the
idea is to figure out how do we overtime
get our desirability up was what you'll
do is you'll create the desirability
because you're collecting things from
diverse groups better quality and pretty
soon that becomes your label where
people come to you for a better quality
product and so because of that you'll be
able to put a premium across the board
on it that's reasonable for the customer
but also gives another point to everyone
downstream from you which then gives you
long term shit if you are not making
money we do business forever it's when
we start having nobody that we start not
doing thank you so much it makes all the
sense in the world it's pretty much like
reverse engineering yeah you got to go
backwards from the retail yep thank you
easy so so I think we'll close on that
cuz I got a deal with dinner
but we still have like a hundred and
fifty people tuned in Monday night we're
gonna have an aquaponics section session
with Steve Ray's near potent ponics
leading the discussion all of our guests
today will be receiving a grassroots
fabric pots living soil raised bed so
you guys have to send me your mailing
addresses and on that note everybody
yeah I was talking to Tyler earlier
today I was like can I give away his bed
she was like hell yeah yeah everybody I
appreciate it and have a good weekend
and by-and-by craft cannabis a quick
shot a southern boy right there yeah
[Music]
thank you odd man hi Chris Chris pink
red thank you
all right we are done