[Music]
one of the surprises coming back again
this third year in a row is noticing how
many people are not here a lot of our
friends that have been here in the past
and I'm not here not for this well not
here participating they might be here at
the show it really we feel privileged to
actually make it past the first two
extinction event level events that have
moved a lot of people out of the
manufacturing products in the market
we're very thankful for our distributor
to help us get it past that point and
our manufacturing partner to help us
begin compliance but it's the landscape
is really changing and we're trying to
stay in it and trying to help our fellow
son grown cannabis folks stay in
business and the other thing I noticed
about the Emerald Cup this year is
there's a lot less we'd like this is the
hall of flowers right so there's no weed
sales in this room where we are but this
time last year there were so many people
walking around with blunts in their
mouths that this room was hot-boxed
and so what I'm noticing is despite
greater access to cannabis there's not a
whole lot of it here like where's the
guy with the blunt bandoliers
what happened to that that was awesome
no I'm definitely seeing the cannabis
industry evolve cannabis culture it's no
longer
justyou're Cheech and Chong kind of a
thing it's your your your mom pop Vado
are starting to use cannabis more the
boomers are actually using cannabis more
and you can tell that has changed the
whole industry that we work and it's
been interesting to watch that
development it's interesting to see how
it's playing out here at the beer
morolto everyone's bringing their
packaging game up the boxes are really
fly this year I have to say over the
last 12 months shared manufacturing
trying to find a location actually build
on trying to make sure that we we could
stay in business and then the BCC
regulations you know making that type of
manufacturing questionable and yeah and
then trying to find investment to
actually keep us floating and moving
forward it's it's a lot of all we're you
live it with me it's stressful so I
think for me the worst was when they
dropped the reg revision after the
45-day comment period and and
immediately banned our business model
with two weeks of comments allowed and
then they sent that off to the oh L to
get written into law so you know that
was it there's been multiple existential
crisis throughout the last year like are
we gonna survive this one that was the
worst
I had like a breakdown like I'm not
gonna be okay for a while but you know
what you come to figure out it's like no
one's position in this industry is
guaranteed or secure and if you want to
keep if you want to be here month after
month year after year it's it basically
comes down to not quitting
how did you come to be in the cannabis
industry from your precision your
perspective okay at that point in time
we're talking like seven eight years ago
I was I was married to somebody who was
having really bad health problems due to
prescription medications and so I told
him he should start smoking weed instead
and it kind of led us down a path for a
while where we got really involved in
advocacy public speaking it shows like
this and then I just I kind of knew that
I just wanted to be around cannabis
nests and and where it was going that I
could actually fulfill my my kind of
inner drive to help people through this
new commercial pathway that was at that
point I'm just expanding right and you
know fast forward a bunch of years and I
had a lot of contacts in the industry
and a lot of jobs under my belt and
experience and a lot of cannabis
knowledge and so when I saw that the the
market in the topical space was
saturated with stinky sticky ineffective
smells like weed you know gunk
essentially I wasn't about to to
recommend something like that to my
grandma who you know was having hip
surgery and it's super Christian and
conservative I was gonna be like hearin
an rub this weed cream on your body and
go to church just freakin to high heaven
know so we developed something just from
the ground to be to solve all those
problems to be easy to use to be
friendly to an old or more conservative
customer to not smell like we to be
highly efficacious and and I didn't
launch that as a product I just handed
that to my grandma
but the emerald-cut came around in 2016
and I decided to bottle some of it slap
a sticker on it and then we won it was
very unexpected how did you feel it
night in that moment from for myself
like when you came into my life and you
discovered me I was working on building
regenitive natural farming techniques
for cannabis because you know I came out
of my background is bioremediation
cleaning up the environment and I
realized a lot of the same techniques
could be used in agriculture to advance
natural crop production so I was I had
always been in Canada into cannabis as a
user and it was only in the last seven
to ten years that I got into it as like
breeder producer it was a good way to to
prove and validate agricultural
principles it's a high uptake plant if I
could prove that I could grow cannabis
well with these techniques I can grow
anything really well with it and the
other half it's it's a clean growing
technique you want a plant that's gonna
be clean for somebody using it for
potentially for their help and I was
seeing a lot of nasty products out there
I I hate hearing the statement what do
you do to flush bro
what do you mean flush what are you
talking about flush what is this flush
you speak of I don't have to flush shit
I mean my plants they they're does does
nature flush I guess
fall rains that would be a flush but I
mean no no that's stupid so that's that
was my passion and getting into it when
I met Chelsea it's kind of a marriage
made in heaven she she does really great
plant work I do a lot of really good
soil work and together where we were
coming to the Emerald Club as a cannabis
consultant team for growing and chose to
enter it to kind of validate what we do
you know put in a flower entry put in a
topical product and ended up winning and
pivot to actually creating a business
around that but we really want to get
back to farming we we do this to support
I can't support our farming habit
essentially and so we haven't been able
to be on farm as much as we want to
right now and I don't want this the blow
up so I can go back to like tending
goats and sheep and chickens and plants
and and that's that's where I'd want to
be you know this is all fun and good and
it's helping people but I really just
want to get back on the land we're
working in association with farms right
now a few of them here being represented
in Boots
but we don't have our own farm that was
the whole purpose for us getting into
this was to actually get to them I might
as well plug our homies right so so two
of our source farms are son of us full
full Sun farms who won they've they've
won multiple top ten awards for their
flowers and their products like they're
manufactured products the other one is
green shock farms which is again one
multiple top ten Emerald cup awards for
their flowers and also turkeys last year
yeah they end up so he they do all their
own breeding in-house every year they
come with a fresh line of strains that
are completely unique and they're rockin
terpene profiles and no one's ever seen
before what did you do to differentiate
our product from the other things you
saw in the market you had spoken to the
fact that didn't one smell like a
hippies man
didn't want to be overly greasy and tap
tacky what were some of the other
factors that you were kind of shooting
for when the product well it's funny
that the product ended up having such
wide appeal in doing well because when I
designed it I had two people in mind
it's very specifically my grandma and my
dad and they had very specific issues
that I was trying to address like my
grandma is still caught up in that
belief that fat is bad and she's like
terrified of cholesterol and she takes
statin
which are just horrible for you and
nothing I do can I can convince her to
stop those destructive behaviors but I
knew that the emu oil which is one of
the ingredients in our topical I knew
that it had the ability to mimic
cholesterol and so when it hits the skin
and is absorbed it essentially takes the
place of missing cholesterol in handling
inflammatory issues in the localized
area where you're applying it which is
why emu oil by itself is
anti-inflammatory so that was that was
half the reason like I knew that the she
was fat phobic and I wanted to get some
good cholesterol fats into her any way
that I could
so essentially working around her own
particular ways of accessing health
which aren't really serving her and
since you can't get her to change
behavior you gave her a product that
worked around her behavior and that was
kind of you were part of your design
constraints and then the herbal
ingredients that ended up infusing into
that original batch of oil was just what
I happened to have growing in my herb
garden because I we were doing
permaculture cannabis cultivation at the
time at the time so I had calendula and
chamomile and a bunch of other stuff
coke planted and I harvested those
flowers you know what pinching off
little chamomile flowers every day
till I had a jar full of that a jar full
of calendula I I took some lemons off
the lemon tree and I peeled them and I
put those skins into the oil too which
so I did all this on instinct initially
and then come to find out well calendula
is incredibly good for healing and
restoring skin and fighting infections
and chamomile is one of the best
medicinal plants next to cannabis I
would put that like cannabis number one
chamomile number two like ginger third
and that's what I finished with I the
one ingredient I went out and actually
bought you know specifically to put into
this that I didn't have on hand was
ginger co2 extract which is hundreds and
hundreds of monoterpenes and sesqui
terpenes and phenols polyphenols all of
all the things that make the synergistic
effect in cannabis with the terpenes
most of those are found in ginger lower
amounts differing varying amounts
different combinations but that's that's
kind of one of the things that we really
like experimenting with also is finding
out the other plants that work within
the endocannabinoid system to help
modulate human human health and human
metabolism
we're researching every day we're trying
new things every day we're trying to
make sure that we you know get it ons
people and get actual people using it
[Music]