[Music]
this is Mother Teresa
of course she won the Nobel Prize in
1979 for her work with afflicted
patients all over the globe how about
this guy anyone ever anyone recognize
this guy his name is Norman Borlaug and
he won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1970 for
ending and averting global famine this
was really the most pressing issue
confronting humanity at the time it was
sort of akin to the climate change of
his era Nobel Borlaug was a plant
pathologist by training and he
accomplished this work through breeding
that's why he's relevant to our talk
today you see after World War two
analysts thought that by the 70s or 80s
the rate of the growth of human
population would exceed the rate of
agricultural production that would lead
to catastrophic starvation and human die
off but Borlaug solved this problem by
breeding improved grain which increased
yield by over 500 percent and he thereby
saved over 100 million lives making him
arguably the most important figure in
human history so why am I talking about
Borlaug Borlaug's fascinating to me
because of a conversation I had recently
with an investor I told this investor
that we intended to double the average
per acre yield in cannabis in the next
couple of years and they couldn't
believe that was possible they were
incredulous frankly and I understand the
skepticism it seems like every day now
we hear new biotech startups coming into
the space pitching disruptive
technologies which will you know change
the market and disrupt the whole
agricultural production we're hearing
about molecular genomics we're hearing
about CRISPR we're hearing about bio
synthetic production of cannabinoids
we all want better faster stronger
plants but what's the right path to get
there the key to successful investing in
cannabis biotechnology is knowing which
of these approaches are likely to be
successful and which are mere fads I'm
here to say the the successful breeders
of the future will create elegant
programs which combine both judicious
science and artful breeding my vision
based on 12 years of experience in the
labs the fields the greenhouses and the
grow houses of California is a little
bit different I've boiled down this
vision to five points five rules for
elegant breeding they all combine
artistic intuitive concepts with
organized scientific concepts and we're
going to go over each individually rule
number one grow plants from seeds plant
production systems are something I know
a little bit about we're hearing a lot
lately especially about tissue culture
which again is something we have
experience with dark heart opened the
industry's first tissue culture lab back
in 2014 and tissue culture is a great
technology space-saving it creates clean
high-quality plants but the production
system requires very long lead times and
the costs are astronomical many will
tell you tissue culture is used
successfully in other agricultural crops
and they're right it's used for things
like bananas and other tropical plants
it typically as a means of last resort
the bananas that we grow are sterile you
can only grow them from tissue culture
most production in cannabis is produced
through clone this is how we make most
of our plants it's really the core
business of dark art nursery and these
plants can be very high quality as well
they're moderately fast to market
and relatively low priced but there's
very high disease pressure for these
plants and that makes it really hard to
operate a clonal system at scale over
time where we're going and where most of
the industry will go is to production
based on seedlings seedlings are the
highest quality lowest cost production
system they're the cleanest plants and
they have very low disease pressure
they're super low cost I mean we're
talking pennies here not dollars
the problem with seeds is that there's
not there's not very much availability
of stabilized varietal so you get a lot
of variation in the crop that's a
problem that can be readily addressed by
breeding and it's one that we intend to
solve we do think that there's a role
for tissue culture and research and
development there's some advanced
technologies especially around phyto
sanitation that are great for tissue
culture but we don't see it as a
production system okay rule number two
include heritage breeders in your
program these are the guys that have
been here for decades at dark heart we
work with them day in and day out
they're farmers right
they understand this plant better than
anyone they've been doing it longer than
anyone and through grit and intuition
they've created an amazing abundance of
unique and interesting varietals that we
consume in the market every day you know
they can seem that they can seem sort of
low-tech and amateur from afar but I
have to tell you in three years I saw
these guys take the average CBD content
of varietals from 1 or 2 percent to 20
percent
it's amazing the work that they've done
given limited resources they're truly
the industry's artists and any great
program in breeding will build upon
rather than replace their work let's
look at an analogy this is the wild
mustard plant humans have been breeding
the wild mustard plant for perhaps tens
of thousands of years and that's looked
like sort of
creative amateurish breeding programs
very intuitive by farmers right across
many many generations and they've as a
result they've created these unique
species the broccoli the cauliflower the
Brussels sprout right none of us would
consider abandoning the broccoli and
neither should we consider abandoning
the breeders that have taken this plant
to where it is today successful breeding
programs again will combine this
intuitive artistic approach and
supplement it with modern scientific
approaches this is a well-known concept
amongst breeders but history is replete
with examples of breeding programs that
failed to acknowledge and incorporate
this basic concept we'll see some of
those examples here in a second okay
rule number three avoid tech fads this
is hard to do you know where there's so
much hype around these new technologies
right and I'm as excited as anyone we've
got these molecular breeding tools that
offer precision and so much power to the
breeder we want to use them but I
caution you don't give the Nerds the
keys to the kingdom just because you
have a hammer doesn't mean the problem
is a nail the solutions we may be
looking for might not be technological
and any technology out of context will
fail
so in the 20s there was a great new
technology on the market where breeders
would apply x-ray technologies to seeds
this would induce mutations in the plant
and the purveyors of this technology
promised that it would create marvelous
new varietals that were quote-unquote
made to order sound familiar
at one point you could actually take
your seeds to like a local drug store or
something like that and they would have
you you could have them irradiated on
site and take them back to your take
them back to your garden and grow them
as interesting as that is you might not
be surprised to find out that this
technology had virtually zero commercial
applications it was all hype
all science you could see some of the
hype but no art there's no understanding
of the crop sometimes the technology can
distract a program with fads right other
times the program can implement good
strong techniques but the goals
themselves are misplaced that brings us
to rule number four consider consumers
it seems obvious but it hasn't always
been how about the tomato how do you
guys like your grocery store Tomatoes
here some people liking them so you know
the grocery store Tomatoes they look
great right they're too bright they're
firm they're colorful but they taste
like garbage I mean they taste like
water right and the reason is that since
the sixties tomato breeders have bred
for everything but flavor right they've
bred for mechanical harvesting they've
bred for firmness they've bred for pest
and disease but like literally the
consumer was not on the list of breeding
targets for tomato programs that
breeding was scientific but it didn't
consider the consumer it didn't consider
the end result of the program it focused
on agronomic traits alone
and that led the program astray you know
nowhere is this more of a problem than
in cannabis where flavor is king right
it's what our consumers are really
looking for and this problem in tomatoes
and other vegetable and fruit crops is
an ongoing problem in response to it
breeders in recent decades have sought
to apply molecular biotechnology tools
to correct it it actually led to the
introduction of the world's first GMO
crop which was created by a company
called Calgene here in California they
called this crop the flavor saver tomato
it was introduced in 1994 I mean it had
a gene that extended shelf-life of the
tomato so this allowed the tomato to
ripen on the vine which is the big
problem with tomato flavor so it's a
tomato that ripens on the vine can be
much sweeter and have a much better
flavor at market it should have been a
hit right it's the only market on it's
only only tomato on the market that
tastes great but the company was led by
scientists right they were eager to use
this GMO technology and they didn't
include input from farmers and other
other people in the supply chain as a
results they didn't really understand
the supply chain or the economics of the
commercial farming industry they didn't
start with really great tasting
varietals and they didn't start with
great yielding varietals as a result the
flavor saver tasted better but it didn't
taste that much better and it was really
hard to produce it was low yielding it
required special packaging to get it to
market the production costs were
sky-high and consumers rebelled at high
prices the product was ultimately
abandoned in 1997 and Calgene was sold
at a discount to Monsanto that same year
it brings us to rule number five use an
integrative approach most understand you
have to understand the context in which
you're breeding what are the targets and
what impact will they have on the supply
chain is breeding even the right way to
address
problem not only do you need
multidisciplinary scientists but you
also need stakeholders from across the
supply chain
imagine if Calgene had included farmers
and processors and distributors in their
breeding program they may have
identified some of these problems
earlier on and that would have allowed
them to pivot the project molecular
breeding technologies like the flavor
saver are super exciting but they have
their limits they allow really precise
targeting of genetic changes they're
like they you know they allow precise
control sort of like a scalpel right and
scalpels are really good really
important tools if you're doing surgery
but if you're building a house a scalpel
isn't of much use to you
breeding is much more like construction
than it is like surgery so let's go back
to Borlaug right what did he target that
won him a Nobel Peace Prize yield right
yield average production of this plant
and really that's what almost all
breeding is about we talk about it in
different terms pest resistance drought
resistance other targets but most of
these are about yield and the thing with
yield is there's no gene for yield
there's no marker that can be identified
for yield yield is a complex interaction
of hundreds of genes and non-genetic
factors like environment production
system and others
here's the proof this is a graph of the
average of the improvement of corn
yields over the last 150 years now you
might consider the slope especially in
the modern era since the 60s to
represent the impact of breeding on the
crop and keep in mind corn is the most
important grain worldwide the u.s. crop
alone is worth 51 billion dollars a year
which makes it the biggest target for
research and development no cost is
spared on breeding corn every tool
available is used on corn now the thing
that I like to point out here is you'll
see my call-out on the graph corn was
the corn genome was sequenced back in
2009 and we might expect that if modern
molecular genomics were breakthrough
technologies that the slope of that grow
the slope of that graph would have went
aggressively up but as you can see since
2009 corn breeding has stayed along the
steady path that it was already on
suggesting that although this tool may
have some uses it's certainly not a
breakthrough technology so let's go back
to Borlaug one more time right if it's
not technological breakthroughs what is
it that that makes a breeding program
successful what is it that made Borlaug
successful
it's about elegant systems right how did
Borlaug increase the average yield of
wheat by 500 percent he bred two crops a
year that's it he bred two crops a year
that was his innovation Borlaug was
breeding here in the central highlands
of Mexico in this town called chip Ingo
right he realized that because of the
difference in latitude at the end of the
breeding season he could take his seat
and move it north to the Yaqui valley
where he could get a second grain season
here this was called shuttle breeding it
was a clever innovation in the breeding
system rather than a breakthrough
technology that clever innovation
accelerated the improvement of corn of
grain yields and it saved 100 million
lives
door locks solution wasn't genius but it
was elegant and unexpected and that kind
of elegance will drive successful
breeding programs in cannabis successful
programs in the future will combine
judicious science but they will include
the think they will include and
accelerate the experienced creative
intuitive artistic breeding that's
already here they certainly won't
replace it all right thank you take
questions hi Dan I wanted to ask because
you've pointed out the heritage farmers
and people have been developing brands
for strains for many years my question
is why aren't we seeing some of these
heritage strains on the market and in
the cannabis products Maui wowie
you know these type of brands that have
been around for many many years that
were very flavorful very lovely strains
that I don't see on the market anywhere
so where are these well that's a really
good question you know it's interesting
because there's actually a lot of demand
in the market for some of those
varietals I would say the biggest thing
that I see is they're really hard to
come by these days some of them have
sort of just I mean that's the thing
about cannabis coming out of this
underground space is that many of these
programs just were lost over time so I
think in many ways there's a demand out
there for them but it's just an issue of
finding them and bringing them back to
market ok thank you Dan thank you very
much applause