[Music]
it's just flour and we're gonna be doing
some dry sieving yeah we have really
nice yeah I have some really nice well I
well I've been into hash for a long time
like all kinds of hash not not
solvent-based hash or rosin really but
like hash you know like resin either dry
sift or ice water not that's kind of
what I did before like so when I was
like you know like twenty years old and
when we were in music school when we
went were like in the classical music in
Europe was like we were all about you
know Europe and doing it how they'd work
and so we were I've been making hash
like that before I even knew about
Frenchie or anything like that where
you're like but I would I would put it
so he's not know but so this is what I
would do is I'd take my dry sift and I'd
put it in like like a little like a bag
like a plastic bag right and then I
would fold that bag up really tight
around the resin and then I'd wrap that
in a piece of paper and tape it up and I
get the paper soaking wet and I'd put
that in the oven so that didn't burn
right and I put it in there for like a
little bit on really low and then I
would roll it with the rolling pin I put
in the freezer and I take it out and I
do it a couple of times and the thing
it's pretty much the same thing you know
it would be like whatever I could get
from my grinder or what you know what I
mean like that's kind of how it started
and I didn't grow splits and
that's what I like so you know like hash
I've always just been into hash and then
once we got in the farming we were like
got more in there like a good hash and
doing a lot of ice water but then you
can't do that with the current
regulations as a farm you know so I mean
I just love hash but I want to like you
know like I want to make good hash and I
want to share that with people but I
also you know I don't know if I want to
get another license to do that I don't
think it's worth it to do that for just
my farm
you know but the dry see if I can create
like I can basically make a similar it's
an equally pure product you know like
we're isolating to 99.99% pure resin
glands and so it's very beautiful
some will be better for dry sip for sure
but the the cool thing is with the
cleaning of the dry sip we're able to
use we're able to work with a lot of
strains that we couldn't necessarily
work with in ice water because well so
in ice water if you have a very very
greasy
melty strain with a thin wax membrane
you have to be very careful to not
damage those resin glands like in the
washing because if you do they're gonna
break and they're just gonna stick to
your material and they're not even going
to end up in your yields and so a lot of
hash makers are like like really sand
sandy or strains because they break off
and they go through the bags easier and
stuff like that so we're able to
actually dry you know these oily or
resin heads and still make a full melt
it's kind of a secret proprietary thing
yeah I mean I will share it i I don't
know if it's like yeah I might as well
share it with you do we're gonna do it
like we gonna have the edge for so long
[Laughter]
Carla says I don't know I'll share it
with you someday once we get it out
yeah I understand I mean that's what
it's like a homes an interesting thing
all by itself just as far as I'm
concerned this idea of like I want to
share these certain things but there's
all these times and places that make
sense and like for me I like the idea of
time stamping because people watch this
video and be like I remember that dude
was the one who I learned this from and
I watched that video which was published
on this totally and few other people
can't be like yeah I mean you can find
the info on the internet for sure make
sense for you guys but like I understand
information sure I mean it's hard to to
say you know anything because it's like
well we could have you know an edge or
any was really trying to focus on
quality and
I'm picking at the right time and if
you're interested in actually producing
something with here biomass or with like
your seconds or like other than you know
smokeable flower and if you're into into
concentrates and hash is a beautiful
thing and dry sip is amazing because
you're not even having to use the water
you're really using water in front of
farming possible you get into like the
Department of Public Health and so it's
a different kind of inspection level on
your farm that you know depending on the
size of your farm may or may not be you
know worth it so dry stuff is a great
way to go and essentially you know we're
using a tumbler and we're we're doing a
cleaning on that and when you do iced
water are you
I'm like a paddle guy and I've also done
some interesting experiments with for
making vortexes through various means
different things you know like I'm I'm
definitely so we have like a it's like a
stainless steel cone bottom brewing tank
and really depending on what I'm doing
I will yeah like a like exactly like a
brewing tank with it and then I'll have
like the little thing and it has like a
nice wide valve so it comes out really
easily and yeah and yeah and then you
know there's a we'll put like a grade
inside so it doesn't all drop into the
cone and then my kind of like a standard
hash machine's friend she's doing but
then we gonna do a hand store in that
like that's kind of unique um I don't
know there's a few of them there's one I
know there's a company that sells like
like I was doing this and then I saw a
company selling these things exact it
was like the exact same tank with like
their logo on it with like you know
little hash thing but they were doing
something for they were like shooting
co2 in it went into one of the valves to
keep it like super cold you know so that
you could do a minimal agitation and and
not have to very gently melt off your
fresh frozen but I'm not I they don't
have any ice but we've dug our own ice
usually yeah and and so now I mostly am
making fresh frozen like for myself
because I enjoy it and not doing a whole
lot of it like just because of the hole
so when you dry said like it's cured
material yeah and so like to keep some
maximum terpenes
yeah well the flavors can blend
differently when you cure it so it's a
different it's a different component and
the melt you know people are very
concerned about the melt the melt it's
like the thing is with fresh frozen like
because I'm I enjoy it right but when
you take fresh frozen you put it in a
freeze dryer your freeze drying it
beyond where I dried my resin right and
then a lot of these freeze dryers
depending on where you put your settings
or whatever they'll have they'll suck
out terpenes and you'll lose terpene
from your
from your hash because you freeze-dried
it and that'll get and if you're some
people put these cold trap things in
there and they'll get the they'll
collect the terpenes that they're losing
but you're gonna lose terpenes from that
rapid amount of drying absolutely and so
I haven't really done test comparisons
but I feel like the enjoyment level is
is equal and the cool thing I think
about dry sift is because people are
always saying like Oh hash is so hard to
drive well these resin glands are dried
individually and like because they're
hanging right there in your room they're
hanging on the plant and they're just
they're dry try any fruit drying in the
air so when you have finished your
trimming and you have your trim in your
your smalls and stuff and you're gonna
do dry sift now you have these perfectly
dried individual heads and then if you
don't have to go through getting them
wet again you keep them dry and you have
and you have the right way to clean them
and you you have an equally pure equally
dabba Bowl you know equally high-quality
product that actually looks like
individual single isolated trichome
heads just like when you take it out of
a freeze dryer and you put it through a
sieve and it becomes powder again
fresh frozen is like there's nothing
else you would get from the garden where
you'd be psyched to put it in the
freezer and then take it out yeah
so how come try comes because they're
hard to dry and they take a long time to
dry and they're finicky and they do
different resin is music it's an
expression on the plant right so it's
just like which it's only creature it's
its own you know it's its own the
expression of that being in and so like
yeah in the freezer it's you can dried
like so if you're gonna be like air
drying some of these really greasy
strains while you're drying them they're
gonna want to grease together they're
gonna want to oxidize on the outside
they're gonna turn more Brown you know
what I mean and you're gonna end up with
the brown patty of goo and people are
gonna be like dude that's shitty ash I
want the white stuff you know what I
mean because that's just what happens
because like and you're like whoa okay
I'll smoke it because it's good but but
you really like really the market once
wants these these looks you know and
there's a couple ways to get them and
you you can either dry it air dry it in
a very cold room and get those you know
and plane it and sieve it and and get
them separated into a powder but you
need very cold temperatures you need it
to be you know maybe a short window in
the winter is how it kind of used to be
but now people are using freeze dryers
or cold rooms to make you know and so
that's really to make a lot of ice water
hash is energy intensive you know what I
mean and and we're seeing like as people
are making like 20,000 gallon washing
machines you know what I mean and it's
like well that's 20,000 gallons of water
just to wash the resin off you know what
I mean
do you really is that route really gonna
be the best way to make mass-produced
products no and that's the other thing
with the dry Steve is like I now AM able
to keep all of my plant material in
composting and I've just you know made a
smaller amount of and a value-added
product it's a value-added product I can
make you know by just quickly if you
guys ever do that when you do a wash you
don't use that water back in the soil
yeah we put them on the hearth and
usually what I do is so you know like
I've I've been able fortunate to like
hang out with a lot of hash makers and I
have like access to some more of the
great people who have taught me some
amazing things it's like not all my
invention totally but you know like what
well the best thing to do is to reuse
your water you know so cuz you've
already got it cold like on the farm
when you're doing it small and you're
gonna wash it again you you read like
you catch the cold water when you sieve
your bags and then you put that back in
to wash it again yeah and then you have
a huge advantage
it's only a detriment if you've broken
the material and you're making green
come through you know if you're if you
have it if you haven't done it if you
didn't do a clean wash and you broke the
green chlorophyll out of the material
and that's mixed in with your plant it
with your resin then matching hash was
rough to then Cobra get with you and
that's the thing with having to go
through that whole extensive process and
there's risk there's a lot of factors
that can affect the yield and the
ultimate outcome and it's a lot of work
and so it it's kind of it's been kind of
like a blessing that's been cool and a
half that we had that we had a few here
that out its scale of like what we want
to be wholly full Miller you can
something we can make right so it's just
our I have some that I pressed out you
know like I I didn't just like with a
with a little hot thing no I think it's
an e wise pocket
it's kind of breaking up because it's
like glass but you know I just I pressed
it out yeah but um this is dry sieve
that was just pressed out and it's like
shatter
so who were happy with the product and
we can kind of this is really really
nice my my simpleton logic I'm a flower
person but I I love this I mean the goal
is to isolate the resin heads right so
however you do that doesn't matter and
like that that look just like you should
put your light on
this
through the clean when you talk about
cleaning them I'm not trying to pry all
your technicality it's like is it
suppose it's a post sieving cleaning so
we do okay I might as well share yes so
basically we do a rough sieve that's
full spectrum and everything goes onto
one one surface right so the interesting
thing about the resin is that trichomes
heads have a static charge so if you
create the right kind of static
situation you can use the static to make
the resin cling to that object and then
you can brush it and you have pure
it's just like when you were a kid and
you'd play with the balloon yeah you
know right here like or like pull the
iron out of the soil or like any of
those magnetic kind of games it's it's
just it's just using static electricity
and they just come right out and so
you'll have all your material will
separate out and you'll have this
perfectly clean it's just all their
heads and then on the other side you'll
just have like this tiny little dust
kind of which was just like whatever was
left through the sifting and to me okay
so this is one of the most beautiful
things about it to me is because the
resin is totally dry when you do press
it it retains this like glass marble
like texture and stability
it's like stable like that it's not
gonna turn into a wax it's not gonna
butter up like hash makers always
complain about when they're ice water
has butters which means it's getting
moisture in it it's totally dry and it's
like glass I totally this was done like
like a hot-water bottle press you know
like in the parchment
and then but I don't do it that hot and
then you remember I don't like rosin in
it I'll tell you I so rosin you know
like do you like just okay yeah and I'm
not knocking on rosin this is just my
personal thing you know but you know
when like all rosin kind of tastes the
same to me because it's it tastes like
juice from concentrate you know like
where there's not a lot of there's no
pulp left and there's not a lot of the
stuff where you're like this is like
like your if you make like the
connection to that conference yeah if
you like like if you're gonna make like
how friend she talks about wine or
whatever it's like that if you're gonna
make I don't really drink wine or make
wine but we like to make like ciders and
the moochers but it's like if you're
gonna like strain out the cider or you
know like a wheat beer it's not quite
the same kind of thing you know what I
mean it's like something about that is
in the like when you when they all stay
together and they blend they blend
together differently and it's like a
fermentation where when you press rosin
it's like making juice from concentrate
kind of extractions you have a you have
a maybe the only the most intense
dominant aspects of it really come
through and they're powerful but because
they're concentrated but then you lose a
lot of the nuance and complexity that
really enjoy and I got the product
initially and I also feel like when
you're grown well when you're growing a
six-star melt you don't need to rosin
press it you know what I mean because of
rosin press like making Roz yeah I
really like I have been sitting with
this like who's the hash thing interests
me because it's part of it regards
reality like even like I am so into the
flower but I know that there's you know
there's a lot of I products of this
plant so then when I look at it from
that aspect I say like the thing that
the rosin crowd and people are even even
hydrocarbon people is this ultimate
refinement in their eyes and they're
removing the the excess their ruin the
skin from the head however you want to
describe that process but that might in
some ways be a detractor that there is
it's so complex that there's got to be
parts of that that aren't just the fats
and lipids and whatever they complain
about but maybe it is different types of
terpenes another minor cannabinoids it I
don't know casing is part of the
preserving of it and I wonder a big part
of it to me is the second to me the
second that press goes down and that
heat supplied you just see all the
terpenes everything just kind of gets
first open and so immediately it's going
to change and then with the resin it
doesn't necessarily burst it open but it
bursts it opened and it forces it
through a screen you know what I mean so
it's like we're stood up into
in that it allows it to be now open to
the outside world it's not a sterile
casing it's kind of like when you get
into like olive oil pressing and you're
like is it urgent is it extra virgin
what are the temps they did it at you
know is a cold-pressed you know because
like definitely a fresh cold pressed
olive oil is something that's amazing
and so some of those Rosen's where it's
like they're fresh and they're pressed
out really low temps they are amazing
being so fresh and that I'm not rocking
we're awesome because there's great
Rossi's out there but not too pressed
flower I've pressed dry sieve and the
thing about rosin is like for me it was
like you had to be at the Machine and to
get what I wanted out of the Roz and I
was making fuck around so long and I
don't just don't like fucking around
with machines
you know things if you like to do that
you probably really get into it it just
wasn't me you know and I don't I totally
get why people are into it and I totally
get like the melt that you get from
Rosen's but I like to see like how when
I grow my hash you know or make hash
from when I grew it's like how good how
did I do you know what I mean how how
well did I grow it and that's how I get
to feedback is how well Roz and also how
good is a hash because you know the hash
it is only as good yeah so it's it's a
great way to like learn about your
plants and what you're growing you know
and what happens after you
- and the ability for the different
types it has to really either show-off
the quality and the need for that type
of hash to have good starting material
and then as you move down the line
towards whatever the the less that's
kind of important because there's all
these refinement techniques and now like
with the media's that people are pushing
product through that's able to hide that
but with something like just real hash
with sift it needs to be a really good
story it's kind of funny because I've
been having actually the last couple
years I've been having a lot of
difficulty with my a shields and they've
been really you know kind of on the
lower end and with the dry sieve I've
been able to like use bigger screens and
like a lot of my a lot of big stuff is
just I'm not being I'm not able to get
it in the ice water like I'm not able to
get stuff that's bigger than 190 190
microns in my ice water screen it turns
out really dirty and gross but when I'm
cleaning my dry sieve I can keep that
and I can keep it all together and it's
like so it's a cool to be able to enjoy
like some of the things that I've been
it's like it's working you know like but
how do you get to enjoy that part where
it gets just lost in the water so it's
been cool them to do dressing
sorry cuz I don't adopt this this is
Amanda you could both touch on this but
let's just go Carlo like so is this
partially a cultivar thing or you think
it's the way that you're cultivating it
that you're seeing in these yes I think
partly it's the way we I think any calls
available and I think it has something
to do with our our app like our region
it's unique to that we're at a low
elevation in a high elevation mountain
area we're only at 1200 but the
mountains around us are all five you
know it goes up to five six and so we
get these really dramatic swings of hot
very hot days very cold nights like
almost we can count on 40 degree
temperature swings pretty much and so we
get very little coast I mean we get some
coastal influence but it's it's kind of
blocked by this big mountain range and
it's the place that I've kind of found
where I'm like okay I can feel like I
can grow in door looking weed out side
but it's totally different because now
the resin is doing different things than
honestly I don't know why the resin has
they're so huge it's it's a mystery
means cool things are starting to happen
area do do also have similar pronounced
yeah it's interesting because it affects
was what they're talking about in about
190 or G that's going to like what they
in hash would they call like work bags
there isn't a lot of sizes that are
bigger than that so really that
typically would catch minor contam plant
matter of contaminants and that if your
guys is glad I can see why it's a
difficult situation for making water
hash we're like driveshaft all of a
sudden allows me more flexibility in
that range it's kind of amazing I mean
it took us while they even and like the
thing is the amount of weight that's in
a head that's between 190 and 220 is
amazing
yeah that's your those are your numbers
right yeah people in your region at
different altitudes not notice well like
we because you notice the inverse which
is other people at the same elevation
noticing the same you know how we just
have started to really explore this
further because we didn't really know
that that was the case until recent
years where you can really look at micro
imagery of your trichomes on a regular
basis I mean that just started to happen
in the last few years and so we didn't
and then with with washing technology
and just where Jacobs evolution was with
passion and like we came to discover by
being able to see them on this level
that OH
there and we didn't know that everybody
like it took time to figure out that it
was this weird phenomenon
that it's unusual oh you want to my
little hasher little pieces of glass
yeah all right carry on budget
production oh no we just that's how we
like it
yeah we didn't know until Reese
this was even a thing like oh our resin
pants are huge that's okay cool and then
it's like sometimes I see it in people
who live in our you know a night but I
don't know what all the factors are if
it's just that if it has to do with the
Sun lunar soil the soil some sort of
combination of things