I wrote a letter to Roger Dale just
stating that as I'm like I said I'm a
nerd so I had to learn stuff so once I
started learning and going through all
these information I had some time
members that are going through
chemotherapy and I noticed the huge
benefits of cannabis with chemotherapy
and cancer patients and help them
relieve pain like Vic and relieve pain
for cancer they can relieve pain for my
guys coming off of an ACL injury because
I'm the pain
it makes you apprehensive when you
apprehensive you play slower when you
play slower you're more susceptible get
another injury so they want you to play
fast at high level without thinking so
in order to do that you have to
disregard your body pain receptors so I
put all that in the letter sticking to
roger goodell this is the things that we
preach in the locker room you know play
fast play hard play smart you can't do
that when you're contracting on your
injuries and then when you're taking all
these other drugs makes you the Thar
Jake it makes you dull sluggish moody
last thing you want is the quarterback
to be pissed off at you and moody and
then you know I get in the ball you say
something to him that he doesn't like in
the locker room and you go on the field
and now he's not throwing the ball to
you and you wonder why so cuz he's
pissed at you why he's pissy I don't
know his hormones are off because taking
all these damn pain meds so I'm talking
about your Dell and saying that you know
there's a huge issue with this a lot of
the players are looking to fight these
pain problems they have a lot of the
alumni are suing the NFL because of all
the payments they took and all the
steroid injections you give them a
cortisone shots to their knees then just
cause their needs to go out if you look
at the older players there they walk
like the Frankenstein and then it's sad
to see that they didn't have the same
type of opportunities that we do now as
far as they do is the medical science
involved with cannabis and I think that
CVD is gonna be the lifesaver of the NFL
when they start implementing and they
did take it off the bench Tufts of this
announced so CVD is off the banned
substance NFL so they're able to take
CBD but it has to be I think hemp
derived a leaf not mistaken so but the
THC levels are still something that they
monitor and NFL and I think that once
they learned that it's less of a
headache if you allow them to smoke weed
then if you take that away from them and
they resort to other ways of caring the
pain because I know there's a lot of
athletes that give TRO for DUIs because
it's legal to drink and when your body
hurts you're just gonna drink a lot to
dull the pain
but then that alcohol stays in your
system the next day and the day after
that now your brain is catching up and
then your body's still catching up and
then you're going into another week of
pain
bringing the baggage from the week
before so I think that once they learn
that cannabis is the solution as far as
helping your body it's just it's as
better overall and Roger Goodell didn't
respond to me so I keep harassing them
every time so every time every chance I
get Peter asked me to come and speak
about this does they put me on camera
I mention it because it's something that
we got to put pressure on them to see
that there's people there advocating for
it now because we're potheads that's
what their favorite go-to is oh we were
pot hits most like when Trump's like oh
it's a witch-hunt
now let's just get down to what it
really is you know it's something that's
going to help everybody as a whole so
let's start learning about it talking
about it being more open about it so
that we can get the people that need it
the best help they can they can get this
out there on the market