[Music]
I've noticed that it seems like the
industry is really in a stage of trying
to just get by and that's kind of the
main focus for most people when they're
starting cultivation sites is I've seen
the mentality switched from like what's
the best site we can build to what is
the minimum we can build to get started
and trying a lot more technologies
coming in that are scalable and I can
start it a lot smaller set up so that
people can just actually establish
revenue and get moving before they try
to like build out this massive project
that they're not sure if they're
actually going to be able to make any
money operating that's cool actually so
you are seeing scalable where you can
kind of start from the beginning at a
lower budget I'm seeing that the I'm
seeing that's what people are going for
more so and that there's a lot more tech
coming to the market that enables people
to do that I'm not so sure that's still
exactly the best approach I think you
get a lot more efficiency by building
everything as one unit especially on the
HVAC side just having integrated systems
that can share Heat loops and actually
like move heat between different spaces
and you know I've seen these like
massive water loop systems where they're
just pulling heat out of every day every
unit inside of all the different spaces
so that you know even if you're running
on different timers or if you have
different dehumidification needs and
your reheat coil is not sizeable enough
you can still be pulling heat out of
these other spaces to make sure that you
have enough to be able to dehumidifier
inside the space and anyway the point is
that there's this there's always these
little band-aids being created in the
industry right now to just kind of like
make it easier for people to get started
because I think it's probably just
because there's so many projects that
have just not really finished and so
people are trying to address this need
as people are a little more timid about
dumping a ton of cash into a project now
yeah that's kind of the hard part
having the for one having the cash to
dump in right investors are getting a
lot more frugal finding companies now
there's
you give me your capital this is what I
could do we're not profitable yet or we
haven't even started yet we're still in
a full startup phase but we're gonna
need five million dollars to build out
our cultivation facility those are the
dots it was ever easy but it seems like
it's getting substantially harder now
than it was well I think people have
learned a lot from the lessons of the
past few years of the industry and
what's been going on at the Canadian
markets definitely created a lot of
scare and hysteria in the industry and
I'm so sure that it really applies that
much to what's really happening in the
US but it's definitely changed the
atmosphere a lot but I I definitely
think it's much better for people to
actually have a proof-of-concept done
before they try to invest five million
dollars into a project and at least have
demonstrated on some small scale that
you can produce a product and you can
get it to market or you can at least
create some sort of distribution system
and/or relationships with retailers that
actually works and then try to scale up
your system but I'm not I'm still not
convinced that you know trying to build
one building with in in sequence and
just setting up individual rooms one of
the time is the best approach just
because of the efficiency losses you're
gonna have in the long term for your
HVAC systems yeah the HVAC is a big one
with that I know that you know I can
remember with us when we originally
started out you know it was kind of
always that way where you'd grow in a
basement and then you'd move to a new
house in a new basement and you knew it
was gonna take a certain amount of time
before that basement was gonna start
yielding you're gonna have to figure out
your space and your environment and then
went from a basement to you know a small
you know 2,000 square foot shop and
those lessons were multiplied you're
like whoa I'm building rooms now I don't
have the regular my HVAC system in my
house is and what's keeping the house
warm and there's different airflow
tracks and humidity is different and and
that's expensive and and then to look at
somebody who's figured that out in a in
a shop and say now you need to go to
vertical racks automation LED light you
know find efficiencies everywhere
from trimming all the way through how
you mix nutrient scare people to death a
lot of times and I get it like it's not
like you can just make a mistake and go
to the bank and have a cushion loan yeah
it's a hard commitment for people and I
sympathize because you know well I'm
always talking about this is what you
got to do you have to like you said we
have to build it efficient from a start
because the amount of money that you
lose trying to shut everything down and
the shelf space the problems you can run
into when you completely revamp and
relearn that whole lesson that's that's
a difficult thing to do if you're
self-funded but what what do you do yeah
it's a it's definitely I think it's the
biggest crux for for the small
entrepreneurial cultivator you know I
can definitely see how it's it's hard to
adopt to that new model and I don't
think that that model of you know what
you're talking about vertical racking
and LEDs and really efficient equipment
that's certainly not been the standard
and that's certainly not what people are
accustomed to and I'm not sure it's
really complete yet the ideas and
concepts that are really going to be
effective in that space but there's
there's still just so much research that
has to be done and I really wish there
were more people that were interested in
uncovering what truths we don't have yet
in terms of cultivation and what are the
most efficient practices we're really
relying on a lot of assumptions that are
being fed to us by equipment
manufacturers and there's not you know
due to its its status as a narcotic for
most of the world you know this is
mostly about cannabis cultivation ok can
you talk about either some research you
have done or are doing or that other
people are doing that you've been
following that you find interesting
sure there's not a lot what I was gonna
say was because of its status there's
not been a ton of opportunity for
academic institutions to really dig in
on crops and understand it dig in on
this crop and understand how to best
grow it and what are the little nuances
about it and that's been done with many
other crops and it's they're kind of
boring at this point because they've
just been researched so much so we don't
really
you don't really have any more questions
about what light spectrums right for
them or at least in maybe we have
curiosities but we can't really turn
them into something that's going to be
that effective in the industry it's just
a few little details that we're
wondering about now but me personally
I've been really fixated on nutrient
research for cannabis just because
there's not you know when I first got
started I just like found every single
nutrient product I could get my hands on
in the industry found out everything
that was inside of it found out followed
all their feed schedules looked at what
the ppm for every single nutrient was
for every week by week that they
recommended and what what was the
phosphate levels they thought should be
going on in week four why did they add
in this other mix and what level were
they aiming for and there's not one
nutrient brand that's the same as the
other they're all totally different from
one another so I just started doing my
own trial so I was buying every single
individual salt nutrient calcium nitrate
potassium nitrate magnesium nitrate mkp
potassium sulfate everything all the
micros and just making my own blends and
seaton testing them testing different
ratios of each nutrient together trying
to find what ratios people were going
for in different products and seeing
what actually worked and it really
doesn't need a lot of nutrition is what
I found it's a pretty light feeding crop
in general I mean you can push it but
you tend to create more issues for
yourself when you push it if you feed it
a ton of nitrogen to try to get it to
veg out a lot faster than you end up
putting on tons of little more nodes
that are trying to branch out and so you
have to deal with a lot more pruning and
you end up kind of making the plant more
susceptible to pests infection in my
opinion when you're over feeding the
plant you see a lot more water damage so
I mean that's what's gonna I was
focusing on mostly just nutrient
research and I found you don't really
need near as much potassium is what most
people are doing for like tomato crops
and pepper crops for their feeding these
like 2 to 2.5 to 3 to 4 EC levels with
like 300 ppm potassium you know you can
be more down to like 150 it doesn't need
to be that high in your nitrogen and
potassium ratios can be pretty close to
one another
the ppm levels can be pretty close to
one another it's it's it's not unlike
it's not like that for many crops but a
lot of the information that's available
has when I really started digging into
some of the publication's it's from
fertilizer manufacturer saying you need
this much potassium and it doesn't
really make a lot of sense I'm not sure
it really works it just ends up in the
groundwater really so and that's another
issue is just the eutrophication effects
that come from over feeding these plants
and then going back into the groundwater
or into our well municipal water systems
and so that's where I saw a ton of gaps
in knowledge and you know we talked
about a lot about light spectrum these
days and I see a lot of people doing
light spectrum research I'm not sure
I've seen a ton that really made me
learn that much more than what I learned
in schools I mean I went to I had a
master's in horticulture and so I
studied a lot photo biology it was doing
a project about growing plants in the
international space station and you know
there's a lot of interesting things to
see but there's not a lot of interesting
changes that have happened over the past
10 years far red lights been really
interesting people are talking about
adding far red light to the mix and
that's because there was something it
was some work being done at UGA where
they were just looking at different
effects on photo siskel and the
different photo systems and how it
changes based on the red to farhad
ratios and I think they're calling to
Emerson enhancement effect was this old
paper that came out a long time ago and
they were kind of bringing back shedding
light on how far red light was relevant
for photosynthesis and there was some
good findings there but I haven't seen
it really integrated in a light that's
being heavily commercialized yet but
it's also quite available in other types
of lights besides LEDs but you've
mentioned kind of growing with kind of
salt based nutrients and stuff are you
oh you know do you explore like I'm
actually I have my YouTube channel open
where the most recent videos Korean
natural farming topic are are you doing
any kind of stuff that explores like
adding microbes and yeah I fungal you
know I'm not a big believer that
and I prefer to grow in indoor
environments greenhouse environments I
love outdoor production but I mean you
kind of you got to be fortunate with a
good piece of land and it's it's it's
not that easy to find a good place to
grow cannabis it's it's you know there's
a lot of people are really fortunate
have a great place to grow up good
weather good soil and that's it's
awesome they should keep doing it but a
lot of people they have to deal with
pretty harsh climates and it's a lot
easier just to do it indoors or in a
greenhouse I do use a lot of microbial
products but I primarily just focus on
like compost compost blends of
vermicompost I don't think you can
really effectively cultivate microbes or
mycelium or mycorrhizae in in a pot in
such a short life cycle of a plant so I
think it's you'll get some but I think
it's just kind of a waste of money so
what I try to focus on just producing a
real good really good
vermicompost make it make a tea or
extract out of it and just apply it to
the roots so that there's a living
ecosystem of microbes being added to the
mix and I'm also using salt nutrients
but I try to keep it really low and I
take time to just feed them plants just
water and from a compost tea to try to
keep a living population of microbes
growing in the soil but I'm not going to
be dependent on an inoculum for that I'm
going to be constantly adding just
living solution to it so I'm not there's
no lag time for me to wait for it to
colonize my roots or to get acclimated
to the new zone yeah you know when we
were working at eco on kind of looking
at nutrient that was coming we were
coming at it from a little different
angle which I found really interesting
we had a resource to be able to pick our
plants take our matter in from the
plants at week one week two whenever we
wanted and be able to test leaves and
the nutrient nutrient content of the
leaves at the different stages and the
different plants and it got really
interesting you know because we we were
working closely with an automation
system for our fertigation and so they
were actually designing a system for us
so that we could down to the milliliter
track exactly how much nutrient was
going to exactly which plants and then
we could tie that into our cultivation
to look like over time exactly how much
our yields were in
into our feed programs as it went up and
down and then when we started playing
with the nutrient and testing those
levels in the plants for mobile and semi
mobile we found cool stuff like same
room same environment we've got
pineapple cush here and we've got the
Flav here and we're feeding them the
same regiment and the Flav is holding a
hundred and fifty ppm of phosphorous and
the pineapple cush is at three thousand
yeah and it was like totally different
uptake mechanisms yeah and then starting
to play with within that uptake what
does it want
does the Flav want to be at 3,000 or
does it want to be at 150 and what being
able to track through our yields and
then obviously economically track
through how much nutrient we're using
and when slowly but surely you could get
to that point where you can start
documenting this plant likes to eat this
for its maximum yield or its maximum
potency and if I'm making a live resin
versus a joint yeah and you know it's a
long project but I like sure yeah it's
great and I really wish people were more
focused on that right now and something
I've really been digging in on and
trying to understand as much as I can
but yeah it's in how do those things
change with different environments is
also interesting you know if you if you
upgrade your lighting system and now
you've got much more ppfd in the space
how how's your nutrients how is your
nutrient regimen going to change in
response to that and is it just a matter
of like this plant likes this level of
ratios of nutrients and all you got to
do is scale it up when you when it's
under in a more intense environment or
does it stay the same and it does more
with less like yeah go through that
grower curse or at least I do all right
I've gotten better at it but the throw
too many things at once you know we've
done one experiment it liked it now
let's change the temperature let's
change the light spectrum hold on how
about we just do the same experiment two
or three times and get like a nice field
of data and then change one thing
yeah and it's painfully slow but that's
what it takes and that's that's why we
need a lot more people doing it and
talking about it and because we're
wasting a lot of resources by not
getting these answers just just quickly
with
you had mentioned can you be specific
about like a cultivar that you grew and
what you may have done different if you
knew you were growing it for flower
versus extraction so we were just
starting that when we had sold the
company and then when we exited that
endeavor in what is now a multinational
lawsuit so super fun to watch all that
research kind of go down the drain but
we were just getting to the point to
where yes we were starting to look at
mono cropping whole rooms because that
feed schedule for that specific plant
was going to produce at a flower level
so much higher than the others in the
room that we were starting to do kind of
the economic balance of okay why are we
growing this drain with three other
strains three times a year when we could
grow at once in one room one time a year
and that is perfect for our flower
production and then we're not going to
deal with putting it with all these
other plants where it doesn't react the
same but you couldn't see it with the
naked eye like the plant was happy and
healthy with six other strains in the
room created great flower sold just fine
but economically once we started to keep
track of that data that was where we
started to realize there is a different
methodology to how we need to consider
cultivation for our efficiencies so that
we're not once again wasting nutrient
and power because I need to boost it up
for you or bring it down for you yeah
and you know they'll tolerate a range of
you know when you're over feeding them
are under feeding them they have a
tolerance and which they'll deal with
that but you it it's a lot harder to
really track the the small effects that
lead to macro scale effects later on the
plant's growth because it's all
compounding you know if you're just kind
of five percent hurting it because it's
getting overfed this one nutrient will
buy an eight week cycle that's it adds
up to a lot even if it seems like a
minor stress you can't identify with the
naked eye there's something that can be
monitored just through analytical
equipment and actually paying attention
and doing structured research but I
think it always needs to stay very
applied for this industry right now
because there's just a lot of catch up
to do yeah yeah and that you know was
one of the things I loved about the
automation equipment
which i've I've had people in the past
kind of reference to me like you're
taking away jobs and you know to be
clear we're not taking away jobs I'm
actually just refocusing that's there's
nothing better in a farm when your farm
laborer doesn't have to mix nutrient
yeah they can be working with the plant
rather than working with the nutrients
or working with the feed system they
just head in do a little programming and
then they get to go actually observe the
plants all day and if need to be prune
if need be transplant that interaction
with the plants it's just a refocus of
job yeah and it gives you more time for
scouting if you have any issues in the
space and then maintaining cleanliness
at a much higher rate as well which is
one of the most important things of all
cultivation is cleanliness especially in
nursery yeah so let it slip yeah so easy
is it Josh your friend yeah so what's
something you and him like either today
or in the past couple days were just
like Dorking out on what kind of mad
science are you guys talking we were
going in about when you move plants
under different light sources the stress
like you know said oak is it better to
go from a metal halide to an HP s from
veg to flour or LED to HP s and like
what what's an okay transition and
what's not and just you know narrating
out about the mechanics of chloroplasts
movement and the leaves and just just
trying to understand that a plan is
always adapting to its environment at
all times you know when it's when it's
building a leaf it's gonna it's gonna
expand it's gonna expand out it's gonna
move chloroplasts around and align them
within the leaf structure it's where
they're optimally positioned to absorb
light wherever that light source is
coming from or whatever type of light
source that is you know we talked about
these pigments today and in the
presentations and those pigments are
selected based on the light source that
the plant is receiving and so when the
light source changes it has to adapt oil
and sometimes it's very difficult for
the plant to make drastic out
stations to a different light source so
that's it's just the things you should
be thinking about when you're making
these transitions as to why it could be
difficult or easier for the plant to
make a transition more quickly
so yeah just you've gotta really pay
attention to the fact that the plant is
building itself as a receiver of its
environment and if you change it it has
to change with that and I went further
with it and was saying that temperature
and humidity can have really stressful
effects as well when it's fluctuating
you know at eight to ten percent
humidity in the grow room or you know
going outside of two degrees Celsius
fluctuations like in a small amount of
time I think it's fairly stressful to
the plants to deal with it to deal with
those changes just on their
transpiration rates and the amount of
energy they have to spend altering their
stomata maybe I'm wrong I don't really
have any data to back it up it's
speculation and research that I want to
see answers to and I don't care if I'm
right or not
and to him he thinks that it's it takes
so long for a plant to respond to a
change in temperature in the space that
by the time it's by the time it's really
realized that something's changed that
it's it's probably gonna have reached
equilibrium again in the space there's
just like these deliberations that go
back and forth about the micro mechanics
of what's happening in a plant when you
get people around each other that both
know a lot about it what are some of
your favorite cultivars to grow I am
fairly why well I prefer plants that are
shorter I'm not I love cannabis but I'm
not super well-versed on the genetics
that have been around I have with not
from California I'm not from a state
where it's like been really prevalent I
grew up in Georgia and Tennessee so it's
you know I've been learning a lot about
the different cultivars and genetics
that are available but I just really
like the the vertical racked intensive
growth model with small plants that are
put that don't have a long veg time and
are placed in placed into this
production model and can be turned over
a really fast rates
trying to explore what possibilities are
available in that space of doing
extremely closed canopy to canopies that
are really close to the lights that
plants that aren't allowed to grow very
tall so just like trying to see how we
can make really small plants that we can
grow at a massive amount of like
individual plants of to create one big
canopy in you know the sea of green
model but just shrinking the plants down
more and more and more but I think I get
that mentality just from like studying
how to grow plants for space transit
when I was in grad school so I'm just
like always and what did you learn about
plants in space it's very hard it's very
hard to water plants in space yeah it's
good you can't else you can't outsmart
it I think it's the system they have
right now there's a production module
called veggie there's two of them
actually on the space station I think
they just launched up the advanced plant
habitat which is one that's a lot more
versatile but the veggie was the one I
was working with and the way the
irrigation system works it's just like
it's a pea it's a piece of foam not all
the one on it's the one on the space
station is a little different it's it's
just like a reservoir that has a wet
surface on it and then you have these
little packets that have a porous
membrane on bottom they sit on this wet
surface they're full of like clay medium
with slow release fertilizers in it and
it just wicks up water of the out of
that wet surface and because there's no
restriction to capillary action where
water will climb something in space it's
only like limited by gravity pulling it
down so water will just climb stuff
indefinitely in space so we have this
like genius model of you know letting
the water just wake up so there's no
there's no free water moving at any
point it works okay it dries out
sometimes some there's also been an
incidents incident of water climbing up
the plant and kind of getting on the
leaves and coming out of the root zone
so there's that there was that aspect as
well so it's just it's hard and it's
well this state the spaces are there
conditions for human comfort and human
community and we don't really have
really good ways of scrubbing co2 that
are really effective I think they're
still just kind of running it through
like a sieve bed that they have to
change out so the co2 levels stay really
high on the space station that was kind
of what I focused my research on because
I happen to get a crop that was
extremely sensitive to high co2 levels
and had a real drop-off in productivity
and when I was reading what Rob was that
Chinese cabbage okay real fun like bok
choy type stuff yeah it looks just like
bok choy it was um called Tokyo Bay
Connor it's a real leafy soft Chinese
cabbage we also did dwarf Tomatoes but
they were we were just seeing so many
issues with the production system and it
was like it was a three month crop to
grow it was like we need to figure out
some of these other issues first because
we saw a lot of similar stressors on the
tomato crop as we saw in Chinese cabbage
which led me to kind of question the
entire idea of co2 injection like and
whether it was really beneficial which
it definitely increases yield that's
definitely been concluded for most crops
but there's also some stressors that it
creates some going through a lot of the
literature of like greenhouse tomato co2
enrichment studies you know they
mentioned they're like yeah but our co2
plants enriched plants had bunch of
lesions on their leaves and they were
turning yellow and brown and like there
was clear stress from from that being
the only different variable so kind of
led me to have a much more conservative
approach to co2 injection I don't think
you should go over 800 ppm cannabis grow
room I just don't think you're getting
much more for injecting any more than
800 Jessie what are your thoughts yeah
you know that's it's as far as co2
injection I I'm not gonna weigh in on
plants in space that's nowhere so
apologize but but you know as far as co2
injection and and I mean even going all
the way back to favorite cultivars and
plants I I don't I get asked that
question a good amount of time and I
think the real answer is all of them you
know there's there is something really
awesome about standing next to a
20-foot tall cannabis plant you know
that has a diameter of 45 or 65 feet
like those thing is just so impressive
to watch what that plant will do in such
a short timeframe if taken care of
or conversely being able to grow for
efficiency and look at what kind of
strains can we put in and at what height
and what level and what we can veg and
you know we found really cool stuff that
was just kind of oddly interesting like
you said about switching environments
where okay we're not gonna go cradle to
grave in the same rooms it's not
efficient so we're gonna have to move
them and are we gonna build a facility
where it's this we can monitor the
environment so closely that we bring
everything to that point and what is the
ROI on that to think that we could gain
how much if we're right we gain an extra
point zero three percent on the plants
yield and so over a 36 year period we're
gonna see an ROI on being able to
balance our environments through the
hallways you have knocking not gonna do
that right so being able to look at
figuring out things like we were growing
obviously vertically in the flower rooms
and we were growing vertically in veg
but if you took in veg our plants had
trays and our plants in flour had trays
but they didn't take up the entire rack
system because it moved over what was a
graded floor so the light in flour from
all the way up top would still filter
through the canopy in small spaces and
wind up getting to the plants on the
lower end so if we took our plants that
were in veg that were underneath where
the white really wasn't filtering from
up high in the same way and we put them
on the bottom where light was now
filtering from high in the flower they
would they would be a little more
stressed out not terribly but it would
take him a little more time to bounce
back yeah so we started learning that
our bottom row veg had to go to our top
row in the farm or at least in the
flower side and so going back but
looking at looking at giant outdoor
plants versus I was always a huge fan of
kind of the old school like super Silver
Haze yeah Hawaiian's snow like I love
the structure of those plants I love the
smell of those plants I love the size
that they'll get whether it's indoor or
out
but always being able to see those new
cultivars have come out where you know
the calyx color changes at a certain
time or their pigments change at certain
times or they produce very specific
terpenes at certain times I just I kind
of dork out about all of them yeah so
you know but like we were talking about
when looking at efficiencies and that's
that's where I think I I will sit around
for days and talk about it and try to
figure it out because just like when we
were growing in basements and it was
like you could see almost like a kinship
where you'd be in home depot you're
grabbing this little piece and that and
you're in your brain creating like an
engineering mastermind of how you're
going to get this system to work and
while you're doing it you'd realize oh
you're doing the same thing you - right
like oh I know you like you just get
that kind of look and I always wondered
if the home depot employees are like the
others like six growers over in the
plumbing online like I always really
appreciated that but you know this
industry right now was built off of
people that that for a lot of us that
has been our lives and so being able to
graduate that up to where you know it's
just an advancement of whether it's
standing in the home depot plumbing
aisle and bouncing back and forth
between that and the irrigation section
or it's you sitting with an architect
and a footprint of a building and
starting to consider how many foot steps
it takes and what the environment will
be for the plant in that transition and
how many square feet and you know even
yesterday I was talking to someone about
you know now we're looking at
cylindrical where the lighting isn't you
know which isn't new but we're looking
at vertical stacked where you use
cylindrical lighting and then create a
circle of plants around that are growing
into the light and we were talking about
that efficiency and once again there's a
problem because you have dead space
between every circle yeah so that's
square footage where I could have a plan
squares work better than circles in that
scenario yeah and so I just love being
able to really sit down and and go
through that because
I've had that question before when
speaking where people say like well so
you got to $189 a pound for indoor
cultivation and you said you could get
lower how did you do it as if I'm got
like some well here let me draw you a
picture and here's the answer like it's
not it's all those little pieces and I
think it's no different than growing and
you're feeding plants right like the
root zone of a plant and the way a plant
uptakes nutrient we have somewhat
recently figured out might as well be
the bottom of the ocean right we're
still making a lot of theory like we're
just realizing in the last decade or two
that we don't know as much about plants
as we thought we did
sure and then you know people always
show you that nutrient availability
graph by pH it's like oh well at low pH
this nutrient I don't like I love that
like that think that's for like outdoor
soil I don't know if that really applies
to Coco husks right and I remember
following that and being like I don't
understand I'm in the green zone why is
it not taking up the calcium yeah yeah
well maybe there's too much iron or
phosphorous area right and then there's
those random times that you know I can
remember hey we didn't realize the HVAC
unit went down and the plants spent all
day today at 109 degrees like it ramped
it up slowly then it didn't kill him but
man I went downstairs and there was you
know water dripping from the fixtures
and I was certain that you know bulbs
were gonna explode and oh my god and you
wind up with a 40 percent gain in your
yield
you can never duplicate it and it's like
what was it was it the temperature mixed
with the nutrient was it the humidity
was it the stage was it the and there's
you know it's like the end it's like the
endless question that growers always
have because we've all hit those crops
where we're like yeah I don't know what
I did
Kent I can't tell you we had a lucid
dream which was one of my favorite
strains to grow because it's really
really purple mm-hmm but it would also
produce really well and had a great
flavor and a great smoke and kind of a
black licorice smell to it almost
barbecue sauce sometimes which was
really interesting but uh it was always
you know 15 to
maybe 19% was its kind of THC range
which is I mean that's kind of right
what I would like and I hear that a lot
more now right thank God but we grew it
one at one point in time and had a heat
issue in the room or no not a heat issue
I'm sorry a light issue not heat because
that plant got really sensitive to heat
if you overheated it it would grow tiny
little popcorns and then morph out and
do a big problem but we'd had like a
nutrient or a light issue where I think
we had the timer's off and I don't
remember what the exact problem was but
that crop came out and tested it like
28% well then we could never duplicate
it again and we were keeping good notes
but you saw an all new genetic potential
in this plant that you thought was one
thing you know that's we always talk
about cultivars but you know I'm always
saying okay let's take your cultivar
let's grow it under blue red LEDs let's
grow it under broad spectrum LEDs it's
grown under a metal halide it's grown
under an HP s let's grow it outside and
then tell me which one's your cultivar
yeah yeah you know we had that fun game
with a sfv and I'm gonna butcher this No
yeah we had that sfv and og so we
brought you know we had a grower that
came in to facility and he's like I got
us sfv and it's so it's so dope and then
I got us oh gee cush and I'm super
stoked and then we put him in the rooms
and started growing him and a little bit
of time went by and I was like aw he's
the same plant
it's just ones grown by the ocean and
once grown in the valley right isn't sfv
San Fernando Valley and og cush is ocean
grown am i like making that up and no no
I think you're right and we kind of
research it like maybe we oh no that's
that's yeah that's what it is well then
what happens when you put them in the
same indoor environment and I can tell
you it takes about a year they become
the same plant yeah it was amazing to
watch where you're like you would get
people that were like oh yeah I'll take
the smv not the og and you would watch
harvest after harvest where they got
closer and closer and similarity to
where it was like well which one do you
want to get rid of yeah yeah it was cool
it's very adaptable and we definitely
stopped paying attention to that there's
but there's there's so much effect that
comes from the grower and from the
cultivation side and from the company
actually producing the flower you know
people are very often from the
dispensary level like oh we need this
strain and we need this strain it's know
you need this grower this brand these
people that are producing products for
you because that's what's really if
that's where the value comes from and I
think we'll get there oh yeah it's just
a matter of time but you know
necessity is what winds up breeding all
of that creation and it was an
interesting thing I was in talking to
some growers here in California about a
year ago a little over a year ago and
they were oh yeah we sell all our flower
for 2,800 pound all day long it's gonna
be at least three years market strong
Rekha's taken off
beautiful because I could tell you from
Oregon lessons that things can change
fast and now you're looking at the
slowdown in regulation epic crops for
outdoor season and all the over taxation
which is driving people who are sitting
on a maybe license
can't get there CU p and you're looking
at taxation that's now starting to weigh
in where for example in example in santa
barbara they've now said that you can
grow but you can't dry because it's fire
hazard well so who do you think is gonna
pay for that that's gonna go right to
the consumer so we've got a cultivation
tax before we send it to the dryer and
that does a dryer have a tax before he
sends it to the processor who has a tax
before they send it to the manufacturer
to put it in packaging who then has a
tax before they send it to the
distributor to send it out to the
dispensary who has a tax for the
consumer and once again now you have a
consumer who says you know I've been
buying bags from Jimmy for $40 that are
chronic my whole life you know and Jimmy
now separates his strains and I have a
total variety and I can still get a bag
for $40 or I can run all the way across
town in traffic because we only have
eight dispensaries in the whole
and I could pay $85 for a gram grown by
somebody I don't know with no clue what
the quality is because I can't see it in
the bag that that and support med men
yeah little bit of a problem well you
know at 38 cents a share I'd have been a
poor endeavor basically talking drying
curing and then presentation to the end
consumer and so I feel like in a modern
dispensary that lonely eight sitting on
a shelf by itself as a grower you're
kind of like it's like the least
impressive representation of what I'm
capable of and that's what people see
with my brand name on it versus if you
could pull it out of like a big bag full
of all its friends to hand to someone
right before they're about to smoke it
so we're talking right before the camera
was on and so years ago many many moons
ago we went through a raid at one of our
sister facilities and so the whole panic
ensues oh my god clean everything out
you know get rid of this like what
happens if and we were we were running
legal but it was still back in the times
where medical facilities were still
getting raided and so so we you know
stashed everything we could stash and
panicked and thankfully it was totally
fine nothing happened
fast-forward a year later I'm in my
horse barn I'm like moving stuff around
I get behind a door and I find a big old
blue bin and I'm like what's this doing
here
thinking it's a big bin a trim and I
pull it out and it's about 10 pounds of
LA and blackberry and it's all food
savored it's all been cured and sitting
in its food saver bags and it's quarter
pounds which is how I saved it and I was
like holy crap I lost this weed for a
year dude like so we open it up cut him
open check him out smells incredible
looks incredible had we were at the time
we were testing all the time
Cavani of the whole nine all the
cannabinoids and terpenoids THC it was
incredible and it sold like crazy at the
dispenser when I brought it out there
but it was kind of that fun game alike
as we've discussed carrying weed is an
art like it's it it is being able to you
know once again to dork out and be able
to get down to like the exact
temperature and the exact humidity
fluctuations and the water activity and
the moisture content for each strain I
think that you can really really get far
into that into understanding exactly how
to cure your cannabis perfectly so that
actually gets better over time if stored
properly
sure yeah there there is some mechanics
to pay attention to this isn't the only
product that needs to be dried and cured
you know they do it with tobacco beef
jerky and dried fruits and I mean
there's there's water activity
establishments for those and
particularly on the tobacco route and
even certain types of tea leaves that
are processed for a long periods of time
like you know they're paying attention
to enzymatic activity going on within
the tissue as its as its losing water
and there's a threshold where enzymatic
activity cuts off there's a threshold
also where mold growth cuts off and
there's a there's a window between there
where you could really slow down the
drying process and let the plant
continue to break itself down and remove
some of these like harsher chemicals and
if the just chlorophylls are not that
great to smoke they just are kind of
minty and but those will break down with
time and try and really trying to
identify those windows where you can
extend out the curing process or even
the drying process for a longer period
of time once you've cleared a window
where you're gonna where you might cause
harm to the crop so yeah there's a lot
and there's lots of details there that
we really need yeah there's it that once
again like add it to the list of
projects yeah you know and it's a fun
thing to think of to like we're talking
about with the the lonely 8th on the
shelf versus versus the joint and you
know like it's my own little personal
thing in the world but the joint is this
little enigma in the space that it kind
of drives me crazy because it's so
diverse and people don't the consumers
don't realize it like we're going to
very specifically grind up this part of
the plant in this fashion and do an ad
back of it the kief that came from that
plant in order to fashion this joint in
a way that is mixed down on on sieve
tables so that we have the right
particulate to burn and we're gonna do
it at scale and it's gonna be great and
meanwhile this person showed up at my
facility and they bought everything that
we weren't even gonna send to extract
that we were saving up because
eventually maybe we'll we'll burn it
down to distillate at some very small
amount and see if it's even worth it
because it's the stocks and the stems
and sugar leaf and leaf and you know
cannabis that was on the floor and they
pick it up and then put it through the
world's largest grinder and stuff it in
a joint and sell it for a the same or
less price and the consumer doesn't know
this there's nothing on the package that
lets you know that's what's going on no
there's a bunch of trim leaves in your
joint yeah that's all you're smoking
that's usually not really communicated
on the packaging and so the joint thing
is the joint world is really interesting
to me and in whoever figures out how to
crack that nut in reaching the consumer
and understanding what's what that joint
consists of and I don't know that it
ever happens right like I mean
cigarettes are still smoked in America
and the consumer knows what's in them
and so I don't know that that ever
happens
maybe there's always a specific price
point and if you want to get up and
above then you're looking at Kanna gars
you're looking at things that are at
that level but that it's one of the
idiosyncrasies in the industry at least
on the consumer side of things that I'm
really intrigued by because maybe we
grew a product that won't look great in
that lonely 8th on the shelf or when
it's getting down to the end we we
always like to grind those into into
joints and now great it's a pretty joint
it looks good it's good cannabis and
it's now competing with everything else
that nobody can identify yeah
you're just looking at labels yeah I I I
honestly prefer the model of all the big
jars I'm like behind behind the register
and let you get to actually like smell
all of the all the bud together and it
tends to hold a lot better smell that
way is I don't think people have really
dialed in airtight packaging as well as
they think they have because use most
the jars I've ever come into possession
of where that came from retail store
that were you know cellophane wrapped
we're really dry when I opened them and
they weren't even that old you know
that's I think there's still a lot of
work to do to actually make that jar
worth it as well yeah I can remember we
would use the big jars that we could put
a half pound in in any order them
they've got the great screw on lids this
is how we're gonna store cannabis we
first got into it we put it in the vault
when we first started the vault wasn't
temperature regulated and so one of our
strains I get in and see it and when I
take the lid off you can see what looks
like glue from the kind of padding
inside the lid and seal it is on the lid
and it started running down the side
there you are and we're like oh my god
how much of this if we destroyed as we
go through this panic phase a little bit
of like we have to get everything out of
these jars if it's glue and then you
start looking you realize wait a minute
look at these other lids there's no glue
on here where is this coming from and
that's when I got to learn the lesson
that terpenes don't taste as good as you
would think when you put them on your
tongue so take that lid and I'm like
what is that glue is it Oh God made a
mercy no and so it was skunk oil yeah
really cool to see that the right
packaging with like that we were
actually getting terpenes to wick out of
the product and on the jar was kind of
its own cool unique thing but it was
once again another lesson like oh
perhaps there's happening there yeah I
mean perhaps there's a better way for it
to be stored at the on site to where
it's not that's not a happening that
it's not experiencing temperatures that
would result in volatility of those
terpenes you know I always see these
charts that say this is the combustion
temperature
for this terpene and you know people
really follow that but I'm like but
what's the like low threshold of
volatility of that terpene when it
starts off gassing you know that's
something I haven't really seen a lot of
data for combustion temperature is one
thing but you know I it seems like it
would be nice if you were if you're
providing a brand to a dispensary that
perhaps you can decide how your product
is stored at that site and you can you
know you know even in like convenience
stores you know like a soda company will
have their own cooler that they keep
their products and because it's how they
want it to be presented you know I think
that model could be interesting as well
just mostly just for how the products
actually kept right but like we're
talking about earlier now you start
getting into that like okay I'm building
a cultivation facility trim dry cure
storage my vault okay my volt needs a
temperature store but wait
okay beta Mersin starts to be volatile
at this temperature but pining is
volatile at this temperature and I don't
want to store them both in the same volt
so how many volts how much space do I
need for storage and then where do I
draw that line and and then once again
looking at that enzymatic breakdown
process compared to the water activity
which ceases mold production and where
that window is and how I can affect my
care rooms and like we were talking
about like you start getting into all of
this and figuring out how to design a
facility that either can do this at the
time which is really expensive or can be
scaled into it without interrupting
operations it's it's intimidating yeah
it is but it's also in my tiny man brain
crazy fun that's the fun part if you
have the capital to do it that that it's
these are the coolest projects
especially at this time in the world in
the industry and the society that we
live in like these are really cutting
edge topics it's I just want to see more
of it I want to participate in it and
yeah it's really exciting yeah it's
gonna happen one way or another it's
just you know there's going to be
someone out there screaming at their
television when they see that you know
Monsanto or Bayer or someone of this
nature has solved the riddle of curing
blah blah blah and they're like I've
been doing that for the last years and
no one I can you know yeah I can see all
of the hard work in some aspects
potentially being stolen away from those
who were kind of the creators of it by
those who have that clout but and once
again and I think we've talked about
this before or at least I've talked
about it before but that's where the
fight is right like you don't just roll
over and say well one day big
corporations and big cannabis are gonna
tear all this apart and none of us are
gonna be left and it's all gonna be
horrible go be the big corporation no
become that person and then just behave
accordingly yeah exactly it's possible
yeah that's that's this all can come
from there so just quickly can you talk
about your approach to drying and curing
like what what what humidity and
temperatures are you in in the drive
phase and for how long and then like how
do you approach curing yeah I mean well
so I will preface this by saying I
believe the drying and curing that is an
art that I would say is definitely my
weakest and it's only because it's so
meticulous and I didn't get the chance
when I was at that level of cultivation
to have access to the tools and the
knowledge to be able to start
understanding those breakdown processes
really appropriately so like most of us
depending on the strain I like to live
in that you know 55 to 65 percent
humidity range that slowly eats down or
up but at the smallest increments
possible is to not make drastic changes
and to live right around that 60 degree
mark 60 to 65 depending on the strain
and the density and once again I would
say the biggest thing that at least it's
been my experience is when you
accidentally over dry and so oh my god
let's throw a bunch of water on the
floor because this is all gonna turn to
dust when we trim it those huge
fluctuations in temperature and those
huge fluctuations in humidity
those are what cost you your terpenes
yeah those are what wind up where you're
like great I saved the crop and it has
no smell whatsoever you know so in
saying that you know curing and drying
is definitely an art form and it's it's
something
the biggest lesson I think we learned at
eco was as we built the facility out
budgetary wise the last thing we
addressed was trim dry cure we didn't
have the money to build it in
equivalency to how we built our flower
rooms and it was it cost us 100 percent
was a it was a mistake and I wouldn't
say was a mistake in the sense of oh we
should have put more money here we just
didn't have capital but we just didn't
and then we got investors and we got a
sale and everything was gonna be perfect
and and of course it wasn't but you know
if you're out there cultivating and
you're looking at building a facility
that's definitely not where you need to
not sync money but that being said well
okay if I'm gonna have a shortfall what
do I do
I don't have an answer for you like you
just can't have a shortfall yeah I think
an industry-standard ideal is 60 60
that's what most people are shooting for
I'm saying I'm around that range I
always try to drive the temperature down
as much as possible without preventing
it from drying I mean you get more
terpene preservation and colder
temperatures you're less likely to
overdraw it's just making sure that you
don't get it so cold like down below 50
degrees where it's just pretty much not
gonna dry at all
and then if you do want to run at those
temperatures your HVAC costs spikes
intensely to actually be able to to pull
moisture out at that temperature is
really difficult because most of our
besides you know drying liquid desiccant
systems which are crazy expensive and
not really user-friendly for most people
we really rely on just condensation of
these like cold refrigerants to pull
moisture out of the air and they have
their limitations there's some
mechanisms that are you know like anti
freeze mechanisms and the compressor and
the compressors too I'm not sure but
they have these like anti freeze
mechanisms to prevent the machine from
locking up and you know that's an
adaptation but it's still just like
trying to create all these like muscles
around the basic concept of just a
compressor that's moving refrigerant
through some coils and so there's just
limitations to what we can actually do
I think that it's I think something that
people are opening their mind up to is
drying and curing kind of on the line
like and together trying to create a
room that can also be the that can
create some sort of curing process as
well or you you can alter your
conditions inside that space to prolong
the breakdown of the crop which could be
done by you know dropping the
temperature letting the humidity come up
just a little bit once the products like
you know at a safe level for them for
microbial content after water activity
level measurement and and yeah just
trying to kind of like put those two
processes together to where you can get
a pretty decent product it's ready to go
into a package without having to have
these separate compartments in your
facility and also a important you know
it's all linked pre-harvest treatment of
your plant has a lot to do with your
drawing care out results you know how
much it was water how much nutrients it
was given towards the end of its life if
it was like just dumped full of nitrogen
until it's the last few days of its
lifecycle that's gonna be a long cure if
it does it's it's gonna take a long time
to break all that down all the nitrate
levels in the chlorophyll spike that
occurs from feeding a ton of nitrate to
a plant sometimes they just start
putting on new flowers and it you get
these slick little worms fingering what
people have tons of different words for
calling it where that's just these
little shoots coming off the flowers
late cycle that looks like it's starting
all over
and it's mostly from nutrients there's
other stressors that'll do it but you
know so knowing knowing what to pull out
of your root system and how to kind of
like starve out your plant a little bit
towards the end but then again that's
really just talking about smokeable
flower products is that really necessary
when you're when you're just doing it
for extracts you know what questions we
need answers to yeah it's a good point
and once again it's it's just another
one of the list of projects yeah you
know like and that that's where that
whole and not only is a list of projects
but that's where that whole consumer
education comes in again too so from
consumer being the disc
sorry too consumer being the consumer
but when you do do that research and we
have gotten there and okay we've put in
the time and the money we've created
facility and we've done the research and
we know how to cure each strain
perfectly for its terpene preservation
and we can keep it on-site and cured in
this environment for a year and then
we're gonna start selling it like fine
wine to who because we haven't nobody's
really figured out yet that to come in
and find a perfectly cured super Silver
Haze that is vintage 2017 and it's two
hundred and eighty six dollars a gram
because it's like so perfect that that
market doesn't exist yet yeah at least
not at a large enough scale so you get
to solve both riddles yeah it's it's
definitely a small community that's
after that market right now but it will
come around
yeah it's on its way just a matter of
time so what consumers value versus what
you would like them to value I feel like
people you know bag appeal and numbers
is kind of what drives what people pick
in the shops yeah I mean so for one I'd
like to say of what what consumers value
I want consumers to value what makes
them happy right if what makes you happy
as a consumer is to get in and your
experience takes you you know 27 seconds
out of your day I just want to grab that
package oints and go I don't care to
know all of this stuff about it it's
just I just want that package oints oh
that's that is great like I want you to
just have the experience you want to be
happy with what exists out there so that
being said it you know I think that it's
our duty as an industry as a whole to
just make sure all the information is
there you know if a consumer comes into
a dispenser who's looking for you know a
wedding gift
that is very unique and they want to
understand like is there something like
a three-year-old cured cannabis does it
matter like
we are reaching that phase finally where
I just want whatever's got the most THC
that doesn't it's not quite as popular
anymore in some of the more advanced
markets we are starting to see people
who that's not what they're shopping for
you don't go to the liquor store just to
buy grain alcohol over and over and over
again but that being said what are we
addressing what is the consumer saying
and what the highest THD number well why
because I want to be as high as possible
well what is as high as possible like
what do you call as high as possible I
want to be so high that I can't get off
my couch for an hour versus I want to be
so high that I spent an hour looking for
my sunglasses that were on my face those
are very very different strains and they
have very little to do with the THC
content necessarily so I think that it's
incumbent upon us to start to get that
information out there because right now
the industry so new a lot of consumers
don't know that that exists and so they
can't want it because they just don't
realize it's there sure and you can't
reliably with it without having a really
good company providing the product you
can't reliably find that same experience
every time you go to the store it's
always a different harvest it's always a
different batch it's always a different
brand being carried you know to actually
be able to trace what it is that you're
after is difficult you know so it's like
every time you go in there you've only
got so many metrics to go off of and
often high THC content is something that
people would use is like well they do
something they were what they were doing
while they grew it I mean it came out at
12% he brought leads like there's a good
chance that you messed something up
there's not a lot of people trying to
grow a strain that's supposed to be 12%
so it is it's just not what they
wouldn't think that that would be
marketable to people but every week and
month that goes by I hear more people
telling me yeah I really like finding
more balance strains than that just kind
of work with my physiology a lot better
and make me feel relaxed and you know
and a lot of people just have been
feeling anxiety from different strains
and I wonder why that is and so I would
just I would want people to just be much
more aware of what go what's in the
product that they're buying and paying
more attention to where it's coming from
and being concerned about
and and voicing their opinion about that
to people they're buying it from and you
know making that be more known so that
they can actually rely on an experience
that they're looking for
yeah and it's it's an interesting thing
too because you think of it culturally
and it has been my experience that
typically if you're looking at a strain
that's you know in the mid to upper 20
percentile of THC and it's really high
in beta Mersin and maybe even a little
high in CBN if you're prone to paranoia
or anxiety those tend to do that I've
seen that do that to people who are that
way
it's a lot substantially less often that
I hear somebody tell me about a strain
that is you know 22% and smelled like
like limes that also gave them anxiety
and so I do believe there's a link there
in that beta Mersin but that being said
it's kind of like I look at it like
tequila like when you say tequila
culturally here in the United States
people go to one place in their head
which is why I can't drink tequila
it makes me mean or yeah I love tequila
it's great but there is tequila the word
tequila and the thought of tequila has
it has like a urban culture amongst the
drinking crowd where did that come from
there isn't I'm not aware of a
scientific study that I read at some
point in time that said tequila accesses
your amygdala in a certain way or your
limbic system it's so why does tequila
make people mean is is it just over time
eventually it's culturally accepted
because it happens so much over time
when we get to a place where people go
oh yeah baby mercy no I don't smoke that
yeah I don't know I don't know how that
information gets out I don't know how
that's cycles around I can tell you from
my life as a firefighter when we go when
we have gone when I have gone on calls
in the past with people who have
consumed too much cannabis through
smoking and they're freaking out
I will typically once once week
have a conversation which just the fact
that you have an emergency worker
present somebody wearing a badge that
has some sympathy tends to calm people
down a little bit until the police show
up sorry guys but no I'm just kidding
but it tends to be when you talk to them
I'll have a discussion about beta mercy
and the strains that they were smoking
and it always turns out the same well I
you know I like to get really high THC
and well you know I was smoking gorilla
glue I was smoking and not bad-mouthing
any of these strengths or great strains
and just for them they always tend to
point to high beta Mersin strains and
every one of them that I've said hey
let's steer away from that maybe steer
yourself towards these type of strains
I've never seen that patient again and
maybe that's coincidental or maybe not
but there's something to be said I think
for the way and that's not for everybody
once again like some people I'm sure
experienced high anxiety from CBD or
anything random it's all on your own
body chemistry but I do think that there
are some as we're starting to get
through this I think that there are some
norms out there as a whole that are
starting to kind of pop up yeah so I
guess just like people to realize that
there's a tremendous diversity of how
cannabis can make you feel depending on
the strain that's the chemo type and how
it was cultivated how it was dried and
processed and the overall quality of the
production process all plays into the
end outcome of how it's going to affect
you and it'd be nice for them to pay
more attention to that be looking for
that be asking for that and also be able
to rely on that being you know
consistent yeah yeah and that's a
responsibility on all of us right we
have to create that we have to create
the space where when you go buy a Grey
Goose vodka you know what you're getting
every time Grey Goose exists and and
it's sitting next to kettle one it's
sitting next to these top shelfs of
vodkas and as we all know that it sits
in that place it sits at that level and
when you're looking at the HRD and that
Night Train like they all said it's with
people need that yeah there's no problem
with that the same company could produce
both
but it's incumbent upon us as an
industry to start creating those lines
for the consumer yeah it'd be really
nice for us to get some some hard
categories to start putting strains into
it that is gonna be quite the argument
oh yes we still can't get over indica
sativa so chemo types perhaps maybe
maybe but once again that's a it's a
long path of Education