hi everybody
i got the brand thingy let's drop that
say hello i got a fun day for everybody
today
uh we are going live here
um
we are going live with everybody here at
the
borough and beyond we've got markets
we've got some good people uh coming
along we've got the team coming over
from the guerrero grow show to visit us
we're gonna have a ton of giveaways
happening throughout the day um so don't
miss out on what is going to be a badass
show uh where am i here
oh see bing giveaways lots of fun stuff
we'll we'll start off right off the bat
by saying thank you to our sponsor green
amber canada who are supporting jonathan
will be along for a visit today which is
very very exciting um i of course there
is no intro thing for me because i am i
am the guy with the with the stuff in
the usual things
so as they hop on i will give this
little addition to the stream
and go full bar as we slowly set up the
day and get comfortable and ready to go
like we mentioned we are just getting
warmed up
i'm going to run some mics over and get
the cum of this conversation
all right guys we got some sesh stuff
coming up we got everything ready to go
we're gonna say thanks to a sponsor
we're gonna hop over right now oh who's
that
hello peter how are you
hello boys and girls
uh here which one do i want to do the
this one
uh we're gonna go i'm gonna walk over to
david over at trim chest and press where
is he
i have him in here with a mic
with a microphone is that the orange
kit
yes the orange photonics light labs
uh the really really cool one so we're
gonna we're gonna
chill out with dave roberts for a few
minutes
um go through
some trying and some smelling and
there's a whole bunch of people you can
see marcus on the right there jeff
therefore beyond vancouver island
homegrowers justin's just off to the
right um but we're gonna drag everybody
over here and get get get started
all right this is cool i got a secondary
i gotta make sure my phone's hooked up
too so that everything's ready to go
so this is vancouver island
come say hi and hop on camera and sit
over there no this over here we're going
to go through we're going to test some
stuff we're going to i got a but i got
like six phenos of one strain
that we go through and press and kind of
see i'd love your guys's opinion on that
um
which is good let me see here i gotta
wait for ken to get in still but
so you know what camera
so you know what camera you what what
phone you're on here
yeah that's the camera that's facing
here i'm going to adjust them a little
bit in a second
oh you know what i just got recently i
got a camera cart
i think so jeff jeff said to park along
the side you might want to ask him it's
just
his spot there yeah
just getting this little bit up
i can't hear you peter if that's what
you're looking for ken hasn't quite
arrived yet so we're figuring that part
out
oh it's kenny coming oh there's ken
are you showing up in person
hey brother good to see you come here
come here come here come here
i want you on on the camera right here
okay first first and foremost
happy little treats you have a good trip
oh yeah
let me just switch up my camera here and
what bob ross
in the shade i made sure that you were
cool and good to go we got ken coming in
take over and jump on our camera and i'm
gonna wrestle some babies to get them
into our show and get them rolling
all right here you go brother
uh actually you're here
bob ross you're my communication point
um
if you need a microphone you're probably
gonna have to throw it
okay i got another headset with a
microphone or you let me know if
yeah
you let me know just because the audio
is all streaming through the device here
yeah don't touch any buttons
looking into it and then i met like jill
carrero online who's the sales rep for
tonight and we just started going
through all the courses but we're
already taking selfies
you got to get the narcissistic so it
holds your phone further
um
happy little trees
happy happy little trees
oh the the lps are super keen on this
machine so
i i've had the pleasure of working with
a few and they do what they call
business intelligence so like
r d on some other stores and stuff um
and then i come in and i run some
samples for them and then they get all
their data and away they go so cool man
it it
kills this
time you use it it just gives you a
marker so you really need like this
right news my friend has one at his uh
hemp farm in uh
in abbotsford oh super cool yeah bc hops
those guys oh cool like dwayne and tyler
mosher
they have this machine in there
i wonder if they said it was better for
thc than cbd though they said that cbd
it falled it fell a little short for thc
much better thc it's off by like point
zero four percent right uh with um
concentrates it's off by point three
five percent but with cdd i think it's
about one percent which is pretty which
is a little higher yeah especially when
they're dealing with like one and two
percent cbd's well and that's it right
like that doesn't even hit a little
canadian hemp does not have the highest
cbd content right it does do a
semi-quantitative terpene analysis here
we know so like low is from zero to one
is there anybody out there yeah i hear
you
okay there we go peter
the turkey
buddy good to see you
usually when it soaks up some wi-fi you
have a little keyword
yeah i've got 15 minutes
there you are and there's oh my gosh
so i'll take a little butt off of that
i'll run it through the moisture
balancer i'll wait until i'm getting a
read on the voice balancer i'll go back
to that
where i just took that little butt off
the bottom of it snip off the rest of
the nut grind it up yourself
i like when people stand in front of the
camera doesn't matter
yeah exactly i'm just uh lp wants me
there at 8 30 every friday because
that's when they water their plants like
an hour in advance so every time
standing in front
i finally got to actually enjoy his medi
kush here the last couple of days
man johnny's got a nice head of hair fun
stuff oh yeah yeah yeah so
like when i try to find it yeah yeah
definitely
they'll be like
i know lily was calling me going uh you
guys starting on time were you guys
gonna be late
12 is what they all like to attend
yeah but i'm an extractor yeah it's like
why would i want to pay ten percent so
are you guys hearing anything that's
going on through the cameras uh on that
end yeah we're live
hey justin you want to see your results
buddy yeah okay so
um
26.7 thc so let's just have a look at
the total holy shit
if you send mac one to high north it'll
be like 36 percent
i will not comment on anyone else's lab
i will not
it's right in the name uh
your moisture content was 19.4 so really
dry on the outside once
[Music]
that's great um and you smash it too
right so you want your trichomes to be
nice and clean can you hear me all right
coming through there
yeah okay okay they can hear you
everything is
telling you yes i'm sorry i had someone
ask for their money back recently
because their shit got darker than the
picture that we originally put up how
long was it from the time you gave it to
them well i keep everything at like -40
but the minute it leaves my facility it
goes into a truck then it goes to a
facility then it goes to the province
then it goes to a store none of them are
cool
none of them cool it and it's like 30
degrees outside
so yeah this guy was like this is bunk
it's all dark and so i took like a macro
photograph of it bullshit
i mean
he sent me a picture that made it look
like some shitty bullshit black hat
here this is what it looks like under
the microscope totally is that's way too
dark
full about full mel bubble though just
beautiful dudes like i want my money
back i'm like did it affect the taste
the potency no anything
this is just propeller i'm like you're
gonna ask you're
are you you have to he'll go on reddit
and start a post oh yeah
how much money you're talking about that
was like 50 bucks or whatever
so there's a whole group end user yeah
yes buying a gram from a fucking
like the picture he sent me was horrific
looking he took a shitty blurry picture
with his cell phone from a distance so i
was like i'll take a picture of the same
hash and send it back to him oh you
didn't listen
i'm just going to run this next time
um
just now which is what justin brought
with him fucking beverages he was about
24 thc it was really nice but
we ran through the moisture analyzer and
even though it felt really dry on the
outside it was 19.7 so
right like if you're buying weight you
kind of want to know what your moisture
level is
i'm loving the conversation this is
great
i like that actually oh dude trust me
because instagram right when it's like
oh my god like
i inadvertently created most of these
morons
that was even the worst part
[Music]
because of my dislocated wrist right
do any shaking so i got a little tattoo
and shaker good
call i've had four of them break in like
a month and a half they're like the
cheapest pieces of shit so we need like
a cheap so you want to smell worthy
and it looks like it looks like a scale
ladies and gentlemen
we're waiting for results
for the next
yeah i don't think you guys realize
we're live right now
dude you might want to see my fucking
conversation was fucking awesome i just
wanted you to know that was right let's
get back let's get back to the
conversation yeah
you can get all these ones
that has like the magnetic field as well
from the bottom
for this you want to you really want to
shake it yeah i want to show you and
ideally like a vortex
it's not the prettiest of the plants but
the aroma profile i don't even care what
it looks like i don't care about it
but what color is it we're going to
switch it up that weed is way too green
for my liking
can you see that shit
weird eh i know people are wondering
people wondering
if you know that you're lives right now
listen anytime i've ever been around
london
i've been live always a camera every
single time
a couple things one
have london bring the audio level down a
little bit
chris do you agree that the audio level
is i agree it's really loud okay now
and that well
and then bring the video back i don't
know what just happened
and then also tell them to shut the hell
up
okay how much does your machine go
everybody else
one conversation at a time
i want to hear everything
i love the dirty laundry uh conversation
in the back
tell me more
tell me more please
really
i was like this is so great
i'm loving this
oh this is great all right here we go i
use that yeti pro and i press about 250
streams
and i have two of them
i'm doing half a kilo
so uh ken
if you can hear me
uh tell london that we have no cameras
right now
[Music]
it took me about a pound and a half to
and we had two cameras that were at the
same uh angle
yeah there we go
okay okay we got one angle that's it
that's what you get when you get right
back into the instagram right where
they're like oh yeah well i don't want
to fuck with those guys
so you can scan that and then you ever
see them posted much more than a couple
grams oh no like all these cash makers
very rarely
but most people are just like oh i made
this i made and it's like great you can
sort out your neighbor yeah but how
about the country yeah that would take
care of your state you're going to take
care of your county different stories
and you take care of your block
you know like those are different things
and the people that take care of their
brother only yeah they are very critical
of the people who are trying to take oh
my god hundred percent listen 100 the
thing i know about this industry is
there's people who are critical and
opinionated oh of the wazoo everybody
everybody grows the best weed everyone
grows you know what though in my opinion
if you're growing your own weed and
smoking it you're growing the best weed
human relationship absolutely totally
but
that guy is different than the guy
that's got a hundred likes
oh oh a hundred percent yeah
yeah exactly
seventy trying to grow to scale is
completely different like yeah no not
for me this kid at good farm for the
farm that's a 48 north owned he was
young he was like 25 years old or
something okay and he planted like 277
000 seeds it's like his first big
outdoor they did 77 acres
and he was like oh you can see like
these ones are okay these ones are a
little bit rough and he's kind of like
talking himself down he's going to look
at the best and i'm like dude
are you kidding me like bro
i'm like
[Music]
yeah the hermes came from a mutual
friend of ours who sold him uh auto
flowering ones that ended up perming in
one corner
dude i was blown away we were driving
through it in a golf cart and it was
like being in morocco yeah
it was just as far as the eye can see it
was just like
turning around already
60 acres yeah a lot and 60 acres of
nugget this big let's see what the fuck
football are those containers
that was speakeasy
did you guys hear me at all
oh yeah
[Music]
those are like
five thousand dollars each four to five
thousand each one of those are like
those are each one of those the little
one on the right here is only five eight
hundred people of someone
there's some really reasonably priced
ones actually
oh yeah so so it's like five hulk
american
oh you guys are on vancouver island
we're on the mainland of vancouver
[Applause]
it's in canada it's in canada it's in
canada it's in canada it's in canada
it's in canada
i think remind myself that's in canada
that's not really
beautiful uh it's only like that for a
couple months and then it
is like
white
because like
snow
so
you gotta remind yourself
i think we got 13.98 grams of whatever
jar you gave me
yeah it is a little wet so i'm not
expecting the highest return i'm going
to use a some of it's going to be a
little bit moisture based but um once we
press like we're probably going to take
this parchment and put it into the
fridge to cool it down simply because
it's fucking 30 degrees out here uh not
ideal pressing weather i could save it
it's going to be a 120 micron bag so
we'll see what we get out of it and then
we'll just do a fresh tab
hell yeah
you can go through impressions
dude absolutely how was that stuff that
i pressed for you last time beautiful it
went very quickly for a year and a half
yeah i think i was watching you the next
day online i think i saw you sort of
taking tokens when you were talking
about
the italian guys
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah i'll get it
done tomorrow
doing some 14 grammers there we're gonna
do a 14 grammer here all right a nice
little one oh yeah yeah
okay
has come a long way over the years man
i'll never forget when phil just sort of
like was
he was like
he was doing the parchment with 14 grams
on the way to the flour and he was
making he was just taking bubble and
just turning it into a sheet that he
could dab that's it and he ran out of
bubble and he just randomly was like i'm
going to do this to a butt he doesn't
even know why he did
it and he just kind of did one of these
and when he opened it up and his dad
were like what the fuck i fucking love
dropped
around oh my god just like
started a whole new scene that's kind of
how you feel like the flower would have
been discovered to begin with right
someone rubbing against it working and
it was open source if this was an open
source if one guy discovered this and
never shared it oh yeah it would none of
us would be doing this because
there really is a very small percentage
eventually innovators are like the 0.1
percent
and the rest are 99.9
that seems like a good idea i'll do that
yeah which is fine too right that's how
it spreads that's how like if one guy
both invents something exactly and he
doesn't have the distribution he doesn't
have the network to get it out
you know you need to get it to a guy
that maybe isn't the innovator but
totally has the distribution network
knows all the people can put it i mean
phil had put it on his instagram for
i think it had been out there for a
couple of weeks and it was spreading but
when he came on hash church
and he showed that process
there were machines a week later
there were rosin companies a month later
and then it was just like bag companies
like everything was just like
exponentially fast because i was like 30
or 40 000 people got exposed to it in
like
a two-hour period
over here so we're doing it uh
182.
that's a real press yeah it's a serious
old-school press
dude my press is
the people that are like
this is the other thing about the
instagram
kind of career where it's like i'm on
he's pressing at 180 right now yeah i
took that 180. yep and i pressed through
it too i'll be about my press yeah
probably increases yield by 30
characters
when you do two grades and you test them
both yeah they're a fraction of the
difference
oh yeah the color of them so what we
have over here was beer
moisture 22.2 percent
okay can you guys hear me now one point
two percent yes so depending on the
temperature might it depends on the
terps
mark
mark because terps only make up the
price your very results are up brother
yeah these are your numbers for your
vera
terpenes 21gs
can you write your email down here
brother i absolutely can i'm going to
email you the results oh great unless of
course if you want you can just scan
that qr code and then whoever wants to
see yeah
so everybody knows that that strain is
20 how many years old is that 20 years
old
is his mother's strain that he's passed
around for 20 years so it's it's an old
old plant that's pretty cool man
a lot of that
i've been wanting to grow something like
that old i've got stuff that's like five
six seven years but nothing in like the
double digits that's like an old clone
or just old flowers
i planted some 25 year old ones from
jamaica i had an old hash plant from
like back in the day
and it it it grew but it was a mutant
and it never i could never get it to
grow like what it was so i just let it
go
but i i i
popped a lamb lamb's bread from jamaica
dude that's one of my fucking favorites
as well
i can't even believe that that's so cool
i can't wait to get that email here
it was just and it obviously it was from
seed so it was obviously still
when you have a 400 500 banger
and you put flower rosin in it
it's really hard to clean
hash rosin just
cleans right out flower rosin does not
when you dunk the whole thing into the
alcohol and you pull it out you can
still see this yellow
which is uh
yeah
dude can we throw that in the interface
why potency-wise i don't mind at all i
just hate the idea of ruining my manga
[Music]
that's
well i've got that for now i don't know
what happened to my jiffy marker but
here it is it's different
okay so it's very poor so what happens
is don't do it on top there dude to the
side
i don't want the ink to run through just
blowing
that's why
[Applause]
well that tastes nice
yeah absolutely um
and start testing it's no rush
i'm gonna test that too though i wanna i
wanna test that
so we can find out what it came out of
us i got some weed on me that i have
tested by pure love to see what this
says cheers
um i'll do a moisture analysis on it
a brand new one
i love that you're doing this
[Laughter]
[Music]
and i've seen that over time and i've
squished that with my farm 58 we've been
here
she's saying this push rates yeah yeah
what's your favorite yeah me my favorite
180 an acre no i mean um
oh moisture level is probably like 62.
um
yeah 62. but when i balance it like i'm
usually getting i'm doing like seven
percent eight percent moisture content
so when i use my balancer and it's
telling me it's like anywhere between
seven and
ten percent that's the best for like
actual moisture weight like moisture
content
for smoking
for smashing for squishings so what's
that moisture content at an aw level
let's work on these numbers
like dry as fuck
i use my balancer to tell me so all i
know is it tells me
yeah i seem to um
[Music]
let's
i ride ktms i got the uh
the fp350 okay i have the xexcfw
and the exc450
so i got a low ratio line
oh beautiful
i don't know i i'm
rocking
yeah
is
is change certain nutrients or because
where's the flavor so they won't go back
back and then like there's the flavors
oh shit so you've been growing within
the last decade you change it you're
going to change your flavor listen our
new chemist or old chemist was amazing
our new chemist is fucking magic dude
yeah
absolutely
here okay i'll just take this for a
moisture balance and then i'm gonna say
we've been inflating the shit out of
that yeah i was poking it i was like
rubbing it using it making it feel all
lovely that won't affect rosin there you
go you finger fuck it to death and i'll
still press all the rubs
put it in a warm room and let it let the
heads melt i'll still get it off
oh
i got some el chapo i'll give you okay
i just finished eating around the old
chapel i don't know it's kind of funny
that yeah
well he's in prison being forgotten
about it
kind of like he had a good run dude but
now you're kind of a nobody
the kids get more uh attention
different
it looks very different looks almost
like
it's very small from the front you can't
tell because it's all buried underground
oh this is all this whole side
comes up over the building on the whole
other side
wonderful
because they're just they don't really
want me to succeed
no they don't
oh yeah
i mean nobody could have shipped the bag
this hard
like not on
[Music]
yeah that's how you make the money yeah
you gotta
so the only way to make it is when you
sell it and then it's in your in your
account yeah exactly so you got out that
was great which is the rarity so that's
what mushrooms did they went from
fucking yeah
[Music]
but are we getting better audio with the
snowball now
i don't get anything shit
not so much sometimes
yeah
some people are doing okay but right now
if you're just doing okay you're getting
you're killing it if you're doing okay
you're killing me exactly
that's the reality of it right now
and if you can just get through this
this whatever this time is gonna be it's
so hot up here
[Music]
they do they do they do every every year
india goes to 50 degrees like every
april and may what was it
[Laughter]
what people do in hot temperatures
telling you just a shitty fan this big
that was like broken it was 42 degrees
in thailand and i just i had it right
next to my bed and i just put my head
here but it was just blowing them i just
needed to keep my brain
that's that's
it
your body
yeah when you start like taking off all
your clothes and being like insane yeah
and too hot is the same thing
okay
he just brought a kid back from losing
his eyesight with gold uh
yeah yeah the kid's eyesight was just
going so i'm doing a whole thing to do
in ice baths
with him well yeah it's going to be part
of the house like you're paying to do a
seminar with yeah i'll pay for it
yeah i'll just do it
i'm doing
no but he's got youtube videos galore
yeah you breathe you go on you start
breathing you start meditating he's been
teaching people how to do it
i might actually i might actually use no
go ahead and use that because i might i
was going to use that as the test for
the um concentration
yeah we were going to test that too
because he's got one of the news
do you know where they live with him on
screen can i steal something to hit go
ahead to try out oh that was the grease
monkey the special one the live room
[Laughter]
it shouldn't be any further than right
here which is the real thing is that is
that okay we're calling it
guys
on it john
you want any notes in it
[Music]
there are i'm gonna pick your brain for
a contact for that big yeah
on the side tab for the branch which one
you want
markers
and you pop them up i'll put the guys
jeff burrow
nice guy throw his name
this was uh last season so
yeah
yeah last season we're gonna air that
next episode i got some grease monkey
here
um
yeah exactly everyone thinks they can
turn them off i'll do that way faster
yeah oh i'm good now how's that going
what happened there
dude it's always just one foot in front
of the other leg dude it doesn't take
much i'll tell you like the leadership
team i had when we were talking to you
they almost just crazy so we will get
absolutely fine we'll get into it yeah
we will go absolutely more and the the
more honest the real yeah
ken if you can hear me
uh you gotta tell london that he has to
bring the the volume down of the shock
or the mic that's over by the uh
by the orange device and he has to bring
his mic levels up because we're hearing
the conversat we're hearing
this conversation
not this conversation
i definitely was one of those people
that had screaming hot dabs back in the
day and we've all evolved from somewhere
it's you know it comes from a time on a
titanium nail where it's like bro it's
not red anymore it's it's good to go now
you know
now you know we have temperature devices
where you create dab right and uh
of course you want a good uh
oh yeah dude i don't know where the
lineup starts or ends i'm just having a
good time
i lost all the uh sound
three weeks ago it smashed into the
mountains
chris
i i don't know if you're she'll be
coming too nicely now
should be better anyway you're not going
to hear anything on your right yeah okay
yeah i
can you guys hear me a little bit better
am i coming through a little bit clearer
too loud tell him to bring the volume
down a little bit
bring the ball i can you guys
hear him on mine
yeah that's fine
how about now you come in am i coming
through all right that's perfect
perfect
how about now guys am i coming through
okay yes you're still coming through
yeah i got i got a nod from peter yeah
beautiful
beautiful how are you how are you how's
jeff coming through probably a lot check
out chester
we really wanted to give an opportunity
to get into this and try it so i've got
some grease monkey
live resin here
beautiful trim dress impressive there
president it's just absolutely gorgeous
i'm gonna see if i can give you a good
view of the
just absolute gorgeous crazy on the
color i feel terrible holding it in the
sun right now i feel like it's the worst
thing you could ever do drug abuse
i love this you position your cup to
hide it i really gotta i'm gonna have a
go on this so i'm gonna try this hippo
glass i'm super super pumped
all right go ahead and scoop your
preferred size of dab i'm just going to
heat this up again because there's a
little bit of wind
so hippo is a really nice guy he's got
an epic long beard too and he's uh you
know one of the coolest glass blowers
he's been doing it for over 25 years now
so really high quality um glass coming
from him he uses a lot of gold and
silver so as you can see there's quite
an interesting technique used with this
uh with this piece maybe you can get a
close-up later on but there's uh it's
like beautiful like feathering and it's
all done with gold and silver infused
into clear glass and then the middle
part is uh gold and silver over like a
jet black color so you can get different
color uh schemes out of it and so i'm
just going to cap this really quick
and then you can uh
yeah
oh yeah
that's awesome
nice
yeah so he was close to sun peaks right
now um
so we we actually went and visited him
in april and uh you know i'm super
jealous that he lives at the base of sun
peaks now because you know
a few minutes to get to the mountain and
uh snowboard you know that's the life
but uh
how was that dab
a little bit bigger full send
full ascendant to the stratosphere
london
london just got carried out in the first
half
no i got more
let me uh clean that up for you i got
more in me
here if uh here why don't you step up
next here just uh clear that real quick
and then uh
perfect i'll clean that up for
him do you want you guys want to all
have the seat down we got the third mic
over and you guys have some dabs
but i put my glasses on for this one
here take a mic let's have a london to
move the camera a little bit closer
again
who's in for a dab i'm here uh heating
up the banger for people so i am ready
as much as i have a foot in this grease
monkey here
i don't need to see their feet
the other day but those are the wheezies
dude
i've got the ceo way for that too i'm
pretty sure that wasn't enough
we have our our team of color
commentators we have
the snack king chris guerrero
we have the
pert plus spokesperson chad westport
yolo having some technical difficulties
here
that looks a little bit different
then peter the man behind the curtain
the wizard of oz himself
peter longpipes
we're all just staring at this like is
it working
look at those wings
this neighborhood probably smells
delicious
a lot of bare feet
a lot of pale canadians barefoot
i heard you're not allowed to smoke pot
if you're not barefoot
[Laughter]
there we go yeah
look at that
amazing yes now we can see what's going
on it was good to meet you at the
conference on the island it was a great
time
ultimately i created the business
completely out of my own self-interest
like i just kind of wanted to know about
like how good my weed was that i was
growing at home i don't think it was
just okay so like trimming wasn't an
option for me so i got some like
mechanical trimmers and stuff like that
and then uh i had to turn on the mic so
then i got myself smasher which um the
lug smasher which is the press over
there which is great so i'm more
interested in the machine the testing
because the potency analyzer is amazing
it's the light lab 3 cannabis analyzer
that's cool um a little bit different
from the
though i had an sri 810 6c
that was another testing machine that we
talked about that was pretty cool but i
mean this is like mine was not you
needed a full like guide this thing is
like a suitcase that's what i like about
this
suitcase it's actually used by a few of
the federal uh wings in the united
states like um like yeah i'm not i'm not
like police agencies that go to the hemp
farms to test that there's not a higher
thc or whatever right they've been it's
been vetted so it's actually they're
using it in the government facilities so
that's giving you some pretty good on
the road i like that they put it up
against 250 brick order labs down in the
states and uh that we're using like a
hundred thousand dollar hplc machines
like that's a pretty serious unit but
not not that price and uh it finished in
the top uh like 25 so it blew most of
the brick and mortar labs like
completely out
disgusting he's going in first first up
i thought i was getting lucky here but i
don't know
no you're not stealing no thunder at all
right there
you know what's great about this is he's
talking about the hplc and that's
something that i worked on with dr paul
hornby rest in peace paul was just an
awesome man gentleman who uh who uh
gracefully passed away um and his
bedside his wife and family were around
when uh you actually
lost with pneumonia like a lot of people
do in their ages and when they're when
they're sick it's unfortunate
very unfortunate but you know
he's like he's got a great dab going on
here and i can see right now
so it's nice to see where we've evolved
because we went from from an hplc then
we went to the the mass back well
there's a mass spec then it had a gc
which is gas chromatographer and now you
have this beautiful little piece here
that comes in a pelican case yep that
you can carry around and instead of
hauling around like we were hauling
around gases because we needed gases i
had to have the tanks yeah all this
stuff so it was a lot it was it was it
was kind of hard to actually take
testing on the road
and it was nice to see as a gentleman
named chuck came in the plane he started
driving around and he was doing some
testing back in the day since about 2013
2014.
i love it dude i find that it's bridging
the intuition with knowledge no but
here's what i'm saying like we got to
keep evolving and showing and people are
able to now they're looking for those
percentages they want to know more but
back in the days i think we were just a
little bit before our time yeah oh my
god absolutely 100 like i when i opened
this business it was in january of this
year at the end of january and my
primary market was supposed to be ac mpr
and it was supposed to be like the
smaller like client the home grower like
yeah the homegrown wants to know and
that's that's sort of why i built the
business but then it turned out that the
lps and the micros had a serious
interest in it too so now i get to go
out and like provide business
intelligence and
um there was one lp that was out in the
valley there and they were running like
eight different new r d strains and i
got to go in and sort of test them every
other week and sort of give them like
potency tracking there you go and that's
a great way of stacking up against what
their actual like mainstay was right and
it turns out that they ended up dropping
the majority of the r d strains because
it wasn't coming close to what their
bread and butter was so
um they didn't have to put in a bunch of
like dollars and cents to find out that
it wasn't gonna pan out for them in
today's market where they're trying to
sell things for high thc like did they
look great yeah did they smell great
sure we're gonna we're gonna probably
we're gonna get into one thing here
right now so they did not legalize
cannabis they legalized t they they
taxed thc
yeah because that's what we're seeing
and what we're talking about they're
dumping the strains and a lot of these
lower thc strains with the terpenoids
and flavonoids that we're looking at
it's always about saving the chirps and
we're looking at that so it's really
it's the education that we've got to get
back in because we know the thai t c
levels you're seeing this because i saw
it for the last decade working with paul
doing exactly doing in a different scale
i love what you're doing like i mean i
command john taking it to the lps and
doing that because when i was around
there was no lps we were we were doing
it and like we're like dude i'm standing
on the shoulders of people that got me
here are you kidding me you know what
like it's a beautiful thing to see that
we're getting to these levels that we
can do this legally you got a job doing
this oh my god we can legally test
cannabis
and have a job and do this the best part
is i get to go to everyone's place you
know what come on
be your like yeah
dude
man let's do it like that would be
awesome yeah we're going to these places
to see and look at that research because
we've done so much of over time and
seeing what businesses are doing what
they're going today and what you're able
to do at home because this man here has
the ability to test and track things so
you can see how things are developing
and we're looking at soil growth right
now it's oh man we we tested some lights
the other day i was at
a micro there's five micros operating on
the same plot of land and one guy's got
double ended bulbs and other guys
running leds but they have the same
strain flipped on the same day and
everything and you know the results
right there and now because we all know
the leds are killing it gives you you
get a result in 12 and a half minutes
you get a printed coa or you get it
emailed to you which is amazing but uh
these guys here their
difference between percentages was seven
percent the led strain was absolutely
fucking killing it and it's like
dude well maybe the terps were low no
the terps were actually higher too it
was crazy i can tell you the difference
between wattages of leds and thc levels
i've really gone down the rabbit hole
that's why you and me are gonna have a
lot of fun because i connect the ability
to do some information that i have in
this
little brain of mine that you can now
look at we connected about it and on
over on the island and now you're here
well i'm also with the unicorn cup which
is dope too you're you are as well i'm
actually trim test impressions i guess
we're getting together it looks like
things might be going down okay i'm
gonna go over there and run another test
um but uh
i thought that was great we're back
get over here justin
talk to me
so that was david roberts that was just
speaking there guys just so you let uh
let you know if you can hear my mic you
need a microphone
this is justin
justin hi guys what's up jeff
great
i was hoping for a reheat i uh i'm i'm
on a bit of a hiatus and i know that
everybody's been like oh no
lame
talking mike yeah he knows this too
there we go
so
not my first
yeah
oh that smells nice that's really
really floral
i've got lavender what is that what is
this
this is a grease monkey
this is really pretty
fresh frozen tasty very derpy this is
like a trip sauce
it is a turtle sauce so it's probably
heated crushed probably a low temp what
did you
super nice
really floral
okay we just got well i did i got high
was kind of nice you got high i did i
enjoyed it you know paul i was just
sitting here everywhere we were talking
about the testing and you work with dr
hornby you were really behind him we did
a lot of stuff with matty one yeah
you're looking at those terpenes that
were the organic line we're looking at
tc levels back in the days when you talk
about testing you've gone through a lot
of these testing you've seen a lot of
these results and what do you see in the
industry today when we compare to the
old see hps metal highlights going
towards leds
like what we were saying two years ago
and what happened in the list in the
last six months and where things i mean
ten years ago we were testing leds and
it was just this dude i was testing them
for you you were banging your head
against the wall dude you gave me my
first spectrum king led you game this
guy gave me a lot of the lights in the
beginning and you know what we were
looking at leds i remember all the stuff
that was coming in a green planet coming
into pnw
all the different lights that we've seen
over time like you've actually got the
one thing i loved about being able to be
a part of the team and part of the
family yeah is being able to see every
light that comes everybody's going to
see the back of dave's head
back of the head back of the head for
dave
back of the head
so yeah no honestly but like led is
finally hit finally haley we we bitched
about it 2015 2016. it's finally covered
some of those lights
oh can i can i not like the purples the
that's what i mean the microphone
the uh the non-stop uh
i know just nonstop banging your head
against the wall right until we knew the
tech was there we knew one day it would
be amazing
and now you can't even give a cmh away
or you can't even give an hbs light away
that's awesome the market has completely
changed and now it's growing under a led
and learning about the growing future
learning about you know more
dehumidification there's a lot of things
you need to learn along the way but so
you know what you got to understand your
vapor pressure deficit absolutely it's
most the key is thing that we never
really learned about growing with hps
metal highlights all you all growers out
there you're fucked
like i know i've seen all you guys
change and everything yeah you're
awesome mark like doing the i figured
you would yeah it's you know so much you
know one thing that i really noticed
honestly is like we used to guess
tell us uh sorry to interject here but
tell us for those that don't know what
is vapor pressure deficit in in the
layman's terms
it's the amount of pressure that's put
on the leaf and the amount of pressure
that's coming off the leaf that control
the amount of the plant is absorbing
nutrients and everything so there's an
amount of pressure that's hitting the
leaf and there's amount of pressure
that's going off for the leaf and you
want to maintain a certain amount of
pressure the vapor pressure deficit
so it's really key important when you
take a look at how much pressure is on
that leaf and how it's growing and we
used to take we take a lot of pressure a
lot of stress on that leaf by lowering
the the vapor pressure inside of the
room by lowering its humidity that
humidity the plant was not off castings
it was starving itself and we've seen
this over time we cause diseases we all
these problems do into not really
properly controlling the humidity inside
the room it's kind of when we look at
ourselves and everything like we we as
humans are 75 water the earth is 71
water your plants are water why are we
trying to pull all the moisture out of
the room they're not growing the jungle
boys key example
they started killing when they started
doing everything with high humidity
growing and stuff
with within reason within reason
understanding vapor pressure
understanding vpd is is paramount the
next part is like we never
as growers we never
measured light no not at all right it
wasn't until wait a second here quantum
sensors we had we had those parameters
that i was using about 2015 from down we
were looking at i did he gave me those
lights i was doing that stuff but
growers for the most part don't measure
light like it's like 740 650 it just
gave us something we've never ever gone
to nanometers we never got into nothing
like that we never got a ppfd now with
technology like troll master we can
actually measure light we didn't
understand dli daily integrals and how
much that plant was willing it's no
different than measuring food in your
reservoir
it's food in the air
and the fact that you can actually hone
in um dpd
and
uh
ppfd dli all these things using troll
master that's really been a revolution
in the industry it has changed it i've
actually seen quite a good thing because
the troll master actually controls your
your well it doesn't control your dli i
don't know if the new light sensor
haven't used them so let me rephrase
that yeah so i mean i look at ppd levels
and i'm able to actually mimic the sun
sets on right spectrum
i'm able to mimic in the room that if
i'm actually doing like if there's
clouds like there is outside so i take a
look at where the now i'm one kind of
curious right now is i know the
difference between see at 10 a.m in the
morning with using my spectrum meter and
taking what it is in the summertime in
the fall and i see higher levels so now
controlling those levels that i see
outside on the inside with the troll
master is going to be my next step of
talking to you we're trying to literally
mimic mother nature my nature had it
figured out they've well you know what
they've got more they figured out
they've worked on the soils and the root
balancer take a look at
that whole thing we're looking at is
looking at those organic soils and
looking at the microbes and
far red's huge at first and right now
we're actually testing some stuff right
now i'm gonna be taking a look at far
red pass at 7 30 and we started pushing
some stuff past 780 was the first lights
that i started testing right now well
now for the last little bit and we
started i started seeing a difference
underneath my grapes because my grapes
was all red so i started seeing the
difference with these light recipes by
looking at the light that was going
through the leaf and what's going
underneath the leaves underneath the
plants outside of my yard and other
people's places and by seeing these
spectrums you're able to start advancing
more in technology to take a look at
what we're seeing because now we have
the technology to measure light
everywhere
absolutely it's awesome oh yeah and we
never looked at it until now as as in
growers as in i don't even know any
farmers that do this like i i know they
do in greenhouses but why aren't we
looking at the outside and how we're
able to shade these plants and stuff
like that and where they're getting
their best expressions
there's lots of different plants to do
different things the cannabis people
have to understand
i keep preaching this cannabis is not
about
color or blood structure
it all comes down to the trichome
and the effect that that has on your own
condition
that's it
your international capability system
specifically
that's what's going to determine uh
the best nugget
this kind of tastes good too though see
you know what mark just keeps coming
with new i know why you just sit down
come back here with all that stuff
he's always got it all i want one of
these i mean everybody you see running
around with everything is because of
that guy yeah yeah i carry stuff around
with him on planes and everywhere and it
was just like he took shit everywhere
and you know what because we needed a
dub no matter where we were
at the airport at the hotel inside the
room
by the way the uh no thc sticker that's
very
apparent well what come on
it's very canadian
hey
we are on the us channel right now which
is awesome you guys got to come up here
and take a look at this beautiful view
and as you can see i can't believe it
wow
so yeah you've got
as you got into it like dr hornby um you
know we've lost
some serious pioneers within the space
french cannoli jason wilcox horatio
delbert honestly randy kane these guys
are like there's so many people that
have us there's bert and there's yeah
there's tracy
there's the whole thing is is is these
people left something behind for us to
evolve from so they gave us the
knowledge to move forward and we take
that knowledge we keep pushing it so we
blessed with what they've done in our
lives and we've taken that knowledge and
pushed it forward from people like
horatio from people like dr horan and
you've got to pay homage to all those
you know pioneers and they literally are
pioneers in the space yeah
the last growing expos that we did we
actually uh
dedicated to jason wilcox that's a
beautiful thing i know we got going i
dedicated in my book is adult dedication
horatio and jason wilcox so it's in the
first opening pages of the book and i
mean jason was a pioneer in the industry
who fought for legalization in the
courts for his daughters to be able to
race to grow his own while he was able
to raise his daughter through the court
system so a lot of people don't know i
sat years and years with jason he's a
very good friend of mine yeah you know
he's blessed me with his presence and be
a part of his daughter's life and be
able to see how we were able to change
as a group and as a community really
evolve and change the plan and how it's
being i mean today presented to the
world because canada really was able to
change that demographics and now people
have been looking at canada they say we
screwed it up but no we didn't we
started it so how
it's legal
i think governments screw it up by
getting greedy and thinking there's
unlimited funds in it
the whole thing is is right now it's i
mean it comes down to and i always say
this and also keep saying until the day
is i mean it's around the world it's the
green way it's growing your own if you
can't grow we can now obtain it
somewhere else which is fantastic that's
all i fought for all we ever said is
what everybody was evolved everybody
fought for the same thing access yeah it
wasn't important it was about access
depending on what access that you want
is where the key by itself is
[Music]
it helps you grow you see something
different canadians are all about to
grow four plants
why aren't they all not growing for
plants i give plants away like crazy
well this year i couldn't because it
just i wasn't able to do a lot of stuff
i don't understand why home growers are
not a bigger segment in the market
i'm dumbfounded i'm dumbfounded people
are still lazy you live in like north
vancouver you have it's kind of still a
hippie community my friends and family
are interested they're still weary you
know a lot of the people that are well
here's the whole thing so buyers are
ones that are walking into your muse
that are walking into your local
dispensaries those new initial buyers
are still running through stigmatisms in
their mind and we're growing the plant
but once we can get there you know what
i mean we you open so many other avenues
cannabis is cool because it could pull
people through in that method also the
next thing you know you're growing your
own food you're growing your own crops
well this is the whole thing we're
getting into that's what we're talking
about right now and i'm using the 104
gallon bins i was getting the next one
with peppers and tomatoes with the
organics and stuff like that moving soil
we just did regenerative gardening the
uh on on uh you know one episode
i i've probably clicked on it
called growing exposed i know
you know you know what um
go ahead no no straight goods like full
regenerative growth changes yeah
absolutely phenomenal like we're pumped
we're going to be doing the live
coverage of the unit well i mean they're
a little bit out of the booth so we
won't be able to get live
are you you're going to unicorn income
uh there's a good chance yeah there's a
good chance you're taking a helicopter
this industry is soft right now dude
okay helicopter money i'm just kidding
i might take an rv rv yeah i'm like you
know what i don't know if i'm driving
this one because i don't know i can do
seven hours behind the wheel right now
but i could do seven hours in a
passenger seat and pay for gas
i could do that yeah i could you know
what
i'm just saying i'm throwing it out
there i got a lot of good friends here
in town i'm definitely interested in you
know look at time frames and stuff like
that but i mean uh yeah it's the vehicle
we highlighted that cup uh last year and
it was really really good honestly i was
i was i was blown away by
uh the nature of che
and his
the warmest human he is such a nice guy
like right like that grow
uh honestly it's it's going down as my
favorite episode we've done
i i'm not like i absolutely think it's
the best i've been a fan i've been
watching it i watched your first episode
like i've been watching live that would
have been a long fucking time man
i said that was me i'm in the first
episode
and that and and that one was i mean
there's some great stuff in there but
that like was really something special
oh yeah from where we've evolved from
the showing this garden his soul you
know what i mean and it's like that's
what it's about every word of his being
the way he expresses
yes and uh his live resin cart
is fantastic and you got that on he's
not here
no he wasn't i was hoping he could you
know what's nice is justin's like the
one-man farm right so
he's like
he's gonna hop on the bike and come out
i actually have we've got an episode
later tonight on the dank hour with my
usual team of nice uh of people and
we're going to talk about the unicorn
cop yeah push it out there a little bit
it's such a beautiful spot it yeah and
it's right on the lake too isn't it it's
it's literally then there's the gardiner
lake is half a kilometer away but
the the main festival is right on the
lake and i mean the most pristine it it
it epitomizes the kootenais through it
through it really that's awesome josh
and kelly are just like amazing people
it's it honestly and
you know we need to be looking at
regenerative gardening as a real serious
well we're here talking about absolutely
and we're pushing it on all these
channels and everything we're talking
about
we're bringing it in the house we got to
bring it into the house yeah experiment
nothing new about it it's teaching the
kids for some people
i grow a lot i grow cover crop in three
gallon pots and after you harvest your
flour you can pick carrots out of it
absolutely three gallon pot i'm using
i'm using green planet nutrients which
is your dual fuel
yeah um and
you know but i use regenerative practice
i've been using the same cocoa for now
three and a half years oh it doesn't
break down decrease the nutrient intake
that that cut that comes into them i do
like because they're just staining three
gallons what ppm are you running i love
low ppm yeah honestly you don't want
people to crush
tds in my opinion or ec you're just
the plant as it dries out you're
struggling easy goes up regardless
you're stressing the roots you're
damaging the plant potential so i mean
that'll bring more teeth here yeah
people go oh you have so much life there
how do you get the water in and it's
like it glides it's like it just moves
directly into the soil with zero effort
or anything yeah you know i put down
some predator insects i haven't sprayed
anything i haven't had to put anything
down and i do a little indoor grow
that's half outdoor
and it just works and it's like i've
been able to stop i mean you have to go
through some pains in the process sure
and you have to come to an understanding
with yourself yeah that's like that's a
lot about like what you do with grow and
expose and what you do
so london i'll ask you a question what
what do we do to break the stigma
what do we do to get that grandma to be
like i'm doing my own veggies already
i'm going to throw a couple pot plants
in there we're going to we're doing this
yeah
you get into every garden works and you
tour around the country and you hit
every garden works and you do uh you do
a pairing i mean they're head offices
sure it's right now but you go hey
absolutely we're gonna we're gonna go
around and we're gonna teach people
about it and how to do it properly and
most of all how to do it safely and then
yeah then you then safely you're gonna
teach people about the safeness behind
the plant and how they can integrate it
into their garden you're already allowed
to use four plants legally for fuck's
sake yeah but we gotta understand i mean
the whole thing is as we keep talking
about but you can't see the reason and
everybody think it's a drug so you got
to put the medical behind it and they're
saying we can't talk about medical and
this is where the health canada thing
comes into play so it's really is how we
present this to the people and how they
need to be growing this and i know ken's
talking about driving across canada
doing these little regenerative little
uh bus tours and trying to get people
those like we did with
back in the days
we can talk recreationally we can talk
medical we can talk anyway we want yeah
you're legally a lot of people that's
what i mean we can talk all about it
stop
like there's no stigma to break it's
legal the biggest the biggest challenge
that i see in the market right now is
the lack of genetics that are actually
honest yeah um there's a there's a lot
of seed there's not a lot of good
product coming out yeah um and and the
problem is is that there's a lot of
disgenuous people providing things that
are brand absolutely indoor environment
and giving the old ladies that are going
to grow outside yeah and this these
things are are are like when the first
time you ever grow and the first time
you ever get that experience even if you
fail you get
some reward out of it but when you
when you get obliterated when things go
just horrendously bad um i mean there's
auto flowers too right like you can get
seeds you can go eat
dispensers
that's been breeding in alberta outdoor
light depth yeah i mean breeding alberta
outdoor light depth like i mean
difficult the the baffling is he has
auto autoflowers he's super auto so
they're like 110 115 days but the
they're bred to be done out here and
take all these seeded varieties that
people are breeding indoors and then
throw them into bc yeah alberta yeah
like ontario there's no way you're not
going to have success yeah and and
that's where people get stopped and i
think also the price of the market is a
little bit ridiculous um when you look
at yield per square foot yeah um when it
comes to seed prod when it comes to any
sort of seed crop cannabis is is a grain
when it comes down to it so if you look
at the volume that you can get per plant
if you're seeding properly
there shouldn't be five six hundred
dollar packs of seeds for ten you know i
get there's a there's these new
hotnesses but that's that's not they
shouldn't be that expensive absolutely
not seeds are seeds are very inexpensive
or at least a bigger pack than 10. you
know like give them give them a 25 pack
at least sometimes
i'll do a plug for a friend of mine's
company propagation station they're
based in salmon arm
these
guys are giving very clean genetics
they they if you've got an mma or a npr
you can buy
cuts through them
and uh jeff's a very dear friend of mine
and
access for the legal market and for end
users is quite easy
um
so
if you've got an mma or a
macm pr
you can access
and then if you can't and you don't have
that you're joe blow and you want to
grow four plants go buy some seeds from
most dispensaries most dispensaries have
seeds and they don't go to the one that
does
and ask for them because you ask for
them and then ask for other products i
mean we did plug shea earlier and we
should we should remind people that he's
got product coming on on
on legal in ocs yeah ontario market and
in bc that sarah secrets was really
really nice
if it's not in your dispensary ask for
it you know like in the next call like
be there requesting it because these are
the type if you want to support
regenerative farming i mean are they you
would you two would know better like do
you know anyone else doing regenerative
farming on a
on a scale
like an lp i mean there's there's true
living soil guys and indoors
a few of them that are actually doing
like uh we're not regenerative but
they're doing the the aquaponics and
stuff that like caviar aquaponics i mean
and we've seen that we've seen a few
things but you know like even even there
everybody's having some problems and
it's difficult right like it's difficult
it's even difficult one of the
discussions we had with che was you know
it's difficult to give the plant exactly
what it wants
in regenerative gardening
it's difficult to change your formula
it's also difficult to flush
like regenerative gardening is fantastic
in my opinion
for extract
all day long if you're harvesting
trichomes
regenerative is the only way to go you
get such great flavors i'm about the
hash though honestly you're about the
hash you're about trichomes you're
harvesting trichomes you should be
growing degeneratively well that's why
i'm just getting it and actually makes
it a lot easier because that's growing
over the last few decades and stuff like
that we go back into the late 80s or i
mean late 90s early 2000s that's all
we've grown yeah i mean that's it's kind
of like but you're gonna go you're gonna
diminish yield
yeah i'm not concerned with you're not
concerned about yielding exactly that's
what i'm saying if you're not
considerable yield you're not commercial
yeah
you definitely should be growing well
the whole thing is is now we got to take
a look at those two and more importantly
it's very mentally friendly
your your your quality is incredible you
can incorporate the practices in you
know using a mulch you know it's just
stopping with the sprains absolutely you
know
there's there's sprays who sprays
pesticides these days
a lot of people they shouldn't be and i
don't know many at all they also
everybody's doing biological things
right now old school dude
every year i get the smell bottom of it
sephora alex you know the product
what do you think of that product
you know what i i don't really want to
give my opinion on if i love it or if i
don't love it um i'm just curious
because i picked it up and i know it's
it's it's a it's a health canada proof
product yeah right and i know it's
basically a form of a neem oil yeah i'm
understanding so i know we have to talk
about other things but i mean it's a
product that it's
they can't even work great for powdered
milk i'll give you my theory on this
every time okay there's a couple things
in no other crop production in the world
do we accept powdery mildew in this
methodology on commercial scale
right so if you have powdery mildew
genetics i mean there's probably a
there's a shit ton of other stuff out
there to find something that doesn't
absolutely
there's a tree
right now maple tree attempted if you've
got one this is what you're going to do
you're going to penetrate it into this
absolutely right you create an
expectation for these products and then
you have to grow them in those
particular places and every time you see
you cut down powder you'll do you
restrict yeah you have to every time you
take something away it comes back to
full i said i cut down bugs and i went
for
life change i had to go for surgery
stuff happens i tried to grow a crop of
weed it wasn't going to happen and i was
like okay you know what i don't have
time to deal with this so it was just
easier to cut it down and get it right
down get rid of it because it creates a
headache i think that video did well for
you didn't it did it went and it was the
two million mark they took it down
and you know it was even like uh
growing from seed you know that was a
5.5 million views and and the whole
thing is is when they're able to get to
that reach and be able to teach people
about taxi this is what you should do
i just don't seem to like that but i
mean we're here we're discussing these
same things and what you need to do like
you're getting these problems you need
to get rid of order you need to find out
where the problem is coming from and how
you can adapt to it and then find the
pattern that's causing it and if you can
find a genetic that doesn't have the
problems to begin with you've
circumvented the issue that's fine so
say you've had a genetic
problems over the last 15 or 20 years
take it back to take it back to culture
so you take it past the petri culture so
what i like doing is i like cutting just
going in the flower week or two in the
flower taking that cutting when that
roots take another cutting yeah right
away so i'll flip this a couple times
with the strain in order to ensure
something because i'm just taking care
of this one thing i mean people have to
understand it because people don't have
tissue cultures
viruses viruses and pathogens can't keep
up with the growth of a plant
so
if you grab off the apical meristem but
if you're i mean honestly that's why you
should go to a cellular level on the
very very top of the plant and what a
cells need
pardon oh i'm on the cell thing cells
need oxygen and water because they're
just going in the microbiology of the
plants and stuff like that and i'm
talking about our human cells and cells
need oxygen and water to survive and get
through things so we've got to start
yeah it's
but they need more than that they need
laughter they need humor they need they
need good food they need the right
environment i mean we're no different
than plants
right if you want to thrive and you want
plant that thrives you got to thrive
honestly we go back to our original
roots of how we lived exactly like we're
so disconnected as a people thank you
very much for that because we are as in
all uh as a whole as well
on a different tangent but so here
here's a question that that i have
because you're feeling my energy and you
know we're gonna get into this
conversation maybe marcus can i get you
in on this one too come on over i got i
got a good question for you guys that i
would i would like to ask you guys as a
group if you don't mind yeah you do yeah
you kind of have to hold the microphone
here take my mic
no here i'll step out you guys you guys
are cooler than me anyway you're behind
i need to shuffle away um but anyway and
make sure i got a bread thing i got like
this beautiful giant cinnamon dough
thing it's going to blow your mind and i
got to chat with nicole because we're
going to have some snacks coming up here
in a little bit we'll take a little
break and do a little bit of a giveaways
but one question that i'd love to ask
you guys before we step away from this
is like how do we support the smaller
market and how do we develop the places
like uh rosebud farms as a community and
as as a way we want to see it move
forward because that's a lot of what
we're touching on is the health of the
planet how do we deal with we
you have to support these farmers by
supporting them by getting their
information out there and making sure
people know that they're around because
we have to get them to the community and
people have to have access and they're
not knowing that they're around so as in
we as a whole like we did as activists
we got to keep pushing these united
farmers that's where you got to get it
from these are the companies you should
be dealing with and the more that we do
that for that individual companies in a
time the nice thing about the craft
market right like the craft market's got
to be pushed and we got to push these
people
what craft is on the market where are
you buying a craft well this company
here grows up to whoever is doing it
whatever companies whoever's got that
craft then we got to push those
companies i like supporting like
small boutique vineyards i like
supporting the small guy i mean i'd way
rather have something that's unique
it's kind of like anything it's amazing
genuinely had love put into it you know
it's not
see for me i like supporting
whoever's putting love and creating
great products whether they be big
medium or small yeah i support them if
you're making great product i support
you yeah and that's that's just the way
it's got to be and you know we've
already seen the pattern of the large
companies coming in and putting a lot of
kind of mediocre low-quality flower out
and you know that's i mean i noticed
today i think it was
texo
it was tilray and it was another big
company weeds whoever's the weed
they were down like 34 14
and 23
each of them in sales in market position
and that was noticeably from smaller
craft companies that are coming in
they're not grabbing all of that but
they're grabbing like two percent and
another one's grabbing one point five
and another one's grabbing four once you
add up enough
you know people like i mean chase shay
is an awesome guy you know he he's
actually a really amazing person so
soft-spoken so honest so in like high
integrity he really
believes what he's doing he believes in
what he's doing and and i i cannot
believe that when you talk to him when
you hang out with him yeah exactly he's
definitely not just you know talking
shit like he's you feel the authenticity
when you talk to him and the sort of
passion in his voice
it's one of the reasons why i'm excited
to go to the unicorn cup and you know i
think he's on the right path with you
know yes dude you know he's in the legal
a lot of a lot of people who are
regenerative and in the sustainable side
have really stayed
in the gray market they haven't been
able to flip especially when if you
think of dragonfly earth medicine they
have this certification that you can't
even get in the lp market yeah so as
much as you want to be regenerative you
can only be so regenerative in the lp
mark you're not allowed to have goats
and cows and chickens on your on your
cannabis farm like interacting with your
of course your soil it's it's going
towards you know it's it's you it's
but it could be how do you buy that weed
man so would i and i have bought it in
the past and it's uh it's a wonderful
thing at the same time
you know i see people doing things
outside of the box i see people
i've seen people grow exceptional flour
which makes exceptional hash
in almost every way that you can grow
cannabis with salts organically
hydroponically aquaponically in earth in
soilless i mean i've just seen six star
resin come out of all of those things so
at that point it becomes semantics
of
you know what do you want to support
which which one of those because they'll
all produce incredible product if you
have the right people and the right
genetics
the right people
you know there's a lot of guys that just
walk into this
that kill it their first second third
crop you normally do one there are blank
slates so they've not learned a whole
bunch of bad
that can be huge in our industry a whole
bunch of bad information
uh two
they've got a willingness
so i'm really
you know i i get excited
to see
the next what's coming up around the
corner me too don't lock yourself in
keep it open and allow for anything to
move in and surprise you absolutely you
know and that's why when you guys were
saying oh i would support the little guy
it's like i'll support anyone if they're
doing everything right absolutely you
know that's who deserves to be surprised
let's be honest like
craft is amazing but we are going to
need to get to a place
where
some groups of people can produce enough
for the country absolutely not for the
neighborhood not for the you know the
county or the
village or the for the you know
for the two people
exactly and it's not there yet but it's
definitely
and five ten years ago i don't think any
of us would have been able to imagine
where we are right now right now
thousands of stores across come on
this is crazy from where we were from
objectives there's things to complain
about but i haven't had a gun shoved in
my face this whole time
i have countless friends who have served
35 40 years of doing that shit i thought
you had more i'll give them a like
am i this old
i was selling weight at 16. this guy's
49 and he's been doing it for 45 years
yeah
no no i'm i'm i'm 50. i'm not a great
year
50 years old
dude he had the full bubble yeah no no
no bubbles
lining up selling joints same thing in
16 years
crushing bubblegum gum and
dabs at a young age
oh it's wonderful man you got the mist
slapping us to keeping us cool and
pretty good you don't look too wet
though john's moist
it's just like a mist
it's really nice you know it doesn't it
doesn't make you wet it's a beautiful
thing it's not too much so one thing i
like we talked about marketing it was a
nice 80s
is uh the
the way things are evolving and
um we got into it earlier um
fucking moment stoner hang on
um
well you did eat a lot of that salsa no
no
it's infused that's why i crushed half
of it when you first got in i was like i
know i'm trying to think of that well i
was kind of talking about the um how
everyone wants their hash to be like the
lightest color oh yeah and sort of it
was kind of like this instagram thing of
like
well it reminds me of los angeles where
back in the 90s you know los angeles
just wanted this flower that was the
equivalent of like a blond-haired
blue-eyed fake boobs hash racist as you
put it yeah it's just like
the color is awesome there's good
there's some like the some of the best
hash i've ever made in my life has been
in
barcelona
jamaica these countries do not produce
white hash they produce ambers and it's
all colors
exist because they're aging it because
they want more cbn well that's it you
know so i'm not i'm i'm a fan of like
once again i'll support hash
that is and i see people doing this for
this advantage of like well i'm just
trying to get it sold and if it's too
dark it won't sell it's like that's a
bullshit concept
how about we educate people that the
color
is just showing you that
this particular group of volatile
organic compounds along with these
cannabinoids
and the oxidization it's it needs to
change a little bit stronger
numbers you know the same way on
instagram everything you know and i tell
my wife this and my daughter like
i saw one the other day that it was like
basically
it was a woman showing her body in a
bikini and then next to it was her as
well but she was photoshopping it she
was like this is
what everything is on instagram and it
wasn't her
her waist was super tight and her
breasts were way bigger and her legs
were all like she just did all these key
things to make it so she was saying
don't believe anything you see on
instagram i think the cannabis community
could do better i think we could show
the truth and show that there's value in
all of these different ages and colors
and
aspects of
variables of hash just smell it
like it's so floral
i need to do a dab yeah right that is
very floral
and it's and it's got color yeah
you know it's gonna probably give you a
yellow orange
it's gonna give you an effect
right and if that effect works with your
own in the cannabinoid system
and it really you know gives you that
wow yeah
that's good that's good
that's it that's what matters that's it
it's it's this
sort of foam mentality everyone wants
something they can't get that they're
seeing on instagram and
then when they get it it's like well was
it even
honest i've smoked a lot of instagram
hash from famous
makers some of it is blowing my mind and
some of it
just didn't impress me at all it was
just like it was like
something so you know what this is
get away from this bullshit um
you know
i love natural
i don't want my wife to have
i normally
and that shines through everything yeah
and you can't you can't fake that you
can't fake it and
honestly
she's aesthetically very pretty
and
other women can be a bit like oh she's
no
the moment they talk to her they're like
holy shit
she's as real as it gets you know
breeder steve said it best
variety is the spice of life yeah and
that that was his company spice of life
seed yes yeah it's like let's create
things
that are different totally you know
there's always going to be that popular
like oh okay we all want this extremely
premature
freeze-dried
white hash
then there's always a real appreciation
for the actual color that's going
absolutely i have probably 12 or 15
different hashes here and they all have
different colors and different smells
you know different effects yeah i love
them all
you know for different times totally
so i could have seen in my house there's
like 15 different kinds in front of me
that's if you get the the flavors and
the different terpenes and the different
times when you need it so each different
strains affecting you in different ways
but you haven't heard of us
i want a 35 thc no but it's not about
the thc which sometimes it is because i
like a heavy hit i like that hot dab
because i need that effect but it's
understanding these profiles and these
strains all those cabinets work together
and we really have no understanding no
we still think all the volatiles are
terpenes yeah you know everyone's
talking about terpenes but no one's
talking about all these other organic
compounds that are also volatile that
also shift the profile of flavor and
taste and modulation
in the plants yeah and there's a lot of
them yeah you know i mean my my a good
friend of mine nick ziegler who worked
at yakima chief hops for years and years
developing different hops
he found 1440 thials in hops like
hundred and forty they think there's 180
terpenes
present in cannabis he's thinking
there's probably at least a thousand
present in cannabis as well of files
that is an enormous amount and that if
you think of that as a little kind of
pebble that the that the profile sits on
like an upside down pyramid sure
the point of the pyramid is sitting on
these very small
you know profile of volatile organic
compounds but depending on how that
shifts
it can shift that triangle to the left
or to the right in a very profound way
yeah and we're just we're just literally
learning about that now which is why
every single crop of the same strain
is different it's different that's
exactly that's why trying to create a
medicine with cannabis that it leads
actually beautifully into
you know a lot of people from where we
come from the sort of heady aspect of
cannabis
a lot of the people they'll say it's all
about full spectrum not about
mono-molecular isolates but when you
understand what you just said is a
universal truth that you'll never get
the same thing twice
then you understand that when you find
something that works for a group of
people you need to take it apart
figure out everything that's there which
we haven't been able to do because we
don't count test for thials and thia
weights
but being able to get that broken down
to exactly what it is and then recreate
it with mono molecular isolates would be
profound for medical patients well this
is what i've always said you know that's
that is the future of cannabis by the
way yeah for for patients it is
absolutely it is because medicine you
know like how about your standardizing
haley's trying to use the haley's
comment and her mom's calling me all the
time going this time it doesn't work i
know it worked last time it doesn't work
this time it's crazy i have a
catastrophically ill child and be
dealing with a medicine that just stops
working that's it you have to figure out
exactly what it is recreate it
and then and then have that be that
thing so but it's not only it's not only
the cannabinoids to be given off the
same
it's everything that's in there it's
everything that's in there to get all
those ratios correct is gonna take i
always thought of this picture a box
right a picture a big box and it's got
little vials in it and you've got all
the different cannabinoids and you've
got all sorts of terpenes and files and
thy weights and imagine that they sit
upside down like the same way you could
poke in with a syringe and pull out
material they sit in this box and you've
got the box and you're dialing in the
profile of the herb you like the best
maybe you've got another box that tests
the herb to give you the readouts that
allow you to recreate the readouts with
this box and see how close you can get
your your dab or your hit yeah to
directly the medicinal components that
you require and then the next part of it
is dude that's that's that is the future
by the way the next part of it is
being able to
dial in your own endocrine abdominal
system and say this is you exactly
and this is exactly what you need yeah
and these are going to be all the
triggers that fire off all those
different endocrine bodies in your head
well that's pretty amazing
that's
that is the future we're a long way off
i think yeah i think so too no like
we're coming up
well you know what don't get me wrong ai
nothing happens ai could occur
and if ai occurred
and we were able to ask ai how do we do
this it would be answered very quickly
yeah think ai is going to i think ai's
there's gonna come a point where ai
looks at us and goes
you're not relevant anymore so fuck off
it's possible but we unless we're
delusional yeah
of how relevant we are
because we are unique there's no denying
it it's like we're used to ourselves and
we look at ourselves as parasites and we
make all sorts of mistakes but there's
nothing else on this planet like us
that's thinking and sentient and
creating and manufacturing and
processing
yeah it's it's so crazy that i can't
imagine a.i
coming up with oh let's just get rid of
them over
wow there's a huge value here in the
human race and and this is this is where
it lies and then projecting out just you
know i i had a uh very interesting
evening once at a
uh
owner's meeting
for pnw in whistler
yeah and mark you might want to hear
this because this is
he can hear you i ended up watching the
joe rogan uh
and uh elon musk podcast they got into
ai yeah and i was already very
heightened i was already very lifted
borderline mangled
and
it was profound
it was profound to me and i was like
when when a guy like elon musk is
talking about ai and going
it's tipped
and it's not able to be controlled i was
just you know
it won't be able to be controlled so
i hope ai looks at us as relevant and
important
there's a really great book
from 1988 called engines of creation and
it's by eric k drexler
and he coined the term nanotechnology
and so in that book he goes through all
sorts of cool concepts of nanotechnology
and he talks about how nanotechnology
won't be created by humans but it'll be
created by a.i
uh he wrote a new book like 25 years
later called radical abundance and if
you really want to open your mind like
check out both of those books i should
avoid both engines of creation
no it's amazing
[Laughter]
i i understand the excitement
and the potential of
because it's the next evolution of
humanity
i just hope that the humanity stays part
of it forthcoming gotta read this book
you gotta read the fourth coming
so this is the fourth turning story
this is the fourth turning is what we're
in the middle of right now it's like a
pretty good book is this like the
industrial revolution this is what we're
going through this is pretty much smack
right on what we've gone through over
the last
little bit so this is going to be a
really interesting book i've been doing
a lot of reading and getting touching
bases on these stories and what's
happening and how we're evolving so it's
cool
great books marcus is opening the goody
bags oh he's bringing oh you know what
you guys want to take a break that's a
sweet looking rig
you guys aren't stuck on camera the
whole day what part that little dab
right where are you sitting here doing
down
there
very very pretty
right now give me a minute and i'll give
you a hug
hey everybody can you uh i can i can
where is is there a camera of me
let me see if i can rotate this out
there we go
there's a terrible photo of me
hey guys how's it going
hi chad
hi peter
hi chris
hi london
hey guys
groovy shindig you got going on buddy
pretty cool eh
yeah
i love that king god out here this is
epic
it's been he's been such an awesome man
so don't go anywhere we're going to give
we're going to do a couple giveaways i'm
i'm pretty excited what do you guys
think of the show so far
good stuff
getting there
looks like a nice day
i like the mister the mystery is a
quality touch
so fucking hot over there it's brutal
it's insanely hot like you can't even
step on the tile with your bare feet
it's just that hot it's like
i'm so happy you guys are here
so we have we have the giveaway tool if
you want to use it where we can just do
a hashtag and then it just randomly
draws someone who
do you have things good to go to like
save the information and addresses so i
can send them to the people to send the
stuff
uh we can work on that i think i can do
that from this end
and then we can
note the winner basically you're saying
can we note the winner and
figure out how to connect with them
yeah i mean i can do it on this end too
that's why i took over for ken
yeah i think between the four of us uh
on this first giveaway we can
successfully connect with the winner
i have i have high confidence
so get ready we didn't have chris here
i'd i'd be a little less confident no
he's getting send an email to chris
if you win
chris will be standing by
do i gotta write
no no here i'll i'll do it uh
actually you can do it yeah yeah no no
no no it's too late now i've closed it
you've committed
well
so what well
why don't in the private chat why don't
you put in a hashtag
okay i will get the hashtag because i do
have them selected because i'm able to i
may i have a brand for all of them
i've not seen this magic voodoo work yet
on the uh stream yard
and is this the unicorn cup canadian
cret now that's
oh yeah it's delightful they adapt yep
okay let me just see what the what the
code is for boveda give me a second and
we'll go do a giveaway for the bavita
pack and as well as the quad pack
um how about save the chirps is that a
good uh
no i've got i've got brands done like
overlays for it to make life
easy i just i didn't write down what
they were yeah the vita is really easy
it's bavita
so that's that's going to be the simple
simple edition so just do are you guys
ready
are you guys ready
uh
i gotta open it
are you doing it
well i have it cued up so you want it
you want
this is the hash okay
that was my question
uh
okay setting a share
share
okay you ready
i'm always ready all right let everybody
know what the hashtag is
show it on the screen maybe
hashtag vegeta
hashtag
i really hope that's not something
really rude somewhere
so this this pack is pretty badass
actually they're giving away two c
vaults
um one's a two liter one's a smaller one
um one can hold five
five pounds point five of an ounce the
other one can point hold point two five
of a pound
uh ten pack of the
size four bavita
uh four pack of the 67 bavita as well so
it's pretty damn dope package you can
see a little picture there of it
get that in the chat
okay
here we go
come on come on give me some more that's
my drum roll entries people
hashtag bavita get it in there
you know what
i'm gonna straight up hashtag from here
scp gonna win
and uh
and and are we shipping globally
uh north america north america here
everybody
so i'm sorry if you're like
really far
but i haven't promised anything to be
shipped outside of north america
so
keep getting come on i want some more
videos in there before we do the draw
what are you snacking on chris what's
your snack of the day
can we get can we get a one two three
snack bake from chris what do we got
going on and don't forget to enter
bavita for the grave pack we're having a
look that looks like one hell of a fried
chicken sandwich
jack in the box
brilliant
come on give me a couple more guys
that is a home giving a sandwich we're
going to be doing giveaways over the
next hour
so like don't go anywhere like i don't
know
where you're going if you want to win
some stuff you should be here there's
like tons of stuff to give away too
okay we'll do 20 more seconds
20 more seconds enter your number
we have such boxes
we got smaller packs
you could
there could you there could be you could
be a multi-level winner today
if you try real hard
i mean like 30 30
come entries
if jesus was here with his like 30
accounts
yeah
yes
jesus ask them why are why our numbers
are below 100.
no problem guys i was excited to do this
we got a lot of fun stuff there's wings
and stuff
we got some snacks we're going to pull
the chef over in a little bit and have a
little chat with them and
see what we can do i've got a bunch of
fun
hash
so for anybody that's joining us late
london where are we what are we doing
today so today we're on the rooftop of
borough and beyond their town house so
we're doing a bunch of giveaways but
we're we have a lot of the vancouver
you know bc canada
growers
elite i would say we got john bertello
uh bc bubble man justin from growing
exposed i i've heard rumors of remo
um
so there's there's a lot of fun
happening we got food we're smashing
nugs we're testing weed
um
it's and we're smoking off of a really
nice glass which is pretty fun uh we
have uh
growing beyond has canadian produced
glass which is which is pretty badass
so you do have some sea vaults there
okay this is the 2-liter
and this one currently has some mac one
and ice cream cake in it
and and if you're in the chat you should
i would love to have one of those people
to get in on the giveaway
man let's see 10
pack of size four which would be
this the four i think this is the four
yeah
that's the four
two liter four pack of size 67 which
would be
this one
uh
sorry small c ball two
so wait sorry there's there is it two c
volts
small and a two liter
so
yeah two c vaults
one
let me see if i have a smaller one hold
on
and one uh
ten pack of size four
oh
no oh man i hope i win
yeah
what are we at we have 34
i think i think this is about time
shall we do it
yeah i don't know the smaller one but
the smaller one i assume uh
3.25 is probably about half the size of
that so you get half the size of this
you get this size
you get
uh
for you get four of these
and then a whole bunch of the like uh
little ones that you can throw in with a
an eighth or a quarter
that size
all right
[Music]
[Applause]
make sure you spell it right
make sure you spell the vida in the
hashtag
if you don't you don't get introduced in
the draw for a small c-vault a two-liter
t-vault and a bunch of boveda packs
and we have a boveda enthusiast in the
chat
big money big money actually
interestingly i i have them uh
keeping my tobacco so i i also have the
tobacco ones which are a higher humidity
and uh they're keeping my tobacco at a a
perfect uh
tobacco humidity which is like in the
high 60s
all right you ready
uh you are muted
i think he knows that all right
let's do it let's do the draw do the
dirty we're at 102.
our everybody let's make it happen
dude we got a ton of swag we're giving
away all right good luck everybody
hands down here we go
we really needed like a mixing board fun
thing oh
it was so close
that's like the uh wheel that goes like
tick tick tick tick and then like just
goes past it all right so
uh
are you
on instagram or can you email us
speak to us don't be shy
[Music]
uh why don't you send it to
uh
chris yeah chris is standing by chris is
very responsive on the emails
uh
send why don't you
put your email in the in the in the
no chat make him do that but but uh
send an email to
uh
how about
peter at
dot daggerdagga.org
peter
at
d-a-g-g-a dot l-o-v-e
and uh
[Music]
maybe if someone can just write down who
the winner was
scc four one nine plus one
this is right uh email peter
yep
theater dot love
awesome okay
and uh
okay
so i i just want to see scc 419 plus one
say something in the chat and then we
can move on
just say hi or like
i see that i won or
you're the winner better
but don't put my email all right don't
put my email in the chat because then i
get all the russian bots that start
emailing me
you think you could stop the community
do you think you can make that slow down
no no
um i can always just take that no i
can't i can only put them in timeout or
block them never mind
i know we can do it from right here
that's going to delete that one but
oh yeah no it says put it in timeout or
block
a for effort though but if i go into
the chat we need to see you in chat
we're gonna give you like two minutes
scc four one nine plus one you are the
winner
please raise your hand
if you're sure
raise your hand
brian secure
yes
i love you peter
thank you for removing it thank you for
removing it
oh nice
brother totally appreciated yeah
you're good you're a good man
all right
[Laughter]
i don't think we have the technical
capabilities right now to have a second
place uh
yeah
how about if if scc 419 doesn't click oh
my god the naked hot girls have finally
oh
[Music]
if scc doesn't claim it uh we will
at london's discretion pick a runner-up
how about that
i think
we should we can we can do another draw
in a couple minutes do we want to do we
want to give them sec a chance
uh over the next couple minutes or do we
want to uh go for another draw
uh i feel like we'd have to use a new
hashtag and then make everybody uh
go again
but what here let me see if
somebody put a camera on the push-ups
for me i want like that one
yeah that one and then
doing push-ups
who's doing push-ups
oh john's doing his yep okay yep
push-up time
let's go people
let's look at the form all right
everybody's hands are like burning on
that tile right
hot i now like it like a giant
one here we go three
four
five flat back
scc four one nine plus one you are the
winner of today's drive you are not
spoken up by the time the push-ups are
done you will not be winning
your package we will redraw
we will redraw
there you go you emailed there we go
or do you need the account there sec 419
plus one yeah the email is i think
someone threw it
where are our banners
there it is that's the email
and
and i hope you're
in uh
in north america
man
that's a way to do it
number five is alive
johnny i have more input need more once
wants to do another draw
so this is this is what i'd like to see
if you want me to do another draw right
now
uh we are going to ask
that
what is that
so he has a pull-up bar at home
i have no idea he does a lot of push-ups
so that's his
that's his big thing
oh further here so if you can all
let's let's help out our community here
because this amazing company has given
us uh some stuff to give it away humic
and fulvic
[Music]
so at i would like to see
a couple people
like them on instagram
if we could so i popped their instagram
in
and if you guys can go on instagram
and get them to 55 people they only need
as one two
three
eight people i want to see eight people
follow quad
uh underscore a oh no
so that we can give away
uh the next prize package okay
thank you so much i got chicken wings
ain't no thing but a chicken wing
he's a badass man
all right who's done it now
we've
come on have you gone on instagram yet
let me do a refresh here
they're giving away a pack of their
their whole organic package
we're at
349 we've had two new followers
oh you can draw again cool
okay so what are you guys smoking on
there's some hermit tendencies there so
strip the bottom
at 8 21.
but it fucking spanx
like hard
i am
smoking
down on farms
garlic cookies
hella bomb
down in the la area they sell it it's
from around me
in nevada county
alpaca powered living soil
flower it's the bomb
okay
all right
there we go we're well over the number
awesome thank you so much peter
next uh
i'll look up the next brand thing for
the next thing i believe it's quad but
let's say get a few more instagram likes
in there please
you can for me people they're a great
small business that is providing product
in the shipping for today's giveaway
so uh it'd be really nice to support
them
they are humic and vulvic fully organic
so that's pretty dope
okay so i need to queue up another
giveaway right yeah we'll do one more
and then we'll we'll take a little bit
of a a chill-out break
i want to tune back into those guys
dabbing and talking about what they're
dabbing on yeah i got a new set of
people going
just uh
jamie jonathan and uh
let me grab uh
[Music]
mark
chris you need to take a long rip every
time you hear it up next interview
no no no all right
so you guys will be up next set to
interview so i got our next set of
interviews ready to go so that i can go
deal with some stuff too because i
desperately need to but i just want to
bring this up where are you
okay so what's our next hashtag
hashtag bongrip
[Laughter]
with four h's you have to
get the correct number of ages oh oh no
no no no hold on
uh uh what were we just doing on the
other channel
hashtag uh gravity box
gravity bomb
that's kind of why i've got the next one
lined up there for you peter i put it on
private chat
you know what chris i did just go down
to the ocean and i forgot to do a
gravity bomb but it was super low tide
and we saw all kinds of starfish and
rock crabs it was kind of magical oh
yeah okay we are ready you want to
announce it
let's do it the ball jar drum roll
let's go
all right hashtag quad is our next
giveaway right now
can anybody name one of the quad city
djs
probably not
already
entered in there
okay so what no i i wanted to hear where
the uh immunity for a second i was
trying to figure out where the little
hissing was coming from
i thought that was in my ear
so here here's some of this stuff that
we're giving away here you want to bring
can you bring me up a little bit bigger
we got the humonic foiler we'll they're
going to throw in a cap here uh
you you know what
give me this give me this you tell me
what's in the package and i will hold
them up like a beautiful girl
you'll be my van away you'll be my vanna
white
night after
is
we have two trios of our one liter
organic trios so they are a bundle of
our humonic and phalonic which is our
base formula
uh humic acid and kelp extract our
fulonic is our pure fulvic acid for
systemic application or a wetting agent
for your foliars and then we have our f2
foliar which is our fulvic acid blended
with
four key micros to support
photosynthesis we've got boron zinc
manganese and sulfur all to green up
your canopy and make those fruits larger
you look beautiful
that's the humonic humonic and phalonic
that's the whole we've got two of those
trios and then we've got the little mini
foliars for a little kiss and towel and
then some quad neutral hats
jesus
so we're going to we're going to give
those we're going to get the address out
to them so you got to get that hashtag
quad into the chat now
um get that in there give me that
hashtag quad i see some good numbers
coming up and guys hey listen we're
going to get another conversation going
here we're going to get some dabs going
we got more giveaways just quickly
collective mary jane it's hashtag quad
not at quad
yeah sorry
quad hashtag quad i am terrible with my
graphics
and i want to shout out from below the
graphic to knc who actually did name one
of the quad city djs booyah big ups to
you everybody knows that come on ride
the train with me tonight
come on ride the train quad city dj
y'all
big ups knz
that beautiful package that we have to
give away
because i'm going to put them on for
conversation they can smoke and tell me
what they're smoking on and i can i can
eat and live sustain myself
come on get it in there hey excellent
medium
did you have a good time
there we go
there we go you need to smoke something
peter
uh can you i i know
what i'm also like super i've been super
stuffed up for the past uh
like since i got back from rhode island
but like my head's
because i'm so stuffed up my head just i
have a constant like pounding right here
so i need to
i almost need like a uh
like an edible or something
do you not have any edibles
no i do i just never usually
take edibles
do it i could i could pop a couple
let's see
give me one thing let
i was muted i was singing that song
again
oh good one though
anybody in chat
tell us when was the last time you used
a gravity bomb
and was it in the sink or did you go pro
bathtub style
because
pros use the bathtub
i'm just saying
chris when's the last time you used a
gravity bomb buddy
oh dude
um
shooter 10 minutes ago
he's living the dream today
dude yep i think you muted again uh
london
i have no
idea yes
it's mooted i'll try and mute you from
this side though
there we go
thank you yeah you got hopefully you
guys didn't get too much crotch shot
20 years ago
so what i love
is uh
my friend jody label these
but you can't really see me yeah
five gallon and a two liter that's the
classic that's the barbecue gravity bong
edition
so
these are tankers and so we labeled this
one it's like taking an advil
oh this one he labeled it's like taking
advantage
and then this one yeah it says get high
and then
this one is like advil and xanax so this
is it like a one to one
yeah cbda thc balanced
and then the advil is uh
thca rich
the xanax is an ac dc uh cbda rich
and then the get high
is thp rich
anyway
seven sacred pools i have been out there
man the the hana highway i think it is
holy cow that's a windy narrow road
but big ups for gravity bonging there
shaun t
90s using the bathtub
yeah that sounds about right
my beats aren't
yeah my my face right now it's like
almost feels like i have toothaches or
like uh
like i got lockjaw when kobet first hit
and i was freaking out because it's like
everybody there's this global pandemic
and it's gonna kill you and then i'm
like i need to go to a hospital or
something but i was like i'm not going
anywhere and i didn't know what was
going on
uh
and then my sister who's a
a surgeon was like i think you might
have lock job
and so i just started taking like
tons of advil and stuff all right
but that's what it feels like right now
just like for the past week and a half
all right so london we ready to do uh
[Applause]
yeah and hey don't don't go anywhere
after the giveaway guys because we have
conversations and then after those
conversations we have more giveaways and
they're not scheduled you gotta fucking
be here that's your choice that's your
option you gotta be here be square
uh but yes
so we got we got 49
got 49 entries for this one you guys
want to do the draw what do you think
guerrero can we get can we get your call
out here i want your beautiful voice
give me that give me that run down
interest way just be like we have our
last entryway for quad
you know how you do it so nicely this is
very interesting right now
ladies and gentlemen
we have our last entry
let's go
[Music]
[Laughter]
and now we have the benny hill music i
got i got to get that brand off so i'm
going to stop covering up our beautiful
chadwick
congratulations dude man bro
dude man bro did you did you hear that
you're the winner of the beautiful gift
package
i wonder if somebody's like tapping him
on the shoulder right now and being like
dude man bro peter did you did you put
in the subject of the oh no
yeah
tmj is what i was talking about not
lockjaw yeah it's uh
that's what i had before
and it feels like it's congrats dude
did he talk
there he is
so dude man bro we want you to email
sorry
we want you to email peter
okay so
uh
banner
so send an email to that and then i'll
send a group email
to our head of fulfillment
christopher guerrero
london
yes
i said our head of fulfillment
yeah i'm the head of fulfillment i will
make sure
i ain't paying for no shipping i'll tell
you that much
yeah so if someone ordered uh
even though on the website it says like
usa only someone ordered three fish
brews
and uh
exactly eventually i want to try to send
one across the border but it was like 50
something dollars for me to ship it
yikes
and i was like i don't want to take that
risk on
like i want to set
so
small sign bro
you emailed right brother
uh you need an email there
yeah no so to the guy who won the first
one who just emailed me back saying i
won i know you won i uh
okay
evidently there are very few people who
are masters of your all so i sent a
group email to you in london
so hit the reply all
so that london also sees
uh
your email
always very important when you respond
to these reply all please reply all
okay i am going to reply to you and put
london back on the thread
chris was recently educated on the reply
all we had a tutorial
the other day
no no i know but i'd like to i'd like to
make it clear
that wasn't that i was educated i was
educated the opposite
well you know you know what it's like
it's like i debate with uh every girl
i've ever dated about whether
after a guy goes pee when you get yelled
at for not putting the seat down i'm
like the seat's up you know what you
definitely know i lifted it to go pee
that's right
so take the win
take the win
and i did lift the seat when i peed and
you don't have to question whether i
lifted the seat when i went feet
yeah
okay so winner number two
uh
winner number two do you feel confident
that you know what you're next supposed
to do which is to send an email to me
uh
oh dude
yep
you should give an ounce of weed away
to only canadians
you can do it you can do it or north
america or no no no no no no
no no we're let's just
let's do it
i could send the us from in the u.s
uh sorry so the dude man bro
i'll sell you some oregano man and his
oil of oregano just essential oil
extracted from oregano
because i have a ton of oregano outside
me too
you ever get curious about that and just
like start pressing stuff like pine
needles what no so i i want to so i have
a um
i always forget what the device is
called it's uh
a little bit about it it's an e it's an
alcohol extraction unit
i used it once on weed
to help someone get a bunch of uh
of oil
but i i want to start just using it all
my herbs like just anything yeah yeah
like rosemary and a lot of the things
that i have in the back i got curious
with that i'm just like man i wonder you
know the essential oils in there you
just have to press it hard enough okay
we have our contact spot back okay cool
i got her or him or it whatever the spot
is
we have someone who's willing to buy
that oregano from you
awesome
okay i'm gonna add london
and make it a group email
okay
[Applause]
and have you been painting happy little
trees while uh waiting to jump back in
nice
i even queued up a uh
yeah we cannot hear ken no
that's cool to see him and london in the
same spot though
that was what ken
that was ken while he was off camera
he's the live painting to the music he
does a live painting behind the dj
that's what it looks like
and this is the rosin of it so i'd love
you guys to have a little whiff of it
let me know what you think and then just
talk about it
yeah
uh i
[Music]
uh here we go
let's have
[Applause]
can you hear me now check check check
check check check check check
check check check
first
there we go check check check check
check check
talk to yourself
that's very very kind to you guys thank
you very much
what was that chad
it was silica
keep it dry
yes keep keep your beans dry everybody
use your silicas
okay
yes
so i guess we'll just introduce
ourselves first so everybody knows who
we are
i've got this wonderful dab that i want
to start with my name is jamie where do
you want it right here is this good
that's perfect
just naturally yes i should be on in a
second
all right here we go this is a session
on top of
a roof patio i'm jamie
[Music]
yeah so i'm jamie from sessions
uh based in kelowna and i'm super pumped
to be out here with you guys what do you
do get some wheat on a tuesday um
marketing and media production that is
our main goal for work for a lot of
different cannabis companies in the
legal side get to smoke a lot of
fireweed
and that's really what it comes down to
is that like uh creating a job so you
can just get high all the time
that's perfect it almost was dude like
i've always
been a partier you know like
i've always wanted to have a good time
that's all what it was always about and
i love
having a good time with other people
and then this industry and this business
is kind of that's what it's all about
nice
well i'm jeff from boro and beyond we do
uh concentrate accessories
and uh canadian glass made by local
people um we've had a shop since 2015 to
2018 now we do it online and we do
wholesale in the legal market with
cannabis retailers and kind of all the
accessories to go with
concentrates so if you want to smoke
dabs we have everything that you want to
smoke them in the highest quality way
possible kind of always researching
like the apex way to take your dab
so it's uh we kind of got the whole
process down to a science and a lot of
canadian glass been sold over the years
a lot of events and showcases we've done
and uh
yeah it's been a fun ride and it's
really fun being kind of the niche that
we do as well and
kind of setting ourselves apart and uh
we were the first in canada to do it
like 100 canadian as well so yeah so
you're you're promoting having a good
time exactly right now what is the best
way to take a dab so uh we have the you
get your piece with the with a quartz
banger on it we've got nine different
ones some true courts to choose from and
uh
basically you heat it up with a torch
and then you have a sensor like the dab
right that's on the table there and
it'll be able to measure the perfect
temperature for your dab it's called a
dab right because after you use it
you'll never dab wrong again
until the sensor clogs yeah but that's
but that's user maintenance you know you
got to keep up on that we're always
learning
yeah so um it's yeah that's the way to
take a dab and then you cap the top on
one of these slurpers and feed your dab
through the bottom and uh
yeah and uh on to the next
hi i'm mark and i just i've started the
vancouver island home growers guild
which is
basically just kind of
celebrating
small grows and what you can do at home
whether it's a four plant grower whether
you have an acm pr in your home and
you're
but you can you're growing at home and
you're you know celebrating the fact
that you can do that that you don't have
to be um
the
like the state-of-the-art facility in
order to grow fireweed because fireweed
has always come from
little
backwoods places and and
from people that are you know
kind of uh paved the way of a lot of
movements like maybe even organic food
and stuff is kind of influenced by
people from weed so to kind of
embrace what the island has always been
and that's like a long long time people
in especially in canada
known vancouver island
is a place
that has got a growing culture so for us
to to
celebrate that and i started with uh
doing seed swaps because i thought well
that's a way to for us as small growers
to get to know each other and
to share with um you know each
genetics is important and now we're
moving on to doing a small cup so i'm
going to
basically the people that have
got together at the swaps are
looking forward to um
celebrating the harvest this fall and uh
and
we're going to have a few sponsors
to
give us some prizes and
just
celebrate what the big guys do but as
the home growers to give you a piece of
that
and i'm looking forward to it i
appreciate that for sure yeah that's
great thanks
i'll pass the mic on though
hey
i'm uh jonathan with uh green amber
canada we're based out of the okanagan
in british columbia
we've been
been growing pretty good weed for the
past few years
um and that's the respect to british
columbians and the hard work that
they've put in all the many years that
they've been growing marijuana and i've
recognized that myself being part of the
part of the uh the industry for a very
long time
so we grow good weed and uh we we do so
through our lighting um so we develop
some lighting that is helpful for not
only you know the the home grower but
definitely the commercial grower you
designed your own lights yeah right
we've designed our own lights and uh we
tested them out in the okanagan for
about two years in different
uh environments and uh over that time
period we saw
trends that we've recognized that we've
now have and we use that in the
algorithms in our lighting that can help
you grow
but at the same time if you are a
smaller grower you are more of a craft
grower that really likes the art
of growing marijuana then these lights
give you those bells and muscles that
help you do that and that's what i've
been doing for the last little while
while we're building out our facility um
but uh it does
help the average grower
know a little bit of how say the sun
travels through the sky traditionally
for cannabis yeah
so what is special about your lights
that is different from others
the
[Music]
ability to change the spectrum blues and
reds
yeah so you can get your own spectrum uh
and you can try and see how how intense
that spectrum is too you can dial that
in at any time uh given given 24 hours a
day right so you can program that in up
to 24 hours in your day and basically
you can see the spectrum change
over that time period
and i'm jonathan fernandez with green
amber canada
i'm jamie morris with sessions
i'm jeff with borough and beyond sorry
kind of marketing
cooper island homegrowers guild
mark with the vancouver island
homegrowers guild
here let me
i'll pass you this one
yeah that's i'm really looking forward
to driving the other thing that we are
definitely
right this yeah and i i'm really looking
forward to this job this is a gift from
marcus to me and uh and from the
dragonfly earth medicine and i'm like oh
yeah here we go this is gonna be fun so
so jeff you're gonna run us through the
process
awesome i'm just doing a quick clean
real quick okay before we do that why
don't you do a clean video let's do this
clean video here
yeah
i need to know too so you get a dabber
you heat it up a little bit and then you
have an alcohol wipe like a swab and so
this you just it'll it's like a magnet
for all the resin so check this out i'm
just going to put it in there with the
dabber now
pressure's on
oh nice nice
that is that is very good
as you can see it's picked up all
the leftover resin and he's and he's got
it out if you can get a close-up of that
you can totally see that look at that
looks a little easier than a q-tip
alcohol in there
[Music]
four guys cleaning one ribs and knocking
shit over on the table just kind of i i
kind of knew this banger would get
hosted today
[Music]
yeah it's a it's a commune
thank you
i i think the guy on the left
accidentally turned his mic off ken
ken's not really listening
ken i think the guy on the left turned
to that i think that mic is off right
now
generally you want to
take the
residue out of it before you take a dab
because anything that's kind of baked on
isn't really going to taste too good
because i mean you're torching it
kind of burning it off
it's like a burnt dab taste kind of
jeff how hot could one of those get
those
those nails so butane burns at about i
want to say
close to a thousand fahrenheit so it
generally when you take the torch off of
it it's about 900 fahrenheit wow um you
want to take a dab kind of closer to
like
under 550 550 yeah
why is 550 the ideal number
you get the perfect balance of
vaporizing the thc to vaporizing the
terpenes without compromising the flavor
but then also you get enough that you're
actually going gonna get stoned rather
than you know having to go in for a
reheat
almost as hot as your deck i'm a big fan
of cold dabs that i'm thinking right now
like i i like taking the terps for for
somewhere at 450 even
yeah but it's a bit heavier on your
lungs though right like i find with when
you when you get those terps and you're
burning them that that at that rate they
kind of just hang around but it's a
lower temp yeah it's a lower temp but
this is like the perfect temp where
everything vaporizes and you get the
most out of everything as good as that
press was you get the most out of that
press at 550. it's also important to
note though that different rosins yes
for sure different strains uh different
um
uh screen sizes
will make a difference very much
consistency of rosin which then your
turn needs a different temperature to
enjoy it okay so this is rosin right
applied so
and there's at least i would say still
about eight or nine percent terps
left in this
um
but it leaves a lot of crap on your bank
for example right because it comes from
flowers it comes from flowers and not
right so the difference in rosin like
look you could put this in a cart for
example right versus say
we're looking at um the big bag
uh from lost boys in victoria
and the big bag is a 73 to 159
micron
[Music]
right it's a it's a the big bag is 73 to
159 micron so that's that's the
the screen level that material that we
used to press this
right
came out of so 73 to 159 micron and this
is what he pulled and this is what it's
why it smells
way it smells
how does it smell extremely earthy
big bag number five
there's citrus there's
woodsy yeah a little bit of pine in
there
terpene for sure
yeah there's definitely some pine in
there yeah what's the effect on the big
bag how would you
it's an upper it's definitely an up oh
this is an upper yeah
[Music]
that's a nice color
jessie at uh lost place once again uh
from victoria does some good work all
right lost boys rosin that's what i'm
looking at
these guys
it's firework it's fire
and uh the color on here is like nice
light that's that wasn't even fresh when
i got it fresh it was like it's been
opened a few times so this is the type
of rosin that when i look at it it makes
my mouth water yeah
just because i know that the
the purity in here this the effect that
you get from this is
is exactly what i want the body wants it
all
that was very very nice thank you very
much that's all i can say
i want to try some of this over here
see how it tastes
now we were talking um
about rosin cartridges on the drive up
here
uh what do you think about rosin in
cart form compared to the flavor and
enjoyment that you get from a banger
honestly i quite like it depends on the
cartridge though some of them are really
high quality some of them
are kind of not so high quality in the
cartridge department so
the best way to represent that kind of
flavor
is uh to have it um you know in a high
quality cartridge now if you have that
high quality cartridge that's meant for
the viscosity of the solvent-less
product oh my god you can get a really
good good result out of it you can get a
flavor that's similar to taking a hoot
off of a banger for example
um
so you're right there
he's okay he's good yeah
oh okay
sorry i just i just wanted to make sure
i
don't need my help or anything you know
are you worried i'm ready to help if you
need it because
those uh those slippers can be kind of
tough to clean with a q-tip so
i definitely know it's uh it's a process
but um
yeah as for rosin cartridges they just
have to make sure that they're also
separated properly
um sometimes you know rosin can be
extremely viscous
but uh if they you know leave like a
really high terpene profile and you
crash out the crystals and uh you know
make sure that it's separated properly
then uh i mean it's it's pretty easy to
do but there's some strains that just
don't
they don't
like warm cure the same way no they
don't they clearly don't right so
everything is different so when you
pheno hunt for example right you're
looking for aspects that you can say hey
when i take this and i wash it right and
i watch this and this and this in this
level what is it going to smell like
right what can i press it into at the
end of the day so it doesn't just start
as as a process like uh processing is an
art but you also have to then final hunt
the exact kind of smells
and and the yield because
even if you can get it to smell if you
can't get that plant to yield right it's
it's tough it's tough to then make up
factors yeah
yeah because it's uh you know they
describe it to me like um
you know you have um the pheno hunting
is in itself an art and then you have um
you know making sure you're breeding for
a certain uh
a certain like trichome type
um but yeah so it's
there's so many factors that go into it
like you know there's like almost like
10 different points that they have to be
watching out for
from uh you know making sure like the
glands aren't uh too greasy you know
making sure that the glands are going to
fall off making sure the terpene profile
is proper for hash making sure
you know there's so many different
factors it's uh
it's really uh here let me help you with
that yeah throw it on top
there you go
no you keep hitting it
inside
yeah but see but the readers now it's
like now we've got degraded thc and
terps now right it smells good so i
don't even you don't even know it does
smell good
yeah but now it's a a second
a second heat get it from the side walls
yeah yeah yeah there you go don't inhale
while you're while you're torching it
though yeah because you might get some
of the butane in there i never really
think too many of these these types of
things oh i think i you know i don't
know the effects of doing like flowers
years but i've done stuff like this for
years
me too yeah
well no like because like so i
what i wanted to get sorry the one i
wanted to get across was the fact that
once you reheat it and it's still there
and it's caked on and you keep heating
and you keep heating and you keep
heating then you're just taking more
degraded material into your lungs
so sometimes you have like keeping it
clean all the time is probably the best
way to do it right yeah exactly
right because like yeah
i'm just saying
[Music]
so what i was thinking we could do is
well while we have you here and we have
everybody over there
let me know ken peter we're going to try
and do a giveaway from two quarts and
sessions while we have the guys that are
up here to do the giveaway so see if he
can get ready to do that one but what
have you guys been smoking on what's
been your favorite to taste so far
big bag
from the lost boys on the island this
live resin is
nice this is exactly kind of what i
wanted for the day a bit of an upper
immediately to the dome
feel great
that's what i wanted
awesome
so you brought a swag bag of stuff to
give away and you brought you got you
got the true course has given away a
banger today right so i've got i've got
them they're going to put up a hashtag
ken's going to let me know and we're
ready to go for that one um
i'm fucking baked
have you lost peter no no no no it's
okay we can live without peter we will
survive
can't we come back to it ask him what
brand so you had did you talk about your
series that you have coming up
yeah so
we visit a lot of different uh producers
in a lot of different facilities in the
legal side of things and
we are coming out with the show because
we travel a lot of different places
our show is called all fire no mids we
represent
great cannabis great weed and the people
that put the time and love into
making great products where are you
what's your name again and where are you
from again my name is jamie norrish i'm
from kelowna
i'm jamie norrish
from kelowna with sessions
talking about my all fire no mids web
series that is launching in september
um and our first episode our pilot
episode is when we uh i don't know if
you've got the opportunity to see it but
the pistol and paris uh advertisement
for their brand um
we filmed that in abbotsford with dylan
and and we documented that so
that's uh
the pilot episode they'll be launching
in september and you'll be able to see
that on the sessions instagram sessions
youtube um big up pistol in paris
pistol and paris fire weed fireweed
[Music]
so epistle in paris um
they are their their slogan is legacy to
legal and
they buy product from um micro growers
that have transferred from the legacy
side
into the legal side that know how to
produce great cannabis and have the
reputation from for producing it for
years and years and so
we started working with them to promote
those people promote that weed because
it's weed that i would smoke myself
and uh yeah it was a huge project it was
a large project four sessions it was our
first one as a as a group and uh it went
well it went great
so
we're moving on to
others sure
i'm just thinking the thing that got me
ripped today
is london's edible
i kicked in a little while ago
on top of these dabs and uh yeah i'm
just honored to be here
i i i follow those uh crystal in paris
it looks like they have really good
really nice flower that from what i see
in the pictures on the website they do
they have some of the top flower on the
legal market there's a lot of great
growers there's a lot of great brands
out there too so yeah um the industry
has changed quite a bit over the last
three years you know where we started
can't say the same thing that's what i'm
saying right now right it was a
different story yeah well these people
are transferring into the legal space
and now producing and providing that
here's a cool little story on the side
for today too is uh i've my family's
been growing a cut for a long long time
and uh i would track it back about 20
years from like when we got it it
doesn't i don't know what it is but i
got tested today it's never been tested
ever right what is it it's uh it's just
called vera
and uh she's uh she's an indica dominant
kind of thing and really nice and uh but
she came out at like what
this is the man right here that we
should introduce him the trim and test
and press because this guy is awesome
dave thank you very much this is super
you should do a dab with us here do a
dab with us yeah come on come on
come on
this is really what like i got vira
tested and i got lindsey og tested and i
did really well like
being a homegrower but what is the link
you wonder what you can actually
like if you can compete
or whatever and i think that the home
grow is fire
yeah i i've done over like 300 flower
samples by now and i'll tell you like
working with micros and lps and
homegrowers the average is like 17 and a
half percent yeah that's good so when
you get a homegrower that's in the 20s
it's great yeah i know a lot of people
slag some lps but i work for some and
they're putting out 27 32 percent and
it's fucking fire so
whoever said earlier like i support
however i put the like whoever puts the
love in like that's oh yeah totally yes
right like that's a true
island one and it was seventy six point
eight percent
pretty fucking strong pretty fucking
strong right so big up the jet once
again jesse came through right
but someone was talking about pistol in
paris earlier there's a grower that
works for them because as they move into
the legal market his name is alex and bc
greenhouse shout out to them their store
in maple ridge
put me in contact with alex and i got to
test some of his dbx the other day and
that was 32.6
so when that comes to fucking market
okay what was the moisture content well
we talked about this earlier today right
now what is the moisture what's the
moisture
if you're if you're putting him in on tv
now we have to know the moisture content
it's really fun because that guy loves
what he does and he's gotten so much
better
uh and made like minor adjustments so
he's had a few tests and he's been able
to look at it and make some adjustments
and now like
i don't know out of 300 plus samples
there's maybe five or six that are 30
plus right it's not very common so he's
absolutely killing it but he's really
taking the data and branding it
the plan is basically hung over dripping
with thc right pretty much it was well
he brings me dry he brings me dried
samples so like all i need is a gram and
a half sample and i can i'll take half a
gram and run it through let's let's look
at the moisture content once again
before we okay
not to say that we
don't have any good results here because
i believe in 32
i believe it's an nbc too so
don't get me wrong right like you're not
going to find it in ontario you might
find it in quebec but you're not going
to find it in ontario unless they're
spraying it with a lot of spray he he
was really like he's really dialing it
in though like on the he took samples
from the inside of his room like in the
middle of the room and from the outside
of his room the variance was huge like
outside of the room from the perimeter
where there wasn't as much fan action
and there wasn't such like
great environment he was down to about
17 and a half percent yeah where
everything was dialed in like he was
pushing 32 so like now he knows what
sample to send
well even like when you use our lights
everybody that uses our lights say the
same thing so we've so we've ran through
these lights for about two years gave
them to a lot of people let them test
them out and the data we generally get
when you follow like a sun cycle
typically if you can do that with your
lighting um oh is it your lights yeah so
yeah so when you do that um you can
basically maybe increase yield thc like
two percent so if you're like 25 you can
hit 27 maybe right so if you can then
control the other factors that you grow
with right yeah so if you grow
organically like we do um well maybe not
like you but well yeah well
yeah we uh we try to
manage our inputs by what we put there
and how it breaks down over a period of
time right yeah yeah
that's cool
that's it yeah
i was over here because someone had like
we're doing a dab you got it you gotta
you gotta try it out
well that was good
she does help me in the garden she calls
them bonsais which is great because when
she goes like i help my dad with his
bonsais i'm like good just keep calling
them
yes
we're gonna do the sessions in the true
courts giveaway here pretty quickly as
this as this dab goes on
there's again a little bit of back mist
which is nice
did
yeah this like i only ever use my
peak so this is kind of near the cool
thing about it is the regulator in the
in the mail i love the regular so here
you can hit the perfect amount of beef
and then i can take whatever size
oh sweet okay
what rig did you just say that you use
all the time
the peak pen as well i just like the
electric or the puffco sorry the puffco
yeah because i just like the electric i
like the ease of it i don't really like
having a blowtorch especially what temp
do you set it at uh i start it green and
then i move up to red so
i know like 180
so we got these guys with this stuff
here
uh you want to talk about what you're
giving away for your giveaway pack of
swag yeah
a little bit while these guys hold it up
and then dave will slowly get out of the
way and while you while they're talking
about the swag that's going on there go
out check out
sessions
on instagram get in there
send them a like or a follow because
they are producing this content over
there i don't know why i'm stepping so
far you know yeah but they have some
shirts
some
awesome stuff
try yeah
there's four sides yep that one that's
the one okay so hashtag
is the uh code there for them to do the
draw are they ready for that
the terp train
ken does it look ready show the camera
all right sessions enter it into the
past tell me about what you got all
right so here what jonathan is holding
up is a
photo that we took in our studio of some
fire i think that's rosin diamonds
and then we have uh all fire no mids
shirt and sticker pack
then we have a high life
this is our other brand too high life
shirt and tank and then there's two hats
here
our new logo and our og logo which is my
favorite logo
and then if you're a winner in canada
there will be another little extra thing
in there that i'm just not going to put
details into but you know what it is
wink
wink hint nugs canadians get in the draw
um
all right go in we got a hashtag
[Music]
we got a thing from uh jeff jeff coming
up next but we're just doing this one so
tell a little bit
tell me a little bit more about what
you've been working on last year
um so
sessions the the the company is based in
kelowna but
we are moving the entire studio and
office to the island
so that's what's happening in the next
few months we're looking for a space for
a new studio but also event space too
i'd love to have a cannabis lounge right
now uh legislation is being written
for bc to start incorporating cannabis
lounges
into the framework and i want to have
one
we'll have it connected to the studio
and
once that's going i mean i hope to see a
lot of them but i hope to have multiple
across canada as well
that sounds happy i can't wait for there
to be a lot more indoor consumption but
we could go to a shop and do this
instead and then get really comfortable
how we doing on the drawing
do we want to get pulling
30 entries
give me a couple more in there and then
let me know how people can support your
community uh so you can follow us on
instagram at sessions high life
uh we also have a youtube channel uh
sessions highlife and follow us on there
we're posting videos all the time uh
we're out in the industry every day new
facilities new people to work with new
brands to talk about um
we follow the fire too so the premium
cannabis is you guys are just
powerhouses aren't you our team is
growing yeah you know a year and a half
ago it started with four people now we
have over 12 employees and uh we're able
to do a lot now so
we're feeling pretty good about where
we're at and we love who we were killing
it
hell yeah
and uh
yeah yeah
let's do it let's uh shall we get the
draw rolling
i think mark has some interesting
questions okay
go for it peter that's so sorry and i
totally fed him too big of a dab
[Music]
okay
so we are drawing right now do we have a
winner
here we go drum roll please everybody in
check go guys
congratulations
glissaholic you got you let me know when
we're ready to move on to the next draw
okay
just be like hey when they when they
find out what the winner is
so glissaholic
send an email there
peter once you got their information let
us know and we will go on the next draw
with true quartz
sweet so who won
uh
yeah congratulations to the alyssa
hollock for winning the pack if you're
canadian we'll put a little extra stuff
in there
uh and if you're not and i i'm super
happy that you're representing our stuff
uh wherever you live that's awesome
awesome really cool so i wanna we're
gonna what we're gonna do is draw next
on the true quartz coming here um yes
oh yeah it's like whack-a-mole i know
stand right now what we're gonna how am
i right now how am i right now
am i right there
you just stand right there so what we're
gonna do next is draw for the true
quartz banger um and is it coming with
you want to tell me what the draw is and
i also because we had a serious
discussion the other day when did this
contest happen it's happening right now
right now
you can you go sign on youtube sign on
youtube you can enter right now you
gotta sign on youtube
right now okay
hey peter make sure jonathan doesn't win
okay no i can't even do anything
it won't be rigged again no we have our
we have our studio guys we're entering
too everybody can enter i really want
three
it is if you want on your way out you
want to tell me oh yeah you can get one
on your way out right
that's right
can you tell me what makes them so
special and why you guys are who you are
so um
basically there are a lot of different
grades of course out there and us being
like connoisseur you know hash smokers
ourselves and using these we wanted we
didn't want to spend a few hundred
dollars on you know an american
uh made or canadian made banger because
it's
it gets really pricey if people like i'm
sure there's people out here watching
this that know that you know bangers can
go over like 500 us dollars each and uh
not a lot of people want to spend that
much on a quartz banger so does it
actually make a dab better
um so this one here
so i mean i love the that one um there's
nine different designs so the sorry the
main thing being with that one is it has
a very big thick bottom
you know
everyone likes a big thick bottom
anyways it retains heat so especially on
a quartz banger so it
so it retains it retains heat uh really
nicely
um you know it's just more mass to hold
on to the heat that you torch it with um
and uh yeah so it it kind of radiates
evenly too
yeah so you plug the top
there's slits in uh at the bottom of the
little small tube on the the slurp area
if you want to just hold that up there
there's a
the smaller tube and then the larger
dish on the bottom there slits
right here and then when you plug the
top
the oil gets sucked into those slits and
it creates like a vortex for us as well
and it really like vaporizes it and
creates a lot of good surface area for
you to like you know completely vaporize
your dab at a lower temperature and uh
it just works really nicely
um
so the main thing about these bangers is
that they use equivalent material that
those north american bangers use but
because there's so many different grades
that uh different manufacturers are
using out there um that it it creates um
you know
like something that you don't want to
guess about what you're dabbing off of
and nobody wants impurities and things
that they're smoking off of especially
you know the surface so it's just kind
of guaranteeing that these are made with
the highest quality material that's
available to the manufacturer um they're
you know a little bit more expensive
than your 40 dollar no-name banger
but they um you know they come with
rubies they they hold heat better they
they're a lot more pure um
this is the one we're giving away here
it's a regular style
they last longer than glass
hold on everyone has the shape stuff on
the other side that's that one's like
it's not true let me start over skinny
and this one's sort of fat what do you
like better
honestly there's nine different designs
and they're all kind of like my children
i like them all equally
there's gotta be one that sits in the
honestly i love the auto spinner because
it's so it's like this bucket here
except it has two angular holes drilled
through it so when you plug the top like
you do with the slurper the little
rubies that come with it will spin like
crazy um so
that's my favorite this is the regular
one that we're giving away it's the
tried and true it's the most common
design that everybody tends to use as
well
just plop a bubble cap on top of that
and you're good to go
but that's yeah the vast majority of
people like this style the most
just because
so it seems easier to clean so again
this is a lot easier to clean enter in
now yeah i want to see a few people go
on to to what do you want burrow or true
course
building
and instagram and try and give them a
like and when i see a few follows and
likes in the instagram thing
i will i will finish the draw so not
only will you speed up the draw
increasing your chances to win by
following them but on top of that
you will get more chances of winning so
draw like help help out the community
it's a 300 it's a 300 banger right no
it's not actually it's not this is the
equivalent mr t put a hashtag in front
of that 300 banger but for 70.
70 dollar bank john lose the e so it's a
it's a really
and stuff like that you do want
a banger that doesn't have impurities in
it that would ruin
what you're putting in you don't want to
disrespect you don't care
then you don't care but people that do
it's important now that
what are some of the impurities that you
would find in glass i mean i've heard of
this but i actually don't know
what it is
trace metals
um and minerals also there's uh
like um
i think that's like a peroxide radical
or something it just ends up degrading a
little bit quicker when it's exposed to
heat and it's just kind of in kind of in
the crystal matrix as well
those impurities like uh some of them
are a little bit more um benign than
others like you know it might degrade a
little bit quicker but um for the
peroxide type of thing but it's uh when
it comes to like trace metals you
definitely don't want that in your cords
so that's
that's something that's really important
is making sure it's super pure
and uh you know got to respect those
terps with a good surface to vaporize
off of i'd agree
does anybody have anything to do
shall we do the draw
go ahead peter do the draw
okay get your good to go
get ready everybody get it in you got
your last seconds before twitter pushes
the button correct entries get ready
here we go
come on get it in there
seconds
[Music]
congratulations
very high quality dabs damn
microphone down uh we are getting close
to the end of it here at three o'clock
and we do have the dank hour happening
in a couple hours
so i i just wanted david do you want to
get over i want to nicole we gotta we
gotta plug you a little bit too do you
guys think you can uh cover for me for a
couple minutes there guerrero and peter
and stuff anybody entertain for a few
minutes while we uh get together or my
next you hear that yes we can how would
we ever
so just quickly uh glissaholic i didn't
see an email so just make sure that you
sent it
that is
for the typing challenge
so can they hear us
yeah those guys know no can't you hear
it ken can hear us okay carrying here
dude can or when
when he was all like
this three hundred dollar piece it's all
like uh
it's a seventy dollar piece
this seventy dollar piece
peter at d-a-g-g-a dot l-o-v-e
it's not
d-a-g-g-a-l-o-v-e.com it's d-a-g-g-a dot
l-o-v-e
um and then to the next person
how did london pronounce ewing i don't
win yeah we
[Laughter]
all right so howard you
also ewing
it's an airplane
to that address
curious
and that will connect you with london
is that like an electric airplane
i see the first you want to fly in one
of those
speaking of viewing though i saw the
dopest epmd times patrick ewing shoes
the other day
they're high tops they're like black
with some fluorescent accents but uh
no those are dope though it looks like
it came out in the 90s pump era though
but seriously the yeah patrick ewing's
got his own shoes man hey he had an
his name is not e-wing
sorry power do you you gotta change it
he's connected e-wing you're an airplane
electric airplane
okay
so where where are they yeah
we're behind in the show
alton's just uh just unsure yeah
like five minutes behind although uh
what part of uh canadia are they in uh
vancouver
oh nice which part is that
so west coast go to the border travel
another 45 minutes and you're in
downtown vancouver okay so it's the west
coast part of canada it's a good part
yeah you didn't you didn't have any
rains how many raves have you been to in
vancouver
man
a lot yes
to me all their cities are like right
next to each other like in canada
it's like that's odd
they're right next to each other you
know what i mean
i don't know where they're at explain it
chris please explain that i don't know
they're driving distance right
everything's driving distance man
there's nobody
there's nobody's water separating them i
don't know man
i don't know i don't know how like
seriously they don't allow me up there
while i give it shit what they're
i think you're allowed up there after 10
years with a felony no
no thank you thank you
married they won't they'll be like no
uh
you can't you can't come up here
okay i still don't see the most recent
two winner
patrick
there
[Laughter]
is there any place by the border where
it's just like a fence and everything
like that they built a wall in the south
or is there is it all like
i've never been to the border of the
northern border is what is it like on
the northern border
trees and moose yeah we have this thing
called the peace arch if that tells you
that's the border crossing it's the
peace arch
it's very friendly very different than
the you know what i'm saying like all
the way across is you're like
is there like actual
no
trees no
could you just walk across the border in
some way anytime you want and you're if
you are migrating you you'd start in
canada not mexico right yes okay that's
the move
yes
start in canada
[Music]
okay sweet okay
uh
cool and one even told me what he won
all right so the one before that was the
sessions right
yeah the picture the t-shirts and the
hats
so i'm thinking if i did that i would
dress as a sasquatch
you get shot
we went by we had tons of stuff in our
car
and they started searching it and they
quit because they were like
your car is filthy you need to clean
your car
like we are not getting our hands down
those yeah the french canadian accent i
was like so are we good they're like yes
you can go
like all right
you're stinky
yeah
they used to go
across the border a lot when
earlier teen years but we were always
going up for a hockey tournament so you
get it they can hear me awesome you guys
can hear me loud and clear yep
all right we've got one last segment to
get done here we're going to sit down
with nicole
we're going to grab leah nicole
and david and sit down with me and we're
going to have a conversation before we
pack it up and and get motoring because
we have the dank hour
happening at five o'clock
so yeah we gotta make sure to hustle
over for that
do you have to actually run somewhere to
do that
can you show us a question
yes
thank you peter
i actually one time dj'd a house party
and i put that on the playlist for my
videos
and somebody with the pen corrected me
to like sister christian i was like
do you think we could get these guys to
do
uh a gravity bomb rift
uh question there's a question behind
the question is gravity gravity dabs is
that a thing
it is no serious do you think we can
give the dude gravity
longer
maybe we could get him to do gravity
dabs did that be sick
sorry
london
let's get the gravity bomb going
oh they're canadians they probably don't
know how to do that shit
metric system
yeah
three liter bottle
like a liter cola please
is are they like a uh
some sort of ski resort or something
all of canada is a ski resort bro
no i don't know honestly
how much do you want bent that
it's really it's american thing that
we've done this
that we've that we've done gravity
they've never done gravity the only
thing gravity they've seen is that
cookies thing that that device that
flips and shit you know i mean that's
the only
gravity thing they've seen
they've never done actual
gravity blind rips they never they've
never done it before i guarantee you
they've never done it
they do them on a frozen pond up there
eh chop out some ice and get the five
gallon bucket put a little ball in there
a little bit of your cannabis
spark it up
they've never done it before i'm telling
you right now
you've never done one have you pack it
up pack it guys let me know when you're
ready let me begin
yes the only thing you're missing london
is the gravity bomb
battle me
i came to win
it's a sin
he doesn't know what a gravity bomb is
your volume is a little low
[Music]
we can't hear you
i think that's the greatest thing
okay we'll take over there we go
i i we are on our last session of the
day
um because it's fucking hot out and and
and i'm getting tired and we have more
shows so we need to hurry but regardless
we have had this immaculate day now it
was very very very important for me to
sit down with these wonderful people and
really chat about and touch on
a couple of the key points then my butt
doing that
um it's uh sorry yeah probably uh it's
very i thought it'd be very important
for us to sit down and like chat with
you guys as we we've kind of been the
workers of the event um and and kind of
the people that kind of making the
action happen and stuff like that too
it'll really take some time so if you
could give me another proper
introduction there chef nicole tell me a
little bit about your background you've
been on the show before and around
before so i'd really like to get in
there and tell us a little bit about
what you prepared for us because the
food was fucking banging yay
i'm really excited i'm nicole hines with
faded living i'm a cannabis chef so
today
i made some honey jerk wings on the
barbecue
with a mango salsa that was infused just
keep it simple guys you know what i mean
keep it simple i do love to barbecue so
i was in my absolute domain even in the
heat so
that is me i also do infuse dinner
parties i come into people's homes and
you know
create a new amazing meal um sometimes i
even host my own dinners
absolutely a hundred and ten percent
i've done it many times over yeah
absolutely and i come in i do the thing
i i i literally can't upset you that's
an upsell
this was what i wanted because you know
the other day i had you come over and we
pressed some we pressed some rosin and
we we tested some stuff and we we tried
this amazing flower and we got to really
try a different experience what i would
call a tupperware party for stoners you
know what i mean like that's essentially
what we've had i mean we've had some of
the coolest people there are in the
industry at this table today and sit
down to chat and be able to be part of
that conversation oh that's pretty
important you got to have make sure your
microphone is that is the fair yeah that
is too good um
so we've had so like i was saying
tupperware party for for for stoners and
and stuff like that so can you tell me
again because you were muted um what you
do what you got into like you know we
talk to you we talk to you
we've had dabs there's been dabs
and there's but yeah i cook with
cannabis i teach people even how to do
it i can even come into your home and do
that um and i'm writing a cookbook which
is coming out in the next
it'll come out i'm aligning it with an
article that i'll be in so it will come
out in like february march of 2023
february march of 2023 what's the title
what's the word
i'm thinking that it's going to be faded
eats
is is kind of the thing i really want to
get into the counter tourism space i
want to get a bowler trailer
and turn it into a cannabis airbnb and
call it the faded camper
and so there'll also be a cookbook with
the camper as well
so you know big things coming my way
yeah so we get a good we get killer food
and infused and then we get a bunch of
weed and then we get we get tupperware
parties for stoners so david can you
introduce yourself now and tell me a
little bit about what you what we were
doing today um why you believe in your
choice of equipment that you use
um and kind of like what what exactly is
trim test impressing can like any any
dude just get this at their house
so
i service the entire legal market
whether it's the ac mpr home grower
micros or even the lps
and i provide either mobile dry trimming
mobile wet trimming i've got a couple of
different machines one for each and then
also
my light lab 3 cannabis analyzer from
orange photonics so i do potency
tracking so
i can come to your facility and
literally take buds off of your plant
and help you identify where it is and
what week and so on and so forth
which can actually be incredibly helpful
especially if you've never grown that
strain before you can start to identify
when the harvest days are or even start
breeding depending on what cannabinoid
you want to sell and so on and so forth
so what started is like i'm a home
grower
i have two dislocated wrists i can't
trim so i'm like i'll buy the machine so
i got the machines and i was like i
wonder how good my weed is
so then i looked up a whole bunch of
potency machines and i didn't find
anything that was sort of
in the genre that i was looking for
until i came across that unit which is a
serious piece of business and then
i thought okay if i can turn this into a
business it has to be quantifiable data
and people are going to rely on it and
they're going to make business decisions
on it so i got the best one that i think
and it's portable which is really the
crux of the business best portable unit
and we were we were talking about these
units last week um on the dank hour with
kyle boyer on on testing because we
really dug into that subject deep so i
would encourage everybody to go in and
check that episode because there are a
lot of interesting um aspects when it
comes to tools that for testing um and
there's a lot of like there's a lot of
different methodologies and we kind of
get get to break into that and we really
talk about how this variability this
method is probably the most ideal and
accurate and consistent when it comes to
what you're what you're looking for to
do it is well essentially that's how you
can
like
build the gap between your intuition and
the data is if you know what it is that
you're doing and i'm able to provide you
that data you're able to use that and
move forward
i think the results for your flower
actually just beeped so it just came up
so each test takes 12 and a half minutes
from start to finish but i include the
moisture balancing so that it adds a few
more minutes but it's important because
you want to know what the weight exactly
so because
when you got to know you got to know
right so he knows the guy right so
that's one of the things i do and then
the pressing i love concentrates but to
be completely honest with you like the
glass scares the shit out of me so i'm
really into like this is my rig here
it's an electric one it's super fucking
easy it is my it is like my hourly
driver like this is like i wake up well
after i drop my daughter off a daycare
of logistics logistics logistics
so essentially there's just uh it's got
a sesh mode which i really like so i
just double tap it on to the front i
usually start at green there's four
different temp settings there's talking
to the mic there's more different uh
test settings and i usually like to
start it off on green and then move up
to red but
that really is how i enjoy my
concentrates and so i've got the nug
smasher pro touch shout out to
nugsmasher i'm very very grateful they
put a computer on their um on their
rosten present makes it really easy for
dummies like me that don't do math uh to
get really good
ross
so thank you thank you for that so what
did i do yeah trim test and press it
says it in the name
i am mobile i'll come to you i go
anywhere from princeton to hope
and my slogan is taking your growth from
good to great because it's not about me
it's about you and let's just see what
we can do about like
what where do you want to go you want to
go better on cbd better on thc what's
that
some of them do have it um we'll talk
about franchising later jonathan
jonathan we'll talk about franchising
later
okay actually in all in all honesty
there's there's a wonderful human being
out in the world and her name is jill
carrero and she's an incredibly hard
working mom and she represents uh orange
photonics and she is
like an absolute fucking genius and
whenever you need anything she answers
like despite the time difference so huge
shout out to jill carrero if anyone's
looking for the orange photonics you've
got it you've got to talk to her um and
yeah she's just an absolute like stud
she's awesome yeah
so well i like i i really
you know first you want you want to give
me a quick hello there leah and say
because you provided some of the
giveaway product today from quad so you
want to stay a little high and and how
people can support you and then we're
going to talk about how people can
support you and we're going to talk
about how people can support you and
then after that we're going to let
everybody know about the show later
today and then we're going to pack up
and run like the dickens because i have
to get all the way into vancouver uh
north vancouver to run a show at 5 p.m
so uh we're gonna we don't need to rush
through this part either but can you
tell me so quad you guys provide an
awesome set of products uh tell me a
little bit about them and then a little
bit about what you do and how we can
support you my name is leah and i'm the
president of quad ag so we
provide humates for plants animals and
humans predominantly in our agricultural
space we focus on
the biostimulants of humic and fulvic
acid as a adjunct to any nutrient
program and we fit into any grow system
so if you are growing in living soil
beds
either as a home grower or commercially
all the way through to aeroponics you
can safely fog our products and we focus
on root zone development and nutritional
uptake through plant tissues so
we're super
adaptive and help basically your plants
create better roots better shoots and
better fruits
[Laughter]
so how do people support us well
we
we love um
well we just basically help everybody in
their grow whether you're growing
cannabis or vegetables in your garden we
look to improve the soil and improve
the ecosystems and so we're seeing a lot
more conversation around regenerative
practices and
regenerative knowledge base and soil
ecology and bringing that knowledge into
commercial systems but that
those lessons learned also help
homegrowers that are looking to do
somewhat hydroponic or hybrid hydroponic
systems at home as well
so we are very knowledge based very
consultative based we sell a product but
we really believe in supporting the
communities that we service so
a way to support us is uh you know ask
your local hydroponics store if they
carry quad and if they do not
encourage them to so that we can support
more people that's a big thing for us
and then how people support you
oh geez um yeah
just give me a call let's work together
uh
so yeah i would like to get this guy
over
invite this guy over and you will be so
ripped so that like it's like i also
have a lead on some pretty cool testing
as well for like hot slaytons and other
things like that roll into what you're
doing
oh we need to talk i actually have a lot
of people that are i've heard that a lot
today um we need to talk yeah we should
talk yeah we should
that's the beauty about these kind of
events is we have opportunities to find
those collaborative opportunities right
absolutely like
um that's what it's all built out of
it's just sort of like grassroots
community and then if it grows from
there it grows from there but i think
that's the best way to sort of like grow
as well and it's a new industry and i
may have been a daily consumer for 30
years but
it's new to all of us in the legal front
and so it's nice to like
make legal mistakes
right it's kind of nice
but no the way to support me like
i do work with a lot of hydroponic
stores and all the way from the pnw
squamish first off pnw is amazing the
dan in mission is awesome and james and
maple ridge is dope and i forget the
guy's name up in
squamish but he's such a nice guy chris
or something they all have my flyers and
everything like that and if i do a three
test minimum so if clients don't have
three tests they can just drop it at a
drop box there and when they accumulate
like five tests they give me a call and
i just run to their store and i test all
the tests that's fantastic if you want
to do that it's like the bc greenhouse
does it they're awesome
john's plant factory is super dope like
well there they all are do you want to
see like it's such a fun community so
fuck like just go to any any one of them
really and drop it off and they'll give
me a call and then i'll come in and i'll
run your test that's awesome and and
don't forget to also check out trim test
and press and follow their instagrams
and stuff if you're not local check out
the business and
support them digitally
my name's leah and i'm with quad ag
[Laughter]
tell us about your shirt
my shirt oh yeah
i got mark's shirt on from uh vancouver
island homegrowers guild he looks like
he's downstairs taking a nap because he
got it very early to come out
and visit it it is good too man i mean
the guy's got the guy's got wheat that's
20 that the mother plant is 24 years old
how can you support me well um i do yes
uh all of any time you want to entertain
uh
and any anything i come into your home
and i kind of will like hook you up so
all of those things um also i have
clothing so like visit my website
fadedliving.com i'm actually at faded
living on all social media platforms so
it's super easy to find me but like yeah
if you're in the vancouver area if you
are surrounding areas well i do travel
um i can come in and do a lot of fun
things if you are catacentric
i know what it sounded like but no it's
all food related um but yeah that is one
of the major things and lastly i am
going to be starting season three a
faded living and friends podcast banging
podcasts
we are at 44 episodes see two seasons 44
episodes already
so a huge diverse group of folks have
been on my show from across the world
actually i have a uk guest which she's
awesome so if you want to um connect
with me and collaborate dm me at
fadedliving or info fadedliving.com
and let's work together awesome and if
you want to do this at your house let me
know i can make that happen uh
we but you could it'll it might cost a
little bit more money
but anyways i just wanted to thank you
guys again so much for taking your time
effort make sure your microphone's on
because i have i have i have a
microphone i've turned it off on you um
thank you guys so much for taking the
time and being here today and helping us
put this together and and just making it
a wild time thank you ken
for being a rock star thank you to all
of our all of our supporters and people
that provided products for the giveaway
today
and thank you peter chad freaking chris
guerrero you guys man you guys make it
happen and you guys really helped us
support and and help this come along it
would be such a dull show
in the crossover periods without you
guys so thank you all for taking your
time out of your day here to come and
join us for for this awesome show i
thank you
awesome and then lastly come to my
wedding guys
everybody you know come to my wedding
it's live streamed this saturday join
that dank hour might get pushed i don't
know if i'm gonna make it home in time
so i might have to push it till tomorrow
but we're doing an interview with shay
uh shay from rosebud farms me and justin
and and john were talking about him
earlier um and we're going to talk about
the unicorn cup which is coming up here
in the kootenays and you do not want to
miss that that is going to be the
premier canvas and i i hear you're a
fucking sponsor yeah trim and perez is
the sponsor of the unicorn cup man i'm
super stoked so if you're going there
guess what you get you get tupperware
parties for dudes
go there and get a cannabis
party
up there
come to the booth man
it is quite the experience so thanks
again guys and if you want to just shut
it down and we'll call it a day and and
see you all next week on canada and
thank you wait wait wait wait wait don't
shut it down don't shut down can you do
me a favor there's a there's a thing
that says green amber
um
there's on the top there there's uh
supported by green amber our sponsor
thank you peter
thank you green amber canada for
supporting us you can find their
information down in the comments below
uh they are
you know badass people with badass
lighting and they were chatting a little
bit earlier so thanks again to them
because without them each week we
couldn't make this happen so ciao guys
happy growing
i'm fucking stoned i don't know you
stoned