one of the things I wanted to talk about
was you know I had like my my mixed
martial arts analogy where you know
someone's the college wrestler at Ohio
State and they get into MMA and you know
when it comes to a ground game they're
amazing but they need to learn how to
box they need to learn how to kick box
jujitsu Maitai all these other kind of
languages to get in the ring and fight
and in growing plants I feel like you
know there's not one right way of doing
it and people are kind of gravitating
towards different languages or
methodologies and so for example Korean
natural farming and we have our second
we have our mastered show and so Scott I
was hoping you could kick it off and I I
want to talk about kind of the roots of
Korean natural farming in the 50s in
Korea you know in a specific period and
time and geography and how you've seen
kind of the cannabis community embrace
it you know here in the US and any
issues or concerns you you have with how
you see people applying it practically
here in the US well so well I'll start
with the preface you know I'm a huge
advocate of any sustainable strategy I'm
a huge advocate of any regenerative
strategy I'm a huge advocate of anybody
that wants to pursue low-cost
sustainable solutions and I feel that
you know I've got some friends that are
big into KNF and they've met the Cho's
and I feel like you know they were in
essence trying to communicate the same
message I think there's some obstacles
with context with KNF that are really
problematic in the regulated space
especially but then there's also some
problems with just cultivation
with some of the KNF for cannabis one of
my biggest obstacles with it is you know
there's the issue of having enough raw
materials within your own property or
farm to create your ferments and most
humans are relying on some outside
source to provide either the fruit the
vegetables or the milk or the sugar or
whatever the inputs are used to make
those kenaf immense and when we work in
the cannabis cultivation space and we
take flour and we concentrated into oils
you know the flour might pass but the
trims gonna fail and the oil is
definitely going to fail and so we see
phenomenons and other areas of cannabis
where we take a large amount of biomass
and concert drought concentrate it down
into an oil or other product and you see
pesticides chemicals or compounds that
were in that flower to become higher
level of detection and so I I think one
of the major obstacles the KNF right now
is you know Sarah and I have worked with
large organic farms with we've seen
pretty good ideas to the cheating that
goes along and you know there's study
after study that shows you know I
remember one where they took some
produce from outside the United States
that was deemed organic and like of the
12 products all 12 had something that
shouldn't be on it you know and so we
have a industry-wide issue with
contamination we have an industry-wide
issue with unregulated agricultural
activities that are using other products
that they shouldn't be doing that people
in the effort to apply regenerative
tactics to the cannabis space or then
concentrating these pesticides and
applying them to their plant so I'm kind
of curious as to what maybe Lydia is
seen in her analytical work the obstacle
with KNF is I suggest these concerns I
have two people that do kaf and I go
well I'm trying to save money so I'm not
going to spend $150 to test for
pesticides on my ferments which makes
perfect sense that makes perfect sense
you know but like I saw one the other
day so I haven't had a can F farm that
then sends there
their product and for testing because
yeah it doesn't make sense financially
but like I saw an Instagram the other
day where a guy had a bunch of bananas
and it had the sticker on it the PLU
stick drink you could read it very
clearly it was forty 11 which is
conventional banana and if there's a
nine before it it's organic and so dudes
fermenting conventional bananas and and
if you look into how bananas are grown
like they actually take a plastic bag
that is infused with pesticides and
insecticides and then as the banana
flower starts to shoot shoots they wrap
it in the pesticide and it grows inside
of a pesticide bag because they're so
ridden with pests and so I think there's
a there's a considerable disconnect
between the agricultural process the
areas of contamination and how that then
affects your plants and I just you know
I haven't seen a KNF garden survive more
than a couple harvests in the regulated
space because of these phenomenons but
that's something that's nobody's talking
about so there's the history of
pesticides but there's also the issue of
sort of the way that they're using it
ecologically in microbially speaking in
the balance of that is may or may not be
scientifically sound as far as results
and what they what they get how they use
it and then the other issue is in just
being able to make the products
consistently with knowing what the end
product does they have alcohol in it
even you know those kinds of things that
I think if you're using it in a
commercial space or any space you
actually need to sell the product and
have a good harvest or need that money
from them from the harvest that it would
be good to know and get that process
down so you know what you're making well
that I think that you know I come from a
business background like I come from fat
what you know what Sarah's saying is
that you know part of being regenerative
and sustainable is that your business
needs to be regenerative
and sustainable and so you know one of
the core components of our business is
helping farms stay in business and so in
order for organic or sustainable
practices or with the regenerative
movement to be sustainable and have an
impact on the market
we need those farms to make it more than
three harvests we need these farms to
stay in business and you know I think
that's been one of my gripes that people
other people in the industry of a large
objection to how volkl I'm being but I
don't think people would people
understand why I'm coming from is that
you know if there's bad advice given to
farmers that puts farmers out of
business you know that's not sustainable
and we need to first be a business that
can make it from harvest to harvest to
harvest so that we can stick around so
that we can produce products on the
market so our voice can be heard so that
we can actually make a lasting impact on
the market wide and if all of our farms
are going out of business because
they're concentrating banana pesticides
like that does not help sustainability I
was just gonna say I mean there are some
tenants that go along with KNF you know
that are similar to permaculture they're
similar similar to regenerative AG is
you know you're being able to use
indigenous micro organisms not using
synthetic herbicides pesticides
fertilizers you know improving your
growing environment creating a more
sustainable culture as best you possibly
can with your facility is gonna lead you
down the proper direction in the long
run but you know we see a lot of issue I
mean if we're not even talking about
cultivation we see an issue you know
with the sourcing of chocolate and using
chocolate for edibles and then that
results in you know heavy metals failure
or you know you're talking about
Cavendish bananas you know how many
different types of bananas do they
regularly ship around the world like
literally three and the Cavendish are
the ones that are the most popular and
it's because you know we all know the
reasons why I've works the way that it
does but you know trusting that the
source of material that you're getting
is gonna
be clean and that you're not gonna have
an issue is poor planning you know in no
offense it's just not something that you
know if it were me even whenever I'm
buying or recommending that someone
purchase and you that pesticides it's
like you make sure that you get that
material tested in the laboratory
against the standards that you are going
to be up against as a cultivation
facility trying to get your product to
market because mistakes happen you know
manufacturing mistakes happen there are
problems where things could adulterated
and they're not meant to be even without
it being the intention of the
manufacturer and so that's just
something that you know I've seen a lot
of and you know as we all know it's like
the horror stories of using minute
municipal compost you know and using
that material to start a compost pile
and what you're going to be dealing with
is totally different than if all of your
materials come from your land which
Scott was saying turns into a pretty big
sourcing issue I see the reason why I
don't work with K enough is that I don't
think I'm qualified at this time where
my understanding of using fermentations
to drive my plants direction to me is
too risky with this crop at the level
and I need to perform but I know farmers
that run K and F operations that are
succeeding in terms of their products do
pass CoA and in their killer products
but they're also some really dedicated
hard work and driven to understand those
methodologies type people and I think
that the reason where you see a fall-off
is that someone throws that word on top
of it K and F and automatically oh it
must be it's better and so it's they
approach it and they don't understand it
and that's where you start sourcing
regular bananas you find out that you
don't have enough diversity on your
property to do fermentation so you have
to acquire material from somewhere else
and now you're picking up stuff that's
covered in insecticides fungicides
whatever because it's just it's just add
products but I I know people who are
successful with it and the people that I
think of that you know the top of the
food chain with that would to be like
you know in our world Chris Trump and
the crew that rolls are under Chris
they're growing some fire and they're
there doing it but I think they're it's
way more in-depth than people want to
admit and that you have to say that
there's a level of professionalism in
every aspect of what we do as
cultivators and you have to kind of
define your success and you can have
ideas of how other things operate but
you have to work with what you're good
at when you start to play a little of
this a little and at whatever said the
other day you guys are talking about
they were going to do the operation and
they're really going to do 10% of the
operation correctly the rescue had 90
percent of the operation was going to be
just you know wing it that's the same
situation here that just because it's
organic doesn't mean it's safe and just
because it's organic doesn't mean it's
better it's just another method of
working with it and I think that when
people start to put the buzzwords on it
makes them feel like they're gonna do
something so like you're competing for
who's most organic and that's not the
point we're trying to deliver a crop to
a customer consistently profitably and
morally it's kind of like aquaponics you
know what I mean aquaponics you've got
to have a water scientist on board and
there's a whole nother thing people want
to do alkaline and I think it's cool we
did it in our office on a small level of
dr. Allen that was super difficult on
that level so you know trying to scale
up and I even watched vegetable farmers
I've done a my wife did a class in
Florida with the Maine aquaponics farm
they did it in greenhouses and it's
totally impressive but and super
sustainable but the level of risk and
how hard it is of how you got to be so
sharp to do it is unbelievable and I can
tell why people don't do it in cannabis
yeah Steve raised a good you know as the
podcast and stuff you know yeah he's a
fish wizard man and but the thing is
what he was you know when I got from him
in the last time we were hanging out yes
you use a composite system in order to
get the yields that he needs because you
can't drive the fertility from the fish
end of it safely or the fish
becoming damaged from too much
concentration of ammonium in their tank
so you end up having a sick fish
population if you want to drive the
fertility so they have to use a hybrid
system of mineral nutrition in some form
of pot that's put into it the irrigation
system where it's aquaponics so it's not
a pure aquaponics system so you can use
aquaponics to drive wheatgrass
but wheatgrass is a far lower value of
nutrient load than cannabis does you
know so every every one of these systems
is incredible if you just admit that
they have limitations in specific areas
and you address it but people get
romanticized with this shit I'm gonna be
somebody I'm not gonna be fucking
bankrupt it's that alone doesn't make
you somebody it's just a tool and I
think that these organic methodologies
as fascinating as they are to me because
they are art you have to admit that like
I said I don't have the ability to
ferment everything in my woods and close
my loops and do this operation in that
way and make money you know so I use our
organic bottom and then I and I charge
it so that I have a bacterial base that
solid so my base level of fertility is
consistent and I can get analysis done
so I know I'm within range and then I
said then I utilize that final escape
technology to get around the
environmental stress but I just admitted
to myself that went on 70 maybe then I
can be a fully closed loop farmer
because I can start to grow all the
products that I needed when I was in
Colombia they were growing all these
products that they were using for their
Ag in general and once they got into
cannabis they just had to increase the
acreage of the things that they were
already producing to use as ferments
because that's how they operated
naturally so for them KNF situation made
total sense because they were already
really following it but it was more like
Colombian natural farming they weren't
copying you know master Joe they would
copy and how they've been doing it since
the dawn of time
and I think you just have to be really
honest about your situation and just say
look there's a lot of ways to get to the
destination choose the one that's going
to work for you and it's okay you're not
in competition with each other for who's
coolest with bro technology honesty
isn't the first policy in cannabis it
seems ego is the best policy
you don't want to either you don't want
to spend shit or you want to spend
everything and show everybody you can
grow great weed there's not a lot of
in-between and the one consistent thing
I would say what the biggest problem
with KNF becoming extremely successful
is that once something becomes popular
people don't want to fall out of that
cool clique and then they don't want to
admit that it goes well and so everybody
just keeps smiling and saying
everything's fine like that mean when
the things on fire and because nobody
wants to be nobody wants to be the guy
that didn't do it well and that's that's
systemic across the board which I keep
saying is the number one throttle on
evolution of the industry wide as soon
as people can be authentic and honest
about how bad things aren't going we can
start talking about how good they can go
and you know people aren't quite right
not being guide like we're just not just
it's not enough you know when when shits
going wrong and strawberries everybody's
talking about it when shit's going wrong
in sugar beets or grapes or anything I
remember when I was a kid they had this
weird phenomenon going through sugar
beets that was wiping everybody out and
all the farmers all the you know
companies everybody rallies around they
shit to fix it and figure out what the
problem is and kind of do a reset it's
just we're not in that category as much
as that's the part of big AG we should
be in everybody really gets together and
really does these things and some of
these people share these trials that are
being done I know a guy that's really I
mean he's a big
in cannabis and he loves cannabis so
it's a great way of looking at it wasn't
a big guy trying to get in it for the
money
he was already in big I wanted to be
into cannabis and bring what he knew and
learn what he can and so basically you
know I actually was talking to Peter
about this guy and saying we should get
him on the podcast I talked to him about
it the other day and he was like I can't
go on there the company I work for won't
let me talk to anybody about shit you
know and I was just like well that's you
know hey fuck you know he would be great
you know I've learned a lot and things
like that but if it's not the company
itself well if it's the company itself
holding back even good people within
that company to share that information
so I mean it's kind of crazy how how
bottled up it is or the what so just
quickly sticking on our KF topic Chris
Trump's actually confirm for next week
so Scott just quickly can you touch on
the use of rice to kind of to collect
and grow things you've mentioned
something about rice and kind of
concerns there and then also kind of how
mastered show from your perspective has
evolved his way of thinking and and what
how he thinks about things differently
and now we're going to get onto a laning
and the soil food yeah I think you know
one of the things that I think is really
missing from the KNF community is a
little bit more solid foundation of the
entirety of the soil food web and how
these things interplay in the root
system of plants and lead to good
results or bad results you know one of
the objections that dr. Lane Ingham and
has had is the concept that we're taking
a strategy from Korea using rice which
is something that naturally exists in
that Reed
they're using it to catch organisms and
using that to be their inoculum which I
think Kevin nailed it like they're doing
Columbia natural farming like okay so
those Colombians have adapted these same
principles of using the available
materials in their environment to
compost them or ferment them down that
they can then use for healthy plant
growth and I think that's something
that's being missed in the United States
and so when we take rice which is
something that doesn't naturally occur
in the forests of the redwoods and we
put it into the root system or soil or
mulch layer whatever it is they're doing
with it they're harvesting organisms
from that environment that are suitable
to decomposing that material not
necessarily organisms that lead to
healthy plant growth within that
environment and you know the KNF
community just objects to my objection
and nobody really you know opens a
textbook to even see what they're doing
or you know takes dr. lanes microscope
course which again is contradictory to
the can of principles of being low-cost
so we just have this kind of obstacle
where you know the entire KNF community
from my standpoint is neglecting a major
portion of soil biology that's easily
and readily found in textbooks that you
can read up on and understand how these
systems work what these organisms do and
how they do or do not have positively
affect plant growth they're kind of in
the wizardry side which I'm down for
wizardry but you can't live on wizardry
and deny the law of gravity you know
well the Brewers have a little wizardry
to little sprinkle of this and a
sprinkler that everybody gets their
wizard hat on sometimes but I'm
definitely gonna break the internet on
this one sky you might have to unblock
some people or so I don't even I don't
belong to the internet anymore it
doesn't
I don't belong to the Internet I come
from I come from Southern California and
I was raised by skaters surfers and
gangsters where it wasn't real that
wasn't okay to be fake like you got
called fake every day if like you didn't
drop in on the ramp properly like so I'm
not gonna participate in Instagram it's
just like it's like the bar scene of
fake ass is like I'm not trying to
participate in that shit like like I
don't even I don't got post Colvin I got
no time for this shit I got no time for
that none so just quickly give me your
perspective like on on ferments and
alcohol and and mastered shows evolve
thinking and water can you and go well I
guess so I what so what Peter I guess to
catch up the live listener I'm I don't I
don't it all want to speak for the chose
necessarily but to my understanding like
the evolution of KNF has even been to
like the jus d'amour jadam which is his
son which to my understanding that's
been communicated to me by KNF people
it's more of a water based ferment and
so I was kind of shocked to hear that
the people here in the United States
trying to grow cannabis are doing like
sugar based ferments which leads to a
lot of alcohols and it seems that the
Cho family themselves are evolving to a
water-based ferment and you know I don't
know the intricacies of that but what I
do see is an evolution from the Cho
family on their own process and so we
need to say that same evolution within
the cannabis space of their process
because you know my wife and I job is as
a lab and we were trained by a scientist
to identify organisms whether you're a
KNF garden or a living soil garden when
we do this analysis and put these
organisms into different categories it's
very clear indicator of success or bad
outcome regardless of the type of form
you're out and you know there's these
phenomena in the root zone that are very
important I was trying to dig through it
last night but we got so many damn texts
this house I couldn't find it but there
is this woman
we were both flipping through books like
where's this clothes you're gonna quote
science you got to be accurate or else
they rip you to shreds on the Internet
but nonetheless this whole paragraph was
speaking about all the functions of
plants that stopped under an anaerobic
condition in the read zone and this is
important because major metabolic
functions stopped working under
decreased oxygen conditions and a whole
bunch of other compounds are produced
and you know so we run this lab where
people send us oil samples from the
smallest garden to the biggest garden
living soil nonliving soil
hybrid KNF we get a lot of it and by far
the weirdest plants symptoms come from
the canif sector like nobody that's
doing a living slow farm calls me
because they're stem turned to gush and
the plant fell over like nobody in
hydroponics has ever called me like that
you know there's some really really
weird plant phenomenons that are
happening and I believe it has something
to do with the horrendous amount of
alcohol that are being poured on the
plants yeah yeah it's just it's cuz I'd
like I think what happens is the
internet starts to rebut me saying that
I'm saying everybody needs to be on my
camp and that's not what I'm saying at
all what I'm saying is if you're gonna
engage in organic activities and talk
about biological concepts you should
familiarize yourself with these
functions and foundations from readily
accessible textbooks in the library like
it's not just my information like
there's major complications with the
strategy and I'm not saying it can't be
done because we've assisted some farmers
that have had some pretty good success
with a hybrid approach and there's
definitely an increase in terpenes
there's definitely an increase that
comes with using some of these KNF
functions but you cannot ignore
foundations of biological concepts that
are just as absolute as the law of
gravity
yeah so that's my two cents we would
just say you know what to echo kind of
would Lydian what Kevin was saying just
whatever you're going to do whatever
system you resonate with just make sure
you take the time to quantify what it is
you're doing so you know why you're
doing it and you don't waste that effort
only to find at the end of the harvest
that you failed for whatever pesticide
that you didn't see coming down the pipe
because you overlooked something and
that happens to all of us that happen
that's a major learning lesson for
everyone we're all in a great big
learning lesson right now on that but
just quantify what you're doing it it
take the time spend the money to do it
otherwise you know at the end of it you
could you know definitely miss something
and film testing and you don't get that
money yeah you just you crop right the
product isn't right it doesn't have a
home anymore
that's right yeah below shell I know
that gives me the right production at
that location and so I think that
direction always has to be specific
where you know it's in terms of
scalability I never intend to scale that
operation that is always meant to be the
size it is and I'm cool with that
for its duration so I can use that as a
specific but anytime you go to any
operation you know you have to identify
the people have the ability first to
even run and do what they intend to run
and do and I just think that there's
people who are brilliant and they know
how to make these systems work and then
there's shortcuts that occur because
people don't understand that that isn't
a shortcut and if you do this you will
get this problem as a result and there
hasn't been enough experience in the
u.s. for operators I would be
interesting to go to Korea and see
people farm and ask them you know do you
use KNF and what like how do they
approach farming in their culture
because that's what I get kind of caught
up in is how does the out of the people
and he's it needs other countries don't
have commercial AG for the same degree
we do in the way we approach it how do
they
generate the products that was what was
so interesting about the Colombian
situation was they was scaling out the
crops that they were gonna grow to
create the products they needed so they
had full control of what they did is an
input and they knew exactly why I asked
them white why do you grow this and he
said this is what we get from this it's
what we get from back so they had a full
strategy and have been based off a
success it's just that like for me my
farm is in is in developed to that
degree yet but the people that I know
that are having success when you go to
their properties it's almost like a plan
Oasis to where they have so many
different things growing in such a
balance that they can create these
balanced systems and you know and I
strive for that as my long-term goal but
I know that I can't jump right into it
and succeed it's too much of a risk it
has to be a progression you know like we
talked about last time you start off
with something you prove the concept you
increase it exponentially until you've
reached you know the full max potential
but if you're just if you're just moving
through time and space running as fast
as you can you can run right into a
fucker wall yeah exactly
and and our core messages we're trying
to keep these regenerative funds in
business that's the thing like you know
that's taken the strategy he is because
he knows it ensures its survival in the
market like we're trying to keep all
these people in business so that we can
make a broader impact you know if we
have all of our organic farms go out of
business because they plant it in the
first year who a culture like that ain't
that's not sustainable like we need to
we need to develop systems that are
actually repeatable that actually lead
to sustainability of your business and
that's that's why I like Kevin so much
he's got a you know business mindset I
came from a business family as well so
yeah I'm on the regenerative camp but
I'm always looking at from a small
business survivability standpoint we we
have to start with being successful and
repeating that that's where
sustainability starts for me you know
and I a lot of times I see farms make it
to the commercial scale and a lot of
them have hired us to help them and they
go so
far to the regenerative that it's not
practical for their survivability in the
market and we have to start with
survivability in the market and inch our
way towards full sustainability of our
property or it's just gonna be a
boneyard of stories of what almost was
you know because I can tell you the
hydro facilities they're not slowing
down they're ramping up and you know
unless some of these regenerative farms
figure out how to be profitable to make
an impact on the market or how we
community-wide figure out how to
communicate strategies that lead to
regenerative opportunities and
sustainability
you know what impact are we actually
going to have and how do we actually
give