so the loaded question in the room the
loaded question in the room -
everybody's like now with this regulated
cannabis industry
this regulated cannabis industry we must
be getting some really good high quality
tested cannabis right that's those
testing facilities must be working
overtime well what has been your
experience on that way there are far too
few labs and far too many people who
need to use them over the few labs there
are they they keep getting themselves
shut down for just like lying
about six months worth of test results
and which you know six months worth of
recalls that's 700 batch recalls from
one lab who screwed up I was fortunate
not to be caught up in that right - two
weeks different on when I had actually
produced that would have been my lab I
would be doing a recall right now which
would be horrible yeah for manufacture
products were screwed because we're like
third down the line in testing and if
something fails somewhere and it gets
recalled earlier like the oil that we
use gots got later on failed then they
come and look at our audit for us using
that oil and we can get screwed twice
but something that did you know because
our our lab mates may have tech tested
it looked at the previous COAS and what
oh it must be okay and not like it I I
worry that we don't get the same quality
level testing that concentrates and
fires do because the labs are trying to
get us through so quickly at the end and
they just kind of probably look well it
passed already
and I'm worried that we might be getting
rubbers now
knock on wood we're not going to
understand but you know what I mean it's
like they do hinky and if if it's a
profit motive for them to get more
people in their throughput and okay as
long as I get this I've done this year
and I made my nut and I'm gone
that's one reason why it looks like this
it's very difficult to do oversight and
regulation of labs because so few people
actually understand lab processes you
know that's a very professional job so
your average person going in to look at
it doesn't know what they're looking at
I'm actually surprised that the BCC
inspectors were able to identify that
that that one lab I was talking about
had a bad machine because normally they
would just take it at your word like
here's our equipment it all works yeah
they they defer to the professionals
within the given field so their
regulatory people they they don't they
don't know STEM methods of lab
procedures they don't know that so they
assume that the professionals in those
areas are the ones that do and even
though we were throwing out various
different questions like well why
doesn't the state have its own self
internalized you know reference frame
like a kanima so they send to all the
tests that they already have tested
themselves to be able to validate what
the machines should be reading times and
you know standardize on a cleaning
solvent so that all of them are using
the same cleaning solvent so they have
the same resolution when they come back
for testing so that you know one group
has a different doesn't have a different
resolution that testing than another one
these are all things that they're
unaware of that they even need to be
looking into because they just assume
that most of these interests trees
regulate themselves
properly and we get stuck with the
problems the testing is also a bit
excessive right so before we ever
formulate our products the cannabis
material the regulated material that
goes into it gets tested twice before it
even gets into our hands and and then
after we make our products it gets
tested again and and where this gets
tricky especially going into phase three
which starts January first phase three
testing and junior first it's highly
likely that common ingredients like the
olive oil that we use or or the avocado
oil or even the ginger extract could be
quote-unquote contaminated in in a way
that would be harmful if you are smoking
a flower but has zero potential for harm
delivered on the surface of your skin
and there's absolutely no
differentiation in testing between the
actual potential for harm of some of
these ingredients they're all treated as
if you were going to smoke and eat them
even when that's not happening at all
and the fact that you know a certified
organic approved to be food grade on the
shelves olive oil could fail a cannabis
test because of something like lead in
the soil that the olive tree was growing
in arsenic in the well water it's it's
ridiculous so the sensitivity and the
tet on the testing
and how far that scope goes way beyond
just the cannabis ingredients but always
every ingredient you're using it's it
needs to be fixed it will be fixed
eventually but for now we're just
hideously over regulated
[Music]