and so that's why we got a you know
improve our scientific literacy we have
to seek out people who understand the
science we have to encourage them to
speak in our community to share their
knowledge and to break it down in ways
that are understandable to empower
everybody in the community
Philo's has significantly damaged the
trust of our community with genomics
labs we can't let what Philo's did
actually impact the science people have
to continue to engage in the science
understand it and deploy it in ways that
are intentional and conscious we need to
control these technologies and deploy
them for our ends not have them deployed
by others against us in ways that make
it so that we no longer have any choices
we need to support people who have the
knowledge and expertise within our
community I've already mentioned that
one that's really where it's at we have
to go back to our roots and we have to
really focus on these educational
opportunities and understand that what
we're doing in these moments and in
these spaces is building culture and
we're building resilience to a culture
that we are all we've inherited and we
are also responsible for taking on into
the future and so we have to have events
like this we have to come together we
have to share this on social media we
have to get out there so that everybody
in our community that decided for
whatever reason from all our different
backgrounds to say cannabis that's my
thing I'm about it we need to be about
it now more than ever because if we're
not 5 10 years from now I mean according
to Mowgli home straight up their plan is
to be at market in 9 months and in 2
years have all existing cannabis
varieties be a thing of the past those
are his words now is it hubris is it
something that is probably not going to
happen certainly that you know best laid
plans often fail that said we have to
expect monsanto's of the world the
Syngenta's and anybody who wants to
adopt that model to come into our space
and to bring their a-game and we've seen
what they've done to everything else and
the only way that anything has ever
developed along a different trajectory
was because people consciously chose to
do so and because they organized around
things that they valued and their
culture in specific places across time
and they developed these institutions
and they got networked so that they
actually could build the resistance the
only reason that train that was if I had
the graphic at which I could show it but
basically 1903 we had hundreds of
varieties of every major crops Oh peas
melons tomatoes corns every single one
of them there were hundreds of specific
varietals being grown across the country
they were regionally adapted specific
cultivars that were useful in their
particular area and while they may not
have had market share to where they were
growing
billions of bushels and making tons of
Monsanto like money they were actually
building and maintaining crop diversity
that had incredible value that we've
only now realized what was being lost in
the 1980s when they went back and they
looked at what was available in the
existing crop germ plasm banks and it
was down to a handful of any one of
those crops so we went from hundreds to
about a dozen maybe two dozen that right
there is something that we can't let
happen Philo says that they have in
their catalog
four hundred varieties
so if we were to look at and have
cannabis in that chart you would have
cannabis with at least 400 distinct
varietals and their plan is to take
those 400 varietals and turn it into a
few dozen and have that be ubiquitous
and be the only thing anybody ever
experiences and gets to enjoy
that's not cannabis that's not what
we've dedicated our lives to that's not
why we fought the good fight and kept
these plants alive under wartime
conditions we kept this plant alive and
we took all of this genetic resources
from all of these different places that
have been developed over millennia and
we did so not just to hand it over to a
bunch of suits and not just to give up
when the going got tough like or goings
been a lot tougher like they used to
show up with helicopters and guns way
it's getting marginally better they're
showing up with briefcases now but you
know we need to stay on it and just stay
true to ourselves I think just to get
into some broader like breeding genetics
things that need to happen okay us
quickly germ plasm maintenance
collecting storing and preserving
genetic diversity of isolated
populations and varietals is key you
need to take your plants you got to
plant two seeds or something okay pop
them do a seed increase make thousands
if you got one seed and it's a female
okay do a reversal make thousands out of
it because that is a genetic resource
and it's something that could otherwise
get lost if we don't make seed increases
constantly and we don't keep these
things isolated and within their own
niches because once we start crossing
everything together we have essentially
a race to the bottom and we lose the
unique diverse
that we have in specific varietals
further than that we need to get into
acclimatization and trait improvement
and the traditional landrace varieties
were the results of hundreds and
thousands of years of acclimatization
and selection pressures that were
exerted on plants by cultural complexes
that valued and cultivated them around
the world I've gotten I explained some
of these before the plant as we know it
is the result of the choices made by the
different diverse cultures that
interacted with this plant over
millennia our tasks as breeders is to
keep in mind that our decisions impact
the gene pool of this plant in ways that
have consequences thousands of years
into the future since the inception of
modern hybrids there's been an emphasis
on primarily trait improvement for
increased yields reduced flower time
cannabinoids terpenes bud structure
morphology and appearance we've
accomplished incredible improvements in
the plant over this time period in a
very haphazard manner without the
benefits of advanced genomics or public
institutions that would support us in
our efforts literally under siege during
a drug war the result is that we have
lots of varietals that have been
significantly improved in a number of
ways however we focus less on
acclimatized stabilized in isolated
populations there are relatively few
acclimatized heirlooms and pure
unhybridized lines that and those that
do exist are incredibly cherished we
need to get back to that we need to get
back to staying in our lane staying in
our communities growing and developing
varietals and cultivars that are unique
to our areas and we need to do it on the
personal level personal cultivators
growing their six plants and being
heirloom preservationist creating
preservationist societies like the
Audubon Society where we actually really
get into this and have just hobbyists
who care only about cannabis and
describe in detail and develop their own
personal lines that is the thing
we need to be encouraging and developing
along with all of the commercial
developments that are going on and we
need for the commercial developments to
be developing what's being spoken about
right here
we need farmers and breeders to develop
an alliances with distributors and
buyers coops buyers co-ops and is
something that we as a community
developed in like the hippy back to the
land movement and it made the renewable
energy market a thing it made the health
food market a thing we can make heirloom
varieties in cannabis a thing that has
market share and market space if we
target every single side of the supply
chain and don't just look at you know
here's commercial here's that we also
need buyers coops get together buyers
buy that good good yeah first of all
thank you so much a lot of really good
content there and I think you know we've
been talking a lot about about this all
day you know the idea of genetic
diversity the idea of cultural diversity
you know and and I think you bring up a
really good point for people that are
just growing for themselves or just
growing their six plants and the
responsibility that we have by having
these genetics and carrying on the the
lineages here and for people such as
myself that you know a lot of us they
used to cultivate and now I've found
other things to put our energy into but
are still in you know in the cannabis
industry still have our love for
cannabis you know but still grow our six
plants you know and it's it's so much
fun to work with that and see all the
diversity that we can and bringing out
the genetics from from the fridge you
know and
all the old school stuff well really a
grateful that she came out here thank
you very much yeah
I'm Jonathan volve 'men this is the
heart of cannabis thanks for coming
you