we get a lot of vendors that come in
with their products over the years and
one of the main things that we're
looking for since there are no
regulations regarding the supply or the
labeling or lab testing we were really
rely on a professional appearance and a
professional product so when it comes to
the infused products it's it's we've
irritated I guess probably a lot of
people over the last couple years but
we've had some strict demands and it
just comes down to their packaging being
lab tested and being accurate and being
professionally packaged and also having
a consistent distribution system so
those are really the first things and
same thing when it comes to the flowers
we definitely want samples we're not the
kind of place that will make a decision
on the spot just by the way it looks or
smells we really need to try the product
and that's probably the biggest thing
that we're concerned with so I have had
people that we've said hey can you bring
some samples and they seem a bit turned
off by it like we might just use the
samples maybe they have this experience
at other places and then never get back
to them but we take taking in samples
extremely seriously we make sure all the
right people try it we have forums for
everybody to fill out and then we
basically we take it from there and if
it's a good product
we usually carry it there's so many
little things that are missing from our
shelf like we just got medicated hemp
milk we didn't have that before why
would we not take someone that had that
we have even handmade cigars wrapped in
gold or cannabis leaf again there's no
competitor in that space so the product
came to us it it's a good product and we
accept it so I think the big thing is
trying to find what's missing on a shelf
but I see especially in the last few
months I've seen so many new products
and so many new categories it's really
exciting but I hate to keep going back
to this theme but like we're gonna run
out of display case space so we're gonna
have to kind of change the layout of
everything
the biggest thing is isolating the
cannabinoids and having different
combinations with those so kind of like
we were talking about earlier of course
CBD has become more and more popular
over the last couple years the vape pens
the we just got in a soda and this thing
take its sprig and it I mean it tastes
like sprite and it's medicated and it's
in a nice can with a nice packaging so
and new vape companies keep coming out
with things because early on in the
beginning there we could get vape pens
but a lot of them had a weird taste and
people were putting like PG and PE g and
these like fillers into the pen because
they couldn't get them to flow properly
and our patients basically don't want
any of that they want them pure and I
think the vape companies have noticed
this and they're and that's what most of
them are doing now so you know the
products are just getting cleaner better
packaged more consistent and it's it's
exciting it's an exciting time to be a
cannabis retailer