we'll end with one viewer question Jemma
do you want to say hi what what have you
been doing while we've been talking no
what have you been doing it so so we got
one Lydia will let you go because I know
that he has to leave a viewer question
let me cue it hey what's up guys this is
blue of green tank I'm a cultivator in
coastal Maine and I really appreciate
you fielding questions like this my
question revolves around living soil and
decomposition rates and nutrient cycling
from season to season in a greenhouse
that is not climate controlled alright
so what we have here is a couple of
grass roots fabric beds a living soil
Edition equipped with blue matte blue
soap and I built the soil that the
intention was high porosity good
drainage and getting away from the use
of unsustainable peat and so what I did
is I used a greater proportion of rice
holes in the soil and I would say
outfitted it with a proprietary Feria
mushroom spawn and we have a nice thick
mat here and then I laid down my blue
soak and everything did really well last
season and now going into this season I
was surprised and looking in a few spots
that the rate of decomposition from what
I'm used to inside in my living soil
systems is far lower and so my main
question is what can I do in this bed to
stimulate some rapid decomposition to
ensure that I have enough nutrient
cycling to provide my plants of what I
need this year so if you have any
suggestions whether it be a more of an
ocular of worms as you can see there's
one Slytherin buyer right here so they
have survived the winter but I figured
that they would self populate or maybe a
sprouted seed tea or compost extract
wondering what you guys would recommend
I appreciate it thanks in advance all
right Scott I'm gonna let the wife get
this one all right Sarah do a wife that
was that was a longtime viewer
first-time caller yeah yeah well first
of all I would say there's a couple of
things off the bat that I would kind of
steer on this is that anytime you're
wanting to increase the nutrient cycling
in a system you need to quantify what
you have first and what that balance
looks like so I would get a quantified
because you don't really know what you
got and where you need to address the
issues or any changes until until you
take a look so I would quantify that if
you're serious about this the second
thing is is you weren't a natural
decomposition in the system a sort of
natural steady decomposition in the
system that is advantageous to growing a
plant and not necessarily a compost site
so I would say that is steered by the
amount of organic matter and the
combination of organic matter in the
system and on top of the system so first
and foremost if you're growing if you're
growing cannabis if you're growing any
cash crop right for for money or
whatever you're doing this seriously I I
would make sure that your organic matter
and your rates of nutrient cycling are
the first and foremost priority of the
system and that requires oxygenation of
the system and that means that the soil
you need to understand that the soil
needs to respire and for the soil to
respire and Bri that needs to be able to
get access to that air if it's smothered
with any thick cake layers of
anything whether that be caked on new
minerals that are too much you know
anything could be too much you know any
organic material any mineral material
can be too much if it's it but smothers
that surface layer even if its roots
growing in the surface layer so you can
have you can have a living mulch layer a
crop layer that is too much that it's
holding on to so much water that now
you're getting gnats and now you're
getting other things like that that
maybe you don't want to have to deal
with in your system so understanding
that when you're dealing with a living
soil system you want that aerobic
respiration in the system so yes you
want organic matter and that can come in
the form of roots make sure that they're
not overwhelming your system if you're
getting too many gnats then that down
make sure that your mulch layer is
something that is not suffocating the
system again if you're having gnats
you're seeing that the your your
accumulating water on the system and
don't try to emulate necessarily too
much of a decomposition in in the soil
per se leave that portion for composting
on its on its own off to the side I
would I would I would suggest so those
are the steps that I would immediately
take is just I get that he it sounds
like he's in a colder climate and he's
trying to buffer through when he didn't
have the plants and that's fine just
take off that huge mulch layer when you
go to plant the plants and make sure
that your soil can respire that it can
breathe that you can kind of see here
and there into the soil and see what is
going on now if you're in a hot climate
and you want to mitigate water loss you
want to make sure that you have enough
mulch layer that you do mitigate that
that water loss so it's just a
everything is context and a balance but
keeping in mind that you want that
aerobic microbial life doing those
processes for you that's what gives you
all the nutrients in the form that you
want and that's what gives you all the
enzymes that's what gives you all of the
hormones and different things like that
that the plant needs
and that's what engages the genetics of
the plant to give it what it needs when
it needs it so I mean microbes aren't
perfect you do have to balance that with
you know your mineral profile too but
anyway I think would work good who's
that and iike on decomposition though
when if you're laying that much rice
whole into a media and you're not
putting in enough of a nitrogen source
in order to go along with it it's
effectively drawing as a nutrient sink
that also slow down that decomposition
process because it you what's like
whenever I've used rice hulls in a mix i
compost it first and then add it I don't
add it as an aeration component because
for me it's always been a nitrogen thief
that's right so it ends up it ends up
stealing my effective nitrogen in order
to break down naturally under microbial
level and so he might have had enough to
drive fertility but he's not getting
enough of biological activity in the way
he needs to really do composting yeah
and and I'm just curious either from
your opinion you know does that make
sense yeah a percent yeah which is what
I was going to say is that the
conditions are what's important for you
know if there's no water out there
there's no organisms doing any
decomposition at all because wherever
the organisms are whether it's under the
snow layer or in the rain forest they
need ideal levels of moisture for those
sets of organisms they need organisms
that will operate within those
temperatures so if his bed doesn't have
any organisms that are suitable to
operating during those extreme cold then
nothing's gonna be happening anyways you
know dr. Lane did a bunch of research
and her work found that some of the
highest rates of decomposition happened
under the snow layer during the winter
and what what she supposes is happening
is that where this where the the snow
meets the soil it's not completely
frozen and there's a little free water
layer that is the ideal moisture
percentage for organisms to perform
decomposition activities and so I would
start to look at the main differences
between his indoor that's having high
rates of decomposition and the outdoor
that's not having high rates of
decomposition I would think one of the
easy components is he's watering the
indoor and he's not watering the outdoor
because he's just letting it try to
decompose so if there's not adequate
moisture in that compost pile so to
speak that nothing's gonna be happening
and then if there's too much of anything
you're suffocating it and again
nothing's happening so we need adequate
and ideal aeration and levels of oxygen
for rates of decomposition to happen you
need ideal levers of moisture for that
decomposition to happen because they
need to be awake and operating with
certain amounts of water and you need
the organisms that will function and
operate under those conditions with
which they're under and you need you
need that again that that taking a look
at what organisms are there are the
organisms even there to do the
decomposition so you may be asking the
system to do something that it can't
really do at this stage in its evolution
so and he did ask about acceleration
techniques and yeah if you add
supplemental things that can encourage
biology which will encourage the in
composition one of the things that he
mentioned was the sprouted CT which is a
very popular thing of all the things
that collapse beneficial populations of
organisms in the organic sector out say
the sprouted CTS are the most effective
and they're just as capable at
completely wiping out soil organisms as
an application of a systemic fungicide
is they have the same amount of about
yeah yeah it's crazy people don't think
about that but an accelerant can also
blow the head off yeah so yeah you can
start your car with a little shot of
ether into the air cleaner every day but
at some point the motors gonna blow up
and so you know if you do add anything
to that mulch layer to accelerate
decomposition you have to also factor in
that where most of us are way over
applying things which causes a actual
destruction of the organism populations
through over stimulation so you need to
not collapse it through over stimulation
it's like a boom-bust effect mmm in any
ecological system so like even if you
have too many rabbits and now you're
gonna have a big proliferation of
coyotes and whatever eats rabbits and
they're gonna decimate the population
and then you'll have too many of the
Predators and that that can go back and
forth and extremes in the microbial
community as well yeah
and Skyy you had said something
interesting about what Elaine said about
snow and what happens underneath it so
he blew is growing in Maine but he's
growing in the greenhouse or the snow
there's not a layer of snow but if you
if you didn't have that top can you talk
about what would happen with the snow
and what goes on underneath well and I'm
yeah I'm not necessarily advocating
adding snow either I just met I think
what's important is I think what's
important is that the snow is providing
the ideal level of moisture on the soil
surface where the decomposition is
happening and so if he harvested those
plants and never added any more water in
there well water oxygen and microbes are
the three things that cause
decomposition to happen so without the
water it's not going to happen without
the oxygen it's not gonna happen without
the organisms not gonna happen so
whether he adds moisture out there I I
think what he really needs personally is
he needs to get a good foundational
composting technique to get that aspect
covered to where he is providing benefit
to his farm in the offseason and and
just let the soil be soil don't try to
force it into composting because by the
time you plant again you might still be
composting like Kevin said you get too
many rice holes your carbon to nitrogen
ratios off your composting is gonna be
ineffective and you're gonna have
problems so I would say focus on getting
a really healthy worm bin you know you
don't need a ton of compost everybody's
after like
mounds and mounds of compost like Sarah
and I take little tiny totes like three
cubic feet so two soil bags of compost
will treat 40,000 square feet of
cannabis like you don't need you know
what I mean like been in a Rubbermaid
tote that's enough compost to treat
40,000 square feet of plants you don't
need a massive amount what you need is a
very healthy amount of compost what we
call what we're trying to turn
biologically complete so that we did
delineate and differentiate between like
municipal compost which is a very
different thing than the type of compost
we're talking about so biologically
complete just means it has its inoculum
grade it has all of those organisms
we're talking about they're doing the
job that he's asking the system to do
alright do you want to good seeing you
guys
yeah you bet and we got Chris trunk next
week so this is jar