[Music]
we are gonna talk a little bit about
codes now and a bigger not so focused on
the specifics of the California code
that Kyle was looking for last night but
really stepping back a little bit taking
a look more broadly at how codes are
developed their role the different parts
that come into play and sort of what the
action has been on the codes front for
CEA facilities so we have a great
stellar panel here with lots of
experience we're gonna hear from Keith
Corson of desert air he's gonna talk to
us a little bit about some of the
various industry led codes and standards
affecting the industry and the and the
equipment that's being used we'll hear
from Alexei Miller with the new
buildings Institute who's been doing
work on codes a national the national
model codes as well as input to other
codes across the country and then from
Kyle booth with a little bit more on
what they're looking at for California
and the title 24 process so with no
further ado I'll bring up Keith and we
can hear about the acronym soup good
afternoon everyone so I'll focus on the
HVAC standards activity and try to put a
little bit of a bow over the acronyms
and all the different standards that are
out there and so if we look at it from a
manufacturer's point of view really
being driven by two different
organizations the first one is a HRI
which is the trade association for all
the air conditioning and heating and
ventilating companies and then a ham
which is more the appliance and the
reason why these two become important is
for most of the air conditioning and and
and larger diamond fication systems
being used they're the HRI one but the
portable dehumidifier --zz fall under
the jurisdiction of the a ham ratings
and so we've got to make sure that we we
compensate and understand that there's
two different rating positions then
those are the professional societies
that we've already heard on the ASHRAE
and the a si B e which
we actually heard from Nadia just before
and I'll just kind of put a little bit
of explanation point on top of it within
HR I there is no plant type of standard
and everybody starts referring back to I
have an air conditioner I want an air
conditioning load and so that would be
the 340 360 but we don't have just an
air conditioning load we also have a
dehumidification load and guess what we
could look at the pool one and and look
at standard 910 and get a moisture
removal efficiency standard of pounds
per hour of condensate with a kilowatt
input but that really doesn't apply
because the temperatures and some of the
other elements aren't consistent and
then there's standard 920 which gets us
into the dedicated outside air systems
and that's a very complicated standard
because it's trying to handle all the
weather climactic conditions that
represented across really North America
and it actually rates at four different
conditions in the cooling
dehumidification mode and two different
conditions in the heating mode and so
when you talk about this multiple
standard multiple parameter type system
it gets a very complicated one and we've
just ended up our conversation after ten
years of trying to develop this code and
have finally got the Department of
Energy to sign off on it you're gonna be
hearing more about that particular code
if you're in the HVAC industry finally
here after ten years of work and and I
bring up the ten years work because none
of these happen overnight there is a lot
of work in developing the standards as
we go forward
so the a.m. actually has the seven zero
zero eight 2018 was the last the code
cycle for it's under the appliance the
interesting thing about this particular
code is all the units being tested don't
have any ductwork so there we call
freestanding they're just put in the
space and they blow out so when you look
at other systems that have to go through
ductwork it cannot apply to the a ham
standard because the the blowers and the
energy costs that they're doing and one
of the things that okay one of the
things that we need to understand and
the difference with that one as as
was just being talked a little bit
earlier by Nadia was the amount of duct
work and filters and other things that
you put on system equipment drives up
the requirement for the load when we
look at that a ham standard the fan has
no static pressure to go against so the
rating is much lower now they're using a
rating here at in SI units at 2.7 liters
per kilowatt hour and you could
translate that one over into pounds an
hour but the problem is there's no
ductwork here how we can apply the two
standards into one common platform as we
go forward within ASHRAE we've got two
different committees that are trying to
talk about it
2.2 is the plant and animal committee
which has just really taken on the
cannabis side of it and this is a very
very recent event they've only actually
met twice to have this conversation at
the trade show in Orlando this past
February they had standing room only at
two different events talking about this
particular standard so there's a lot of
interest in it a lot of people coming
together the other one is the large
building segment that kind of owns a
little bit of the related one and so
these two have to work together so
they're both trying to write a handbook
stand or to start to get preliminary
information out there of how you have to
size the HVAC equipment in this new
industry and so it's going to provide
the guidance to the engineering
community that are working with all the
other people in this area we're also
looking at getting some research money
put together and talk about the
evapotranspiration rate which is the
critical aspect to sizing the HVAC
equipment lighting load is one but
because of the cooling effect of it we
have to know how much is being
transpired otherwise we can't calculate
the load you can read all you want there
isn't a single documented research paper
that's going to say for cannabis this is
the type of rate that you have and we've
got to come to that conclusion if we
want right-sized equipment the a sa B E
is also working on it and they've got
two different standards that are
involved the first one is in the HVAC
side of it and they're kind of
looking at it from all the same elements
that ASHRAE would look at it but they're
trying to to do it and we've got to make
sure that we we stay in in concert with
both organizations and so they are
talking they have already published the
s 642 which is the recommended standard
for the LED light type system and so
really what I'm saying right now there
is absolutely nothing out there to
define a standard for the HVAC units it
doesn't exist and if you were at the
code to conversation last night with the
title 24 people we just have to use some
loose verbage in these early days
because there's nothing we can reference
as it goes forward and and so with that
I guess it gives us a chance to kind of
organize our thoughts and get going at
the HRI spring meeting we're actually
going to be bringing it forward to look
at a development of a standard and
here's where my request is going to come
back to the rest of the people that
we're all in this room today is that we
have to come back and come up with a
rating standard which means I have to
have a temperature I have to have an RH
and as a single point going to be
acceptable to this industry do we need
multiple points that get weighted and
and so these are the type of decisions
that we need to come to feed the the
systems as we work on this standard and
I can already tell you that as it goes
we get federally regulated the
Department of Energy is then going to
take over the standard they've done it
every standard that we've done at a HRI
and it it matters to what's going to go
on I'm going to switch over because
there were some conversations the other
day on this whole refrigerant transition
what I can tell you is that the HVAC
industry is absolutely committed to
going to proper GWP low GWP rating
refrigerants it is moving forward
whether the federal government goes that
way or not now we know all the states
are starting to do their own little
thing along with it but we cannot move
faster than the research allows us to
look at it and the leading
candidates going for the large bulk of
HVAC equipment will contain flammable
elements and all the building safety
code people have to sign off of this
California was a prime example where one
group was not allowing it actually
disallowing it the other group reporting
to the governor was promoting it it gets
very difficult to be able to put a piece
of equipment and where two different
people are saying you can or you can't
so this is going forward you're not
gonna see anything really come into the
industry until 2023 at the absolute
earliest my gut feel is it's gonna be
2024 or 2025 that the low GWP
refrigerants are gonna finally get
through all the design and research to
become part of the platform so the good
news is we're gonna get there the bad
news we're not gonna get there for a
couple more years Lexie okay I'm going
to shift gears just a little and I'm
gonna bring bring it from the standards
which are referred to in codes up to the
level of codes and I'm gonna go as a bit
of a broad brush here I'm looking in
large part at model codes at codes that
maybe transcend more than than one
jurisdiction because they're adopted by
several different jurisdictions and NBI
has been involved for for some years in
the development of national model codes
a little bit of background I'm not gonna
get too deep into anything because I
have what eight minutes here but a
little bit of background on why we are
even talking about building energy codes
in this context according to the do-e
they say energy codes save building
owners about five billion dollars a year
in energy cost and that's per year
obviously this is quite a bit more over
the lifetime of a building so they say
2010 to 2014 that 30-year span we're
looking at 126 billion dollars with a B
of energy cost savings to building
owners because we have codes in place
and something like 245 coal plants worth
of carbon dioxide emissions avoided it
is critical that we think about when we
want to do this efficiency it's it's a
lot easier to do these kinds of project
when you build the building than it is
to go try to retrofit this stuff in
later so the the idea with an energy
code is is build it pretty good the
first time it sets the floor that is a
form of Quality Assurance for the people
who are going to be using that building
and the occupants of that building
whether they be plants or humans so we
want to have codes that achieve these
kinds of goals and we're pretty good at
it
reasonably broadly speaking we're pretty
good at it for buildings intended for
humans it's been a little bit of a
square peg round hole situation trying
to adapt these human centric codes to
plant centric buildings and and
occupancies the way building energy
codes work in the briefest nutshell it
sets the minimum efficiency requirement
for a building something that triggers
code right and it defines what I like to
say is a code defines the worst possible
building you can legally build you got
to do at least this much and then on
from there and it's a subset the energy
code is one of the several building
energy codes or building codes sorry you
know you got lighting you know you got
energy you got structural you got fire
you got water plumbing those are coming
from national model codes so there's
this organization the International Code
Council that for example one of the
things I do a lot is work with the
development of the International Energy
Conservation code IEC C which comes
under the ICC's ambit broadly and a
jurisdiction Colorado callable not
California Colorado Oregon everyone
thought California basically says we'll
take the 2018 version of the
International Energy Conservation code
we'll take the 2015 version we'll take
the 2021 version and then they make some
amendments they change things here and
there sometimes a lot sometimes just a
little but they have this common
framework that they're starting from so
one thing we have focused on over the
years is moving that national model code
forward so that as jurisdictions adopt
they have a better framework and we're
all dealing with something reasonably
consistent across the across the
marketplace now in indoor AG with
cannabis specifically you also have lice
requirements and some jurisdictions have
said well we're not going to do this
thing during the code through the code
maybe this doesn't really fall under
energy code but we can do it in a
licensing requirement scenario so now
you have things you got to do it to meet
code that can vary and maybe there are
also some of the elements that used to
be in an energy code or could
potentially be but they're actually part
of your license RIT very briefly the
idea with national model codes is to
provide a consistent framework but of
course all every state and lots of
jurisdictions sub state are on different
or in a different place with the
adoption so there's everything it's
probably pretty hard to read those those
captions down there but that's
everything from ASHRAE 90.1 2007 all the
way up to 2013 and of course there are
more versions coming out it's a three
year cycle going through here and then a
couple of states especially Arizona in
Colorado Colorado pretty relevant in
this market have a lot of local
adoptions so NBI for example helped
Boulder develop their energy code for
the last several years we wouldn't we've
been doing that so it's it's a
consistent framework but it's in
different places in different
jurisdictions around the country so I'm
gonna talk a little bit about what is in
this broad national model code framework
and I'm gonna start with lighting
because that's that's where we've we've
spent some effort MBI was successful in
moving through a proposal for the 2021
IEC see the model code that jurisdiction
can choose to adopt and eventually many
of them will to say not less than 95% of
the luminaires light fixtures used for
plant growth and maintenance shall be at
least as efficient as 1.6 micromoles per
dual rated in accordance with the asabi
standard Mesabi actually has three
different standards dealing with this so
yeah you have to have a proper thing to
refer to here thank you wasabi - they
put together a good standard that's
something you can reference in a model
code so this was approved by the the
voters the which are cities States
Building Department official
etc for inclusion in the 2021 national
model code it's going to be a few years
before this filters down but what this
does is this gives a common framework
which as as we know isn't always exactly
the same thing and Kyle talked about
that a little bit about how it's not
always going exactly this way but there
is this common framework and a baseline
right you can still do double-ended HPS
that's about 1.7 micromoles per Joule
but probably not single-ended and not
fluorescent so it's a it's a you must be
at least this good to play it also gives
someone like a utility someone running
say a utility program a way to say well
here's a reasonable baseline maybe if
you get a product that's on the
qualified products list from the design
lights consortium here's the difference
between how good that one is and where
the the code is so you know sets the
floor puts us all in a common
understanding and uses this metric let's
talk about HVAC how about where our
national model codes in HVAC and
dehumidification what do we have in the
model codes not much nothing there yet
that's not to say this topic is never
represented in codes and it's definitely
not to say that codes are not relevant
in terms of HVAC systems going into
indoor AG or into horticultural
facilities because you you do have to
pay attention to codes in terms of HVAC
when you put a put a facility together
design a system all that stuff it's not
really in the national model codes but
it is a relevant concern so why why is
this a challenge and I mentioned earlier
there's a little bit of a square peg
round hole situation when we try to take
these codes that were originally built
for humans and adopt them for plants or
for facility's intended to to grow
plants well as we've been hearing
several times through this conference
there are differences in creating
conditions in a space that are ideal for
plant growth dehumidification is a huge
piece of that and and I'm glad to hear
as Keith mentioned that there are
efforts to create consistent metrics for
these dehumidification systems and maybe
we will end up in a place
we're kind of like for lighting I'll go
back a couple slides where we have this
generally consistent oh it's over there
this generally consistent approach where
we say here's you know here's the basic
efficiency be at least this good and off
you go
maybe with some good metrics on
dehumidification there'll be something
along those lines right but we're not
there yet today and that's probably fine
because there's enormous variability
between facilities between practices
which makes it hard to define the
baseline so we're faced with some
challenges and opportunities as we try
to define consistent code frameworks in
the national model code in the ways
jurisdiction my jurisdiction might set
up their own codes and their licensing
regulations right because they can act
kind of the same way I'll just highlight
a couple of these here one question of
course what is the baseline is is a
pretty important piece it is not always
clear where we're starting from if
you're running an incentive program or
or as a jurisdiction what is good
practice and Derrick and his team at RI
have done some really good work in
defining best practices on lighting and
HVAC both there are some places where
the code touches these facilities that
can be can lead to unintended
consequences or or can lead to some
challenges for example if you've got a
facility with a ton of indoor loads
lights dehumidification and it's
producing a lot of heat
should it be very well insulated or is
that insulation just keeping the heat in
and leading to more energy use so you
need to deal with the code may say
insulate your envelope the code may also
say put on an air site economizer so you
can bring in outside air but in Oregon
for example in a few facilities there
are folks that have had to do that tried
to get a variance didn't get that
variance so they built their facility
they put in the economizers they had to
put in the first thing they did weld it
shut yeah there's an economizer on the
roof but it ain't doing much right so
that's that's really an unintended
consequence of using a code that was
built for human occupancy for plant
occupancy so there are there are some
challenges there I like to say in terms
of lighting lumens err for humans and I
think having a
PBF PBE photosynthetic photon photonic
efficiency of efficacy excuse me
provides a good way for us to think
about efficiency or efficacy in in terms
of lighting fixtures and that's
something that people in this room I
think have a pretty good handle on in
the case of Massachusetts and now
Illinois we've got a different animal
going on which is watts of lighting per
square foot of canopy so now you've got
these two different approaches that that
are a bit different and are introducing
I think something of a challenge at
least have the the ability to but the
main point I want to make is that
broadly speaking we want to move codes
forward because we want these facilities
to be built well both in terms of energy
in terms of greenhouse gas impacts in
terms of getting good facilities for the
people who are you know procuring them
right the people the owners the
operators and doing their job these
things are not there to save energy
they're there to produce plants but we
want them to do that in a responsible
way so we want good code approaches we
want consistent code approaches so the
market knows what to do but we all have
some thinking to do about how do we come
up with the right approaches define the
right metrics whether that's for
lighting various components of HVAC or
some kind of integrated everything -
holistic solutions great we need to
think about how to actually do that for
indoor horticulture specifically so with
that we'll be onto Kyle and then
discussion thank you all right thanks
Lexi and I want to thank everyone that
joined the codes discussion last night
it was definitely lively and it's just
amazing what happens when you schedule
it after happy hour so thank you all
that joined so I'm going to talk about
the statewide utilities team for title
24 part six of the California Building
Code okay so why do codes matter into
our cultivation is expanding and
particularly in the urban areas and and
we're expected to see I mean 390
gigawatt hours by 2021 so that's that's
a large load and that's just in
California
so you know the proposed codes are
designed to save growers costs by
reducing energy energy use so you know
here we just have a quick example and
you know looking at if a facility had
244 lights on flower you know you're
looking at annual cost savings of 83,000
you know veg looking at upwards of you
know a hundred hundred plus thousand
dollars annually savings so California
building energy efficiency standards the
the energy code is on a three-year cycle
so right now we're working on what's the
2022 energy code so it's just barely
2020 so we're a couple years you know
out and that won't take effect till
January 1 2023 so it is a regular
process in California and it's on a
pretty regular cycle with formalized
steps that allow for a stakeholder
engagement review of the proposed codes
and all the documentation that's
associated with it so a little bit
different than some of the legislature
that's gone through and you know
different states this is a formal
process that's you know on a rolling
basis for the you know the energy code
okay so controlled environment
horticulture you know this proposal will
impact newly constructed warehouses in
addition to major renovations so you
know we're not going to tell a grower
that's growing right now you know as of
January 1 2023 switch all your lights
out it's going to be someone who is
building new or putting on a major
addition or a major renovation you know
we're looking at more than just cannabis
so we are looking at you know vegetable
crops microgreens basil lettuce tomatoes
flowers we have added greenhouse
lighting and greenhouse envelope as
proposed measures the greenhouse
envelope I will touch on that because
that's a little bit different than some
of the other measures it's actually more
of a codes cleanup because what we've
run into is some growers meet the
definition of a conditioned space by
having mechanical a/c you know some of
those type of like sealed greenhouses
that we heard about earlier and they're
having a lot of trouble meeting
compliance because they're triggering
the envelope portion of Title 24 so in
that envelope portion there's nothing
specific to greenhouses so they're
having to meet basically like a
warehouse or something like that
envelope so as you know that's really
not feasible with regular greenhouse
materials so we want to make that so it
is you know it's it's possible to comply
with okay so the statewide utility codes
and standards team so they actively
support the California Energy Commission
in developing these codes this is a you
know congregation of all the i/o use in
California and they're really trying to
make they're trying to produce energy
savings through feasible enforceable
cost-effective and non proprietary codes
so those are really important you know
we don't want to propose something
that's not cost-effective or that is
overly burdensome for the growing okay
so the overall goal here is to provide
the information needed so that the
Energy Commission can make an informed
decision on how to set a code so that's
energy and demand impacts cost
effectiveness technical feasibility
market impacts crop quality and
productivity you know we're getting out
of the human space so it is important to
think of you know okay this is a process
and we want to make sure that anything
that we propose isn't going to hurt that
process so suggested code language
compliance and enforcement you know how
are we going to make sure that what
we're
recommending is actually done and done
properly so yeah
okay so here's some key dates for the
controlled environment horticulture
measure and I do have some Flyers that
you guys can take after so I'll have
those out after this
so April 16th is our next stakeholder
public stakeholder meeting you'll see at
the end of this there's a link to you
know how to sign up for that and and
register so I say you know I hope
everyone will join and definitely give
your feedback draft case report will be
published the case report is really our
recommendations and documentation of
what went into all this research so that
will be published May 15th on title 24
stakeholders calm and that's a really
good resource for just anything as far
as updates on on the code process and
you can go and click and look at
controlled environment horticulture and
it'll give you an email
you know mailing lists specific to that
measure so any major things that happen
to that measure you'll get you can email
final case report and then after we do
that part it goes to the Energy
Commission and they have a series of you
know public public stakeholder meetings
and then next year in April 20-21 is
when the actual adoption of the
standards will will happen and then
January 1 2023 is the effective date
okay so looking at the particular sub
measures that we have and I know we're
running low on time so I'm going to go a
little bit quick but leave time for
questions after we're looking at a
horticultural minimum lighting efficacy
dehumidification efficiency
environmental and irrigation controls
circulation fan minimum performance and
then the greenhouse lighting in
greenhouse envelope
okay so looking at horticultural
lighting efficacy we're looking at using
a product efficacy so PPE in specifying
a certain micro moles per Joule and one
you know kind of some things that came
out of last night were you know helpful
in kind of modifying this a little bit
so there was a suggestion for doing a
certain percentage of the wattage to
leave some exemptions for you know
particular purpose lights like for
propagation or other things like that so
that will likely be built in and yeah so
then we also have kind of some typical
product types here and then let's okay
here's some existing codes that exist
we've got in Massachusetts Illinois
Denver and Washington State
Massachusetts in Illinois I going with a
lighting power density Denver and
Washington state going with a PPE
similar to what i ec c is doing so and
the nice thing about PPE is that it does
you know it there's not as many issues
with how are you going to define canopy
you know the loopholes that growers can
have to kind of you know space their
plants out and do things that we really
aren't trying to get them to do with the
code but it's ways they can work around
it for dehumidification there was some
really good discussion on this last
night too
you know we've been wanting to establish
a minimum moisture removal efficiency
but based on you know where the industry
is at right now and what's available for
standards this may not be feasible this
code cycle but Colorado actually just
put through some
standards for dehumidification equipment
that would be a good start right now so
specifies you know several different
acceptable methods of dehumidification
so we'll we'll be modifying this and
here's a couple of current standards
Santa Rosa having a ventilation rate
requirement Illinois with their HVAC
requirement circulation fan performance
so this is to do a minimum CFM per watt
and this is one that as Nadia pointed
out is is definitely a lower priority as
far as energy savings but the idea is to
kind of create a minimum floor so in
green house lighting efficacy very
similar to the warehouse just you know
in in greenhouse facilities as well the
other measures dehumidification controls
circulation fans will not be applicable
to greenhouses just into our facilities
so that's an important distinction to
make
and then environmental and irrigation
controls a lot of facilities might have
most or all of these so this is really
again trying to set a minimum floor make
sure all newly constructed facilities
have you know temperature humidity
controls irrigation controls yeah and we
want everyone here to get involved so
sign up for the email updates the second
public stakeholder meeting thank you to
everyone that already has given your
feedback last night was very productive
and you know I I really thank everyone
for staying that extra hour because you
know it was I was happy to get people
for one hour so too was great yeah and
you can send comments on code language
to info at title 24 stakeholders and
copy myself on there
great alright thank you thanks so much
Kyle so we have a few minutes for
questions if anybody has any questions
for our panel a great presentations
thank you I noticed a little bit of
slippage in language over the course of
this event and so controlled environment
horticulture versus controlled
environment agriculture
I don't those are small details or maybe
they're big details maybe you could
comment on that and also to keep the
question on you know are we using the
right terminology when we say HVAC in
controlled environment
horticulture agriculture
I'll take the second one first yes we
have to use the HVAC because as we look
at what these standards are going to be
it's going to be the eating food of
cooling ventilation unfortunately
there's not the D part of that but it's
implied within the industry so I think
we don't want to remove it we want to
keep calling because it covers all those
segments
I can address the first part so
controlled environment horticulture we
had a couple iterations of what the name
should be there was CEA is another
acronym that the energy commute
Commission uses frequently so there was
a conflict there and it was in a
definition that seemed to really get
narrow in on the facilities we were
looking at so I I do understand that
there's you know a little bit of
industry terminology differences there
but there were there were some specific
reasons we had to go with that - he said
technically agriculture includes animals
and that was one of the reasons on the
national model code level that that IECC
21 20 21 proposal is indoor
horticultural lights not just
agriculture specifically for plant
applications although it also says it a
little further down Kyle is flora
culture in ceh is their flower
production in California as it covered
under horticulture and that double-ended
HPS lamp efficacy that shows up in the
goe 2017 report I don't know if that's
bear lamp but it's certainly not fixture
efficacy the highest I've ever seen is
like 1.7 - when I tested it so it seems
sort of like an outlier compared to the
others sure yeah so thanks to address
the first part as far as flora culture
yes so all crops are considered you know
for for indoor and for greenhouse
I imagine the greenhouses will have the
higher you know percentage of the flora
called culture so that will be you know
just the lighting measure and the
envelope and the envelope is only for
conditioned greenhouses so the
definition of conditioned in title 24
part 6 is 5 BTUs per hour per square
foot of mechanical cooling so not
evaporative cooling but like AC and then
10 BTUs per hour per square foot of
heated
so I was wondering if were you know
since we're expanding title 24 and we're
expanding building codes to nominally
cover horticulture are we now
considering that all greenhouses are now
going to be real buildings with real
codes about how they're built and and
that we're going to be going down that
path as well and as a kind of follow-up
question to that are we also looking at
other types of industrial facilities
like car plants and are we gonna have a
special code for car plants and a
special code for paint factories and a
special code for all of these other
kinds of buildings that are really
purpose-built and that might not have
that same level of customer ignorant
when they get sold or when they get
rented sure that's a great question so
as far as I'll start with you know the
different processes so there are some
processes that are already covered
within title 24 part six refrigerated
warehouses compressed air parking lot
Lighting's and there's a few others so
that may grow but this isn't the first
time that that's been done it's been
done since 2008 so there are several
other processes that are involved in
that as far as you know how deep the
Energy Commission will dive into
greenhouses in subsequent code cycles
I can't necessarily comment on on that
you know as far as what we're looking at
now with green house lighting and the
envelope you know that's that's as far
as we will go in this code cycle you
know I just can't comment any further on
that
I brought it up the other night but how
would you see the policing of something
under the DLC requirement being you know
anything let's say it's at one point six
anything between one point six and a DLC
minimum because there's no independent
third party looking at that and yeah if
you can just speak to any preliminary
thoughts on that yeah that's a great
great question Brady so this is you know
something we're currently considering
how to deal with that you know one one
possible solution is to characterize the
existing incumbent technologies that
that fall you know below that that
threshold and iron on the DLC qualified
products list you know so that that
could be one and then adding a table to
the the building codes so that there is
accepted you know PPE ratings for those
particular technologies there there is
some complexity to that because you're
gonna have to look at you know some
different variations of reflectors and
you know of course single-ended versus
double-ended i I see those is almost a
different fixture even though they can
both be high pressure sodium and then
also making sure those are well vetted
with the industries so you know making
sure that those are industry accepted
members so that's that's one possible
method independent testing is another
that's got its own stickiness to it and
so a couple possible solutions
all right there's at least a standard to
test to at this point
all right great thank you let's give a
hand to our panel
[Applause]