and so this is your this is our baby
this is grow coffee and it's like oh
gosh yeah
Oh a fertilizer that can help your
garden achieve beneficial runoff be more
beneficial if you're gonna leave a
footprint leave a beneficial footprint
yes I would agree with that
yes
grow Kashi Rhea solid state fermentation
technology and effective microorganisms
and a blend of multivitamins to create
that I lost there's no way I could I how
do we say effective microorganisms the
pathogens during our beer making
so I come from a dairy background where
as a child I traveled with my dad and we
would cover up the feed for the animals
at the dairies and it was just at the
beginning of a science called solid
state fermentation the runoff from the
silage cured the pollution in the manure
lagoons so that's when beneficial runoff
the idea beneficial runoff came around
especially involving lactic acid
bacteria so years later I got into the
cannabis business when I moved here to
the Emerald triangle about 2000 and
because I had a background in the
bioremediation
of the toxic Superfund site I thought we
could use the same microbes when growing
the cannabis to make our farming
beneficial I grew up working at many
many dairies in Washington State in
California and so after I was out of the
dairy business I was in the cannabis
industry and Jack hare and Eddie lap had
me trained to make this Bokashi product
because of my background so those were
my mentors oh well we try to source our
inputs for this product from only people
and companies that have been proven to
give back and you know be deemed at
least organic you know in certification
processes so my beta testing group vets
every single product that goes into this
product
she says the ratio is for soil but what
with this bag be good for is this for
our soil or is this for 20 square feet
if we were building soil we would use
one gallon to one yard
later on we would use 1/3 cup per square
foot top dressed bi-weekly several weeks
after your application it is the food
for your beneficial microorganisms
she says and adding it to your garden
top dressing is best in my opinion
although you could make a drench and
drench your plant and the soil use it to
make tea absolutely it's a multi-purpose
probiotic we could take an activated
area to compost tea like Elaine Ingraham
talks about and then use this product at
the end and stabilize it up to ten days
throughout the grow season but I tend to
stop about halfway into a flowering
period because the product has a
tendency with some crops like onions and
cannabis to keep the crop from ripening
fully I believe that it's because it
keeps it in a regenerative state
the trichomes would stay clear onions
and other crops are also known to not
mature fully if we keep this product
going I think the one thing that we all
have in common is that we would like for
our farming to be beneficial
[Music]