[Music]
hi my name is Alison justice and I'm VP
of cultivation and al collapse I also
own a 40 acre hip farm in South Carolina
along with an extraction facility I was
here at the cultivation classic today to
be on a panel with some of the industry
leaders to talk about production science
and then I'm gonna let my partner here
introduce himself hi giro court chief
product officer at pop in Berkeley we
are a California wellness company we
make topicals tinctures capsules and
pain relief patches all our products are
solvent list I'm happy to be invited
here to the cultivation classic it's my
first time in Oregon which is surprising
but you know a lot of great people here
a lot of aligned values around the
future of cannabis and how we need to a
self-regulate so seeing the folks from
kind looking at evaluating farms since
you know the feds aren't doing it of
course you know talking about being on
the panel with Allison and just talking
about science and it was great to be
flanked by two scientists that are
data-driven where I'm kind of in that
weird mix where I have this CPG company
and some years of anecdotal evidence and
I'm just kind of plodding along as the
industry needs data so it's great to
have these panels and these talks where
we start to share knowledge because one
of the the best things about the
rollback of prohibition is the ability
to speak openly and share knowledge and
you know connect with folks that you
know just know different things and have
different approaches and every time you
meet them they grow your mind and and
hopefully you can do the same for them
so one of the things I wanted to touch
on a little bit with you specifically
was you know I absolutely agree that
this medicine works the best as a full
botanical so as a full plan so getting a
piece of a little bit of everything the
terpenes and the flavonoids the the
plant facts fats chlorophyll even but
you know it stresses me out how do we
determine that you know because
if you're growing under LEDs and I'm
growing under full Sun that same strain
it's gonna be different if you dry fast
and I dry slow the terpene profile might
become something completely different
than we intended depending on how we
extract if you do ethanol and I do co2
it's gonna be a different yield but then
even on top of that if we both do co2
extraction
well maybe use different times and
pressures and heat and so that's all
gonna gild something completely
different so you know when trying to
figure out how to standardize that with
it not being just the flower there's so
many variables that you know it's
exciting but at the same time it makes
me question how we can standardize it to
the best of our abilities so I think the
answer lies in data collection and
luckily we have these things called
computers that love managing variables
right another complex thing is ourselves
and we're each different right so once
when we were sitting around at our
company we have these things call for 20
meetings where it's not a work meeting
it's kind of like exactly what is on
Wednesday afternoons where we just
vision and imagine what the world could
be imagine if we were able to not first
of all we do a poor job in our country
right now of tracking people's medical
history so if we had a device by which
we were tracking people's medical
history individual them as an individual
tracking what they use and it's complex
parts perhaps with enough data we would
start to be able to understand even
something as complicated as whole plant
medicine consistency is a really good
point
it can't natural medicine in general is
inconsistent right even if the same even
if you hold them all the variables the
same in a natural environment there's
gonna be shifts there's gonna be more
rain one year less rain more Sun less
for all these different things and then
the drying you know all the terpenes
that you know if we say that you know
THC and CBD are the engine or the
cannabinoids engine and terpenes drive
the ship if we go with that analogy
well those terpenes those volatile
organic compounds yeah they're exactly
that VOCs it's like a little bit of heat
a little bit of the way we store them
all of that will change their
composition right so we know also that
cannabis has had
this affects and I often think of that
as winning the lottery like for some
reason your physiology and the strain
that you came across created a miracle
for you so I hold that okay that that
miracle is out there there's a way to
get it but there as you put a variety of
variables that we can't quantify right
now to be able to reliably reproduce
that effect right so I would hope that
if I had to just vision I would say that
perhaps one day there will be a medical
tracking software that not only tracks
the individual patient but tracks the
products if they've used and they're
infinite variability and then over time
starts to point definitively towards
these specific things that are in common
over time that have worked for them and
we need good statistician to compile all
that data yeah it's funny in our company
we just now are building out our
data-driven apps our data-driven ops
people you know to start to track we get
a lot of feedback a lot of testimonials
and that while that's not a clinical
trial it's like our products have gone
from not using - you know we had a lady
in Richmond say that you know she unable
to walk upright for the last five years
started using our bomb and I'm like
while I know it's effective I'm like
whoo you know there's a huge placebo
effect going on with cannabis right now
that that also corrupts the data right
there are a lot of newbies that come in
and it's almost like their resistance
turns into a positive because the
placebo effect just completely you know
miracles are being created and so we
have to you know part of me as a
business person is like yeah put that
one up and then as a scientist I just
want to be like wait a minute
like slow down like we need to like be
able to recreate these experiences
before we can highlight them yeah so
data is key right and and and definitely
in the black market day data was not a
thing right and as you're building a
business data is not your first thing to
get but like and and we are in a nascent
industry so even an analytics around
market sharing stuff you know we
struggled to pay BDS because we're like
do we really need to do that or do we
just need to continue to stay on shelf
but we do need to do that we do need to
encourage people who are gathering data
whether it's at the register whether
it's at the clinician level because
without that we can't make educated
future decisions
right nothing that's data on every piece
of the puzzle right growing extraction
drying everywhere we need this data you
said you had a hemp farm in South
Carolina are you able to start to work
towards different cultivars that will
produce more oil rich products or are
the regulator's still trying to hold the
different cultivars to more agricultural
style hem South Carolina is amazing
my my varieties are 22% CBD you know
they're minor cannabinoids are upwards
of 5%
so yeah we're absolutely able to reach
out of that restriction zone a little
bit and that's due to the way the
regulations were written you know
looking at only Delta 9 you know giving
that opportunity that if you do go over
0.3% but you're under 1% you can
remediate in some sort of way so it has
give us a huge opportunity in terms of
breeding you know not being afraid that
you know having that leeway of pushing
it a little bit but also not being
scared that you're gonna lose you know
your life savings in this farm because
they're gonna burn it down so yeah South
Carolina fueled the other southern
states have been really really great and
helping us to be able to expand on that
too to not just be stuck with these two
varieties that everybody else in the
whole you know us is growing and get
really creative you know terpenes up you
know above 2% it's just it's really
really great environment for for working
with him yeah I think it's important
just to note that that that's awesome
because I that was not the answer I was
expecting to be quite honest and it's
just important for everybody to know
that there is a way to growth CBD
cultivars that are federally legal but
you know kind of like I said in our
panel I don't really use the hemp word I
just it's all cannabis to me it's this
one plant and there are different
varietals and when you're talking about
producing medicine you should be looking
at the right varietal if you're talking
about producing cloth you should be
looking at that right right correct
varietal so it's good that the state is
giving you the latitude to grow the
that you need for what you're trying to
do so and yeah and with the farm bill
that means that you know perhaps I can
give you a call and get some of that
because our 50-state product right now
we source it actually out of Oregon and
we have used the cherry CBD and the F
cancer strain out of Colorado but yeah
that's awesome
and then one of the question you know my
next question would be does it wash well
I don't know if you've done any solvent
production but we are desperately
looking for that CBD cultivar that we
can do our ice water extraction with and
get you know a clean solvent list
extract that can be used as a
concentrate right now it typically the
yields it's possible of course but the
yields are so little that it's not
economically viable but that has to do
with the cultivar and so I can say this
our Bay aux produces great Keith
so haven't had a try to ice water hash
but would love to work with you
[Music]