all right well we're here with lindsay
from aloha humboldt and uh we're gonna
be talking with her today about her farm
what makes her flowers unique hi lindsay
hi russell how's it going it's going
really good excellent glad to hear it um
so maybe tell us a little bit about your
background and how you got into cannabis
at first what how did that start
um i got into cannabis when i was 16.
it was a great way to break the ice
growing up in southwest michigan we had
a lot of great cultivars some that we
still run bubblegum was one of the first
oh yeah that's a classic but i was able
to see when i was 16
and i was really just in love with the
plant right from a young age that's
amazing and then so you came out to
humble started aloha humble
and kind of started more indoors
so
ryan and i moved in
and
we were in arcata for a year
and we did like
six octagons in a basement and
uh maxed out the bedrooms upstairs and
then
you know classic humble grow
in 2002 then we moved to uh another spot
that had a basement in eureka
and then in 2008 we moved to willow
creek nice yes you guys have been almost
20 years 20 years and you've been in
willow creek now for
since 2008 so yeah that's 14 just about
just about that's quite baker's dozen
yeah so you've been doing out you know
learning how that environment works for
a while now yeah um in 2008 uh we put
out like
the 99 that we were allowed underneath
but we had smaller pots so it was like
45 gallons and then we sized up to 100
gallons smart pots
and then transitioned into having some
beds and greenhouses and started doing
depth we kind of held back on doing
light up because it meant that you
didn't get to go to the river as much
because you had to be at home in the
evening
um so we were in the valley close to the
river
and so the climate was really
drastically different from where we're
at now um so then we got the property in
anticipating um the rack market we knew
that we wouldn't be able to afford um
agricultural land so we just went for
whatever we could get which was a 141
acre parcel of tpz land that we
converted
and i did a bunch of remediation on and
and we're at 2600 feet now interesting
2600 feet elevation yeah so that's
pretty high so i mean transitioning into
that i mean what makes so that your farm
is pretty unique because you've
developed it it was tp zlan you've
obviously like done a lot
of work
with just ecological repair
a lot a lot of work with ecological
repair so the farm has been was
cultivated on since the 80s
and it was kind of just like um
they put in the different flats when
they were doing the logging so they were
logging uh flats and then um there were
old school dugout greenhouses that were
put out oh wild because um they're a lot
easier to be hidden from the helicopters
yeah so really low profile
um easy to pull tarps terrible for
canopy um
but the ones we have
we have like 11 different cultivation
zones on our property so instead of
having just one big flat where we have
greenhouses we actually have
you know six different areas that are
then pieced out and our lower flat we
did
three greenhouse removals and fixed a
rock slide
and did a lot of environmental cleanup
down there wow interesting that's really
interesting do you feel like in your
farm you've
uh incorporated any interesting
methodologies you know that would you
know intend to have your give your
flower some type of interesting
definitely quality um well over the
course of just getting to know the plant
more and being outside
um like i said we were in smart pots for
a long time and then realized that we
really needed to just have all of our
roots in the ground so we transitioned
to having everything out of smart pots
everything's in raised beds yes
yeah awesome yeah that's cool and you've
been doing some level of you know inner
cropping or companion planting do you
feel like what do you have any you know
we love cover crops well and then you're
one of the experts on ipm you know so we
get to you know work together yeah um
but we've been doing cover crops since
you know 2010 we would even do them in
our smart pots and it was a lot more
work but you get a lot more biodiversity
and the plants are a lot healthier the
soil building process fpf really helps
that organic matter
just year after year it's like the
plants deplete the organic matter and
then you have to rebuild it and cover
crops help with that yeah it just is one
of the things that we learned from
friends and that's the great thing about
our community in the willow creek
cannabis alliance is because we get to
do a lot of exchange of knowledge see
what's working what's not in genetics
and cultivation practices nice well
speaking of genetics
well
you got them over there i do yeah well
here we have um our apple fritter okay
and then a couple of collaborations we
did with cookies we've got the london
pound cake and cake mix
but half of our product that we grew for
them we decided to put in our own
packaging that can i crack those oh yeah
please
so these are pre-rolls they're you know
a little bit more desirable right now in
the market because it's a lower price
point and you know that's good
and it's just ready you can just take it
to the beach
um these have really similar terpene
profiles uh it's the uh
beta-caryophyllene linoleul and humulene
and then the other one has just got the
humulin and limonene so it's uh
out yeah check this out this is what i'm
smoking uh is apple fritter a lot it's
one of my favorites
nice yeah yeah it seems like it's i've
uh
i've
heard it's pretty decent yielder yeah
it's really dense it's got a spicy
earthy tone
something that i'm really into i love
that tone
what else do we have here
yep this is another jar oh yeah i'll
check it out i'm always like looking at
different cars um do you think do you
have any you know interesting uh
techniques you know obviously growing is
half the battle and almost harvesting
and drying is the other half right you
have any interesting you know things you
do to try to help
preserve terpene yeah we like to make
sure that our room always stays really
cold you know even in the summer when
we're running our light up we run air
conditioners in our drying rooms to make
sure that it's climate controlled
controlled system we don't let it get
back over
you know a high humidity once we pull it
this is the london power so good
thanks yeah that's a favorite for me um
really similar to profiles but that
one's got a little bit more lemon right
wow yeah yeah it really it really pops
oh wow it's like really pretty and
fluffy and like it turned really nice
and purple it's weird yeah
um you know as far as
different cultivation methodologies we
do a pretty extensive prune
we're cutting back a lot
we still incorporate super cropping
which is um you know just a method of
twisting the stem
and
i really enjoy doing foliar feeds on the
plants i can smell this all day
it smells good it's like it's weird it's
almost like a london pound cake like the
name actually reflects it has a really
it's like a dessert smell
yeah
that's cool have some of it yeah yeah i
know i definitely so wow these these uh
so you've these are the varieties yep
and um
do you is there a place where people can
buy these or would you do normal
wholesale or yeah well uh you know for
people that are looking to carry it in
their shop we do our distribution
through up north distribution and
they're statewide and we actually have
around 240 uh dispensaries that carry
our product awesome off and on
almost every place in humboldt carries
us as far down as san diego area and
actually the bay area is really
supportive and um i was really surprised
sacramento smokes a lot of weed
so that's a good sign especially for the
small farmer yep it is well speaking
about the small farmer i mean you know
we're dealing with a lot of corporate
cannabis we're trying to balance
balance that very carefully um
do you have anything specifically you'd
like to talk about your product that
stands out you know what what makes your
product different than corporate
cannabis
i think that a lot of it is to do with
the way it's grown and the intention
that's put into it and i know that's not
measurable in numbers i think we talk a
lot about thc and the different
cannabinoids that's really important too
but i think there's a real energetic
exchange between the farmer and the
plant
that can then carry over to the end
product and experience
i think that as the market matures we'll
talk more about the experience
and less about just the numbers i think
that it makes a big difference how it
actually makes you feel totally and i
think in you know the 90s and early
2000s people were more interested in
smoking the herb and experiencing it
before purchasing it and you know now we
can't smell it i know we can't you know
the nose knows
so i just think that it's a miss to not
be able to have your consumer smell the
flower and understand what is going to
work with their chemistry i think
there's a lot of knowledge in in that
that's being lost i'd like to see that
yeah interesting yeah yeah that's really
cool so that's a good change and we kind
of went into that but if i had to ask
you any other changes you'd like to see
like a specific thing if you could
change one thing about regulations or
education what would be the positive
outcome you'd like to see out well i
love wine and so when i think about how
ryan and i used to travel and go down to
dry creek specifically for those
infandels
i think that something that could be
really exciting for people that love
wine and food would be to find a way to
say you know well in willow creek
the expression of the
terpenes that are more like gassy and
spicy those really stand out i think
that those more hearty terpenes are
going to be able to withstand our
diurnal swing because we've got really
really hot days
really really cold nights and so it
takes a hearty 50 degrees
we'll have a huge swing in temperature
and so our climate only really allows
for the most hardy plants you know it's
it's a rugged community you know so you
think like in terms of like having the
ability to like to basically direct to
consumer sales where people can come
visit the farm experience i think that
cannabis farmers should have all of the
same allowances that people that make
wine do and craft brewers i also think
that a big huge thing that would help is
a way to
mitigate taxes for craft producers so we
can't compete at a commodity scale but
we can compete in quality and experience
so if we're able to have
the first thousand pounds
have a tax rebate in q1
you know that way the people that are
selling bulk then when they need to plan
for the year they have a return of funds
i think that that would be a wonderful
way to do it or if they wanted to just
remove those taxes right away for us
that would be fine with me too are you
sure you don't want to run for
supervisor or send you know
gubernatorial positions well i actually
did apply for the cannabis advisory
committee i don't know if it was
something i think that it's something
where we need to have equity and legacy
producers represented and it doesn't
mean that it should be me but i think it
should be someone that has a perspective
that can represent farmers authentically
absolutely not from a special interest
place or being an ancillary company
because i don't think you have the same
view exactly and it's the same with
whoever made metric was never a farmer
right
well and then you have to look at who
you're aligning with because then when
you have someone that's you know doing
your marketing or things that are
representative of the community it
really should be authentic um indeed
cool well uh i think that pretty much
wraps it up here today
so i did want to talk to you guys about
our rosin so it's over here let's check
it out
the other thing that i think i always
love to touch on is collaboration so
especially um working with getting our
products to market
and not just selling in bulk but selling
with you know representation
um i think that piece is so important oh
cool you're working with humboldt chirp
count yeah i've known rob since like
2002. yeah we used to do fish tour
together oh hilarious oh wow that's so
funny well like we would both go we
weren't going to get there yeah no
totally yeah
but this is our papaya um so the papaya
turned out really nicely it's actually
dropping on the up north menu on monday
which will be the
hca
cbd
nice it has a really interesting terpene
at the top that's um gwyol that i hadn't
really heard of that much but i did a
little research so it's got pinene
limonene and then this guy all right
maybe i'm saying it wrong i'm a sucker
for isn't it elite it's like one of
those nice the papaya is so nice i'm
excited about it so the wild is similar
to
pinene in flavor but it has more of a
eucalyptus yes and then can kind of lean
towards like woodsy rose oh my god
i've never smelled a terpene profile
like that awesome so the other thing i
want to mention is the wine and the food
pairings so we've done for all of our
cultivars that hit the market we've got
a sommelier down in the bay area that we
work with and she's a
has passed her french scholars exam and
so she's literally studied how to
describe flavors and smells and so she
does our
strain descriptions and then pairings
and so
like wine
a lot of the fuelly and more robust
flavors actually pair well with reds and
then the things that are more floral and
fruity pair better with whites very
interesting that's an interesting
development
fun way to experience your cannabis
that's amazing i love that that's
quite phenomenal are you guys doing much
flour rosin production
so
last year we did a lot of flour and then
you know trying to be more market savvy
you know thinking about doing a bigger
batch seem to make sense because then
you're cutting your testing costs but
once it's in a jar it's going to degrade
quicker and so i found this year that i
really wanted to make sure that by the
end of the first quarter that we weren't
going to have any more flour to sell
i wanted to have
we're doing bubble hash with
actually the guy that's playing in the
band tonight my friend matt engel he's
opening a store in eureka called mocha
awesome and it stands for modern
cannabis and he's doing a product called
basic bubble it's like oh basic bubble
but we're collaborating on the london
pound cake
it's a bubble gum guava
and then we also have the cake mix
and so we're going to make some hash
infused pre-rolls out of the bubble hash
that we do with them
with peak and then i think we're going
to still
jar some wedding cake
and
do another batch we've got this
zev
and that's going to come out as rosin
from terp council and then we're going
to do a batch of papaya resin cool well
it's all about collaboration bob's
definitely got the high-end level terps
i love the myron jars
the chirps yeah they're
real nice perfect well thanks again i
appreciate you thank you thanks for
letting us know about your farm and
totally look forward to smoking some
that awesome thanks guys