[Music]
the appellations project man sir Ivan
this is something that you hold near and
dear and I know some other people that
are tied to it but really you talked
about this at an earlier future cannabis
project video in a basement in Venice
and an old speakeasy of all places with
some very interesting folks so tell us a
little bit about that because that's
really what put things on the map yes so
nice fun part in the pond yeah so we so
the founder of the Mendocino
appellations project one of the things
that we did with a with the Appalachians
was that you know I come from a design
background and I had been building
greenhouses I mean I've been in the
California industry for about 22 years
so I'm very familiar with Northern
California and the cannabis trade I
understood what was going on from a
political standpoint because of course
you know I was on the other side of the
gate and then I was on the Food Policy
Council so I was working a lot with
policy around food you know over policy
development you know for food and also
writing online software programs for you
know virtual food hubs for distribution
decentralizing production farm-to-table
dinner series for about 10 years so had
this idea of small batch craft and how
to how to support taking cannabis money
and supporting the local food system and
then I got arrested 2012 and ended up
very publicly exposed for my work in
nonprofit sector and you know I had a
choice either apologize for being in the
cannabis industry which we had supported
all this great work to that point or
step up and do something got into policy
council development to develop the
Mendocino Policy Council with a few
other Mendocino kind of cannabis policy
council with a
with a you know few other people and
then my skill set was really in that
design so I was like I was noticing
where I really get in where you fit in
and I started drawing this map I started
drawing an Appalachians map they've
heard the concept of Appalachians of the
wine regions France grew up with them
there's like super stoked on you know on
how they had developed what it seems
protections for small batch and craft
wine producers yeah you know very
similar protecting products of place
essentially protecting IP because when
you give the farmer IP you give them the
power not the corporation's correct so
the market then demands back to the IP
which is connected to the land and the
land owners versus the corporation and
the product so it's products of place
and of place being the number one
determinant so drawing that map really
was cementing our regional heritage and
legacy moving forward and then drove
around with the map and you saw the map
today but you know with the pin I've
seen so that's a state map so this is
our first shot at doing a state map
where as you guys are down at my neck of
the woods I think you're out in the
desert no no no no we're launching we we
do we do mapping so we're identifying
regions where cannabis is being produced
in geographical indications settings not
necessarily for appellation of origin so
the expression the metabolome expression
of the plant this relationship with Sun
and soil is the most important thing so
therefore desert it's not really a place
where you can do that you have to do it
engineered or inside and that's yeah you
don't get an appellation so but anyway
you know it was a really good way to
protect small-batch and craft cannabis
producers there's a real way to protect
the legacy and heritage of the region
and a real way to you know make a
quality differentiation in the
marketplace and so which we hope to see
forward with organizations like emerald
exchange and and craft Kenneth's
producers everywhere so how that that
affected a bit of the policy here in the
state California right because I know
there's certain brands like Humboldt
will pick on one that had to segue their
name into ptosis to go through that
because of the Appalachians grabbing
just as
yeah I mean so you can't claim the name
of a place necessarily as the brand name
yes you know and a lot of people are
gonna start to see that when Appalachian
petitions start to come in there's gonna
be this huge backlash against all the
brands that have the name of either a
lot of it comes down to the strain names
as well you know so it's like Big Sur
holy Bud is an example that were
tremendous and brought up the other day
you know that's that's really because
the Big Sur holy but it was just call it
holy mud grown in Big Sur California and
or Big Sur Appalachian giving the power
back to the Appalachian not the strain
you give to the strain Dickie grow it in
Ethiopia and have Big Sur holy breath
growing all around the world and it
doesn't necessarily maintain that same
marker of quality that it comes from
that specific region so holy bud grown
in Big Sur then becomes the marker of
quality makes sense so so getting into
this and you you know we hate to compare
this industry to the alcohol industry
but it's kind of hard not to and it's
one of those things where celestial
brands anheuser-busch we know Miller
Coors has been focused on for a minute
so I'll ask both of you could start with
you ricardo because something's in your
back yard I mean Miller Coors is right
down the street from you in Golden
Colorado yeah sure so what do you think
of as some of these mainstream alcohol
and even more recently obviously tobacco
companies where do you see us in a year
as far as the larger corporations versus
the smaller micro if you will versus
macro I think this is only the beginning
and apparently that guy agrees but no
this is only the beginning right I mean
we're just seeing the first giant
alcohol brand the first few big beer
brands of course now Altria the owner of
Philip Morris International is is in the
game with a very legitimate
billion at 1.8 billion dollar investment
in in Cronos up in Canada we're gonna
see a lot more of this I think it was
45% oh well that's what Rachel 4:55
totally but yeah but ya know that it's
it's only it's only amplifying we're
going to see so much more of this and I
think it's inevitable and I think the
only thing we need to be aware of is
most of these industries have not been
the most accountable have not been the
most transparent or honest and we just
need to be conscientious about what
their involvement could mean for the
potential future of this industry and
the businesses they're involved with
because you could watch madmen you could
watch another number of documentaries
and read books but but yeah especially
Big Tobacco and and and of course let's
not forget pharmaceutical because the
largest donor to the opposition campaign
and in 2016 election in Arizona was
iNSYS therapeutics proud Ares active
item a bit that was an interesting story
I know maker have a crazy strong and
deadly fentanyl but I think we need to
just keep an extra close eye on these
entities you know whether it's Pharma
alcohol nicotine to make sure that
they're not practicing the ill deeds of
their past
now what's your takes I mean this is we
know you've grown up not too far from
where I grew up up here
and we've seen it with like the micro
booze right I mean very few but we try
to keep these micro brews from jumping
the shark so to speak and go into a bee
and become a just in our name like Goose
Island or Breckenridge brewery Colorado
so how do you see that playing out
NorCal hasn't been true that companies
like in the nicotine space of in
purchasing property up here is north of
San Francisco you know you never know
that's the thing right you never know
until you do and then all of a sudden
it's like
you get into the common sense right it's
like who the hell would want to move to
Northern California and produce 10,000
square feet of craft cannabis when they
can go down into Imperial Valley Central
Valley she'll be good at the Coachella
Valley they can go down to you know
Salinas they can go to Carpinteria they
can go to San Luis Obispo and they can
grow a million square feet of really
beautiful cannabis that they can put
into packaging and sell for a premium in
the consumer marketplace like Los
Angeles San Diego Sacramento at
literally you know pennies a gram you
know you're looking at some of these new
productions coming a little bit five
cents a gram at scale right let's just
say at 10 cents a gram we're at $45 a
pound right five cents a gram we're at
twenty to fifty a pound so we would have
to grow tens of thousands of pounds here
just to support the taxes and the
mortgage on our farms so the idea that
we would ever survive as the commodities
competitor it doesn't even make sense so
we're extremely hopeful and optimistic
because at the end of the day we have
projects we have media projects telling
the story of who did carry this torch
for this number of years right so it's
like I've got 22 years of shipping out
of out of you know Northern California
you know five you know five decades of
production I mean it's a legacy and a
heritage they carry the torch for
everyone now if industry comes in and
decides they want to homogenize an
entire region right then it'd be kind of
an asshole move right so and and it
doesn't make very much sense it seems
spiteful ucba just tried to do something
very similar the retail space or they
were saying like well we're gonna we're
gonna block events and we're gonna block
small-batch crafts cultivators from
having direct access to consumers yes
and
and you know not because they had to but
because they could you know not because
it made sense but just because they were
kind of pulling the little jerk move and
and that's okay you know we see people
doing that all the time but one thing
they can't have is Northern California
the one thing they can't have is our
redwoods
they can't have our land right they
can't have the millions of people that
come up here to visit our coastlines
they can't have all of these things that
we already have and trains it
intrinsically linked to our to you know
to our survival already which is tourism
dollars yeah right so we have an
industry now we just have to say I was
lucky that I got to take that yoga class
you know for 10 years I was lucky that I
got to coach soccer for those years I
was lucky that I got to do all those
things that was a blessing it was a gift
that the medicine gave to me super great
now I got to pick up the hammer and the
saw again I got to learn how to build a
gland yeah I've got I've got it you know
I'm gonna go down to the thrift store
I got a Venice Beach out my little
glamping tent and charge $200 a night
and give him a joint so it's like that's
what that's what we do and we just have
to wait we have to stop crying we have
to stop scaling because if we scale up
to 10,000 square feet we're taking all
of our good resources and dumping it
into a failing market yeah which is the
commodity space we are not commodities
farmers I can produce 10,000 square feet
of crap right and yeah but but but and
or I could produce you know 2500 square
feet of the finest cannabis on the
planet and people will pay for that a
little pay for that the premium is it so
we just need to just go back to what it
was that we were doing before yeah you
know we're homesteaders now a lot of us
moved up here is economics Refuge and so
now we've learned how to farm we've
learned how to build we've learned how
to survive we've learned how to pump our
own water we've learned how to do all
these great things now we just get to
share those gifts and skills with the
rest of the world yeah in the world is
gonna change I think it is you're right
and we had Kevin Joe jury a mutual
friend of both of ours
Kevin Joe tree on and you know some of
the things that he's doing specifically
in humble I mean it has that name has
such a reputation internationally as his
Mendocino but humble definitely does and
that's what we talked about like some of
that you know we've got to bring this
money in gotta bring the right money in
the positive money in and tourism is
where it's at because this is still an
epicenter I mean traveling to places
like you know Spain for for spannabis
so you're traveling just getting back
from cannafest Prague I mean there's
people they know these names they're
synonymous with top-quality fire not to
say good genetics don't exist in Europe
- but Northern California definitely has
that image it should be well it also
also is going to be the capital of
regenerative farming across the world
because at the end of the day we were
behind locked gates and we we became
permaculturist by also by necessity we
shared by necessity we communicated and
became community by necessity we were
geographically isolated we can teach the
world these values in these skills and
an institute style retreat style basis
we can bring people up and teach them to
be permaculturist
right and we can show them living
systems that we've been building over
decades as well
losing the closed loop forwards up there
is a good example these guys from
aquaponics to film I mean composting
annualized I mean it's it's it's really
a digitized an ocular inoculants
microbiome in ground soil like I mean we
that we do it so we do polyculture for
real you know you mentioned home stairs
because that's one thing Kevin under
this guy's so great you if you guys know
if you grab probably fuel Howser right
with California gold I compared cavity
collards this guy moved from Tennessee
but he knows more probably about
California specifically north to San
Francisco the most natives that I grew
up with and here this guy is just so he
preaches it so well but the education
that he shares as far as what's going on
in the fact that the largest acreage a
privately held property by far is in
that county of this entire state I think
that says a lot about the whole
neighbors and how you all coexist and
make
happen and do it as a collaborative
right do it as a team effort more more
so now than ever so what do you feel
about you know we had we had a Mendocino
once a Mendocino generations on earlier
that we were talking to you so as a
project like that something that's
making a difference to your point as far
as taking care of the smaller growers
well I mean so Mendocino generations is
positioned on green fields ranch which
is the oldest intentional community in
Mendocino County so back to the lenders
in the 1960s came back planet cannabis
you're seeing Mendocino generations are
the second and third generation farmers
from that original group of lenders from
San Francisco yeah right and it's
hilarious I mean I've stayed and hung
out and you know you know in in green
fields for a while he's watch sunsets on
at Steve Ryan's property before he
passed on the top of the hill and you
know and watch his big 25 you know
monster you know ten pounders and you
know and in you know and and I've rented
a property across the street in Running
Springs for a while and I got to know a
lot of these guys and got to know a lot
of these people in the Mendocino
generations and they're it's a really
unique model a lot of them are micro
branding right but then they're still
putting it into the common pot to then
support Arkana
which is their flower right in the
market so it's so it's really cool it's
kind of get that like sort of like
Thundercats transformers model where
like they all come together make this
super thing and then they kiss micro
thing yeah I've been running farmers
markets in Mendocino County for five
years now
we would rent out of a hall and we would
do it below ground and you know it
underground farmers markets and our
original farmers that would come down
from the hills we're coming down from
Thompson and green fields but geo was
one of the original farmers and she was
one of the original brands as well
madrone you know Arkana
Mendocino generation yeah some now
blazing Oaks is working with those guys
like so you're getting a lot of these
farmers that are coming in through three
sisters you know a lot of these brands
that are able to be their own farmers
market booth out of booth space and then
when we come to a larger space come
together and without me otherwise
and that's a cooperative model it's
necessary in all industries that's
another thing that we can teach people
is how to act like like an organism like
actually act like humans right that live
in community existing coexist and move
that model into economy right and start
creating economies of scale that aren't
necessarily scaled large but they're
replicas Blee small and scalable and
that's what and that's what we see with
our kana and it's an actual working
model and and being agile and adaptive
like that it's going to allow them to
survive because what Darwin adapt and
survive right so we are doing that model
and it's funny you mentioned we just had
this kind of became a bit of an
international show and we'll get into
like the vibe on the show from you I
want to hear from both you it's just
it's not your first radio Ricardo it is
so I can't wait to talk on that as well
for this specific event but we just had
some of our friends from Santiago Chile
it came up they just did that at Expo
wheat they're like hey Lance we want to
get you in these five other brands
together and do this a collaborative and
I was like a hundred percent makes total
sense they were all brands that
complemented each other we had similar
messaging and mantras Rick you and I
were just talking most a minute but ago
the culture matters in a company and we
want to align ourselves with other
companies that have this similar culture
and ethic and that's exactly what this
was
see welcome and yeah it was a cost
savings as this is that but the fact
that we had that continuity and we're
all able to co-exist I mean that's again
I agree it should be a more than just we
grow flour it can be meaningful but I
mean also it's it's it's the things that
we can teach one another right but it's
also things that we should just be
learning from other industries so we
shouldn't be teaching it's like you know
you go to consumer packaged goods and
you look what's happening there because
almost all of that will be applicable in
the cannabis industry of the future even
if it's not that way yet so but then we
ask the question this is the question is
it right right should we be learning
from extractive industries that have
destroyed the planet or should we be
teaching regenerative systems to
industries and getting into the policy
see that's the thing as we now
have grassroots policy advocates that
are getting in and changing laws and so
we can change packaging laws because you
know what at the end of the day it was
our survival on the line of whether or
not we were packaging or not packaging
at this I mean I've watched brands
packaged for six months spent all of
their money and then the BCC changes
package and and we as small batch
cultivators can't afford a twenty thirty
thousand dollar packaging head yeah so
we get back in and we advocate and we
write and we become participatory
democracy we can teach industry that we
don't have to roll over for policy we
can change policy to change industry to
become less extractive to the whole and
that's something that cannabis is going
to teach people it's a teacher it's a
plant spirit right so it's taught us for
all these decades how to act right to
the earth how to honor the earth and now
that we're moving into industry now we
have to act right an industry needs to
follow suit because at the end of the
day the parents climate Accord and what
happened with Donald Trump and what's
happening around the world it's it's an
up it's an a cry it's a rallying cry for
humans to start acting in a way that's
in accordance with their mother or get
kicked out like like we're out so we
have to change and I think cannabis had
a larger sense it's like telling us like
please change these other industries
please for the love of all things holy
yeah well and and I God man I hope
you're right and I wish you were right I
think it comes down to how we treat the
plants and how we treat our resources
absolutely but it also comes down to how
we treat our human capital and you know
I think we all hoped that this industry
could be different than any other
industry right and we saw early numbers
like let's just talk about how we you
know were three dudes up here how do we
treat our women partners in this mix and
and and they deserve more because what
is the average number of women in CEO or
ownership positions in traditional
industries it's in the twenty percent
to your point in this industry we were
know and and it has declined every year
the last three to four years and so I
want cannabis to be better I want to
believe that we can be but right now
we're just proving to be to just fulfill
this inevitably sad pathetic destiny of
being yet another industry controlled by
the patriarchy and I will tell you that
you know it is empowering as a white
male in this industry to hand that over
we had Jessica cure our as our CEO per
number a year have not get amazing as
soon as she left like I asked Michael's
girlfriend I was like Theresa will you
please be our CEO like it because we
need that female leadership because
cannabis sativa L you know as feminized
now like in the seedless cannabis is
what we're smoking it's a female it's a
goddess it's what we're so like needs to
be female run an executive director of
Matt Janine Coleman she cranks out like
30 emails before breakfast she's amazing
she's a workhorse that's the type of
leadership that we need because Taylor
Blake Taylor Blake you know yes III was
in on this with it you know watching
Taylor run this pretension yeah Tim
started but tailored jacket you know and
and and and yeah exactly so well yes so
his Desmond's birthday yeah as Desmond's
birthday and and it was Desmond's
birthday and then it became and then and
then you know and then it became the
judge but anyway but yeah so but but but
to say it is I see that is so great the
way though she wants to be handed off to
the female and how the females are
acting so well in the space and it is an
it's teaching me I mean at least I'm
learning so if anybody else doesn't
learn at least
that's a good transition because that's
exactly the last question I had and
again we kind of talked about off camera
but Ricardo came up from Northern
California and you know obviously a
veneer pass as well so this is your
first cup yeah so congratulations this
is not he has been around the block for
years ladies and gentlemen and very much
an advocate for the industry but this is
your first era most cut this kind of
cool so what do you think it is my first
Emerald cup thank you for the welcome
god I will say that this vibe is special
you have to come here to get it I get it
now it's it's it's special it is it is
an expo it is a trade show but it's
infused with this spirit and and and
more than anything even though you know
of course there's the booths like this
one that we'd expect but it still feels
like it's a celebration of sun-grown
cannabis which i think is what tim
started as originally all those years
ago and latent villain yeah I'm I'm I
feel very warmly welcome it's good to
see you my that's great to meet you and
and I can definitely say that I will be
back I'd love to have you back maybe
we'll do a little little tour here there
next time you come up we have a couple
of friends just up the road love to show
you what they have going on and then you
we've discussed this before and that
Mike knows that's why I've been a
supporter of Emerald exchange since the
beginning but you kept in my opinion
living in Southern California and going
to an emerald emerald exchange this is
exactly what I compared it to just
bringing down that culture in that
NorCal vibe sits and you've heard about
this wreck you know norcal socal either
you claim one or the other it's funny if
you're from here it's like you know and
I'm NorCal everyone knows I hate LA I'm
not a fan I just not my the pretentious
the hole so when I went to my first I am
so not a fan of LA and I had to I do San
Francisco in my opinion is the best city
in the country not even the state but
it's efficient you look at LA nobody
drives in LA that there nobody walks
away that's a real song eyes definitions
everyone has to drive compared to here
we're gonna be a rent-a-car Bruna's
six different means of mass transit but
I digress but you you captured this
that's a rich saw it like this is what
school is he's seen it this first year
you captured the energy of NorCal with
5060 small medium-sized growers and you
brought them down to of all places the
Santa Monica Mountains like we're
talking few miles from the Malibu finest
in the richest hoity-toity and how did
you do that like what and how does that
compare to what you've experienced over
the years here so I was doing the the
exchange in Northern California so I was
doing a farmers market with an infused
dinner at night and I was you know you
know doing a banquet style table all
full farm-to-table 100% local within the
within the county and then I was
bringing out brands right mostly it
started with Mexican blankets and mason
jars right and then evolved into of
course bringing in branded you know and
and your neighbor right you know drawing
a really cute logo and getting it
printed and get you know those happen
but um I you know about two years
throwing the event in in the village of
Mendocino yeah and I went down to Malibu
I have a friend of mine who's Jeremy
from San bazan yeah you know so we're
down there sanctuary on PCH having a
conversation and one of our black-market
friends shows up and he starts talking
shit about Sundra and I'm like he's
offering me like $900 and this is two
and a half years ago from you $900 for
og sun-grown pre-bought and I told him
that's bullshit
that he's gonna buy it for eighteen and
love it right and that I asked Jeremy if
there was a way that we could take the
event that we were doing in Northern
California and bring it down to SoCal on
to his land into Malibu and the the
thought was is how do we link a culture
right so it's like do I bring a large
group of humans from Northern California
and put it in downtown LA the large
group of humans
Southern California or do we take a
small group of humans from from you know
the village of Mendocino and from
Mendocino County hills and bring them to
another medicine culture a place where
you'll find teepees in your yards and
where there'll be a peyote ceremony
possibly every other week and yoga and
yoga and and and sound healing all of it
and and so our culture meeting their
culture so as to medicine culture is
actually meeting so coming in and then
you know creating this sort of you know
it's not really a festival it's more of
like a wellness activation so it's like
it's create creating activations you
know instead of just booths creating a
bazaar and then having the brands
actually have yurts and teepees and
tents and air streams and you know and
separating it out and then bring in
having something to do throughout the
entire day but really what it is is it's
that replicable small scalable model
where we were saying we're going to take
these small batch cultivators and go
directly to influencers media businesses
and and investors you know say help us
scale in a small way in a place that can
afford the margins that we need yeah
to do that you did a great job that's
one thing I remember and I was so
impressed by and I think Jessica was a
bit of a force behind this as well but
coming from a digital media background
like Rick that you guys got a lot of
coverage a lot of organic coverage yeah
that surprised me it wasn't just Lopes
pub per se well it's mainstream you want
to sit want a secret huh I'll give this
one over so the original meeting for the
Emerald exchange right that where I met
Michael cast yes actually my
sister-in-law Megan champion she hooked
me up with Michael Katz and then Matthew
from foria and Britney come for Matthews
PR person and we're all at a dinner
hanging out and Matthew is very reserved
I don't
you know Matthew well but Matt he's very
reserved I think things are a good idea
but he's strategic and he's built a
really great brand and a really good
business model and he's great but having
him come in as a sponsor was a little
bit iffy so what he did was he gave us
Brittany his PR person his sponsorship
contribution was Brittany I did talk to
know all of that national media and
local bougie media that foria was
getting then became our media with the
exchange and I hired Luiza and Jeremy's
wedding planner to come on and curate
the original event so we had bougie
media and a bougie Malibu wedding
planner throw this event that was ended
up being the perfect storm and they came
out of the cover to the LA Weekly saying
this farmers market proves that weed is
the new wine and that was it like as
soon as that headline comes out I was
like oui oui
it was a gated box it was amazing but
you had a couple of trustafarians a
couple of the hipsters come up from
Malibu a couple those spoiled kids but
it's cool because like it was it was
even just the gas it was the people
attending that kind of kept him in check
like they kind of came in with this la
attitude and I remember people like
they're sitting somewhere and kind of
being rude to someone they're like no we
all share the table yes it's not your
table my table this is our table here's
like oh yeah you talk about the Malibu
Gold guy idea was you know is that we
hand select and curate our attendees we
don't just broadcast it out we are
influencers then invite their friends
that they want to see and meet the
farmers yeah so it's not like we're just
hey guys want to come to an event it's
like you know hey more than that hey you
know you should really tell a couple of
your close friends because we like you
maybe you know I can pitch up and get
this guy to come out oh yeah no you need
to come down as for what yeah and if he
has an office out there now yes excuse
come visit I have a guest room just
saying that's so well I want to thank
both you guys I mean this is we're in
the final hours you can hear all the
teardown noise in the background here
but I really really sincerely appreciate
you guys both taking the time which was
just us catching up his old friends in
the hallway taking the time to catch up
with us here so thanks again thank you
yeah
[Music]