she says tell me a little bit about what
you do so ok who are you what do you do
hi my name is Steven Rae's 'nor are a is
n er and my company name is potent P ot
ent ponics P o n is and I work with
aquaponics aquaponics is using fish and
fish waste to provide nutrients for
plants to grow this allows us to use a
lot less water and a lot less nutrients
than traditional farming methods how
does it work with low water how you use
the fish farm so we use significantly
less water by recirculating all of the
water from the fish tanks so none of the
water goes into the soil and into the
ground where it's not available again
for the plants this also helps in
extremely hot environments because the
plants have a lot more water available
so for places like deserts or island
nations where they have a lot of heat
with not a lot of water it can be a
great way to grow up both vegetables and
medicine plant medicinal plants
what filter do you use we use a separate
called a radial flow separator or a slow
pass-through filter that allows the
weight the fish waste to the heavy fish
waste to settle to the bottom as the
water flows through the chamber where it
can be then separated and vacuumed off
the bottom put into a separate tank and
turned into a compost tea of sorts to
unlock the nutrients from that fish
waste in a similar manner to what
happens in soil with animal compost
hydrogen and the fish waste oso4 pH and
the fish waste fish castings using worm
castings she says in there or is it just
fish waste fish water or other elements
to it or yeah how they're similar yes
okay so so she was asking how fish waste
is similar to terrestrial creature waste
so in the soil you have the terrestrial
or soil food web in aquaponics we use
the aquatic or water food web and this
allows us to unlock those nutrients the
same way that they would happen in soil
just using different species of microbes
do you have to add anything to it to the
the water for the fish or for the plants
or is it a a good standalone media so so
you do have to add iron and adjust the
pH with things like calcium or potassium
just to maintain stability but you you
don't have to add very much
she says something I would love to try
that methodology one day mmm yeah it's a
great it's a great gardening method and
provides a lot of different options and
much faster plant growth plants can grow
almost twice as fast in using aquaponics
she says saves a lot saving water is a
big thing yep very important a lot of
water to feed plants and she says it can
be exhausting did you imagine everybody
just using up all the natural resources
of water she says I mean that's the way
a future if it stands the way it is
absolutely that's why we need to work
together of soil organic growers and us
aquaponic growers and you know we're all
on the same team of less water and more
sustainability keep it simple absolutely
look to nature look to nature well thank
you so much thank you very much for your
time we appreciate it
I appreciate it if you had to come up
with a a body language for hydroponics
what would you imagine in your head
well you paint that picture like
like water plants maybe a fish swimming
into can you do can you do like his
because you have it's a water solution
with the nutrients so you have the or
maybe nutrient water plant or is that
too much like to watering the
yeah
like exploding fish
[Music]