all right so tom sent the sos distress
call out because when i was here two
weeks ago
all these buds were looking beautiful
and
uh and not so much anymore so we called
our ipm specialist
sawlin to uh come help us
out so yeah and everything kind of went
south very quickly i went away for
literally
overnight to go visit or grow in las
vegas
got back and noticed right away
the next morning that there was
something wrong
and i don't i didn't know what it was
and it
and um it it was
then quickly rampant let me tear
tom bring the camera over here we'll
we'll tell you exactly what it is
and this is what remember what i grabbed
last time that one caterpillar
so look yeah you can come over here and
see his buddy over here
wait tom first look do you see this one
what's that right there right there
right
and then his buddies hanging out over
there where's the other one
or of the many right here
oh wow that one's huge
tom that one is a fat caterpillar that's
that's gorging itself and then the other
clear
sign they're turds everywhere
um let's look around and you'll see them
there um
as they feed they just put their drops
oh yeah there's a little black uh
yeah yeah pretty much um you can see
them on many of the buds
so what is this that we're looking at
what are the what are these uh
we're just looking at some caterpillar
signs and symptoms
okay um here's some more
very likely that would be chewing damage
yeah um
but you can see it basically where we
where we see our our foe
over here where is this guy where'd he
go where did he go
um i thought he was up here he's been
roaming around here he's been laying his
turrets
right here right here and he's been
chewing everything here you see all that
chewing damage
does it take just one to do all this
damage you i've i've seen two in a bud
yeah but um when you see this damage
it's not long before you find them if
you just start looking for them
and so you go you look for this here
looks like chewing damage and then you
look for their turds right
we already saw what those look like um
you see that they're not far
there's a great picture of a of a
caterpillar
feces right there we're right where
exactly that leaf right there really
that's what that is
let me get this huge guy where's the
huge one
here's some more feces
there looks like it
look at that this guy has his head
buried into the uh
right into the middle of the of the bud
here's something to shoot at
which one their feces isn't always dark
brown dark brown there's some lighter
colors too
okay so let me take a picture and then
dark down here too you see that
all this you see these all that right
there all the dark stuff doesn't all
have to be
dark brown ah they're sometimes almost
orange or even
yellow yellowish brown
some fresh poo as valen as my daughter
tells me
yeah chewing damage poop
look around and you'll find them and
it's it's important uh
as soon as you see them um oh look here
look here here's what i meant
that's two different colors oh look at
the broad colors right there
okay so let me take a picture of that
and they're dried they look like yeah
so that dries it can range it can range
anywhere between those
those colors there
here's a bunch more right here it's
actually looks like pellets
wow yeah
easiest way they were i saw them but i
didn't know what they were yeah i mean
the easiest way to distinguish
i don't know if you can see that here
come over here easiest way to
distinguish between slugs or snails
and caterpillars because they do a lot
of similar chewing
oh so the feces is the species is
caterpillar and slime trails is
slugs and snails can you see that
perfect
that's awesome i hope i can get that
from you yeah
okay so so is that pretty much the main
problem we have going on here i mean do
you see other
um well actually these are this is all
poop everywhere right yeah yeah
it's a it looks like bud rot right yeah
did you one question asked is what was
the weather like before you
left was it overcast and kind of muggy
or
not particularly it was uh you know out
here it
hit that the 117 it was super hot a
couple of weeks ago
super hot yeah yeah and uh just a few
miles from here it hit the 121 in
woodland hills
yeah we did have you know and yesterday
it was 10
5. one of you know so it's been triple
digits and
but that was extreme heat and uh shortly
before i left
the praying mantis have been slacking
diamond i assumed they they would show
on the caterpillars
they would yeah if they're big enough
because i've been so i mean i
tell you i did get a little complacent
because i had like two praying mantises
in here they were all over so it's
interesting because when we were here
uh two weeks ago i saw a caterpillar and
i
took it off i found one the other day i
took it off but i didn't i obviously
missed
so so some of some of this could come
around this side because the camera's
right
there so some of this could be partly
because of the caterpillar
right so bud rot
or gray mold is botrytis scenario
it's a fungus that affects all kinds of
different plants
um strawberries and grapes being other
big crops that
it's actually a big problem um
and usually it's something that
appears or shows itself
once you've got ripe fruit or in this
case ripe flowers right
um they have you know been growing and
their sugar content's high and
that's exactly what botrytis can grow on
but but it's a it's a disease and that's
that's not all well i was getting that
the caterpillars will wound
the tissue and spores find it easier to
get
into the plant tissue and and germinate
right right so that's a very common
cause of
of bud rot so they're almost symbiotic
in a bad way
yes i've been creating the environment
for the for the yeah
yeah so you're seeing bud rot and
caterpillar damage you're seeing
i'm saying yeah well i mean it's tough
to see the caterpillar damage
on the buds themselves because it's just
a hole you can't really see
you can pull that guy out and you can
see that you'll see the hole get rid of
this big one
no let me uh do you have a knife or
something to
what about that uh
here hold this yeah tom goes into his
tool kit
well what about the scissors sure yeah
yeah i want to show you something i see
here
i don't know if uh i don't know if i
could go back in time here
but tom did you cut a piece of these
flowers off right here
it looks like you uh uh yes
is that where you first saw it uh
probably or on this planet
look through the viewfinder when you're
talking yeah
that was the one thing i noticed from
the steve cantwell videos that i'm i'm
steve you wonder
no i'm saying but you're you're probably
went off a little bit
you're like you're like holding it over
here or talking oh yeah
um yeah all right so here so you found
two
two specks of it here right yes and then
you came in with a
brown and it knife right off it pulled
right off yeah so
yeah but it was already infected right
so
some people are of the mind cut it if
i'm close to harvest and i can keep
what's below some are the mind
you know cut it down low eliminate
another source of the spores especially
if you're early
right like you are now you know so or
what you were right
i tried early on but i realized i mean
it happened so fast within literally a
day through the view
i know within a day of the viewfinder
that damn
that it was out of my out of control
yeah i i didn't know what to do because
oh it's it's quick
yeah it's quick i've seen yeah it's like
with any disease i mean um
you guys guys my question is for
something this is obviously not a large
grow if you do see it what do you do
uh so what do you do when you see it
basically i can do is what we call
roguing you know you remove
tissue that's about what you can do if
you find a caterpillar in here
you're going to look down below you see
all these turds that drop down
on all these buds below could have been
he was just feeding up here looks like
he was feeding up here
but all these all that feces that
dropped onto these very right flowers
and then given the right conditions
those contain spores too
i mean if he had been feeding on them at
that not just that
you know they begin to decompose the
tissue around where they land it also
begins to decompose it's usually that
combination of like
something wet and the caterpillar feces
and then it it blows up so get rid of
that cola
and if that's where it started and do a
major so can we do this so looking
because
obviously those are much worse these
have um
sort of been trying yeah to maintain
themselves so
are these too far gone honestly um yeah
you can still save this for extract
um there's you know you'll get some
extract there
but uh but get in there every
hour that passes stand right there every
hour that passes is
lower yield right right because you're
not gonna get much out of these dried up
uh
you know sections yeah pieces of flour
so basically if you start noticing it's
almost like you want to chop early to
save what you have it may not be perfect
but
yeah yeah i mean if you could afford to
you could
um like what we would do where i
where i managed ipm is
you know it was kind of susceptible
strains were susceptible to this
this fungus so you start seeing it
blowing up on
um a particular particularly sensitive
strain
um you would uh see i'm gonna take a
picture you might harvest that early for
you know for fresh frozen so say you
haven't seen any of the bud rot um but
you've seen a couple of the caterpillars
um what is there pest management we can
do
to to sort of uh keep these caterpillars
oh yeah yeah there's there are lots of
strategies
the caterpillar at this stage that we
saw there there's not much else other
than
picking them off because the materials
that
you might use at that advanced stage
aren't allowed
in california cannabis right which are
what
um just substances they're natural
substances called spinosads
um a number of products have them it's a
stomach
neurotoxin for uh for insects
the insect chews on plant
material that's been sprayed with it and
it it
basically poisons itself right so that's
something you'd want to do during veg
when it's yeah yeah i mean you would you
can't though it's not
it's not totally illegal so um
the other you know this is
this could be done this could be done
when it's just starting let's put it
that way
and if and if you see big caterpillars
you're not going to get them with the
other strategies the only spray strategy
you might have with a big caterpillar
is to spray spinosads which we can't and
that's kind of a question that tom was
asking is what can we do at this stage
when you found it
um what about if you first see a
caterpillar yeah
that's your that's where the answer lies
okay okay is
um if any of you heard the other
uh video or streaming that we stream
that we did
you probably you probably recognize that
i'm big on monitoring right
so you need to know what caterpillars
and their adults look like and when
they're present
as soon as possible so that usually
comes in
in in catching the flying adults right
so males and females
will meet up with each other they'll fly
male will
you know mate with the female female
will go off and lay eggs
right so if you're so good about
monitoring for moths
right you catch that before all that
exchange has gone on right right
so and then what like you you might so
you see them how do you prevent those
them from laying their eggs out so you
you trap
right um there's very little you can you
can do to like reduce their numbers
um but it's really important at that
point to identify the species that
you've got right and it's hard to do it
from looking at the mobs
all right so for instance that one is uh
do you see it
that one looks like it's like the
cornier worm right
so would this be like the white moss
that i see flying around everywhere is
i think it is a white moth i'm really
bad at uh moths and butterflies
but um yeah i think it is it's like it's
not like a monarch butterfly
oh no wait it isn't it's a bra i'm sorry
it's helicoverpa
zaya and i think it's a brown one let me
uh so i have a question like
looking up here at at all of these up
here
um did were the caterpillars hitting
each one of these or is there is there a
disease i don't think so
i don't think so if this is you know
botrytis it does look
very dried up and then yeah usually it's
you know there's something going on
within the plant usually yeah the
botrytis has actually entered the plant
not not the whole plant but the tissue
that's affected
now maybe um the botrytis flared up on
you because of some
some climate event like some humidity or
something that happened but then after
the heat this is
this could be why you got all this quick
browning yeah you know because the
tissue was dead already yeah um you just
probably weren't aware of
of the symptoms i mean we'd have to we
have to break some of these buds open so
that you could see what although there
is a lot of caterpillar damage so
a lot of this could have been from them
yeah so this was not just caterpillars
although geez i'm finding
lots of feces yeah and i didn't think
that one
should have had any
so basically you're seeing a one-two
punch of botrytis
and caterpillar yeah yeah um
it's a disease that here's
this for you another seed
what's that a seed nice yeah so there's
a disease and then there's
i guess effectively what you might call
it the vector although it's not really a
vector it's there's
what's causing a uh a susceptibility to
the plant
and then it's the the caterpillar is
injuring it yeah
right but back to monitoring if you if
you can id
moths those are going to come in earlier
right
so mods are hard to control there are
strategies but
um they're very difficult for the ones
that are normally attacking cannabis
but that could be the trigger for
certain applications for example
the the um bti have you heard of bti
bacillus thuringiensis good idea
also let's uh there's these plants over
here while you're talking all right i've
got a few more yeah you see uh
you're getting it here it's just
starting yeah
and here you don't see the chewing
damage
might be some here but i doubt it
although i'm seeing
feces right here that looks like feces
i would say a good chunk of it is
because of that feeding i mean these
they seem to be in a lot of your buds
like right there
so there was a caterpillar here at one
point feeding
it it's possible it's it's a primary
reason huh
i mean i've not seen i can't find them
either that's the other part yeah that's
caterpillars
yeah yeah but yeah there's quite a bit
if you look in here
that's a clean flower right there right
more or less
yeah but it's just been completely shat
on
um and yeah so any humidity change
any injury just the fact that you have a
little fermenting
um little compost pile of caterpillar
turds
on tissue that's already well advanced
and
nearly ripe close to harvest you know
it's
it's setting yourself up for another
site where
where the fungus can blow up on you
right right
and then the spores from this plant here
looks like this cola pure you cut back
too right
yeah you took it you chopped this one
off too
when you first saw it yeah yeah so he
started up
it started up here can send it that way
you have more injuries or really soft
tissue and then you get the
right weather conditions and now you've
spread it that way
it sounds like once it's it's spreading
it's kind of hard to uh yeah yeah
yeah very difficult um there's really um
i mean this one looks actually well now
there's the bud rot yeah
yeah top cola and what's interesting
what we've been finding a lot of is
almost every diseased even the the
kind of the less diseased buds are
covered in caterpillar
if you see so i at this point i
i might say it's the main reason i mean
it's any flower that's got any
meaning the caterpillar just overwhelmed
it and then the detroit the
we only found those two but that was a
quick glance and um
yeah it's uh that's what i'm saying i
mean i've been out here every day
looking for caterpillars
to find them you saw they're green
it's like a grow where you only have a
couple plants they're not like all
bunched up it's not
hot and humid and no air circulation
you know there's there's there's also
strain susceptibility so
are you are you aware with the disease
of the disease triangle i've heard of
that before it's this concept that was
developed
related to disease um implants but it's
the same for humans
um disease disease triangle consists of
it's a way to explain how disease
happens how it proceeds and how it can
damage you economically right there's
three components to it the first
component is the presence
of whatever pathogen so
come out of the heat come out of this
good idea whatever pathogen we're
talking about right
in this case it would be actually
botrytis scenario
right um spores could be the presence
but there's also what are called
sclerosia and that's it's uh
near the end of the season it goes into
a sort of like a hibernation type
you know suspended animation uh
basically it's a survival structure
and then that structure can stay in the
area
and once again germinate in the right
conditions
when there's on in the next crop you
know what i mean
it can survive on plant debris it can
survive
on rich soil i mean it can survive in
rich soil
so it's just waiting there to germinate
again so
the presence is is uh one of those
components of the disease triangle
obviously then there's the susceptible
host
right so that's where i was getting here
this is obviously a susceptible host
it's a problem in all cannabis
production
grape grapes also it's a problem in many
you know vineyards in strawberries it's
also a problem in
strawberry so we're talking about hosts
that
will can be parasitized by the fungus
right and
and yeah um if we think about it we've
got
different susceptibilities right
there's a in the vineyards for example
there are a couple grapes that are very
thin-skinned varieties
that are much more susceptible to
the botrytis sponge they call it bunch
rod and vineyards
versus a loose uh versus a hard skin
grape
right that has you know tight tight
little
berries they're less susceptible um
they're not it's not as easy for the
fungus to penetrate the tissue
so varietal differences in grapes make
it make a difference well guess what
they also do in cannabis i don't know
what strains you have here
but if you have those susceptible
strains
you you can see the difference between
you know
five percent and one strain let's say
and thirty percent
in another string yeah right so strain
is big uh we still don't understand that
very well
um mirror implore cannabis
growers to take notes so are there
certain pests like you say even just for
a small home grower like this that i
might want to keep around to sort of
counteract the butterflies or the yeah
let me get to that so the last component
of the disease triangle is actually
um the environmental conditions for
the disease to infect right
and basically the concept of this
disease triangle is
you have to have all three of those
components present
in order to have disease or have disease
that's
economically you know problematic
right if you can break with one if you
can control one
you can control the disease right right
so if you had if we had a cannabis
strain that
was not susceptible to um
to you know to this uh to the fungus
zero percent susceptibility and you grew
only that guess what you broke that
triangle there you eliminated a
susceptible host
right um another
part of susceptibility we talked about
it the chewing damage
caused on the on the uh on the flower
being a an area where the fungus can
infect and get to the tissues easily and
quickly
and feed on it and sporulate and pretty
soon
destroy that bud right so if you don't
have that damage
then you've not you've made it less
susceptible whatever host it is so you
can see how you can focus on these
areas so the big one for botrytis
honestly is
is environment um environment is
uh by far the largest uh the most
important part of that disease
uh triangle so how would you evaluate
this environment that doesn't look
too tight let's put it that way but what
i mean by that is
fungus likes humidity yeah fungus like
likes a certain range of temperature if
you
grow plants too tight uh two the
canopies are too
yeah you're not you won't allow for
airflow right
we were talking about botrytis and
grapes the two susceptible grapes that i
that i was talking about the
thin-skinned ones also have very very
tight bunches
right so if a spore gets in there
there's no way
to change the environment in that
cluster
to be other than just humid and dark
right and when the grapes get sweet
now it's got food right so you've you've
got this strain that's got a tight
tight cluster formation whereas a loose
one like you see in table grapes
you know how you you you can see every
grape inside the cluster on
table grapes so not as susceptible even
if these plants had been
uh farther apart they still the nature
of these plants was the large leaves
they
were growing abundantly leaving a lot of
shade underneath and probably still a
lot of opportunity
for uh the bugs to uh
be comfortable i mean i've not seen this
before where
every bud seems to have some feces so a
big
i think a big part of it must have been
the caterpillars um but
but uh i mean again what strain is this
do you have
the other this is like uh um
uh what's the high cbd strain it's it's
a high
cbd cross bite with an alien uh
fire um so we know each other
we know even less about steve but what's
interesting is these are these are two
different cultivars so
all these over here are one but those
are all autos that are totally different
mm-hmm and this this one that over here
that was simply destroyed
that was an auto now these here are
newer ones
and they haven't been quite uh affected
yet these are our younger plants this
one however
you're not yes that's probably not going
to go very far yeah and you've already
got it there that won't go very far i
think
and i think i can see in here the
caterpillar
never mind yeah yeah you've got quite a
bit of feces down here
so and you got quite a bit right there
so wow
well how about those okay so what what
keeps the caterpillars back what's our
yeah so okay well i wanted to i wanted
to talk about that disease
triangle just because you know then
you're just where do you sit on this you
see the impact of the
of the caterpillar right it's making the
host more susceptible right
sit on the couch so obviously uh just
destroying that particular component of
the disease triangle
is uh you know is going to be helpful to
ending the disease or keeping it from
hurting you economically right
so what's the strategies well we talked
about monitoring that's the foundation
all right you want to know as early as
possible
right you have a you have an insect
who's going to lay eggs
they're going to hatch or we're going to
want to feed you've got some time before
that happens to
to put in some control out um action
for for caterpillar um so
fastest the earliest sign would be when
the adults are flying into your grow
right so monitoring for the moths is
super key right it's it's very very
important
there's a lot of ways to monitor for the
mods but when you see them
you can begin initiating actions
that don't even require for the larva to
be out and about yet
right such as um you can be
you can start your bacillus
thuringienses i was saying bti
it's a another it's a bacteria that um
when the caterpillar
feeds on it it grows in its stomachs
and it's stomach in the um so so would
that be like a foliar spray or something
or spray yeah so you put it what like in
water and yeah it would be a
foliar spray right you see you see the
mic wouldn't i have used that i mean
why wouldn't someone just use that
anyway as a precautionary measure well
you know there's philosophies about not
wanting to spray for
any number of reasons right um you know
there's there's
there's disease and there's potential
for burn and then there's
there's expense you know every spray is
labor and material
right there are a number of reasons why
not to but you make a very good point
this this particular bacteria is
specific to caterpillars
it really doesn't it doesn't really hurt
any other insect or any other animal so
it's pretty safe for other life eaters
like an aphid wouldn't really be
affected by that that's interesting no
not at all
um it's it's specific it's a it's i
guess you couldn't call it a disease
it's it's a disease specific for
caterpillars well for me in particular
knowing that i really have a caterpillar
problem back in this yard it might make
exist
maybe it's all the dog food and you can
decide you know yeah
absolutely um i'm where um i've been
working with some um
cold crop growers in salinas and right
now salinas and
other people say cold crop cold crops
like uh
cabbage that kind of stuff okay
[Music]
the salinas is going through a big
problem with diamondback moth
and they're using these sprays for the
caterpillars and some of the growers
have sprayed
geez um like a dozen times you know
where they would have only
done three sprays in the in in previous
years
and it's just this real big problem and
there will be years where certain
caterpillars are going to be more
problematic than others
but you're right if if you kept up on it
early enough
you can put those sprays out and what's
important to know about those sprays is
the caterpillar has to feed on them but
once the caterpillar is advanced in
other words
far along on its development one of the
later larval stages
they're not they're not as susceptible
anymore to it so like our friend right
here would be an example of
he would probably yeah he would just he
would eat
the the bti gemma can you be our
caterpillar model can you show
can you just put your hand out thank you
yeah he would eat the bti and then just
uh give you the finger that is
some caterpillar okay so so all right so
earlier so there aren't like okay so
what else what other example what else
can you do so
so when the caterpillar's young and it
feeds on this stuff
that's when it gets them okay so you if
you can put that stuff out right about
when they're hatching
so i saw yeah we saw some pretty small
caterpillars about two weeks ago so that
would have
been it you could apply like four weeks
ago we should have sprayed if you had if
you had known
right the week before that and had
started here had some eagle eyes
on the uh well we saw them i just didn't
i would have done all of them yeah
i didn't know time was speeding up i
mean instead of instead of
yeah that's what i'm here for all right
you were feeding
them um but yeah you know that's that's
strategy there's more good to it than
bad
the usually the formulations for that
bacteria
aren't really dangerous in sprays so
they're very safe sprays and you know if
you're doing it everything the right way
and you get those on early enough and
you can't just do it once and expect it
to
to work you know you've got to come back
at whatever the label recommends and
and just just know i i can't find the
eggs i don't know where the tiny larva
are they're really difficult to find
they're green
they're smaller than most of the leaves
so you're not gonna find them always
they're
they're in there they're chewing if they
chew on this if they just happen to chew
on a leaf that i sprayed with this
then they're toast and control can be
achieved now before that
that part like keeping like even trying
to do something so that you don't have
to spray
would that be just limited to like
trapping the moths or because i'm
outside
mass trapping for mass trapping for um
for moths
is is really that i know not a really
good strategy for control
because they can fly in from everywhere
but if you want to dive in a little deep
um there are pheromones and you know
what pheromones are right they're what
males or females emit to attract the
other sex
for mating um there are so um all moths
this is how
females attract males through pheromones
right and they they
they could be miles away even and the
male can pick up the scent
right well for some of some moths
not many and actually none
yet that i know of that that hits the
cannabis plant but but
you know we never know when one of these
mods that i'm talking about will start
hitting us
we've been uh scientists you know
have been able to synthesize
these pheromones in the lab and then you
can use something that's called the
mating disruption so if you take the
synthesized pheromone
you put it in your farm you put it you
know you distribute it through your farm
and you have this huge cloud of
pheromone
like a like a million or like a trillion
females are in that field
that would attract all the males it'll
attack track the males but the strategy
is where is she
he's blind and there's this huge cloud
that he uses himself to guide himself
directly to where she is oh so so if
there are
females you scrambled his radar
everywhere and he can't find the female
so he can't mate
yep that's called mating because where i
thought you were going is like you know
when i was growing up we always had
beetle traps where you have the
pheromones too which attract them and
they go into the trap that they can't
get out of and you have a thousand in
there the next day
there are some some pests where that
really works effectively i thought you
were going well you'd put the
uh pheromones near a pigeon and then so
they'll start mating with pigeons and
you know
another interspecies yeah yeah
anyway but yeah but
like i said as i said there's there
aren't very many
species where we have these pheromones
for um
we do have a few i know um i used to
battle
light brown apple moth in in herbs
and there happened to be a mating
disruption pheromone and that's exactly
one of the arms of the strategy we used
um as as well as the the bt sprays
well it sounds to me well let me ask
this have you seen
something of this decimation scale
in a in a commercial grow recently um
the odd part is is i can't find the
caterpillars
but i can see all their feces in there
so they're crafting
it's about looking i'm sure there's more
i mean it took me about what two minutes
to find two of them right yeah
can you go find us some more
caterpillars
look look in the fluffy flowers
yeah so again i don't think mating
disruption is a good strategy for
cannabis because we just don't have
you know we barely know which
caterpillars are gonna hurt us and the
ones that are hitting us i don't believe
we have
maiden disruption so you've got is that
pheromone applicable to all different
butterflies in moss or like only one
species specifically
so you know it's not even it's not even
family specific you know like insects
have fat
so so you'd really need to know which
one is infecting your plants
so like that was corny or worm right um
but what's the strategy there okay well
um that there's nothing specific for
coronary worm
um but but we'll get to the bio control
also okay
so so the pheromone wouldn't work for
chronic cornea worm
but the bt toxin would work right right
um what else is available then you can
talk about
you know um macro you know predators
beyond just the bacteria that's a micro
predator right it's a parasite of the
of the caterpillar right um there are um
what are called
um the parasitic wasp the uh the
okay trichogramma wasps yeah have you
heard of these yeah so
um wasps are really interesting um order
of insects in that they're
very commonly parasitic their lifestyle
is parasitic so i'm sure you've heard of
the tarantula hawk
and how it it'll inject its eggs into a
tarantula and then the eggs the
larva will eat the tarantula from inside
out new
adult hatches right or emerges right
right um
there happen to be small teeny wasps
the yeah they're actually programmable
right the same thing with
uh yeah except except that they inject
their eggs
into the moths eggs so they'll search
for and find the cluster of eggs or the
individual eggs
and inject their egg and then during the
development
so you want so say you were going to do
a wasp
treatment you would want to do that um
yes when you have the food available for
them
when you've got it's they're not eating
right they're not oh yeah no no yeah
it's not a
it's not food yeah yeah they're putting
their eggs they're putting their eggs in
them yeah um
why wait why wait okay have them have
them there
so they will so if you if you bring the
waspsmen they're not going to go away
they're going to stick around they will
go away yeah so that's the thing is
you know they will be they will search
for caterpillar eggs and then if they
find a hornworm egg and it happens to be
one of the ones
that species that likes hornworm there
in your
in your tomatoes then they might just
fly over there
and and work on that and then eventually
get distracted and go look
um but that's the whole point with
monitoring let's say you spot
the adult you you know how to identify
the cornea worm adult right
right that's when you start your bt
sprays but you also start your wasp
releases
okay so and you you guys
breed parasitic wasps so we would bring
a container
and tom would what like just put it like
at the base of the
there's a couple options there's um
there's loose eggs
that you can put and they're not eggs
actually they're pupa um they are the
eggs of another moth
right that was that have
have a mott development what about all
the feces can you tell from the feces
what you're dealing with
it's hard it's really difficult um you
mean like which caterpillar yeah i mean
small feces might mean a small species
of caterpillar but it could also be a
larval
a younger larval stage of a big species
of cattle right whatever
but no the the way to do it and it's
even difficult
it's even difficult collecting um the
you know when you collect the individual
um caterpillars because you know they go
through numerous
stages they mult through their life
stages so
and they don't look identical i have a
slide on a presentation
which has five different looking
caterpillars and i ask people how many
caterpillars do you see here they say
five they say no that's the same one
it's just different larval stages
so you you gotta kind of at some point
you gotta
sometimes have to rely on an expert with
the comments so yeah
not only do you need to monitor but you
need to be ideal
and entomologists because here's the
thing is
those wasps there are different species
of the shrubs and like we rear three
right they tend to target different
species of moths
so if you release the wrong one you
might as well not be releasing it all no
doubt
right so you got to know not just which
ones you have but
which other ones you know you may have
more than one caterpillar
yeah exactly okay so the challenge is a
huge parasitic wasp
only focuses targets one type of
caterpillar egg
no they do cross over to different
things it's just it's just
the research has shown that this
particular wasp
can can control this particular
caterpillar
in these crops whereas this one can't
even though it may
on occasion inject its larva maybe it's
not a preferred
choice for it or maybe just didn't
evolve on that
particular caterpillar and the egg is
not viable
and or the larva dies you know it's just
almost
you know the research had there had to
be a lot of research and you'll often
see where these trichogramma wasps will
all
target one species but there may be one
that's
really good at controlling it right so
that's why you want
to know what you got who are they what's
where
when did they come and and who are they
and you can distinguish
caterpillars not just by their
appearance but their moths
so if you're catching the big dark moth
and you're also catching this little
tiny yellow moth uh that's two species
right well that was going to be my
question do you think tom has multiple
species
of we only saw that that that corn ear
worm
but i didn't but we saw two of them we
saw there's yeah they're the
same species okay yeah so um so
possibly there's another one but it
could just be it could be but we haven't
found it
right right so yeah there could be
although it's not so the cornier species
is there a specific parasitic wasp
species that
love yeah yeah yeah there's uh you know
the trigger grandmas like i said
um i can give you more details on a list
of
you know we have three species of
trigorama of a list of what
which ones they tend to prefer and can
have been shown to control
um so next season
we would be we would bring those out
early
yeah yeah yeah it's always preventative
i mean i
i'm uh i i focus on biological control
right i've been doing
pest management now for six years um
um in different different crops several
different crops
um but the the bulk of those years has
have been
um putting together what what are called
bio-intensive
ipm programs basically they're founded
on on the idea that we're going to try
to control
our pests and diseases with
biological agents such as so that you
that
okay continue but such as bt that's a
bacteria
um these wasps they're also they're
they're also they're insects right um
and there are other predators of
caterpillars too so
so basically anything that's living that
would attack the thing you don't want
whether it's a bacteria
a fungus another bug what about the soil
does it begin there um i mean
soil i mean that that's where everything
starts right
um you know the um
plants evolved in soil right so and we
know that nutrition
and um the right kind of soil but
but something like a caterpillar would
love to eat a super healthy plant well
that's what you know yeah
is a tough one to say that the soil soil
plays a big
big part of it but you know you have
good soil
you can have a healthy plant with better
defenses to fight off
certain things like the botrytis let's
say you had
a flower that was grown in very good
soil
you know and by good it's a broad
definition of what we mean by good which
includes microbiota
right but we're talking also struck
structure of the soil and
you know the food and
as well as the microbiology going on
there but any number of these things
that can
strengthen the plant one of the ways
that the plant is strengthened is by its
tissues
uh it's its cell walls thickening you
know
and what's that mean that means it's a
lot tougher for a disease
to to injure to actually some of these
diseases actually send
what are called these fungal diseases
send what's called an aprosoria
which is like a drill and they'll drill
right into tissue
um into the cell cells of the plant well
if they
like hold on to and just to get in and
start and then start
proliferating inside of it right they
don't even need an
opening for them but uh you know if you
have
uh tissue that's that's more you know
that's that's
tougher right because you took care of
giving it
absolute perfect soil conditions
then you have some level of there's less
susceptibility right and so you've
weakened that one component of the
susceptible
sure makes sense to me yeah a little
disappointed because that was what this
was all about
was you know yeah our trump to really
you know yeah builds really strong well
again this gets back to my question with
is like i don't i think a super healthy
plant a caterpillar would
love to eat yeah sure and and at that
point you're you know you're talking it
um the the
the these things you remember these
things looked amazing
two weeks ago they were just like yeah
that's why
that's why botrytis and and caterpillars
are are a bane
in outdoor growing so okay so so
botrytis is that something that lingers
like doesn't fusarium linger in the soil
so even if you like
clear all your plants out and you plant
again it's just like sweet
yeah um so a lot of fungi will go into
we were talking about earlier the the
state of suspended animation
um you know normally called a survival
skill to have
yeah a survival structure so like
powdery mildew has one
um that it can occasionally at the end
of its life
form one of these structures that keeps
it essentially alive in this structure
ambitious definitely has one and matter
of fact one of the managing techniques
for managing strategies for managing
botrytis and strawberry
is to remove infected fruit
from from the rose so dead fruit from
the rose
when you harvest the harvesters go
through and if they spot both try to say
may i leave it
or cut it into or they may see a
they may drop strawberries that are
infected with protitis well that's a
source
for more botrytis for the well you're
saying they're doing this accidentally
right not intentionally
some sometimes they they cut them to to
squash them and keep them from you know
being at least above the ground
right so others if you ever see a
harvest in a strawberry field it's
riddled with you know dead fruit
afterwards
if you don't get in there and clean it
up soon and you have infection in that
tissue
then you're just risking the next flush
of strawberries right
same thing if you grow outdoors in an
environment where you leave filthy
plant residue after a harvest let's say
you're an outdoor grower and you happen
to be growing in soil and you don't do
something about
the survival structures that botrytis
may have left in dead tissue
you know you you you'll have it there
for next year and it's just waiting for
so so the physical manifestation of
botrytis is bud rot basically right yeah
you got it
that's good that's a good way to look at
it and then what about fusarium what
would be its physical
manifestation that's a number of
different
uh symptoms um
the most common so fusarium is one of
the wilt diseases
right so the plant everyone knows what a
wilting plant looks like
um what's interesting about fusarium is
you know if you have a plant that
that wilted because you forgot to turn
the water on for an hour
and you run out there you turn it back
on it'll it'll pops right back
up but you you won't do that it won't do
that if it's in affected with fusarium
right because
because what fusarium does it it gets in
from the soil
and it um it actually plugs the vac
vascular system of plants right
so even if the water even if the soil is
wet
they just can't pull water up and so
there's just
chronic wilt where they're not getting
the water they need
right that's typical the other one the
other fusarium
symptom would be when a plant dies and
let's say it didn't even die from wilt
you can cut the the base of the stem
usually
usually the further down you go the the
pith the inside
is is is brown it's not the healthy
light green color or
almost you know yellow color it's brown
and soft
right and that that could be
one of these wilt diseases best thing to
do
you know you know we know we know
fusarium
um lives in soil too and that's how it
moves around through the roots
um you know if you have old soil
and it's in there you know you're you're
risking
the next crop right so what can you do
there's a lot of things you can do
right i just that was going to be my
question yeah so
let's think about what the strawberry
growers do they suffer from these wilt
diseases as well
they conventional strawberry growers
will use what's called methyl bromide
have you heard of that
substance that's been it doesn't sound
good it's close
it's it's close to being to being banned
completely but
um if they did my understanding is if
they banned it out right
strawberry the strawberry uh industry
would really suffer
uh because so like everybody's using it
yeah well no no
not everyone's using it but but it's
still it's still something that could i
think
really hurt the strawberry industry if
somebody just organized strawberry
growers no you can't okay
it's a toxic so buy organic strawberries
it's a toxin that's actually fumigated
into the soil
and there are fields out there where if
you didn't do that
within a maybe two cycles you're you're
just losing money you might as well not
climb what is it combating a a rot
the the uh the storage uh the the uh
the survival structures the fusarium in
this oil and
other other soil diseases not just
fusing what um
when apples rot what is it that's
rotting them the
famous oh there are a lot there's a lot
of rotten uh
uh apple rot diseases out there um i'm
not an apple expert but there there's
there's quite a few fire blights a big
one that bacteria
um that that well so how come banana
growers are so
fucked with a fusarium is it like more
vicious once it gets into soil that
bananas are in because it
seems like you're like oh strawberry
growers get it all the time but they're
not like we need to abandon these 10
acres for the next 30 years
not 30 years or like burn the fields not
30 years but they will
they will take breaks and grow something
else because if you just keep it going
you don't
you just don't not allow enough time for
that fungus to those survival structures
to
to you know not you know but i thought
that period is like
years and years and years it's like like
i'll just hang out until you come back
but it depends on the pathogen
right where does fusion feed on it it's
a
it's a bacteria yeah so it's a fungus
that gets
yeah it gets into the plant through um
through the roots makes its way up the
vascular system
feeds on whatever sap is going through
begins to multiply as it grows
it causes clogging of the vascular it's
kind of like i guess
arthrosclerosis kind of yeah i was gonna
say getting like uh
yeah like clogged arteries or whatever
yeah yeah pre-heart attack
wow okay but the good news is tom
doesn't have fusarium in addition to
betraytus
and butter and yeah we wouldn't know but
you know
going back to our conversation we had
last sunday with uh
with chris you know we talked again
about
endophytes and you know relationships
and
you know we we ourselves have all kinds
of
microorganisms living in us right and on
us
you know the the micro flora in some
cases they're beneficial in other cases
they could kill us but
they may not they may just be living in
us
because we have a nutrient nutritional
source for them but they don't
explode to such levels of infection that
they will harm us you know so we could
have all kinds of pathogens in us that
could kill us
and and the way it happens with with
humans is
it's the same thing that happens in
plants is
um some kind of susceptibility is
increase in the human
can be from a stress it could be um
from another disease for example um some
of the
um immuno some of these diseases that
affect the immune system for example
um aids aids affects the immune system
right lupus
and then it's something else that kills
it and then something that was already
in you
that was being kept at bay because
you're mowing yeah
yeah and it pops up same deal so um i
mentioned
a plant pathologist that i've worked
with for years now
um steve koike and he's seen enough he's
seen enough plants now i mean
i've asked him this question a number of
times and last i saw him was about a
month ago and
he he was still wondering about that is
how much fusarium is there out there
we're just not seeing
is it really a problem or is it a
problem
under certain circumstances is
is this host susceptibility do we mean
probably yeah or in humans uh no no in
in plants
yeah so in cannabis specifically yeah i
mean we
found um we found fusarium but it was
interesting uh it was first time i took
it to the lab
uh i think we collected 30 plants that
had symptoms
we sent them in and two of them had
fusarium
you know none of the rest could be
detected by any of the
symptoms i mean steve plated them out
for us
once once it grows a few days it's
pretty easy for any
microbiologist plant pathologist can
identify usually
by looking at the the petri dish it was
grown in right
so you know okay so what's the deal here
these do these have it obvi it sounds to
me like the symptoms in these plants
even though the same as in these two
plants is the same as these eight over
here
um it may not be related to fusarium
right so 30 of the 32 plants did not
have it
even though they all expressed the sound
yeah yeah it was so did they know what
those other plants had
they didn't test you know they had
mosaic appearance of the leaves you've
you've heard about the mosaic viruses uh
you know also affecting the the crop um
they looked like mosaic they did not
have any mosaic he put them through a
panel
of of different pathogens and basically
all he found was
fusarium now this was before we knew
about the viroid so
if that my expression would be hotplate
and viroid
we don't know because at that at that
time
i don't think the viroid um i think
they're called the primers which is
the what you need for the test wasn't
really
commonly available because it was just
kind of we were barely learning about it
i i very clearly remember coming back
from that uh you know from
when we sampled um it wasn't until
months or probably even a year later
when i first heard about the viroid
right and um had you seen what turned
out to be the viroid much earlier and
then when people told you that there was
this viroid and this is what it does you
were like
i've seen you know you know the testing
the heavy testing for viroid
happened after i left
um where i worked and and moved to
beneficial insectary
that was really when everyone started to
really key in on testing and um
some places went out and tested all
their um you know their mother tissue
every single plant and eliminated every
one that
that had the virate in it so it was it
was a it was some time ago that you know
i i learned about fusarium actually
you know potentially being a problem in
cannabis before i learned about the
virus it's like every year there's some
new diseases
oh yeah it's not even every year it's
everything i went in on this cannabis
party too
and fusarium where does it come from
like where would it
come from how would it be introduced it
could also be a survival structure
a mommy and a daddy pusarium have a baby
for cereal
yeah i mean how do they get into your
garden i mean brought in
it could be in there could be that
some other plant here in your garden is
susceptible to it
and there are survival structures and
you were watering your lawn one day yeah
so the same strain of fusarium could be
infecting other plants species yeah well
okay well
um there i know of at least two
i think it's three species of fusarium
that we found
at in our soil right one of them
the one that's thought to be the main
culprit is fusarium oxysporum
and that's the the same one that hits
other crops
like give me an example of another crop
that it loves i like that's strawberries
that's the main fusion but
so basically it's like yeah i mean
that that's like a super disease that
can like you know how
like uh coronavirus it's like
they don't think necessarily cats and
dogs like we couldn't transmit it to a
cat
they can transmit it to a person but
with this it's like it could go from
like
tom's cannabis plant to like the
neighbors strawberries and then like the
next neighbor is growing weed and it's
like what's that like
exactly so you do yes i can find food
sources yeah there's uh there are
there are really interesting
strawberries and wheat and socal
well like fusarium i got one for you in
the middle of the state where you have
all these different
central coasts well you're surrounded by
them um i got another one for you
okay um so so think about this so the um
i was talking about grapes and botrytis
right um
so the grape that the grapes are
typically affected by botrytis are the
pinot noir
and chardonnay grape those are very
commonly that's a very common fungal
problem these are thin skin grapes
remember we talked about that they're
not very
tolerant of very high temperatures so
they could easily get sunburned and
damaged
so that's why they're normal specific
regions
still coastal cool climates that also
happen to have
a high humidity so that they have a very
susceptible host with the thin
cluster thin skins that are clustered
tight and then they have the
the perfect environment and then as soon
as that spore lands there guess what you
have the disease
the triangle components right so
but try this scenario is
yeah yeah at some point there had to
have been some kind of weather
event um i'm pretty convinced it was the
the heat wave because okay how about
this so we have a new batch of auto
babies that i just brought over
so they'll be susceptible yeah
but wouldn't it imply that they need the
same shitty like
weather event yeah but let's think about
this
we can talk about macro environments
right since it's already here
it could easily get to them okay so so
let's talk about the macro environment
right that was behind you as well don't
forget the other we got it everywhere
yeah yeah so there's there's not a plant
that does not essentially there
it's like covered right yeah even in the
white house
okay yeah um have you have you ever
noticed how your biggest
buds that top cola are the ones that are
normally first affected by
botrytis right so you can see it
have you and then second question is um
those were the ones that you were
trimming where you saw it first
right you cut those off because they
were the top bud yeah right
that's usually a really big bud up there
right well we
cut those because tom didn't want the
neighbor to see his gigantic plants so
okay
all right so you injured the plant we
gave it to them gave their botrytis and
entry
but uh but yeah so
what about that micro environment inside
the flower have you noticed that
botrytis starts from
inside the flower right the gray mold
usually i mean i'm not saying it doesn't
on occasion start on the outside tissue
even
even on stems you'll see botrytis
i haven't seen that routinely but i have
seen it
that big flower which is tight um that's
not one
solid piece of plant there's nooks and
crannies in there right
and we're talking about microscopic
spores right so we're talking about a
very
humid environment in there right and
it's also dark and co
and you know so even something like
raising the humidity for a few hours at
the wrong to oh
that that big bud once it's closed up
and gotten tight
that's close to harvest right what
happens to fruit once it
it's closer to harvest it softens right
all of a sudden now that hose is much
more susceptible
because it's began to it started to
decompose it's part of the
natural plant process to decompose
tissues get
thinner and more easy to for the for the
week
fungus what's happening it's weak it's
vulnerable it's weaker
it's softer it's full of sugar it's it's
it's
it's got spores inside it's like a
salmon that swum all the way upstream
and the bear is just sitting there being
like
this is too easy right you got it it's
tired good analogy good analogy so so
each part of these this
triangle can can can give you a
different impact in this case you had
a the susceptible host was caused you
know
if you notice it started on your biggest
buds so the ones that were the ripest
were more susceptible and the
caterpillars came
bit holes into them and allowed faster
entry into the flower and
you you basically you got susceptibility
of hose maybe the environment didn't
have as much to do with it
this time around um you know but there
was presence there of of the uh
of the fungus there was uh
susceptibility
and and the environment had to have been
at some point perfect for it to have
um germinated yeah we did it tom
we're so proud
actually you know this is the biggest
colders the ones at the top were the
last ones they see yeah i don't know
i don't know they were pretty brown up
there well now they are
yeah you you've got i mean i it's kind
of remarkable i don't know
um like to see
i mean how much feces is out there it's
practically every bud have you never
seen have you
is this like the most feces in a like
yeah plant that you've seen my god we
are breaking records
and you've seen a lot of commercial
facilities hey listen you learn you
learn about a really important symptom
and um you know now you know to monitor
for mods early you know okay right
so the recap for next year's start what
what's our prescriptive strategy again
what i do what i do is that your
daughter
gemma yeah give her a quarter for every
caterpillar she brings to you
right and then get everyone and maybe it
is only cornea worm right now you know
now we can use cream sandwiches there
you go
now we can look for what does that moth
look like now you're gonna have to set
up traps probably at some point
right start setting up uh light traps
are a good way you know a lot mods are
attracted to light
um is there a pheromone trap that's like
literally the zapping light
oh any light right mods fly around these
light bulbs right
no no but but you're saying put a trap
out yeah you don't have to put a zapping
trap that'll destroy it but a sticky
card trap or something like that
you can buy moth traps that are based on
glue to you know so
maybe that's a way to do it there's also
what are called the delta traps you may
have seen them the county puts them out
for
different flying pests it's a little
folded looks like a little tent little
paper tent
that's hung in the tree that has glue
all on the inside and it has a little
pheromone which is actually intended to
attract the male now if you capture some
of those moths that'll tell you what
kind of caterpillars you're going to
wind up with right maybe
yeah maybe perhaps maybe well
okay so um i'm never i'm never a sleep
roller
is it a problem in cannabis i've never
heard of any of these
leaf roller families being a problem
in cannabis i have heard of them showing
up and feeding a bit
um right but what's the what's the one
tom has but here
it's a corn ear worm and what what's the
adult version of that called
it's uh this is the same coordinate
cornea yeah it's a corner of moth
current cornea butterfly it's
helicoverpasea what's the difference
between a moth and a butterfly
uh mostly mods are
night flyers mostly okay that makes
sense yeah yeah
but um likewise most most butter i think
that's i mean there's there's
families there's i mean there's there's
i'm i'm really nice yeah i never really
see caterpillars flying around at night
i'm not good at what i call the the
order lepidoptera it's a tough one it's
i mean distinguishing leaf roller mods
from each other
that gave me fits in school um to turn
them over that'll be all training
i'll train gemma in that skill yeah well
so
we we don't know but but we i've never
seen mealybug in in
in cannabis and i've heard some people
say oh yeah i've seen it and
i kind of found it hard to believe it's
like i've never seen it well
that's that's a little bit arrogant um
just because i haven't seen it
um i got a photo of some from texas
a few months ago so maybe leaf rollers
aren't a problem in california cannabis
but
what's it going to do to oklahoma right
so
knowing what's around and what's going
on regional pests
so so what were you seeing a lot of in
in norcal well actually on socal too
you're up and down the coast so what
were you saying
oh so we have what everyone's getting
it's it's not the only one they're
getting
i um actually but like this is
a noticeable uptick in this across
california
from previous years no no
in fact it could could have been a
pretty okay year but
actually the some of the lake county
growers i work with
they they are reporting um
they are reporting a bad caterpillar
like okay lake county
yeah so like the caterpillars are honed
into some different regions so i was at
um a greenhouse operation in salinas
there's a caterpillar
um and you know we found the damage we
found the damage i could see it it's
like okay it's a matter
of time no turds i don't see any feces
at all
just a matter of looking around and
there he was about that long
this is not does not look like a cornea
worm but i'm not positive like i said a
lot of
a lot of these wait is that the one from
here no this is from a grown salinas
like i caught it yesterday
because it could be younger it could be
a younger one
yeah it was bright green it even painted
that you have alcohol greens
vials do you have like hundreds of vials
with different insects in them not
anymore
not hundreds what are you gonna do with
that well so
i'm gonna take it back and i'm gonna
look at it under a scope
and i'm gonna look at features sorry
where where was that one from it was a
selena screenshot
do you need to uh develop a program from
them based on
that it helps because then you can
target to the most effective wasps right
right
right um that that so okay so so by the
way
next season you you need to show up
what's today like october
what are we what day fall apart today
october 3rd so he should have shown up
here like september 1st
for like the ipm inspection slash
strategy you're going to have an ipm
person
but that's true but then coronavirus
because we knew that this was something
we wanted to
yeah we just didn't we did want to have
this yeah like
two months ago yeah or a month and a
half yeah i mean monitoring starts
monitoring starts when you bring the
first plant into your grow and never
ends after that
here i'm going to leave these for you
and uh
i i give i hand these out to some of our
customers what do we just put alcohol in
it or what do you put in just
isopropyl alcohol or and then the bug
and if you find it
catch it kill it if you don't i mean we
live
close so you i could actually get it
from you come pick it up we can show up
here yeah um
but if not if you're far off somewhere
you know another
okay so people send you guys bugs
just just catch it catch it kill it in
alcohol then
stretch it out so it's not moving around
on you and take photos very close photos
very clear photos from different angles
and off not often sometimes it's not
enough um
we've got a really good so what are some
of the interesting
bugs that have come across your radar
recently that that people have like done
that and taken pictures and sent them to
you guys
oh geez there's a lot well i just saw do
you have that scale insect what did that
leaf end up
oh oh it's over on the uh the straw
okay yeah cause um i took pictures of it
while it was uh
would you leave it on the straw over
there yeah but i'm gonna see about
you know taking this thing so what did
you find interesting about that
well there's a scale insect oh a scale
inside yeah
but i think i think i think it may be
dead now actually
because it was it was on green tissue
this was green
put it down i can actually get a i have
i have a photo anyway it's a
it was it was a lot lighter orange color
it's right there that brown thing
i can i took a photo before it
before it met its end
here here's a really good one here oh
wow
wow is that that yep
i'm gonna get a super and what is that
it's a soft scale
i don't know which one yet but what's a
soft scale
it's another insect that sucks
on plant sap and feeds on them
and wow is a problem in
some crops citrus has
the um california citrus scales we
have pathogens within them and it looks
like a little know a lot about
scales you know what it look at this
photo is gonna look like a raisin does
it look like a turtle shell to you
yeah kind of yeah that's what they look
like they're little and what is it
it's a it's a soft scale i don't know
which one oh that's the type of insect
what's like that family common for like
known for
well they'll feed on plant sap right um
but do they become a problem
you don't know enough yet but that's
bran
yes these the adults are the adults can
fly right
um the males can fly i believe it is
mostly but there's they're they're so
small that they'll
be carried on yeah and if there's
females around then they'll mate and um
the females will lay eggs
these these often actually these have a
these actually are have keep their eggs
inside of them so if you flip them over
in fact if you had a scope we could do
it although i think it's fried now
because it's sat in the sun
yeah but um was it so it was alive
before
yeah well look at the color difference
look at the color difference it's this
was a green leaf
like half hour ago right yeah that
thing's been big yeah and um
it's cool it's i probably still have
enough to make some kind of close
identification of it
um but yeah is it right there uh no it
is
where'd it go right here oh there it is
that
yeah it still kind of looks like a like
a a turtle right
but now it's more shriveled wow yeah
good eye man and so you haven't really
seen that
i haven't ever i mean we suspected a
possible
this is amazing i suspect they're
my my colleagues and i had had a few
photos that a grower
sent that we argued was is it scale
is it is it um a seed a seed
that that's uh i'm sure if i went to a
scale
expert they'd be able to id that
that's that's an okay photo right there
you can see that's
that could be this little dot here could
be where it's uh
where it's waste drops out of general
we're looking at bugs
so yeah so i will take him let's see
what i mean is
if i don't get him i can't positively id
him because i
haven't seen him or her it's actually
her
um gemma who gave you the ipad
is laura the best host ever so so
so tom look around for more of this huh
yeah look around for more of this
because
yeah yeah text me that picture yeah
and i'll send you uh these ones it's not
difficult right
no not at all all right little yellow
turtle all right so
tom had let's recap again tom had
betrayed us
you're rubbing it in now now you're
rubbing it in you had the scale bug
right yeah which again we don't know if
this is even a problem right could have
been a confused
but you've never seen it before so not
this no even if it's not causing
problems it's never been seen
no yeah but we're so new at this right
i'm sure i'm sure someone else has seen
it
oftentimes they'll see it but not be i'm
just saying like it hasn't been
like if you've never seen it it hasn't
probably been commonly seen like maybe
one guy's seen it a couple times so that
bodes well right if if no one's seen it
and you find one
uh there's uh there's a a bug that is
particularly like what what's the last
thing that's kind of been like the uh
what's the asian wasp like the big
garbage
that's what's it called yeah the that
like the killer killer wasabi
but anyway like something where someone
saw the first one and then it's like
shit like i guess it would have to be
you know
most recently was that the cannabis
aphid you know
that that blew up uh so i
i heard about it and again i'm like what
what was the last year no one talked
about it
no one talked about it in in salinas
because
keep in mind tiny area that i worked in
nobody talked about it um let's see not
18 we saw it um
17 sometime around 2016. sometime around
2016 nobody was talking about
and then suddenly like some people were
talking about no no oregon and colorado
and um it had been described it's not
like it got discovered on cannabis it
it um it's a hemp aphid you know it
evolved
on hemp but were oregon growers and
colorado growers seen it even earlier
than 2016.
you know i don't have to go back and
sort of notice that i'm not i'm not
great about exactly when it happened but
there was
there was a bulletin sent out by the the
oregon department of agriculture to all
the cannabis growers
they legalized a little earlier right um
they they're
that hey this is a passive cannabis be
wary of it
um it it got to salinas like i said the
first infestation i experienced was
in 2018 we were
at first it was difficult to figure out
what to do about it
now we have some strategies how
problematic was it at first was it
destroying whole crops
that's a problem is we never we never
took the data and that's again i want to
stress that
is we really really need the growers to
get diligent about that
um there was like reporting it yeah
there was a situation where that first
infestation
hit me it was about probably an area of
about 500 square feet
that it was a mess it was a total mess
and i begged that we harvested it
earlier so it wouldn't spread to the
rest of the crop
in the end we were able to contain it to
one area but it was bad
um it was really really bad um where to
the point where
they crawled off of i mean it looked
like an army crawling off it when it was
um where it's drying
uh where when we were drying the buds um
they crawled off
and you know i i that's right right when
i left harbor side
and i said hey i beg you
check the potency and yield on this
please you know but unfortunately nobody
went that next step and said hey let's
go let's look at what this aphid in this
extreme situation
did to this bud i mean we're not going
to know what it what potential it had
you mean did well that's what i was
going to say was there a baseline of
like
no but you could rest itself this
amazingly last
where's that you could you could compare
it to the rest of that crop in that and
the different maybe there was a the same
exact strain in the same exact
greenhouse
but in another corner it's like years
and wine grapes right
like there are certain years that are
like yeah exceptional years and the
bottles reflect that in their price
yeah some some like that i guess yeah so
but you know that would have been a
great one where
okay take good record of the yield of
that particular strain
and then do it again the next time you
grow that strain and then do it once
you know keep them under you know keep
them from being attacked maybe put
special
special um you know more resources into
keeping
that strain from being attacked and then
now grow on where you have okay i had a
successful crop with it here
and compare your yields per square foot
and compare your potency
in the flower and then if you found
a drop in one percent yield
and half of a percent of potency was it
a problem
it looked ugly right and yeah it made it
stick around in your garden in your grow
and it moved to other crops so yeah
that's a problem
but how problematic is it really how
damaging is it's just
really early although at a certain point
you know we know in other crops
aphid infestations when when you see a
plant covered with aphid that can't be
good
right but how many are tolerable right
we just don't we just don't know the
resources
what is that the point of like some
pests is good lots like of a species
like having a couple aphids like
i wouldn't use good but like not
negative let's put it this way and then
like but having a ton
is obviously the nature's typically
balanced right you don't see
massive infestations you know well
unless like somehow humans might have
been you know interfered but you do see
them on occasion but
nature balances itself right populations
of predators
climb with the populations of the pests
pest populations drop
off populations of predators drop off
it's a sign it's like my compost bin
where like
there's a food source outside my house
where there never had been one
and now black soldier flies are like
and they're larva i mean it's like
millions of or not millions but like
hundreds of them in in like in my worm
bin they're in there too the worms
aren't very they're just like
i love those guys i gotta tell you i
gotta tell you a story sometime about
those because i was i was planning about
worms or black soldier flies surge of
fry larva yeah
and cannabis i love them but they keep
the the larva keep finding their way
under the the floorboards into the house
and so
my wife sees like these larva crawling
across the floor
and that is i was i was growing them
indoors myself and i would
like when i see them i'm like sweet like
let me release you outside yeah
that's cool do your job and she's like
the fuck but yeah
it's it's like that's something's gonna
come you plant something
something's going to come and you know
we've you've made something artificial
here right
um some of the pests it's less
artificial than just the grass though
it is yeah it's getting back to but
you've brought a a non-native plant
into this environment it's true and who
was here waiting
corneirwin was here waiting susceptible
all the native
pests that have been waiting for worm
was probably
around here for since you bought the
house you know it's been here forever
where has it been feeding i don't know
maybe your neighbor has some corn or
uh oh does it love corn yeah okay
yeah they're critical it actually likes
corn ears
ah interesting yeah so it focuses
specifically would the ear be the
outside part
no the ears uh is the actual kernels so
it'll it'll do the same thing it'll
go inside it'll go into the the court
like yeah
i'll tell you what go to your farmer's
market if there's anyone here that grows
corn locally
you know that bacillus thuringiensis
is that bacteria i told you about one of
the first successful monsanto gmos
they they took corn and and inserted the
gene
of the bacillus thuringiensis into the
corn so the corn naturally produces the
bt toxin and when the corn earworm feeds
on it
it dies the corn is poisonous to it but
not to us
but anything we know that it's about to
eat poison potentially
that's exactly what monsanto will yeah
yeah like it starts munching on the buds
if you make a bt
make a bt cannabis and then you you you
if it's a ct
short for a bacillus thuringiensis
so and they've done it for corn and
guess what in
it made the difference between people in
africa
you know having something to eat having
crops and not
you know oh yeah but it's it's a
around here but but on that front of tom
what if you grow some bt
corn out here yeah around the corner
ah as like uh what do you call it a
banker plan
right yeah yeah see what i'm getting
that would be the power move some
monsanto corn yeah on the perimeter
yeah not to even eat just for it's it is
keep in mind it it
it evolved we think it evolved on
grasses
gross put some not to grow out here
because these same caterpillars
you just couldn't like breed and then
sell them to other people
or use them grow it actually that's the
phrase the moss
will fly to it lay its eggs on it as
soon as the caterpillar hatches and
starts feeding
and it doesn't move into your crop it's
possible that cornier worm moth
likes the smell of corn better than
cannabis so maybe more moths will go
who would i mean that doesn't i mean
they were
so pungent you know they were amazing
they're still playing they had huge
potential but but
but gmo crops that's uh i don't know
that's not really sexy in cannabis right
but but it's interesting to have it as
the trap plant
yeah you have to be like i'm not even
going to eat the corn yeah there are
other bt crops out there too
you know again i don't want to be well
gmo cannabis is an inevitability
you know heck it could be you know but
not in tom's backyard
no but you know there's genetic
modifications that are not
tom may be rethinking that remember
remember that there is more than just
outdoor growing cannabis you have
greenhouse and indoor
cannabis and typically they have that
extra
protection of exclusions so they have
screening
the question is is there are there
unintended consequences to making the bt
corn
that oh yeah they're gonna be very yeah
they're we don't know for sure yet but
there there can be you know that that
that
yeah you're making it resistant to these
you know
to these disease to these diseases and
this this predator
but you know what's the trade-off are
you killing there's a lot of trade-offs
nutrients
and what it does to your body well we
don't know that
yet but you know imagine you've you've
heard these stories right a farmer down
the road from a monsanto farmer
pollinated and then it's the fucking
like
his fault it's the wind's fault and he
can't use his seed
there are no laws i guess between from
pollen flying from one farm to another
so you trespassed onto my property and
now i have to pay you
you stole yeah i have to pay you now i
can't use my own seed
you know but you know
it's it's it's all handled in the in the
courts and
if you've got the money you've got the
lawyers
yeah yeah i think that was monsanto's
strategy just to bulldoze legally
yeah so there are those and then and
then you know you could you could
consider
you know corn has wild relatives out
there and if then if you
you know if there was some kind of
cross-pollination with a wild relative i
mean that's possible
now you created this wild plant that
with that defense that is protected from
caterpillars and then
what happens with that can it now
dominate and out compete other plants in
the same
you know yeah corn abyss corn abuse
it's a crop yeah fuzzy bear
i don't know it's a it's a topic it's a
it's fun to talk about it but
um yeah you'd have this wild uh
mutant gene that's like
sees its path to like total freedom by
not being controlled right so right
yeah exactly but again you know like i
said uh ear
caterpillars are are a problem usually
an outdoor cannabis and then
the next would be in greenhouse you
could get pro you can have
problems tom's going to move into that
well we are going to maybe this is our
inspiration to finally set up the uh
the yeah well yeah they're they're tough
to battle
but the strategy is once again
monitoring and
and acting early you know as soon as you
have any hint that it's time to act
with these guys with these with these
bugs
then then act you know start your bt
sprays
um start uh this is hemp right
no no this can't this is high thc
is it oh okay for some reason i thought
you said it was this high cbd
why not start all right this one's like
right down the middle
the autos are actually you're selling it
as thc cannabis
or i mean you're growing it fresh yeah
if you were growing it commercially
you'd be selling it as th
as yeah right right so so yeah because i
was gonna say in hemp i'm not
i'm not as aware of the laws but then
you still have that other weapon that
that spin assad i told you about i
i'm not sure if that's legal in hemp
still i know it's not good
if not in cannabis but in hemp it might
be so you have another weapon
and you got your sprays start your wasp
releases early
they're really not that expensive you
know just we
you know we recommend a certain
frequency and a certain amount some
growers say
i'm going to double the frequency and
i'm going to triple the amount
that's how bad i want to protect and
that's how that's the kind of investment
i want to make to
to just have one more weapon uh to throw
at them well you deal mostly with
obviously with with
commercial drugs um but obviously
everything would be less
i mean oh yeah for just a little growth
so our
the smallest container we sell the
trigger grandma wash is going to be
you know ten fold more than more than
for that yeah
right so how much so what does that cost
oh i'd have to dig into it
um well go go to our website um
greenmethods.com and
and that's cool that's kind of the
retail that's our retail website so you
can see what that
but of course if you're commercial then
there's hundreds of dollars oh
i mean no they're you know we rear them
ourselves
uh you know we're yeah they're not
they're not that expensive
it's it's totally worth it let's put it
that way for prevention it's
i mean you can see this i go through
count
cut your heart i would if you're gonna
harvest this for oils or whatever you're
gonna do with it
but take the time to to give them to
your to your daughter and
and have her go through every one and
and see how many of them have the turds
in them because
i i saw i don't think i saw one that
didn't
it seems like they all hit you and um
you know it's and it could just be the
drying of the of the
the chewed up bud too you know it's
yeah so it's well worth it look at look
for other caterpillars
i mean the question is then also where's
it where are all the caterpillars
or the question or could one caterpillar
i bet if we started
digging in there can they they can they
can
but normally they don't move like they
don't move they kind of like
yeah but this could have been any number
of events i mean i
i did not see classic botrytis
you know mycelia you know the the
hyphy i didn't see it so you know i'm
still like
what what what the hell it's dry so does
that mean that potentially it's not
betrayed us at all you know it looks a
lot it looks like botrytis
um it looks like that end stage of
botrytis i was in here
you know a few weeks a week ago to see
what it was like but
but uh yeah i broke up
yeah yeah the um
see
yeah there's some gray there
it's tough i am i've seen a lot of
botrytis but this is
this is odd so but yeah look for more
caterpillars
just find as many as you can and
send them my way or i can pick them up
when i'm out here again
um so you live in l.a yeah i live in
palms just
north of culver city yeah so i
i have a few growers out here in the
valley i was just here last week
or the week before visiting some of you
guys
indoor guys yeah yeah and what do they
have to deal with
well indoor and greenhouse pet pest
complex is a lot more it's a lot more
similar
um indoor guys have a really
a harder time with rude aphid than than
maybe the greenhouse ones do and then
outdoor guys have
very little problem with rude aphid so
it seems to be like the opposite with
the caterpillar right
with the that you get a lot of indoor
growers that are saying i can't get rid
of these root aphid
whereas in greenhouses you might have
easier control and then
outdoors are rarely a problem i've not
heard of a problem
outdoors usually what happens is an
infested plant if it gets
if it's got them in the pot and it gets
transplanted to the soil
they'll that'll end that'll often end
the infestation of root aphid
just transplanting outdoors you know so
it's like
um it's a different environment that's
interesting so people who are like
propagating in greenhouses for outdoor
grows they could have root aphids in the
indoor part and then bring them out and
it's been seen before and we have
hypotheses on why that's the case you
know so
well that's a clue right there there's
something in that indoor environment
that is conducive that the root aphid
likes
i tend to think more so my my hypothesis
is
um those are not very good diggers the
aphids are
root aphid it's rice root aphid actually
came from rice
um it was a pest of rice let's say
that's how it was identified so it was
called rice root aphid
but it does like so this is a
it jumps plant species too yeah
i know it's a problem in you know the
the monocots
like the grasses rice being one of them
so
would it be a problem with corn i don't
know but i know it's also a problem
in broadleaf because i know it's a
problem in
salinas celery right the same exact
aphid and we know that it
it effects it infests uh cannabis but
what i was getting to is is i don't i
mean i'd like more data on this but
i've done a lot of this where you know
found infested pots of aphid
and then after harvest cut the cut the
um
the root ball in half and looked for
them and they weren't
in inside the pot they were populating
that space between the soil
and the pot that that which makes it
that
that border there which makes it a lot
easier with
all those spaces and caverns in there
for them to move around
and for them to find roots so that's
their optimal place to hang out
once yeah if you notice indoor gorgeous
doors rockwool growers
you know the the rockwell cubes are
wrapped
guess where they are they're in between
that plastic and they might have gone
into you know the rockwool's just like
fiberglass right it's a bunch of
laminate you know of just layers of
where they can feed on the roots
yeah they feed it on the roots yeah they
can get into some of those little
those little crevices too so but so
hydro growers deal with them too
hydro growers deal with them too um i i
often say
um like
soil is probably the best because um
like like i would be hard-pressed to
think that you're ever gonna find
your root aphid become a problem in that
setup because
they have to they don't dig well like i
said they can
they can move in those cracks
to get to the roots well roots are a
little bit farther away from the walls
and by the time the roots do get to the
walls of the of those pots there
i mean that plant might be large enough
to yeah
where it's not a problem yeah so the the
environment
really defines where the vulnerabilities
are it could
yeah it could tom i remember this same
view two weeks ago was beautiful and
epic
of these lush plants and and you know
what that's
actually i mean hate to learn from this
experience but
how long really was that two weeks ago
you said yeah
what if you'd cut what would your yield
have been if you'd cut last weekend
double what you have now right so it's
it's a lesson for
some growers i mean most growers they
they're aware of this as soon as they
see
one flower they're they're in their
cutting um
lesson is if if this was botrytis it
looks like it and
um you know it
it may be i always used to say salinas
is a hard place
to grow cannabis if you don't have good
good environmental control
and i'll just say if you know without
the the good environmental control we
don't call the harvest but try this
cause a harvest
right it's the one that decides you
either pick me
you either harvest me now or i will lose
everything or i'll take it all
right so and you know sometimes growers
that's tough to do you've gone through
the whole life and then the last week or
two
is when this starts up and you're like
what the hell and
at that point it's smartest thing we did
once when we did have a little problem
was
was harvest early and send that out
fresh frozen to live resin and yeah the
yields suffered but it was
not as bad as if we had let the cola go
to a dried up
crumbly you know
i mean this might still have thc in it
and
you can use the the turbo over there
yeah there's there's mech
there's i mean we we probably all smoke
mexican weed that looked worse than that
right
yeah but uh yeah i don't
i don't think unfortunately not for a
very long time
yeah well this is has been really
interesting
um i i mean i thought about that but i
didn't even know i mean how i mean
because the flowering cycle was really
started relatively recently
too and that was really fast too
everything was beautiful
that's what you know you know now yeah
as soon as you see it
a moth you know you gotta set up traps
next year once you
as soon as you you start as soon as you
take it
like rocky knocked down by apollo creed
and it's an eight
count and he's getting back up to plant
again next season
yeah well it's not too late right
couldn't you do anything
but yeah you just uh you know the other
thing we talked about is uh if we are
talking about botrytis which
you know again i'm not i'm not really
convinced yet
um wait you're not getting 100
that that's what's going on you're like
98 yeah it's just i don't see like
typical
structures of the fungus it's all dried
out and the fact that i see all that
you're seeing a unique disease maybe in
addition to the scale
which is unique we also have well i mean
that is
but it's like a disease rather than just
like it's just
it's just again break those buds open
and if you find
feces and every one i mean i did i
looked at a lot a few quite a few of
them
you saw a lot of females then it is the
cat yeah and then where are they
where did they go did they finish their
that you know they've got to go into it
and you've become an
expert in identification of the
different fecal matter from different
uh species of caterpillar no but you
know there's a difference between like
snails you aspire to that skill set
eventually i'll get there i guess
maybe that's one of our gemma trainings
to be able to identify the different uh
caterpillar poop
by flavor
cornea where cornea worm tastes a little
corny
all right well i think that was a good
well yeah that's a good deep dive and i
think we have a
a semi game plan for earlier in the
season next year
oh yeah i mean just start monitoring
look into
again first step let's id those collect
as many as you can and put them in jars
i left you these
and then uh you know because that that's
where it starts and then okay well we we
have at least we know who's hitting us
yeah we know the one we had on the table
uh uh
uh what is it what does a caterpillar do
inched it inched away yeah
anyway it's it's you let's say you know
you have three of them eating your buds
three different species in your buds
then you go look for what the adults
look like
you figure out how to identify them and
that's what you that's what you look for
in your traps as soon as you see that
one of those adults
that would be epic if we actually
identified two different
dis specific species what happened we're
totally
we actually discover them so then we can
create and get they're also new
on discovery yeah well right now i think
i'm uh
jet well i have to name them what's it
the uh corn ear
yeah the corn ear worm yeah that's
that's
our worm of choice yeah it's a common
one in the valley
of los angeles but it's not the only one
though gemma can a killer or something
like that right well
nate we'll name the new discovery after
gemma or we'll let her name it when
you're called in
is it uh is it i would assume it's
better for you to be working with
grows like from the get-go yeah so
i do i i work for a biochemistry brought
in once there is a problem yeah
is that your least favorite time to come
in that's probably one year well i
work yeah unfortunately so that's that's
a big message too
um so i work for a bio control company
right we we sell
insects for crop protection and other
predators for crop protection
right so um in in our industry
it's it's all about vigilance because
if we rely on sprays and try to
integrate a biological control program
you will struggle
because some of those sprays will hurt
the predators you've put into like how
are the marone products
um i have some experience with them
they um they do say i've attended some
of their presentations some of their
webinars
and they do say that they are softer on
beneficials but i personally haven't
seen the research so i don't know
so they're like while this may do
something to beneficials
uh it is not as bad as what it's doing
to the thing you don't
yeah and that's a it's a tough one you
got to say okay well give
give me the mode of action how is it
behaving because for example um
bt basilisk or in genesis if you told me
you know what this is dangerous to your
to the caterpillars
but it's not dangerous to aphid that's
absolutely true because the mode of
action is
only for caterpillars right so if we
knew the mode of action of some of these
other products that claim that they are
harmful to
pests but not to the beneficials and we
find that it made sense and there's some
research and made sense that
they would they would hurt your pests
and not your beneficials and you could
say all right well
you know there's something to this right
you know
tom i'm digging those uh flavored waters
uh i don't i think we're out oh she got
more
i don't know
i thought they were new purchases when
they uh
showed up mysteriously in front of me i
drank both of them oh did you already
have one
i had two oh
no i didn't well so you do you take the
the video and then you do it you add it
out and everything all that kind of
stuff
yeah like a two camera i mean this is
like it actually
i mean this camera i think overheated
but uh
like it's effective and it's budget like
i can easily carry two iphones around
and two microphones
and be like i could actually do a cool
conversation
oh shit yeah that's the same worm
it'll hit you at the right at the same
time right about
close to harvest is an inchworm a
caterpillar yeah
okay it's just called inchworm yeah
they're
actually the more common name is uh
looper like
uh and butterfly or moth
butterflies and moths produce
caterpillars no no no an inchworm
oh um a looper's a moth okay um
so even though they look cute and see
they call them loopers because
okay nice oh yeah great thank you
appreciate that sorry i drank your
previous one
thank you
should i turn this on
you can turn that one off this is uh i
guess this is a
they just call that a green looper yeah
yeah
so common cute intro so let's look up if
you know i'm pretty sure that that's
cornier worm it looks like many
they uh i took some macros of it
uh but then it got away
um here's here's what the adult looks
like okay
it's a brown moth um
it's not tom we should also know what
the adult form looks like so you don't
kill
all the ones that aren't doing here's
here's corn here's cornier worm um
one one all right that's definitely it's
not
knock to it i think is a family noctuaty
thing looks big
my noctuads can be very did you see any
of these around tom
that's what the adult looks like it's a
brown
tannish brown moth you know beyond the
lookout for that one
yeah that thing isn't okay what size is
it you know
it's kind of big again i've it's not a
pest that i commonly battle
uh look at this this wedge shape is like
that's it's a knock to it right i think
it is even though it'll look for him
[Laughter]
yeah well that's it you know that is
what that's the other place where we
come in
like all
for example after i came two weeks ago
i'm bummed that like i didn't come
five days later because we would have
started to notice stuff
here's a good photo it's it's it shows
you that kind of triangular
yes yeah yeah you know they look very
like that
you gotta look for things like the
spotting on them
and you know you see this on the on the
second
wing so there's two wings like that
right is that male or female
i don't know i'd have to look but you
see the brown you see the second wing
you know how
butterflies have two wings this bottom
wing has that browning on the edge
that could be a big identifying feature
well what happens when it lands
is it going to last i'm just generally
any big moth take out
well don't kill them don't kill them
catch them catch them because we can id
them if you if
you catch them on glue right but once
the idea
yeah put them in there put the glue in
the refrigerator
and and a guy a guy um i work with a
another cannabis grower he's indoor and
out there up in santa cruz county
he um last time i visited him he's
like hey um time you put the pin through
it i found a bud
he said i found a bug a a weird red bug
i'd never seen before
at the base of one of my plants and it
it was just
like a hundred of them just at the base
and i said did you catch and he said
yeah and he caught it but the mistake he
made is he didn't put it in alcohol
so it just shriveled up to it shriveled
in the fridge at least he put it in the
fridge so when i id'd it
luckily this bug is so distinctive it
was easy to tell what it was and it was
a
bug called the bagrata bug which is
common in cold crops and a problem in
cold crops
bro i found it on his cannabis on
cannabis so okay so does that come in
first sighting of bagrata bug that i
know of okay
but and when was this it was on the base
of the plant
and this like the trunk of it the very
bottom
trunk right and and it it
was a gl what is it you know
gathering there but how could it be
feeding on such
tough tissue i mean hemp tissue is
really strong and this was a nymphal
stage this was just a nymph
um no it had not molded to an adult yet
it was in the process of molting um so
it didn't have its wings yet you could
tell it was a nymph that's how you can
id that
okay you can tell okay this looks like
the second stage yeah
yeah and you can find you can id them
with their eggs so what could have
happened
is a bagrata bug from a local cabbage
farm
or some wild mustard out there flew in
got confused laid its eggs that's what
could happen with that scale
oh and maybe won't eat the plan no i
mean well my problem at all
it's like it's like a whale that went up
the river and then like couldn't figure
out how to get back yeah
that doesn't mean that we should block
all rivers so the whales won't go in
right
um where's when's it a problem right
it's uh although i could see california
doing that
let's over regulate this
cripple everybody so um yeah
yeah so yeah do most props like they
they
like they do they lose a percentage
to uh to stuff like this
like do they have like an acceptable
percentage of crop loss to yeah so great
i mean
you're you're hitting on you're hitting
on the subject that i like to talk about
we're asking good questions so they're
on fire yeah so
okay so you know obviously um we
have we can see what pests can do right
um
they they'll harm your they harm your
property and they harm your
your yields and therefore your you know
what you make
what what what you what you're money
maker yeah right
so but tom shakes but but
but bt is not free right you have to pay
for it so
at what point is using bt
a good idea right right all year long
every you know from start to finish
yeah you probably stand more chance
protecting from
caterpillar if you do it that way but
did you
did you really make more money or
did you throw it away in your material
you use right so there's
there's what we call the co the concept
of the economic injury level
which is like well like first of all you
have to figure that out so
say you have so what is the cost of uh
of the bt for say you know
i don't know uh you know 100 plant drugs
i'd have to i'd have to really look that
up honestly or is it
like percentage-wise like you're going
okay you know i mean is it
in the single digit percentages that
you're
you know i mean usually a lot of these
soft materials are pretty inexpensive so
but um but again you know it's
you put labor into it also
you know you you put you had to put
labor into it
you um there's all that involved in it
and and
that's why we've developed this concept
of the
economic injury level where at a certain
point it pays to do
something before that point it doesn't
pay to do something so
okay so this is an extreme situation
because
everything here has been impacted by
this but you
but if you and this is not a commercial
but in commercial you
certainly would would not want this
which is why i asked about
is is there a percentage like that like
if there's a trade-off but
if but how does how does a farmer know
what percentage of their crop they might
lose
to a situation like this before they
happen it's a very simple solute very
simple answer
research university research and how
long have we been researching this crop
at the university level now
let's talk about other lucrative
california crops let's talk about the
top two
almonds and grapes right do they have
guidelines
they actually do you could get on go
online there's resources available
where they'll tell you if you have x
amount of
this pest per leaf after sampling 20
leaves
in a 100 square foot area then you must
act
but before then you don't see what i'm
saying
we don't we just don't know yet so we
don't have those and the guidelines for
the crop
are very can be very detailed i mean for
grapes and uh for grapes and
almonds um you know they're they're
fairly
this is really interesting for other
crops there's guidelines so if you see a
certain percentage of pests
um in a certain uh
area then it's then it's a time to act
and those are very specific guidelines
it's it's a it's a mathematical equation
but that none of those guidelines
haven't been established for cannabis
not yet not and that's uh i think we
blew past these safe caterpillar
thresholds there's no question that we
did but that's why i asked it's like
like this is just a home grow but for a
commercial you wouldn't want to lose
your entire right
and neither did we neither did we so
it's not all loss you could
you could still still you can pretty
close
you can get some live resin out of that
we can make some but if we don't know
how we have bridges
is there still anything that's small
like would you make hash out of that
sure yeah you can make like like like
ice water hash yeah like you would
there's there's trichomes on the leaves
there's you know
but there's also a whole lot of botrytis
right yeah but you're filtering
it you're filtering it out right your
bags filter that out
a lot of it um not the spores okay what
what do the spores do when you burn them
i don't inhale them i i would i would
venture to guess
not much you'd probably have less
botrytis spores yeah into your life
i mean if we're talking about
aspergillus lungs yeah
if we're talking about aspergillus mold
then don't forget does aspergillus grow
on plants
that dying tissue yeah so i can
guarantee you that
i know but that would be only like you
could eat it it's just if you smoked or
actually no the sport is inhaling the
spores yeah well i mean if you if you
think about it you you have a joint
right
and you light it or pre-roll you light
it that first puff isn't all burning
smoke
there's some whatever spores were in
there went right into your lungs
alive and they got shot right into your
legs nice
so you know but yeah i mean in a resin
you know in a in a in a live resin
you're going to
go through all this purification i know
live resin i'm saying
ice water happens i couldn't tell you i
you know dive into the research but try
this lung
problems and i'm sure someone's done
something but i haven't heard that it's
prominent
right all right well let's uh
so i just realized that gemma missed not
only her three-hour chinese class this
morning but
she also just missed her uh dance class
too oh
is she happy from that she does the
dance she yeah she
she hates she hates it yeah so she
wasn't going to remind you
she wasn't going to remind you four and
a half hours of
zoom oh so it's all online
the dance class too yeah the dance class
was and i and i knew it was 2 45 and i
texted her mom being like what like is
there a zoom link for her 245 class
she's like
i'll check on the link i think class is
at 3 45 so i was like oh okay
and then i come back and yeah like she
forwarded something from the teacher
that's like we'll see you at 2
45 and it's now
like 4 10.
well you learned about cornea worm
that's right well yeah it was a good use
of my time
yeah yeah i mean my interest in this was
like really literally first of all doing
it experiencing it but then
well yeah i've been smoking it and all
that but like
it's the homegrow aspect it's trying you
know it's trying to
bypass having to go and pay all those
taxes and you do all of that so
obviously
there's risks and there's all of that
and there's costs and there's time and
there's
there's all of that but and it's a
learning process but generally there's
sadness right now
well yeah i mean this is not you know
the outcome
that you want right now my my dominant
feeling is
like a lot of other people who might you
know like and everyone's doing their
gardening
now and you know there's a big argument
for like people probing their own
cannabis especially if you need
more you know if you wanna you know if
you're a patient and you wanna do that
but you you really gotta get past this
it takes a while there's yeah there's a
there's a learning curve
you just have to remember we've taken a
plant from nature
and have we have bred it for
a certain characteristic right
production of
cannabinoids and terpenes high in oils
right um well there's a cost to that
right there's a cost to that it's the
same as um you know like we've taken
cows and
it used to be a wild animal that that
used to have better defenses against
predators
and nowadays we've you know we've
created cows their entire life is
intended you know they're just producing
milk
well and they're also in like cow cities
we're creating um plants with less with
fewer defenses potentially
yeah and if you look if you compare
indoor growing with outdoor growing um
you know a lot of indoor grows you're
you're further coddling the plant right
you're giving it everything it needs
you're making it an indoor plant and now
you've got a caudal
totally dependent little baby yeah yeah
yeah so
that's often this is why these these
plants are more susceptible i mean
there there's there's i told my wife
she's an indoor plant
she lives inside the brentwood bubble
yeah i mean you can see the difference
you can see the difference in indoor
grown plants versus outdoor grown plants
and their susceptibility to
certain things it's you know it's an
artificial these are cultivars that were
artificially produced right would they
do as well if you put them back out in
the wild probably not as well as their
you know
wild type relatives out there right run
free chihuahua
yeah exactly we ready to be tiny and
helpless
at one point that chihuahua was hunting
rabbit
right you know but also they've been
bred to have these extremely desirable
characteristics yeah
look the smell and other creatures are
equally as attractive
or even better i mean more attracted
it's uh you know there's there's a
what's starting to you know like come
out
of a lot of you know the growers that
are paying attention is
is you know the susceptibility of
certain strains with certain
terpene profiles yeah i think i
mentioned this at the uh
it's high with one terpene it would it
potentially
could attract a certain pest it could or
a certain
terpene profile represents a a plant
that's more susceptible not just to
insects
it represents a female to the male moth
i mean the breeze is picking up i can
totally smell them yeah
so we just don't know enough yet that's
just
it is interesting like like terpene
profiles are kind of like frequencies
and at different
like for example the mod like are
pheromones with like
is it a smell which would imply it's a
terpene they're hormones
they're actually hormones that you and i
can't smell but the male moth can
but does that imply that it does have a
smell to
to him or is it a chemical that they say
it's a pheromone
it's a pheromone so it's not a smell
thing okay so it's not a terpene it's
like it's
but it's a in the same way you think
about terpenes with smell a pheromone is
to like a chemical
yeah i mean it could be that but let's
let's keep in mind that a lot of these
trail with the ants so mods for example
let's just look at the single mop
mods and and what does the butterfly eat
well the the adult nectar and water
so would it make sense for nectar for
adult
flying moths and uh butterflies
which are nectar feeders to have the
ability to smell
flowers nectar find the nectar that way
i say yes
right but if you put like a gallon of
nectar in front of me i would probably
be
able to but what if they're not what if
they're not only focusing on nectar what
if they can smell
terpenes that those flowers are
producing wow and what if they prefer
a certain plant that produces a certain
flower that's right
so you could in breeding cultivars which
all kind of are going off and like the
berries and the desserts and the
whatever
but like you may cross paths with some
insect and you're
and the insect's like holy shit that's
my favorite smells good or maybe it
smells like something that you really
like
so it smells like it i mean limonene
what is limonene
it's a terpene that's in lemon in every
can in cannabis right but it's
it's prominent in in limes and
citrus fruits right it's one of the i
mean it smells like limes
that's why it's called limonene right it
smells lemony right
um could could that lemon smell be
something that attracts
a a a you know a a
citrus pest to the citrus trees
we just don't know is it it could be
right um
and if it is with more limonene attract
them to or a plant with more lime that
produces more limonene attract
that same pest i just you know and then
and that is the idea that they taste a
leaf that they've never tasted before
and are like i actually like this
yeah but this study is really important
to crop management and all of that
so is this type of research so get to it
so
okay so yeah well what are you doing
sitting here with us
getting high i'm not
part smoking your research yeah i mean
it's it is i mean
okay we work close with um a lot of
people that are in
the research side of it right um and um
you know so you mentioned steve as one
person he would be one easy
give me some other people um well you
know um uh we we know uh
people at you know different
universities that that are animals like
i would assume uc davis is very strong
uc davis is strong um are there any like
professors
cornell is also um there's a lot of
these these
these universities that you know we have
some contacts there i mean um
there was um the recent find of the
cannabis
aphid we up until it came to salinas we
weren't sure whether one specific
species of a wasp was capable of
parasitizing the aphid
until we were actually able to put them
together until we were actually able to
have some adult wasps emerge from a dead
aphid
and send it to an expert in that
particular family of wasps
in florida and they came back because
there was no one in california who had
that specific expertise
or maybe that's the only person we knew
who was an expert in bricant so they
they um well i didn't know them but i
was introduced to them we sent them
the emerged adults and they came back
and told us yes in fact it is this
wasp that is commercially produced from
us probably heard about it the
affidavits called money wasp
up until then we really weren't sure if
kalamani did do it so yeah the research
is ongoing
and that's when you guys were like we
got a new bug we're going to breathe
well when they get it they'll spend a
million dollars a day
yeah research and that's what they'll do
and then they'll knock it out
i found this yesterday as well which is
exciting
um you've got all sorts of violence see
that aphid right there it's black
yeah it's actually dead and it could be
it could be that uh it is one particular
species of wasp
that when it puts its egg in the aphid
the if it turns black
if it is we might have another weapon uh
so you may see a wasp emerge from there
like in the next
i collected it that's what i wanted to
do with the that's what i want to do
with this i want to
cut it out and look underneath to see
what there is down there
and you're like this may be a wasp that
we don't currently have in our lineup
i suspect it's one that is commercially
reared okay
um that's my suspicion he's dead right
there right that if it's dead yeah he's
dead but he's not dried up and he's
black and actually
it looks like the cannabis aphid it
could be
another aphid um but this grower had
the cannabis aphid that's about all they
had um and it doesn't look like the
other black
colored aphid that i've seen um
attack cannabis is there something
called the cannabis
yeah yeah that's what we've been talking
about
[Laughter]
yeah hemp aphid floridon
floridon cannabis um
are there any vials that you haven't
pulled out and shown us
well i just i keep these i tell i tell
growers give a handful of them to your
crew
have them carry them around with you
always
catch it so i you i can tell you the
yeah i still have one at home that's
right
i could send you actually i have a
picture of it on my uh leaf hoppers are
interesting we were just talking about
beat curly top virus right
yeah last week um now a reason to start
really thinking about
whether or not leaf hopper is going to
be a pest of cannabis
because it we had them it's what
transmits that virus
but yeah and by the way we had them too
and that's when we had we had like the
praying mantis were like what's
up this place is amazing so you can
imagine a situation uh where a farm is
infested with
uh the beet curly top virus and uh those
that's being transmitted uh within the
farm by a
a leaf hopper and that somebody decides
to put a farm of
of hemp right like in the same way that
a mosquito
transmits from canada okay got it got it
it's it's exactly that it's maybe
the virus has been around forever and
the leaf hopper's been around forever
but it wasn't until you put
the virus that got into the
plant that the leaf hopper was feeding
on you know what i never
posted a picture of it i posted a
picture of a different one from home
leaf hoppers this one was uh yeah
um i was like you're kind of cute
yeah there's a but no yeah that reminds
me
it's beat curly top virus it's uh well
um it makes the tops of beats curly
oh okay yeah
it's it was it was found in b just like
the name says
i guess and that's where they came up
with the name be curly top virus we're
very
literal in the naming of uh pests of
insects and
uh tomato spotted wilt virus what do you
think it does
right so but yeah but it's not
exclusive to beats it has other hosts um
apparently now
cannabis or hemp is a host nice
plain that thing is cool looks like it's
made of wood
it's probably it's like a wood plane
right for the wildfires maybe i don't
know
now that seems more like a vintage like
yeah
all right well let's uh that's a strong
yes strong ending tom's mind's blown he
has a lot to think about
that's right in the next season we'll
develop a game plan
right well hey you know you know i i
didn't know you
we'll start this we'll take this disease
now you know him intimately do you feel
like that kind of like
uh like you get to come and intimately
evaluate people's gardens like their
grow operations essentially yeah that's
my job they're basically burying
themselves
that's why i don't mention names of
people i work with right i don't want to
tell anyone
where whoever who i might be selling
bugs to so this specific grower had this
dessert yeah that's
the way it was terrible yeah this grower
and selena
i wouldn't buy their weed in a shop yeah
exactly it's like no that's uh
yeah there's no reason to mention anyone
under the bus
yeah everyone has them i mean every one
time you're
burying everyone else's thousands of
people right now
so you're very brave yeah i mean but
then again there's
there's a reason for this right you're
learning you learn through you know now
you have one more strategy but
hey you know we didn't know each other
we were sacrificing you to teach others
for the perspective
like my perspective it will always be a
non-commercial perspective
that's not what this is about so you
know
so everything is considered from a home
grow point of view into the cost what
i'm going to do how can i
protect this and that doesn't mean the
grief isn't you know
this is real you know in the sense of
the grief israel and the time and all of
that
but you know whether that changes your
decisions
maybe not because the lessons are still
the same
you know uh you have to you have to
be vigilant from the beginning the
question for me has always been is there
something i can do even before all
oh yeah like preventative you know yeah
what
so i'm not a bio control specialist
although i i know a bit about bio
control i'm an ipm
specialist and that stands for
integrated pest management the keywords
integrated
it means one not one strategy like one
of my props used to say
all right if you had a boxer come out if
you had mike tyson come out and all he
knew how to do was throw an uppercut
it wouldn't take long before his his
fighter knew
the fight so that is the killer punch
and punch-out it is his killer punch but
he but he's also throwing everything
else at you
but if all he did is that the one where
it's like left left right right
i i never played i never played it and i
i think i did once and then and he
killed me like
in the first round and then i stopped
but um
but let's say all he did was come out
with an uppercut and he just like wound
himself
up soon you'd know how to how to defeat
him right
it's the same idea you got to use
everything you got to use right crosses
jabs the pests are like we saw that
strategy last year you're not going to
fool us again
yeah you just have to throw everything
at them so there's so there's all kinds
of it's not just about
when we talk about pesticides and when
we talk about biological control we're
talking about
one arm one strategy in ipm
that's the eradication strategy that's
kill it
that's the last thing you do believe it
or not that's a
that's like your last straw kill it
right you know
you have things like keep them out of
the ground how do you do that
or under control select select strains
that are more resistant right
right how what about hitting their life
cycle something that
you know the disease triangle we talked
about that yeah you can think of
strategies right off the bat we talked
about strategies
if you control the if you control the
caterpillar you make it less susceptible
to the disease because there's less
injury
right so there's all these it's a myriad
it's going to become a black belt in the
understanding of the disease triangle
well it you know it takes a lot of
reading and time and but to think
thinking about it but you know that's
kind of my job is
you know design a program that is you
know more
bio-intensive in other words trying to
work around bio control
so that we can reduce or eliminate
sprays but at the same time integrate as
many
strategies as i can think of and it also
again coming back if you're dealing with
commercial grows these are grows that
will
have different strains in in different
you know seasons and all of that so
but i assume that what they don't want
is to have to fight the same battle
year after year or face
i mean i guess this is just the
challenge of agriculture
anyway yeah yep so
um it just seems that that the cannabis
in particular which is not only now
really starting to scale up is dealing
with these
issues on truly commercial scale
you got it and um there are things we're
doing
that are good and they're probably more
things we're doing that
are bad it's um it took a couple of
years before the cannabis safe it really
became a problem in salinas from when i
first was it on a different plant like
do people know
like it came from this or it just came
out of nowhere no
it's uh um i mean obviously the name
implies i talked a bit about it on that
last sunday right remember totally
the whole time ford on the the totally
honest david's a g
in the genus ford on and it has a
relative that's very
closely related to it which is the hops
aphid
hops and hemp are related so the pests
that feed
on them happen to also be related so is
it
is it outside the realm of possibility
that the hop safe it can
host on cannabis and vice versa is it
outside that like
it did a neanderthal like diverging to
what are we homing what are we we're
hominids hominids
anderson was dominant too but but it but
we're not neanderthals so my point is
do you think maybe in a short period of
time the hop aphid like
like diverged like well no they're
they're they're they are clearly
different species
right we don't know and we don't have
one point like a million years ago or
even a thousand
like because bugs recycles like they
they have so many cycles yeah in the in
a year
versus us i don't know how many foradon
aphid there are out there but it is a
family
of aphid and so they're they're related
in some of their
genetics didn't they recently find um
like amber of and i want to say
something like
uh why wasn't it did you see some giant
news
in the past of of what i think it was a
fly
insect right wasn't it it was a sperm of
an insect right
and it was i think it was still stuck to
the female i think
she i think that she could so does that
mean that they could design she was
inseminated and
but what does that mean could they
recreate that fly
like in vitro at this point the
technology is not there yet as far as i
know
you know um oh sure it's there like a a
prehistoric flight yeah i was here
it's probably like this big
no but you know it's firm inside is it
possible that
the hop safe it can can is it is it
possible that the hops
aphid can bring hopslate and vira to
cannabis well definitely because
basically if you like beer you like weed
and everybody by the way this is our
tom's expert opinion
[Laughter]
what about those of us who like
disclaimer well
tom is not an expert you can like weed
too you like weed too yeah
beer and buds and we didn't want if i
liked hot yeah i do like beer and i do
like weed so
yeah so i am like these so that but the
cannabis safe it's known
only to host on um on the cannabis
although you know
it obviously has to follow some some
somewhat of the lifestyle
life cycle of like the hop safid which
goes
which hosts between cannabis and
um stone fruit prunus prunus species
okay but sorry before cannabis was
around the hops aphid was going
obviously hops are grown all over i mean
not all over but like
where what's the other one dragon what
uh the the you're talking about the
trees that no no
you mentioned another yeah like prunes
and peaches and all that
okay that's the definition and it hosts
on on both yeah because it's got the so
when there are no
hops fields around it's like i'll hang
out on the
peaches you know i still don't
understand it although i do know
that it will can overwinter basically
feed and
actually also you know believe it can it
can
you know reproduce on prunus you know
like
the stone fruit and then back to hemp or
hops
you know we i'm not sure about this
aphid whether whether
eliminating and there is no way yet but
eliminating all the prunus trees in the
area will
just break its ability to overwinter and
then
help with control i i don't know oh
because hops die at the end of the
season and those trees linger on
and it's in temperate climate like do
those trees mo
like let's say i assume they grow well
in like the central coast
do they lose their leaves in the winter
are they just going full year
you know it's um it's it's even just it
doesn't necessarily have to feed on
leaves right it could be feeding on
on branch tissue or something you know i
don't
a lot of aphids when they overwinter
will overwinter on a naked tree that's
you know in
in the bark or you know um how about in
cold environments like i grew up in new
england
yeah i mean because here it's like like
if you survive all year long in
l.a where did prune where did prune
trees come from originally yeah you know
i haven't
researched it but um at some point they
bred them to grow in different climates
right
in iran so they were bred to grow in
different climates and
that you know if there could be you know
there could be a prune that grows here
prune a species that grows here that
doesn't back yeast and
vice versa yeah this is very interesting
i mean i think have you dealt with a lot
of any these large grows where the
farmers transitioned over to hemp from
other crops
and so yeah so you know
because we've been hearing about this
for for years you know large growth and
a lot of them didn't make it they kind
of didn't know what they were doing they
didn't know what they were going to do
with their crops after they harvested
them
but now there's this other component
where did they know what pests they were
up against with this
with these brand new crops and and and
all of that
yeah now you you to grow something
completely new there's definitely i mean
the the blueberry
farmer up i think in washington state uh
i talked to a couple months ago
he then grew hemp at scale and he was
like my first season
and he's like a world-class blueberry
farmer
um and he was like it just slapped me
around
yeah i mean if you're not ready for it
you know it's like anyone you know
there's a there's a uh a learning curve
for every crop
there are some easy crops to grow how
would you like go away from a crop you
know blueberry go oh here's this new one
i'm gonna make a killing
and you know i i don't understand the
mentality
because here's like a smart person how
could you not even how could you do that
and not
do your bottom line research
you know again there's
the bottom line research isn't there um
you have to remember
and then if it's not there then you're
taking a real challenge
yeah well it's like all the people who
are growing hemp and then we're like
shit i have nowhere to store all this
stuff once i cut it down what we were
saying they didn't they didn't know
where they're gonna store it they didn't
know how to cure it they didn't know how
to then manufacture you have to
try and cure this if you want to sell
the flower why would you make that
investment if you don't know
could it be could it be that the
investor for the cannabis operation
is a different animal altogether could
it be that somebody that wants to switch
let's say from
ornamental flower production to cannabis
here we're talking about the people who
are doing hemp farms at scale
like not cannabis but like well same
same deal um but it's
such a bigger scale of like what you've
never done this before
and you haven't thought out like and you
didn't bring someone in who knows what
they're doing
but but see so that's what i was getting
at is you have it the chance of success
for somebody that has grown another crop
and has done it for years and
understands everything that goes into
the business of farming
having success with hemp i think is
greater than you know some
somebody that's just investing to try to
oh 100
is that there's a body of knowledge
unique to
every different thing that you grow that
you know if you're not aware of it'll
fight you know yeah absolutely on the
pest side
i i ten i focus on cannabis i've i've
had
what three years now just almost
exclusively focusing on this crop
because
it's a new crop and so you know it's
like i'm
i am learning more and more about
you know different indoor outdoor
greenhouse
uh you know environment environments
pest compasses
different different states and their
pests but you're learning
the curve my learning curve is like that
yeah so that's so that's kind of my goal
is
focus on this niche um i know i couldn't
tell you anything about plant nutrition
you know other than what a basic
botany class or plant physiology class
taught me
you know but going forward that would
probably be really helpful to you
because oh sure
that not like yeah you know when you're
talking about
well don't get me wrong i mean i do know
i did take i mean aphid afib is known to
blow up
and uh plants are excessively you know
they have excessive nitrogen right
exactly right so so why wouldn't that
apply to this
i don't know if we're sure about that
yet but it's something i follow
you know and we we definitely you know
you can't get you can't get into
agricultural pest management without
knowing something about plant physiology
yeah because of those relationships or
but i would never jump into growing
let's put it that way i'm not
i i would land fl i could probably
protect the plant but
it would be a spindly you know weak
plant low yield
but it'd survive unlike times it might
be pest free oh yeah
yeah robusto that then
right i'm still letting them go it's so
funny because even some of these back
there are sort of like
they have a will to live well keep in
mind if there is a disease there
you're harboring that you know
potentially harboring botrytis so
all that dead tissue when when you get
it you want it you want to clean up yeah
you're going to want to clean that whole
area
you know yeah um burn it strawberry
growers like i was telling you
they pick up the the strawberries and
toms
yeah they clean up get rid of them get
them far away
yeah it's uh because you've you've uh
you basically have a propagule something
that can
come back to life once it has a
susceptible host
right right and a and the and the
environment
and then the toastmasters like airborne
like spore life right
and if botrytis is a problem in tomatoes
and you have those there or if it's you
know a problem in any one of these other
crops of yours which
this one looks like a poo with leaves uh
coming out
it looks like a poo with leaves coming
out of it
yeah you you um you know you
if you have spores that landed on your
lawn there and you watered with a
sprinkler
and this is one way that spores can move
from plant to plant
the drops of water hit the ground pick
up the spores and splash
onto the growing bed and then it happens
again
and or the wind dries that spore now
that it's gotten closer to the plant and
the
spore flies up and lands let's say on a
pistol as it's just beginning to show
signs of like the flower primordia right
that's all you need
that's spores there and that could be
exactly what happened
it could be the death of watched it
happen it was like i knew it was
happening
because it's like you know you can see
it happening it's obvious
but i didn't know i mean there's nothing
i could do to prevent it
i didn't know i mean you know i mean it
was so fast literally within a few
days and also i'm like i i need like
rather than go in and do that i'm like
oh right this is the first one i know
what's happening but i need i want to
have someone come here
you know that's what we're going to do
yeah so that's why i
saw we're setting up next year i think
it's the plan
go in and rip everything you know like
all the brown
because i i bent that with a few of them
and there's nothing left
yeah there's a chance that if you had
harvested this last week
gotten rid of all the dead dry brown and
got it got in on maybe some kind of
really aggressive drying of everything
else
that you'd have saved half of it but
yeah i know i mean that's uh
i think once peter and i met that was
kind of the
the idea is if i become part of this
thing
you know i'll be around next year or
next time in l.a
yeah yeah yeah to to to see what we
could do to
you know do our best to protect you know
there's this other thing
we need eric nugshot to come uh
i'm so like such an advocate for
homegrown i've had this i'm gonna admire
this with the camera and like
you know like tending to people you know
that's why there was another part of
this like let's see if we can
and we have an indoor thing here can we
uh successfully do some home grows
oh no doubt and then i thought well you
know take
ten of them for people you know um and i
think that actually
with with with cannabis um you know
people should want their home growth but
it's a lot of work i'm realizing it's
really a lot of work because
you know you almost have to have daily
eyeballs on them
and um i was wasn't really aware of that
and even something as small as this it's
like
you know like catching like seeing
like catching like it's it's work it's
work
like you you know and and i even got one
of these
like this just so i can get in real
close nice um i still didn't touch all
of them but that's what it takes so
it does and there are all kinds of tools
for it
and um you know if you if you know me
long enough you'll know
i'm a pre i preach monitoring i preach
it's it's you preach mono what
monitoring
monitoring if you don't spend
the labor resources on monitoring um you
could end up with
you know a really bad situation quick
yeah and um really quick yeah
like within two weeks last year
even even more than that because when i
i let him know
right away what was going on and he has
the text
it was and i was like i think i've lost
the whole thing yeah i think
that was a week and a half ago easily i
go i i'm pretty sure this entire thing
is gone
because i saw what was happening and
that was a weekend
yeah i was in rhode island yeah yeah
that that that hot event could have also
been something to do with it right
although
yeah the heavy presence of so when he
texted me that
my response was keep an eye on the other
buds look into them with a knife and
eyes
to see if you can find any caterpillars
like pri prime of
like look closely to see if there are
any caterpillars in there
well now you know to look for the poop
and the feeding the leaf feeding damage
right but clearly once you you you know
what you need to
you need you know you need to you have
older bodies on that smell
and then have her bark
when she smells it that specific worm
poop i mean uh caterpillar poo maybe the
cats will be better
that's right that's an interesting idea
using dogs yeah
dogs for scouting yeah you're pests yeah
yeah
i mean yeah okay i gotta go home and
cook dinner
but uh this was awesome
[Music]
you are like uh jesus
sacrificing himself for the good of
other home growers everywhere i'm a
homegrown martyr
and next year we'll bring some new
diseases and plagues well i'll tell you
to attack your plants it's so
demoralizing because that feeling like
two weeks ago when i was like you know
because i've gone
and just not even because i don't like
touching them but and so
like so sticky and i'm like oh my god
i made this happen because i've been
taking so much good care of them and i'm
like
and so that feeling was beyond
if you're a cannabis lover and go and
because that's how they work like
i wouldn't even touch them and my
fingers would come away i'm not even
touching them
and contrast that with your current
feeling
so how how how long have you been
growing here's the thing
this is my first yeah so you just have
to talk to a few cannabis growers and
ask them the messes they've had to deal
with oh you know i already know i mean i
know i mean i know
there's a learning curve yeah no i
there's always a learning curve i know
this loss is relevant all i'm saying is
like
that coming from that feeling down to
the other one you really have to do a
little work to
to revisit that you know to jump back in
and go okay
but um but like all the growers i've
talked to you know who've done it
they're like you know you know
well your plant's done yes they don't
you know
yep you know uh and then you grow new
ones and it's the cycle of life and
you know yeah
so but here's the other thing he brought
these things over the experience
even even the one on the left just like
i didn't think it was going to make it
it was like
sickly it was nothing and it's like
every day so they're like little babies
and nursing them back and it became this
beautiful little plant only then
he's bonded with them i have bonded with
them
i have it's sad i know yeah i've um
but here's the other thing these were
also designed it's not a
it's not living soil it's like but
and we everything was according to
uh these guys you know organics alive
great guys
well you're you're um the caterpillar
just uh yeah
the no no it just ignored all of that
ignored it's it's
life that came so it's sort of like
finding the balance you know
i don't want to fill the caterpillar if
i don't want to yeah well
we're gonna basically these beds over
the winter
we can uh build up and and the beds
i just get some worms in there las vegas
letting soil grow i think in all of las
vegas in the first one
beautiful this is steve cantwell steve
cantwell you know who he is
he was a martin martial arts champion
now he's got this
grow it's this now he's an indoor living
soil
right there and he uses these
beds right and it's all and they're just
it's so
it's indoor you know it's controlled
environment
you get dressed in your little booties
all of that this is his weed
this is his weed the banana really cool
guy
and um you know um so
you know we're just i'm going going for
for uh a living organic environment that
was
the idea so when you come back next year
tom's gonna have a 4x60 bed
in those lines she was at his 22nd
i think cultivation in that's in that
same soil
and so he's supposed to get richer and
richer as it goes on 22 is a lot
yeah it's like years you know it's
it's really i think it's foreign
over five i think uh i think we did the
math might have been four and a half
it's on the table
yeah yeah it's it's all it's a science
um and it's an art um you know people
have to have worked with a crop in a
specific growing system to really
figure out how to make it work some
people are gifted
um yeah it's uh and everything was
consistent which
is always impressive to go and see the
plants everything was a
beautiful grow not even terribly
large and he has his hands on everything
this guy who was a mixed martial as guy
and now
and his knowledge is so he's totally
into it and so that was basically the
question because everything he
produces he sells right he's got a sweet
little small business
but everyone wants to get bigger we're
not selling any of this no
no none of this but how do you get
bigger and maintain
quality control maybe go slow maybe go
slow
i've seen i've seen so i've seen so many
people fall
flat on their face just biting off more
than they could chew
um and if you're making it with a small
business if you're paying your people
you're making some money
what's wrong with that right that's why
people go to
um and and major in in and get degrees
in
agricultural business because you know
that teaches you how to do that
how to start a farm yeah and make it
successful and
and grow and and eventually become rich
from it yeah
you know but you you jump into it
without really knowing
what's involved you you've kind of
you've set yourself up you know um well
i mean would be interesting i i think
you know it's interesting to know at
what point you know in cannabis scaling
off does it become like
a real like a real different type of
product you know and
you know less you know what is it less
crossed the budweiser threshold
yeah give us give us another five years
we'll know a lot more
exactly all right you don't want me uh
you don't want any of that no that's
done i got what i needed
so yeah let me grab what that
what are these specimens doing here what
was those
that was that was gemma was uh
there oh my god on cue gemma was feeding
the caterpillar but then it got loose
we're going right now baby girl i want
to leave in 10 minutes no
i'm going to leave now and let's go cook
some dinner
and look at our plants at home you can
if we get back quick you can go in the
pool that's your incentive to want to
leave quickly because we got to leave
quickly
when something we have to do aligns with
what you want to do
amazing things happen you ask ryan about
the little leather pouches
no no that's the leather pouches
what's that they were in the bag
i was like thank god
i thought i checked in there they must
have been
shoved gemma we had some amazing
conversation out here that you missed
but gemma we decided some things you're
gonna get really good at where'd you go
you're gonna become our caterpillar uh
identifier you're gonna be like our
patrol
like on the uh what's the north wall in
uh
in game of thrones what do they call it
i don't know but i get i get what you're
saying
yeah i never will i only watch the sex
[Laughter]
gemma the glass is my okay don't bring
these over for the babies
i did
no i assumed you had all right so
there's all right
all right can you um totally out
baby girl and so i was trying to save
this
like the gardener it's a totally
different
this plant over here brought it to me
the gardener brought that like from his
house
tom that's like a vector of in fact he's
it probably has like
mites and yeah that's a that's like a
spider mite and
actually i would love for you to look at
that right now and be like dude this has
all sorts of stuff you don't want to be
introducing
wait so the gardener was like
what is it looks like
that looks like dirt actually yeah you
know i mean it's
totally different so he was like
flowering all right he was like you're
growing weed i'm growing some wheat
he goes here really well and he had it
in terrible soil
and i so i put it into this and put some
better dirt in there
tom you are such a caregiver to these
plants well i wanted to try to help him
but i think i'm gonna give it back to
him it's doing okay but i couldn't mess
with the roots so i couldn't mess with
his original
he just had it was just shitty it was
really
dense and you know do you see any like
spider mites
oh it was i wasn't even looking for that
um
was do you know what was he growing
inside or outside
i don't he didn't tell me i mean have
you been keeping it
in the shade the entire time no i don't
know but but
it started to i'm not sorry you had it
over there right it was yeah it was
burning
it looked like it was burning a little
bit so i took it out of the sun but it's
been getting plenty of brought in there
what's that there's definitely rot in
there nice not nice
we're not the only ones it just got here
just got here tom you are like the grim
reaper for well yeah yeah weed plants
but this was it was it wasn't doing this
they're like i don't want to go to tom's
house yeah
why not harvest it yes baby girl
crackers and cereal you can see them oh
my god
you're you're taking food to go yeah
my god she gave it to you you just took
it quickly yeah
yeah get it uh ground up i mean these do
look like
a little bit like turds but no i think
this is just dirt
yeah now we're finding them left and
right so show me how many uh
it's probably one minute about a minute
of scouting
how many are in there i don't know i
lost count probably ten yeah
and it just took about a minute so i
mean we've yet to see one bud here that
doesn't have
the poop in it so all right so basically
in
better non-blinding light we're finding
tons of caterpillars
they they're probably going to hide when
it's hot
right right so
uh now that it's cooling off they're
coming out to feed they might they might
be more likely to
come out and start chewing on social
green parts meat
yeah i mean if there is botrytis here
that's i'm more and more convinced
convinced
it's not the real problem the problem
with all this so we have
predominantly a caterpillar infestation
yeah now that you look well
you know then you can you'll find them
and
i mean that's that's a lot for
like a minute of scouting right yeah
this is uh
but the turds give it away interesting
that the leaves weren't focused on they
just came at the right time the moth
laid that's eggs at the right time
uh so sometimes they lay their eggs much
earlier and then you start i mean
you see like a lot more of this yeah i
mean you see normally what i see is a
lot of leaf chewing damage which leads
you to the area where you
like this here which which leads you to
where to look for them
you know so um okay i see that leaf
chewed i see that leaf chewed there
there's got to be a caterpillar here i
look but normally
where you don't see leaf chewing you
don't expect them to be there so
i'm wondering if what happened they they
hatched by the time there was
significant amount of flower tissue and
started feeding
unbeknownst to tom and
by the time you got to this stage they
were everywhere
they were just hiding here's one see
it's uh
well i mean i have had people out here
who were more knowledgeable than me
but they didn't well i think when we saw
that first one
was kind of like the early days of them
exactly when i would have started i mean
if i'd known
but you know what there peter does make
a very important point is
when you scout is important i tend to
like
cooler part of the morning for scouting
for exactly this reason
when we first came out here was nothing
like this and now we're seeing them
i mean i'm picking them out of practice
one-handed
yeah so they got you good but you'll be
ready next year
that's right shake it off tom
okay i'm gonna bring gemma home actually
i've already shaken it off this has been
uh i mean the thing is is like you just
need to know i could ba i
i could that that is you you can i could
deal with that i can
i'm already dealing with with
caterpillars next time yeah look at this
look at why not just like the
turds
yeah knowledge is power right absolutely
i'm not scared of that so we know the
strategy scares me is not no
good thing is so far it's just been that
corny like miniature rabbit
pellets all right cool
i'll leave you guys to you guys are like
uh gorillas grooming the uh
a lot of unhappy caterpillars and
alcohol
so you basically id these and be like
they're all the same thing
it looks like it's all the same
caterpillar all right that's crazy
okey-dokey all right it's hard to walk
away
it's like it's like when did we find the
last easter egg we don't
really funny so young a very young larva
there
brownish yellowish brown all the way to
this
big fat green one but it's all the same
appears to be all the same did you get
that piece in one thing that was
just we have some more caterpillar okay
you have to dig in there and you'll find
them
more than likely if if you find this
many oh here's one i forgot that one
that one's a baby and they're all the
same species
okay so that is the uh corn ear
that's what it looks like to me i'm like
i said no what is the corner
it's the striping that that um i showed
you the photo
okay i'll show you the two stripes that
go down it's it's back
it's uh
you