interesting appointment it was a
different appointment that I think most
people are expecting I think that you
know we all knew that Matt Whittaker was
a temporary appointment so now it's a
question of you know getting a real
pointment through everyone thought Pam
Bondi had a really good chance who's the
current AG of Florida and now we've had
a new guy named who was formerly you
know working for George HW Bush who's
you know kind of most famous legacy of
that administration was that he was the
person that championed pardons for every
one of the iran-contra criminals or
people that were involved so when you
think about you know the reason that
he's being appointed you know I don't
think that's a great deal to do with
cannabis I don't think as a great deal
do with you know criminal justice reform
or anything else you'd think an AG might
be involved in but it certainly has a
great deal to do with you know the
Muller investigation what you can expect
a new AG that you know what Trump
expects this person will do in a
specific situation so how does that
relate to cannabis we don't know enough
yet this is a you know this name was
only floated around probably in the last
week it came as a surprise to me I
thought there was three or four other
people that certainly were gonna get the
nod before he did I think that because
HW was in the news a lot last week with
his passing that people started looking
at some people that have been around for
a long time that might be an easy
confirmation and I think that this is at
least to come from a nomination that
will be confirmed relatively easily by
the Senate because he's already been
there before he's had bipartisan support
he's largely seen as someone that is a
law-and-order guy but now we've gotta
think about what it means for the
cannabis industry and I I don't know
enough yet I would expect based on what
hws policy was towards cannabis and
towards drugs in general I mean this is
a guy that presided during the Len Bias
issue and was the person that escalated
the war on drugs probably in a way that
we'd never seen you know for those of
you old enough to remember what Humboldt
County was like in 1989 it was probably
the worst you know pop famine summer
we've ever seen because camp was flying
and dropping nets like we've no never
seen any since so that was led by by
this AG so we'll say but I can't imagine
it's good for the industry but I don't
think it's you know any worse than
sessions
give me your reflections it's
surprisingly I'm gonna say I didn't mind
him as an AG you know I absolutely
detest him as a person going into the
position I thought he used to be
terrible for cannabis when his
nomination happened but the day he
recused himself from from the Russia
investigation was the day that he was no
longer powerful as an attorney general
yeah he no longer had the ear of the
president it didn't matter what do you
wanted to do it he wasn't gonna have the
ability to get through and you know he
was probably the most feckless Attorney
General I've ever seen in my lifetime
and it didn't really it didn't really
affect the cannabis industry at all it
was one of those things that you had so
much fear and there was so much hype
about you know sessions taking over as
the AG and the worst thing the guy did
was uh was repeal the coal memorandum
and then never even you know go after
anyone never prosecuted him and never
really changed anything in a meaningful
way but it was a he allowed the industry
to continue to proliferate which is you
know no different than what Holder did
no different than what Lynch did no
different than what any other AG is done
for the last you know call it 12 years
so I thought sessions
I thought sessions be a lot worse and
I'm pleased to see him gone but but I
don't think he really had any real
effect on canvas