[Music]
attracting is not the issue I feel like
there's lots of people right now who
want to get into the cannabis industry
on the ground floor it's like a big buzz
there's lots of people who want to get
in sifting through all of those resumes
this is something that's a little bit
trickier and he touched a little bit on
that that we have this really lengthy
hiring process to make sure that the
person that we're bringing onto the team
is is really a good fit because we do
struggle with a lot of turnover and it's
very difficult to to bring someone on
have them fill out all that HR paperwork
train them in all these different things
just to have them walk away you know a
couple weeks later so that's I feel like
more of a struggle is sifting through
and finding the right addition to the
team what I'm looking for when I'm
sifting through resumes is more people
who are bringing experiences from other
industries than necessarily people who
are bringing cannabis experience most
people who have cannabis experience have
experienced it in the legal industry
where they're expecting things like cash
at the end of the day or not having to
show up to work on time or being able to
be overtly medicated while at work that
is a huge misconception of is that oh
you guys are just all back there smoking
all day like no this job is hard you're
gonna be working a lot so finding people
who are interested in cannabis the way
we do it and not cannabis the way that
it was done five ten years ago is is a
little bit trickier so I'm looking for
people with either retail experience
inventory experience medical experience
these are oh absolutely if you have
experience in local government like yes
I'll definitely hire you but these are
all things what we found is that you can
take these skills and and adjust them to
cannabis instead of trying to bring
somebody
and and teach them customer service you
know if I can take someone who came from
a retail background they understand how
to talk with people how to to study a
product line and do all these other
things so that's a lot easier for me to
train than necessarily someone who's
just a cannabis enthusiast because you
can meet lots of cannabis enthusiasts
that are very intelligent but there's
also the flip side of it that that's all
they're interested in so I think it's
important to make sure that you're
finding people with diverse interests
that can that can do a lot of things
from the store and for me the the thing
that I a lot of times higher for it's
something that I I cannot train I cannot
mentor it there's is integrity so and
that's the same way that I do purchasing
so if I have a company that I don't
align with their business philosophy I
no longer carry their product because I
cannot I feel like as an activist and a
leader in this industry is I want to
support the best and that means that
when I'm hiring people or buying product
I want the best and then that puts us
into the situation of okay now you have
them how do you keep them and this is an
industry which is never give paid
vacations or even proper pay legal pay
and you know Cassie and I regularly have
meetings on do we need to where can we
give raises you know who needs a raise
who's due for those who needs a vacation
and we want to make sure that that's
taken care of because if I don't offer
it there's another end another company
that's coming forward that does offer it
and then that's I mean that's which is a
really good thing it drives us to step
up our game on how we're going to take
care of staff before we hired solely
from the fact that there were people
that didn't want to work in in any other
industry they only wanted to work in
cannabis and only ever had work in
cannabis so their standards were not at
the same level as a lot of other
industries and now as we're pulling
people from other industries over here
as I was the one that hired Cassie and
when I worked with another store but
typically in the past when we were under
they only the medical umbrella is I
would love to find people that have
worked in healing and other areas
specifically natural healing even
pharmacy technicians I mean their
understanding a lot of the medications
that some of our patients were on so
having a healing background was actually
something that really attracted me to
actually bringing Cassie on was because
she had such a diverse background
specifically in natural healing and
that's what I feel like cannabis is and
I oftentimes if somebody is like my
sales manager is was the sales manager
for Nordstrom like this brings their
best practices over to us and you know
it was somebody that they were ready to
get into the cannabis industry now our
goal is to keep them on which would be
really difficult when you're losing your
management team and we're having such a
deficit in this industry of finding and
keeping good but genders because they
move up quickly as long as they're good
at their job and they reap the benefits
of the training that they're receiving
on their job and a year they're a
perfect candidate for a pretty good
sales rep position for a company which
is gonna offer more flexibility in their
schedules so this is where you know
Cassie and I have to understand that we
need to meet some of these needs so that
we can keep you know qualified
candidates on the good bud tenders are
definitely being poached by brands but
they're also being poached by management
positions you know because good
management is also in deficit in the
industry so you know if you've got good
skills and a good work ethic a lot of
times you're moving up the ranks very
quickly which then we lose our best
people on the front lines you know
because your bud tenders are the face of
your business there are the people who
are out there talking to patrons every
day and we have some people that that is
there that is the goal that we have both
decided upon when we hired them that we
knew that they would be moving into a
different track that they would be
coming on and soon would become a team
leader and then a team leader is before
you get to assistant manager and then
assistant manager before you get to that
and there's some times we hire people
that just plug right into one of those
roles they don't go from that section
but we want to have upward mobility for
all of our positions and all of our
staff member to understand that one of
the worst things for any business
is where people feel stuck in that job
and they can't move up and so we do
oftentimes hire and promote from within
and there's times that we need to bring
in something to add to our best
practices and I think this goes back to
the retention question is how to retain
people yes good pay and good benefits to
stay competitive with other industries
is essential but just having people feel
good within their job things like seeing
internal promotion like if I work hard I
can get to this these goals are fabulous
and I had mentioned this a little bit
before of just organizational structure
people understanding how the business
works this is your role in your job
description this is who you report to
and this is who they report to I think
that that really gives people a lot of
confidence in in the business that they
okay they know what they're doing
instead of sometimes like oh well
somebody's got to do it so I guess it's
me which kind of happens a lot I think
in cannabis and then people get cranky
like oh well we're making the same wage
but I'm working so much harder where
when you when you say okay you are
working harder you're a team leader
people feel a little bit more of that
they feel as though they're being
recognized for what they're doing and I
think that that helps retain employees
when you can say I see what you're doing
I want to reward you for that and keep
you happy in this position and that's
why I am merit based not seniority based
so if you've worked here for a year and
you're not showing me that you're
growing and you're not showing me that
you deserve more and many issues then
that's probably not going to happen
however if I have somebody who comes on
and they're just killing it every step
of the way if I don't support that and
let them know that
doing a wonderful job here they're gonna
start pulling back I'm big on positive
reinforcement for my staff so it's like
you're doing well Cass and I both are
very much so we praise our teams and
praise our staff members when we hit
goals when when we have some eye that
just goes above and beyond like we
utilize something that I brought from
another business over to our industry I
mean to cannabis here at the store Joe
is slack which is a in-house
communication like email instant
messenger all-in-one where it has helped
us with a lot of communication issues
because in the past when I worked for
another dispensary we only did things
for email and text message and it was
just things fell through the cracks all
the time I personally only checked my
email on days that I'm working I don't
check my email on on dates that I'm off
because I need that I need that break
there if there's an emergency we can
contact through slack or you can you
know it helped us tremendously and using
software systems has allowed for us to
increase our efficiency in our store and
create better dialogue and communication
between each other which I think helps
with staff morale because staff morale
can just be very detrimental to your
staff if you're not taking care of them
if you don't have you know a good
discount program in place where that
they can afford to buy their own
medicine then it creates issues and then
you're having issues of theft and you
have issues of shrinkage and now we're
moving into metric where I can have a
2.5 percent variance on my inventory
that's gonna be a big issue for us and
making sure that our staff is is you
know doing their best to not have sticky
fingers and oftentimes when employees of
any business when I came from retail
world and in veterinary if you take care
of your staff and you respect them then
their integrity level actually goes up
there because they don't feel like well
I'm being shorted over here so I'm gonna
short them over here and that's
something that we're all gonna have to
understand moving forward especially
when we're going to be
such strict compliance is how our how
our employees handling inventory are
they actually reporting it properly and
which will be quite interesting to get
in this next six months because this is
where a lot of I think the fruits of our
labor will actually come through is
because a you know casting I feel like
we've always been ahead of the pack and
leading in this industry and every time
we've hit milestones we're like July 1st
like we've not stressed as bad as I seen
my brothers and sisters in this industry
I absolutely agree with what you're
saying about communication being really
important for retention in morale I have
been in a situation where you have a
budtender who's told completely
conflicting information by two managers
right so when you've got somebody here
they're trying to do a good job but
they're hearing this thing from one
person this thing for another person and
they got a patient yelling at them right
now like that is a very stressful place
to be in so by us communicating better
and again back to this organizational
structure you have people who just feel
more confident in what they're doing
they know yes I can go back and get this
inventory because I understand the
protocols where when that communication
isn't there there's a lot of times where
mistakes happen and people are yelled at
for those mistakes even though they were
never really told what they were
supposed to do in the first place and I
think one of the biggest misconceptions
I think about cannabis staffing is that
being a budtender which we call them
customer assistance so I'm just going to
switch to that is an unskilled position
because it's really not we're asking
people to understand an entire product
line to understand complex regulations
and body systems and with the addition
of that final one these things are
changing on a day to day basis and
they're dealing with angry clientele who
doesn't understand why those changes are
yes we're obsessed with the regulations
and reading through them every day but
for the most part as patrons are coming
in they're like what do you mean I need
a bag what do you mean I don't need a
bag anymore this is really difficult I
think for for bud tenders to deal with
and so they have to be trained to deal
with how they're going to study that how
are they going to come in to work on a
Monday
and explain all this stuff and then
Tuesday they have to explain a bunch of
different things that's not for the week
I don't think so I well and we used to
have monthly staff meetings and we did
our best to make those happen however
now when a business is oh you know we're
here from 7:00 in the morning until 10
11 sometimes at night having staff
meetings it can't exist and so something
that your team implemented which I think
was brilliant is they have shift
meetings so it's coming on a DS shift
and it's something that y'all alright a
document together that's shared between
everybody all the management team to
wear the same message is being delivered
at every single like shift change so
that everybody is up-to-date with this
changing policy and i which i think is
brilliant and that's what we need to be
doing because in the past when we've
taken it away from one cook in the
kitchen and we've started to give
responsibilities out and that's when
employees start to feel like well who do
I go to on this I'm getting one person
telling you this one and that's where we
have to create to continue to vote to
define those roles where the staff
doesn't feel like there's too many cooks
in the kitchen like oh I go to the sales
manager for this or the inventory
manager or the processing manager and
it's you know we need to make those
roles more defined and that's what we
continue to do is just when we were met
with these issues we write better SOPs
mm-hmm if you take what you view as sort
of the baseline average dispensary and
what they do with employees can you give
me like three examples of something that
you think
I make our training programs are pretty
innovative I think that I've heard a lot
of times from employers like oh well I
was a cashier they trained me for like
two hours or like I know everything
there is to know about cannabis like I
don't even know everything there is to
know about cannabis you know so I think
that that is definitely something that
sets us apart is that we make sure that
the people that are coming in that are
using our POS system that are taking out
and restocking our inventory we make
sure that they absolutely know what
they're doing it might seem like
overkill it's like hey you're gonna bud
tend for me uh-huh
but that's really the best way to do it
and to make sure that that transaction
is rung up correctly to make sure that
they understand the inventory protocols
inventory how easy is counting rain I
have a four year old she's great at it
but how complicated our inventory
protocols making sure that not only
floor stock back stock holds defective
products um things like all these
different things have to be found in
inventory so it's not simply as easy as
going out on the floor picking up a
bucket and counting it you also to make
sure none of those packages are damaged
that they're all in fact the same name
so these are all things that people
think Oh inventories so simple but it
actually requires a little bit more over
walk through the process so I think
that's one thing that I feel like we
almost get made fun of by our employees
for extensive training program but I
also feel a lot more confident that the
information that we're giving to patrons
is standardized because I know that
they've all been through this with me
and they know what is good and not good
to do and save and there's a lot of
myths in our industry that are sold as
facts and so you know what I'm really
excited on is this next phase of lab
testing when we're going to get into
terpene testing that I have a good
friend who manages stores in New Jersey
and there are only time they're allowed
to say sativa and indica is when they
say that it's not true and that's where
I'm really looking forward to us when we
have somebody come
like I need something that's good for
sleep you know it's like we can go to a
strain that's high and lean a lowland
mersin versus let's just say like OG
Kush which is oftentimes one of the top
terpenes and OG Kush is pining which is
a stimulant that's why
oh geez hit you hard and so I'm really
looking forward to this and that's where
to hit on kasi space is that training
you know if a patient comes in they're
diabetic and they're on insulin and they
want to be on cannabis like we need to
let them know that your blood sugar
could shift and you could become more
responsive to your insulin which is a
benefit however if you're injecting
yourself with insulin every day and you
don't realize and you're on the same
dose every day and you're not checking
your blood sugar often you may deal with
issues of low blood sugar if you're on
warfarin and which is a blood thinner it
could increase the effectiveness of your
warfarin these are things that patients
and and customers need to know and as an
industry we've done a very terrible job
of explaining this slowly for the fact
that the research is not readily
available to everyone but it's it's
getting there
and I also think that something that is
very unique about how we do things very
differently is solely just our hiring
methods and how we work and how we sift
through resumes and how we you know
bring on people to our team as an
introduction to where the entire team
isn't just like phase oh they're just
new personality here and it shifts
everything over and it can create bad
stuff around like everybody feels like
they get brought on as a team member so
they know that the whole team pretty
much I wanted them which makes them feel
great about coming to their job and the
rest of the team knows that they that
this is going to be a good candidate and
I think oftentimes just starting people
out if it starts on a bad note those are
employees that don't tend to last long
like they come into work dreading coming
into work their productivity shows so I
think in general like our hiring
practices and
just our accounting practices are very
different so we basically begin with we
go through resumes and we pick X amount
of candidates that we invite for a group
interview so we usually hold it's a
little different because the volume of
the store but you we usually hold for
group interviews which we try and fill
with as many people as possible and then
from that you know that's held with me
and then one of my other managers who
does a lot of scheduling it's ten
candidates with me and another one of my
might its assistant director and she's
in charge of mostly scheduling and
things like that so you sit down with
the two of us and we filter through we
ask you a bunch of fun questions like
Brett said we go off your resume so
everybody introduces themselves and why
they want to be in cannabis but after
that I'll pick from your resume hey
you've worked twelve years in retail
tell me about an upset customer or you
know you've been a paralegal that's we
don't get a lot of those but sometimes
clerks and things like that you know
talk about different reporting
structures that you had to do in and how
you kept those organized you know so we
ask people specific questions to their
resume and it's great we learn a lot of
things we also try and touch base on
their cannabis knowledge do you know the
difference between THC and CBD indica
and sativa etc so from there we choose
our favorite candidates which return
then for a working interview now the
working interview is not done with me
and the my other manager who has done
the group interview this is done with
other members of management and then
with the team so they actually come in
and they spend two hours in a department
so sometimes they're more in reception
sometimes they're more in sales but
they're actually working alongside team
members I think the biggest benefit to
this is that who you say you are in a
job interview in front of people who you
know are hiring managers and things like
that is sometimes very different than
how you act amongst your peers so this
has been I can't tell you how many times
I've loved a candidate and then somebody
else is like no they were you know rude
or unprofessional or all these other
things that comes from my team members
not just other members of management but
their peers the people that are going to
be working on
and they give examples of what the
situation you know just say like it from
a just a condescending way like oh I
just didn't like them like there's
actual proof behind that and that's
actually a best practice that I took
from veterinary industry because in
Texas you're not required to have a
license to work as a veterinary
technician or to run anesthesia or to
place IVs or anything like this and
there's multiple reasons for that and
it's also one reason why you know we
have Texas A&amp;M is the largest vet
schools and Texas it's a way for them to
actually work with more people and the
veterinary costs are significantly lower
there however hiring people is much more
difficult it's it's kind of like the
same ways when I was buying product
before that didn't have lab testing and
all these things like I had to require
all those things well when hiring vet
technicians they needed to come in and
show me that they knew how to place IVs
that they knew how to do these things
even though they may even have a license
that says that they they are registered
vet tech some of the registered vet
techs I knew could not place an IV to
save their life because they always
worked with a vet who placed them and so
there was a checklist of what we did and
it was a lot of it was you know vet tech
staff are very close-knit and if this
was not going to be a personality type
that worked well with it or they didn't
have the skills and to allow them to
work well with it it was gonna cause
issues so when I got into cannabis that
was such a foreign thing like you just
hired pretty girls like I gonna like no
now you actually force them into
stepping inside of their comfort zone
and big thing I look for to its critical
thinking skills or like okay so you came
from banking you were you know a bank
teller you did this like I need to know
that you can translate some of your
business practices over to this and and
I think that's in general I won't get on
that soapbox about critical thinking
skills in general suck most of the time
so where a lot of people especially
younger groups and I'll just be honest
well that is another thing like we do
get a lot of really young applicants so
trying to pull from other places to get
a truly more diverse workforce because I
know
patrons love to see like we have a lot
of older patrons yet they're always
talking to young staff members and it's
really hard to have you know someone
half your age tell you what's up and
that there's there should it be
understanding for their training and
things like that there but I think it is
really important to make sure that your
staff does look like the diverse
population that you get a good sample so
that you know there's somebody that
pretty much everybody can relate to on
your sales floor and it allows for a lot
of empathy across the team of
understanding where what may work for
Brett who is epileptic and they don't
have it they're gonna you go off of what
works well for him and that's what we
also promote cross like but in doing
cross patient consulting we're bringing
on another but gender or a patient
consultant or customers assult a
consultant to help on it with a patient
or a customer so that we can give that
that person the most well-rounded
experience but back to the interview
process they have to heard that working
interview that we go through where we
test for all these different skills and
I agree that it is it's good for current
employee morale because they feel as
though they have a little bit of say and
they're not just gonna somebody who's
gonna come in that they're not gonna
like you know they they feel so they're
part of building this team then after
they do that we have a 30 day a
probation period so you're gonna come in
and you're gonna work for us for 30 days
it's like an internship you're basically
going to get paid nothing and we're just
gonna make sure you can cut it no it's
it's above minimum wage no but we bring
them in at the Epis lower rate to make
sure that again that your weren't
feeding us lip service during your
interview that you're really someone
who's going to be a good fit for this
team and anybody listening to this who's
actually been in a dispensary knows that
the the front lines you know what you're
seeing on this fails for is very
different from the vibe and back of
house you know so being able to be in
all of those sections and as much
it's an interview for us to make sure
that this is a good candidate I think
it's also an essential time for that
candidate to make sure that cannabis is
for them you know they might have
thought oh it's gonna be cool to work in
a dispensary but then the ins and outs
of being there and having to take
seriously something that maybe has been
only fun in your life is too much of a
transition so I think that 30-day period
is also super important and it's during
that time that you get your sexual
harassment training and your cannabis
training and you fill out all the
paperwork and all that and we can extend
the probationary period based on if
there were any issues had come up that
they weren't hitting the milestones that
we were needing them to hit and there's
where at the end of probationary period
we may decide that they're not a fit for
the team or we may feel that we need to
extend the probationary period so that
they can have a better understanding of
what we need from them and I think that
it that's prevented largely with good
communication so if we're every time
they're coming into work we're doing a
better job of like guiding them through
the process this is an industry that is
just regularly hired people just plug
and play and just let them learn on the
floor and that just doesn't work well in
general with any job mm-hmm what I think
is something that's unique about us is
just our accounting and our payroll
services you are getting a paycheck you
are getting pay stubs you know it's like
you paid your taxes your taxes not
getting hit with that event exactly like
we're paying our taxes for you you know
you know that we're paying employee
taxes and workman's comp which is very
different and so I think that's
something for us that is unique and it's
something that's been in my business
practices since I've got into this
industry so we know that payroll should
be realistically taking you know fifteen
to thirty percent of our budget and you
know if we're sitting there where we've
grown so much recently at times that
we're making up 10% or 11% of our budget
is payroll that is a key thing
forecasting high when we need to go and
say hey we need to hire people we're
sitting here only making a 11% of our
budget is going towards payroll that
means we need to do raises and we need
to do hiring so that we can fill that
void because I know as much as like oh
I'm saving money and it's like no you're
really not because you're burning out
your staff and so for us it's an
and a big component to that is now
offering paid time off I myself took
vacation this summer for a week the last
week of June so I didn't have to be here
for the July 1st deadline and an Cassie
just came back from vacation herself and
for us as directors we get burnt out
really quickly I mean we're working 50
60 hour weeks regularly and I'm
traveling significantly for my job as
well and I get burnt out and when I'm
able to just step away take a three or
four-day weekend and come back at it I'm
able to just my productivity soars and
we've noticed that if it's doing that
for me how could it not do that for the
rest of my staff I think another thing
unique to HR that I think we're doing a
lot of that I'm not sure is happening in
other dispensaries is performance
evaluations I mean you sit out with me
every couple of months and I fill out
the same form like ranking you know it's
like communication skills and
dependability I'd like all these
different things with places to comment
on it so in this way I can make sure I
sit down and I'm appreciative of my best
employees and then I can also help to
develop someone who's struggling because
a lot of times as you're filling these
things out you realize okay I'm
frustrated with this employee because of
her tardiness or something like that but
then there's all these other fabulous
skills that they bring to the table so
how do I reach her on this and having
that one-to-one time and mentorship and
things like that are really helpful with
that so again I feel like it's something
I'm teased by with my team like we're
gonna sit down and read this paper again
but I think in general it does it they
feel more confident that they're gonna
have time to know how they're doing to
ask me any questions to give me feedback
about how it you know the the company
culture is feeling for them I think is
really important and something that I
don't see a lot you know that routine
evaluations I see people do them when
somebody's either troublesome or getting
a raise I'm not seeing that say I didn't
see it in the past with those two things
and and which I do when I'm doing a
written warning which is not very often
what I do I do a performance evaluation
but largely that's actually just as
important to me as it is to them so it
allows me that when I
go into this copy having this
conversation that I'm not doing it from
a perspective where I'm like I'm mad
about this specific thing like it's
allowed it allows for me to give much
more constructive criticism like you're
doing wonderful in this area like I see
the skills that you're applying to this
take those same skills and apply it to
this area so that you can feel that
deficit and that's what's causing you to
have this write up right now so
performance evaluations aren't even
they're not just necessary quarterly or
every couple of months or depending on
the employees that is even it's used to
allow the the manager to have a better
discussion about the changes that they
need to see in the employee and I think
one thing I just kind of touched on a
little bit that's really important is I
also really appreciate feedback from my
customer assistance I want to hear what
their thoughts are I've heard so many
creative and innovative ideas in these
meetings you know where they're not
always sure how to speak up about hey
you know at my old job we had inventory
and we did it this way
they're not always sure how to talk to
me about that but the performance
evaluation is that perfect time when
they have my undivided attention and
that stuff really comes out and I think
that that's really important because it
allows you to see who your staff really
is because not everybody is super
extroverted but like gonna hit you over
the head with their skills you know some
people need a little bit more
development and they still have great
ideas they still should be implementing
them but they just don't always feel
confident in talking about it so taking
that time to sit down one-on-one you can
really get a feel for who your best team
members are
[Music]