[Music]
it's funny because a lot of people
really discount Auto flowers they think
that other low yielding and they're not
good for the breeding scene and and I
got to tell you that Auto flowers are
great for a very particular kind of
grower
they're fantastic for patients they're
fantastic for people with mobility
issues they're wonderful for folks who
live where we live where you know we
start to get the rains they're the last
week of September the first week of
October and our eight-week blooming
flowers are just getting finished and
then the mold rolls in whereas with an
auto flower you can pop a seed on June 1
and harvest on September 1 and you're
well ahead of the you know well ahead of
the weather you might need to you know
you might need to plant twice as many
but the idea that you can get done
without your plants molding is a huge
win
so most people may understand that autos
finish faster but that doesn't seem to
be that doesn't mean the best
application for autos are readily
apparent to everyone so I would like to
hear you both starting with you Jeff how
will autos influence cannabis growing in
horticulture going forward well let me
give two different answers the book as
you indicated is really an introductory
book I like to say it's a book for your
sister and your brother it's a book for
your your Uncle Bob and Aunt Sally it's
not a book for our professional grower
I'm convinced that Auto flower cannabis
is going to change the general
populations attitude about cannabis
because it's the next tomato plant once
in a lifetime I'm 70 years old it's only
happened to me once once in a lifetime a
new plant is introduced to the general
horticultural gardening public the last
time it happened it was the snap pea
they took over the pea world and every
gardener grows snap peas a couple of
times during their career and probably
every year that's what's gonna happen I
think to these Auto flowers because
they're so easy to grow their quality
has risen so high as a result of the
genetics and so that's the first answer
the second answer is this is a plant
which you can grow on a deck
which you can grow outside in a garden
you can grow it in a perennial bed you
can grow it in a pot in the ground and
so it's something that is accessible to
all growers not just people who have big
farms or a big greenhouse and because
they don't have a photo period it means
that people who live in northern
climates like Alaska where on September
21st your plant finally gets the
darkness that it needs to set flower you
also get a frost that night and then
finally for those who do professionally
grow here is a plant which you can use
to enter space between your plants as
they veg the same thing your plant says
they flower you just put them in they
don't care what the light is you can
give them 20 24 hours of light they're
gonna flower based on their genetics and
so you can use your spare space this is
a dream for the entire horticultural
world fantastic so so Seth I know you're
coming from a little different direction
Jeff and I share that we were but very
interested in home growers and patient
growers the other thing I wanted to hit
on was it was how appropriate these are
for patients and for people with lower
mobility because like Jeff mentioned
these are very compact plants right
these pretty much top out at around
three three and a half feet and and
because of that you don't have to do the
reaching and they're not hard to break
down and and you know the patient can
stand up and look all around them for
mold instead of you know trying to work
with some of these nine footers where
they're just impossible to work with
they're beautiful and I love them and I
want to talk them right but but they're
really they're you know they're all
caged and difficult to work with so this
is something that that folks who are
living in an apartment who are growing
in a tent can grow for these together
with no sweat you don't even need to
scrub them and and then if you're a
patient they're so easily it's easy to
use and always going to flower in a
particular timeframe you'd be ready to
go that it really opens up the door but
let's not leave the impression that
these are little teeny baby flowers
because they're little teeny plants you
know I mean there there's there's a
there are some I've seen colors that are
80 grams Wow unbelievable and they'll
have you know 10 of these colas on a
plant so so these
not the the lowrider that you remember
these are a totally new plant ready for
primetime in the book I'm stressed that
it's that from the perspective of an
amateur growing these things they they
don't really like to be repotted all the
time I mean you so I always tell people
to grow them in the original container I
started out with three three gallon
containers because you know I thought
the plants were cute and everything else
and there's something they call it now
super Auto flowers they're really the
same thing but different soil structure
and different soil amounts and so now
I'm telling people I five gallons is
good that you know you'll pick what is
Hardware bucket but seven gallons is
even better and you put the seed right
in it I mean I don't even start them in
a because I think if they if they are
stressed they will flower and the worst
thing you can have is something that
flowers when it's they're not cheap
seeds although you can grow your own
seeds and they become cheap yeah it's
disappointing when they're five inches
tall yeah and I actually I actually did
that for my first time and I have I can
admit to making that mistake my first
tray last year I still like my idea I
put them in root Riot plugs which I like
because um when i find when i propagate
right into soil it's a lot more
difficult to keep the soil or keep the
seed in a moist environment right the
the top of the soil dries out really
fast whereas those root riots while they
are soil and so i'll put the seed in
there let it pop and as soon as i've got
like you know you know firmly
established coddled and leaves then i go
ahead and i put it in before the the
roots are coming out the bottom and they
do make some cute little plants i mean
you I saw a little plant growing in a
thimble with with it with a you know it
had a beautiful little head about that
big was just yeah kind of thing you put
on Instagram and go look at this anybody
goes Wow and so I had a tray of these
right I had a tray of these and and I
let them sit too long in the tray before
I because you're right you said you know
that same week you know right so so I
let them sit to there and so I
tray of very expensive beautiful 8-inch
Auto flowers and each one had this
gorgeous big noggin top and and you know
the the yield per weight was incredible
the yield per $15 seed was not right so
so I'm growing my own and still paying
$15 a gram which is like not not a win
but they made awesome gifts to people
because you give somebody a small plant
with this fully mature bud and you're
like here you go snip it off like let it
dry for a couple days and smoke it and
they're like really well and actually
you know I know we're getting getting
out of order here but but but keeping in
my idea that this is the next tomato I'm
convinced that that in in the next
future few years you're gonna be able to
walk into you know Whole Foods or
wherever at Christmas time and they're
gonna have a little shelf and it's gonna
have you know 30 little Auto flower
plants sitting there that look like a
little Christmas trees they're decorated
you know and then at Easter Easter time
you know you're gonna have a play you
know plants with a little that little
green plastic crap you know this is
these plants are unbelievable they are
so much fun to grow I just cannot you
can I'm peeing in my pants I love this
so so I wanna I want to bring the
conversation back to medical which
obviously I keep bringing this
conversation back to you because those
are the people I work with a lot and so
and we're gonna keep going with you Jeff
and then we'll jump back to Seth so so
in terms of medical Jeff I'd like you to
speak a bit to the ease of growing and
and I've heard you talk about how you
can actually do too much right so I
wanna I would like to hear that and then
and then and then Seth would you pick up
since you are analytically breeding
these to help with particular ailments
I'd like to hear from you how the the
breeding of Auto flowers are can be so
targeted because they're so they're so
quick to cycle so but Jeff let's start
with you well you know these are these
are unbelievable plants and and they
just just the you know the only thing I
could compare it to as a marigold you
know I read a garden column in the in
the newspaper up in Anchorage
and and you know marigolds are the one
plan I say you know you got a have you
got a plan something or you're not a
real gardener so you plan a marigold you
can have you a kid do it with you
because it's the only seat you stick the
seat in the ground it's like a sunflower
seed there's certain see you just put
them in the ground you walk away you
don't do anything and they grow well
they grow the way they're supposed to
grow and that's what happens with these
plants if you put too much fertilizer in
the soil if you put any for I don't put
any fertilizer the first time you grow
it because you may not need it ever you
know you got to watch these plants very
carefully they grow so quickly that you
know that when the whitefly or whatever
decides to hit it all of a sudden it's
going through the stage where the where
the you know the right kind of juices
it's wait a minute
what happened to my plant it's not the
same plant anymore and the insect moves
on I mean these things don't need a lot
of care now you got to keep an eye out
for mildew and the kinds of things that
you normally do but they grow so quickly
that that that if you if you push them
too much they're not gonna grow well the
only thing I do to mine to start when I
buy a seed from somebody I don't know
what you know well there's gonna be any
good I put the mycorrhizal fungi on it
and that is all I do
and generally I've never had to
fertilize any of my plants and they grow
so fast
for those of you who grow indoor
especially in tens you don't really have
enough time to screw them up and that's
fantastic right you know I had never
heard your example Jeff about the the
plant growing through the stage of life
that appealed to any particular pest but
that makes sense the first round I did
I've got no mold issues no pest issues
and and we're you know where I live on
Vashon Island we don't have that much
pest but we always get mold right and
and it's just that their life cycle is
so short a lot of that stuff doesn't
have a time to take over and they've
been bred to get rid of the mold so I
know the good the people that grow it
new breed seeds that's what they were
looking for mo let's get rid of that
mold and they did in terms of being able
to use these plants for different
medical conditions I always defer to dr.
Ethan Rousseau who is somewhere out here
so I'm not going to speak to exactly
what type of compounds are going to help
for particular ailments all we know is
that all of these different compounds
are very useful
trying to figure out exactly how to
triangulate and make use of those
compounds and get them into plants in a
way that's useful for patients and for
people across the world is is really our
goal see unless you live in Alaska where
you let have six plants three of which
are allowed to be in flower you know so
I always tell people don't treat this
like broccoli you know where you plant
it all at once you stagger it and I
don't mean you wait for the crop them to
harvest you know every two weeks or
every week you put it in a couple of
more seeds and then when the regulator
comes to your house you go now I got
three in flower
you know forget the fact that I got 50
pounds of drying weed over here but but
but they really are everything you say
again sort of emphasizes the idea that
home gardener would you know people grow
heirloom tomatoes you know married Mary
and next-door neighbor she's famous
because she's got the Oregon summer
spring and and George next door is
famous because his are plum tomatoes
gonna make the best sauce you know and
they give them away and and that's the
same thing that's gonna happen with
these auto flours mine look at the
colors on this one look at the landscape
capabilities on this one you know
they're not they're gonna be landscape
plants they're gonna be a plant that
everybody access we've got to get rid of
that stigma but it's happening and this
is the plant that's gonna carry us over
the line I'm convinced and help the big
plants as well so I really like what you
said too about neighbors sharing right
because if we all have got plant limits
we're limited by our variety and you
know it's just like tomatoes right you
know if you grow tomatoes at home you're
still gonna end up buying Tomatoes at
the store it's not like commercial
tomato growers are all hosed because
we're all growing at home tomatoes you
buy the ones at the store so you get the
seeds so you can grow yourself okay but
but this is another great idea because
neighbors can you know grow different
varieties and trade and it creates
increased community and everybody gets
to try more wheat right yeah and so
that's the win as well so last year in
the a at the Alaska State Fair they
actually in Kenai they had a
you nervous entry thing and I'm
convinced every every State Fair in the
country is gonna have an auto flower
cannabis contest you know I mean it's
just this is the best thing that ever
happened to our industry because it's
gonna get mom-and-pop and Uncle Bob and
he and Sally who normally would be
against it into it that's what we really
need so we can get the taxes out of them
amen
[Music]