[Music]
what are you seeing as far as the
advantages for Auto flowers for folks
that are growing at a scaled level at
acreage size yeah and I would I would
say since this is gonna be on the
internet for ever is for posterity go
back and take a look if you're very
interested about geeking out on some of
the historical background on ruderalis
that's that the technical term for auto
flowering plants ruderalis is Latin for
derived from ruderal which is rubble
from the rubble these are plants that
can grow anywhere like they can grow
where it freezes they can grow through
frost they can grow in very very crazy
situations and actually finish the the
trick at industrial scale is really
being able to get them in the ground at
the right time so whether that's a
direct seeding or transplanting before
the plant goes through stress there's
some underlying genetic mechanisms that
lead the plant to go directly into
flower when it senses a stressful
situation just to step back for a second
because of that posterity say take a
look for that geek out moment at Ernie
smalls
Ernie smalls as a Canadian researcher
who's been working on cannabis related
issues for the last 45 years
brilliant gentleman and he is the person
that was responsible for coming up for
the industrial hemp zero-point-three THC
rule and if you go back and look at his
earlier writings that was based on
taking a leaf off at the top at the
plant rather than testing the top eight
inches of flower at 0.3% hopefully
that's going to be incorporated into the
USDA rules to say move forward at the
farm bill but in 2018 he wrote a seminal
paper and I'm sure that this is going to
go down as one of those Testaments to
auto flowering plants and in the long
term the the paper is about highlighting
the fact that these day-neutral auto
flowering plants represent really the
peak in human agriculture so in a lot of
other crops the reasons and rationales
that we have for expanding the total
productivity of each individual crop on
a per acre basis has come down to plant
breeders geneticists
over long periods of time being able to
make the plants more compact make them
more uniform and take wild types of
plants that tend to have seeds in
varying places on the plant and
consolidate them into a usable machine
harvestable really energy dense organism
and that's been a true for many of the
other crops that have been domesticated
Ernie smalls goes so far as to say that
that is the most profound thing that we
have seen in over 13,000 years of human
agriculture is this move towards he
called some semi dwarf or dwarf germ
plasm so the title of the paper is dwarf
germ plasm and essentially it's about
how to get tremendously large yields
both for food crops if you're growing
for seed hopefully in places where
they're not growing for sensimilla or a
cannabinoid products we'll get into that
later but also for cannabinoid
production in general so it's it's all
about being able to maximize the space
minimize the inputs and really allow
both farmers and people who benefit from
these compounds to have more access to
them and and to benefit from this plan
and auto flowering plants are tremendous
at this maybe we don't know explain so
these plants if you if you're not
familiar with Auto flowers two things
first of all they'll start to flower in
eighteen days up to three weeks they'll
just flower period which is pretty
incredible which is pretty incredible
and then the the the other thing about
them is that they that you can you can
you can overdo it with them this is a
plant that grew quickly they were
discovered and and and about 1900 1903
scientists found him in the Volga River
area in Russia he described it it had
low low THC or no THC and so they
basically forgot about him and then in
the 70s people started to say hmm maybe
we could breed these and so you know the
breeding happened and then in 2003 a guy
was able to successfully commercialize
one called lowrider
and and you know these are the ultimate
heirloom kind of thing they're not a
land race really I don't think anymore
but they're their heirloom and you can
you can breed these things they go
flower and the you know 18-day third
third week by nine weeks they're
finished you harvest it Wow
the breeding potential and opportunities
on these things are just spectacular so
so the opportunity to be able to improve
on this plant like we have in theory
improved on some of the some of our
agricultural plants is absolutely
incredible
another thing that I love about them is
that if you have got a greenhouse
environment but you don't you really
want to supplement with light for for
whatever reason you can actually do two
cycles of Otto flowers without light
depth and that's crazy right
no I'm experimenting with that this year
and the biggest thing I ran into was
trying to keep them warm
because Otto flowers don't particularly
like to start off their life with cold
feet but the idea is you know you can
you can have your you can you can start
something early spring and have it
finish 4th of July and then put put
seeds in that same no-till environment
let those pop and they're done by
October 1st
so you've run two cycles and and and you
don't have to pull any tarfu which we
all love to avoid right and so um so
that's fantastic and the other thing I
wanted to hit on was it was how
appropriate these are for patients and
for people with lower mobility because
like Jeff mentioned these are very
compact plants right he's pretty much
top out at around three three and a half
feet and and because of that you don't
have to do the reaching and they're not
hard to break down and and you know the
patient can stand up and look all around
them for mold instead of you know trying
to work with some of these nine footers
where they're just impossible to work
with they're beautiful and I love them
and I want to talk them right but but
they're really they're you know they're
all caged and difficult to work with so
this is something that that folks who
are living in an apartment who are
growing in a tent can grow for these
together with no sweat you don't even
need to scrub them
and and then if you're a patient they're
so easily it's easy to use and always
going to flower in a particular
timeframe you'd be ready to go that
really opens up the door but let's not
leave the impression that these are
little teeny baby flowers because their
little teeny plants you know I mean
there there's there's a there are some
I've seen colors that are 80 grams Wow
unbelievable and they'll have you know
10 of these colas on a plant so so these
are not the the lowrider that you
remember these are a totally new plant
ready for primetime just to add on to
that so yes you can make them flower in
general for field production we're
looking at about 77 days from the time
that the seed emerges in a starter plug
transplanted into the field within the
week 77 days from that time of emergence
until we harvest it and what Jeff is
saying is absolutely true what we see
with regular photo period plants is the
stem in stock weight accounts for about
27 and a half percent of the total
biomass of the plants with these
day-neutral plants you're looking at
roughly nineteen percent so this is a
order of you talking about a significant
percentage of increased biomass now the
one thing that I will say and it's it's
a little bit of a little bit of a brain
bubble is try growing one of these in a
hundred gallon smart pot okay so it's
really nice for patients or someone
who's just trying to experiment with one
of these plants in the three gallon
container to have it on their deck it's
amazing it's really cool the very useful
plants they stay small they're not gonna
flip out if you'd hit them with a porch
light in the middle of the night when
you go outside but if you put one in a
much bigger container you're gonna
notice that the flowering system is
genetically determined based on stress
and stress particularly to the root zone
so you can actually grow five six seven
eight nine foot tall auto flowering
plants if they have enough root space
and they're not restricted they're
actually when we think about cannabis
one of the things that researchers
always go back to is the amazing
plasticity of that plant and its ability
to respond to the environment that it's
placed in Auto flowering plants the
stain
are to me it's the epitome of that all
right so so I don't know I'm gonna pull
together something Jeff just said and
something you just said and take it
further so Jeff loves to talk about how
these scrappy little plants from Russia
you know you can put them in in in Rocky
crappy soil and they still very much
thrive and and you have spoken to me
before just like you just did to all of
us that that thus it's the stress of the
of the roots hitting the bottom of the
pot that's going to trigger flowering
and but I've never heard you give this
example before of these large hundred
gallon pots which makes me very
interested in growing an 8 foot Otto
flower just to do it right so here's my
question is that if if if how do how do
they grow in soil then cuz like I know
you go right into the ground but there's
no eventual bottom of the pot so there
has got to be something going on
scientifically genetic so what's the
trigger yeah in part and one of the
things when you're there are many many
different soil conditions in the
Willamette Valley were blessed with a
number of things including and we'll get
into this as we talk about farming at
scale but we have in certain locations
38 feet of topsoil and if it's properly
prepared you can end up with very large
plants and we had plants that were
averaging a pound and a half per per
plant planted very densely in in the
field just north of Corvallis last
summer for one of our indie trials it
really comes down to proper soil
preparation and the ability for those
roots to just go out and do their thing
when we look at different plants from a
breeding perspective what we're really
trying to do is we need photo period
plants for very particular locations we
need plants are gonna flower early but
they're still photo period sensitive and
we need auto flowering plants so that
you can deploy these these plants in
basically once you've developed a
particular chemo var you can deploy them
anywhere in the world and that's really
what makes these different compounds
available to people so having CBD
varieties having CBG varieties CVC rich
plants more importantly now working on
CBD vc b GV and and cbcb along with
other other minor compounds that we
don't even know how to
to quantify and don't have reference
standards for all of those are
incredibly important and not just from a
from a from a patient perspective being
able to grow it at home and take care of
your own family or take care of yourself
through the joy of actually gardening a
plant or something emancipatory about
being able to do that I think everybody
feels that but being able to make sure
that those compounds are available at
scale at a price that individuals can
actually afford to treat themselves so
it's it's pretty important and these
plants make that possible one one good
example of that is being able to use the
plasticity of auto flowering plants for
a particular ecological niche so most
most people here are probably familiar
with how much grass seed the Willamette
Valley produces so well well I'm a
ballet so them to 95 percent of the
world's grass seed production we're able
to grow grass seed in the Willamette
Valley for better for worse due to the
climate the climate that we have so we
don't normally get rain in the
Willamette Valley through the middle of
July up until the middle of August we
have a month of generally speaking very
very dry conditions and it allows a
competitive advantage of grass seed
farmers who have good irrigation and
great soil to be able to grow this
particular crop cut it down field dry it
it sits in the field for five to seven
days and then it gets combine and picked
up no other place in the world has that
steady climate that allows for that
particularly even though you know most
people like food rather than lawns but
no one else is able to really do this we
can actually do the same thing and use
this Texas ecological advantage paired
with a technological and horticultural
advantage by using these auto flowering
plants to plant thousands of acres of
very rare and useful compounds that are
present in these plants after specific
breeding grow them out and dry them in a
way that doesn't require a huge drying
infrastructure that you would you would
have to have for other crops or in other
locations it's a it's a huge I think
it's a huge step forward in terms of
being able to make these compounds
available make them an everyday thing so
that you can literally walk into any
supermarket and find something that is
useful and targeting a particular malady
we just need to figure out exactly what
those come which is which yeah right on
I've got to follow up questions for you
the first one is is you know I hear from
a lot of folks when I wouldn't you know
I'd become kind of an evangelist for
Otto flowers because I'm so into them
but people people come up to me and
they're like like you know we don't want
Otto flowers because we can't breed with
them and and they're they're not for
everybody and I want my nine-foot plants
and you already dispelled the night.the
short plants thing I didn't I did not
know they were a taller but um but I
like that you just said that there are
particular nature environments where you
want the photo period some that are
photo period but finish early and then
there's the Otto flowers I've not heard
that analysis before so will you go a
little more in depth in there why do we
still need the other two categories we
don't it's just it's nice to have
diversity well we do we do need them I
mean we need them to breed with because
the land race strains our photo period
and so we need those so I mean we need
them good example is when we're this is
something that a lot of us living in in
a black market it was difficult to be
able to get information about the way
that people produce in other areas of
the country or other areas of the world
a great example is Kentucky and
Tennessee so Kentucky and Tennessee have
incredibly wet July August and September
and then they have the very into
September and then through October they
have perfect weather and it's it's
almost like what Oregon is like in late
August early September before the rains
hit so it's most of us know here we need
to make sure that our plants are out of
the field taking care of harvested dried
properly handled it if it's not done by
the middle of September you're really
you're really pushing yourself you're
really chancing it in those areas it's
it's the opposite you want to actually
get your plants out at the end of
October so in that case a long season a
full season photo period sensitive plant
is really the way to go if you if you
have if you have an auto flowering plant
in certain areas you can plant your auto
flowers in early May go back and replant
in mid July and end up getting to crops
and and basically double the
productivity
of what you have available to you I will
say that they are a pain in the ass why
from a breeding perspective so we make
feminized seed we don't use males and if
you can come to me with a good argument
as to what is actually contained in the
male genome that's useful and how you
can access and figure out what those
traits are I'm open to having my mind
change that's what science is about but
the way that we operate is we make
feminized seed and we use females
because it allows us to know what the
chemo type is to know what the terpene
profiles are to know what the potency is
the flower structure and then be able to
figure out how that's inherited from
generation to generation auto flowering
plants are a different animal in the
sense that when you plant that seed that
clock is ticking you can't just go oh
hey that's a great plan well I'll just
revenge it and get some cuttings off of
it and use it for breeding it's done a
great example of this last year we were
I was working through had about 20
different CBG rich plants trying to
figure out what the the average ratio of
CBG to THC was to identify which plants
we could use or at least what the
frequency was for developing really
really high ratio plants and one of the
individuals from that population we sent
the the results into a third party lab
after we tried to screen them in-house
and they came back and said whoa
fifty percent of your total cannabinoid
profile was a compound that we've never
seen before it's not a terpene it looks
like a cannabinoid from its molecular
weight but we don't have any reference
to Enders to be able to identify what it
is and this is this is Pyxis in portland
they're a very good lab they have more
cannabinoids available to them than most
labs in the country and very good
equipment very well-trained personnel
and the person I was interacting with
said can you send me another sample and
I'm tearing my hair out saying that was
the only plant that was it it's gone
it's gone you can't get that back and so
you go back and grow hundreds of those
plants out and you never find that same
plant again so for a structured breeding
program when you're trying to isolate
these individual compounds and turn them
into useful field ready or home grower
ready seeds it poses a significant
challenge
because you only have a certain amount
of time we have literal professionals
now working at our company who are
trying to find other ways of making this
happen and it's this is a it's a
significant technological challenge so
there's ways around it but it takes a
ton of space a ton of time and a lot of
motivation to to really be able to
isolate them so just a they're a
different animal when it comes to the
breeding standpoint that's from a
professional perspective from you know
real amateur perspective if you take two
auto flowering plants and and breed them
together you can breed them ah and
they're fun there's nine weeks holy
crowing all of a sudden you know I don't
think I'll name this year for my wife
just like my big guys do you know what I
mean but it's really kind of fun and the
idea that you can get somebody's you
know genetics and now I could be careful
they talked about genetics yeah sorry
folks I joke here you know too soon too
soon
you know you get somebody's great
genetics he said yeah I wonder if I as
an amateur can I fool around with this
stuff a little bit you know these guys
obviously but you can you can fool
around with it and and you can do it all
winter long and you know under 20 hours
of light you can do it all night long if
I mean it's just this is a fun fun plant
to grow yeah it can be difficult and it
can cause some problems and if you're a
professional grower you got to adjust
yourself a little bit but boy if you are
a professional grower you're growing
medical cannabis get into these Auto
flowers see what you think see if we
can't improve the ability to get more
medicine out there and it it's it I
think it's a really important point to
you you brought up the historical
reference back to the low rider
varieties from 2003 that was a shitty
plan oh but the waters are worse
I grew some of that and it just made me
sick to smoke I mean it's horrible the
terpene profile was terrible the
structure was not great but you can see
the promise you could you could see the
promise and what it took was small-time
breeders who were working under either
medical programs or in their garage
surreptitiously to improve those plants
and it wasn't until 2010 that I finally
consumed some
thing that changed my mind about auto
flowering plants someone had taken one
of DJ shorts blueberry varieties merci
and dominant with a number of different
minor terpene different Terp minor
terpenes that end up making it a very
calm anti-anxiety experience and it's
it's a beautiful piece of work but they
finally instilled that into an auto
flowering plant that made the effect and
the flavor just as good or better than a
lot of the other commercially available
varieties at the time and that was that
was the no you're right the early ones
the interesting but they weren't any
good and that's why you know I remember
I remember there's a listserv called
auto-flowering dotnet which we kid about
they they threw me off because I I got
on it and I say gee I'm writing this
book I need some pictures and they threw
me off I finally thanks this angle got
back on again and Ted has but but you
know when they first started you would
be on grass city or one of those other
forms and you say oh I'm growing autumn
flowers people laughed at you they made
fun of the other you were stigmatizing
basically you were drummed out of the
community so somebody started the auto
for auto net you know and if you go back
at the way you know people were just
sort of struggling services and around
2008/9 somewhere right in that area they
hit the sweet spot you know and then
they started laughing at other people in
the pictures oh my god and on Instagram
just yesterday I saw one somebody had a
one of these movies where it went from
seed to harvest you know in two seconds
holy cow
fabulous I'm telling you folks get some
seeds you are going to love these and
and you know I love to buy feminized
seeds for for my own home growing and to
help patients right because being able
to take males out of the mix if you're
not breeding them this is this is a win
but right now there are still lots of
auto flower seeds that are being sold
regs right so you're going to get boys
and girls and so you know if you if you
really if you just want the flowers and
you don't want to play with the plant as
Jeff is suggesting get yourself some
like fantastic modern you know feminized
seeds from like Mephisto
genetics or somebody who's got a good
reputation and it's all very plug and
play just like Jeff is describing but if
you want to enjoy that that extra
horticultural experience of making
something that did not exist in the
world until you did it you know find
yourself a pack of auto flour reg seeds
and pop a couple of them that you think
sound interesting and it's really easy
to collect male pollen you know you take
you take a branch and put it in a bag
and you shake it a little bit now you
got to back up on and you walk to the
other side or maybe your friend's house
and you've got a paintbrush and you put
some of that pollen on there and yeah
you paint it on to one branch of the
plant and then when you're done next
year you're gonna have like you know 40
or 50 seeds and and like you said you
get to name it which can be the most fun
part but you don't have to wait till
next year that's the other thing I mean
you know these things grow indoors
really well you know in Anchorage we're
really excited about about the
opportunity to grow these things because
we got a photo period the same time we
get the frosted plan this is gonna just
change our whole world right now so Otto
flowers as you just heard from talking
about the low rider old kima bar you
know a lot of people nowadays still
consider them cute right but
professionals are like man you know this
is this is just something on the side
that isn't gonna you know matter to the
rest of us but then you know you meet
Seth and you you walk acre upon acre of
these beautiful plants in September and
the air is filled with terpenes and you
know you're just like oh my gosh I want
to lay up and lay up my content and just
like live here right and so um what I'd
like to hear from you both are you know
commercial applications right or and
specifically let's let's talk about
yield and quality because it's one thing
that it's all incredibly easy and we can
grow them intense but but a lot of
people are thinking about you know this
scale for commercial and also am I gonna
get enough flour for my effort for home
grow so so I'd like you both to kind of
speak to that option well here in Oregon
I mean I would start with new breed
seeds frankly they're in there you know
they're from Oregon they were
the first ones to get their license to
be able to sell seeds and and they are
growing for commercial growers I think
the last time I spoke to him they said
yeah you know the selling the seeds that
the dispensaries just a peon yes so they
want to go home and there are lots of
commercial growers that are using these
things for a couple of reasons all the
ones we've already discussed if you're
growing indoors on racks if you get the
right size plant double racks triple
racks you know you can use the whole
ceiling all the way up to the ceiling
the space on these things make it so
that you can inter space them in between
existing plants which is really a useful
thing to do you you know you've already
got the heat you've already got the
light if you're indoors and to be able
to interspace a little small plant
that's not going to detract from the
bigger plants that you're trying to grow
there's you know it doubles your ability
to get more income as a result of doing
this stuff so I so in that regard it's
important and then of course the idea
that you can get something in seven nine
you know if you want to go longer 12
weeks Wow I mean from a commercial
perspective if the yield is good and the
and and and the power is good if that's
the probably the terpene spectrum you
know you're there why would you want to
grow anything but so so I really highly
encourage you to try these they're
really quite something and to contact
you know people like new breeze season
and get names of other commercial
breeders that are doing it go see what
they're doing we all share information
that's what we do so oh I'm glad you
reminded me of that too before you
answer I want to plug with the correct
URL Auto flower dotnet yeah and cuz I is
a Jeff story with spot on right the
these were the people who were laughed
off of other forums for using Auto
flowers and so they decided to create
their own where they could be misfit
toys together and so you know one of the
things that we've lost in our scene I
think as people gotta have gotten more
money focus is everybody's got IP now
and everybody wants to hide and protect
things and you know back in the day
outside of just like not wanting to go
to jail people were really open to
sharing within the community sharing
best practices swapping seeds all this
kind of stuff which which you're seeing
less on the commercial side
you're still seeing on this group at
Auto flower net because they are they
are all trying to learn from each other
they are sharing best practices because
they haven't mattered for a while and it
really excites me to see some of the
leaders in that particular community
knowing what's good things are gonna be
like in three or four years when Auto
flowers just falls off people's lips so
easily and and these people will be the
new generation of superstars and and
that you know that's cool when when
people who I love an underdog story
right so so so say have some of the best
bud porn I have ever seen yeah the
photos are just incredible so so Seth
going back to you um specifically you
know the the people that you are sowing
seed to are growing at acreage size
right and and and when people are I mean
you don't have to give people pitches
about your seeds anymore but but just
for the sake of this conversation what
does that pitch sound like when they're
all like you know like really you want
me to you know plant a whole field of
these what are essentially still
probably gonna be smaller plants what's
the name of the company give which one
yours uh we don't advertise I owe you
like five emails so we like you know we
can't handle the advertising right now
honestly we we don't pitch it to people
people come to us and say hey I really
want to try this I really want to try
this and we say no you don't it's really
hard you're gonna fuck up you're not
gonna do it right it's taken us it took
us three years to figure out how to get
the plants in the field without having
flowering in trays and actually getting
a good yield this year we're moving on
to large-scale field trials for
different density of planting and we've
stepped back and we're actually putting
it into the hands of much more competent
farmers who've been farming other crops
for their entire life and how many
cultivars that's such a technically how
many different kinds of plants roughly
one okay
not really yeah there's a number a
number of different varieties out there
it all comes down for us it's not about
cultivars ours are chemo types we look
at plants as having very particular
chemical compounds that are replicable
generation after generation ship
corrected it's okay don't worry but it's
it really it comes down to trying to
figure out how you in the same way that
you're describing maximizing space in a
small area inside this is how do you
maximize the productivity on a per acre
basis over thousands of acres and it
really comes down to what we've seen
with successful farmers is either direct
seeding which is wrought with all kinds
of problems that most of you probably
don't care about but it all comes down
to the depth of the the planting of the
seed and you're talking about literally
millimeters will make or break success
down and then the other side of it is
the density of planting for both weed
suppression and to maximize lateral
minimize lateral branching and force the
plants to basically just turn into one
solid flower that's that's really what
we're looking at this year I and then I
would say for 2020 dad definitely will
be ready for you to buy autoflowering
seeds both type 3 CBD rich plants and
type 4 Pierce EBG lines so what are the
other advantages amines clearly the
short cycle is great for scaled
agriculture but when I visited your farm
you were mentioning some other things
like the fact that the plants are
uniform so they're really easy to repeat
cut on a sled cut on a slit so so what
are the what are the you know
traditional farming advantages of this
plant versus the photoperiod ones the
the main one in it again it's gonna
depend on your location in certain areas
you can't cut the plant down and let it
dry in the field and a lot of people
have had questions about that we did our
team did some amazing experiments this
last summer long hours in the field very
hot conditions harvesting about 15 acres
that believe it was about 38,000 plants
in early August cutting him down laying
him down in the field to basically cook
at 100 degrees during the day
and then grind him up and put him into
totes just to see how much CBD would be
lost and what the terpene loss was going
to be and what we found was about you're
gonna lose about two thirds of your
terpenes they're very volatile they just
they vaporize they're gone but there's
still enough to be able to get some some
efficacy from entourage effect depending
on the type of terpenes that you're
working with and their their volatility
the heavier sesqui terpenes tend to
stick around the the really volatile
monoterpenes are always going to be gone
but the moral of the story on that was
that CBD content did not change there
was no statistical difference between
plants that were cut down and dried in
the field versus plants that were cut
down and hung up in a warehouse so again
that's a that's a great thing if you
happen to have a very dry late very dry
late July early August but if you have a
rainy period that may not necessarily be
the plant that you want to use so it's
it's really about like any farming or
any any cannabis production it's about
being able to use the plasticity of the
plant to adapt to your own local
ecosystem and climate sixty five to
seventy percent of them are mere scene
dominant so what we're seeing out I was
fun to walk through and take a look at
the the flowers that ran it for the
competition this year and see the
different terpene profiles and watch the
evolution of what growers and breeders
are targeting at this play go through
and count how many are mere scene
dominant this year compared to years
past versus Turpin alene dominant plants
that's the it's a big thing it's your
your your fuel flavor your diesel flavor
Turpin a lean beta carry awfully and
alpha pining we're seeing that now
emerge in auto flowering plants as well
and it's a little bit more difficult
with auto flowering plants just because
of the breeding that we were talking
about earlier but they definitely pack
all of the flavor and to be perfectly
honest the the potency as well out of
our type four high CBG varieties that
we've developed the individual plant
that has far in a way had the highest
overall CBG percentage was an auto
flowering plant and it came in at almost
16% CBG was over 17% CB GA before addi
carbing it's it's definitely
able to create absolutely terpene rich
cannabinoid heavy and diverse chemo
types with with these day-neutral plants
and i know that you're having the
analytics and you test everything
in-house do their numbers come out
comparable to photosensitive plants as
well on average they tend to be a little
bit lower but it also depends on the way
that you treat them in the light
spectrum don't they also have a little
bit more CBD yeah you can change any of
those I mean from an amateur Rohr seems
to me that there there's always CBD in
my Auto flowers but but I'm not sure
there isn't my bigger plants I don't
know but yeah we haven't seen that cbc
there is a little bit more CBC there at
least there tends to be and that that
actually it depends on the varieties
that you're looking at but it is it is
definitely present amount of flowering
plants let's just spell another rumor
about taste I know that you spend a lot
of time breeding them and a lot of
people say okay so this is a cookies
Otto flower so essentially that means
that's cookies crossed with a ruderalis
plant and a lot of people say that Rudy
Rudy plants taste like crap right so so
what do you have to say about people
saying that there's all this like this
this ruderalis terpenes coming along for
the ride there used to be I think that
used to be a valid a valid valid
distinction one of the main things to
consider as well is normally what you're
trying to do in a breeding program is
look at the f2 so you take two parents
that are very divergent across them and
then do it either an open pollination or
a targeted selfing in the the f1
generation and then you have f2 plants
that exhibit every possible combination
or permutation that you can possibly
imagine it's where the most diversity is
expressed if you're a plant breeder
that's where you should be looking for
amazing things if you have a specific
terpene profile that you're trying to
target you can't overlook that f1 cross
because that's that's actually where you
would identify the plants that have the
most similar profiles to whatever it is
that you're trying to target so yeah you
can we get very I won't say very easily
but you could take a
Jiji for a prostitue an auto flowering
plant and then do your initial selection
in that f1 inbreeding one more time and
you can you can lock those terpene
profiles in it obviously takes more time
for stabilization of traits and that
sort of thing but terpenes making it
taste good we can do
[Music]