we're really excited about the s like a
fertigation system called rhythm that
we're just having installed and so that
can really just dial in some of our
systems further it's like we can
actually see like how dry the plant is
and what that time like okay here's when
I watered first this is my dry vac time
and the system will know exactly based
on the parameters we set in it when to
water it again and some other day that
we collect okay what's that runoff look
like what's the tissue analysis the
plant look like what's the soil holding
what's still inside there so we can kind
of go back in program and dial in these
strains even further so like we've
developed a regimented system where you
know we know the genetics of the strains
you know like my Saturn og is an Afghani
cross and so you know I want to borrow
that right and we can actually optimize
the system faster because we have that
good data set of collection we know it's
like okay this Afghani likes this kind
of this kind of fertilizer blend or this
little bit of soil difference and if we
find another strain that might have
another Afghani cross it's like okay
well we've already got a baseline for
that genetic so we can optimize it
faster by doing that but I'm really
excited about that you know the
environmental control systems like link
4 we're working with them pretty closely
so I'm really excited with kind of the
data collection and now we've we've
hooked up a lot of those servers and
sensors to a sequel server database and
we can actually pull all the data out of
that and mash it up with like these data
visualization software you know I think
the the thrust of it is data is that
collecting more and more data about how
much what are they using and so forth
and really getting it down to a very
fine art you know it's really when you
get the most production right the
cleanest production also and it's it's
repeatability to