so Sabrina brought up an excellent point
the July first transition so the bureau
took a lot of heat when we did not
extend the transition period there was a
tremendous amount of pressure on us to
extend it we did not we did not change
our regulations and we did not extend it
I am one question two questions for the
panel how did you feel about that
decision and how did it affect your
business operations you know my personal
feelings about the decision were that I
had been approached by some retail
operators and other operators in
industry to to put my name with those
who were asking for an extension and for
ourselves as the laboratory an extension
wasn't really going to be material one
way or another in terms of readiness or
our execution because we were already
doing what we needed to do for July
first but what I was seeing was that
having to do with the inventory that was
being held an evaluation of inventory
that was either owned by yourself or by
another party that you were in contract
with that the particulars around the
ownerships of those inventories and the
date of its production in some cases
because the deadlines either weren't
understood or anticipated with respect
to when things were manufactured or
harvested and when they could continue
to be sold that I became aware of
certain people who I personally cared
about a lot that we're going to take
enormous losses that could potentially
put them out of business as small
business owners and so as a small
business owner entrepreneur I have a lot
of compassion for those people and I was
I was dismayed that they were having
such a negative impact because I've
known them since my company was founded
eight and a half years ago and to be in
business for eight and a half years or
ten years and suffer that kind of blow
and you know in one that you really
can't affect and and and maybe if their
own responsibility in their own fault
because they weren't prepared or they
weren't engaged and that may have been
what happened but it was unfortunate
just as from a humanistic perspective it
was unfortunate to watch that happen for
people yeah
I personally I would have liked to see
an extension for all the reasons that
you said the I do wonder though if we
had extended I'm sure this is part of
what inform the decision not to us would
it have been any different another six
months hence right so personally I would
have liked to see extension an extension
because I think that it needs to be a
smoother transition from the unregulated
to regulated market from business
perspective though anticipated that it
would be held hard and so to that July
date so we amped up for it and there was
a lot of market share to be got during
that period of result and then lastly
just you know kind of embarrassed by the
Instagram and social media posts of just
all these empty shelves throughout our
state one of the biggest you know
concerns I have is the the lack of
dispensaries in our in our market being
a supply chain company so I hope to see
those shelves filled again and that's
robust market so it's a little scary how
much of a reset it was yeah I agree I
think it would have been delaying the
inevitable if you had just moved it and
there the reactions would have been the
same it I made sure that you know that
the buyers at BPG were in communication
with their vendors to make sure that
they were as prepared as they can be and
and you know how that communication gets
through and whether it's received on
that end I I don't know but I I I think
that it it definitely helped to provide
a sort of a process for them because a
lot of them didn't really know what to
do or what was even going on or that
there was even a July first deadline and
you know just to ensure that we did have
enough products and and you know didn't
lose out on any of that and all of the
testing and Berkley's testing standards
have always been extremely high than the
highest in the state so most of the
vendors that we worked with were pretty
used to you know meeting those rules
anyways so the testing wasn't as much of
an issue as the packaging and labeling
which also kicked off a lot of
discussions and arguments but I think
that yeah I mean a better
to happen now and to have everybody
adjust right now if this is all it's
inevitable and you know we've been
fighting for this for a really long time
and here we are so this is what it looks
like and I just look at it as growing
pains and you know it's it's really hard
to see you know like you said some of
the these own smaller business owners
that just don't have the resources or
the bandwidth to really keep up with all
of these things and and find themselves
in a situation where they're not
completely able to comply to the extent
that they can get their stuff online
right away I think a lot of this is a
very flexible creative industry that has
managed to survive through many
challenges in the past and I think that
that spirit will continue on and people
can be innovative and and find a way so
I I think it was it was good yeah I
would say that despite preparation
beginning in June for the July 1st
changes the end of that grace period you
know flow Cana suffered significantly in
early July as we didn't agree with our
retail clients on what were the
packaging requirements and that was that
was really challenging to not see eye to
eye have us all trying to comply but
disagree about what the rules said that
was very challenging and at the same
time despite the pain that we felt and
what I assume many many companies felt I
would say that I still salute the BCC
for not flexing on that because this is
the beginning of the relationship of
there's an open period where we all get
to talk about what the rules should be
and then we will enforce the rules and
so I salute you for enforcing the rules
when it was time to enforce the rules
and we learned that this is this is a
sort of a weak link situation a weakest
link situation in the industry where
those who and we're gonna confront it
again in the near future probably when
these regs go final we will have those
who didn't prepare enough and
businesses will choose oh you're not
prepared I'm not going to do business
with you right now and that may be a
make-or-break moment for those who
didn't prepare and yet that is the way
this industry and any industry works
you know it's competition and we can
seek to out-compete each other on
compliance to the state's benefit and I
think a lot of farmers were kind of
caught off guard I mean granted the
transition period was published but
we're transitioning away from kind of a
bulk flour market so traditionally
cultivators have provided bulk flour
into the retail sector and that's how
it's gone into vending departments so a
lot of cultivators weren't prepared for
packaging they didn't have a brand they
didn't have containers they're used to
bringing whole pound units and then
having the dispensary package and so
when you're in a position to try to or
have to start figuring out packaging
first of all the timeframe on that is
you know six to six months to a year to
just try to figure out how to source and
how to put together compliant packaging
so as humble its finest we started our
rebrand for compliant packaging in
January and what we what came what we
came up against was that as early as
April the distributors we were working
with were like oh no no we're not taking
anymore product unless it's prepped for
July and we're like oh my gosh this is
kind of crushing because here we have
packaged product that you know should
have been able to be on the shelves
until July and then our our distributors
were kicking it back because they didn't
want to have anything in their stock
right come July 1st that wasn't
compliant so we'd already been doing the
testing and for us it was dealing with
the child resistant packaging component
especially when we looked at pre rolls
we do a lot of pre roll cigarette or
cannabis cigarettes so trying to figure
out how to especially in single serving
sizes manage that CRP component was
really challenging and it was expensive
but we're there and I think if people
didn't plan you know six nine months
in advance they really got caught off
guard with it and so it's it's a yeah
basically have a point person that you
could put on that and the resources to
do it to be prepared as what we found
you know one point to add on I think
that was actually really important about
the July transition that's very focused
on the lab sector was the increase in
testing requirements and the increase in
the compound lists because the phase 1
pesticide list really didn't encompass
what's normally used on cannabis and the
things that were usually the most
concerned about finding and so I think
that delaying the implementation of the
face to pesticide list especially would
have definitely been an error yeah that
really it's really helpful to your
perspective
[Music]