I mean as a rush maker I wouldn't trade
this place for anywhere else in the
world ever I mean I would go back to
India for a spell but you the plants as
hash like its flower because everyone
smokes flower but if you go to producing
countries they don't see the plants or
something to dry everyone's talking
about hash ashes in the culture you have
kids from the age of three or four
helping and robbing and caring plants or
at least going up to the beaches to the
oldest grandmother and it's like they're
all working and they all know it I mean
the adversity harvesting the mountain of
the Himalaya is not quite the same than
just race of the Unversed
here in the mountain I hear it's like
fuck it's so fucking an Elsi that
sometimes you don't really want to be in
the middle of your office when it should
be the most amazing time of the year in
in producing country actually it's
because of the people coming to rip you
of the police there is a lot of stress
and gun and people lock sheep a on edge
because it happens then on top of it if
you have bad weather and you don't want
to be around it like it is for there is
no joy into it it's not until I came
hard cap let beepers out to relax and
they tackle kids done because it has to
be done there is so much on the cap
let's say