[Music]
we have to continue to make the case for
why we believe prop 64 should become law
today and so I'm just honored to be here
and to talk about the possibility of
California having a legal adult use
Recreation
marijuana industry potentially in the
very near future and uh as Californians
um begin to think about how they're
going to cast their votes um we know
that there's been a lot of information
about prop 64 that's been put forth a
lot of misinformation also uh but I
think it's fair to say there are still
concerns on both sides whether you're
for or against it uh I personally I'm
still on the fence and I will tell you
why as I um uh present my remarks
clearly clearly from a social justice
perspective from the perspective that uh
we have had this uh wrongheaded drug
policy uh for decades after decades that
really hasn't done much with respect to
um uh um really minimizing um serious
drug use but also with respect to our
incarceration policies uh this is
something that uh the time has come to
address that however when you look at uh
what the Practical effects of this
measure will be and I'm you know and
I've been doing public policy work
particularly in the finance arena for
almost 35 years and I like to think that
um you know I chose the finance Arena
because it's a way to actually try to
approach problems not necessarily by
throwing money into it but looking at
you know how we can actually use um
dollars as an incentive there are lots
of incentives for voting for this
measure uh the first of which is the
economic impact to
California uh the entrepreneurial
opportunity this could
create uh tax revenues for local
agencies in the state and as I look at
those numbers it portends well with
respect to why we should be voting for
prop 64 uh the initiative as you know
allows uh people ages 21 and older to
possess and cultivate in their homes
small quantities of marijuana for
personal use now supporters say is going
to raise significant funds for after
school programs for job training drug
treatment programs and also reduce
criminal justice costs by the tens of
millions per year um now most of you
knows I was introduced by Susan I am the
state's Chief fiscal officer so I bring
kind of an economic perspective um to
this issue prop 64 would regulate the
industry and generate substantial tax
revenue that is definitely true uh
opponents even some who believe that
marijuana should be legal make strong
arguments that prop 64 does not address
enough of their concerns and this is uh
we've heard him uh it is uh things like
not establishing um DUI standards um it
allows advertising that can be seen by
young people uh one report touted by
opponents of 64 suggests that marijuana
should be treated like tobacco legal but
unwanted and it's been 20 years since
voters approved prop 215 the
compassionate use act allowing medicinal
use of marijuana some 55.6% of
California voters said yes to prop 215
back in
1996 and uh I was serving as uh the
chief Deputy to State Board of
Equalization chairwoman Carol mden from
San Francisco when Senate Bill 420 by
the late Senator John bin celis took
effect about eight years later in 2004
and as you know that bill allowed for
the formation of cooperatives and
collectives to provide cannabis for
medicinal use it also created the card
identifying um qualified patients and
caregivers uh who were authorized to
procure cannabis on a patient's behalf
and this protected patients and
caregivers to to some degree but in the
eyes of the federal government uh they
were and are still engaged in illegal
activity none of that changes under prop
64 as the state's Chief fiscal officer I
view the possibility of a well-regulated
adult use
medical Adult Ed marijuana industry in
California in terms of potential and
also in terms of challenges and as a
California tax official I've seen
firsthand some of those challenges uh
after my predecessor um Carol M left the
board to be Equalization for seat in the
California state senate I was appointed
to serve out her term in my first months
in office I heard of uh dispensaries
that the Board of Equalization had
denied sales sellers permits for
medicinal marijuana because retail sales
had not been
legalized and the Boe sellers permit
itself explicitly stated that it was uh
not to be used for illegal
activity uh some operators sold
medicinal marijuana for years without
collecting sales tax and found
themselves on the hook for back taxes
that were high enough to put them out of
business and in September of 2005 9
months into my service on the board the
Third District Court of Appeals
determined that Senator vonellis uh bill
Senate Bill 420 did in fact sanction
marijuana
dispensaries so I recommended at the
time that we revised the Board of
Equalization policy to Grant a seller's
permit to anyone requesting one for the
sale of medicinal marijuana as defined
in the compassionate use Act of 1996
and the medical marijuana program
created by sb420 for the purposes of
collecting taxes due to the state and
you remember back in 2004 it was a very
different landscape very different
landscape we were seen the DEA quite
often in California uh they were subject
to the um the direction of uh the uh
George W bush era uh we had uh frankly
been putting up the fight with the feds
because a lot of the seized assets were
tax revenue that have been put aside in
bank accounts that belong to the state
of
California uh ultimately the compromise
was to say that the Board of
Equalization should end the explicit
refusal to Grant sellers permits to
businesses engag in illegal activity and
to no longer require that cannabis
businesses disclose the nature of their
sales and this was a way that we felt we
could actually have dispensaries um
really operate as legitimate businesses
in their communities and certainly not
have the tax board make any judgment
about the uh illegal or illegal nature
of their activity
so uh it was an unanimous vote I
convinced my Republican colleagues to
vote for this and the effect was to
allow dispensaries essentially to
operate within legal guidelines and
collect taxes due to the state but even
so the wording of that compromise
highlights the fact that the state
government still found itself walking a
tight line between state and federal
regulations and do not want to be seen
as condoning Federal illegal activity
and I remember how much of a tight RPP I
personally felt like I was walking I
felt this was the right thing to do it
was a way to get those who were
operating Underground to come above
ground to be recognized as legitimate
businesses and yet at the same time I
have my chief counsel of the board just
essentially kind of put his arms out to
say don't get too far out there because
of the federal prohibition so this
conflict is not um easily resolved and
obviously some further Federal um
further effects of federal prohibition
relates to
Banking and you know when I think about
some of the the issues that are still
unresolved today that will continue to
be unresolved when prop 64 uh should the
voters approve it become
law we still have the nasty issue of
banking that has not been resolved and
to me that is the singularly biggest
issue that we have got to make some
movement forward and uh it's my hope
that if California voters decide that we
should have an adult use recreational
marijuana industry here in California
that the federal government and our
Congressional Delegation will begin to
move to allow banking practices uh to
support uh marijana
[Applause]
businesses uh for 45 years the federal
government has had a banking secrecy act
that Outlaws laundering money obtained
through illegal activities through
financial institutions and uh I know
there have been some financial
institutions Credit Unions I know we've
read about in other states Colorado
Washington uh that have uh tried to be
of support most big banks will not
create an account for cannabis business
regardless of state law because
federally it is still illegal now the uh
Financial crimes enforcement network is
an arm of our federal treasury charged
with enforcing the banking secrecy act
and known as finson this enforcement
Network laid out some very specific
guidelines and said it will not take
action against financial institutions
that follow them the finson reporting
requirements are so time intensive and
labor intensive that financial
institutions if uh they allow
dispensaries to have accounts will
charge a steep monthly fee and for just
your uh regular uh normal dispensary uh
it probably is not worth it financially
despite the risk of running an all-cash
business so many in law enforcement have
conflicted views on legalization on the
on the one hand they would love to
eliminate the danger people people face
when they encounter illegal grow
operations guarded by well-armed
individuals um you know I look at our
tax board as not necessarily law
enforcement we are there to facilitate
tax collection and uh but I do have to
say it continues to give me pause when
uh each month or every quarter we have
to make special arrangements with
medical dispensaries medical marijuana
dispensaries to uh accept their sales
tax payments in cash you know from a
public safety perspective and you can
imagine and that getting magnified under
broader legalization that's a huge
concern so on the one hand while I don't
necessarily um agree with our law
enforcement community that uh the
typical public safety issue of Law and
Order is going to be um front and center
with prop 64 it does present other
public safety issues including this so
um Washington state has been very good
as I said with helping um its Credit
Unions understand the finson guidelines
and make accounts available to State
authorized cannabis Sellers and we hope
that this is something that our um State
of California government can also help
facilitate the state of Colorado was
leaving it to the feds to provide
stronger guidance and leaving it to
financial institutions to decide the
level of legal risks that they are
comfortable assuming uh it is estimated
that Colorado will have 1.2 billion in
cash transactions this year alone so
this is a problem that's not going away
and in fact will probably come exact
maturbated given the growth in the
industry uh overall about 40% of
cannabis businesses Nationwide say they
have been able to open a bank account uh
and that's a start but it leaves six out
of every 10 cannabis businesses in a
potentially unsafe position uh clearly
there are challenges to uh to address in
order to successfully launch a legal
recreational Cannabis industry in
California but there's also amazing
Economic Opportunity and I believe
that's why most of you are here Colorado
Washington and Oregon are averaging a
combined 123.5 million in monthly sales
of legal recreational marijuana and
that's uh as of this year and Oregon has
not even opened its retail stores yet if
steady increases continue there's a
potential for them to have $2 billion in
total sales this year there are between
100,000 and 150,000 people already
employed in the Cannabis industry in
Colorado they are even seeing what some
call um Can tourism
now uh tourism in California Susan was
asking me about this uh we have a uh
tourism business that amounts to about
12223 billion a year and uh Leisure
travelers to the state of Colorado uh
spent $98 million at our recreational
marijuana uh at recreational marijuana
stores last year um which represents 17%
of total sales but what they're this is
becoming a tourist industry and so we're
seeing bumps of potentially 20% in
tourism dollars uh which certainly can
help the economy as well so 20% of$ 122
$123 billion it's pretty big pretty big
uh gain for California uh sales could be
um 1.6 billion in the first year in
California and by 2020 the legal Market
in California could be well over $6.4
billion uh the California Legislative
anas Office estimates that state and
local governments could collect net
additional revenues that could
eventually top a billion dollars a year
and recent polls by the public policy
Institute showed that support for
legalization has increased since the
failure of proposition 19 and 2010 when
53% of California voters said no to the
prospect of allowing recreational adult
use of marijuana so the needle has moved
actually uh pretty quickly in the
direction towards legalization today 55%
of likely voters say they support
legalization I think some of the more
recent polls have that higher and the
partisan divide is not as wide as one
might think uh Republican support has
increased 10 points since 2010 to
44% now the only demographic that has
not increased its support for
legalization are people 35 to 45 years
old and particularly those with children
under the age of 18 perhaps reflecting
some of the concerns I mentioned
earlier now as the person who pays the
bills for the State of California and as
a member of the board charged with tax
collection I am looking at the Canabis
industry the uh adult use legal cannabis
industry as an eventuality
uh we will get there whether it be this
November or sometime soon and as such I
look at the challenges faced in terms of
seeking the solutions necessary to
overcome them and it's imperative that
when we do legalize cannabis we do this
right we do this right uh you know there
is enough public opposition to this
measure whether it be from concerned
parents whether it be from law
enforcement whether it be from you know
just uh those who believe that uh this
is the beginning of you know what we're
seeing um being developed as you know
big big Corporation cannabis you know
being established um there's even
frankly opposition within the industry
and so when we look at this opposition
it's imperative that we understand what
the uh arguments against the measure are
and to also look at how we're going to
get them addressed because they are not
going to go away and frankly the
opposition opposition um interests are
all going to be looking for missteps as
we carry out uh the uh mandates of the
initiative should it pass and one
misstep could really up in the industry
so there's a public perception but
there's also a public reputation
associated with this issue and I think
um you know I've been uh one to where I
feel my role certainly as a as a tax
collector certainly as a CFO I'm not
going to be part of any of the
regulating authorities in California
under prop 64 but we have to do this
right and I committed to rolling up my
sleeves and figuring the stuff out um
I've long advocated and have made the
ask of our federal officials to allow
California to actually have a banking
pilot you know just give us a chance to
just interface with our financial
institutions and just see what it is
that is so problematic that we have uh
dispensaries be able to do business with
our traditional financial institutions
so um you have a panel that's coming up
that's going to be talking about
different perspectives about um adult
use and um but the other thing I just
wanted to say um is this when we look at
um what the proposition provides for you
know the other great concern I have is
that we haven't had a track record with
respect to the regulatory framework that
was developed by the legislature for
medical cannabis and uh some of you know
this in the room and others may not but
I've spent the better part of the last
15 years working with the medical
cannabis Community it has been a tough
fight it's been a tough fight and we're
still not done so so aside from banking
we need to be sure that the federal
government recognizes these businesses
as legitimate businesses for tax
purposes so we can have business
expenses deducted and all of the other
tax benefits that it may uh it may use
to uh reduce their cost of doing
business but also uh as I look at just
even the regulatory environment as it
will evolve with the passage of
proposition 64 you have the Department
of Consumer Affairs that will be the
lead Agency for oversight of this adult
used cannabis industry you have the
Department of Public Health that will
have jurisdiction over testing and
Manufacturing and I will tell you right
now that department has zero banwi to do
that and how are they going to develop
that we have the department of food and
agriculture that will oversee all issues
related to
cultivation and we know that when uh
agencies delve into their specific
jurisdiction other issues will emerge
and I don't know how you speak about
cultivation without looking at issues
around pesticide use energy use water
use so I'm surmising that when all is
said and done and we actually get a
regulatory framework which now looks
like if 64 passes we'll piggyback on the
work that's currently being done for
medical but that is um I can easily
foresee over a dozen regulatory entities
at the state level overseeing adult use
recreational
marijuana now doesn't give you comfort
in terms of being a part of that
industry but at the same time uh I think
what we have to do to be honest about
these issues that still remain thorny
relative to what we have to resolve in
getting a an industry regulated and I
and I just need to applaud all of you
because I don't know of no other
industry that essentially has stepped
forward to say regulate
us right right who does
that who does
that and frankly that's your selling
point that's your selling point we want
to be looked at as legitimate businesses
under the guise of the law we want to be
regulated we know what happens when
we're not regulated we don't want a
black
market right and so um but kudos to you
for doing that and I have to say
particularly to the medical dispensary
uh folks who just really paved the way
for that that was not easy for them to
do uh but they've opened that door and I
think that's what we need to do but
here's what I'm going to say u in my
closing
remarks you know as I said we've got to
get this right because the forces that
oppos that still are quite strong and uh
we can't afford any misstep but the
other thing I'm going to say is that
this is going to be need to be very
exacting it's not okay to speculate what
will be or what won't be and there is
more that the body of science behind
this is becoming more and more
robust and certainly with respect to
cultivation there's a whole lot more
track record and experience that can
inform what we do here in California but
I say this to you because um you know
when we are regulatory bodies at the
state level and particularly regulatory
bodies you know up to a few dozen
potentially if prop 64 becomes the law
we don't have the expertise or the
bandwidth at the state level we're going
to need to reach out to
Industry and you have got to have your
act
together I mean to the point of being
very exacting being able to point to the
resources that are have been
demonstrated that have been researched
that have you know just uh shown what
works obviously from a government to
government perspective we'll be reaching
out to our colleagues in Colorado
Washington Oregon but from a business
perspective from a cultivation
perspective uh from what you all have
already begun to do and will continue to
do more of and expand into California uh
we need your
expertise but it has got to be robust it
has got to be based in um hopefully
research and empirical
evidence and it has got to be such that
when we devel this regulatory framework
more broadly that there is
a understanding and kind of a standard
and foundational level of understanding
such that when there is State oversight
and local jurisdictions decide how much
they want to get into this area that
they have the comfort that the state has
got their back so that's what's at stake
here and part of the reason I'm on the
fence is that I don't know that we're
there yet I don't have I don't have
faith in my own state government frankly
uh but I also feel that we can't be
casual about the opposition that's out
there it's very real you know there are
days that I still get mail from parents
who are on me about you know the the
what I pave to kind of make 64 possible
today and uh you know frankly wake up
parents it's out on the street your kids
are getting their hands on it
so you know when we talk about
regulation and that's why you know
that's what you all have done to be
responsible regulate us us but when you
say regulate us give us the tools to be
able to do that effectively and so while
I stand before you on the fence about
proposition 64 I also am very hopeful
about the kind of industry this could
become in California but I'm going to
say but I'm also going to say within
your community within your community
come together there's been a lot of work
done in this Arena and I just need to
applaud those who are in the medical
cannabis Arena because a lot of that
work was pioneering ground break
groundbreaking
and frankly a very lonely time for many
of them many lessons learn from
that and uh you know for me I want to
continue to see some recognition of
medical cannabis when we do have adult
use uh legalized recreational use
because at the end of the day what we're
all after I hope I hope is safe access
to Safe
products and as soon as any of that is
compromised the whole industry will tip
on its head
so it's precarious but it's exciting at
the same time it is serious but also the
possibilities are you know quite
Limitless and it is one where it can be
a game Cher If all of you really step up
to the plate and begin to inform how we
begin to get a system in place that is
responsible that begins to set some
standards and also where as local
governments decide whether they're going
to get into this Arena or not
that they have the comfort knowing that
the state knows what it's doing so it's
a lot of lot of responsibility back to
you but at the same time I'm going to
say that I'm one state level official
who is not going to be shy about rolling
up my sleeves whether a tax official or
otherwise or in any of the other number
of boards and commissions on which I
serve that when the voters approve pop
64 it will be the law of California and
my job is to enforce the law but my job
is also going to be as the chief fiscal
officer how to be sure that this is a
successful industry successful for you
successful for the state successful for
our local governments but also
successful in terms of the state
providing the type of oversight that
will help make this industry Thrive and
hopefully be a model for the rest of the
world thank you all very much for the
invitation to speak
[Applause]
[Music]
he