it's great to be here in the future
cannabis project talking about 2018
reactions and assessments I have to tell
you in 2018 I need to I need to answer
this with with two things that caught me
by surprise the the rapid pace have
changed in terms of perception of
cannabis in this country medical you
know full wreck you name it
little old ladies bi and CBD online from
Amazon it's extraordinary the pace of
change to me even though I thought it
was going to be extraordinary has been
beyond extraordinary from the investment
community's perspective I'm not
surprised at the sophistication of the
players and and the folks at this table
that have you know done this and other
in other venues and are doing it here
and big institutional investors I'm
surprised at how quickly the the
investment community is sorting through
different types of businesses and
different verticals within the cannabis
investment sub sectors and making quick
decisions right now
on who's gonna win and who's gonna lose
and frankly it's pretty interesting to
see how quickly we've gone from people
who were it seems to me and maybe I'm
speaking my own book but you know
assessing where the first mover
advantage was something that seemed to
be universally rewarded and I think
people are now fortunately looking at
companies that are really executing in a
clever way not just because they were
there first from from an international
standpoint it's hard to be surprised
than much you know the Jeff session one
really got me when you know he came out
there's a stark difference between adult
use like medical cannabis I probably
lost at that point maybe 40 50 million
dollars of investor confidence in a day
and I'm like are you actually that
concerned about these things like we
know medically we have these protections
like with omnibus and so forth we know
adult use is totally illegal
we know the ancillary sides completely
fine it's real estate its packaging but
I was surprised that so many serious
investors are so distracted by some of
these little political things that have
been known forever and that that was
really surprising I thought the seasoned
rural investors would know the rules
understand what's happening that's where
I learned a lot of investors don't so
when they ask those questions now I'm
like you're not even serious like we'll
talk to you bout our next funded like
we'll talk to you later on the
international side seeing
what we did in denmark in portugal what
happened in macedonia the preliminaries
to greece we're probably the largest
like licensing group internationally i
would say on a private side but i saw
maybe 25 countries pop up that we're
totally anti cannabis but when they see
the revenue when they see the other
pieces the kids with epilepsy the cancer
all the additional pieces where it
finally clicked for them and my company
our consulting company just went off the
hook on international to where
international needs to be 30 percent of
our book now it's maybe 80 percent of
our book and then seeing where the u.s.
is the largest consumer market but
there's this whole thing called the rest
of the world and like that all needs
medicine ham protein sources so seeing
so many countries come online so fast it
was just realizing this is gonna come
faster than we thought it's always fast
but it's getting exponentially faster by
the day and really the most important
skill set being male to sift through
what's real what's not true due
diligence like in a country that has
four licenses that we have one and here
twelve groups say they have a license
there there's a lot of talk about what
people intend to do versus what they're
actually doing and how they're doing
that or what they did correctly there so
it's gonna get faster if that was what i
realized quickly and I needed more
translators and more Deloitte access
than I would ever think i profits they
previously needed I think the bigger III
I agree with Nick the surprise has been
how fast how many states how many
countries how many people are looking at
this surprised that the Trump
administration let it go and let it
continue I think the biggest surprise I
had this year was the CBD him becoming a
separate industry crossing into all 50
states being to export health and
wellness products made in the USA to
people in Indonesia and the Far East and
in Dubai it's created new markets new
revenue and I think it will help
legitimize the benefits of cannabis
by the CBD getting out there and helping
so many people
[Music]