like just the the thing that surprised
me most was like very very calculated
moves in lawmaking that literally just
undercut the farmer undercut everybody
and and then pretty soon everybody just
started like you know going into fear
and backbiting and all this and
like it just like poof that's that's
crazy so anyway but but kudos to
everybody who's surviving and like you
know putting it in putting in all the
word yeah if you research the 1862
Homestead Act that was the methods for
removing the small subsistence farmer in
the way for big AG and so they're
following the same protocol to wipe out
the cannabis farmers now and they're
doing quick work of it and I think one
of the things that's really caught me
off-guard is like I knew at some point
there would be legal facilities and so I
just put all my focus into knowing the
knowledge that would be valuable at that
point I didn't really put my bandwidth
on much other you know and I some of
this other stuff really caught me off
guard and one of the things that really
caught me off guard was how quickly
we're diving to the bottom and that
really breaks my heart because not not
it's just it's so unnecessary it's like
right now you're you know you're going
some of these trim farms that are doing
acres and acres and acres of just
garbage and they're their business model
is literally to race it to the bottom
sustain people at the bottom and win out
at the lowest quality and just you know
the quality drop from last year to this
year has just been remarkable and you
know we're just trying to be a champion
for you know we can produce low quality
we can produce more we don't have to do
it in a low-quality fashion you know
there's big oil producers dank stuff I
mean when I was talking to Tim Blake
about oil you know for me on a oil
return they're doing it through a
hydrocarbon extraction and we like to
see you know eighteen percent and up and
so when I'm talking to Tim he's talking
about 17 percent listen
yeah well we and he goes no I mean hash
oh bubble hash at 17% returns that
would make some frickin oil I mean so
some of the genetics and some of the
things people have are stashed and ready
to go but some of those people don't
have licenses yet and that's the biggest
change for me to see in 2018 to now or
17 is just the remarkable amount of
people that we're there that aren't
there that are working their way in
it's a pay-to-play type of thing and
it's just definitely you got to stay on
your toes to be in it you can't it's not
coming for you you got to go after it
that's the biggest challenge you know
staying afloat with all the different
changes and fluctuations that have to
keep we're not gonna stop no they're not
gonna stop and you know whether you're a
small farm or whether you're a large
farm adopting science-based principles
for your decision making is the way to
survive in the market as the profit is
dropping because we can't afford to have
catastrophic crop loss we need to do
pretty predictive testing to try to
assess what the tripping points are
gonna be and we need to mitigate those
risks so that we can still produce a
crop we can still be profitable and we
can have an opportunity to make it
through these next couple years you know
we're seeing a lot of pests it's like
another thing that's taking out farmers
is you know pests and disease from
different you know clone nurseries and
you know I had a you know one of my
hydroponic mentors he he lost six of the
first eight flowering rooms because the
clones he got from a nursery had viruses
in them and what really blows my mind is
that how long these products are being
pushed before it's being accepted and
dealt with and you know you know we just
recently had a situation where the grow
off passed out a couple clones with some
rude aphids and they immediately jumped
on that they immediately made a public
announcement Joe drew came out and
immediately owned up to it and tried to
make it right and you know of course the
Instagram gangs you know tried to mean
them off the planet of the earth which
is like the first response and you know
it's unfortunate that that's the view
that the community has of that type of
situation because you know my situation
I analyze these things and so I've been
hired by three nurseries and
last calendar year to deal with rude
aphids one of those farms sent out cuts
for four months with black and brown rue
de foods without owning up to it you
know and so it's like you know it's like
you finally get a license and you
finally get going and then someone with
a shitty conscience gives you some
horrible clones and you know it's like
we're seeing this across the board and
so it's like you know hats off to Joe
jury for be the only dude with balls
enough to own up to some like that
you know deal with it and the other
thing would be you know well so I came
from the world of medicine I was a nurse
before I decided to do soil science and
in medicine you absolutely own up to
every problem immediately or people die
and so kudos to Jo Durie for stepping up
to the plate on that that is huge and it
sets the bar and the standard for
everybody the way it should be
there's no need to hide any mistakes you
absolutely own that that's the proper
way to do it so we appreciate you
yeah thanks mark around
future cannabis project comin atcha
[Music]