[Music]
all right what we have here is an
experimental part had some people
hitting me up talking about
sustainability and using things from you
know your area and so mine started
cooking it and we've got here a
cantaloupe and white bean biology bomb
basically soaked white beans and then I
boiled them then I let them sit for a
couple days until they just started to
give it slight tinge of funk and then I
did my regular avocado tactics on it
malted barley kelp
gypsum crab meal and just went in use
bio Foss and inoculated with Bokashi
little maple syrup and what you have
here is an avocado tech pod sin avocado
we got the white beans in place even in
the structure and the cantaloupe is high
in potassium so yeah here we go gonna go
put these down and get on some
experimental stuff there's no reason why
you can't grow your own melons grow your
own gourds grow your own pumpkins and
use things that are as local as possible
to you like kelp that I harvested off
the beach
local Maine malt company Blue Ox shout
out to them and just trying to use
things that are as close as possible and
you could omit some ingredients and add
some extra ingredients depending on what
you need so mixed up a bunch of the
filling I even have a little bit extra
here because I did some extra beans and
I'm gonna add that into some old avocado
shells they already have up there for
some other plants but hey I couldn't be
accused of not being down with the
movement and so here we are come up with
some different ways for you to use the
avocado tech the biology bomb the fruit
drop theory and use it for your garden
so we're up here in the garden
and everything's in veg right now just
reaching the screen on both sides and
I've chosen the spot for the pod here
underneath this peach skunk not scuse me
it's a cassava which is a cantaloupe
Hays times Bruce Banner number three by
deadpan head short squat little wide
leaf drug cultivar whatever you want to
call it
indica this is the spot I have a trip
emitter right here not too close to the
stock but in the same realm I saw some
worms as I was placing it so this is a
good spot the drip emitter to the side
it will just cask out cascade down the
edge down below sort of umbrella down
keep everything boys another good sign
is there is a little fungal life here on
the top of the cantaloupe I can RDC a hi
boys but smiles they cased radio left
Samantha's crawling on the top here he's
saying what's going on but anyway I've
placed it this is the spot I like to put
it underneath a hub of moisture and
underneath the plant if possible and
trust me the other plants in this bed
will benefit from this as well this is
gonna carry this on a lot longer than
just this this round even
great minerals in there that are not
even soluble as yet but other things in
here other than cannabis are
hustle cherry or the Cape gooseberry
down and and that we have minuet and
herb or aka herb Estella which is an
edible green has a little salty kind of
aspect to it it's great
probably sequester sodium in your system
and then I have some wheatgrass as well
as bush beans yellow bush beans and I
didn't see some dill popping up here now
it's interesting yeah I toss seeds that
I think will be beneficial willy-nilly
in here when the system kind of accepts
them wet them it sprouts them it's on
them not me so everything's looking
great man and I'll check into nan this
couple days three to five days we'll
check in peace I'm back it's been five
days and got some great growth in here
everything is really jumping up to meet
the screen some of its exceeded the
screen but I wanted to check on the
attack here I'm not gonna flip a pod
today only because
besides of fungal hyphae spreading out
all over the place around the bottom
edge I don't know if you remember but I
believe they discovered penicillin on
cantaloupes again there's definitely a
lot of
tivity going on here
so yeah I'm not gonna disturb it I'm
sure that there's a lot going on under
here right now but I'm gonna wait until
that 10 day mark to really give you guys
a view into what's gone on since I put
the pot down but definitely a great sign
to see all of this
activity happening several different
strains it looks in various different
stages of decomposition but it is going
around the entire bottom and also
creeping up onto the cantaloupe itself
one thing I haven't studied before is
how the shell of the cantaloupe or the
skin reacts over time so that will be
another one of my experiments here to
see if it holds together and holds that
humidity dome or if it just collapses
altogether but hopefully we have a lot
of worms on the underside working
working that a ammendment field goodness
of white bean as the primary base that I
put down so I'll keep you posted and
check back in with you in a few days
we're back
all right it's been ten days canapes
filled in very nicely throughout let's
continue plants he's doing really great
it's the time to check out the
cantaloupe tech it's been 10 days let's
get down in here it's
yeah
well I can easily say this is more
overtaking with the fungi on the surface
than anything else I've ever put down as
far as avocado goes so pretty excited
about that starting to get more of a
white food and sort of that blueish
Trichoderma so take a look let's get
under here and see what's going on this
is literally cemented to the pod I'm
just going to remove this family for any
Erica's getting in the way a couple of
these families actually
let's dill springing up next door
let's give this thing a left
I would imagine there's still quite a
bit of filling left because of the sheer
density of the filler
it's pulling away but look at that
I couldn't even get underneath it
the flash on the inside so it is
sticking a little bit still a fair
amount of filling left but a awesome
fungal blue
on the inside here of course you can see
worms writhing around on the bottom
couldn't get underneath you know what I
can see movement under there I don't
even want to move it I don't want to
break any into fungal bonds that are
there but we have awesome amount of
worms that have moved in there I can
tell I can see from a distance you can
also see micro life is teeming
straighter lips
shemitahs hanging out on top where the
fungi go as they tend to go and I think
that probably means feed for them
whether it be bold lights or those
little red orbited mites yeah everything
just looks great the feed is going down
it's been 10 days again roughly twice
twice as much feed in the pod so I would
imagine I'll take twice as long to
decompose there's one handy thing about
your avocados it just seems to be the
right size this is a jumbo pod which is
fine you know what this is going to be
for is a pre flower and going into
flower so I'm still in veg I'm probably
gonna give it maybe one more week to
completely fill out some of these spots
and reach the screen
salmon's over here I've got a couple
little guys that are lagging behind for
whatever reason but
everything else is just looking ragin be
healthy and you can see my clover back
there's
you ever grown some heady indoor clover
good stuff
all right so that's what it is I think
we'll extend this out to a 15 and a 20
day check just to see what happens
eventually to this I would imagine that
over Tom's just gonna get to look like a
blown out tire and the fungi will
consume everything so thus far you know
there may be a little bit of an aerobic
activity going on there but it's it's
it's a non-issue I think you've got
enough competitive decomposition going
on that this is healthy for the system
and as you can see the cassava from dead
pan-pan degrees it likes it and so does
its counterpart right next door the
dirty Starbucks from so good seeds
cheers everybody I'll check back I'm
back it's been about 15 days and we are
gonna take a look at the cantaloupe tech
aka the cantaloupe avocado touch I've
applied the same principles as I do the
avocado - I can't elope a little bit a
little bit more longer than something
that you can wildcraft yourself you can
definitely grow cantaloupes and many
excuse me climates melons per qubits
meaning everything of the cucumber melon
family by yourself so I just want to
highlight that that can be used for
avocado tech in place of the meat of the
avocado I opted for some white beans I
think I use great northern white bean so
let's take a look and see what's
happened Wow excuse me she'll even more
overtaken by fungi I did reposition the
hose as the pod started to collapse so
it's literally cascading down over the
top which seems to be pulling up some
moisture which definitely is helping
with the fungal breakdown let's take a
look and see what we got under here
though again the filling may break away
from the pod it's just different than an
avocado but again families have come
into play and are in the way so I'm
going to tuck these that's a beautiful
large lower fans here don't need to
quite remove me yet although coming up I
probably will do a nice little
defoliation as you can see down here in
the under and the underbrush you've got
some work to do I like to clean up all
the legs on all these plants and and
take all the foliage off up to the
screen here so as you can see I got a
lot to do here
plants have risen to the occasion and
our crust in the screen this guy was a
really short broad leaf variety that
it's still taking some time to gain
stature but it's still wide and has a
lot of nodes so looking really good yeah
the moment we've been waiting for
drumroll please
millipedes red wigglers all kinds of
foam going on in there looking good
see if I can separate the two
mycelial mat just covering the feeling
at this point that those red orbited
mites they're chewing on things it's
free to left Simitis predatory mites
okay even see a partially blended beam
there the tough worm is going after and
this one to highlight you know one of
the uses reasons for using Bokashi is
that you know if you have a big pod like
this with a lot of filling and any air
in a rubix situation happens this can be
a means of breaking it down anyway there
it is in action I think this will be a
good 2025 day pod so you need a long
slow release pod this might be your
method cantaloupe and if you can produce
it yourself even more sustainable
regenerative and all the better alright
peace everybody