[Music]
I'm really glad that everyone's here to
have this discussion on materials
specifically biomaterials but like
materials affect everyone's life it's
such a degree that I think sometimes
people forget about it like parents
buying a new couch or office managers
buying holiday gifts or even the Olympic
Committee who is playing like the LA
Olympics are going to be the first zero
waste and energy positive Olympics in
2024 and so like everybody is really
affected by these materials and like
what happens to these materials when
we're done with all of these products so
I'm glad that we can have this
discussion tonight first off we're gonna
introduce Jessica Aldridge who has had a
lot of experience in sustainability and
waste so Jessica you want to tell us a
little bit about your journey yeah I I
have worked in zero waste and resource
management and recycling world for 15
years almost
I am a sustainability and zero waste
programs manager from one of the largest
recycling companies in Los Angeles
County I have my own nonprofit which is
called adventurism waste and it's just
going through its its rebranding because
it used to be Burbank and Alliance and
instead of focusing on sustainability as
a whole we also helped start the local
350.org chapter which is SoCal 350 and
now I'm just focusing directly on waste
and trying to the concept is to bridge
the information gap and experience and
knowledge between those in the waste
industry and the experience knowledge of
those who are just everyday people and
so that we can come to solutions and and
building a site that's a go-to resource
hub so it you know this concept of oh if
someone asks you a question someone ask
you a question you're just writing
everything down on a cocktail napkin and
you hand it to them but in the waste
world a lot of us have that same
experience of the concept is to take
that napkin and put it into an actual
hub of information
that would be very helpful I I forgot to
introduce myself to you my name is are
dia denies and I am the founder of pole
EEMA and I'm helping companies find
materials made from waste and biology so
having that kind of resource to to send
people to or we can actually understand
everything that's going on with
materials would be super super helpful
yeah definitely so what I would like you
to kind of tell us just so everyone has
like a base knowledge what is how is how
are we doing with recycling right now
like globally what's what's going on are
we doing a good job
well we're hurting a little bit right
now for sure there's an extreme global
shift that we've never seen before and
where we used to take our materials to
be recycled the majority of 60% or more
going to China 60 more than 60% of our
exports of of waste going to China from
the United States to be processed in
some manner is not happening anymore
because that door is closed and that
door is not closed because there's a
trade war there's sanctions in all this
it's it's closed because China has been
on this path for the past seven or so
years to say we want less and less of
your contamination and your waste and
when I say contamination I'm not just
talking about food being on a recyclable
I'm talking about metals mixed with
paper and paper mixed with glass and
stuff that we just can't really recycle
but we've been told by our cities and
we've been told by everyone don't worry
it's recyclable in some place in the
middle of North Dakota where there's
some guy who can actually break it down
in his garage but that doesn't really
actually mean that it's really
recyclable and that there's a global
market for it and China also they want
20s got 20s guys a blue skies by 2050
that's their goal so they have this
green sword that says if your
contamination rate is over 0.5% for most
of the product we're not going to take
it and if it's metals its 1%
contamination we're not going to take
this stuff and so the whole globe is
trying to find new places to take this
material and have it be processed and
the
a lot of the recycling companies he's
small some very large recycling
infrastructure but then China have
picked up moved and gone to other
countries as well but these countries
are now getting this material and
they're like hey wait a minute we can't
process this we don't have the
infrastructure here or what
infrastructure we have doesn't take that
stuff and you see in places like the
Philippines where countries like Korea
and Canada have gone and docked their
BART barges of waste and said oh yeah
it's diverted we diverted it we took it
out of our country and we stuck it
somewhere else and then the Philippines
are like no no you're gonna take this
back so they just one of activists there
just want a great campaign to get Korea
to start taking this stuff back and I'm
gonna be targeting Canada soon so we are
recycling rate here in the United States
is about 26% and I in California it is a
little over 40% where it used to be 50%
back in 2014 which is what it regulatory
wise is it supposed to be 50% or more so
we're going down and down because we can
no longer say that a product is divert a
ball and just go stick it somewhere and
outsource our problem on to someone else
is suffering which is known as a form of
waste colonization we can no longer you
know do this and be honest about this
thing we need to take this material back
we need to process it in our own country
if we're going to become if we're going
to be creating this material and saying
that's recyclable and we need to build
infrastructure here we need do a lot
more than that you need to stop we don't
need to be creating this stuff in the
first place but and that's the thing is
now people are saying oh gosh plastic is
so bad since we're doing such a bad job
at recycling it let's stop producing so
much and let's produce some new products
but what are the what are the issues
with bringing in these completely new
products into the waste stream like what
does that look like when they're at the
end of their life and what problems is
that causing yeah and just to say about
the plastics we've only since the time
that they have been created since the
1950s have ever
recycled maybe nine percent of all the
plastics they've ever been created yeah
and the rest are in landfills or in
those who made eight point three billion
metric tons of this material and have
wasted six point three billion metric
tons of it
it's it's it's crazy and and just
another fact the Ellen MacArthur
Foundation through the the new plastics
economy are the thing I got that right
um I am like rattling off things in my
head and like wait a minute said that
the amount of waste that we're looking
at creating in the near future by 2050
we're going to have more plastic in the
ocean by weight than we are going to
have fish and currently right now the
way that we create plastic is through
oil production and 6% of our oil
production goes towards creating plastic
by 2030 it's going to go up to you know
20% of our oil production is going to go
towards plastic so we need to stop the
source where it's starting and then we
need to also move into other options and
opportunities and first and foremost is
not making this stuff in the first place
because we can't just trade one
single-use disposable item for another
single-use disposable item no matter
what it's made out of we need to look at
solutions that say no waste in the first
place but then when we go into this
trade-off of single-use disposable items
and or maybe not even single-use
disposable use maybe it's you know it's
couches and it's you know it's chairs
durable chairs and couches go figure we
we have to understand how that material
is going to work within the system as
well so the people who are creating
these materials need to be talking
downstream to where that stuff is going
to be processed in the end and if it can
even be processed so when we look at
stuff like bio plastics material that's
not plastic but it's made out of you
know corn or potato starch or whatever
it might be and they they create a
product that looks like plastic but it's
actually made out of plants can that
material then be processed can it be
recycled or can it be composted
as we said everything could be recycled
in some place somewhere in the middle of
the country or yes but everything can
potentially be recycled but is it going
to actually be recycled is there a
market for it and with composting this
material because it is a plant-based
material so people think oh it's
compostable and if it's certified BPI
certified biodegradable products
institute certified says this material
can be composted in a high-heat compost
facility or in some of them like paper
products in a backyard backyard system
but do we have those facilities in Los
Angeles yes well we have them outside of
Los Angeles we have facilities at
service Los Angeles but the problem is
the BPI certification certifies for a
degradation of six months so they this
product needs to sit on average the
product needs to sit in the high heat
compost facility for six months if it's
an aerobic compost facility with is
which is with air could be wind road
technology big rows of what is
eventually compost it's it's a three
month degradation process and because
that's the process they can get they can
get the materials in and out there's a
lot of materials that are coming in with
new legislation that's passed we need to
get 50% of the organics out of our
landfills and into these composting
infrastructure or whatever it may be and
so they need to process this as quick as
possible so it's a three month
degradation so if a compostable
bioplastic item goes into an aerobic
compost facility it's probably in the
current situation it's probably not
going to break down and a lot of these
compost facilities are going to see that
either as a contaminant they're gonna
see it as a contaminant period it's a
it's a contaminant that they accept and
then they'll pull out but everything
that goes over the line at a compost
facility needs to leave as diversion and
if it's trash it's not leaving as
diversion the other issue is given
regulation if the come if they want to
sell this compost to an organic farm or
farm that that you know grows organic
food they
have any inorganic material in it so if
the end these bioplastics are seen as
inorganic material whether that's right
or wrong it's currently seen as
inorganic material so when this material
comes in they have to separate it out
put it in a different window if they're
gonna process it like that so it's a
very hard product process and because of
the legislation and needing to take more
organics and turn this stuff quickly
because we do not have enough organics
infrastructure in place some of these
facilities are going to a one-month
degradation so an aerated static pile
where they're going to cover the pile or
the pile has aeration coming through it
so it doesn't need to be turned and if
it does maybe like once or twice so
that's gonna be a one-month degradation
with a little bit of curing time so that
those compostable --zz if they're
certified at that six-month degradation
are not going to break down so these
products these the building of these
products need to have those
conversations with the processes that
are out there and saying okay can we can
we create a product that has a 1-month
degradation and can we certify for that
or can we prove that can we use more
fiber based material are there are there
rating is there a rating system for
degradation like how do I know like say
I'm going to the store or say I'm a
business that wants to find better
packaging like how do I know what it's
rated as for us and in the what we get
when in the waste industry when
something's brought to us the only thing
we get to see is if that thing's BPI
certified and that BPI certification I'm
not an expert in that area but they they
have to go through a testing third-party
testing system to find out what the
degradation of that is so they're gonna
know that the people but not everything
not everything is certified I'm guessing
not everything but a lot of compostable
where stuff is is becoming BPI certified
baits expensive it's also expensive so
then it kind of prices some small
entrepreneurs out of the market not
surprising yeah exactly exactly yes
yes so there's anaerobic digestion as
well for organics ad facilities and the
current one that's in Paris California
one of the largest ones that we have is
not taking any bio plastics at this
moment they're not even taking fiber
based from what I've heard so even the
paralysis though is not scalable at this
moment so you're talking about a product
that you're like well maybe this will
work so we can we can create all this
product and let's put millions of
dollars into Krane paralysis versus
creating a product that works within the
system that exists so that that's an
issue that a lot of us in the zero-waste
community which I didn't define zero
waste but we we push for solutions
within the situation forces spending
millions of dollars to solve a problem
that could be solved by product redesign
yeah so what are you what do you think
you don't think that legislation to deal
with bio plastics is the answer that is
what I'm here you say what it sounds
like is if we could create like a
zero-waste system that that would be a
much better alternative i I think right
now I don't see a need to legislate on
the bio products at the moment because
if the if the businesses can work with
with the haulers and the processors and
and they can figure out the system
within I don't see why to legislate that
there's need for legislation when we
have situations where we have to tell at
the state level I am at the federal
level when we say you kind of need to
pull these organics out of the landfill
you know that because if we don't say
that the state doesn't say you need to
pull this organics out of the landfill
the jurisdictions the cities are not
going to tell the haulers you need to
start pushing organics collection and
recycling on the businesses in order to
pull this material the landfill and the
reason why we need to get organics out
of the landfill one organics is the
largest amount of material that goes to
a landfill it's about for state of
California it's 30 percent and then
that's all of it including food and food
accounts for 14% of the overall
the United States it's it's upwards of
almost 40% is organics in the landfill
and that creates a lot of methane and it
creates methane so organics in general
organics in general is just paper
usually comes out pretty high but it's
it's food foods if it's a massive amount
i just grouped their gangs together so
you've got your your tree waste your
yard trimmings your wood and your food
together and the reason why that's such
an important thing to target is our way
of a b32 we have climate legislation
strongest climate legislations ever been
passed in the United States that says
that we have to reduce our greenhouse
gas emissions to 1990 levels by 2020 and
right now I think it's 2019 so but one
of the the second largest source of
anthropogenic methane gas in the state
of California and the third largest
source of anthropogenic methane gas in
the United States comes from the
organics in the landfill and personally
we had to legislate that because I don't
think anyone any business or any hauler
would have said yes we need to target
that I would really like to hear like
what your dream waste solution would
look like the concept of zero waste is
this weird not understood singular
blogger pop idol popularize concept and
that's not what it is at all in 2004 and
then updated just recently the zero
waste international alliance which is
the one that came up with the first
peer-reviewed definition of zero waste
back in 2004 this is their their newest
update zero waste is the conservation of
all resources by means of responsible
production consumption reuse and
recovery of products packaging and
materials without burning and with no
discharges to land water or air that
threaten environment or human health so
my ideal and I prefer my little notes
my ideal right here my ideal solution is
something that's equitable that is
scalable and obtainable for for all of
the market and that does not cause harm
to any community that the community is
involved in the decisions on how that
that product might be cultivated within
that area or mind or whatever it might
be that there's full corporate
responsibility that the responsibility
does not always put back on the consumer
um it's managed locally the waste of it
is managed locally with local
infrastructure and that there's a I want
I want B core certification with zero
waste application to it so I want there
to be zero waste checklist that
considers all aspects of a pre-imposed
of a business worked into the B
corporation certification that's good
yes that's a great idea I think I can
you know some of those things can be
attainable like it's like just a really
comprehensive comprehensive way to for
any business to work is to just consider
all of those all those things
you know I as a product developer
consumer and working like let's say last
year in the neighborhood right st
neighbors to be the plastic cup whatever
we needed t-shirts to make rugs and all
that i learned a lot about how
disconnected and how we discuss how to
connect it we are from each other and
the other thing is how people just don't
think about so you know we just entered
supermarket so as much as we talk and
I've been working with cycling cycling
innovation material forever
for 20 years and I go to yeah so time
goes by and go to Trader Joe's it's
there all the supermarket all the class
of second to nothing it's like one Apple
you know one thing it's all so in this
zero waste speaking is there possibility
to have like
that really goes into the manufacturing
or the retailers that we can have below
package because if we change those I
have thought about doing like with my
neighborhood including all the plastic
from so that's yeah that's like the
corporates corporate social
responsibility of designing designing
for the end in mind right and cradle to
cradle kind of mentality cradle I'm it's
there but those bad so there's extended
so there's extended producer
responsibility legislation it's very
hard to pass they finally after ten
years got to take back program for
pharmaceuticals and sharps it took ten
years because of the pushback from the
industry that controls that market and
so you're totally right and we're also
not only disconnected with each other
we're disconnected with our product
we're disconnected with our earth were
disconnected with the resources so we
look at places like in the UK where
they're saying you know we're we're
going to move towards something where
the products have to be made out of
something that was recyclable
compostable or reusable Berkeley just
passed a an ordinance that said if
you're going to be a restaurant in
Berkeley
you have to charge 25 cents for any
disposables that leave your place of
business and all of you businesses have
to have reusables on-site that you can
no longer use disposables so there are
small pockets of that sort of happening
it's harder California is a little bit
easier the larger the country is even
harder but it's harder it's really hard
to push on extended producer
responsibility laws so while those are
happening while we have entities work in
that area we as consumers also have two
key
pounding that pavement because I know
personally from working with Trader
Joe's that they are hearing you and they
are looking at phasing out unnecessary
plastic within their stores hopefully
they do it and it's not like just
something they're saying at this moment
but it's it comes from all aspects but
just know that plastic pollution that
plastic consumption the single-use
disposable consumption even though you
are choosing to buy that it's not your
fault it is their fault it is the it's
the corporations that are giving it to
us as fault
[Music]