[Music]
yeah it sounds to me like there's been a
lot of this kind of like top-down this
is an assessment of how things are this
what needs to happen and I kind of take
things with a different approach which
is like how can we design a project we
usually call them businesses that do
something to create some value that
people find compelling and so they you
know having a new having a new something
service a product usually that changes
people's behavior is something that I
mean it's one of the few things that I
can say capitalism has going for it
right but this is a model that we see
happening all the time wait you know we
stopped using our dis man when we
started using our iPod you know it means
something that we do all the time so
then the question is like how do you
design how do you design this project in
a way so that it's compelling you know
we've talked a lot about technology here
but what I've not heard is like they
speed the market people people you know
meet stuff and some of them want to do
things in a better way some people want
to do things that weren't sense way some
people want to do both anytime that
someone has asked shall we do like so we
have a law passed or should we change
some regulation I kind of heard some
reticence about that was I think is this
wise because at least in the culture of
this country people a lot of times don't
like being told what to do now on the
other hand in California we kind of we I
think I think what's going on is that we
hold we do hold the environment in such
you know regardless of kind of like
political persuasion that we realized
that like tourism is important we like
to breathe clean air some of us have
seen the environment you know we're here
at times maybe we've seen the
environment worse than other places we
see what's going on news so really
excited that we have this place where we
care about the environment and we're
kind of willing it's not the same
everywhere it we're willing to say okay
yeah you know what I'm gonna be willing
to pay five cents for a plastic bag I'm
not gonna revolt this time but other
places you know people don't like being
told oh how do we either align
enough people to do what we need to do
which is when I say what we need to do
is accelerate the industrialization of
our economy it's cool to think about
cool little technologies but I'm here to
tell you that most of the technologies
that are going to save us are probably
pretty old we've understood from Milan
and it's yeah everyone so why don't we
get a new when you get a new cool trick
you know we did a combustion engine we
did nuclear power you know sometimes we
figure out good things to do with these
things and sometimes we kind of fumble
around a little while fossil fuels you
know this time place for certain aspects
of fossil fuels there's lots of other
alternatives there's questions of
Technology questions of product you know
how do we how we put together a value
offering but typically you take in lower
value feedstocks and you try to find the
highest value purpose for those
feedstocks a lot of business plans that
people talk about in this space and the
NSA sustainability if you just kind of
like do that dot to dot it's like people
are trying to take something high-value
and make something low value out of that
that's backwards so it's not how you
make business let's not have any money
you know and so then there come some
situations where it's kind of really
hard just fine how to make a business
and
were you know regulation may come in
where we say maybe we need a carbon tax
maybe we need different ways of managing
fuel credits and you know things like
this the people in this room really need
to get tight with their language because
it really is important to be able to
explain to people what organic is the
agriculture versus what we're ganna is
to a chemist and what bio-based can mean
and you know talking about hydrogen and
some of the energy stuff it's like you
know I really appreciate the people are
coming from a lot of different
perspectives but there there are some
key words that all this kind of you get
on the same page with you know so that
we can we can be good a be that there's
a hand raised in the back yeah this is
in created thousand a lake everyone
stand up work here come I called me she
runs it it's sort of a friendship of our
city so they're in line is on their very
first
it's an ileostomy equity program yeah it
sounds like mentors and you should do
events every future so with other be
seasoned
critic grid what would I read once and
that work actually have a happy hour RT
but I want to give respect to to the
information and what you have brought
out you know and I agree with you and
the language is so difficult to because
I work in education and outreach when it
comes to my my job and so I have to find
the language that people understand when
it just comes to waste and so even just
on the organic thing I pushed my company
and I keep pushing them on like always
put an s on the end of organics because
I'm not gonna say this is organic waste
these are organics and that's because in
our industry we refer to it as organics
and we're not that language in our
industry it's not it's not an industry
term that I can change but I can I can
at least try to manipulate it in a way
that is not going to hopefully have
another layer of confusion added to it
for the consumer but you're completely
right when it comes to language and and
us share a my and my best friend his
husband as a pharmacist and she's a
nurse and so we always get in these
conversations especially about organic
and other terminology because we come
from different worlds and and and I and
that I think is a solid point a solid
issue that you brought up you also
talked about demand a product demand or
the demand of the individual and you
made a comment if I can even if I
remember it correctly it's like some
people want to do the right thing and
then some people wanted you the bad
thing most people not the bad thing
sorry sorry that was my brain going but
but some people want to do maybe for the
environment other people that's just not
where they're thinking that's not what's
they're trying to put food on their
table they're trying to get through
their daily life they're trying to do
their two jobs they're trying to maybe
just come home and relax you know that
the concept of making sure that I buy
the one product that's made out of this
with this and it's going to go here is
not the thing there
thinking about and so when we create
product if I'm getting this right and
how I took it
is that when we when we're looking at
creating a product in order to meet the
demand of what is out there in the
communities people want better options
for water bottles or getting their water
I I think there's a level two things I
wanted to say I think there's a level of
demand that we have control over as as
businesses as entrepreneurs that we can
that I see happening to where it's like
here's this product I think you should
use this product I think we should be
using products that do X Y &amp; Z and I
think sometimes we can we can change
that to man because that demand is put
on us anyways by the corporations that
demand is put on us by commercials and
what we see out in the and and I'm just
talking about like just you know our
chips and our you know pizzas and
everything else but those that's a
demand we think we see this product we
say that I want that product I want
something like that and so I think we
have control in changing that narrative
as well but then also for me personally
we're talking about like and I didn't
say it earlier but we're talking about
oh there's these little you know things
that you can use for water you know my
first thing came to my mind it's like
that that's a cool idea but why is it
that why is the demand not on water
scarcity and why is the demand why we
have water issues to begin with why is
it that we still have issues in Flint
Michigan why is it that we still have
you know we had water issues in
Willowbrook and Compton where they
couldn't even drink their water why is
why do they have to buy these little
pods in the first place in order to be
able to meet the demand that they need
why is it that we have to have a demand
for water bottles period because it's
been sold to us that our water is not
drinkable why is it that our if our
water is not drinkable why is it not
drinkable if our water is not accessible
why don't we have a drinkable accessible
water fountains to throughout
and I think the solutions I mean answers
to all the rhetorical questions that
you're presenting and they have like
concrete answers that we could put up on
a like work right now so she's point to
our whiteboard so it's like people so
I'm saying take an empirical approach
and say okay people do like convenient
single use or you know maybe low repeat
reuse containers that are low-cost maybe
what we want to consider having a
conversation about this like change
management and thinking about the
psychology of change because I think
that it's like you know I sound like
someone was aligning by a lethal
you know back when we were focused on my
easel we were really excited that there
was this possibility that we could take
some of the output of farmers and offset
some of our petroleum fuel use and then
wanted to turn out the way that result
is you might wonder where did all of the
biodiesel activists go well because the
state California and a few other states
said you know what instead of like you
want us to use 100% biodiesel you want
us to use 20% you know what we're just
gonna make everybody put like 5% and all
of the diesel supply so we got our you
know free to fight the same fight of
diesel in California and you know you
might say well it's not 20% that's that
sounds like it really sucks but for the
amount of emissions decreases that you
get proportionally for each percentage
of that biodiesel when you only put you
know three to five percent biodiesel in
the petroleum fuel supply you get this
really awesome
reduction in particular manner and so
it's kind of a success it's you know
maybe we can say it's not perfect but
it's like on the way anyway so once we
sort of knew
and I'd like to hear what you have to
say about buying pieces but the only
reason what I pick it up is that we
moved on into realizing table actually
chemicals might be more of an
opportunity and that's a lot of what
we're talking about today is bio
chemicals you know how to take different
deep socks can birth them into something
valuable now I'm kind of thinking well
you know technology the technology is
probably not gonna change all that much
but people's minds are what we really
need to be thinking about changing I'm
not a marketer I'm actually an introvert
I don't love being in a windowless place
but you know it's kind of it kind of
sounds like you're you know talking
about the economic and there's a lot to
unpack there I'm gonna do my best
the the the economics of being a
sustainable business aren't all that
attractive a lot of the time to be
completely honest it's really not you
really have to drill down there's a lot
of regulation the the the amount of
material that you need and the minimums
that a lot of these manufacturers need
are its daunting it's very daunting
honestly it's a long road and I think
coupled with the economic discussion
you're talking about a cultural and a
social impact as well so doing those two
things in concert hopefully you'll have
a successful business there's no
guarantees but at the end of the day I
think there is a growing demand for
consumers as a consumer I should say
that they're demanding that these things
change and the economics of a
sustainable business is what's driving
these huge brands like the loop play and
things like that that unfortunately in
H&amp;M and that unfortunately is what a lot
of drives a lot of the social currency
and a lot of the the cultural aspects of
the world we live in so I think you
can't ignore one without the other if
you're trying to be a sustainable
business without looking at the
economics like okay cool I'll see you
when you're you know getting collecting
your welfare check in a year you know
you're not you're not going to do well
if you are just worried about the
cultural aspect of it without the
economics same same same scenario just
the environmental or just you know yeah
and that's why it's a trifecta and they
all it's not - it's like three it's you
know social equity economics and
environment or profits people plan it
and he it's helpful to come back to that
light it's just simple and I reduce
reuse recycle you know it just becomes a
quick mantra that you can just catch
yourself is what I'm doing profitable
potentially is it good for people is it
good for the planet if those things you
know yes yes yes and maybe there's a
business kernel in there that you can
deal with so I was a gapper if you know
that is a chief lighting technician
before that electrician and then I was a
DP so so yeah so I spent 30 years behind
the camera and the last you know a bit
of it in the early 2000s I was uh we
would demand you know biodiesel in our
generators you know in Hollywood so I
wouldn't get it in in Tennessee but I
would get it here in California we you
know but it took a little while we had
to do his red dye and we had to like you
know can we had to convince the the
generator operators to go to their
insurance agents and say yes you can do
this it will not break your warranty so
you may have been part of that policy
but in California it was very clear it
will not break the warranties and so it
took a year or two and it took basically
getting you know celebrities whoever was
the most you know prominent producer
actor on the set to throw a hissy fit -
you know you know we have to use
biodiesel on these shoots and so but we
got it and basically 90% of the industry
of the you know generators in Hollywood
and today sometimes I don't know I've
been bent out of her for a few years
since I shifted over from film tech to
clean tech right so and I drove about
days over like 10 years and I drove
biodiesel 100 99.9 you know all over
California and it didn't change it the
reason it changed was because of the
by of a diesel leak an underground leak
in Northern California it the diesel
leaked from a regular petroleum diesel
leaked into the ground from an
underground tank the lobbyist that wrote
the rules to address that made it so
that biodiesel could not be stored
underground and so therefore I used to
drive around and go to my b99 stations
and get biodiesel all over Southern
California you know eight places now I
had to shift and go only where they
could have above-ground storage tanks
and that's not in the city so I'd have
to drive out to Sun Valley get my
biodiesel and then come back to
Hollywood and you know yeah I could go
to all but I can I can go up and down my
neighbour's alleyway and I could get
biodiesel hey you got to biodiesel yeah
my boyfriend's actually on that board
for the biodiesel co-op for Los Angeles
I saw hey Jack ight yeah oh yeah they
again they have had these issues I mean
we're not gonna go and buy this I guess
but but but they made it they
financially regulated them out of the
market like oh you have to have a
specific handle and the handle cost this
much you know you have to have the
locking system like this and this cost
as much and they would they would meet
the regulations and then there'd be
another regulation and another
regulation and another regulation which
was making it well but there's a
different outcome the outcome is that we
got we got shut down because of the way
the lobbyists wrote the rules in
Sacramento and we didn't have a strong
enough team up there to rewrite those
rules to allow underground storage of
biodiesel that was I market creation
right and so that's what I'm talking
about in terms of length to make think
about the
that you brought up like the influencer
you're like yeah we can make cool
happen if Leland Leonardo DiCaprio says
like yeah we have to and and I saw Cyril
from Pilate for the oceans
I'm very familiar with that with that
company they're the ones that created
the thread from ocean plastic for adidas
for their shoes
that was the parlays first product we
think they're going further now and
they're really focusing on kind of
creating a culture P AR l ey and their
their next step is really focusing on
like creating a movement but one thing
that the founder said recently was that
I think it's very catchy and I love it
that purpose is the new luxury and that
once these influencers start start doing
this and like that Pina text little bag
I gave you is like $250 or something and
it's like this stuff does cost more
money a lot of times because it's in R&amp;D
mm-hmm and so if we if these like
influencers of all different sorts can
show off how great these products are
that they are cool and that there should
be a demand for this stuff then I think
it's a very beneficial way to be helping
new products
you can say they're doing something cool
and innovative than interesting and
here's what it is I would say that most
of them have little cool things that
they're trying to do from time to time
so I mean you know one of the things
that has been kind of interesting is
plant bottle from from coke so you know
this is an example where they use one of
the ingredients to make pet peepee
it's it's more affordable to make it
from a bio-based source so ethylene
glycol that's 30% of PEP bottles so they
looked at the math and then they hired
they teamed up with some other startups
and they said well can we make a hundred
percent and so startup that I worked for
per few years eventually their
collaboration with coke on plant bottle
and a couple other companies they said
yeah we wanted to we could make a 100
percent bio-based PT polyethylene
terephthalate by the economics don't
work so our plant bottle that we that we
use now or that we see in the market now
that's 30 percent bio-based this is
plant bob one most you do in fact I
think all of them to do so you get a
little bit of 30 percent you get to slap
flat bottle the logo on it and there's
definitely they'd get a marketing with
because people are like well this is I
don't have to feel as evil about you
know having my sugar fix here so so
that's an example where you know but
it's like you can find almost every
brand owner you can find is doing you
know has done they have one press
release at least that they're doing
something cool yeah but the question is
is this enough and the answer is no it's
no no well no I think that is an example
of that not being enough this CNA which
is a large fashion company in Europe
they I think last year released the
first completely certified Cradle to
Cradle t-shirt for like five dollars or
something like really really cheap and
that sounds like a great thing I think I
was when I
learned about this I was sitting next to
a small small fashion company owner and
she's like how like thinking of like
this pina text cost this peanut X bag is
$280 she's like how can I compete she's
like if if this shirts $5.00 and it's
awesome and they're you know subsidizing
it with all kinds of other sales of
stuff like how can a small sustainable
business compete with that and I think
it's a good question but it's still
they're competing right now yeah they're
competing with fast fashion
yeah there's $5 shirts all over the
place yeah all yours but it's still a $5
shirt because most people aren't gonna
go into a store and be like oh it's a
cradle-to-cradle certified by that you
and I might but they still have the they
still have the competition if the
competition's there no matter what
yeah it's not based on the
sustainability I don't think yeah it's
based on price based on market demand
terminology misery waste is a broad
terminology so city of Los Angeles Falls
state regulation so you're going to be
seeing organics recycling at most of the
because we're talking about what's the
largest piece of material going to a
landfill was the largest piece of
material causing methane gas out of a
landfill that's gonna be organics and
truly that's what you need to target
hardcore but that's already regulated at
the state level and that the
jurisdictions start to and that's part
of their waste
I think we've gotten this really weird
skewed idea of what zero waste is
because of social media and people with
their jars of trash I so zero weight and
so it's a lot more carbon under than
that
so the organics recycling you're gonna
be seeing across Los Angeles Southern
California all of that the city of Los
Angeles passed a franchise agreement
that says one there's eleven zones and
each zone can only be serviced by one
hauler by one trash company for the
businesses and the multi-family
residential of four or more units or
five more units sorry
and they have to work with the city in
order to make sure that they're meeting
the state goals and those diversion
goals the the regulations on organics
and things of that nature there's gonna
be a lot more education and outreach
there's a information that's gonna be
able to be provided to the businesses
that they didn't have before because
that was not regulated because the
hollers didn't have to provide that all
of the businesses are getting one on one
communication with their recycling
coordinators in order to be able to help
them through the process and help them
reduce their waste this is a ten-year
plan so it's not gonna happen overnight
so the city of Los Angeles definitely
passed that the city has their city they
they have their la plant their plan plan
PLA the city
yes so the city has a it's called the
plan P la in yeah that's theirs that's
their sustainability plan zero waste as
part of that element but they have to
work on the different elements on how to
get there so there it's not everything's
not written into that plan like we have
to have all white roofs and we have to
make sure that we have more green space
and then we have to it's the the
franchise the the concept of the
franchise is part of that plan so
there's different elements that they're
doing in order to get there when you
talk about zero waste them I'm kind of
assuming that maybe you're talking about
waste in general like plastics or foam
or something in that nature that that's
not part of that plant it anything that
comes anything that they they push
forward on is going to come from from
within that plan like they're gonna look
back into the plan and say we want to
push on this piece of regulation because
it meets the needs of this plan
you're not gonna probably at this moment
see a foam ban in the city of Los
Angeles because I know personally
because I'm I'm sort of working in that
circle I'm not sort of I am working in
that circle that they're looking at a
larger more comprehensive look about how
we manage and and and use our waste or
the products that we're putting out
there and that conversation has not all
fully been laid out but it is one that
is happening start from is a brand if
we're gonna talk about chemistry it'd be
polystyrene expanded polystyrene but
polystyrene is without the without it
being expanded in the foam since that we
know it huh or what
yeah extruded but the thing is that you
can here's the hair little tidbit you
can make any plastic in the foam because
all you have to do is just extrude it in
the specific manner to where it I was
gonna add that so this city so basically
you know from the city plan the city the
Department of Public Works LA Department
of Public Works
as their La sanitation department inside
of that and they have policies and in
and that's an interesting space to be in
and that sanitation is municipal solid
waste and sewage treatment ations not
going to be pushing on those regulations
that look at like they're more of a
product exactly yeah and the city and
then there and then the county actually
does a lot more in that direction than
the city does so it's really the county
the county one's not out yet
so the county one they're just doing the
community meetings on and pulling in
people from different industries to have
a conversation on the county's
sustainability plan so you won't find
that one online but you will find the
the city of La plan online oh that's
great so the zero waste yeah so so Pam
like the there's the zero waste cut the
definition that you gave is like is is
the right definition but then there's
sort of the generic don't put anything
in the landfill so there is no away
right and so we can't throw things away
any more how do we you know live our
lives if you can't throw things away
okay so that's I think you know going
back to like the personal story part the
personal journey you know how do you do
that with your family how do you how do
you do that you know it's like it's very
it's not easy and so what is you know
that yeah and so so from this other huge
other layer is look at like yeah but but
but from the corporate level you look at
like Walmart Walmart by definition they
they they zero wasted their corporation
between like 2003 and 2008 they they
reduced by 90% what they used to throw
away but they don't threw out their
check there their whole supply chain
yeah but they don't contain
organics organics boy I'm sorry but but
a lot a lot of what was left in that not
that last 10% was organics because
that's the messy part that's hard to
that's the hardest part they were just
simply they used to just you know use
their crates once and throw them away
boxes inside of boxes inside of boxes
inside of boxes for what's gonna the
consumer is gonna use and then they just
designed better systems to use less
weight throughout from China from India
to the store they just they cut that by
90% what used to get thrown away
well well also know that zero waste has
to do with when when companies say that
there's zero waste but they're not
certified zero waste like through true
which is the zero waste certification
that same thing as us GBC LEED
certification but for zero waste that
that certification only looks at the
building it looks at the brick and
mortar it doesn't look at the the
supplies that are coming in unless
they're toxic and how that impact was
upstream and if they're what this is the
way situation was up there and with the
health and community situation social
situation was up there and they don't
look at how it is on the back end either
how what happens to it when it leaves if
it is actually recyclable if it's
reusable if it's durable they don't look
at that they're just they're looking at
the brick and mortar and and then you
have companies maybe like Walmart and a
few others they have a my name in my
head then that name um that will say
we're zero waste companies because
they've defined what zero waste means
they've defined what recyclable is
they've defined that if we burn 60% of
the materials no no no no I'm sorry so
is the definition of ninety percent
reduction to landfill without
incineration okay so that was you know
there's many companies that burn their
their stuff and call it zero waste
yeah there's countries that do the same
thing Sweden yeah yeah exactly and
gasification is burning
I don't know you define organics even
once tonight oh it's to me no anybody
has any one organic what has organic yes
oh so as opposed to this which we would
not would not be organic yeah I can
define up for the waste industry so the
waste industry when we say organics
matter and what like when the waste
characterization comes out by the state
or even by the EPA and they have the pie
chart and they say what's in our
landfill and they'll say what's the
recycle ball so what was the organics
and what was the landfill in there
though today all of them ok by sandy as
well but they but they then pie chart it
out and they'll say this percentage in
the landfill er or the overall municipal
solid waste
I was X you know these are the pie
charts when it says organics what
they're talking about what falls under
that is yard trimmings plant matter food
scraps wood and then it does get sticky
for us too because sometimes depending
on the study
they'll also throw the paper and the
cardboard in there as well so did that
you know as you could be composted in it
pretty much so for the waste industry
that's what it means and I I completely
understand from a science and chemistry
background that there's another time I'm
just trying to I have the same issue I
have the same issue because I have to
define it to when I go out and do
education
and burning so burning is bringing in
oxygen so that you have you know this
complete combustion as possible so
basically you're turning solid things in
carbon atoms into carbon dioxide right
and then gasification is where you do
that in a much more controlled way and
you are introducing oxygen into into
this you're kind of like partially
burning things but you're not burning
everything up - gasps oh yeah it's dead
you're ending up with well in some cases
you are anything above that sometimes
you're ending up with gas and some some
materials some solid materials they come
in from if if polymers are gasified for
instance you might end up with some
stuff that you can make yeah
thank you guys so much I want to make
sure
but I'm super glad I think that we were
able to have a discussion you're super
welcome to stay and chat
[Music]