I did want to show some of these
materials that I have here to everybody
things that I'm excited about
so this is do you want to send me one
the past together patsies around this is
restock the hemp paper yes you can
this is Pina Tex so I I was in
Copenhagen and went to materials library
at this university called Kea and here
this has this is like my purse so yeah
but but they have they have this
materials library and they had a large
sheet of Pina text the largest sheet of
Pina text I've ever seen and it it
listed was actually in Pina tux which it
listed unless this has changed it's
listed as 70% PLA yes which I was really
disappointed about so PLA is plant based
plastic that's uh it's called Pina text
and so that is a pineapple pineapple
leaf waste pineapple leaf based swatches
yeah PLA is poly lactic ass it could be
any type of bio product could you know
there's different things out there so
maybe they're taking the peanut X and
chemically it's considered poly lactic
acid when it's it's not degradable they
say on their site that it will not
degrade that it we have our compost yeah
because they have to put additives in it
to make sure that it's you know stay
long I was really bummed about that but
that's why I love this material which
has nothing added to it at all it's
called it's a company called malai and
it's a bacterial cellulose alternative
leather which I think we need like a new
term for because I feel like it's in
between leather and textiles we can't
and not flutter and it's not leather
because I have a problem with that a big
problem with leather but that that
company
they take waste coconut water from some
farmers that are raising coconuts for
some other reason and feeding it to
bacteria and that bacteria accretes
layers of cellulose and then they layer
the cellulose together and add some
waste banana fiber also to give it some
tensile strength and there's different
colors if you can see in those
prototypes so I think that's super
exciting I also love my friends company
can bucho biomaterials they're making
kombucha rolling papers so just a
hundred percent Scobie I can put that
down for the reusables you can do it
[Laughter]
[Music]
yeah we do not it's a it's a product in
a service right we do not charge
anything for our service so we're
collecting all of the waste and
providing an opportunity to the
cultivators to purchase that back so we
do encourage them to purchase that back
but we we are we are getting it for free
we're not paying for it and they're not
paying us that might change in the
future but that's the way it is
currently which is good because they
legally have to have it collected not
just because it's it's cannabis but
because under state regulation a B 1826
and also new regulation SB 1380 three so
eighty 1826 says that any commercial
account business or multi-family
residential has to have if they create
four cubic yards so with just a normal
sized dumpster of material municipal
solid waste so any type of trash they
have to have organics recycling in place
and this is because the state of
California wants to
you have a 50% reduction of organics to
landfill if they don't reach that goal
they're gonna go to if you have two
cubic yards and that's going to go to
every single business so these
businesses because they participate in
because they have an organic feedstock
they have to participate in this they
have to have some sort of collection so
if he wasn't collecting it for free they
would have to pay for it or they can
find some other illegal solution I'm
sure they could compost they can compost
on-site if they have that opportunity to
do so yeah but a lot of these large dela
growers have too much they have too much
and they would need to be a registered
and licensed fully come sir defied
compost facility which in an in itself
is very daunting to be a certified in
and be to maintain has to maintain under
a certain temperature a large conference
facility and then they have to get
regulated in a different way yeah but
you know to answer your question I mean
we're saving them money on you know like
we were talking about percentages of
organic waste 60 70 percent some cases
of the dumpster is going to be organic
green waste so they're the the dumpster
cost for them pipe by week or by month
is drastically reduced through using a
service like ours yeah
because otherwise I know that some any
sort of farmer there either they can
burn they can burn their agricultural
waste which releases a lot of carbon
emissions or they can just let it kind
of rot and not like compost it in a
certified way but that prove that
promotes such a it's a slippery slope
because then you're promoting the
ecosystem of toxic runoff and air
pollutants if it's rotting and molding
and no one has a farmer especially a
canvas farmer you do not want mold on
your facility yeah there is a time frame
associated with that but it's again it's
up to each county to kind of drill down
on that which is kind of a little bit
more of the bottleneck of what's
happening right now and the relationship
I mean that's what we're being told by
our cycle but then the county is telling
us nowhere it's not on us go talk to Cal
recycle so it's kind of like a game of
hopscotch pass the buck but they're
doing what they can which is great and
and they're very proactive so Jessica
the the cost for hauling and disposing
of waste I'm assuming that's going up
and up and up yeah right like how do you
have a sense of like how much it's gone
over is there a projection of like how
much more it's expensive it's supposed
to get no well it's all dependent on the
contract that your jurisdiction has
worked out with the collectors in that
area
a lot of cities in the United States
around Los Angeles at around LA Southern
California are franchised or non
exclusive or exclusive franchise so they
have contracts with the people or they
work the businesses that can come in
there and collect this material and they
set the rates because of the changing
market you know some of these franchise
agreements were extremely low and don't
really cover the cost of being able to
transport and process this material and
because of the fluctuating market and
the market sort of you know heading
downward at the moment it will even its
way out but the it needs to be
it has to reflect the actual cost and
for the longest time in the 90s when we
started pushing recycling and started
setting recycling legislation and
diversion legislation we said you know
this conversation about don't worry
recycling is free you get so much money
for the recycling if you if you recycle
more your waste bill will go down but
recycling is much more expensive than
Lam filling a tip fee and the state of
California is so incredibly low in
comparison to other parts of this
country New York City East Coast the tip
fees are we tell you sorry the tip fee
is when you go take the material tipping
a truck when you take the material and
you tip it at the landfill you have to
pay to tip it if you don't own your own
landfills you're really paying a lot of
money to tip this and so but the the to
tip it out of landfill to get rid of it
to dispose of it is so cheap to recycle
it is you know adding over a hundred
dollars a ton you know 70 80 depending
on where you are depending on the market
you know you're getting up there and
$100 ton composting because in in the in
our Southern California area our
composting infrastructure is usually far
away from our largest cities and so that
transportation cost because it is the
heaviest material that you're
transporting it's wine got to be
processed so if it stops to get
processed and has all the bad material
and removed from it I think it spit back
on the truck and then that truck goes to
a facility that's like four more hours
away that cost is so expensive and then
you have to compost it and you're
hopefully hoping that the people around
you want to use the compost and that
you're not shipping out to two farms two
hours away and you're really losing all
your money on this so you're looking at
something like a hundred and eighty
dollars a ton or more for just organics
because of how the whole system is set
up the true cost of this is not taken in
consideration but these cities that are
looking at sort of subsidizing these
costs in a way where they make the the
landfill rate higher
and they make the recycling rate lower
and their gang straight lower they
subsidize it by increasing how much way
you know how much ya incentivizing and
increasing how much the waste is
actually gonna cost them so is it gonna
go up yeah it's always going to go up
transportations expensive you know we're
Curtin and we're running out of room we
have well you know I gotta say I guess a
two we've got two really massive
landfills here in Southern California we
had the like third or fifth at one time
it was the largest but third or fifth
largest landfill we have which was it
was looking at the world I was looking
at a thing the other day I think it was
like third or fifth and it was Puente
Hills at the time that it was open I
know but looking at that list I was like
oh where are these other landfills and I
know are pretty big we have some other
big landfills here in Southern
California we have one that's the deep
one of the deepest landfills because
they've drilled out a mountain and then
we have another really I'm just gonna
leave it at that just because then we
have another landfill that is not really
being utilized it's out near the Salton
Sea and it's just really large and one
of the reasons it's not being utilized
as much as I think they thought they
were going to be able to use the rail
system in order to to transport the
waste but they really didn't tell the
wit rail system that they were gonna be
using the rail system so there's been
some issues with that so we have the
landfills it would have been a lower
carbon trip to the land didn't work out
so yeah so we have the landfills yeah
they are closing around the world yeah
we're going to not hopefully be creating
a more landfills but we just we don't
need to be relying on them in the first
place
[Music]