[Music]
tell us about restock what what is
restocks mission and how can we be not
burning or throwing away a bunch of
organic material my name is Lucas I'm a
founder of a company called restock what
we do is we take byproducts of the
cannabis and hemp world and convert that
into sustainable products namely
paper-based packaging so we work with
some of the larger scale cultivators on
the planet and we give them the
opportunity to buy back their waste in
the form of packaging for their consumer
lines I mean I think it's everyone in
this world and in this room can
understand why it's important but I
think from a larger perspective you know
the industry is coming out of never
being regulated ever it's coming out of
the black market and typically it's it's
been burned
you know let's hide the evidence kind of
mentality and we've been working on
these applications for the last four or
five years and I think you know combined
with innovation and regulation the
industry and the volumes that the
industry is putting out now are finally
reaching a level that we can actually
make an impact on there's it's a
tremendously versatile plant it's it's
not just about packaging it's about
finding the most appropriate
applications for it in concert with new
innovation because I technology is here
today yeah yeah and there's all this new
innovation coming about with like
studying hemp as well as the waste
cannabis product so that's all it's all
really exciting Tom how about you
introduce yourself and tell us about bio
products Innovation Centre yeah thanks
Tom McGrath you see we we formed bio
products innovation Center last year so
it's about a year and a few months old
we loosely basis on an initiative that
we were working on with Jason for the
last several years on sort of a green
chemistry kind of approach
more from the industrial side out of
Ohio bio products innovation center and
we got some of the inspiration from them
and they're an academic based nonprofit
so we're a standalone non-profit based
out of La clean tech incubator and I'm
the chief sustainability officer for the
nonprofit and we we really look at the
conversations around the organics
circular organics economy and how do we
achieve that goal and how do we help to
move that conversation forward looking
at you know effecting change through the
the triple bottom-line guidelines of
benefit corporations or be corpse or you
know profits people plan it and the
argument is that you're gonna do better
for the planet and better for the people
by having profitable business around
around sustainability so the idea that
you're gonna make more money because
you're doing the right thing with with
this and so if we get into this you know
zero waste mentality the sooner we get
there the better we'll be so we also
look at it from the perspective of
energy so we look at sustainable we look
at through the lens of sustainable
energy into the water and soil
conversation so it's really sustainable
energy water and soil here we're talking
mostly about soil but you can't talk
about one without the other so they're
all connected so how do we make better
soil the food and the bio biological has
come from the soil and they will return
to the soil if we're doing it right
we're not making plastics that you use
once and go on the ocean so so those are
some of the main ideas you have to break
it down to reality and who's doing what
so we're we're we did some some
interesting work with doing admin on
some on some composting projects with
schools and communities here in LA to
help the city
public works go through you know
promoting compost and community scale
and it's just fascinating all the
different challenges that you come up
with on all these you know they're
growing food at the school they're using
compost for the fertilizer and you're
teaching you know how to like get this
circular organics economy evolving at
very small scales that but they're
significant and they helping to really
you know train the younger people we did
at an old-age home to in in a little
tokyo and they're doing Bokashi
a type of type of compost thing that you
know they can they can compost their
meat in addition to their fruits and
vegetables so it's it's an interesting
what they don't consume so it's it's
interesting there's so many different
layers of this so we can you know but
but and it goes to the big you know a
picture of - you know our industrial
life has led us to the worlds and
industry has led us to this place where
we take fossil fuels we take fossil you
know oil and natural gas coal oil and
natural gas and we we do things with
them
for industry and it's a sink it's a
linear conversation we extract 400
million year old hydrocarbons out of the
earth and we burn them turn them into
plastic any number of things we destroy
them and then we're destroying mother
nature and in the extraction part but
then in the use part we're putting that
carbon in the atmosphere so what doesn't
end up in the ocean as plastic ends up
in the atmosphere is carbon dioxide and
that's what's choking us right now this
issue right so if we could so so we can
do the hydrocarbon management without
extracting it from that we can do four
month old or four year old hydrocarbons
from bio-based caballo methane but we
can we don't have to extract from 400
million years ago we can produce the bio
carbons that we need for our life here
for billions of people living on this
earth and we can do that in a way that's
sustainable more sustainable so let's
move in that direction
yeah and the conversations of recycling
and the conversations of hemp as a as an
important biological source for these
hydrocarbons
that's the these are the answers that
are that get you there can you explain
that a little bit more how do you
extract four year old hydrocarbons
through anaerobic digestion but you can
also do it through gasification if you
wanted to but essentially you you make a
soup you hire you put biologicals in
there from human waste to any kinds of
organic food trimmings if you if you
have a pure source of organics then
you're going to get three things out of
that you're going to get gases you're
gonna get liquids and they're gonna get
solids the gases are hydrocarbon gases
and the trick is the hydrogen we all
love hydrogen right it's number one it's
the first element right so we love
hydrogen we're here because the hydrogen
so the hydrogen you're getting the
hydrogen from the water the the bugs the
little microbes are consuming the
organics in the water and they're giving
you ch4 you know four H's and one C one
carbon four hydrogen's that is we're
lucky that we can do that that that's an
important element that we need access to
and it's and we're getting it almost for
free from these microbes we have a waste
product the quote unquote that we use
things we used to throw away now or
things that we can grow and the
byproducts of some of these we can
channel into the bio energy conversation
and this gets us out of the fossil fuel
conversation so it's a one-for-one
exchange for natural gas for fracking
for natural gas you can get that not
renewable natural gas or biomethane from
today so that's it 400 million years ago
four-year-old 40-year old tree whatever
it's gonna be you can get bio gases from
that and with the same hydrocarbon gases
you can make plastics you can we can
make the things that we use today that
we find convenient or helpful you know a
heart valve or something or you know
there are some you know good things for
if you you know if you need to use
plastics there are reasons to use it but
it could be bioplastic bio-based it
doesn't have to be from the fossil fuels
lucas instead of using this amazing
organic waste and then doing this whole
process and turning it into methane like
how like what have you been your
challenges in in diverting that waste
and keeping it away from like different
sorts of digestion like how is it how is
your work been challenging thus far with
working with waste cannabis I would say
that it's been challenging in first and
foremost in the lack of infrastructure
and processing here in this country it's
the the industry is just kind of coming
out of it's shell so to speak so to
process the organic waste into a useful
reusable sustainable material within a
reasonable distance has been a challenge
so we're actually breaking ground on one
of the first bio refineries in the state
at hopefully the end of this year to
create these regional circular economies
that Tom was hinting at California yeah
[Music]
but yeah the infrastructure is not
really there once you travel more than a
hundred miles with it could be the most
sustainable material on earth the it
immediately degrades that value so I
think restock was a little bit ahead of
its time in the sense that the industry
wasn't producing as much material and
the infrastructure wasn't really in
place luckily now the demand is there
and certainly the industry is growing
there and now last piece of the puzzle
is the infrastructure in place to
process all these different inputs were
primarily focused on canvas and now
mmm-hmm so by infrastructure you just
mean the processing like the bio
refinery exactly processing with a
different with more than one end result
more than
one application whether it's textiles
whether it is paper-based packaging
whether it is bio plastics whether that
is some kind of alternative energy there
are a lot of different ways to do it and
people who are much smarter than me are
thankfully in charge of that we're just
really fortunate to have some partners
in that space who who've been the most
helpful allies for you the state has
been very encouraging I will say that
despite we were talking earlier about
just you know the the back and forth
between regulators and the bureaucracy
red tape surrounding that has been has
been wild but CalRecycle
you know the governor's office have have
been very encouraging they're just you
know like I was saying earlier you know
they have their their plates really full
with with how much they should be taxing
giving out all these licenses how are
they going to deal with the the influx
in cash all these businesses so a lot of
times waste management and recycling is
the basement level of what they're
trying to accomplish so they've been
very helpful and and partners like
circular systems which are the
manufacturing partners that were
building this biorefinery with have been
tremendous and they're focusing on
textiles they're focusing on textiles
yeah
we're you know developing a couple cool
projects with them they were just
awarded the HTM global agents of change
award for 2018 which is like the Nobel
Peace Prize for fashion which was a very
big deal for them they were just voting
with the money they came with yeah some
money as well they were voted Time
Magazine's top 10 smartest sustainable
ideas of 2018 so we're honored to be
working so closely with them but I think
you know innovation is is should be
driving regulation and that's a very
slippery slope especially given the way
that the exchange of information is so
fast nowadays it's very
difficult to stay ahead of something
like that but I think California is
doing a great job and they're doing what
they can to stay ahead of that but the
technology is here and it's it's
honestly a race against time as I'm sure
you guys you guys will agree yeah yeah
I'm curious if if any of you have any
like dream allies their dream partners
that like you have not gotten the chance
to work with and you feel like gosh if I
could just work with this organization
or this person like we could really get
some stuff done I would say like a
company like like Patagonia they're
there they're just the best right
exactly
they're they're just such a model for
for change and and and being radical but
being thoughtful and also understanding
their consumer and not not alienating
one demographic or another they you know
you can see almost anyone wearing
Patagonia and they feel good about it
that would be a dream from fur for us
maybe maybe they could be using some of
this paper right CRISPR labels yeah that
would be cool right are you doing the
textiles mm-hmm paper slut easier first
beginning a thank you yeah
just before I would answer that question
I just talked about like this concept of
up upcycling or you know finding value
in what used to be considered a waste or
a problem so you have it like for any
kind of business case you're just
looking at that like okay so you're
starting off with the negative and
turning into a positive you're already
ahead of all the other businesses that
are doing starting up at zero and going
to a positive so we're working with
something that's just a gimme I mean
there's so many great businesses that
come out of this so you it's it's
inspiring so there's uh there's you know
there's an awesome you know company at
LA CI that you know recycles bio
plastics so they have but you have to
separate it you have to get it separated
in order to do that and that becomes
part of the of the that's it's both
consumer
and ultimately corporate responsibility
for how why did you buy it but it's it's
it's it's a lot of it's a lot of change
that has to happen at once and it's hard
to orchestrate that so I just you know
it's it's really interesting to see all
these different people trying to develop
the modality for change we you know even
people are feeling that sense of urgency
in different ways but you know I think
everyone senses it that we have to
adjust you have to make adjustments you
know and so how does that work from you
know you know working with you know
innovative you know amazing innovators
you know Elon Musk doing you know
amazing you know getting us all into EVs
and you know do that but you look at the
lifecycle analysis of a lithium battery
and say okay well if there's issues
there yet the things that we have to
work on and so I don't know it's not
nothing's gonna be perfect right away
but you know there's a lot of steps you
can take you know right away to create
businesses and Enterprise around
sustainability around bio products
around renewable energy around clean
water
I think Tesla would be a great dream
Ally yeah like if we could be like
making a hemp car you know like all the
maybe the inside could be have textiles
alternative leathers well I think it's
it's places like like Lacey are very
important I think that you know a clean
tech incubator is is something you don't
see a lot of it's it's fantastic we're
honored to be a to be a part of it and
to be working out of there is very
inspirational motivational but you know
from a day-to-day perspective and level
like it's it's kind of a lot of doom and
gloom when you look at the current state
of things so it is hard to maybe stay
motivated a lot when you're looking at
all this going on in in in the air
quality in Mexico and all of the burning
of trash in India and it's it's all
happening around us so I think using
incubators like like Lacey and having
the young minds who are taking some
accountability and some responsibility
for what's been done to the planet
continues to be done is so rad to see I
just wanted to go down one little
channel and then I let go but I spent a
lot of cycles and working in Jamaica and
they've had an illegal you know
Jamaican was something big in the 80s I
remember but we you know it's we've been
down there and they're there organics to
waste 85 to 90 percent of what goes into
the is not it's not a LAN throw it's
it's dumped in Kingston 80 to 90 percent
of that is organics so that is an
attractive target for for doing a better
you know you set up a Murph 90 percent
of your activity that you're going to be
doing recycling a sorting Center you're
gonna focus on the organics because
that's 90 percent of what is going in
there so so we had a two-part program
one was to to to to to attack the
problem of the waste and that's a big
problem there are fires oh they're
always burning things and things are
happening they are a bad air quality
very dangerous for the people that live
right around there
and then and then the next is is they
have lost it had a sugar industry that
has lost their business to larger
companies like Brazil that can produce
sugar less expensively because the high
cost of energy so what we can grow
grasses or you know like hemp like king
grasses or you know other we can we can
grow material that can then be digested
and produce the renewable natural gas to
replace the diesel that they currently
run their whole island on diesel
electricity so there's these are like
you know island why island solutions and
islands are really great because it's
such a metaphor for our little blue
marble right I mean is you know
everything has to be managed you know so
you can do that circular organics
economy at in island nations I think
with a really good very positive
outcomes and clear need and desire to
have a more sustainable system because
they they they pay have such incredibly
high energy cost so and that affects
everyone from you know schools to you
know hospitals they have a problem with
their electricity and then these
hurricanes come in soap were to reco all
the work that you know people been doing
down there so obviously at that but this
circular circular organics model you
know I feel I feel very lucky to be in
California because it seems like there's
so much that's possible and people are
so interested in finding new solutions
whereas I know in a lot of places like
Mexico and and other small countries
it's like there's just waste everywhere
like there's there just are no systems
but here we have like such an
opportunity to to actually figure out
what to do with all of this stuff well I
think you're 100% right about about the
the island nations actually needing to
manage it even even more so their
resources are extremely finite and so
micromanaging that is like of the utmost
importance I would love to pick your
brain about that that work you did there
as a whole and they could do and
textiles yeah yeah and solving the
problem the waste issue doesn't just
always come down to the biomaterials
either right there's there's a systemic
there's there's systemic change that
needs to happen and there's the the
issues that affect one country are going
to be different than how where they come
from or how they affect another country
what we have here when we look at our
waste system and you're asking who would
you like to work with I don't have a
particular business I want to work with
I want it I want to make sure everyone's
at the table so that we can have
conversations to try to figure out what
the solutions are particular to the
waste issue that we might be having and
those solutions are not just one-off
trade it for this you know let's get rid
of plastic and trade it for a bioplastic
it's it's not that there's so much more
to it than that there's a complexity
there of we have to get to a point where
we are reducing our consumption we have
to get to a point where we're not
allowing corporations to tell us that we
have to consume in order to live it's
hard to have any business with the
business plan
yeah then actually feel good about it
like I don't really want you to buy this
but I want you to buy the model but but
I think there's
then we'll talk about scalability if
there's if we reduce the amount of need
and we have you know we have enough of
these businesses coming out and saying
okay to be able to trade this product
for this product or be able to produce
here I think I think we have solutions
within there I don't think that it's
gonna put people out of business unless
they're trying to get their product into
Walmart or something but when you look
at other countries sometimes their waste
issue is not about oh they have this
waste now and we've got to deal with
their waste because they have a lot of
poly you know pet water bottles number
one water bottles if does not use
terminology I guess we have number one
water bottles and we have a lot of film
plastic and we have a lot of chip bags
and granola bars and these sort of
wrappers and they can't do anything and
they never had this stuff twenty ten
years ago but have it now so that the
problem is the waste no the problem is
that we're going into their country
they're colonizing their country they're
taking over their land they're saying
you cannot you can't grow your own crop
anymore because we're gonna take this
amount of land here and we're gonna put
a palm oil company on it because we need
palm oil and the products that we buy
and our soaps and our conditioners in
our food whatever it might be we need
that palm oil but that palm oil is gonna
be wrapped in eco-friendly wrapping so
don't worry about it so if we we have
this so they take over the land they you
have communities who are living in that
land
all throughout who are now having to be
forced into one small area they can't
grow their own food anymore so they
don't have a they can't you know
subsists on what they used to subsist on
and they need to to go and work the the
palm oil plantation to be able to make
the money to be able to go buy the food
because they can't grow their food now
they're saying don't worry about it
we're gonna set up some markets within
this little neighborhood that you've now
been shoved into and at these little
markets as little markets there kiosks
there kiosks with diabetes causing food
options that come in single-use
disposable product that they can't do
anything with they don't have the
infrastructure for landfills they don't
have the
not really going to get recycled
incineration is in my opinion out of the
question and I know there might be
people here that disagree with me but
it's extremely expensive and that and
the the talks the the amount of toxicity
build-up goes within the community the
community pays for that eventually
besides the fact that it's more
expensive and it creates more co2 than
coal and nuclear but I mean you can look
up Gaia if you have any questions Global
Alliance for incinerator alternatives
but we won't get into a deep dive on
that so so now they're told you have
food you can buy all this product they
eat that product they have the trash
what do you do with it
they're gonna burn it they're gonna open
pit burn it because you don't like trash
on the streets here in Los Angeles why
do we think that people in countries in
Central America and Africa want trash on
their streets they don't it's a really
good point because with the with palm
oil because that was the solution that
in America we thought oh boy we're gonna
have like sustainable fuel and it's
gonna be biodiesel and we're gonna make
it from palm oil and then this huge what
they call a carbon bomb was offset from
deforesting so much of the Philippines
and like there's I think there's still
fires burning underground like in there
Pete Oh Indonesia Indonesia and it's
just such a good story of warning of
before you start running off with with a
new sustainable idea like make sure you
go all the way through the process and
look at all of the consequences because
now Indonesia like has a lot of problems
and we have colonized them and lost so
many trees and
it's just that process yeah you use the
word underdeveloped but he use that as a
verb we underdeveloped that area through
this prosecution so it's an active verb
it's not in magic
[Music]