[Music]
just quickly because I'm sure everyone's
hungry but can we ask you about what we
were talking about up there which is
your philosophy on whether it's making
hash or tinctures of mixing cultivars
versus single cultivar sure I don't know
how deep to go into it but a lot of it
for me is I've come to realize how much
I don't know about this plant and what
it can do and yes the there are
cultivars that pop up that you know
they're intriguing to the nose and when
you breathe in the smell of that plant
you feel it in different parts of your
body so there's all those kind of cues
that are involved for me in trying to
understand what the particular chemistry
of this plant might be able to do for a
person who's seeking help with cannabis
and at one point in the work I was
really focused I felt like yes I want
strange specific products because if we
find a strain that actually does sorry
cultivar not strange as dr. Russo says
strain is something that happens to your
back
wait it's not the name of a plant okay
so cultivar if you find a cultivar
that's actually working then you want to
be able to know that particular cultivar
is going to help this person but what I
came to realize at some point there's a
couple of problems with that one it's
hard to have a very specific version of
a specific plant year after year after
year that's a lot you're either talking
mother's and clones or tissue culture or
a very skilled breeder who can create a
seed line that will be consistently that
same thing over and over part of why I
started mixing different oils together
is that it was a combination of things
one of them
one of the issues was one of the most
challenging folks that I was trying to
work with needed a whole lot every day
of one specific cultivar that just did
not do well on my farm ACDC
is a plant that was first selected here
on the coast of Northern California
where the humidity is forty to sixty
percent and the temperature never gets
above eighty degrees and under those
conditions ACDC is just a happiest
little girl she produces these big
beautiful buds right reminded me of one
of the old school Bubba pushes I used to
work with years ago but I never saw that
version of ac/dc until I was in an
indoor room and part of what I was in
that room for was that I'd found
somebody who was growing ac/dc endorsed
and I was like oh I got to see what this
is how this is working because in my
garden it grew like a fern it couldn't
even hold its own weight up it was just
crazy and meantime I had this person
severely challenged by epilepsy whose
parents were utterly convinced ac/dc was
the only thing that would help so that
particular case I that first year I was
able to provide them with ac/dc I knew
someone who was growing it indoors and
made a trade with him so that I could
give it to them and but that next year I
was growing it again and I the family
came up to visit the farm and I showed
them I said this is the this is what you
want me to grow and and look it over
here here's a plant that has exactly the
same cannabinoids it smells different so
there's different terpenes going on but
it's the exact same cannabinoids that
are going on in this one so why don't we
try this for your son and see what
happens and they were I think they had
come to trust me at that point so they
were willing to try it and what we what
that year I had five different things
similar to ac/dc high CBD really low THC
and so I gave them what's that
those five worse our tzunami a plant
called Electra which is with cross of
auto and Valentine Valentine mother
plant auto of the mail
OTT oh let's see Electra sour tsunami
Harley Sue remedy and I don't know I
don't remember the fifth one anyway I
had I had like five different things so
I gave the family a pound of each of
those different flowers and suggested to
them that they try a little bit making
oil from each of them and give a little
bit of it to their son in his feeding
tube and see if one of them might work
better than ac/dc and it turned out in
fact that they because they only had a
pound it wasn't enough from the to do
the extraction process that they
normally did so they on their own
initiative decided to mix three pounds
together and two pounds together so they
made two batches and one of those
batches was so spectacularly successful
at helping him they the frequency
intensity and duration of his seizures
fell off dramatically enough that mom
called me like wait I don't understand
what's going on but the seizures have
stopped and I'm you know I'm just like
beside me so it was good news and the
question then became what was it one of
those three or was it all three of those
things together and I didn't know the
answer so meantime she tried the other
preparation that was from the other two
and one of those two was Elektra and
that preparation not only didn't really
help him particularly when she gave him
just Elektra it actually made his
seizures worse and so when we tried to
understand what was going on there we
think it was turpino lean because Turpin
leaned in that particular cultivar was
about five times what it was
in the other four that we were working
with because of all of that that's a
long-winded way of saying I really came
to realize I don't really know what is
going to be best for this end user and
because in trying to make create a
product you're not really you can't
really compound formulations for one
person in the regulated market you're
creating a product for hundreds or
thousands of people and so because I'm
so convinced that the chemistry that the
cannabis plant makes cannot do any harm
if it's free of contaminants and other
issues that come with mixing it with
other things if it's free of
contaminants the plant cannabis plant
itself cannot do any harm so if we can
take chemistry from several different
cultivars and put them together it's
quite likely that maybe we'll get 80 or
90 of the possible hundred and 50
cannabinoids that the cannabis plant
makes in that one product and what one
of the things that we're finding is that
the cannabinoids particularly some of
the rare ones have really profound
effects at very very very small doses so
I'm really pretty convinced that the
whole plant medicine concept really is
not specific to one cultivar it is
really about making salads is how I view
it you're putting together some of this
one and some of this one and some of
this one and yes you think about what is
the cannabinoid profile that you're
shooting for at the end in your product
and maybe what kind of terpenes are you
looking for but what's really true is
even the scientists can't tell us for
sure what actually is going on and
because I'm not really a scientist I'm
just I love this plant and I've become
so convinced it can't do harm I really
want to offer the widest array of
possible benefit to any end-user that's
going to consume a product that I would
make and that's why I gave up for the
most part in medical preparations on
strain-specific preparation
because I'm pretty sure we don't really
know what's gonna be best for the folks
and so in trying for the widest efficacy
for the most number of people I think we
want the widest array of chemistry
available to those Center users that's
how I got to it so let me ask you
because we were talking earlier about
how cannabis is so hard for dosage
because everybody is so unique and
individual yes yes
so is your thought process on this on
the you know making it not cultivar
specific and bringing in as many
cultivars as you can is your thought
process then because everybody is so
specific you are going to be hitting the
majority there'll be something in there
that's the hope exactly that he will
actually be effective for more people
because there is more diversity in it I
love that you chose the word diversity
for this because that's exactly kind of
where I'm coming from in much the same
way that you were taking those
inoculations or those samples of the
biology at different places on your land
at different times of year you're going
to get a real diverse selection of the
things that are there in much the same
way that we build our soil in our
gardens I think that through selecting
appropriate foods fermented foods the
idea including cannabis in those foods
we are in effect building the soil of
our bodies that and one of the like you
could think of the plasma that the
intracellular plasma and that the liquid
that makes up our bodies as the soil in
which we grow that that's where our
health springs from and if that is full
of diversity and beauty and everything
from you know
sauerkraut's in your gut to phyto
cannabinoids from the plants to the
herbs that you use in your cooking i'm
it's just and it and all of its coming
from where you live you are
incorporating the biome that you live in
into your body
and so the diversity that we as
dragonfly Earth Medicine farmers are
trying to create and our farms is also
reflected in our bodies and I feel like
this is a really important component of
live real food and and to me it's I
think it's really important that it be
said that cannabis is not a silver
bullet it is not the answer to
everything we really need to be
integrative in our approach to wellness
and it includes our food and it includes
our attitude and in our intention and
the place that you come from in your
garden and in your work all of that fits
together to make something that crew is
holistic is is sustainable in the sense
of we can continue to do it while
flourishing diversity yes yes
let's see thank you I really Wendy