[Music]
we start talking about block J now I was
thinking about this in preparation for
this panel
you know I've I've been doing technology
development for the last 20 years which
basically means that for the last 20
years I've been hearing
middle-management spew buzzwords at me
about the latest technology that we need
to integrate into into the into the
solutions and it's made me really bitter
in a lot of ways you know I can rattle
off a list of a lot of technologies that
you've probably heard acronyms for that
don't know a whole lot more other than
the name of I think there's a lot that
we can we can blame that for I don't
know how many of you are familiar with a
concept called Moore's Law it's a
concept in computer science it's a
concept and technology period basically
what it comes down to is it dictates
that the speed and capacity of any
technology will double approximately
every 18 months ever since the advent of
personal computer and the internet
that's been something that's been pretty
steady if you look at processor speeds
if you look at the internet speed
Moore's Law has been a pretty good
indicator of how things are gonna
progress and it's created this this
culture of the shiny new object
in technology it's created this culture
of well I'm using technology that's 2
years old and and this my new guy this
24 year old who just started working for
me is trying to sell me on this new
technology that just came out it must be
better it's 2 years newer let's move to
that right and so you know for the
purpose of you know this conversation I
was joking with these guys that I'm
gonna play devil's advocate a little bit
and because of the fact that you know
really if I've had a nickel for every
time someone told me that blockchain was
in a solve every problem I had and my
software company I would be retired by
now so let's we're gonna take some time
to figure out what's going on with that
what's really real what's important
what's what are the real applications of
this technology and what's not so from a
friend of perspective of a technologist
for me I look at blockchain
a modern-day example of what we've
always referred to as a datastore right
like as a database when it comes down to
it it's a digital ledger to distributed
ledger and it's a place where you can
store data and and reference it later on
so the first question I want to ask the
panel and give these guys all a chance
to answer is what differentiates
blockchain
what makes blockchain different better
and more applicable to the issues that
you're each facing on a day-to-day we'll
start with Ken so I think the primary
value of blockchain technology is the
firm a transaction perspective is the
absence of third-party intermediaries
finding financial intermediaries so when
you think about you know processing a
traditional payment it goes through
multiple layers probably about seven
different parties we need when you
compare that to that of the blockchain
you know it's it's a transaction that's
occurring between you and the other
individual I think that you know being
able to have the decentralized model
allows each person to become their own
bank and have full control of their own
money and and without all the expenses
the cost that it associated with you
know paying each individual in that
transaction stream from Trent that's
just from a transactional perspective
all right sure I'm thinking of it a
little bit more from what you mentioned
as a new type of database you know we so
at ages for looking at cannabis data
from a couple of different angles one is
that you've got everywhere from
manufacturers testing facilities
dispensaries really collecting a lot of
extremely valuable data data that's both
valuable to them in a business sense as
well as potentially a valuable source
for medical findings for research
findings I mean I think the billion
dollar question right now this industry
is matching up a specific person or
their needs with a specific strain which
is really a specific set of chemical
compounds that best help them so unlike
many other medical industries we don't
have an NIH Institute
that's doing this for us and I think the
blockchain is a really great way to
organize this data in a way that
everyone can contribute the data in
exchange for returning data back or
returning results back and at Ages were
also really interested in kind of the
bottom-up approach which is collecting
that data and everyone knows that their
data is valuable these days it's just
most people understand they don't get
paid for it they get their free service
it exchange for personal information and
I think there's a chance to couple the
transactional potential potential of the
blockchain with a way to actually
collect some of these data from
individuals in a way that we can
incentivize them and reward them for the
sharing yeah you know I was fortunate
enough to be part of the web hosting and
domain industry back in the early 2000s
when we had Oracle databases and
Microsoft and sequel databases and now
we look at the stored value of data
which is blockchain and being able to
utilize that capture it and have it in
place where you can't alter it unless
you change the hash it's gonna enable
people to be successful in a way where
they can utilize that data over and over
again without having to have the
hindrance of big data cumbersome
companies coming in to really alter my
business plan like a Microsoft or an
Oracle so now we all can become our own
Microsoft and Oracle to develop these
products for our customers on a very
quick basis and that's really that the
agile development that blockchain gives
us in order to deliver the right product
to this industry in particular I want to
stick with you banking is an area that I
think most of people are very intrigued
about as far as how blockchain can help
I mean it's a it's a widespread problem
I was talking to my team about this
today you know I've had individuals just
today two separate individuals on my
team have to transport thousands of
dollars in cash to a bank right and
we're not dealing with the same level of
currency that we're talking about for a
day-to-day dispensary operation so I can
only imagine how you know how
nerve-racking that is for those teams so
you know obviously mark you you can
speak to this a little bit as far as
a transfer of value a banking solution
you know what led you to the solution
that you're working on right now what
was the problem that you first
identified and what led you to the
blockchain as a solution yeah really
banking is is not the problem it's the
cost of banking that's the problem is
really what it is that the compliance
and the rules that you have to follow
which are set 2014 FinCEN came out with
rules to follow how I got it is my
backgrounds actually technology and
private equity funding I had a group
come to me they wanted to invest in one
of my projects I was so excited I'm like
this is gonna be amazing
and they go okay I go here's my terms
loved it here's my contract they loved
it and I said here's my wire information
and they go why don't you come out to
the farm and we'll spend a little time
together
they showed me more cash I've ever seen
in my life in one spot I go let's get it
to the bank and put it to work like Lots
our problem we don't have a bank account
and I couldn't figure it out I was I'm
not from the cannabis industry and I was
like okay I can figure this out well
then after months and months of finding
that it's a serious problem for not just
these folks but you know everybody in
the industry I was fortunate enough to
find a company called integrated
integrated compliance solutions that
does AML and kyc and and VSA software
for banks today and I go this is amazing
so I became a venture partner and they
go you know one of our biggest problems
is the ability to move payments from
what from b2b selections and capturing
that known source of funds for that and
I go okay and so hence c2 was born and
that's why we chose blockchain to solve
that problem got it great Ken I know you
guys focus a lot on and all 36 you have
a lot of focus on the consumer
experience as far as the transaction
from the I know you do other things as
well but there's a lot of focus on the
consumer experience and also I would
have to say that this crypto as a
solution to a lack of credit card
processing is one of the pitches that I
hear most often when it comes to
blockchain so you know what
differentiates to all 36 you know why
why have you guys been able to achieve
the amount of success that you have so
you've probably heard a lot of pitches
do too
the increase in icos in the market
initial coin offerings so a lot of
projects have come up in the market that
have created and velop their own
single-use utility coin that's specific
to say cannabis right we have pot coin
and there's a couple other projects out
there I don't want to mention but
essentially what we've done is we were
really tackling it from the omni-channel
aspect right so we realized that the
cannabis industry is extremely
vertically integrated so the b2c is one
of the aspects that we're tackling it
from so what we've done is from the the
consumer perspective we want to make it
as seamless as possible blockchain
digital currency it's confusing it's
complex probably scares most individuals
that are not in this room maybe some of
them that are and so what our whole goal
is to basically kind of humanize digital
currency right and so what we've done is
we've essentially created a simple way
for consumers that mimics traditional
financial institution or services but
yet has all the benefits being able to
leverage all the benefits of blockchain
technology and cryptocurrency in the
background so when consumers from the
b2c side interact with our application
you know there's very little difference
between what they're doing now with
PayPal and what they're doing with us
additionally you know we're also rolled
out the b2b side of it as well we would
complete the first integration with can
trade it's our first b2b wholesale
marketplace they connect the
dispensaries of the vendors and
suppliers so we wanted it from the
consumer adoption perspective we didn't
want to just tackle the issue from one
from one angle we wanted to be able to
approach it from all angles even moving
to you know how do we get rid of you
know the the remaining amount of cash
that's in the industry you know from
those that won't adopt you know
technology and whatnot we've actually
we're actually even rolling out our self
checkout key us slash ATM so those that
you know or I don't know what digital
currency who's all 36 I just want to pay
in cash and I want to get my project and
get out so they can pick out their
product they can go over they can put
their cash in and they're out
so I think by you know really taking an
omni-channel approach to this I think
we're really able to not only achieve
mass consumer adoption but really kind
of get a grasp on this problem in the
cannabis industry as far as cash is
concerned Thank You Adam so happy that
you're here as well looking you know
future forward and thinking about
solutions that are not involving banking
or payment because that's I think where
a lot of the focus has been placed on
where there's potential solutions using
this technology you know with with ages
you guys are doing product development
you're doing research you're trying to
formulate products to help individuals
that are otherwise using opioids etc so
I think we can all get behind the cause
I'm curious to hear more about how you
foresee blockchain being a tool that
you're able to leverage to help in that
endeavor sure absolutely
so this builds a bit on my academic
experience and doing cancer research in
that environment we have of course the
NCI the National Institutes of Health
the National Cancer Institute as well as
the Big Pharma system and all of these
central organizations are what have
created these really amazing data
repositories that have sped up so much
molecular biology research the human
genome there's protein atlases where you
can look at what does it what's
expressed in any particular cell type in
my body and these are tools that when
scientists and researchers go to ask the
next question you go to these databases
first you don't want to reinvent the
wheel you want to look for something
next and ultimately in d convoluting
this multitude of chemistry of chemical
compounds that you have in cannabis with
what's hits any particular cell or set
of receptors and a given tissue in a
given disease state that's a hugely
complex problem and unless we go back 30
years and start doing hugely
reductionist science science of doing
these compounds one by one we're gonna
wanna use large data sets and some AI if
roaches and ultimately d convolute what
are the most effective compounds now
getting back to the database problem in
cannabis of course due to the
regulations and laws we don't have any
of these central of repositories built
we don't have the National Institute for
cannabis research but what we do have is
people like that are in this room that
have all of their own endeavors going on
they're all producing exactly this kind
of data that we need and really it's the
same kind of data you would get out of a
multitude of research labs what we need
to be able to do is integrate that data
in a way that you can not only analyze
all of the data but ask really your
important question of how does my sample
how does my chemistry compare to what's
going on so that you can establish your
unique niche in the market and target
the right customers and I think the
blockchain is uniquely fit for this
cannabis approach in that the industry
really prizes their independence as has
already come up and people I don't think
are even looking for one corporation or
one national agency to put this together
for them they want results now and the
blockchain is going to be a great way to
contribute data where everyone knows
that they're contributing validated data
as things were the big problems in data
integration and analysis is data
formatting and getting different kinds
of data sets integrated for further
analysis and these are all things which
can happen with community building in a
way that doesn't have a centralized
structure trust structure through the
blockchain approach the lack of
essential moral authority as a whole top
that we can get on to you as well I'm
gonna stick to the script for the time
being that's always that's that's that's
a fun one to talk about in the cannabis
space historically in technology there's
a difficulty in getting adoption for
what I'll refer to as black box
technologies so it's kind of something
where you give it an input something
happens that you don't know and then the
output comes out and you trust it and
move forward it's something that
consumers have a hard time with it takes
a lot longer for people to adopt those
sorts of technologies so
I'm curious how what do we have to do
how can we get the consumer to trust
blockchain technology you know whether
it's for a crypto perspective or or else
otherwise I'll start with Ken you know
how have you seen you know the adoption
of the - solution in on among the
consumers right looks like what sort of
education have you had to provide in
order to provide comfort to people in
order from nationally interactive system
absolutely I face this every day I think
it was on a call about three hours ago
where I had to kind of argue my way out
of this and so from a consumer adoption
perspective right every most people like
what they real what they know is that
the word blockchain right other than
that they know the benefits of it maybe
the four or five benefits of it right
but for anybody that's ever used digital
currency it's it's extremely like I just
mentioned this before it's human
confusing and how do you even obtain
digital currency right if I tell you
guys right now that - is at nine dollars
a coin and tomorrow it's gonna be at 300
I mean you guys would probably be able
to do it but they might not be able to
how would you go acquire - coins right
and so there's a lot of aspects that are
hindering the consumer adoption of not
just only - digital currency but of
digital currency and general blockchain
projects in general for the purpose of
this I'm just going to talk about
transactional purposes um and so the one
thing that like I had mentioned before
that we've done is we you know our whole
goal is to simplify the process right
everybody's so familiar with traditional
financial sir can you trust them right
you trust PayPal you trust right trust
Square but when they first came out why
did you initially decide to you know
enroll with those services right because
of the hope and value that it provided
and you know one thing that most you
know dispensary operators talk to big
things right what are the - price
volatility of the currency and consumer
adoption those are the number - those
are the top two things that everybody
has concerns with right so when we take
a look at consumer adoption you have to
provide incentive to the consumer to
change the
behaviors right think about Apple pay I
use this as a example all the time
I've Apple pay on every I have Apple
paid draped on me all day long I've used
it never there's no incentive for me to
use other than convenience right but
it's not convenient for me to actually
go and change behavior that I've that
I've known for 20 30 years now no so but
if the Apple pay if Apple said listen on
every one of your purchases we'll give
you 1% back or they had a loyalty
program that incentivized me to you know
get rewards for and you know that I
could use towards travel or other other
things right they don't so what we've
done is we sat down with the - Network
and we we explain to them that consumers
are not going to adopt a process unless
they feel like there's a benefit and in
actually adopting it so what we've done
is we're incentivizing the consumer in
multiple ways for adopting our
registering and opting our platform as a
preferred method of paying for cannabis
so in incentives exist from $25 off the
first purchase just for you know
registering in our platform to you know
double loyalty rewards points with the
loyalty platforms that we've worked that
were integrated with and I think that's
the that's the biggest thing and that
combined with not scaring with all the
aspects of digital currency and
blockchain hash algorithms like Bitcoin
prices - how many digits that all freaks
me out so try to keep it as simple as
possible and not freak anybody out
probably good move mark I think you're
another in a slightly different position
with the services that you guys are
providing you're focused largely on b2b
it's a smaller audience that you have to
convince to use your technology but that
being said I'm sure you have had plenty
of pushback on the fact that you're
using blockchain
what is the pushback what does that look
like and you know what are the
detractors saying our potential issues
with technology we decided to go a
different route from a technology
standpoint utilizing blockchain so we
offer traditional banking services first
and the blockchain is utilized to
capture known source of funds from the P
os systems the know your client data
when you do background checks we sign
people up so from a currency side that's
not how we utilize our blockchain we
utilize it simply as utility token to
move data from one place to another
since we are a traditional banking
system nationwide we can bank THC in any
state legal and CBD in every state I'm
convincing a business owner to open up a
bank account a traditional bank account
that they don't have access to today and
that's really our biggest standpoint on
this and then blockchain gets utilized
it's just part of our compliance week
just like MS sequel does or Oracle
databases it's just something that gets
utilized in the background in order to
enable those transactions so when we do
get OCC audits or state audits from a
banking perspective we can meet those
compliance and we can ensure that no
three-letter agencies come at anybody's
door so really we solve that problem
just by being a traditional banking
resource to allow customers to do
traditional wires when they need to send
out to the to make payments from a you
know a utility perspective or their
landlords but if they handle any
cannabis related business it has to
utilize within our blockchain
perspective so we can capture the known
source of funds so when the receiver
gets that money and if they get audited
they're gonna know exactly where that
money came from and who did the
transaction and what it was for so we
capture all that data so really it's a
it's a slightly different model but
traditional banking is really what we
have to offer and that's that's that's
how we can take blockchain and apply
that to this industry and not just this
one but every other one to do faster
transactions we can do it cheaper and
more efficient than you're gonna do in
any other thing you know you guys
probably wired money before right man
what a pain in the ass that is plus it's
expensive what if I could tell you I can
put a million dollars in Ken's account
right now in two seconds does that
appeal to you what's a blockchain does
and we can do that in a compliant way
one dollar transaction fee yeah
transaction fees one dollar yeah I have
to charge something if you want me to
charge more well if you don't mind
nobody okay no takers okay Adam I'm
curious to hear about by the way that's
on any amount so you it's one dollar to
move 100 million dollars
again moving away from the finance guys
sorry for a second Adam I want to talk
more about the scientific community you
know are there concerns amongst your
peers about a blockchain based tracking
system you know if there are you know
what are people worried about I would
say it's just the opposite I would say
the approach overall is more similar to
Marx and that really the blockchain is
kind of built into the backend and it's
really not the users concern was their
concern as it gets the job done and the
main concern when people are discussing
how to use this data is how do I know
that I get the value for my data how do
I know I'm not disclosing anything I
don't want to and really these are
exactly the kind of of answers that the
blockchain can provide in that it is a
way to lock down your data it is a way
to track what happens to it when it gets
transferred afterwards and I think a lot
of both the security and the potential
data security that comes along with some
blockchain applications are more of a
solution
to data handlers than a problem right
and I think with a lot of especially in
this industry as well bringing it back
to how this relates to cannabis with the
breaches in data breaches and security
systems going down I think that's
something that probably a lot of people
can that's a problem a lot people can
relate to I want to not quite pivot but
I want to focus on something that I
think is really to me one of the more
interesting aspects of blockchain
technology and that's smart contracts
for those for those here who don't know
what a smart contract is it's basically
a scripted contract that all the
criteria for completion are scripted
into the contract before it takes place
the contract automatically executes upon
the fulfilment of all set criteria so to
think about at a high level it's it's
like when you stand in front of a
vending machine there's a smart contract
between you and the machine that if you
give it 2 bucks and 50 Cent's and push a
button you're gonna get a coke right
that's a very high-level example of what
a smart contract looks like I'm really
curious to hear what the implications of
smart contracts are for each one of you
and your businesses you know how do you
all think that smart contracts are going
to impact the business world at large
but also you know specifically around
what you guys are doing and what are
some potential shortcomings there well
we use smart contracts for is if
traditional escrow services somebody you
might about a house or some other
transaction where you needed to parties
had to agree and provide certain things
in order for a transaction to get
completed so we can use smart contract
from that so we provide full escrow
services for all our clients that are in
our banking platform right so I want to
buy thousand kilos of ice lid or I want
to move you know ten million dollars
from one transaction or another we can
actually put that in a smart contract
act as an escrow service for you and
again we can do it almost for nothing
that means the cost electricity at that
point and that's one of the most
appealing things for us to do so instead
of costly you know you might use safe
funds or something like that to do a lot
of your larger transactions you don't
need to do that when you have smart
contracts and we can we can already
captured your data because you're on our
banking platform so we know who you are
we know your known source of funds and
now all you got to do is give us a
criteria for your transaction is it I
had a license bonded warehouse did it
get delivered
what are those expectations we put that
in once those are met transactions
completed and then it's done so that's
smart contract for us and I think it's
really amazing it's gonna revolutionize
how cost the transactions happen I can
absolutely see applications at the
higher level once we have a lot of data
pooled together where there are some
type of incentives for doing analysis
for for working on the data but what I'm
really excited about the smart contracts
is for data collection there's so much
we're in this really unique position
with cannabis right now where because of
not only the medical recommendation
system but especially legality we
basically have an uncontrolled clinical
trial going on at all times with
millions of people people are treating
specific elements with their favorite
products and this data is hugely
valuable as a whole for for medical
analysis and and everyone knows that so
I like the idea of if people are willing
to give us more data longitudinal data
more personal data we can use a smart
contract system to pay them for this
data and then pay them again once a that
data is in a pool that's used by a
company for analysis it it's I think
using these methods we can incentivize
people to not only give us data but
really give us kind of a live look at
what's happening with them on the level
of every other little Internet of Things
device and Apple watch that is coming
out and yeah I think I think as a whole
that would be we need to collect this
this data before it's gone I think smart
contracts are awesome
you think about how many inefficiencies
are within every one of our experiences
in life right you ever go you have a
broker involved in any process that you
do mortgages buying your car Minh
efficient I mean what are they doing
that's in your best interest right what
is a broker doing is everything that's
in his best interest rate and it's not
necessarily an efficient fair
transaction right but from a smart
contract perspective I think that you
know within the cannabis industry given
that it is so vertically integrated
let's use California for an example
right
I think smart contracts combined with
and this is cool what you can do with
different blockchain projects is you can
have every blockchain project as you
guys probably know has a different
purpose right there iam smart contracts
- transactional so by combining two of
the projects you know in incorporating a
transactional blockchain project within
a say a smart contract project as the
supply chain moves throughout as the
product moves throughout the supply
chain everybody knows right how many
points is it in 15 points right now in
California something around there but
that we can enable
so that as the supply moves through the
product moves throughout the supply
chain the individual will get paid in
real time I think that's probably one of
the most beneficial uses to and removing
the the whole aspect of brokerage again
coupling it on escrow because that's
probably one of the most utilized
resources for smart contracts great
awesome thanks another thing that I've
been doing a little research on lately
and and strikes me as really intriguing
is blockchain as a tool for Identity
Management I think we've probably all
heard some story about crypto
millionaire who lost all their money
because they left a USB Drive with their
private key in their pants that they
lost right that sort of thing right so
Identity Management is a real
significant issue when it comes to to
blockchain is there I mean along with
this as well I've been reading a lot
about the refugees that so many refugee
problems around the world and how they
are having problems with identity as
well not so much from a financial point
of view but more so of you know these
are these are individuals we've had to
leave their home without their passports
they have no way to identify who they
are and basically that means that they
don't exist in a lot of ways and there's
no way for them to identify who they are
so the question I have and I guess you
guys need to take it in its own in your
own way
is is there a way to leverage a
distributed blockchain solution for
identity management that will help
alleviate some of the issues that we've
seen I think we already carry a few
things that fit Identity Management
which sees right here which enabled us
to work 24/7
unfortunately I'm sure most of us do
really you're gonna see blockchain focus
on more of just like I said aggregating
data and information and being stored in
a central location might be a chip in
your neck or a chip in your phone but
it's gonna be somewhere that you store
with you right just like a poker chip
you you carry out on a poker chip that's
the value it's if I lose that just like
my ID or my credit cards or anything I'm
really upset about it
but I can't lose those things so if I
put that in the blockchain and being
able to use from an identity perspective
if I can scan my arm and all the sudden
the paramedics know that my blood type
and any other known sickness or illness
or whatever's wrong me that'd be pretty
cool and I'd do it something call Big
Brother but really that's the future
where we're gonna go and I think that
would be one of the best ways to solve a
refugee problem cuz I could identify
myself and if somebody came across me
and they scan me they know where my
family could possibly be because then
maybe we have GPS locators on us again
we already do with Cameron on our phones
I think that'd be pretty cool to help
solve that
yeah identity is identity is a really
big piece of the evolution of health
healthcare right now and I mean I'm sure
we most of us have had the situation
where you go from one doctor or another
or you go to see a specialist and
somehow all you do is walk down the
hallway in the same hospital and
suddenly your records aren't available
and it gets even worse if you're going
between hospitals dealing with insurance
and blockchain based identity for health
health record tracking has been really a
pretty big you know application
discussion IBM's getting big into the
area and I think mmm really cannabis use
is just going to integrate with the rest
of your health care and how does
cannabis interact with the rest of your
drugs and it really just kind of
dovetails into I think the larger future
of having your medical records not only
shareable between hospitals but
accessible to yourself as well because
that's another thing that is really hard
to get done when you need a paper copy
of something so I think that all rolls
together with some of the digital
healthcare and identity that's coming so
for me I didn't need management
perspective I will talk about kind of
like identity of you know specific
products because it can be tracked to
personal identities as well but when you
think about genome tracking right from
cannabis perspective you created og cush
how can you prove that you store that
information in the blockchain as a
sequential form of blocks that that are
built behind it that are immutable so
essentially if you're able to store that
data within the blockchain you're able
to identify the original creator of that
specific strain and be able to track it
back throughout all of history and
that's great thing about blockchain
technology is permanent until the end of
history and I think that's you know from
a cannabis perspective that's one of the
biggest things from an actual user
perspective I think why don't you know
one of the benefits of blockchain
technology is the fact that you know
when you make a transaction your
personal identity is not tied to that
transaction right the only thing that's
tied to that transaction is your wallet
address and that in the transaction
amount right so one thing that you know
I think from a compliance perspective
that the government is trying to you
know really try to figure out and this
is the topic of conversation and
blockchain is how is the federal
government gonna regulate this from a
compliance perspective right we talked
about AML KYC anti-money laundering know
your customer well when somebody makes a
transaction on the blockchain there is
no identity
PII personal identifiable information
associated with that transaction so I
think you guys are all aware of what
happened in Silk Road right I you know
they're still going back and mining the
blockchain and pulling out records but
they still can't tie those individual I
mean Ross Albrecht poor guy
but anyway so they can't tie those
individual transactions what there's
ology dressers well addressed to an
actual human so I think from an identity
perspective you know the government and
and I guess where we and I'm not trying
to pitch our company but and also him
know pitching we were I'll pitch him we
do kind of similar things from a you
know an AML kyc perspective you know
we're able to verify and tie an actual
identity behind that transaction so that
way you know nefarious illicit
transactions are being able to be
tracked and and stopped in real time
versus I mean what's been happening with
blockchain technology and people using
it to avoid all sorts of everything so
also I'm gonna open it up to questions
here in a little bit but I just want to
give these guys a last minute last
chance to kind of talk about what's next
so again a lot of people look at
blockchain as this blank canvas solution
to so many of the world's problems so I
guess last question I have for each of
you and we'll start with mark and work
our way back up what else
what haven't we talked about tonight
that is an a valid application for
blockchain technology as a solution I
think we already touched on quite a bit
from a medical perspective a personal
perspective a financial perspective we
can tokenize anything I got people
coming to me right now I work with us
gold we're making tomorrow you're gonna
hear about a launch of a new gold token
it's coming out of Wyoming so watch out
for that didn't pitch though but so we
can tokenize anything if you have an
asset like energy which is a really big
one real estate just think of how we can
get away from again escrow services or
the reason for all the transactional
peace and unfortunately might put people
out of jobs but we'll figure something
out later but really what that's gonna
do is enable very quick transactions
again compliant to ensure everything's
wait it's supposed to be like title
companies there's no reason for a title
company it's really no reason for
brokers and you know mall brokers to but
there's no reason for that we can really
solve all those problems
utilizing blockchain it may sound corny
but it's but it's real and you guys
right here sitting in front of a lot of
people that are pioneers in this
industry and we're you know we've been
in this 15 minutes longer than you you
should get involved because it's really
gonna be something's gonna change your
life so the way my research career
evolved over the last decade or so I got
really involved in well it's a company
called science exchange and one of the
things they do is connect people that
need experiments to people that have the
equipment and expertise to do it and
this kind of distributed science
approach has a lot of potential
it certainly is faster and cheaper than
spending two million dollars to set up
your own equipment and reinvent the
wheel in your own laboratory and the
other thing that comes into play is
there is
a glut of phd's in this country right
now 20 years ago the NIH system exploded
and there are people that have been
sitting in the same lab working on the
same thing for 20 years and these are
just talent and minds that are ready to
be put to work if they have some
incentive so I love the larger concept
of using the blockchain to issue some
type of Technol tech or science
challenge here's the data tell me what
you can do with it
earn your reward like an X price
situation differ for data but in a
wrangling smaller and maybe smart
contracted because I really see people
that would love to work on this if they
had the data in hand and a little bit of
incentive it wouldn't take much for
these academics and I really think
that's that's the way a lot of good
science is gonna get done in the future
great all right now I'll throw to one
from the cannabis industry one from not
the cannabis industry so the cannabis
industry I think a good applicational
use would be cannabis futures
I think that's an entire market that you
know is there's a lot of players right
now that are exploring it and they're
starting to put together platforms and
markets to try to tackle this but I
think if we were to utilize blockchain
for you know the cannabis futures market
I think it'd be a significant thing non
cannabis we've been you know we partner
with the - Network probably about a year
and a half go we've been working
actually with the congressman Schweikert
in Arizona I one thing that we've been
we've been talking about and I think it
would be super beneficial to not only
part time workers but you know so these
micro transactions micro transactions
are they cannot occur in a lot of
environments right every single
transaction ESCO through our bank
there's fees associated with it and the
it's not worth actually processing the
transaction but much removed drivers or
lyft drivers and so forth these
part-time employees that don't
necessarily get retirement benefits and
so what we've been working on is being
able to provide micro transactions for
these large organizations so that way
they can provide incentives to these
part-time workers that may not be you
know privy to getting you know I'm not a
full time employee I can't get
but being able to at least provide them
the fractional amount that they should
be getting based off the work that
they're doing so there's a lot of cool
things you can do with it it's just the
tool right it's a tool I think that's
what you know one thing that if there's
one takeaway for me from everything I've
learned about blockchain is that it is a
tool a lot of people want to give it
magical sort of attributes and and and
paint it as the solution to all the
world's problems but at the end of the
day it's it's a tool no different than
Oracle was a tool it's a tool no
different than jQuery was a tool it's a
tool so really interesting seeing what
everyone does with it now you guys have
been sitting so patiently and quietly I
want to thank you guys for that covered
a lot of different things jumped all
over the map on this curious if anyone
has any questions for anybody up here
the main topic here is is around
volatility concerns that people have
around cryptocurrency right and so I
don't know how many people know how how
a transaction and cryptocurrency works
but basically you take fiat currency
dollars Canadian dollars whatever have
you euros you transfer it into a
cryptocurrency you then use that
currency to transport that value from
one individual to another
at which point if the individual wants
to be able to use that currency for
anything I'll still have to transfer
that back into fiat currency so the
question I think specifically is around
that volatility so if the market is very
volatile if the transaction takes a long
period of time there's a potential for
the asset to be worth less when
converting it back into fiat currency
than it was when it first was converted
in so I think the question is how are
you accounting for that and what are the
solutions that you provide absolutely so
like I said earlier that's one of the
one of the two major concerns for
dispensary operators so we were luckily
lucky enough to partner with probably
the top five blockchain projects in the
world one of them being exchanged so
what that does is allows us to provide
the ability within our platform so when
somebody pays in digital currency we can
actually convert immediately back to US
dollar without with the zero vault with
zero exposure to the volatility the
price and so
at the beginning what we're doing is
we've enabled our Auto conversion
feature on all transactions because we
feel that most people and forgive me I'm
talking about those guys not you guys
I'm just kidding but most people don't
understand digital currency right they
don't understand the markets they don't
understand what volatility means they
don't understand that you know over the
course of eight hours that the price can
you know drop significantly or it can
increase significantly right so given
the fact that most people's exposure to
risk is very very low we we've enabled
the auto conversion now as people what
we feel as people get more comfortable
to accepting digital currency and the
volatility price understanding how the
markets work you know will allow them to
control that actually we still do right
off the bat we allow them to control
that feature so say that say the price
of the digital currency is significantly
increasing that reak well I'm not gonna
Auto convert immediately we give them
the option to create strategies around
increasing the the valuation of the
money or the funds that they're in
taking so you know say for a week
- currency is significantly increasing
well I would encourage them so they
accept you know they accept money from
the consumers at a certain price over by
the end of the day they've increased the
price of that by you know a certain
percentage maybe they batch out at the
end of the night so we give them options
that maybe you know do nightly bashing
hourly batching whatever they feel like
doing but we want to be able to give
them the control as they feel
comfortable as as their threshold of
risk so how is that any different than
using a banking solution correct like
how does that the question is with this
digital currency system being merely for
transferring the monetary value from one
holder of fiat currency to another
holder a fiat currency but at the end of
the day they're still left with that
fiat currency right like how can they
then is there a banking solution or how
can they work around the fact that
there's not a banking solution for that
fiat currency so so the the thing that
we're running into it's not even it's
not even a banking problem it's it's the
ability to be to accept payments via
Visa MasterCard the payment card
networks right so from a banking
perspective banks actually
they love us because they're seeing
those funds coming from the exchange of
digital currency rather than from the
proceeds of cannabis right given that
we're you know we have money
transmission licensing where money
transmission business or service
business through fencin fully registered
you know they they actually they they
don't have a problem with that
whatsoever it's more or less getting the
money from Visa MasterCard in the system
without actually going through you know
the actual rails so I they I don't see a
problem with it
do you at that point yeah it's it's very
similar so like ken's product just just
like ours is we start as a compliance
company first
so when Kent's taken in that money he
knows there's no source of funds or I
don't know where you're at but known
source of funds is probably the biggest
thing for banking and so like so we go
through OCC audits and state audits and
if we have that information then we can
comply with FinCEN 2014 requirements and
so so you've seen the cash problem so
now that they have cash on hand how do
they get it to the bank the the
follow-on question was now that the
banks have a known source of funds is
that what will placate them in order to
allow these individuals to then bank
with their institutions so so the the
topic that a lot of people they don't
even like to mention it's like money
laundering let's talking about money
laundering there's money laundering is
not a bad thing if you understand
regulation and compliance there's two
types of money I want to be on record
doing saying that absolutely I do I'm
gonna look at the camera and point at it
because I believe in my compliance team
there they're amazing I
so there's illegal money laundering and
there's legal money laundering illegal
money laundering is basically you're
trying to clean money without without
tracing it or without reporting it right
and then there's there's there's legal
money laundering too where you're
actually reporting that money that
you're receiving and you're creating a
traceable record of it back to the
government as long as you're complying
within FinCEN's BSA
the Bank Secrecy Act all of their
regulations which the amount of time and
believe me costs that we've put into
doing this I think that we're in full
compliance of everything that the the
federal government's asking for at this
point so so how so how are you solving
the solution to the problem of tying an
identity to a source of funds using your
solution so from a so when so we provide
that kyc layer as far as understanding
who our clients are and where the money
is coming from right we actually provide
that and it's actually built in just
like his platform as well but we've
actually automated the entire kyc
process within our within our platform
so that way you know we're identifying
where the money's come from how much it
is reporting it to the necessary
entities that way there's a lot I can't
talk about but FinCEN you know SARS
reporting all that good stuff
yeah I'm not supposed to talk about it
according my compliance officers but
there's a lot of the stuff that's going
on back in that we're doing that ensures
the government that we're tracking all
of the funds that are going through our
system and we're actually tying an
identity to those wallet addresses and
at the same time if we want to take it
one step further
you know we've integrated compliance but
our compliance aspect to where risk
scoring so we actually every single
wallet that hits our platform we hit
every terrorist database we have every
dark web database to ensure that that
wallet address is has not been used to
for terrorist activities or you know
illegal act dark what we we make sure
that our environment is as compliant as
we can be given the pseudo anonymous
anonymity of blockchain transactions I
want to take the opportunity actually to
add a follow-on question because I think
there's a distinction between your
platforms that is very interesting you
you glanced over earlier Markin and that
you guys use a utility coin right as
opposed to a to what Canada's it's more
of a traditional coin token can you give
a brief explanation of of the difference
in why it matters utility token compared
to a transactional token is is we use
ours to store data and value
and move it from one place to another so
if you deposit a dollar into your bank
account I'll give you a digital
representation of it so you can move it
just as you do when you use we need two
digital payments it's just again
happening in the background where you
have a transaction that gets utilized so
it's there's no volatility there's
nothing to it the dollars in your bank
account you can look at it at any time
if we just use a digital representation
to move that in a cheaper faster
lower-cost way so utility tokens are
going to be more of a norm we'll call it
asset backed so that's really what's
gonna happen just we talked about energy
or gold or anything else as long as
something has some type of asset that
it's gonna it's gonna help utilize that
as a utility to transmit information or
data from one place to another got any
more questions out there Oh got a bunch
John so the question was I'm sorry so it
was around the fact that and it's
something that's a topic that I've
actually spoken about a lot like until
the day comes when I can swipe my credit
card and there is no difference in the
process to me as the observer the
consumer of how that value gets
transferred from my credit card to the
proprietor of the dispensary how far
away are we from that day to when that
can happen well again we'll get back to
the banks ACH automated Clearing House
vs. Visa MasterCard right so we're
probably a ways away from Visa
MasterCard being PR friendly with
cannabis related companies but from the
consumer perspective right that's really
all we care about is a consumer picks
out their product they pay for it using
the account the means that they have
necessary to pay for that transaction
with minimal friction involved so from
the consumer perspective when you
register within I'm not trying to
promote our platform but essentially
when the customer register simple
process they link it to their checking
account via the plaid plaid integration
I actually incentivize them for doing
that's a one-time behavior every single
time they're going to the Spencer all
they have to do is pick out their
product verify the transaction via SMS
text notification the dispensary has
their funds in real time
the customer has their product it's
actually simpler than a PayPal
transaction but I will say and here's
where I get to play devil's advocate
that's not what we're looked at snot
what he asked about what do you asked
about when can I swipe my credit card
and everything is exactly the same as it
was before I was snap
I don't know I'm not yep it's right now
absolutely right now we launched about
two weeks ago we we're we just got fully
integrated our first b2b wholesale
marketplace our second partners almost
completely through with their
integration on the b2c platform we have
about 15 other integration partners will
be hitting the industry pretty pretty
damn Marg so right you'll see you soon
so the question is yeah are the BCR the
banks cool with this yeah the banks love
it because here's the thing right like
he was saying before what is the most
why are the banks not accepting cannabis
related accounts right cannabis related
business because of all the compliance
policies and procedures that go into you
know know your customer czars filing on
every single transaction it's costly
they actually do not make money on
cannabis related businesses so I mean
when you when you sign up as say you do
get a bank account look at the fees you
have to pay
it's insane I think we just priced
Windows 12,000 just to get a bank
account but but the whole whole thing
about it is is that you know the banks
from from you know our perspective they
love what we do because we keep them
arm's length distance away from cannabis
we actually provide and we refer I've
all those let's call it compliance
features that they would normally have
to do and in we send them great accounts
and they love it so I mean from our
perspective you know we have a portfolio
of banks that we work with both domestic
and international because you know we
don't just operate in the US or a global
company so work city works out pretty
well I guess we're gonna have to wait
and see what the adoption looks like you
guys should have a conversation
it sounds like yeah we have some more
any more questions one what this
gentleman do we take on all the risk as
long as we're abiding by FinCEN's
regulations we do not take the risk
so I mean what let's talk about what
risk are you are you talking about legal
risk or financial risk oh oh yeah
snap yes absolutely yes yes and that and
that was kind of our whole the whole
purpose in us implementing what and not
just you know building out a kyc AML
policy but actually building that into
the technology and creating the software
protocols that automate the process so
that way we don't have to think about
what we're doing and it just did we stay
compliant while we sleep so it's kind of
cool sounds great
a lot of the questions we got
we got one we got one
so track and trace yes yeah and I think
that's actually something that we didn't
touch on we actually did attempt to get
some folks to join us to speak about
tracking trace and you know we've I
think those of us in the industry
especially anyone involved the
dispensary knows the nightmare of the
current compliance landscape whether
it's metric or any one of the other
systems that everyone has to comply with
whether it's outages or any other sort
of situations that people have seen or
just you know for lack of a better way
of saying at a lack of sophistication
amongst the systems right I think I
personally think there's a lot of
opportunity for someone to step in and
really disrupt so it's great to hear
that you know that someone is and I
think you're probably not alone there's
there's definite lot of other folks who
are seeing blockchain because I mean
it's kind of tailor-made for that right
I mean it's it is a distributed ledger
that allows you to track all these
different transactions with no central
moral authority to say we're gonna shut
this down because X Y Z which is exactly
what you want and because of the fact
that it's distributed there's no central
system that is required to be
operational in order for for any of this
to work at any given time right it
should just always work the question is
who's gonna build the best in my mind
the question is and I'm sorry I've been
waiting to talk so the question in my
mind is you know who's gonna build the
appropriate system right again it comes
back down to the to the point of this
being a tool as opposed to a solution
right so the blockchain is a tool who's
gonna build the appropriate solution
that has the best user interface that
does the best integration with all the
point-of-sale systems but does the best
integration with all the cultivation
management systems right like who's
gonna build it so that that actually
happens quickly and efficiently and you
know that's that's a question I don't
have an answer to I don't know if if you
guys want to add anything to this but
it's it's something that's T be seen one
thing that's another part of that big
system I've been working on this is that
at least testing laboratories and I
believe manufacturers are required to
keep their records for seven years in
the state of California to comply with
metric so it's just once again not the
blockchain is the best solution but it's
certainly another data storage is
another
right and so ICS what we do is we
integrate into all the known seed to
sale systems and metric green
I'm sorry green bits we're in trees
we're an MJ freeway bio tracks or if
you're using any of those systems we're
already connected to the system so all I
do is I take your ID and I can integrate
that information and so so that that
behavior doesn't have to change from a
front-end and so I don't aggravate all
that data because we can't do that yet
but again that would be really cool if
if just one Authority was able to
integrate into all those systems and and
go do something awesome with it but yeah
absolutely it's just hard to do they're
there and those api's are available and
that's that's what we do the questions
to Adam about a statement he made
earlier about wanting to track product
efficacy amongst patients who have
specific needs and the need to then
compensate those patients for the data
in order for Adam to get the data he
needs to be able to identify what's fact
and what's myth about what strains work
for what application so I think the
question is how how are you incentivize
the patients to do that right so the
just sat on the last bit is how do you
make sure that that falls under HIPAA
compliance and that all the boxes are
being checked in order for it to be
legal right yeah there I think there's a
couple of good reasons here the first
one is the integration of the smart
contracts for the micropayment sort of
data we're not what we wanted to do is
really reward people for reporting and
tracking what they're using and how it's
working and it's close to real-time as
possible
we know this data is going to be hugely
messy these are self-reported
observations on how did this
particularly make me feel this time and
but that's okay a there's a lot of
fields in science that are able to
handle extremely messy data with the
proper computational tools and and data
set so and not only that but the smart
reward system I think allows us to tune
in what kind of data is most valuable in
order to get over the messy data process
and really focus on what could be
meaningful such as longitudinal data is
something that's extremely difficult to
to collect in clinical research right
now and that means those patients taking
a patient I'm sorry this patients taking
a medication how does this work over
time they may know in the first
treatment but really if you have a
chronic disease and cannabis is all
often for a chronic disease kind of
state your data of following up with
that single patient for a hundred data
points is a lot more valuable than a
hundred single data points from
different people so I think the smart
contracts are a way to incentivize
really smart data collection number two
is that there's not going to be I don't
think one authority one corporation that
takes over this data collection and just
dominates the field it's gonna be a lot
of different people doing these efforts
in a way that most helps their business
and their product now I think putting
stuff on the blockchain with the kind of
micro control you could have over who
gets to access what data people can pool
their data and yet still have it
scrubbed in a way which is traceable
HIPAA compliant because there's clearly
only certain data packets that are
included in that particular particular
transaction so those those are the ways
I think these micro transactions would
help us aggregate the data into a size
where we can find something meaningful
and I just want to touch on one point
that you brought up which is HIPAA
compliance right it's something that a
lot of folks talk about when you use the
word patients and medicine all of a
sudden you fall into the category of of
something that at some point should be
HIPAA compliance but it's just really
weird catch-22 right now because it's
not federally legal and hip was a
federal body right so there's not going
to be a need for HIPAA compliance until
that happens and once that happens then
those well there's no patients
absolutely yeah no I agree yeah they
absolutely deserve that right for for
the HIPAA protections yeah but again
even getting back to the federal
regulations when somebody's using
considers themselves a recreational user
oh but it helps me sleep now do they
classify as a patient of course we
wanted to treat their data with the same
consideration and security but this
whole like right and I think that's
that's not a bad thing the other thing
that's a great thing for cannabis if
running you know it's true but when it
gets down to the regulations the
difference between running and
fda-approved clinical trial with a
hundred thousand patients and collecting
this data on the ground the way we're
able to is I think where the opportunity
is right I think that's you know that's
a really good point to bring up is that
with a lack of a federal legalization
there's a lot of things that we can't do
right so people are trying to figure out
ways around that so we can do it legally
and effectively I mean that's very same
problem that you're talking about I've
had brand customers of ours come to us
and say hey we need to know how
efficient our products are like people
are coming into the store and buying
product X because they think it's going
to help them sleep they think it's going
to help with their lack of appetite they
think it's gonna help with their
arthritis pain and we do the best that
we can in order to give them a
recommendation that should work for them
but then they disappear into the ether
these people never come back and give
you feedback about whether or not it
worked and it's a huge problem that
currently has no solution I mean people
are trying to fix it in many different
ways I think this is a really
interesting application yeah I think you
know we're focused on the patients on
the medical aspect but it would be
hugely informational and important to
dispensaries and how about the growers
growers don't get any credit for pride
and good product right now you go to the
dispensary you don't even know you know
you're you're Green crack is gonna be
the same thing next week it may come
from somebody else under different
conditions and so finding that thing
that works for you the track and trace
and and connecting you to the right
medicine is really where it's at
absolutely we have any more questions
out there I think we probably ought to
start wrapping it up here pretty soon
I'm very proud of all of us for making
through an hour
yes question guy number one so yes and
this is actually really Justin question
it comes up a lot right as the industry
continues to grow you know talking about
the origin of Green crack for example
how you know how can we be sure that as
you know she grows the right people are
getting credit that it's actually
tracked and and and that we can identify
that this is the actual formulation for
green crack for you know whatever it
might be like how can how can blockchain
be leveraged in order to make sure that
that intellectual property is stored
correctly and reviewable and easily
accessible it's a really interesting
question for a couple of the reasons we
already mentioned one is which you
really can't file patents you really
can't go to the FDA because the federal
regulations right now so I think it's a
little bit of people trying to come up
with solutions that work and you see
people doing things like sequencing the
genome other of their plant hashing into
a blockchain for posterity and they're
calling it proof of prior art a lot of
times kind of a pre legal classification
for showing this publicly the other
problem or the other twist is that was
that 15-20 years ago the patent system
cited that you cannot pant patent
natural genes so if you discover a gene
in nature if you discover a seed as I
think this would fall under you're not
allowed to patent that natural genome
sequence right now you can patent
modifications to genome sequences which
of course would say I'm gonna have GMO
cannabis which freaks people up but it's
could be really interesting to see even
what is patentable versus trade parka
Bowl you could say this is my green
crack and now you've said I've got this
chemical profile and there is a way you
know when I'm doing I work in a lot of
drug discovery research from natural
products actually and what you could
patent was the application of a certain
compound even if it was natural so you
may be able to say well I can't patent
the genome to my seed but I'm gonna find
out application patent for this exact
ratio of THC CBD in these
or terpenes for treatment of nausea and
you patent a formulation and application
that is still going to be possible but
of course then it comes back to can you
replicate that in platform or now are
you talking about some type of farm or
product right and we're seeing that with
epidemics right coming out now first I
don't know how many of you guys know
about this first FDA approved cannabis
based medicine for a very specific kind
of epilepsy if I'm not mistaken so
that's already starting now and you know
there's and then there's you know we can
have a long conversation about the
predatory practices of pharma I'm sure
everyone in the room was involved in
cannabis has had plenty of those
conversations and you know they're
talking about this being you know a
medication that costs upwards of
something like $12,000 a month or
something like that for the patient so
it's really pretty absurd what people
are trying to get out of this status
right now thirty two thousand thirty two
thousand a year that's where it is yeah
nope there you go so yeah absolutely and
that's actually really interesting and
just to add something on to that because
obviously you haven't heard enough for
me yet tonight I what I think is really
interesting you know for me as the tech
and data guy for so long at Baker one of
the big problems that we've I mean we
still tackle is data normalization
period right so we work with close to
1200 dispensaries each one of those
dispensaries has their own menu system
now we might have gotten that menu
system from their data they put up on
Leafly or on weed naps or from their
point of sale or from from any number of
sources right there's no UPC code there
is no universal product code in the
cannabis industry to indicate that this
product is the same product that I
bought you know six months ago or that
even that this product is made by the
same producer as this other product that
I bought and it makes for a norm an
enormous mess you know there's whole
company the headset a BDS analytics are
two companies that you know I've been
doing making great strides and trying to
solve this problem and trying to figure
out how to normalize data across the
industry and run analysis of that data
so you know they can already provide
trend information about what sort of
products
trending up what sort of products are
trending down and a lot of I know
operators are using that data to be very
to be more efficient in their operation
but at the end of the day it doesn't
exist the most simple like single
product Universal traceability system
doesn't exist and again I think that's
another opportunity for a blockchain
solution to have a centralized registry
based on the blockchain
you got any more questions guys Oh Rahul
okay so the question is when when we
refer to a blockchain or the blockchain
which actual blockchain are people
running off of is it aetherium or is it
another chain of proprietary and I think
both these guys have their own answers
to that question so my company uses
proprietary blockchain it was developed
for the music industry years ago to
capture song data and then royalty data
so it couldn't be altered to ensure
everybody got paid so that's we turn
that into a FinTech product and so again
we we own the exchange and we own the
tokens that's why we're able to do
transactions in the background without
outside interference so we're not a
distributed ledger well we've been at
least considering working with on the
stellar platform especially because of
their partner stellar because of the
partnership with IBM healthcare and we'd
also been working with them for
different direction
kind of came back around nicely we work
with the - network you know I've been
working closely at the founder and the
CEO and basically what they did was they
took a look at the blockchain protocol
and they've improved upon it you know
from blockchain scalability to
transaction time transaction cost so
given the fact that you know they've
improved on the metrics that you know
was first introduced into the industry
in 2008 - is the it proves to be kind of
the transactional blockchain that that
works best for our project and for
transactional money transfer monetary
purposes right just to clarify one thing
there I know we talked about transaction
speed earlier and efficiency and it was
a question about it from the audience
the speed at which transactions complete
is something that's very it's crucial to
this sort of solution right I mean you
can probably beat this better than I can
can block a Bitcoin is how long is the
average transaction taking right now
four to eight minutes can spike up to
thirty minutes for a transaction to
finish right so if you're looking at
this as a solution to I'm standing in
front of the point-of-sale wanting to
pay for something it's just not it's not
viable you just can't do it you can't
ask someone to stand there for up to
thirty minutes waiting for their
transaction to complete for that
transaction for in order to use that on
a regular basis so the the fact that
alternis six is using - specifically if
I'm not mistaken one of the reasons is
because of performance right we got a
transaction time - she's got a
transaction time down to a fraction of a
second and transaction costs a fraction
of a cent so I mean from a from a
utility perspective you know the
merchant doesn't want to pay a high
transaction fees the customer doesn't
want to stand at the point-of-sale so
you have to be able to it's a two-sided
platform so you have to be able to
maximize utility for both parties
involved and I think - the way that they
built out their network has been able to
tackle all those different components a
lot of people don't realize this but no
one really knew what they were getting
into when they built these exchanges
early on and one of the major flaws of
you know since no-one's representing
Bitcoin here I'll just go ahead and and
talk about them one of the major flaws
of Bitcoin is that no one really took
into account that the transaction time
was going to grow somewhat exponentially
with the size of the network so their
own success is their undoing you know
the more transactions that happen on the
system the slower the transactions
become and it gets worse and worse like
a lot worse over time so it'll be
interesting to see where that ends up
and all here's the other thing you can't
just like stop trading and like fix it
right it's just kind of like it just is
what it is and so we'll have to see what
that means for the for the Bitcoin
community and I know that other
exchanges have looked further ahead than
that one thing that you got to think
about as well is who makes the decisions
in blockchain network the miners those
that are solving the hash algorithms
that are that are that are verifying
transactions and where are these miners
located
they're in China right now and they're
based next to dams that and they're in
there paying off Chinese officials so
that way they can get free electricity
right now the Bitcoin network uses as
much electricity as a country at Denmark
was Ireland last year it's up to the
country of Denmark so when you think
about a governance perspective who makes
the decisions in the Bitcoin network the
reason we're not another reason we chose
- as well is because they built in a
second-tier governance system that
allows actually the members in the the
network to be able to vote and it's a
truly democratic network it's it's
pretty amazing kind of fully encompasses
the decentralization of the blockchain
it's great awesome we have one last
question from anybody Tory's thinking
about wrapping it up no well we got one
more okay so the question is when do we
all think that I'm assuming you're
talking about cannabis legalization that
cannabis will be federally legal and how
what should we anticipate like what's
gonna happen I'll start I'll throw that
out that it's a conversation that I
think we all have on a regular basis
some people are saying as long as five
to ten years I think that's far too out
in the future I think it's going to be
used as political leverage in the next
presidential election I think that
everything that we're seeing happen
right now on the East Coast
if you look at the legalization dominoes
that are falling on the East Coast Chris
Christie gets put out of office by a guy
who says you don't legalize cannabis lo
and behold he actually does it Cuomo
goes goddamnit now I have to do this
thing because Cynthia Nixon is also
breathing down his neck telling him that
you know I'm gonna run on a legalization
platform whether or not she wins he
still has to change it right not to
mention they both got Massachusetts
looking over their shoulder going hey
well we're about to do this in earnest
starting next month and you know unlike
the states in where everything is legal
now Colorado Oregon Washington where
they're relatively isolated you can be
in half of the eastern seaboard within
half a day's Drive right so you know
it's I think we'd be naive to say that
people are gonna stay within their
states to buy the cannabis if they want
right there's gonna be stuck nothing
stopping anyone from driving from New
York to Massachusetts once a month to
pick up their medicine
right and so that that tax that loss of
tax revenue on top of the fact that this
is totally political leverage right now
I think will mean that I'm calling it
two to three years before we start
seeing rumblings
I absolutely it's not gonna happen to
within this administration I actually
have the same exact thoughts he has on
this yeah I agree except I think that
CBD and perhaps maybe from cannabis
maybe only from hemp will be federally
legal by next summer
I think CBD is gonna happen real fast
the farm bill just basically did that
right and right and I think full
interstate transport everything's that's
where I was gonna go CBD and hemp is
gonna be what's gonna be legalized first
across the board and right now I can
transact in all 50 states so as far as a
product goes it's it's up and going and
it's pretty amazing I mean the health
benefits there outweigh and more
importantly the marketplace right my
parents have never smoked weed in their
life but they're taking CBD now and they
feel amazing because of it right so
let's think about it how many how many
people will actually want the siphon
topic effects and how many people want
the benefits well that markets gonna
outweigh and guess what guess what the
government wants taxes and they want
they want to get received that revenue
base and that's what's gonna change the
market is the ability to capture that
revenue awesome guys please help me
thank these guys for taking the time
other days and popping us I think I know
I'm gonna stick around for a little
while afterwards
Rico's here are we doing the raffle
right now I think it's a raffle time so
we got some goodies for folks
[Music]