i just want to show you around the
side of my house here we've got a blue
mat system in this little greenhouse we
use this greenhouse for a lot of like
kind of test projects
um the whole thing starts right here
with a
blue map pressure reducer and then we
jump up to this half inch poly tubing
and then that actually kind of snakes
along and into this greenhouse it
stops at various places and this is
watered with blue mat
all these mint plants but um
you know basically that water line comes
in here
and you know there's a few there's a
bunch of veggies in here right now
got some raised beds these um
these raised beds are all controlled
they come off of this line here and
there's a blue mat here you see that
which is connected to a little header so
this water line comes through here
into the blue mat into this header and
then this is one of our manifold beds so
here's that header line this is
connected
to four pieces of blue soak
um and
this is mostly wood chips in here
there's a bunch of
you know some potting soil on top
but the main thing is the
there's wood chips in the bottom and
they're heavily inoculated with the
stropharia rigosa annulata the garden
giant
so we get a lot of mushroom production
out of these we probably pulled
30 to 40 pounds of mushrooms per bed out
of this last year
anyways you can still see that water
line coming through
um again these are all on blue mats
they're slightly buried under some mulch
you can see some tape coming up here but
this whole thing is just on autopilot
from here this water line continues on
into kind of the rest of the garden
you know there's just a few things out
here right now
and the waters are mulberry trees and
the line actually snakes all the way
around here
and you can see there's that
that line right there that's eight
millimeter line
um that's connected all these blue mats
so all these you know tomatoes and
mint plants and even all these petunias
they're all um connected to blue mats as
well
um just the hibiscus
and we've got
some more production oriented
greenhouses across the
way over there a couple 30 foot
greenhouses
i'm gonna show you also the blue matte
classics um
these are cool they're just look like
this and these are what we use for house
plants but
basically you just stick this in the
soil and then you put one end of this
tube in a bucket of water and it siphons
the water out
so you have
your glue mat in there siphoning water
from this bucket
that's great for you know smaller plants
or seedlings
you know rooting clones things like that
this here's a line
an additional line that comes in this
one has
used this for a nursery production but
i'm coming off this line we have more
blue mats so you know i can
individually uh water
you know 5 gallon pots in this case on
this rod this is one of our
blue matte moisture sensors
what's that reading at 99 perfect it's
right just right where you'd want it
so yeah this is just part of the
kind of garden space here
at my home in colorado