[Music]
hey everybody i'm josh from dragonfly
earth medicine and i'm kelly from
dragonfly earth medicine and today we
have here with us Bob Snodgrass
legendary glass maker educator amazing
human being and community leader and we
are talking about what you know where
cannabis has come from and you won a
Lifetime Achievement Award this year and
we would love to know how you're feeling
about that
here we are it's 2018 I'm having
flashbacks two days before any kind of
regulation I remember a guy once telling
me that he used to make jello water and
sprays plants with it to get extra
weight well they're instantly didn't
want to smoke anymore of his weed but
today we were tested for how many
terpenes what your THC is but also you
get tests that say no mold and no
pesticide so that kind of reassurance
really brings in a healthy approach to
what we can do with our thousands of
strains so many have been developed that
there are weird characteristics to so
many pots so if one of them doesn't work
for somebody find one that does because
they all have a kind of a different
trait
and then anyhow here yeah and so and so
what have you really seen like you've
been in a really black market really
hidden you you've done a lot of Grateful
Dead tours so traveled with the Grateful
Dead family and now being here at the
Emerald Cup in an event where obviously
there's a lot of Grateful Dead family
all around all day today and yesterday
what's it what's it like now in a being
with this whole family in a state of
legalization makes me giggle first off
it's like yeah for the approach that we
have now we can walk out there and
there's a sign that says you can smoke
on this side and not on that side and
everybody can and everybody can carry I
see people carrying around clones and
I'm just tickled the open sharing in the
glass world opened it up that we've made
advances in glass tenfold at exponential
rates well this kind of event for
cannabis is allowing that exponential
ality to boil over into us growing
better pot and
my goal is a glassblower was to make a
pipe that allowed it to operate that
would let pot work at its maximum
potential and now we have so many
growers that are getting the pot to grow
at its maximum potentials and it's
really exciting it's really exciting we
would like to you know thank you for
opening us up originally to clean
cannabis smoking and being able to smoke
out of a glass pipe originally when it
was metal pipes and and dirty
apparatuses and and plastic bongs you
know you really kind of helped us get
into something clean in tin cans back in
the day when I first hit dead tour my
sales pitch was have you ever smoked out
a glass because 99.9% of them hadn't and
[Music]
career came after that of people
imitating mine and working at that to go
on and say really like the way you live
I want to do the same thing can you
teach me and I had people come out of
the woodwork from all over the country
all over the world and I I gave away all
the secrets but one that was the plan
and
[Music]
today that's what should be done with
everybody's pot we appreciate you
leading us like that and with the
grateful the spirit of the Grateful Dead
and the giving and in the spirit of what
you've taught us by teaching everyone
you taught us about the bell curve and
how we all learned together when we all
learn together we rise our as our
consciousness and our awareness and yeah
and it's you know you you have you've
open source educated you have been an
unbelievable shining example of come on
over if you have the time and the
dedication I'll teach you and you never
I know from way back in the day and
going out to the bus out in Vinita you
know there was a ton of people around
you were really always teaching
everybody whatever that they wanted to
learn and now there's all these amazing
glass blowers all over the place that
really have carried your legacy and have
really taken it you know even to their
own style and what's that like for you
to see that they're not all a bunch of
outlaws nowadays nobody has to be really
ducking and it's yeah you can be part of
a system and like I'm encouraging people
I think that I know that our growers to
check out their local Grange's and find
out about establishing coops because
bigger businesses are going to want to
come after you pretty soon and
method to stand up yep and that's what
we're working on with dragon fire with
medicine bringing people together and
we're upholding the spirit of what Bob
Snodgrass is done in the Snodgrass
family thank you so much for joining us
and giving us the opportunity to share a
little story you're the best thanks
[Music]