[Music]
first of all how long have you guys
known each other like when did you did
you first meet and like the Amsterdam
scene yeah that Noster Dome in 1993 or
393 somewhere around yeah and and what
was the scene like back then like who
were some kind of the people you were
running with in the well I moved to
Amsterdam actually I originally just
planning on touring around Europe and I
stopped off in Amsterdam first but Adam
Dunn who later form th seeds he's an old
childhood friend of mine of them
virtually all my life so he had been in
option ahhm for two or three years at
that point and he was like hey you got
to come over you're an old old-time
cannabis guy you're gonna love it here I
thought I'd go check it out for a couple
of weeks maybe a month or so I think I
told my family and friends that I'd be
gone total for a month minimum maximum a
year and I'd end up staying for six so
yeah and I was gonna travel all around
Europe and I just traveled through you
know Netherlands Belgium and then France
and then decided to come back to
Amsterdam and stay there for the
remainder of the six years and what in
kind of the early to mid nineties was
the state of genetics cuz people always
talk about I always view it like jingis
Caan has kind of you know he spread his
seed all over the world and like Dutch
genetics have kind of cross pollinated
with all the land raised so what was
going on in Amsterdam like what were you
seeing back in the early to mid 90s well
I look at Rob because a lot of what was
in Amsterdam at the time were the
pivotal varieties that came from
California and ended up such as such as
Hays skunk one Northern Lights which
didn't come from California but from the
West Coast West Coast afgan one Durbin
poison
early girl you know plants like that
we're so Durbin poison came into
Amsterdam not through South Africa but
through kind of people growing it in
California
it actually was collected by Ed
Rosenthal years ago in a coffee shop in
Amsterdam okay and then those seeds came
back to America things were selected
here and multiplied and then ended up
back in obstacle so he grabbed them in
what decade decade that would have been
the mid-70s okay and then started
growing in California because I know
with Jim Goodwin who fell Frank who
ended up being the keeper of those seeds
and what were you doing at this time I
was in 93 I was working with Hardy farm
and developing things that ended up
being used by GW Pharmaceuticals okay
yeah that was the aim at that point just
beginning harder for me you grew up
where because Adam was lived in
Jamestown Rhode Island for a while Adam
did live in Jamestown for a while Adam I
believe was born in Woodstock New York
and I was born in Big Sur California
kind of on the opposite ends of the same
spectrum and his family moved to
California when he was a young young
baby and that's where we met and I grew
up in a cannabis community you know the
Big Sur was a kind of a beatnik artists
enclave of people who had gone back to
the land to do their thing and it was
cannabis was definitely the one thing
that kind of connected the entire
community you know whether there were
musicians or artists or cultivators or
poets or communists or hippies or
whatever you know it was definitely
cannabis was the connective thing and it
was definitely a part of my life from
the beginning right and then what about
you Rob where did you grow up I was born
not far from here in Del Mar California
you're a California boy oh yeah I went
to school UC Santa Cruz and that's kind
of where it all began for me got it and
so when when you both first were playing
around with genetics what like NorCal
what 80s and SoCal probably I don't want
to date you but like late 60s in the
early like so I went to school and UC
Santa Cruz in 1971 okay and I did
actually technically I did grow up in
Southern California I spent most of my
formative years in Southern California I
left Big Sur as a fairly young child
moved to New York City and then back
over to the west coast and I first
planted my first seed of cannabis in
1983 which would have been some Big Sur
developed african hybrid that was pretty
popular at the time malawi based thing
that was definitely what one of the
first i mean it was the first plant I
ever grew but it was also an imprinting
kind of moment where it was like the
smell and the effect associated with
those first early plants that I
experienced definitely shaped what I was
looking for in cannabis for the
remainder of my life because that was
kind of the period when it changed from
in the late 70s or early 80s where those
early narrow leaf varieties started to
get hybridized with more Afghani based
stuff and is that something that you
still are breeding or find today or is
it been lost I'm still I think what what
it is is I'm still breeding towards
those goals but I think in many way I
mean it's hard to say what what we
thought cannabis was in the past and how
we're trying to you know achieve those
same effects or traits or whatever
because it's a memory at this point
unfortunately we don't have analytics to
go back on but there's always been a
certain effect that I felt was most
interesting for me and
the Afghani kind of base stuff was just
never that interesting so I've always
kind of been chasing that that type of
narrow leaf variety and and trying to
improve their agronomic capabilities by
figured crossing them with things that
maybe are a little bit more early
flowering and higher yielding and stuff
like that but it's definitely the
effects side and I still see it today
when I encounter people's land
race-based stuff it's definitely the
what I like to consume the challenge is
always looking at it and going wow how
can we bring that to the market how can
we bring these things that I think a lot
of people really desire from cannabis to
the market and in a way that we can make
it happen because I do think that
everyone appreciates those older those
varieties and what about you I also
really appreciate landrace sort of
cannabis everything's become with the
exception of the aromas involved all the
cannabis today is frightfully similar
and that's really what most people are
used to unless you were exposed to
cannabis 20 years ago you never really
had much of an idea that there's so much
diversity possible but but when you're
talking about landrace strains or
cultivars today can you give me some
examples of some stuff you've come
across recently and who has them and is
it something that that person had like
seeds that they forgot about from the
70s or that they've been breeding it
diligently for the past like they've
been the the stewards of those genetics
for the past thirty years or a little of
both I think there's a few seed
companies that have been championing
land race-based genetics and have
continued to provide those so people can
still go out there and find things land
race based because it's not a land race
once it leaves the region and the
geography and the people that created it
so but know there's there's some new
stuff that I've seen that have come from
seed companies and also a pheromone
stuff that just came from those
custodians of their old varieties and
they're yeah they're they're unique but
they're not unique they're they're just
great cannabis varieties that make you
feel good and and have a lot of positive
attributes that you know that people
seem to enjoy it's it's it's always been
a discussion of you know I think from
the original hybridization of these
narrow leaf and broad leaf varieties to
now I think people really appreciate the
effects associated with what we call
sativas and it's always this marriage of
you know can you get a farmer to grow it
versus all my friends who want to smoke
it you know and it's a compromise and
that's what we've been doing for decades
is making these compromises but those
original land race-based varieties that
were imported from around the world they
were all very unique and different each
one of them because there was no they
were all came from a very far off land
where they solicited yeah but but
specifically what who are some of the
the breeders or people who like recently
you've come across you have some of what
you're talking about I'm not really
known breeders more more old friends
that have the similar ethos in terms of
like I'm willing to grow varieties that
take a long time to flower and yield
very low and are hard to sell and doing
that for decades at a loss in order to
maintain what they believe is high
quality cannabis and what people should
be smoking needless to say a lot of
those people are not commercial growers
right that's just not their main if they
really want to make a bunch of money
they grow the same thing as everybody
else grows but a little bit different
well I mean you just sit on kind of the
California regulated market and kind of
like love and you know like the fact
that some stuff takes much longer to
flower right like it's we're in a market
where it's like yeah but a turn stuff
over quickly and yeah but that's also
partially because we haven't the market
hasn't matured enough to appreciate all
the the full spectrum of possible
products that you can make from cannabis
I mean I think that in to draw a
comparison to wine which is often not
necessarily accurate but if you think of
how California looked at wine production
in sales 30 40 50 years ago
they wanted to grow a lot and they
wanted to sell it for cheap and they
wanted to provide you know as much as it
could to as many people as possible and
the idea of boutique wine and and wine
that had been aged and wine late harvest
wine and dessert wine and all these
things that we now realize that there's
a there's a consumer that will
appreciate every possible right you know
there's the hundred dollar bottles of
wine there's thousand dollars of bottles
of wine there's $5 $2 bottles of wine
and with cannabis we're right in the
middle of that commodity specialty
market where it's all the specialty
products are all bound to the commodity
market so they can't really break
through that ceiling and say you know
what this is a really low yielding late
flowering variety but it is so amazing
you're gonna have to pay the farmer the
equivalent of what they'd make on a low
yield a high yielding early flowering
variety but I do believe that'll happen
once people get to experience them and
appreciate the difference what well I
think another bottleneck is on the
farmer's side when you're thinking about
you know producing for the regulated
market you know if batch size testing is
50 pounds and you're producing less than
that but you're still incurring the same
cost and then you have to you know all
the costs associated with being
regulated those people are probably just
staying out of the market right now it's
yeah they have great stuff that I would
love to smoke but it's not gonna be on
the regulated market anytime soon right
because you as a consumer haven't
convinced the commercial producer that
you're gonna pay more for it yet so it
definitely regulation has driven these
eight nine-week varieties to to capture
the entire market you know where we used
to have you know people used to grow
outdoors and
grow big giant super Silver Haze plants
that took forever to grow but they
figured out a way to make it profitable
and they were able to supply but now
it's a production era you know that
we're trying to ramp up production and
figure out how to turn this into
agriculture instead of horticulture and
the first thing that you look at are
things like yield and flower time and
stuff like that but but once I mean in
just a backtrack to the Netherlands what
one thing that I thought was just really
interesting and made it work there's
that they had almost every coffee shop
had a menu with two sections they had
high or four sections actual hydro bio
indica sativa and and you're they paid
more of a coffee shop would pay a
cultivator more for an organic sativa
because they knew they said look we need
to have this product on the shelf
because people want it and the only way
you use a cultivator can justify growing
it is if we pay you more and this was
stuff that was growing greenhouses or
what was a greenhouse was an indoor but
it was just basically acknowledging that
haze for instance was just not something
you could grow in these big chunky sea
of green production models and that it
was probably the most desirable cult of
Harr in the entire city so how are they
going to pull it off the menu when it's
what everyone wants well the only way to
keep it on the menu is to pay the the
farmer more still on the menu and it's
still there
and it still costs more yeah and you can
buy a is easier and I'm strong and you
can buy it here yeah so that's just a
more mature market as well obviously
well I feel like Amsterdam also has
taken what I would consider some wrong
turns recently so can you talk about
kind of the Amsterdam which was the
mecca of cannabis consumption and and
the scene how it kind of bungled like
what have you seen in Amsterdam I mean
what was the last time you were there I
was there in 2018 in the summer and that
was the first time I've been back in 13
years and I was surprised to see that
little had changed that they didn't
embrace they've all
and the Dutch were really good with
looking at things from a social policy
angle and so they didn't really look at
cannabis from a supply chain production
side and so they never really created a
robust system that could grow so I go
back to Amsterdam 13 years later and if
you buy up gram of cannabis and they
pull out a Tupperware and they shake it
all up and look at it and then pull it
out and squeeze it and cram it into a
little ziploc bag and take a sharpie and
write haze on it you know and I'm just
like wow like we're in California we've
got all this manufacturing and
production and all these different vape
pens and pre-rolls and and they just
suck now we're just keeping it the same
way they're not trying to make it happen
and now they're looking at actually
creating an actual system that might
accommodate more of an agricultural
model and I can only imagine the coffee
shops and the patrons are nervous how
about on the cultivation side because
the Dutch are known for their ability to
grow massive amounts of fruit vegetables
and agriculture in general where are
they on cannabis cultivation using their
domain expertise of agricultural
production I don't think they've really
looked at that you have to remember that
all this was done by turning a blind eye
it was legal to sell cannabis in a
coffee shop it was not legal for that
coffee shop to buy cannabis and they
cannot claim it on their taxes so it's
never been part of the business
structure now they're talking about it
now they're talking about how limiting
cultivation to only a few growers to
supply the coffee shops whether this
will happen or not I don't know but
that's presently what they're talking
about
that won't be good for consumers they're
suddenly won't be anybody who's going to
be growing a haze because that I really
won't care and then you're gonna have a
situation that will be the final blow to
the diversity they used to experience in
coffee shops they're right I mean when I
first went there they were imported it
was imported cannabis and what was it
mostly coming from the US mostly
freaka Africa okay and since um from the
Caribbean and South America and all the
normal supplies of stuff we had but
closer to that from Africa was a kind of
land race oh all of it and so what
countries was it malawi South Africa all
the subdivisions of southern Africa
essentially it was yeah it was mostly it
and then what are kind of today some of
the most intriguing kind of cultivation
regions in your opinion like what are
you keeping tonight like Colombia
different parts of Africa well any of
those places if somebody's far enough
from present-day reality that they
somehow missed out on growing spook then
yeah great but it's gone going landrace
collecting those why bother I mean if
you really know somebody is way off in
the top of the reef mountains somewhere
and it's possible I suppose but when you
get on Instagram sites today and you see
Afghan guys in Afghanistan growing
California varieties you're like it's
done you know it's done findell ato
the last place landraces really came
from was Afghanistan I mean no late
seventies they were the last ones to
kind of come on the block other ones
have come along since but nothing that
wasn't there already it's been reef you
know refueled a bit over time in the 80s
but since then good luck so basically on
the mountainsides of a lot of these or
in the valleys or whatever you're seeing
kind of blue dream and purple punch and
I was in Morocco last year and it's a
it's incredible really
I mean I was there in late 70s no early
eighties and and it was still mostly the
traditional narrow leaf tall keith
plants which they made you know zoom
Toshi's from but
not now you don't see those at all and
it basically looks like indoor or
greenhouse grow except the building's
gone I mean they're all it looks like
fields of cuttings there you generally
not they're generally all female seed
varieties but they're quite you know
inbred to make that happen a bit and
they're very uniform you can see
differences in blocks of so many seed
versus somebody else's but the next year
people won't be buying so much female
seed and there's still plenty of males
around so it's all full of seed which
makes the buds even look fatter and more
amazing than they actually are cuz
they're chock full of seeds but but
they're yes just bizarre there's a drip
tubing everywhere and always identical
or compliance and nothing's more than
four or five three or four feet tall
most of them you know six feet it'd be a
big plant you can see over the top we've
always filled yes so historically in the
seven all is when you go to those fields
there'd be to look our camp fields right
today really close together and just a
lollipop as we call it on top of a stick
that was it just one big bud one coulomb
no branches maybe well like turkey today
went our Hempfield said about 30 plants
to a square metre square yard
approximately 35 maybe so yeah it's not
not pretty much room in there you can
squeeze in between I hope you want to
walk through it but yeah so can can you
talk about you know on Instagram people
always talk about pollen shuckers versus
breeders and so can you you just kind of
talk about your approach to breeding
yeah well what makes a breeder of
breeder in your opinion where you where
you personally would call someone a
breeder like what are what's either like
an academic rigorous I mean no I don't
think so I don't think that's fair I
think it's the intent
you know more I mean for instance I
talked to a friend of mine recently who
who was the guy who popped the original
Sour Diesel seed you know and I was
gonna write something up for him for a
magazine and I said look I want to write
something up for you you're the breeder
of sardines he's like whoa whoa I didn't
make the cross I'm just the guy who put
the seed in the ground I rely to say who
that is no necessarily we can get into
that another time but but he put the
seed in the ground and there's there's
there's you know consensus amongst all
the people who were involved in that
plant that he is the guy who put the
seed in the ground and where was this in
upstate New York okay and but he wasn't
the breeder so he didn't really breed
that variety but he did make it he was
the steward he was the custodian he's
the one who made it happen he deserves
all the credit and get me wrong but I
guess what a breeder is to someone who
has some intent to actually create
something like I'm gonna do this in
order to make that and I'm gonna
thoughtfully take something from here
and something from here and this is what
the outcome I'm either trying to achieve
or maybe I'm trying to achieve some
unknown outcome it's different than just
letting the pollen fly at will and then
just selling seeds it's a little
different you know yeah but but at the
same time that being said as far as I
know all of the modern varieties the
amazing modern cannabis varieties that
we've smoked over the past decades all
came from someone who just had a few
seeds that fell out of the bud that they
had in a bag all of them there hasn't
been an amazing cannabis plant that was
developed by a true breeding program by
a PhD cannabis breeder right so there
are but they're not in our drug cannabis
world right no twenty of plenty of plant
breeders who could have been working
with weed or cotton or anything that
worked with cannabis but they're
basically hemp breeders you know but and
people have done some medicinal breeding
generally it's seeds that fell out of a
back
whether the bag came from a brick from
Columbia pencil and race or whether it
is a bag seed from something wasn't
supposed to have seeds in it which is
most common right and they made
additional crosses with that I'm not
saying that they just pulled it out of
the seed out of the bag but it wasn't
under a big breeding program that was so
so the smallest the the smallest little
operation some guy who has four lights
or a little backyard grow those are the
guys who produced all the most amazing
genetics that we consume for you know
recreational or medicinal purposes like
if you think of any variety I mean
they're all just came from small growths
that's why we're at this precipice now
where we have all this all these
varieties that have been developed some
of a really amazing and valuable and now
we can actually improve upon them with a
little bit more of an advanced and you
know larger approach to greeting so
that's that's the future but right now
it's still where we are right so so we
touched on it for a little earlier but
can you talk about your intent and what
you're trying to create my intent was to
stay with one line has always been to
that there was just like I mentioned
earlier that there was this kind of this
white whale that I was chasing something
that you remember from your youth yeah
absolutely 100% and I remember I
remember it and then I remember losing
it and then finding it again and once I
found it again I decided like well I'm
just gonna breed this I'll try and
improve it but I'm not going to try and
create a bunch of different varieties
with with a with a bunch of diversity of
flavors and and different fee knows that
people can kind of just you know what's
the fee know what's the strangers you're
coming from this breeder I really wanted
to stick to the Sage line so that
everything that came out of it really
felt like sage and whether they were
slightly higher more seen varieties that
could be maybe slightly it's a data
version of sage or higher to appealing
varieties that were more energetic and
focusing that it would just be along
that line and for about 20-some 24 or 25
years I've pretty much done that
where I haven't really introduced much
so every time I would introduce a new
cross I would work through that over a
number of years before I introduced
another cross just to give an example of
something that you introduced and what
you are looking to accomplish yeah
well the most I guess the most distinct
difference was when I came back from am
from Amsterdam to California and tooth
in 1999 and I was good friends with Josh
D and that whole crew and they
introduced me to OG and I saw some
things in that plant that were really
valuable in terms of breeding such as
what
well marketability honestly yeah that
was a big part of it I mean it's it's a
powerful plant it turns up the octane on
a lot of other when you cross OG with
things it definitely turns up the volume
a little bit and into 11 it goes to 11
mate yeah but um and I always felt sage
was just fine and plenty it was enough
for me but when people were smoking a
lot and getting into dabbing and stuff
like that doing concentrates people
really want a strong variety of cannabis
so I crossed oh gee with sage and then
had a sage OG male that I crossed back
to sage and that produced a variety
called zeta which to me had the majority
of the sage based effect in attributes
but it had a little bit of the bag
appeal and slightly earlier flowering
period of OG and that helped a lot you
know it definitely made a more
marketable
variety you know but um but I still
missed the old sage at that point that
was also when I didn't save enough of
the old seed and con went down this line
diverged along this path and didn't
maintain what I really was into which
was which was kind of the lighter I
almost view it as like the light version
right you have like the one that packs
the punch which is the one that's
crossed with og and then the original
which is yeah like a wine versus a yeah
killer shot absolutely and and just more
focused and energetic and a little bit
um you know kind of weed you can smoke
all day and it's still strong enough
that if you smoke enough of it you get
you know and have you gotten back there
or are you still trying to get the less
I did I did get back there a little bit
through selfing and going into that
actually I brought back some more a sage
Paul a sage mail that I crossed against
that sage OG cut and diluted it just
enough to parse out a little more of
that those og characteristics but still
have some of those bag appeal and then
is the ultimate goal to once you where
are you in terms of creating the sage of
your dreams are you there I mean
obviously you can always keep on
iteratively bringing it in directions
but you have something right now that is
like this is a masterpiece for my
personal taste yeah kind of I mean close
so definitely you could I mean you could
always improve things I guess but at
some point you have to settle you know
but yeah I have a variety that I call
holy which is kind of at one point the
there was Big Sur genetically Holies in
the sage family right like is is your
whole mo like everything's gonna be some
sage yes yeah this and I'll explain that
because there's a lot of confusion
around that but in the seed stock that I
used to make sage was from partially
from Big Sur and in Big Sur there was a
variety that was known called Big Sur
Holy Week from the late 60s and early
70s and Big Sur holy weed was
predominantly Mexican and there was
pretty at one point everything grown in
Big Sur was called Big Sur holy weed
because it was the way to you know add
an extra couple hundred bucks on a pound
I guess but so but the variety that I
use to cross into sage was actually a
African variety but it was grown in bigs
and in the 90s when I was in Amsterdam
and just quickly by African since it's
obviously a big continent is this like a
southern Appalachian City and and are
those on the same parallel as where you
were in Big Sur like the the southern
equatorial equivalent of your no no I
think it would it would be know a little
bit I'm not sure so microclimate it
wasn't kind of mimicking the northern
kind of reflection of I don't think so
okay I don't think so I don't know how
important that was I mean yeah it's a
good question though
but um but anyway there was African
genetics in that original sage and I was
born in Big Sur and at one point seeds
were sold as sage times Big Sur holy
wheat so there there was this kind of
misconception that there was original
Big Sur holy wheat genetics in sage and
while exploring different crosses sage
crosses I did find something that did
really remind me of some of that early
Big Sur holy weed a fact that high
terpene alene kind of Acapulco gold like
a fact and I called it Big Sur holy or
holy and just because it reminded me of
the homeland it had that knows and that
that feeling of of way back and that to
me is just what I enjoy smoking and
everyone who tries it seems to think
it's just a really nice really nice
plant to grow
would you agree with that but you could
make it you can improve on it I mean
it's a late flowering variety and if you
could get that same effect in a nine or
a ten week flowering plant then you'd
have something really special so that's
an example of something that you're now
focused on is how do i shorten the
flowering time of this yeah as much as
possible without compromising the and
what would be some strategies to get
like would you cross it was specific
like you have your eye on specific
cultivars to cross it with no probably
my next move if I was trying to improve
that line would just be a larger
selection
to try and put out enough seeds that you
could get hopefully something that was
earlier flowering okay so as a breeder
what's kind of you've created cultivars
that you love you think other people
will love what's what's your next move
is it to sell seeds is it to sell clones
is it to flower it out yourself and
create a brand it's to all the above
into some extent not really in the seed
selling business never really have never
bought seeds actually just recently
bought my first hundred dollars worth of
seeds from some land race provider but
no the next goal is to get these plants
what I think have value in commercial
growers hands and to try and figure out
a marketing strategy to teach people how
to appreciate these varieties and to
teach you know retail outlets how to
sell them and teach consumers how to
request them and you know I think it's a
big topic that where the whole industry
is kind of experiencing and we kind of
used the word landrace to kind of
describe it but there's there's this
interest in these heritage lines that
have either just a point of difference
which is really important well you're
trying to establish a brand or they have
really do have a different effect that
people can notice you know and I think
that that's an important part of this
stage of our industry is consumer
awareness and like once people get to
experience it and really not just smoke
it once at a party but actually have a
retail that provides them on an ongoing
basis then they will come back and say
no I demand it you know and I'm willing
to pay more and tell the farmer to grow
more and you know it almost needs a push
and pull strategy right like that yeah
the pull coming from consumers coming in
and asking for what do you have that's
unique and not the hype strains and
maybe land race and then the push of you
know farmers willing to grow it on us
you know and then get it through the
distribution system and yeah well back
to the wine thing you know Northern
California grew a lot of hi Northern
California in Central Valley grew a lot
of high yielding wine grape varieties
there were high sugar high yielding
varieties and they were well established
you know Mendocino County and Sonoma
they grew a lot of Zinfandel for
instance and some of those vines were
really old and produced a lot and
established and Hardy and they remember
the White Zinfandel thing in the 70s
these two press red grapes to issues
yeah and they would no contact with the
skin so they'd make this white wine from
a red grape it's very popular in the
early 80s I'll have a white zinfandel
and but it was crap wine it was really
bad and right at that same time people
were learning about you know Burgundian
style Pinot Noir
you know growing Pinot Noir grapes but
then producing them in this in the style
similar to how they do in Burgundy in
France and as soon as people got a taste
for that they're like are you kidding me
this is good stuff my drink in this box
wine right and then but what do they
have to do they have to cut down acres
and acres of Zinfandel producing and
then plant a little thing that doesn't
even yield any fruit for years in order
to wait for the market to mature and
wait for the consumer to ask for that
bottle take a bunch of steps back to
take a bunch of steps forward
well agriculture requires foresight I
really believe that you know that you
have to say and it's not the consumers
fault or the farmers fire fault it's
that we have to have this feedback loop
this push and give and take that creates
those demands and you know that's part
of our job as cannabis historians and
aficionados is to say hey there's
varieties out there that we think are
really interesting and you might all
appreciate I actually have a question
for you guys as breeders and like moving
from the from the point of that most of
the breeders or the the strains that
we've been smoking in love
from small producers growing those four
six or ten plants how do you maintain
the integrity of your genetics when you
scale up and what's the most important
thing about that process is it
consistency is it like wine that each
year might be different do you want to
maintain control of the cultivation
process do you let the genetics out of
your hand and trust other cultivators to
take care of what you've created how do
you think about that that's a lot yeah
well well I mean I asked because because
like I've been asking for years how like
the the crafter boutique cannabis you
know industry like I've been asking this
question for years and the answer I get
back from industry marketing people is
in all industries you have to create
your mass market first and then out of
that comes a craft industry which means
that the craft and boutique as we know
it now has to go away and and that is a
tragedy of unknown proportions to
someone like me who goes way back and
never stopped consuming cannabis I never
stop so I have the long memory as well
of those of those old of the of the old
strains and the old genetics and I miss
a lot of that stuff too and I'm like
well how are we gonna get ha how are we
gonna get from here to there if we have
have to wipeout does that have to happen
I mean I'm not I'm not saying you guys
have but that's why I ask these
questions because it is really important
to a lot of people that we continue to
have those types of experiences and not
you know wind up with cannabis that is
all the same so you know and but you
know when you talk to big market or is
there like nope that's not how it works
in today's world right there right it's
not how it works but we have a little
bit different circumstance part of your
question was
how do you keep the quality up well like
wine grapes or hop comes for that matter
these are perennials you know they're
they're vegetatively reproduce they're
identical to each other unless something
should happen to them pick up a virus or
something so that's three equality comes
from your beer consistency will come
from from variety now they're exactly
right that the industry is gonna be you
know five varieties or something or five
different types let's say then there's a
few varieties of each that are
economically feasible to grow but the
other ones they're not going to
disappear they're still in people's
backyards and garages and they'll still
be around and people still know about
them because people will still share
with their friends so they'll be there
and slowly I don't think the craft side
will go away
it's gonna be tough and it's gonna have
to live and another guys the softer part
of the regulatory market somehow none of
these little people are gonna get big
fat licenses to grow six plants to keep
something alive they'd only grow six
plants anyway you know so what's this
what's the deal so I think we have a
little a little better chance of
preserving things I give you a little
example of grapes too I worked in
Hungary for years the Soviet system
basically did their very best to rip out
every traditional Hungarian Friday and
they did very well they grew these white
sour green sort of grapes that they
wanted for the export market to Russia
that's all he cared about but as soon as
the shackles were taken off it bounced
back immediately because they went
around and they went to everybody's
backyards where they did not get every
vine because they only ripped out the
commercial ones and they brought back
their wine industry in just a few years
really fast so and we're in cannabis
were in dog years so hopefully we are we
are experiencing this like as we could
become a more agricultural model we are
seeing the craft being challenged
although we never really had a craft
cannabis market the way craft alcohol
works but that's for a number of reasons
but hopefully we'll push through this
period really quickly we're actually
working with the group now called
breeders best which is that's a big
focus on that company is that there's
this opportunity there's a there's an
opportunity in that transition that to
kind of save varieties and to help
commercial groups see the value in
varieties whether it's their unique
terpene or cannabinoid profiles or
agronomic traits that make them
desirable is appellation a part of the
scheme
well appellation is is it's a word that
it means a lot in you know appellation
has a lot to do with mandating certain
cultivation practices and certain
varieties and stuff like that yeah yeah
it's a lot well well I think that we
won't have the ability to utilize
Appalachian and terroir the way the wine
industry is until we settle on things
like varieties and figure out where the
market is for a while so caffeinated
soil you're using yeah it's about a
point of difference is saying one
appellation versus another one terroir
versus another is about showing that I'm
I grow in you grow in in Napa you grow
Pinot Noir but just because I grow it in
Sonoma I'm in a more coastal appellation
which has different influences on the
grape therefore it's a more acidic and
it's a lighter blah blah blah so you can
use that as a marketing strategy but you
have to both grow Pinot Noir to be able
to do that you can't just all just say
hey I grow whatever I want and then I
throw it in an appellation and that has
some type of a marketing strategy to it
it doesn't really work that way you
think French wine and how you're really
bound by structuring varieties with an
appellation in order making a marketable
product you can't just wiggle around
that oh that's great we got to tie down
the varietal end of the appellation it's
right to wild on the icy mix you can't
grow Sangiovese in bordeaux and call it
a bordeaux period you can call it French
wine so there's all different ways
a police right gets shot for that I mean
as you well know you know the the
difference in elevation in a distance to
the coast all those factors are real and
really do make a difference
sure so it seems like the potential
really is there if there's a little more
discipline there's yeah and there has to
be a structure so you have to be able to
point out those differences and if it's
just a different variety grown every
year for instance no one can compare how
it's grown if nobody realizes like hey
you know what I've been smoking this
this wedding cake in Carpinteria versus
this wedding cake in Solvang and they're
so totally different they have to be
there so we have to settle on what
varieties are grown and how we're
marketing those varieties in order for
people to learn about Appalachian and
terroir and then eventually it may be
that wedding cake doesn't grow near the
ocean very well so it's gonna be grown
in solving because it's outside of the
fog belt and that's others are agronomic
considerations that will come to bear as
well and people didn't go to hump
originally in the 70s people did not go
to Humboldt County to grow cannabis they
were back-to-the-landers they found
cheap disused and abused largely land
and they you know brought it back and
made really lovely homesteads and
financed this whole process by growing
weed all right and when Mojave says
there never really was a boutique
industry there wasn't it was an illegal
industry and everybody was a boutique
grower there were smaller ones the
larger ones but now you've got guys with
ranges of greenhouses they're acres and
illegal and and you're not gonna compete
with that you're gonna be part of the
system that we're where you can fit in
but the pricing and everything you kept
these people going was strictly the
prohibition base that there's no real
economic you know reality in it so
everybody's having to restart as far as
that goes so when you guys breed now do
you breed for
do you create with do you go I'm gonna
make something that I like that I want
or just or their market considerations
in mind as well
where's both I mean you know it's I
forget what the the there's it's false
to make the assumption that just because
you like it other people like it as well
and a lot of people make that that that
um that mistake but I do think that you
know you have to start with whether you
like it and then you try it out and if
other people like it too then you're
onto something and you know it used to
be that all good cannabis was good
cannabis and everyone liked everything
to a certain degree and now it's really
about finding your consumer base what
demographic likes what and if you can
kind of pair those two things together
then there's a there's potential for
just a lot of different varieties in a
lot of different applications but it
really if you miss that and you develop
something that you really like for
reason X but you don't convey that to
the consumer then they're gonna miss it
so no let's talk about that for a minute
because you guys have been around you
going to a million shows you know you
see how the market is developing you
know things are fractured you you've
probably had retail experiences where
you've gone in and you've seen how
that's going how do you create your
audience now and find that consumer like
how do you how do what what are the
technical how do you do that now um I'm
not really sure to tell the truth it
hasn't been a focus of mine recently
we've been more working with other
groups and trying to figure out how to
you know push their agendas forward but
I think ultimately you know nowadays
it's all done through Instagram and
social media reading the hypes creating
the hype strains exactly but but I think
that the real way to do it and hopefully
the better way to do it is to create the
god what's that horrible marketing
strategy is you career
the void and then you fill the void
right you know create the problem you
create the problems of the solution
exactly and people today I think are
doing that organically there's this
coronaviruses gonna kill you all and I
saw I have this thing mass yeah right
exactly people have been people like
these effects associated with what they
call a sativa you know and right now
cultivators are all looking for our
sativa leaning hybrids and sativas are
often the first thing that sell that
that are sold out on the Shelf you know
so have have they displaced indicas no
not at all no no not at all but about it
but the market wants it is what I'm
saying the market is creating this void
by saying how come like every now and
then get to experience these plants that
I love but for the most part they're not
as readily available as these hybrids so
I do think that that's happening
organically it just get you it's just a
matter of getting to the point where
everyone connects and they understand
what they're looking for because
cannabis can be so many different things
for so many different people and you
know CBD has shown that some people
don't even want to get high but they
want cannabis and they want it to taste
good still so there's smokeable CBD you
know and we you have to if you don't if
you don't create a strategy that aligns
specific compounds with the consumer
then you not only do you miss the
opportunity for them to enjoy that
experience but you lose them as a
consumer as well so it's really
challenging I think for dispensaries to
train staff and to have the type of
products that their customers want when
they walk in and they say I want to
indica leaning hybrid with the high mere
seen low pining but you know they're not
quite there still we talk to dispensary
owners California included but
especially in other states peep ninety
percent of customers eighty percent of
customers vast majority it's put it that
way they buy by the numbers I want a
twenty five I don't want a twenty one or
twenty five now they don't realize
selling the 20% THC might make them way
way higher than someone's 25 or 30
percent THC not always you know but I
mean drunks pick wine by the alcohol
content okay
connoisseurs don't I mean people would
just drink table wine with their food
don't buy it by the alcohol content so
III pulled these out because this is a
friend who grows up in humbled and for
the market he grows things like Mac and
ice-cream cake he doesn't smoke this he
you know he's like I'm just one example
but like lambsbread is something that he
really loves and you know but it's not
what the market wants and he's like but
every time I smoke my friends out his
inner circle they're like I love that
but he doesn't have the confidence to
grow it at scale to see if the market
will accept it and so he's still growing
kind of the high-end and it probably
yields half or two-thirds what these do
and takes three or four weeks longer and
I think the market I don't think it's as
much as figuring out whether the market
wants it is convincing the cultivator to
grow it first is the the Vegas lead
right so you got it he's got to make
that decision am I gonna grow this thing
cuz even though it yields low and
getting it on the Shelf I mean we're in
this Renaissance of cannabis aromas and
like we can loud terpene profiles where
the it's like leaping out of the jar
into your nose and selling itself before
you even consume it and some of those
terpene profiles may be indicative of
the great effect associated with that
variety but some of them might just be
loud smelly things and we're really
trained now to follow our nose and like
oh this big Baba blah thing and some of
those varieties like lambs bread they're
not they're not dessert item Turk
flavors the earth they're earthy and
they're spicy in their herbal you know
and they're woodsy you know the original
Thai stick is exactly that example it
was nothing to look at
nothing really no real great odor to it
but it killed I mean it was exceptional
I mean the real one going way back which
I
for decades and it was exactly that if
you went by today's aesthetics you'd
never pick it up the only would touch it
right it's just maybe why pre-rolls will
be there saving grace for everybody you
know just shut up and put it in your
mouth take a hit don't look at it
I'm looking fixie yeah what's it so we
just talked terpenes they're kind of for
terpenes that dominate moderate at least
in California I mean it's what Mira seen
pining
Terrapin alene and well it's it's mercy
and limonene and carry off leaner almost
all cannabis out there it's the most
those three Terps kind of compete for
dominance and all the og based stuff and
the sours and the Kim's and the wedding
cakes and the gelatos and the cookies
and stuff pretty sure those are the
three dominance so so getting back to
breeding what-what are you interested in
seeing people breed
what other terpenes are you interested
in exploring or seeing other people
explore well I've always been super
interested in terbutaline always that's
definitely been what I've been chasing
is Hydra peeling variety and why because
they seem to have the effect that I like
there are these more energetic clear
focused type varieties but what I'm
really interested in is cannabis
varieties that have their own signature
terpene profile instead of this tropical
punch which is amazing like you get a
tropical punch you drink it and you're
like oh my god it's guava it's pineapple
its banana it's everything but you lose
the ability to pull them out and say
like well I just want to taste a guava
drink right now and and and having these
Turk profiles that are a little bit they
can still be really chirpy and dominant
I mean high Terp levels but having it
not be so many competing peaks that are
so like there's a variety that a friends
given us recently and we had it tested
and it had the the least amount of
detectable terpenes out of the twenty or
so that they were looking for it only
hit on twelve and most of the other more
hybrid II varieties had 16 17 18 19
detectable terpenes because they're all
hybrids of things that have all these
different herb profiles so these this
other variety was just a real high spike
here and a real high spike here and
nothing nothing nothing nothing and then
a high spike here and a high spike there
and that really show helps it to show
what its attributes are individual
character had they had it for a long
time or had they created it they had it
for a
long time man they created it but they
didn't dilute it by crossing it with
everything and once you dilute things
it's you know it's hard to it's hard to
pull the Chihuahua out of a wolf you
know what I mean but we went from a wolf
to a chihuahua with with all the
selective breeding and we've got all
this diversity of all these different
dogs but if you lost the wolf then it's
gonna be really hard to get to the
Chihuahua and right now we've got away
I've left her lapdogs oh my god I left
his lapdog mutts
yeah and we have so much hybridization
in our in our industry now because we've
had these elite cult these elite clones
that really just took off that we're
inbred and everything shares that's why
everything has a similar effect to it
where it leans a little bit this way or
leans a little bit that way as opposed
to distinctly different tastes and
distinctly different effects and
morphology I mean you used to be able to
look at different plant varieties and
they all looked very different some of
them were super tall and thin and
branchy and some of them were super
squat and tight and now you look at most
modern hybrid II plants kind of look the
same what what's the one of the craziest
plants you've ever looked at in person
what is described it you have seen some
really wild ones for sure um back in the
day I used to like some of the ones from
Colombia that we call creepers they're
really and I just grow from seed so you
basically just said one tall plant I
didn't like top and things too much and
a lot of my friends didn't either unless
you're trying to hide them because you
wanted to see the natural structure
element and plants that look like
Christmas trees are just pretty somehow
very graceful these plants that grow up
810 feet and they all the branches would
hang down branches or up three feet we'd
hang all the way to the ground and if
you tried to grow this indoors and it'd
be a nightmare
but when I could just stand outside on
its own it was really cool and it
happened to be super nice sweet to also
hide terpene Alain type varieties gone
now but fantastic stuff and I'm really
interested in one of the things that's
ruined our industry is is the concept of
bag look bag appeal yeah bag appeal
be a little nugget a nug that goes in a
bag another painting with white yeah
yeah I'm fine with all the resin Glantz
but I wish they weren't squeezed on top
you know in Brax that are stacked on top
of each other so tight they're miserable
to make a she shadow that's the problem
with them I don't okay granted hashish
varieties Afghanistan they were hashish
varieties and the things like making
eyes I think making hash is great I
think you think consuming hash is great
it didn't have to bring that one today
but all that sheesh
oh it wasn't there this morning Jim took
that one on till yeah cuz he bagged oh
yeah okay okay just a syllable but yeah
I was looking for it that's why I didn't
find it and I just realized why right
now but it's okay um yeah I say cache
she's just great I like the cultures
that were around it when I moved out um
stirred um started hanging out with
Europeans we knew what cannabis was but
it was basically a raw material for
making ya know and I like the things
from all these different countries and
that's why I wrote about it well people
still well the sculpture still went on I
probably would have thought it would go
on the way it was forever since it kind
of gone on forever but that's all
changed
well so what do you think in the modern
twist on the rosin Prince thing rosin so
he moved from a dry sift to bubble hash
to rosin pressing and that's kind of
what all the kids are doing yeah I think
it's great I mean the step she left out
there were all them nasty solvents
people were yeah in the solvent solvent
world I get it but when I saw it happen
it's all unless yeah good but yeah it's
it's that has been the trend and I think
it's great they're all solvent loose and
I think this is the best yet and you can
also take your water hash or your dry
sip and it crawls and out of it so it
all fits together very well
that hashish is also really cool yeah I
have to say I really feel like there's
no there should we should be seeing more
hashish on the market and it's great
there we have these high concentration
extracts but hashish in its traditional
form was really cool because you could
was really easy to transport you could
put it in your pocket you could put it
in a little container you could take it
out with your finger you could break off
a piece you could put it in a joint you
could put it in the bowl stick it in a
glass you don't even you know any
paraphernalia all the modern you know
the the BHO and the rosin 's and the wax
and stuff they take a lot of gear they
take a lot of knowledge you have to
understand how to use it
I think it's intimidating to some people
the way hash is just a really simple
product and also there might even be
something to be said for having a
certain amount of plant matter left in
the concentrate that it rounds off the
the whole plant extract profile can have
a profile thing and you know I grow
pretty much the same ver I smoke pretty
much the same thing every day for like a
long time you're very consistent I'm
very consistent yeah I'm a routine guy
exactly I have my tea in the morning
I don't drink Budweiser but if I did it
would be the only thing my dad drank
Budweiser exactly but um I smoked the
same thing and I have just quickly do
you do you do you kind of have one thing
you like to smoke or do you like to to
dab are you a tapas kind of guy I'm yeah
I like all of it especially when I'm in
California cuz there's such a Laurie
yeah for sure but I always like coming
home from travels but I was gonna say is
um so ice because I smoked one thing I
have every extracted version of that so
I have sage and I have sage BHO and I
have sage rosin and I've sage water hash
and I have sage rice if all from the
exact same point does sage does it yield
your definition of
a good good hash producing cultivar is
it good hash producing cultivar it's
it's medium I mean it actually produces
really good sage some of the hybrids
produce better better at hashish it's
about how well that gland snaps off at
that abscission layer and makes it
through that little pore and something
for some reason some of these phases and
sages they I think they smear the glands
just don't make it through as well and
you end up with a bunch of leaf material
that has all your burst glands all over
it and they just don't quite but under
the right conditions it does make good
hash but I was going to say is that at
every different type of extraction
creates a very different effect so from
the from the BHO to the dry SEF their
third on opposite ends of the spectrum
and the dry sift is the closest to
flower so if I want the effect to be
closer to flower but just kind of the
volume turned up the dry SIF kind of
does that but then by the time you've
got to rosin or even BHO you've kind of
drifted away from it so there's
definitely something to be said for
these whole plan with the BHO kind of be
like louder like it's more like almost
like young and loud it's louder in that
it's tur pure but it's also a different
terpene profile because there's been so
much degradation and decomposition and
all these things have happened to it and
you're missing the plant matter that you
know it's just it's just very different
well it's a you you like having the
plant matter and I feel like a lot of
the the younger guys who make rosin
they're they're so focused on getting
every bit of plant matter out of it and
they don't want any of it right well cuz
there's also a purity it's also how they
market their product is that I've been
able to refine this and make it pure
it's kind it's very much similar to
alcohol distillation it's like I'm not
saying there's anything wrong with
whiskey or scotch or vodka I like a a
good drink every now and then as well
but I tend to drink beer and wine
because it's closer to the plant version
of the thing that's making that alcohol
and with cannabis you know I do think
that you know you can have a extract
that
has the profile that you want but if you
had it in Flour and maintaining it from
flower to final extract is really
difficult especially monoterpene so just
cool just why you process the more you
lose yeah you're also getting rid of
extraneous plant matter or whatever you
don't want but you're also getting rid
of some good stuff along the way so
there's a point of diminishing returns
that's amazing that people do it I guess
is part of the fascination runes that
we've been able to refine it to that
point I mean honey oil really had like a
real small blip when it was available
back in the day and it was amazing that
you could oh my god you could take this
not so you know flavorful variety and
just turn it into this big you know
aroma and I think the fascination is
there and and that's similar to alcohol
it's it's really cool that you can do it
I'm not saying there's anything wrong
with it but to me I feel like it loses
some of the nuances of what the
varieties are growing you know and once
you start dabbing with the other thing
about increasing your intake you know
once you go once you go loud you can't
go back it's really hard there's this
thing in the in the the beer industry
called the loop Yulin threshold shift
when you start drinking hoppy or beers
you can't go back because your brain
resets every time it goes up and says I
need more anymore I think anymore I've
been moved migrating in the hoppy
direction reason like in the past six
months and I'd always kind of been like
the chase for like the IPA that's more
hoppy than the other guys IPA I was
always like I just want like a Pilsner
or lager or whatever and but now I'm
it's hard I'm noticing myself buying
more hoppy beers and the markets changed
too they've in a year they've gone to
having the happiest and highest alcohol
content beers they could possibly come
up with to the point where if you just
were doing a market survey you would
assume that it was impossible to have
super hop forward beer that wasn't at
least six and a half percent alcohol now
it's changed again now you're going in
the market and there's a whole bunch of
beers that are actually some of them
under five percent
a little bit under the European norm and
and our hop forward they're not super
hoppy but that was kind of being
overdone a bit too so now you're getting
the beers that are really a nice balance
and you can drink a few and not do
damage to yourself room for another beer
aren't people also adding terpenes now
to their beer creating new products yeah
I'm not a big fan of like the mango
yeah some of these are spiked and but
the real craft brewers are not I mean it
once again it's if somebody who is a
craft brewer now is selling way too much
beer to be called a craft brewer or
maybe that's not really the right term
maybe independent brewer is a little
better but yeah the once they're no
longer independent brewers the larger
market forces take over and things tend
they make their production easier and
more consistent they didn't want their
beer tasting different each time a real
craft brewer kind of doesn't care I mean
ok this was a little happier to last
them so what maybe the next thing
doesn't have any opportunity but they're
not bottling it they're not you know
selling hundreds of thousands of units
they're they're taking it down to the
local rotary tap place and getting their
mates to drink a couple of kegs so they
can go home make some different you know
and that that's real craft thing but
like these market guys are saying ok we
add prohibition and then we had alcohol
everybody knew everybody knew somebody
who's a moonshiner I think my
grandfather knew people Ramone shiners
he used to take around samples is who's
Salesman for the southern cottonseed oil
company which became hunt Wesen Foods
but he used to go around with his little
oil samples and test tubes of course it
was whiskey that's how he got his
customers you know and everybody knew
somebody who could who made moonshine or
grew heed its yeah we've gone they got
put out of business now they're back now
he can actually afford to get a small
distilling license there was a time
there when a small distiller that the
economic thresholds were - I eat
didn't have enough you couldn't sell
enough favorite license what other in
this where we out like that that's right
where we're at now
you can't sell enough and enough for
profit to pay the overhead of operating
and Eagle II exactly full circle that's
right without interstate commerce and
the distillers and the Brewers kept
people out of this business they kept it
for themselves as long as they could and
I'm it now has changed and I got lots a
little we have three thousand craft
brewers in California that's what a
couple years ago right for now and
Judith can you kind of talk about some
of the most intrat
when you were running the hash book kind
of like some of the your interesting
thoughts and insights on kind of hash
yeah define hash how do you define hash
yeah I would say that hashish is a
mechanical concentration of cannabis
glands or the resin contained within
but the glands are made intact for the
most part and they're it's not the
active ingredients are not dissolved in
any way water hashes not because water
is the universal solvent and in fact it
works because him resin glands are not
soluble in water it's it's just like
moving around with air you're moving
around the water but yeah that's the
definition for me I think the
fascinating they are made off no
botanist by training so the fascinating
thing to me is the plants and the
cultures and hashish was a great example
everybody has varying strategies for
achieving essentially the same end and I
find this also with fiber production
with hemp I'm very in-depth textiles and
hemp for a seed and fiber as well and I
like the different strategies that
people around the world to come up with
for working with hemp fibers and to take
him all the way to making fine texels
wrong so yeah it's interesting it's for
me it's much more about the people than
the plan
if yeah so for those cultivators who
cultivate for hash you know they which
we and we know several who do is in that
is that also about the person rather
like been the plant it's the poor it's
if we know some of the same people which
I assume we dear that I'd have to answer
that question in the affirmative but
because those people are characters but
they don't represent cultures if you
know outside of North America yeah well
one of them said to me once you know you
should write write an article on the
cultivator in the hash maker and I said
and I realized that I knew three or four
different relationships that were that
relationship a cultivator who had a
relationship with a hash maker and out
of that relationship they created a
third product and haven't done the
article but I thought it was really
interesting and a great idea just
curious what you think about those
relationships is it was it real are they
real because they're they're actually
really out there it was real enough to
make that batch of hash apparently it
was good so yeah I mean it's it's kind
of the same way with the land races land
races are there because there was a
culture that raised the plant in their
own local environment
year after year from seed so there was a
chance for genetic variation each year
and without the cultures you lose the
land race it's it's not just that we've
gone back and taken Dutch scoop seeds to
Nepal but it's part of the problem but
the problem also is that the Nepali
people who were making that Ashish back
in the day that they got older they
don't live there anymore or they move
because they've degraded the land around
them or it's just everything changes
it's and and you can get really
sentimental and the older I get I guess
the more realistic I get a hope
but also a bit sentimental and and you
miss these things and you there are
times when you wish time would stand
still and things would remain the way
they have been but the essence of
culture is change and all we ever get is
a snapshot we if it didn't change it
wouldn't be culture and it really
wouldn't be interesting so yeah that's
that's it - and and the Hat
transformation from a hemp plant to a
textile or cannabis plant landrace are
not - a piece of hashish or rosin or BHO
for that matter I think this is all
interesting to employ have they taken it
to these two limits I mean just recently
I saw these THC a to me ISM I mean I saw
it ground up there's a white powder of
course in a lab substance over the years
and looks like all it looks like every
other cannabinoid pretty much except THC
which is just not a white powdery thing
at all it's almost if you've never
messed with it it has got to be the most
viscous sticky liquid on the planet just
about I mean you can tip this if it was
filled with THC right now you just tip
it over inside even a warm room
temperature like this and half hour
later might be just kind of starting to
think about leaking out on the table
it's incredible THC a is a dry freely
flowing powder if you grind it up and
otherwise it's these beautiful crystals
which these young guys now are getting
to precipitate out all these different
shapes so you can cut these flat kind of
triangular big crystals and you've got
ones that look just like rock salt and
you've got other ones who look just like
rock candy yeah and wands great it's
fascinating what do you got to do that
put the terpenes back in it you know I
think people are like that literally
just to show that they can do it it's
awesome and there's no IP on it if you
want to know how to do it just log on to
YouTube and they'll be any number of
kids they'll show you their variations
for doing this stuff and it's it's great
in this world where we're all struggling
for IP which is part of what we're just
talking about I also find it really
refreshing that all this stuff is just
out there and anybody wants to do it can
do it you know and yeah
nobody even tried to claim the rosin
thing because everybody already watched
it happen on you to watch the first guy
do it and he went dudes check this out
everybody can do this it's amazing my
wife's hair straightener yeah all right
so then the next episode of t-shirt for
us