what I'm hoping is that there will be
more than one company that will give
breeders an opportunity to just breed
and then that will commercialize their
genetics and that these companies will
compete with each other for the rights
to those genetics and that the breeders
will have basically it'll be like the
music industry and that breeders can
basically bring their their genetics to
these companies and let them compete
with each other for rights to these
genetics that's I don't know how soon
that's going to happen but that's what I
would like to I would like to have plant
breeders really be like the rock stars
and be the brand that's what I'm hoping
will happen and I'm I'm gonna do my
little part to make that happen but
can't make it happen alone