to think the way I think of it as I've
got this huge palette of colors to work
from then it's the best palette of
colors and I can draw on that to make
any shade of anything when I do I don't
feel limited to just pursuing two or
three paths I really like to keep the
keep the door wide open to what what is
required and what people want and I
think from a production point of view
what people are going to want is going
to be sterile versions of those plants
so once you've got the plants you want
then you want to work on making sterile
versions of them because the sterile
plants won't take seed so if you want to
grow a field with no seeds in it even if
the neighbors have hemp all around you
need to have sterile plants so that's
going to be the real one of the notable
features of the current cannabis
genetics Renaissance are seeing there's
so many more people involved in cannabis
genetics research now than ever was on a
more professional level than there ever
was more academic level let's say you're
gonna see a lot of advances from plants
you don't need the trim the plants that
can't be seated in plants that mites
bony plants that are very very resistant
to different fungal issues it's I think
we're gonna see an enormous leap in
cannabis genetics it's just in the next
five years like there's gonna be more
happening in cannabis genetics in the
last five years than has ever happened
you were talking sterile before right
the sterile plants that I'm referring to
that I've seen and that I'm endeavouring
to reliably produce they right now I'm
only about 50% success rate but I need
him to be at a hundred but those plants
have no pistols they're female plants
with no pistols so you can smother them
in Poland say name their barren
basically they're barren
won't be they cannot get pregnant yes so
so is this something is this something
new or has this been ER I've seen is
there word for that first time I saw it
it was in well the sterile females is
essentially apathy there's different
routes to it I found and the first plant
I found were in 96 and there's hormonal
ways of inducing this and some people
aim for polyploidy mutagens others go
for mono points I think the mono Koide
is the way to go there's also the
possibility of doing if I gene editing
but I'm not as happy about that it's the
problem I find with gene editing that
scares me about it is that there's been
instances of the bacteria used to cut
the chromosome is it ends up
occasionally inserting its own genes
into the organism so you end up with a
transgenic plant even if you didn't mean
to because maybe you you know you think
gene editing oh it sounds nice and clean
but it's not as it's not as clean as it
could be yet and it's filling its
infancy I thought but let's say there
was a gene for hermaphrodite amande you
had a great plant you loved that plant
but it threw some bananas at the end
every time and you're like I can't keep
this plant cuz I hate Hermes I can but I
don't want to lose it because it's the
only one I've got that tastes like
whatever so you say if only I could get
in there and just remove the
hermaphroditic tree that would be great
but if in doing so you introduce a
foreign gene then you may regret it
another ways down the road so for me the
jury's out on it in a way and I wouldn't
I'm all about learning from these
techniques but I would be really loath
to release and
thing done that way without knowing a
lot more about it because I'm not
convinced it's already for release but
I'm totally convinced it needs to be
studied you know the concept here is
basically sterile females and then you
could plant a field full of sterile
females and never have to worry about
the hemp farmer down the street in
pregnant you know Kay the fox in the hen
house coming in and pregnant it but but
your old plants you put them out they
can not make us and they're incredible
but what you're saying is that we don't
know you know it's like every
pharmaceutical drug commercial like this
will this will solve problem a but
you'll have anal leakage and you'll die
no no this this is a I was only talking
about that in reference to gene editing
as a pathway the other ways of doing it
through mutagenic readings really is not
gonna have any risk of transgenics
there's nothing about that the the other
the hormonal II induced ones the other
way of doing them there's not harm only
inducement and does bring you back to
the tissue culture angle is pollen
culture some people do it as ant ant
their culture but you could take a
single grain of pollen they come I mean
think how much grains of pollen you'd
have in one gram of Poland it's
mind-boggling if you think of those
grains of pollen as a haploid seed and
you raised that grain of pollen in its
own test tube into a Kahless and from
the Kahless you initiate grain growth
and start a new plant that plant is a
haploid it doesn't have a mother and
father is only the father so it's a
haploid the cannabis is typically
diploid so it's got two sets of
chromosomes and one from the mother one
from the father same as you and I are we
talking somatic and
Genisys well yes somatic embryogenesis
is a Kahless culture that is Kahless
culture but growing you can do careless
culture from somatic embryogenesis is
when you do Kahless culture and you
encapsulate it first synthetic c so
that's the somatic part that you want it
sleeping so you're taking you're making
tissue culture dormant for a little bit
thinks and encapsulating it is somatic
embryogenesis but that starts as Kahless
culture typically but Kahless culture is
usually a Kahless is an adventitious
root so when you look at the bottom of
your trunk right above the soil line
there'll be some little white bumps on
the bark and if you buried them they
would grow into roots so those little
bumps are called adventitious roots also
known as Kahless so if you sanitize the
surface of that and took a razor and
nicked off some Kahless you could
propagate at a cellular level and raise
up you know you could put those Kahless
in a blender and make it into a million
little kala cells and grow them in a
suspension culture and then as they get
to a size where you want them to have
some great because it's very easy to
have been throwing in the white the
trick is to get them and different for
every variety but to get them to
initiate the green growth and you
typically would do that by changing the
spectrum of the lighting over your
bioreactor and hormonal initiation so
the once you've got those little
artificial seeds in suspension you could
start encapsulating them but that has
nothing to do with the sterile females
other than the Kahless culture could be
initiated from if you're doing it just
from a mother you're just making
cuttings of that mother but if you're
doing it from my single grain of pollen
you've got you're doing it from a plant
you've never seen yet you know and when
you
throw that plant out from a single grain
of pollen not a lot of people are doing
that I know I think I know two other
groups actually doing pollen culture
right now and this is something that
you're researching yep this is something
we're playing with that I have because
because I think and I really want and
we're working on the financing in-house
testing because right now for sequencing
I have to send it out so we can prepare
the samples but we would send it out for
sequencing but it's quite expensive and
especially when you want a sample high
volume so let's say I want a sample a
million grains of pollen you look for a
specific trait you know that's a bit
cost prohibitive sending that out of
1,500 bucks a pop for a sample right so
if you can get high-volume sample the
equipment which is very expensive but if
you can get that and run it in-house and
keep it busy then it makes sense so
sifting through and weeding out plants
even from seedlings right if you've got
a million seedlings started you can take
a little punch out of the second or
third leaf that's growing from each one
and you could say okay you know whatever
trait you're looking for if it was
purple or green or sterile and
non-sterile you could separate those
plants out you know male female or
hermaphrodite you can separate those
plants out at a very young age and and
if you're looking for one that's a the
highest and CBD v which one if you have
a known marker for CBD v then you're
saying which ones have the the best
concentration of that marker you know
which ones are really gonna push the CBD
v so you can start once you can start
isolating your selections you know
through lab assisted selective breeding
even without doing any transgenic
madness you can have some really stellar
information quickly from large batches
and that's the
you so much time you know you still want
to take the contenders and finish them
off and see them in in under real
conditions but just being able to thin
the herd out by looking under the hood
that's a huge advantage because those
pollen grains are gonna make a haploid
plant which has a single chromosome
rather than you and I have
we're diploid x' because we have one
strand from our mother and what strand
from our father whereas that one only
has the screen from the father never met
the mother and we went ahead and took it
to the next level
so so starting with haploids you can use
that and cross it to itself later and
make a double half lloyd and it's got
the identical two strings of genes so
there's different pathways you'll see
people using to get to the sterile
females but important thing to remember
which I was about to touch on earlier
but we switched here somehow but there's
two types of sterile females and in the
world we see part on the carpet which is
the virgin fruit which is the only way
I'm interested in that will not take the
pollen and then you have steno carpet
plants and that has little aborted seeds
in it and that's useless for us so
that's like the seedless watermelon
seedless grapes and you get those little
white tips in them and stuff but they
don't develop a finish seed but nobody
wants thud that's all polluted with
little white seeds right so it's not
good enough that they abort them later
which is Stena Karthi we don't want them
to make them in the first place that's
part of the curtain and that's the the
big dividing line I've seen a lot of
breeders fail to make sterile females
using polyploid and polyploid czar how
stand the carpet plants are made are
people using these procedures in in this
in the stator or how humans live I've
seen one American and
in Spain and then us in Colombia so
there's it would be the the cost of
doing this the lab cost I don't think so
if there's a straight-up sterile females
you don't have to spend you know
millions of dollars the first time I saw
it was in 96 and it was out of
somebody's basement I mean you could
make it was like you know when the first
sterile females came out is when people
started trying to make feminized Heat
and it was before anybody was using
silver even people were using other
hormones they'd be a chocolate and it's
basically just a freaky little what's
the form factor like if people can
create sterile females and you could
plant a whole field of it is the form
factor like could you create seeds where
if I popped those seeds every female is
sterile or is it tissue culture or do
you have to have one mom that's what
we're working on now the best I've done
is 50% so I'd get a hundred percent
female seeds and only half of them had
pistols but I want to release those with
a hundred percent without crystals so
you can you can make a selection right
now without with only get it in half
Attis turtles you can make a selection
and propagate those and vision culture
but ideally I would like to be able to
make the seed 200% that sterile so that
they can just go straight into the field
without having to be propagated any way
shape or form they have recently brought
up an American friend that has a lot
more explaining to me in molecular
genetics and he was growing spice in the
92 early 2000s he came to visit the
beads which one he's a longtime spice
fans by issuer he was growing aquaponic
sweet tooth in like 2000 and now he's
spent the last 20 years getting degrees
and studying molecular genetics
he said hey I want to do a PhD on
cannabis if your company kids collection
yet you bet with you guys we were able
to bring in it so it's really fun to
build the teams so with him specifically
what what kind of problem what kind of
tasks problems do you want to task him
with solving light light like what
what's what's what's his first project
find us powdery mildew resistant genes
but also the sterile females is me I
said that's really got to be a strong
focus on each of the pathways doing it
to chart them and what's good and bad
about each of the pathways we found to
which doing that the photo resistance
goes understand that's really deals to
watch but as far as like I like send out
prepared samples to be sequenced I can't
read the information that comes back so
I require genetics interpreter that
knows how to look at a sequencing
analysis and say okay here's what you're
looking at and it explained it and they
can decipher that so he's pretty gifted
at that sort of thing and he showed me a
lot of the work he's done has been in
tracking specific markers and lettuce
and he would attach a glow-in-the-dark
gene the thing he's looking for and then
it would make a very obvious because all
the lettuce fruits that had it good in
the dark so I mean that's transgenic
lettuce but you know we don't
necessarily want to eat that let us
first book it but to be able to work
under the hood like that not just to
look under the hood is an asset I don't
necessarily want of making transgenic
animals but I wanted them to be able to
help me identify and track markers for
the development of trades