[Music]
years ago the situation with cannabis
was there was a lot of low potency
material around but don't let anyone
tell you that there wasn't good potent
material there was it was just a little
bit rarer harder to find more expensive
also at that time there were a lot of
what we called land races so these were
cannabis types that had been grown in a
particular area for many generations
they were ecologically adapted to the
local environment they could deal with
the past they were vigorous but beyond
that they had very interesting psychic
psychological characteristics a
psychopharmacological
effects that we just don't see today one
of the big problems in cannabis breeding
from my standpoint is something we heard
about earlier that we've had this
homogeneous Asian part of this is a
byproduct of prohibition and basically
in a situation where a drug is illegal
it makes sense to have it as potent as
possible so it's the lowest volume of
possible which helps prevent discovery
by law enforcement in particular so what
we've had is selective breeding for the
last 40 years for high THC to the
exclusion of everything else what we've
ended up with in the market is a
situation in which we've got almost
everything is high THC and high merci
that combination is notorious for
producing couch lock now I know that
people some people like this effect but
most consumers of cannabis aren't really
looking to be immobilized they're
looking to
either a good experience or a
therapeutic experience and if you have
pain and have to sleep that's a good
combination but if you have to work or
study it's not basically cannabis has a
great deal more to offer and part of
what we'd like to discuss this evening
is that and why targets and goals I'd
like to share with you because I think
that this represents an avenue going
forward where what I like to call
barefoot breeders I hope nobody thinks
that that's derogatory in any way but
these would be the people like many of
you that have been dedicated to the
plant maybe living off the grid for a
long period of time I've never had the
rewards from your effort maybe on a
personal level but certainly not on a
commercial level where you could make
this a living a viable living doing this
and this is I think a worthy goal it's
not about making millions of dollars
it's about being able to do what you
love on at the same time helping a lot
of people out there and I don't mean to
exclude what some people call
recreational use of cannabis because if
the question is can we make recreational
cannabis a lot better you bet and I
think we could help with describing
those characteristics but I'm going to
primarily talk about medical
applications so beyond the high THC high
Mersin this is spilt over now there in
the last several years there's been
great interest in cannabidiol for all
its medical attributes but we've ended
up with an analogous situation and that
now we have a bunch of CBD kiemce of
ours
they're also rich in Mersin which has
created the misconception that
cannabidiol is sedating it's not when
you've got CBD without mersin it's
actually innovating and a lot of people
or you
CBD preparations instead of caffeine in
the morning but what we'd like to have
people aim for is CBD predominant chemo
VARs with little or no THC that could
qualify as hemp although I have
difficulties as a scientist and the
current definition in this country of
just 0.3 or less percent THC so we're
also interested in CBD key movers with
little or no Mersin rather to emphasize
some of the other terpenoids the
aromatic components that modulate the
effects of cannabis specifically CBD
with high limonene limonene is a great
antidepressant you combine that with the
anti-anxiety effects of CBD and you've
got a great agent for a variety of
psychiatric conditions or just
garden-variety bad day anxious that kind
of thing
similarly cannabidiol with hi Linda Lou
Lin Aloha like CBD is an anti-anxiety
agent famous for coming from lavender
but but you on that both of them are
anticonvulsant and from colleagues who
have used these types of combinations
and patients with severe epilepsy
they're seeing success where there
wasn't any before with just CBD so these
are the kinds of potentials that we can
see another really interesting target is
CBD with hi Carrie awfully Carrie
awfully tends to be the predominant
turpenoid in a lot of extracts so it'll
be preserved say in a co2 extract
whereas you'd lose some of the lower
molecular weight monitor annoyed the
limonene the myrrh seen on the pining
but CBD with high Carrie awfully knows
ents a very broad spectrum of medical
activity both are anti-inflammatory
together they can be analgesic being
relieving
ah both have anti addictive properties
and could help people get off of opioids
in any other addictive drug and then
they would have application in
autoimmune conditions so it's really
limited only by the imagination another
thing we'd like to see inbreeding is
more type 2 preparations so a balance of
THC and CBD
additionally selective breeding where
you're going to have that kind of
combination but with high selective
terpenoids as well especially pining
pining is an acetylcholinesterase
inhibitor acetylcholine is the memory
molecule on the brain and when you have
more of it you don't have the Oh what
was I saying the short-term memory
impairment for which THC is infamous
that's funny in a social setting but
again if your chronic pain patient and
you have to work you don't want to be
forgetting so four alertness and clarity
of a high pining is what you want to
look for then a big one how many of you
are familiar on an experiential basis
with cannabis Jarrell CBG so I see a few
hands go up canapa girolle is the parent
of the other cannabinoids in the plant
of course it's in the acid form so can a
bird can can of bigger Olek acid easy
for me to say we know almost nothing
about what CB GA does but we do know
quite a bit about CB g in my way of
thinking this is the next big thing in
cannabis and heretofore it's really been
pretty much ignored but this is a very
unusual molecule
first of all odd has very pronounced
antibiotic activity including against
some really bad
like methicillin-resistant Staph aureus
that has caused some Hospital epidemics
and this is why they scrub you before
surgery so that you don't get horrible
wound infections beyond that it has a
very interesting profile in that it's a
very powerful anti-anxiety agent without
being sedating anybody who's taken
medicines like the benzodiazepines
valium at all almost all the drugs that
have been used pharmaceutically to treat
anxiety have been sedating and often
addictive on this presents a profile
that's really benign in comparison to
those drugs
additionally CBG is very active against
a number of types of cancer particularly
prostate cancer which is number one or
number two most common type of cancer in
men so a great potential there
additionally it seems like we have
evidence of a variety of chemo VARs that
are very rich in CBG that will have
little or no THC and could qualify as
hemp and eventually if we get the laws
right could go across state and
international borders and I'm hoping
that Dale will talk more about
strategies there we think with the right
legislation or even without it there may
be some work around so that your work in
one state could reach other
jurisdictions I'm also interested in
something that almost nobody is is
working on and that would be zero
cannabinoid plants now why would you
want that well there are two reasons one
is very interesting for research work
where you want to compare the entourage
of the terpenoids against a similar
entourage of terpenoids with
cannabinoids but that's a little bit
nerdy another reason is that
you can make essential oil of cannabis
without the liability we'll call it of
THC content and some people are going to
want to use this as a flavoring or as a
perfume or a Roma therapy agent and they
may want to use this to make
preparations to help if you have a keema
var that has one profile that you like
but you want to add more line meaning to
it you can selectively breed for that
you know ideally we would prefer to have
chemo VARs that have the exact profile
we want but that's that's hard that
takes multiple generations and there are
some shortcuts where you're still
working just with cannabis and it may be
that pharmaceutical agents are made this
way sativex which is approved in 30
countries is actually a combination of
two chemo VARs one high in THC one high
in CBD next THC V tetrahydrocannabinol
is THC with the three carbon sidechain
instead of five this is a really
interesting agent as well it's found in
low amounts in cannabis from southern
Africa it is different to THC however in
that it's what's called a neutral
antagonist at low doses it opposes the
activity at the cb1 receptor so it
actually allows hunger it's very good
for diabetes metabolic syndrome but
beyond that it is anticonvulsant and it
is good for neuropathic pain
experientially when there's a good
amount of it with THC it makes for a
clearer high rapid onset a more rapid
offset as well so we think that this has
great potential and then you can get
into things where you're really seeing a
combination of ingredients that can be
therapeutic so
Keem there are key movers that combined
CBD CBD V Lynaugh Lowell and carry off
allene maybe with a touch of THC all of
those can have beneficial effects on
epilepsy so together there's every
reason to expect they'll be synergistic
and provide much better medicine than
say CBD alone which now is an FDA
approved drug in this country just a few
words about others I haven't mentioned
cannabic Romijn so CPC is considered one
of the major cannabinoids but we
actually see very little of it in most
types of cannabis the reason for that is
unlike THC and CBD which are products of
dominant genes CBC can a macro mean is
produced by a recessive gene so it's not
going to tend to be expressed
additionally it's going to appear in
higher concentrations in immature plants
it's actually possible if you've got a
plant that has a good amount of cannabic
Romijn you could make hash out of it at
a younger age to produce what my former
colleague David Potter called ETP an
enriched trichome product otherwise
known as Keef but this is again a very
versatile age and it's shown some
antidepressant effects in the animals
again has anti-inflammatory activity
it's good for a wide range of cancer
cell types and we really haven't had it
available in insufficient amounts to do
the kind of work that would make it good
commercial target then the acid
cannabinoids many of you live in this
area may be familiar with juicing
cannabis but that's like
headed for the right target but using
the wrong technique juicing is generally
done with fan leaves massive amounts
often people are juicing 30 big fan
leaves a day and it's just an impossible
thing for most people to sustain unless
they've got acres of material rather if
we're going for the cannabinoids their
concentration of course is greatest in
the the flowers on that should be the
source of it why are we interested in
THC a tetrahydrocannabinol ik acid which
has been billed as being non
psychoactive and has been actually in
the past called inactive which is
absolutely wrong well as many of you may
be aware this also has therapeutic
activity is quite distinct from THC
itself about in the prior decade it was
established that this works on something
called tumour necrosis factor alpha
which is very important in certain
autoimmune conditions including the
inflammatory bowel conditions Crohn's
and ulcerative colitis but also an MS
rheumatoid arthritis so we've seen a lot
of people that will juice or get THC a
from flowers that have had very positive
influences on their autoimmune
conditions and then two years ago in
Spain it was noted that there was
another important activity various of
the cannabinoids work on something
called P / gamma this is a nuclear
receptor it affects gene transcription
which sounds really scary but you can
have good effects or bad effects the
good effects of P power gamma are that
it can contribute to weight loss and
people who are obese it can positively
affect cancer on a variety of other
disease conditions and as it turns out
THC a is much more potent on the people
are gamma
laughter than any of the other
cannabinoids so part of the problem with
THC a is it's unstable it breaks down
into the stuff called THC it gets people
intoxicated which again can be a good or
bad thing but there may be ways to
stabilize THC a and certainly when
people are making fresh material it's
freely available and again makes a good
target it's a now analogous product is
CBD a cannabidiol like acid again we
know a little bit less here but we do
know is tantalizing some of you may be
aware that cannabidiol also works on
serotonin receptors this is the basis
for it's anti-anxiety a fact as well as
a number of neuro protective benefits in
the brain and possibly its
anticonvulsant effect but cannabidiol ik
acid does a hundred times more potent on
the 5ht serotonin when a receptor
additionally based on the accounts from
the renaissance herbalists they used raw
hemp which would have been relatively
rich in CBD a and treating a variety of
tumors so we really haven't looked at
that yet but this soul is a product that
deserves a lot more attention on I
wanted to finish this section with
cannabinol CBN now I'm sort of amused by
this CBN is an oxidative breakdown
product at THC
if you have cannabis that's been sitting
out for a couple of years its THC is
going to turn into CBN we've got a lot
of companies touting this as having some
real advantages I think that a lot of
this is wishful thinking it is true that
there's a misconception that CBN is very
sedating and they're there for a good
for sleep rather it's a case of CBN is
and it's basically
25% of the potency of THC the reason
that old cannabis makes you sleep isn't
because of CBN it's because you've lost
the more alerting monitor Pinoys in
favor of sedating sesqui terpenoids and
beyond that I think that this quest for
CBN is a way of trying to use up old
dope that wasn't good for anything else
now some people may disagree with me but
I guarantee that most of the people that
are heavily marketing CBN have this in
mind just a very little bit about the
terpenoids beyond what we've said
already have mentioned limonene pining
and Mersin and Lyn Ahlul Turpin allene
terpene lean is an interesting terpenoid
we seem more in California than other
places it's beginning to get popular and
in Washington where I live
odd one in that got discrepancies and
how it affects different species its
sedating in animals but when people use
it it has more of a buzz and again like
pining it may have some effect to boost
acetylcholine levels on a lot of people
like it if they have to do use cannabis
and do work like cleaning the garage
might increase their focus and I
mentioned Kerry awfully Nazz well again
very impressive agent this is working it
has the distinction of not just being a
terpenoid but a cannabinoid as well it
is directly affecting the cb2 receptor
so this is the non psychoactive receptor
which nonetheless has important pain
reducing and anti-inflammatory activity
as well as being anti addictive so
having carry off lien in a good amount
in a cannabis based preparation is going
to cover a lot of bases therapeutically
and quickly mention in carol carry off
allene oxide this may be what is
responsible for is the scent that
sniffer dogs key in on but beyond that
it seems to be an extremely strong
antifungal even working on nail fungus
and there's one of the prescription
drugs that's advertised on TV you can
spend five thousand dollars over six
months and have a 50% chance of curing
your nail fungus but apparently on an 8%
solution to this reportedly can cure
nail fungus in in two weeks so what's
wrong with this picture so there's great
potential out there i think that's all i
wanted to say now i want to start by
just saying that one of the things i
like doing is talking to audiences that
are kind of new to cannabis i i spoke at
the association of university technology
managers so these are these are the tech
transfer offices and universities that
try to get patents on whatever it is
their professors have discovered and
then they once they get the patents or
lately a patent applications filed then
they find a licensee that wants access
to that and they'll pay a fee and the
university can replenish its its
research funding and so on but
universities have completely stayed away
from cannabis because they don't want to
lose their federal research funding and
you know you touch the plant and you
might lose all your research funding and
a lot of universities would just dry up
so i had a chance to talk to them about
the cannabis industry and i think about
february and i realized
alright these people might be where I
was a couple years ago where well a few
years ago when I first got into the
cannabis industry from just my more
conventional law practice I didn't know
what CBD CBD was I went to MJ biz con
one year
talking about CBD I had to look it up
and I realized now you all I mean some
of you've been in this for generations
as many of you your whole life but I was
talking to an audience that had had
begun to hear about CBD you know well
what I said is a few years ago none of
us in this room had heard of it and now
your grandma and your dog are both
taking it and they knew that's true and
then the news flash was cannabis has way
more than just THC and CBD and you know
depending on which number you believe it
might make a hundred and fifty different
cannabinoids plus all the terpenes and
and ethan talked about many of them but
it makes way more than the ones he
talked about plus the the flavonoids and
what's really interesting is at the
receptor level and I learned a lot about
receptors some in grad school but also
some working with a company that that
found natural insecticides that were
based on the way essential oils
completely safe essential oils acted on
the receptors the olfactory receptors in
insect system okay now let's stop there
for a second why would that happen
because plants evolved their essential
oils as defenses and so somebody thought
well okay let's look at instead of
looking at these one at a time let's try
making pairwise combinations and some of
them were more potent than the most
potent chemical pesticides others were
extremely potent repellents and was
completely natural stuff you could spray
it on your kitchen counter and all the
Flies would die but you could wipe piece
of bread on it and eat it you wouldn't
wouldn't taste very good but you could
do that so the point of all this is that
as soon as we start to look at the plant
as not just THC or CBD or soar it's way
more than just how high is the THC how
high is the CBD what is the terpene
profile it's there are so many different
active molecules that could act at
different receptors in combination and
create amazing synergies and sometimes I
don't think that even shows up in a CoA
because some of these some of these
molecules will be active at levels that
are either just at detection or even
low detection but they're at receptor
activity the receptor could be really
powerful especially in combination
so the reason I'm going into all this is
that I honestly believe that the future
of medicine the next century of medicine
is going to come from this plant it's
not going to come from you know
manufactured molecules in the
pharmaceutical industry I'll just stop
there for a second have you heard of
combinatorial chemistry the wave farmer
discovers many of its drugs it starts
with some core and then it makes a
million variations on this core molecule
and then it has something called
high-throughput screening where it tests
those on cell cultures to see if
anything happens and it's just
completely random you know random works
if you if you have enough of a sample
size and you can afford it but instead
how about if we look at molecules that
we already know operate on human
receptors in many cases for an amazing
array of benefits so what does this have
to do with this what ethan calls
barefoot breeders I've worked with plant
breeders my whole career since I I was a
plant scientist before I went to law
school
and so I kind of got channeled to that
in the first law firm I was in and I
worked with some companies that were
developing special fruits and flowers
that had great commercial potential and
we helped them launch their their
licensing programs all over the world
well when I get into this industry and I
and I start seeing what the struggles
that plant breeders who are passionate
about the plant the struggles they face
with taxation regulation licensing just
funding and I realized okay I've talked
already about standing up to big AG we
need to be different from big AG big AG
is going to have the firepower to do
marker-assisted breeding and genetic
engineering all of that stuff let them
have it my sense is that we have in this
community in this and yeah is it I would
say in the community is a better word
than industry especially in this contact
we have people who have decades
individuals who have decades of
experience breeding the plant and we
have at least hundreds of them maybe
thousands and if you think about how we
can be different from big AG and
actually be way damn better than big AG
we've got the biggest R&amp;D team in the
history of pharmaceuticals or medicines
and and it's all this is this isn't even
this is jus if we just took a snapshot
of what people have in their greenhouses
in their seed collections we've already
got way more person years of R&amp;D on
plants that are promising to be way more
powerful than combinatorial chemistry or
even marker-assisted breeding and so my
sense is we don't know all the things
that cannabinoids Ethan's been talking
about we know what cannabinoids 1 &amp; 2 is
THC and THC and CBD he's been talking
about maybe cannabinoids 3 through 10
and they've got all these amazing
potential potentialities but then let's
talk about cannabinoids 11 through 150
we've got to be able to find him we've
got to be able to at least detect him in
high enough levels that we know which
plants to breed to elevate those levels
and then elevate the levels enough that
we can start to figure out what the hell
they do but is there any doubt that you
know if if 1 through 10 have these
incredibly powerful effects any of which
can be can be used in the right way to
have a beneficial effect do you think
that 11 through 150 are gonna have some
value absolutely so we don't know what
what it'll be yet but it's super
exciting so our barefoot breeder program
is that I have what I've found is I've
worked with a lot of plant breeders is
some of them are really good at Bizness
and the ones that are good at Bizness
you've heard of them or some of you are
here but it's like okay the gene that
makes you a good plant breeder whatever
that gene and it's not genetic but if it
were the gene that makes you a good
plant breeder and the gene that makes
you a good business person
are not linked right it's it's a happy
coincidence when that happens but it's
it's a it's a coincidence there are a
lot of people who are passionate about
plant breeding and really good at it who
don't even want to be entrepreneurs they
don't want to start their own business
they don't want to go find funding they
don't want to hire lawyers and on and on
and on and after talking with several
breeders that were like that was they
exactly fit that profile they had
amazing work they've done amazing work
they had amazing cultivars but zero
interest and maybe zero opportunity to
become great entrepreneurs and and take
the the cultivars they had developed and
really get them out there to the world
after several these kinds of
conversations I realized that somebody
ought to have something like a record
company where the breeders are the
songwriters and the singers and they
don't have to be good at anything else
all they have to do is do what they're
passionate about and be good at it and
then somebody else steps in and says
okay we got you we'll take it from here
and by the way like a good record
company instead of a bad one we will
take care of you you'll be proud to work
with us you'll get paid fairly and we'll
get your work out to the whole world and
so you can even have groupies in fact we
all wish we had the groupies and Ethan
has right but we were talking about that
a while ago just watch so anyway that
the the beauty of this is that they can
be good at what they're good at and then
they can let somebody else take care of
the rest so I talked to a few people
about this in the industry and they were
pretty receptive very receptive to it
and then I went to a friend of mine who
has been a really good CEO for some
startup companies that I've worked with
and I said hey would you be the CEO of
this and he said no but I'll help you be
the CEO and not fuck it up at at that
please I guess maybe and so actually
Ethan and I are started
company called breeders best and it's
really going to this isn't even a pitch
for that because there needs to be more
than one of these there needs to be a
whole whole ecosystem of companies like
this so that breeders have choices
my example of that is how how boring
would downtown be if there was one
restaurant and one bar there's got to be
there's got to be competition there's
got to be selection to really establish
what is a fair market and what is a
vibrant market and to give opportunities
to as many breeders as possible but
we're the first ones to try this model I
think and our goal is to figure out to
hopefully be good at identifying
cultivars that really have strong
potential and then protecting them the
breeder will own the the the rights
permanently the breeder owns the rights
we would be the licensee and we would
help them get this out to the world
and then probably the most exciting part
of this is that you've heard Ethan's
wish list he might now have access to a
whole RDR me like the world has never
seen before if we can communicate this
and we can enlist breeders to say hey we
can tell them go look see if you've got
this already you might already have this
and if you don't go make it Ethan wants
it and he's a rock star and he's gonna
make you famous so that's what we're
working on and we're excited about it it
it's this is not meant as a company
pitch it's meant as having us all think
about the vast potential here and that
there are lots of ways to get from point
A to point B but we need to get from
point A to point B this is us taking a
shot at it but I just I want as many
breeders as possible to really succeed
at this yes
testing are we gonna be able to test
some of these things to sift them out
and figure out what they are is that
part of the I think if if we have that
they ever have the money right now we
have $10,000 in investment which is
pretty much paying for some t-shirts and
a booth that emerald-cut but you know to
start right if we had the money to do
that I would love to see some legacy
breeder brings his or her seed
collection and we grow them up and test
them one of the breeders that I'm that
I'm already working with he's a dear
friend of mine now and he actually sent
some samples that we will be able to try
later on he he did a vegetative testing
at early stages of some seeds that he
obtained and found decently measurable
levels of THC v even in the leaves
selected some males cross them and he's
been working on this project for a few
years but what he gave me on my way up
here was a cultivar that is eight and a
half percent THC v and seventeen percent
THC and got a bottle of it that we can
try the point is that if we know what
we're looking for
and people have these incredible
collections and they have so much
passion to to you know let's put the
chocolate with peanut butter together we
might get something that tastes good I
think there's incredible potential I
really do believe that it is old-school
plant breeders that are going to change
the face of medicine in the next couple
generations absolutely and it's you it's
you and your friends I want to do what I
can to help with that but it's not it
doesn't depend on whether we do a good
job of this or not
it depends on opportunities like this
not only this but opportunities like
this for for this great army of breeders
I wanted to say one other thing that I'm
really excited about cannabinoids 11
through 150 we know that if if you can
find it
if it's there it's going to do something
with a cannabinoid receptor because
that's what cannabinoids do right and so
one of the things that we're doing on
kind of a heavy science part of this
company is we're gonna look at and I
could talk about this now because we've
done what we need to do to protect it
but we're gonna look at not just flowers
you know if cannabinoids evolved as
defense molecules do you think the plant
might want to defend its roots and its
seedlings and its meristems we're gonna
look at other tissues to see what turns
on the cannabinoid receptors and if we
find some there well we'll go to the
breeder that that let us test this
material and say hey guess what you got
some cool genetics there if you want to
work on developing this cannabinoid
there could be a real pot of gold at the
end of the rainbow that's the kind of
thing that with investor support we
would fund but I really believe that the
discovery and use of cannabinoids 11
through infinity is gonna come from
old-school breeding that's what I think
thanks so much Dale and if we didn't
seem excited about your eight percent
THC v/o
we are we are we're excited to smoke
that later thirty four point nine five
percent total cannabinoids yeah mostly I
will be exciting let's do that later
yeah okay cool one thing yeah you know
what Dale said is not just theory I
can't say too much about this but one of
those undiscovered cannabinoids has
shown recent testing to be an order of
magnitude more potent than THC so it
might explain why something tests at ten
percent but people are getting their
minds blown by it
so there's incredible potential out
there and again following on to what
Dale said we know a few of the
biosynthetic enzymes of the cannabinoids
and a little bit and the terpenoids but
how the plane
controls that turns on and off those
jeans has not been worked out at all and
these are the kinds of things we'd like
to work on but it will require having
the profiles that are worth
investigating to find out what makes
this particular Kimura var tick on you
know I can work on what it's good for
but again we'd love to give you the
targets and have you get to work awesome
and Ethan what about the four FS food
fibre fuel and pharmacy feel like you
covered that yeah okay well again you
know I'm fond of saying that if you're
on the proverbial desert island and had
to pick one plant of course it should be
cannabis we've been talking about maybe
second yeah but unlike the potato with
cannabis you not only have food you can
have medicine you can have clothing you
can have fuel I I think it's hard to
burn a potato but yeah another thing I
wanted to emphasize is as mentioned
other parts of the plant can be really
valuable you're all familiar with fiber
I'm a walking Patagonia and I'm wearing
a good amount of hemp myself but beyond
that I mentioned the fan leaves before
they actually contain a 0.2 percent of a
thing called canna preen which is a very
promising anti-inflammatory agent and
right now going to waste nothing's been
done with that I think you're probably
familiar with hemp seed nutrition one of
the most complete dietary ingredients on
earth having very important essential
fatty acids as well as a high quality
digestible protein called it deaths
this is in comparison to soybeans that
can name contain genestein which is
actually very bad for your gut
there were soybeans were described in
China for a thousand years before they
appeared in the diet
no took them a thousand years to figure
out how to use them in a way that wasn't
bad nutritionally and that's why in
Chinese food
you see sprouts and fermented products
you don't see raw soybeans being used so
I'm not an edamame fan I will say that
so if I turn those down at your meal you
know why and then we've got the roots
the roots are have been used
traditionally in medicine for as long as
the flowers have interestingly they
don't contain any cannabinoids but they
have very important other benefits trace
amount of alkaloids and things called
tri terpenoids which again very
importantly anti-inflammatory and
anti-cancer effects and Deol mentioned
the flavonoids I'll just talk about one
flavonoids are very important
antioxidant molecules so if you have a
lot of good vegetables in the diet
you'll be exposed exposed to flavonoids
and these will exert benefit on helping
to prevent cancer and things like that
one in particular can flavin a and B can
Flavin's are unique to cannabis they
haven't been found in any other plant
they have an anti-inflammatory profile
that is considered ideal in that they
have the benefits of anti-inflammatories
without the liabilities of the
non-steroidal anti-inflammatories which
are all acting through on enzyme cox-1
or cox-2 but the side effects of those
are well known they produce ulcers they
can produce art
attacks or strokes can't flavin doesn't
have that activity and should not have
those side effects so these are again
just a few of the products that we could
extract or produce from cannabis beyond
the flower thank you so much