[Music]
so yeah we're going to be transitioning
now into the IP intellectual property
section of the discussion IP is a very
misunderstood issue in cannabis there's
it's in flux it's very complicated in
the United States when it comes to
patents and plants and the United States
system is very unique in this regard but
one thing is that patents are kind of
the the elephant in the room and
everybody's worried about patents
there's a lot of discussion online about
patents biotech industries LLC has
applied for and received several
cannabis related patents some utility
patents as well as cultivar patents that
fall under the same category as their
utility patents so this is something
that's not very well understood there's
a lot of confusion about it and there's
also a lot of facets that we're not
necessarily looking at or discussing
online things like trademarks Appalachia
as there are lots of different ways of
protecting IP and we're lucky enough to
have Sheila here with us she's a patent
attorney she has experience in this
field and so yeah I'm gonna kick it over
to Sheila to give us a little bit of
background on the patent system in the
United States but also to help us start
a discussion and start thinking more
broadly and you know rooted in the facts
and what's really going on here what's
misunderstood in this industry I think
there's so much and it's such an
open-ended question but I would start by
saying maybe you know yes you can patent
a plant there in the US like Trevor
mentioned is different than most other
countries in that there is a system
that's divided by whether it's seed
propagated or its clones asexually
propagated
and so plant patents that you see are a
sexually propagated clones and those are
just for the clone that one genetics it
so whatever else you see in the
description
that's all required in order to describe
that clone it still only covers that
clone and anything a sexually propagated
so would be identical genetics in terms
of infringement you'd be looking at
genetic testing and finding out that yes
the you know more likely than not this
is the same clone
there's also utility patents utility
punts aren't limited by whether it's a
sexually propagated or seed propagated
and you can they do require a seed
deposit which currently in the United
States you cannot deposit seeds within a
USC Bank but you can deposit in Scotland
and you can have a utility patent that
would be somewhat broader and we can
talk a lot about the scope of patents
and whether or not you know going for
too broad of scope which I think we've
seen some of with biotech industries LLC
might actually get you a invalid and
invalid patent so that's utility patents
and I skipped over USDA protection USDA
protection is the plant breeders rights
and you see that internationally that
there are programs set up around the
world each of them might differ slightly
u.s. differs right now because it is
only for seed propagate propagated
cultivars but it is for they are opening
it up to a sexually reproduced cultivars
but that's under USDA control USDA
following the 2018 farm bill and as most
of you are aware USDA hasn't set forth
what their regulations and requirements
are going to be but we hope they're
coming soon the one thing about that is
that you do have to make a deposit to
get that type of protection currently
for seed propagated it's 2,500 seats and
they go through the u.s. testing to
determine that it is a stable line
that's the patent and plants side of
things and then Trevor also mentioned
trademarks and currently what I'm seeing
and I think that there was some
discussion today if you know patents
isn't the way that you're thinking about
going
you have trademarks as an option for
protecting your brand and that is you
know that you are the source of these
genetics and that nobody else can use
that brand name because that brand name
designates you as a source that's sort
of a very high-level overview of what's
available
there's also trade secret and I guess if
you're vertically integrated and you are
not worried about your clones getting
out or any of your breeding techniques
or things your protect them with trade
secret you can do that provided that
everything remains in your control and
everything remains secret you do have to
take protect you do have to have
precautions that would protect your
secret and you do have to be able to
establish that you have taken
protections to protect your seat or
taken precautions to protect your secret
in order to have any claim for damages
in in a lawsuit that's trade secret and
then copyright is the last branch of IP
copyright is more for creative works but
can be used for logos and then you know
other thing that I see a lot of in this
industry
a lot of pictures of your genetics
whether or not you're protecting those
pictures whether or not other people are
using those pictures especially on
social media are they just reposting
your pictures without your permission
and so there are all these different
layers of IP protection but the one that
I see the most talked about right now is
patents and so the point there is that
there's an incredibly complicated system
it's in flux right now because it's
changing literally right now the USDA is
drafting their regulations with regard
to how they're going to deal
specifically with hemp plant variety
protection and those are for seeds so we
have see
protections for plant variety protection
x' this was created under the 1970s
plant variety Protection Act before that
dating all the way back to the 1930s
people could get protections for clone
only varieties essentially the plant
fruit tree producers lobbied the
Congress to pass the Pat plant patent
Act of 1930 so that's why clonally
reproduced plants are held under a
different sort of system this is why the
United States is totally different than
everybody else everybody else has plant
patent the PvP plant variety protection
x' apply to everything in the United
States we have two separate systems
where plant variety protection x' apply
to seeds and plant patents apply to
clones correct
but that is going to change and that is
going to change and that's why so much
of this is in flux and is really
something that is a gamble people like
biotech industries are seeing this
emerging legalization and are pursuing
an IP strategy that is very similar and
akin to what big tech was doing but well
it wasn't big tech back in the day but
in the 1980s Silicon Valley people were
just gobbling up patents and patenting
all sorts of things that may or may not
have been unique and they were setting
very my new patents up and collecting
all of them as an IP strategy biotech
seems to be pursuing a similar strategy
right now because it's not even clear
that they could enforce or protect their
patents as it stands today they may be
able to in the future that correct
correct and one of the things that's
really interesting about the USPTO so we
have a government and I think that's
something that's really important to
realize is these are all different
government
agencies and they're all treating
cannabis very differently so and even
within a single agency so you have the
United States Patent and Trademark
Office that is responsible for issuing
both patents and trademarks reviewing
them issuing them and they treat them
completely separately and part of that
and so you'll hear a lot of
misinformation about no you can't get
patents because it's federally illegal
actually for patents that's not even one
of the inquiries of the Patent Office so
it has not been a hurdle and in fact
that there have been patents been
issuing for cannabis for a long time now
in fact I think the government applied
for theirs I think I want to say it like
1980 it's I don't know exactly
government does have patents on the life
protecting or you know life-saving
properties of cannabis which is a biting
irony so that's not an inquiry of the
Patent Office the Patent Office what
they want to know is is it new is it
well isn't useful have you described it
in order to meet the statutory
requirements and is it novel and
non-obvious over what was already known
in the art there is no inquiry about
whether it's you know there's any moral
or you know legal reason to not issue a
patent on that technology contrast that
with the Trademark Office which is the
same USPTO and the trademark office has
a requirement that you are using the
mark in commerce and in commerce has
historically been interpreted to mean
regulated by Congress so you know the
state can regulate what goes on within
the state but then once you move you
know outside of the state then you know
interstate would be in commerce and so
that is the issue with trademark
protection for cannabis is that you
can't show lawfully that you are using
your mark in commerce not for anything
that's federally illegal you can for
ancillary parts of your business that
are federally legal or that don't
present the issues of the CSA and now
even after the farm bill and once the
USDA gets their regulations out and
we're able to show that we can use the
marks and commerce for hemp even still
for CBD for example their trademark
office is still going to look at the
Food Drug and Cosmetic
so still that would be something that
you wouldn't be able to put that in
commerce and so the trademark office is
very literal in how they're issuing that
type of IP protection but you have the
same government agency the USPTO not
worrying about that at all as far as
patents are concerned and well hobby you
might have some experience here at least
observing how this is played out a
little bit in Amsterdam there's been
issues and controversies surrounding
names and there's been AI P strategies
predicated on trade marking names like
white widow and how was that played
yeah well I can't really speak to other
people's trademarks but I can I have I
have there's three different companies
who have trademarks on plants that I've
bred that I don't have those trademarks
people just went and preempted me and
went and got trademarks and one
particular company actually acquired
some genetics of mine and they because
they understood that you couldn't
trademark the plant they just
trademarked every possible package that
the plant would be in from vape pens to
bottles to baseball caps and everything
so yeah and there's been I mean in
Amsterdam there was a lot of internal
battle going on between seed companies
over the rights to these different lines
and most of them didn't trademark them
until it was too late but there was also
I mean we could get into some nasty
stories but there was people who broke
into you know people's grows and stole
clones and killed moms and then went and
trademarked that variety essentially or
didn't necessarily trademark the variety
that they killed but saw that there was
this opportunity and so in shyla
mentioned something really you know
relevant is that the trademark has more
value in many ways than the patent a
patent is as far as I understand very
difficult to enforce compared to a
trademark I would agree with that
although a patent can you have more
right so in terms of a trademark you can
prevent them from using your trademark
but a patent is what would allow you to
prevent them if you had a utility patent
for example you could even prevent them
from breeding with your genetics but if
you had a plant patent you couldn't
prevent that but in the case of having
stolen then you could you know certainly
that they couldn't you know use it or
continue to use it and yeah the point I
was just gonna make was that we need to
be thinking individuals if you're out
there if you're branding you're you've
actually built a brand start thinking
about trademarks now and start thinking
about that ahead of time because your
brand could become hijacked from you
like so many have before we've
experienced this the Amsterdam
experience like we all have to a certain
extent the benefit of having seen what's
happened with other crops we talked
about that earlier be it crops like
apples or in the wine in the booze
industry we also have Amsterdam and we
can look to there's a historical example
for what has happened and how to protect
ourselves now one thing I'm wondering is
that what what strategy do we have as
breeders because it it seems to me the
biggest issue is prior art and novelty
and how far do you look into the
ecosystem to prove that there is prior
art or that a varieties novel so I've
been told that the USPTO is looking
further every day that they're gaining
new tools to actually look into this
cannabis issue but it seems that it's
really just first-come first-serve at
this point yes and there's a difference
between well first you have to reek you
always have to be clear whether you're
talking about a plant patent or a
utility patent so for a plant patent
because that's only can
that's only protecting a single clone or
single genetics then there isn't much
that you need to establish in terms of
novelty in fact the fact that you have
you know produce this new clone you know
it's different it's novel it's not
existed before and so that's just
accepted and and there isn't that hurdle
when you're talking about novelty you're
really talking about utility patents and
that is the biggest hurdle right now is
because this you know we're talking
about an illegal industry there isn't a
lot of art to sell what was known in the
art before even though you know in the
culture everyone knows you know or you
probably have a lot more understanding
of what was known or you see these
patents and so you'll see companies like
biotech industries and I hate to keep
beating up on them but you know they
have this really broad patent coverage
and they were able to get it they're
able to convince an examiner at the
USPTO that this is novel and non-obvious
and they have a patent what's more
interesting is when we're going to see
if they're going to be asserted because
what happens once a patent is asserted
is that defendant gets to and typically
one of the first things they'll argue
the first two things they're gonna argue
one is that they're not infringing to
the patent is invalid
and if a defendant can invalidate a
patent in court
that's just God for everybody and so
that's one thing and I know we've talked
to IRB's not we've talked a little bit
but I've seen you talk a little bit with
Dale about the recent case law I think
it's in Colorado and one of the most
interesting things to me is is in what I
haven't seen yet and I hope to see is I
hope to see the community band around
that defendant and invalidate that
patent because it doesn't just help that
defendant as quickly this is United
right yes it doesn't just help that
defendant but it helps the community as
a whole and so I do think we're gonna
see a lot of very broad overreaching
patents
I don't our what I hope to see is I hope
to see the community band around and
help invalidate those patents you know
bring forth the prior art that we could
use to invalidate those types of patents
and then I hope that eventually we'll
see actual
it's for true innovation because there
is you know there's so many people
who've dedicated their entire lives -
you know innovating in this field and so
they deserve to be rewarded for that
innovation but right now it is a little
bit of a land grab and what they choose
to do with that we'll have to wait and
see we've already seen you know that one
that's been asserted and so my hope is
that it'll be invalidated but the other
thing that happens is you know there is
a lot going on behind the scenes as well
so they chose to pursue it in court the
other thing is to try and make everyone
pay royalties and so it isn't until you
ask someone to pay royalties and they
say no that you end up you know
typically that's how it happens you end
up in court so I in kind of one analogy
is I used to do a lot of work in the pet
Diagnostics industry and this was very
early on that I learned this is I was
doing a invalidity searched or an
invalidity opinion that I was doing a
search to see what sort of patents that
my client might be infringing on and
then I was giving an opinion on whether
you know we had a non infringement or an
invalidity position as to each of those
patents and there was one of them that
was clearly invalid it you know there
was prior art all over it and the claims
were way too broad and when I presented
it to the client clients response was
well everyone in the industry just pays
that royalty and so there is that that
can happen if people decide that it's
you know it's easier just to pay the
royalty that they're asking rather than
deal with it in court so this is the
game that's played and yeah one of the
things about IP and patents is that this
is a game that is being decided by
people that have deep pockets and it is
a patent litigation is always a
financial calculation and so for
individuals sometimes it's going to be
worth it just to pay the licensing fee
and not to pursue litigation because
you're up against a highly capitalized
firm that is going to be able to just
draw out litigation and
beat you other times there are certain
in distill it again very actively and
aggressively and it remains to be seen
one thing I would like to kind of talk
about is different models there's so
we've talked about biotech I've you've
likened it to a land grab I've likened
it to the Silicon Valley in the tech
industry there's also Philo's by Llosa's
probably why I'm sitting on the stage
right now but so they've pretty clearly
adopted a the Monsanto model they're
looking at creating a plant production
pipeline wherein they will create tons
of a sexually produced plants that they
will seek patents on and will then sell
through a licensing arrangement with
different farmers the most likely
easiest way for them to do this we all
know that they're looking at powdery
mildew resistance if they identify
genetics that have powder mildew
resistance they can take that powder
mildew resistant gene introgression into
all of the existing clone only varieties
that we have Josh deez OG the chem the
cookies etc all of the varieties that
have large market share they could then
create powder mildew resistant blah blah
blah
that is what looks to be their strategy
they've written it out they've talked
about it Mowgli's talked about this at
the AEI see which is a big biotech
conglomerate where they all get together
and share their plans that model is that
model one that is here now that
literally could be rolled out and
implemented today or is this a model
that they're looking five years down the
road where we could essentially roll
this out if we start now be ready by the
time federal prohibition ends or is this
like literally today could Philo start
pumping out tons of clone only powder
milk
resisting clone only varieties not even
genetically modified this is just
traditional breeding this is
marker-assisted back crossing so you say
here's we've demonstrated that this
genetic is powder mildew resistant
it's because of these specific markers
that it is powder mildew resistant and
now we take those markers and Trog rest
them cross them into these other
genetics and then just back cross it do
you know who's doing that work for him I
mean the actual work the actual work
no like I mean to the extent there are
people who we assume might be doing it
but we can't really say because they
won't come clean on it but you know we
we suspect that there are certain
individuals in I mean well I would say
that that possibly their intention was
to crowdsource that information that
when and this is why you know most
people have submitted samples to Philo's
myself included if it came with no chemo
tipic data no terpene analysis you know
can habit analysis it really is little
value to them for this breeding project
that they're embarking on but boy did
they I'm sure they wanted it so if
everyone who submitted a sample said oh
by the way mine is powdery mildew
resistant sure that goes searching for
that marker in that sample or looking
for a common marker within all the
people who submitted that hey - powdery
mildew resistant but most people didn't
so so it was a lost opportunity for them
that forced them to embark on their own
breeding program in order to identify
those markers because the galaxy didn't
fulfill that that goal yeah and that was
really stage 2 like the discovery
project as it's been dubbed by them was
specifically about this and I've read
the contract that they presented to
heroes of the farms and it's very clear
from that contract that they were trying
to identify powdery mildew resistant
varieties in his genetics
and they were claiming to be able to
bring others to bear now they took that
same deal to at least 16 other producers
breeders who have historically been
breeding and growing I don't know who
actually agreed to move forward with
them I know for a fact the Patrick of
heroes of the farm said no way and never
signed anything with them but that's our
concern like real talk a lot of people
are concerned about five OSes ability
not only just like to steal not steal
but crowdsource and crowdfund a whole
bunch of information and create an
opportunity across where we just put
into their system but what is the
possibility that they're going to now
take the information that they have and
build out a Monsanto type pipeline where
they're producing plants that they're
able to then get patents on is that
something they could do today absolutely
I think you know anytime that you're
creating a new clone or a new variety
then yes absolutely you can get a plant
patent but remember it is for that
specific clone so but the issue comes
with big AG in that if you're talking
about a commodities market and they can
grow it more efficiently and effectively
and produce it you know your your
genetics with you know this resistance
in it that's where the Monsanto's of the
world come from that and they did it
with genetically modified but you know
if you're saying do the same thing with
marker-assisted breeding then yes if you
have something that you know in if you
eventually get it to a stable seed loin
and you can distribute seeds and have
everybody growing this more efficiently
than anyone else
then then yes they can get patent
protection on that now as long as you're
not growing their genetics then you're
you don't have a problem from an
infringement standpoint but you
absolutely might have a problem from an
efficiency in keeping up with them
standpoint yeah no this is a big concern
the ability of the Monsanto's or large
capitalized AG they're able to bring
economies of scale and the main concern
is
that we as producers license cultivators
don't buy into the hype of efficiencies
and economies of scale but stay true to
what we've historically done selecting
the thing that may not be the largest
yield there but is the best best for our
particular needs and desires and what
we're trying to produce and create here
and so we need to recognize that while
there are companies that are going to
pursue these IP strategies we got to
develop our own responses and not not
get caught up in the hype you know and
we also need to not don't you think
they're gonna just really select for
size and yield absolutely yeah right I
mean over yeah well think about Monsanto
since we're talking about Monsanto what
was the main thing that they sold to the
world Roundup Ready Roundup Ready so it
was it was they said hey this is a seed
that can take the beating from the
pesticides and all the crap that were
the herbicides that we're gonna also
sell to you so it was a little bit of
shame on you farmer for buying that
dream a little bit and it's the same
thing with with biotech and and these
patented varieties is that if you if it
becomes the overwhelming the the the
cultivar of choice where a lot of people
bought into Monsanto's dream they said
wow I really have a problem with weeds
and I would really rather kill all these
weeds and still be able to grow my crops
where the people who didn't mind weeds
and we're growing biodynamic they're
organically didn't have any I didn't
have a an issue with it it wasn't until
the drift thing when Monsanto said oh
well some of that pollen drifted over
into your cornfield and we tested your
corn and it shows that it has our genes
in it and therefore you can't grow your
corn you know so they get bigger and
bigger and their impact becomes stronger
and stronger and they control a bigger
market share of whatever crop they're
producing but it's really resisting that
is our our strength at this point I see
it a little bit differently I think with
the Roundup Ready when you're talking
about organic farming I mean that's a
lot more expensive process to do so
unless you have
market who's gonna pay for that then
you're forced to compete so I don't
think it's necessary that the farmers
I'm sure some of them bought into the
dream but I think some of them were
forced into it just from a pure survival
standpoint like could they produce you
know their corn at the same price and
sell it and still have a profit margin
compared to all the farmers who were
selling the Roundup Ready corn and so I
mean I think that that's you know an
unfortunate reality of big AG and one of
the things that you mentioned about the
the pollen blown into the crops and I
know that something people are very
afraid of and it's something that I
looked into because I wasn't sure very
much myself but I ended up reading the
case law and where that came from was
that was actually one of the farmers
defense when they were sued by Monsanto
they said that you know the wind they
didn't know how they ended up with their
you know with this growing in their
field and that maybe it was the wind
that had blown it into their field
actually what was found out is they had
bought the seed from the back of a truck
somebody else has leftover seed and it
was something I've seen numbers between
60 and 90 percent of their crop was
Roundup Ready and that they also knew it
was Roundup Ready because they had
sprayed it and noticed it was Roundup
Ready so that's a little bit of a myth
but that is really a good point like
what we're faced with right now is a
proprietary economic model and it is a
predatory economic model so they will
try to maximize their control of the
market share and leverage their
economies of scale in ways that are
designed to try and push us out and so
we need to be able to bring our own IP
strategies to bear and part of that's
going to be pursuing trademarks for our
brands some of that's going to be in
certain instances when it's appropriate
people pursuing plant variety protection
and patent protection another version of
IP protection that I'm not sure how well
you versed on it but I know that
appellations of origin or something that
the state has mandated for us to create
California is going to create a Palacios
for cannabis and they're mandated to do
so by January 1st of 2021 licensed
cultivators will be able to submit
applications laying out standards
practices and varietals that are grown
within a particular region that can
apply for appellation standards or
status and you'll be able to essentially
apply a sticker to your plant there to
your products and say this was produced
here under these standards these
practices and with these varietals and
this is a Palacios are a form of
intellectual property they're a
collective form of intellectual property
and so this is something that we can
everybody needs to look in to read up on
it check it out get with licensed
cultivators in your own area and start
thinking about these things and start
thinking about them in a way where what
are the standards the practices and the
cultivars that are unique to your place
what are the outcomes that are unique to
your place because I know where I'm at
we have a very unique environment that
is very distinct from up in Mendo or
humble or in other areas because we're
more inland it's much drier much hotter
much more arid environment their unique
outcomes and results so if I grow a
cultivar in my County or in my hillside
it's going to be way different than that
same cultivar grown up and humbled and
this is something that could be very
unique we could have people essentially
saying okay Calaveras County we grow og
and the og ends up like this over an
Mendo they grow the same cultivar but it
ends up expressing differently
we're both protecting the intellectual
property and the specific product that
we're producing that's unique to our
areas and even though we're both calling
it og it's different and it's different
because of the environmental inputs that
you know I mean we all know the fee note
types are an interaction between the
gene and the environment and those
environmental factors are going to
produce unique distinct intellectual
properties and product properties that
we can hopefully protect and this is
something it's going to be rolled out by
2021 we can start to organize around
these ideas now and start to develop
this is a more of a communal or
collective form of intellectual property
so we've got individual corporate
strategies if you've got a business
start thinking about trademarks start
thinking about patents start thinking
about the implications that it has for
you for better and for worse and also
start thinking about linking up with
fellow cultivators in your area to
develop an appalachia system and I'm not
as familiar with that but it sounds to
me like a trademark type protection so
that would be like a certification mark
we're only in again trademarks identify
the source of the goods so that would
identify the source is coming from this
one specific region a lot like
champagnes or even tequila is regulated
now and so no I was the one who
introduced Dale to tequila and set the
record straight it was interesting you
may both appellation because the
challenge with an appellation is that it
can limit what you can do so let's let's
remember that that like for instance you
mentioned champagne
what is champagne champagne is Pinot
Noir or Chardonnay grapes grown in
Champagne period that's it same with
Bordeaux Bordeaux is I believe Cabernet
Merlot Petit Verdot and one other great
so if you want to grow an Italian
varietal in Bordeaux France you cannot
call it Bordeaux you can call it
Sangiovese but no one's gonna buy it
so Bordeaux the Bordeaux wine makers and
the begonia winemaker Association got
together and mandated what can be grown
in this appellation so it can go the
wrong way when big win big
corporate interest get in there and say
no we're trying to protect this
appellation and this is can only be
ground here and it's the variety the
variety that we happen to own that's
absolutely true one good thing about
this system is that it is driven by the
licensees so licensees it's a form of
local control that we have it's probably
the only decent form of local control
that came out of prop 64 so if you are a
local licensed cultivator definitely be
thinking about this and get out there in
front because all of these IP strategies
all across the board have risks and
benefits there are ways that this could
protect people in the industry and there
are ways that it could be used by other
capitalized interests that are trying to
push all of us out and so we definitely
we got to take hold of the tools that
are at our disposal and make sure that
we're in there playing the game and not
just getting pushed out but the
appellation it seems like what it would
do is prevent let's say somebody from
New Jersey saying that they are growing
you know weed from here but I don't see
the protection in the form of making
sure that your genetics your particular
genetics are protected and so it is a
form of IP it is a trademark right and
so in that sense it absolutely is but I
don't see it offering the full
protection in terms of actually
protecting your clones and actually
protecting your life's work and what
you're what you're doing and in that
regard what I hope to see and maybe that
will be part of it is I hope to see
communities start to pull together their
patents and their IP and you've seen
this in other industries where you know
they will pool patents either that
there's two different forms of it either
that you're all gonna allow each other
to use each other's technology without
the threat of of having this these
patents asserted against them so
everybody brings their patents to the
table puts them in the middle and
everybody has access to that you know
the other form of it you know in terms
of you can use all of this patented
technology the other form is everybody
puts their patents together in terms of
defending against a lawsuit so we agree
you know the four of us agree if any of
us get sued
you can use my patents his patents you
know and because the best thing to do
when you get sued is to have have a
counter defense to be able to counter
just quickly where have you seen these
two strategies played out so if you look
at like Android technology for example
the way that they've been able to build
that platform is they allow everybody
from Google to LG to Samsung to Oh to
use their you know the different patents
they all pull their patents together so
they can all build on that platform and
so you know there's a difference though
with with software and that software
comes with its own IP software's
protected as soon as you write your
program it's got copyright protection
attached to it you can do anything to
get the copyright or protection you
should register it but you don't have to
it's a little bit tougher in the
Cannabis scenario where you would
actually have to file and get patent
protection or your your plant breeders
rights attached to it but then you would
then agree to share that but that you
know it's done in others but that's the
most familiar one that I can think of
off the top of my head when we're
talking about patents and these sorts of
IP strategies what type of costs are we
talking about are we is it even viable
for somebody like myself to consider
pursuing a patent and break that down
both in terms of the application process
and also in terms of the defense or the
prosecution right so in prosecution I
know to file a plant patent I would
ballpark that around $2,500 just to file
and that's to have the description in
order and every way that you need it you
know obviously the person that you hire
who's more experienced is going to be
able to write it more thoroughly and
correctly in a way that you shouldn't
expect as many office actions and not
make you know typical mistakes that I'm
seen in some of these patent patent
applications that are being filed plant
patent in particular so that's for a
plant patent and then in terms of
prosecuting it you know getting it from
your original filing all the way through
I asked Dale because he does more plant
than I do actually I don't do any I
refer them to him I do trademarks and so
he ballparked it I want to say around
$10,000 is what you're looking at over
the course of obtaining the protection
which could take a few years trademarks
is a little bit less expensive I
typically encourage everyone to do a
thorough search before they file for
their trademark protection and that's
because trademarks you have common law
rights as soon as you start to use a
trademark so if I'm using a trademark
here in California someone in Florida
decides to file their trademark
application for that same mark
I still have common law rights as far as
I've used it and established that
trademark they can't shut me down just
because they've now filed and so
particularly in this industry where I
see everybody using the same marks which
by the way don't like let's just start
using more original marks and so in in
that way you know I do encourage doing a
full search so that you're aware of what
are the common law rights that somebody
else might have even though you get
federal protection where are you gonna
be limited from using your mark or where
are you not going to be able to shut
down this mom-and-pop shop who's been
using it since you know 1980 so if you
were to get the full search and the
trademark application you're looking
again at about $2,000 to file a
trademark application for a single class
of goods and that includes the USPTO
fees and then if you've done your search
and you don't get these more substantive
rejections in terms of finding marks
that are confusingly similar then
there's only a couple other time points
where you need to spend you know an
another three hundred five hundred its
so I would say probably just ballparking
three thousand four thousand to get a
trademark if it goes through cleanly
utility patents much more expensive it's
a much more thorough disclosure you
don't have opportunities to amend the
way that you do with a plant patents so
everything has to be done right from the
outset so utility patents you can get
depending
on what your disclosure is what your
technology is how broadly you want to
claim it if you wanted to just claim
your deposit that's obviously gonna be
less work than trying to claim some
broad formulation and so that can range
in terms of filing I would say again
probably starting up to 3,000 and I've
seen patents just for drafting a patent
application go up to the ten fifteen
thousand dollars to draft a patent
application copyrights much less
expensive you can do it yourself if you
care to go through all the tedious
screens on the copyright registration
portal or whatever what you have you and
I think it's $55 to register your
copyright so some of your more priced
pictures your videos I've seen people
getting very creative with how they're
advertising their genetics like you know
register you're more important stuff for
copyright protection and then I think I
saw Dale quote the plant variety
protection I think he said something
about it's fifty one hundred dollars
just in the filing fees alone so it's
not inexpensive so so just quickly
because we have a band that has to set
up for the people for the two people on
the stage who have unique genetics
what's your strategy for protecting your
intellectual property and well my
strategy was to not share was was to I
mean I started breeding sage in 1994 in
Amsterdam and I you know was just a
young guy living overseas and plenty of
people offered me money for cuts over
and over again seed banks traveling
American cultivators and I turned him
down over and over again over and over
and over again and the few people that I
did give plants that were very
explicitly told not to share them that
this was a backup that I need you to
hold on and and it one of my varieties
got out because someone stole it as
simple as that someone stole it out of
the grow room and sold it to another
group and that group sold it to another
group and
so it's it's trade secrets it's
protecting your trade secrets by not
letting him go and since that happened a
number of years ago I have held plants
even closer to the chest than before and
that there's some some varieties that I
think people should be enjoying that I
haven't let out yet because I didn't
have a robust tool to protect them
because it's not just the physical
security that they require in a facility
but its ability to go out into the
ecosystem and make sure that other
people aren't utilizing your plants so
yeah that's what I'm doing and waiting
to do great things in the future as much
as that could say yeah for me it's
different I didn't create OG but really
more importantly I think everybody
should grow oh gee like as a variety in
their garden right so that would make me
you know more happy than anything right
now is if it just ended up all over the
country all over the world and everybody
you know had a piece of their farm
growing it right nobody should get a cut
for that that's ridiculous but in the
future I mean then the other side of it
is like holy shit I better I better
think about this cuz I'm gonna be paying
a lot of money in licensing fees right
and that's that's just the irony right
now but you know so of course we're
looking into it you know it's a it's a
strange thing but I mean I just don't
for me it's hard to come to terms with
this but we're gonna do some breeding
projects in the future I mean for me
it's all about the future you know you
know and then we'll talk about patenting
something that is actually something we
created you know Pat going out to like
we're gonna go to a clone shop somebody
with some cash we're gonna buy likes our
D all these things are just gonna Pat
and everything spend like a billion
dollars like I'm just gonna patent the
whole library everything out there yeah
that's and that is the reality also
since I mean we talk about Philo's
earlier and like Philo says is kind of
you know they're the bad guy right now
because they came from our community
but the reality is is all these plants
are in there are in the ecosystem
they're all available at a shop or in
seat for him anyone can go online and
buy all the most amazing seed and they
can go to shops all over California and
get all the most amazing buds and you
can buy clones so yeah we're we it is
about the future because up until this
moment we were working under a different
umbrella and now we're working in a
totally different world and we're
structuring things differently
breeding trademarks patents everything
but the past is the past
you know and Philo's kind of speak spoke
to that in a way and you know they were
the bad guy because they were from us
but everyone's doing the same thing you
know there's there's biotech companies
all around the world and pharmaceutical
companies all around the world and
people who go into the rainforest to
exploit you know whatever they can get
their hands on you know so that's that's
the world we live in and with that I'm
told that the band that's gonna rock the
house from 9 p.m. on needs to get on
stage so thank you
[Applause]
thank you I've been doing IP law for 17
years now and I was in the biotech
industry not biotech industries ll see
the actual biotech industry in for 14
years prosecuting pets for cancer
immunology therapies and buying that
came to cannabis via canna kids
Tracy Ryan and Sophie Ryan I began
following them as part of my passion of
finding a cure for cancer and became so
intrigued and inspired by what they were
doing that found myself all the way into
the cannabis industry and in January
this year decided to start my own firm
because one of the hurdles I was facing
as a big law attorney was the
limitations that my friend was placing
on me about whether or not they wanted
to have cannabis clients and so that's a
little bit about my background but in
terms of what I do so I had a I had to
share in practice many of you might know
Dale hunt Dale and I had a practice
together and so we've done biotech plant
patents AG patents
green tech and then I also do trademarks
and copyrights and we've also done trade
secrets so that's a little bit by way of
background