[Music]
Brian Chaplin founder of medicine box we
make mindful medicine through the wisdom
of cannabis our product is a tincture
that's a sleep elixir by the name of
equanimity my definition of equanimity
is remaining cool calm collected when a
person place or thing is triggering me
and everyone has a different
representation of what equanimity means
them in the scientific world we hear
homeostasis or equilibrium this
particular product that we make has
blended with chamomile lemon balm catnip
skullcap musa acuminata which is a
vitamin b6 and tryptophan so tryptophan
converts your serotonin while you sleep
and then we blend that with a specific
cultivar that's grown out of Nevada
County California we have a local co-op
in Nevada County Sun grown Cirrus Sun
grown co-op they have 45,000 square feet
of canopy space and in Nevada County the
maximum square footage of canopy is
10,000 square feet so all very craft
boutique artisanal farmers born and
raised
men of medicine boxes values as
collaboration with our community so we
are providing them with our specific
genetics we provide the genetics as the
brand to the to the polite to the coop
where are you
those genetics have been passed down
through the wisdom of cannabis in Nevada
County okay yeah it's a specific
cultivar that landed up on the North San
Juan Ridge around 1974 it does it was
yeah there was a so yeah we use full
spectrum extract and we blend that with
the other synergistic girls that makes
make makes a very very potent sleep
elixir so the concoction was created
just really following the mission and
that intuitive guidance of Medicine box
which is blending science with the
practical wisdom of cannabis when I say
practical wisdom that's all the
anecdotal experience and the knowledge
that's been passed down way before prop
60 for 40 50 60 years thousands of years
with indigenous cultures and that
knowledge has been consistently passed
down and we all know experience turns
into knowledge knowledge turns into
wisdom
so we're blending the science and the
wisdom of cannabis with our cannabis
culture absolutely absolutely so the
amount of R&amp;D that we've done has been
it's been a couple years I brought on a
PhD plant scientist from Israel to help
formulate and this isn't just throwing a
bunch of herbs and some you know
full-spectrum cannabis in a pot mixing
it up over grandma stove this was actual
specific ratios and combinations of the
herbs and their absorption rates and
then a lot of experience all data that
we've
and handing out to people as we know
there is no real blanket umbrella
approach to treating people or helping
them sleep everyone has a little bit of
different experience as I like to say
every body is different and everybody is
different it's not a one size fits all
so there will be that variation on a
little bit of trial and error to figure
out what dose properly works for you
and it might take 2-3 times but again
back to that mission statement is
mindful medicine through the wisdom of
cannabis a tincture would be sublingual
okay we prefer to use a sublingual as
dosed by one dropper is 10 milligrams
okay 10 milligram between 5 and 10
milligrams
what the majority of our consumers or
patients that have taken that find that
between 5 and 10 milligrams is the
optimal dose for sleep anything under
that between 1 and 3 milligrams as a
micro dose can really help calm the
central nervous system during the day
and you're not going to get drowsy
anything over that 3 to 5 milligram
threshold you may as well sit down and
take a siesta
we're selling sleep we're not really
selling the tincture we're selling sleep
but anxiety as a sleepless life I sleep
it is that the anxiety is a sleepless
person's worst nightmare pun intended
they go hand in hand it's like staying
in the beach things people with riddled
with anxiety ruminate on their thoughts
when they lay in bed they can't sleep
they don't they don't get a good night's
rest the next day they're filled with
anxiety cognitive functions off their
homeostasis is off they're not in
equanimity when we're in equanimity we
show up for ourselves we show up for our
loved ones we show up for our business
partners
if an employer is selling academic I'm
selling equanimity huh and some and for
me equanimity was my mentors this is a
really good piece of culture here
my mentor Michael Hollister god bless
him he passed away with cancer last year
he was 52 years in the cannabis industry
as a breeder and medicine maker and he
passed down a lot of his wisdom to me
which I was able to formulate and then
take like Frodo Baggins and some Mordor
right and to Mordor with what the
industry is Mordor right now and I feel
like Frodo Baggins and be able to really
blend the science with that so I owe a
lot to him
and that's part of that wisdom of
cannabis that's been passed down and it
helped me personally as the founder I'm
a recovering alcoholic drug addict that
celebrated seven years of sobriety on
the 9th of September and my physician
prescribed me an SSRI two years in peaks
and valleys peaks and valleys a little
SSRI by the name Prozac I didn't know
any better I was on Prozac for about a
year and a half and my mentor and I used
this blend of equanimity and another CBD
high CBD ratio blend that we'll be
bringing into market next year in
combination to transition me off of
SSRIs CBD isolate verse coal plant
completely different beasts Copeland as
a full spectrum blend furthering the
science behind this
is this massive trend CBD ghetto right
coming from hemp with all this deceptive
marketing practices full-spectrum
isolate full-spectrum hemp 300
milligrams of cannabinoids hold on 300
milligrams of cannabinoids is clurel CBD
isolate is singular compound all right
so whole plant medicine when I say whole
plant we don't use the trim we use the
whole flower we use the tops of
sun-grown
flower and soil Sun and water we use the
tops so we get the full spectrum range
of cannabinoids and terpenoids
there is one particular genetic that has
a beautiful combination now I'll get
into some combinations of specific
terpenes mercele in a little visible
abetik roughly it also has a nice ratio
of CBN CBN in combination with THC is an
extremely effective sedative two and a
half to five milligrams a CBN see pill
labs of the study is as effective as 5
to 10 milligrams of diazepam all right
however the rare cannabinoids have to be
in combination together for them to
effectively work so let's go back to the
CBD isolate ghetto first the whole plant
okay CBD just take CBD in your your all
your problems will go away
no no CBD
is an antagonist which means it does it
only binds your cb1 receptor THC is an
agonist which activates your cb1
receptor THC the cannabinoid that Co
mingles with your synapses your
presynaptic and your postsynaptic
actually acts as a key and unlocks your
cb1 receptor or in laymen terms
it's the lubricant I like to say tea a
little bit of teach see is the lubricant
to unlock that cb1 receptor so all the
other cannabinoids and herbs and terpene
profile can come in and work its magic
in your endocannabinoid system cb1
receptor as your central nervous system
that helps regulate your sleep your mood
and bring you back into homeostasis or
equanimity
I like to live my life in like Venn
diagrams a little bit so let's take a
simple Venn diagram here's the cannabis
industry but over 20 billion by 2022
here's the sleep industry right here
here's a cross over sleep industries 50
billion plus the same year our product
sleep industry anywhere from mattresses
apps on your phone
white noise makers fans bedding curtains
noisemakers herbal things essential oils
anything like that sleep it's an
epidemic right now we live the lack of
sleep is an academic which translates
into more anxiety more anxiety
translates into lack of sleep
it's a bitches cycle and then as an
entrepreneur in the cannabis space
there's too many pressures and there's
too many people places and things that
knock us off balance so again the very
thing that we're all going for in the
cannabis industry we forget it's the
very thing that can help us and that's
what I'm all about being of service to
others and helping people have a more
holistic lifestyle through practical
wisdom that's it and if people are
getting off they're ambience and they're
prozac's and there's olaf's and there's
annexes at the same time we're winning
we're all winning okay
ambien is a hypnotic so you don't get in
that REM you need to get into your REM
sleep so you dream right when we dream
we create
Google was created through a dream how
many great inventions are created from
dreaming and sleep sleep is something
that people it's an afterthought right
like let's look through the lens of
sleep and wellness and that's what
that's what medicine Marx is doing with
this very niche product the amount of
people that I know that don't know how
to sleep well are looking for solutions
right they don't want to be on ambien
right my my friend's grandmother was
trying to get off ambien and is using
this product to help with that okay I
want to get back to the euphoria with
teeth you asked about the you forum glad
you asked about that again that's like
the let's use the spoonful of sugar
analogy again okay and not CBD but THC
if you just take THC alone or just we
know it as distill it right you were
going to get high all right we don't use
distiller distill it you take everything
out of that to get the THC and it's not
about getting high
it's about getting well okay a little
bit of euphoria we don't need to be
scared about people don't need to be
scared about a little bit of euphoria
are you that you for a phobia that's
going on CBD good it doesn't get you
high THC bad it gets you high no it's
not CBD verse THC it's CBD in THC they
are friends okay a little bit of THC in
our product it's actually it's actually
the highest concentration concentrated
cannabinoid in this specific product but
it works well with the CBD the CBG and
the CBN
and when you're sleeping again let's
think about like when we were children
right we're just called big kids right
our mom or dad or someone or grandmother
on they would lullaby us to sleep
what's THC do a little bit of THC gives
you a little bit of that euphoria
that's a lullaby it's a lullaby THC is a
little let's not be scared or euphoric
feeling and again CBD is psychotropic
anything that changes your brain can
chemistry is considered psychotropic so
there's a lot of that to set the
marketing going out there and CBD
doesn't help you sleep CBD does there's
there's being marketed and sold as sleep
CBD is more of a stimulating cannabinoid
then and that does not help you sleep
it's it's it's a it's contradictory so
CBD isolate blended with a little
lavender and they can say it helps with
sleep that to me is a very lackluster
generic shit product and it could help
you sleep and the specific cultivar that
we use as it is in indica and it is bred
from Afghan indica that came from India
in 1972 that's the wisdom of cannabis
right there and the wisdom of cannabis
also has open source I mean these
breeders they they worked these seeds up
and down the coast of California up to
British Columbia down to Mexico and just
like wines have specific Appalachians
those specific that's landrace genetic
adapted to those Appalachians to those
Roma condition
there and Grass Valley in Nevada County
the elevation that is at between 1200
from the valley floor up to 3000 feet
the amount of sun exposure that we get
hot hot hot summers mild wet winters
just like the Mediterranean climate
it grows specifically well there so we
use a localized cultivar and a local
manufactured product that is distributed
throughout the state
no one ever said this was going to be
easy you know and getting getting
medicine to people that don't even know
they need medicine it's been it's been
really rewarding it's been stressful I
use my own product
the politics of Grass Valley I have to
give a shout out to the avada County
cannabis Alliance I was a former board
member there there in 2016 there is a
full-on ban on cannabis cultivation in
that kind of a measure w the Nevada
County cannabis Alliance was formed to
overturn that ban and within two years
we voted in a new ordinance okay there
are now 11 licensed cultivators in
Nevada County in about a city which is a
municipality of the greater County as a
dispensary elevation to 477 and we're in
that shop there is
there you go
good to see you this Nevada city has
adopted all license types throughout the
whole supply chain we got two new
supervisors but we got a new sheriff
Keith royal that's been raining down his
propaganda and stigmatization an anti
cannabis crusade against Nevada County
is finally out we have a much more
progressive female shannon moon hi
Shannon
I am I live in Lake North Lake Tahoe but
I I own real estate in Nevada County and
our base of operations is their base of
operations is in Nevada County the
source of inspiration is in Tahoe and I
blend those together how people buy your
products if there is if you like what
you hear and there's a local dispensary
that you want us to be featured in let's
just do some grassroots cannibal good
old cannabis culture marketing you can
find us my Instagram is underscore Brian
Chaplin that's a lot of my personal
lifestyle educational books and our
company is medicine underscore box
website medicine box green and keep an
eye out by the end of the year for a
podcast that we're doing and we'll be
talking about a lot of this and all this
practical wisdom and holistic lifestyle
we do yeah and the reason why we didn't
go with multiple products I really
wanted to focus in and laser in on that
niche again we're selling sleep we're
not selling cannabis or a tincture we're
selling sleep cannabis is really that
evolving medium that weaves it all
together and medicine box
it's a binder you know it's like
cannabis is the is that thread that
pulls it all together and it's not just
the herbs
it's it's a lifestyle so medicine box
really is what's in your box of Medicine
what is if you opened up your tool box
and dumped it at your feet what are
those tools that you use to heal
yourself or stay whole or in equanimity
day to day my initial calling are the
vision for medicine box was that the
majority of human beings across the
globe would replace the traditional
contents of their medicine cabinets with
the cannabis health and wellness
supplement or sit and meditate or do
Qigong or walk in nature or be an
advocate for the plan right or recover
from drugs alcohol harmful relationships
physical you know all of it hold it it's
a it's a it's a holistic lifestyle and
that is the that's the truth that we're
really trying to bring to the table and
yeah you can say cannabis helps you
sleep but again like is it smoking a
joint taking a bong hit
taking a DAB rubbing a topical eating a
Nevel what what is the specific product
that's really going to make an effect on
a wide range of people and that's a
product that we created i've bootstrap
this whole venture and I'll continue
bootstrapping it and we finally it's
like you make it to the next level to
the next level to the next level
celebrate those mini triumphs and get to
that big win right
we finally have a fully licensed
compliant product through a licensed
manufacturing facility in Nevada City we
did a 5,000 unit
right very attractive product very
attractive brand got brought on to a
distributor in Santa Rosa through a
friend in the cannabis industry and an
associate that I built a relationship
with again the alignment was there the
mission the values were there very
gravitated towards the product signed us
on after a 30-day negotiation okay they
represent 150 stores astronomical
service fee for distribution hey it's a
pay-to-play they have the relationships
you know you're gonna get us get us in a
tenant 1020 percent of those stores by
the end of q4 I'm good with that I don't
need to be in all of them six weeks
two stores in six weeks so enter turmoil
and conflict with the internal startup
team and the Canadian food company that
acquired them before I knew they had
Canadian funding I didn't know the
details of all of that everything's
really warm and fuzzy and chummy and
we're negotiating we're doing a good
great job negotiating doing our due
diligence 5,000 units that was our
proof-of-concept run they have a full
sales team bulla Geist --ax they carry
several other internal brands we are a
third party brand okay so as a third
party brand we kind of just stood alone
on the side street right and Canadian
company trying to run a California
cannabis company without giving
themselves the proper time to understand
the principles and personalities of
California cannabis okay and I can have
some compassion
but then my patience runs dry okay so
what happened getting any company
acquires and starts pushing around the
internal startup scene what's happening
over here
one year one year one year yeah we say
one year but the the fractionated
coconut oil acts as a preservative
anybody can sit they can't sit for two
years my brain can't sit for two years
I need be make important momentum
involving okay so a lot of drama
happened in the airdrome royal inner
turmoil for timing but what did it do a
little bit of chaos bomb as enough
entrepreneur and keep you on your toes
and we're pivoting and we're maneuvering
and we'll see what happens
we negotiated non-exclusivity that's
what took 30 days so we can go with
another distributor and any seeing
localize what I've learned through the
process is seeing localized in your
local community as part of our value and
teaming up together
yeah yeah it's turbulence you know it's
like we sat on the runway for 30 days
negotiating right we finally take off
the runway and we hit this momentum but
we expend we have experienced turbulence
and we haven't even hit cruising
altitude yet the original person that
brought me in was their global brand
manager and the CEO of the acquiring
company fired him because he was
speaking up on behalf of the brand that
he brought in on customer service so
instead of sitting down like that so
much that
I'm my control saying saying in
equanimity the best I can write and
trying to preserve the relationships
that I have and I just saw the CEO of
that company and I looked him in the
eyes and I said through this whole
process it's humbled me and I realized I
wouldn't trade my problems for your
problems right now and we can hug it out
because we're homies and we came from
the underground world the cannabis and
there's not going to be any hard
feelings so but this the guy who sold
his company yeah
and he's he's working hard at leveling
the playing field with it with his
startup team and the kidney and the
Canadians so I learned a lot through
that process but what did it do it
toughened me up and it made me realize
that I can be in control of my own
destiny
oh yeah one of my best friend's his his
babe is an extract company his
distributor yeah
it's happening the distributors are
trying to push out the little guys and
it's it's a it's a tactic like let's
annoy them let's shadow band now let's
not give them the customer service
representation that they deserve and
hopefully they get so frustrated that
they just quit I'm not gonna quit you're
not gonna see me quit
I am yeah or sit down it's all out on
the table now I do it's part of that
yeah we have representation in their
booth and I'm also here to network and
do this I've been talking to some other
distributors yeah and it'll be by the
time this comes out well I think all the
distributors came in and realized you
know let's get the distribution license
let's try to control the supply chain
let's make all the money right let's we
don't care about bringing on brands in
my opinion Hall of flowers is here to
showcase brands ultimately brands will
have all the equity and the cannabis
space distributors need brands just as
much as brands need distributors and
brands also need a supply healthy supply
chain retailers and the retailers you
know they're the end of the supply chain
they need brands to and I wholeheartedly
believe in my mind in my heart that the
retailers and five years will be the
wooby wellness dispensaries it's where
people can go to get a high end value
based product like the one that we make
flower concentrates that ocean
marketplace of commodity
they'll they'll there will be a clear
contrast of those dispensaries you know
I'm here in dispensaries that have 1200
SKUs that's it that's like Trader Joe's
that's Whole Foods
you know so finding and aligning with
retail spaces that have it you know the
niche products we aren't I always say
stay in your lane
that's CBD Brian you need to do a CBD
frog no no that's a different Lane I
call it the whole plant medicine lane or
the intuitive highway I just follow my
gut and sometimes I think we might be a
little bit too far ahead of the
oversaturated flowers and pre-rolls in
faiths and gummies
it could be a disaster so we're working
it out and you know no and I and in the
best product we have is the brand itself
I just want people to understand to get
people how to think what is medicine to
them
it's all logistics and I'm very grateful
for my associates and my co-founder to
stay back in Nevada County today to sit
and have a two-hour meeting with our
manufacturing Alliance and I'm here
doing this we did one run and then we're
going to do another 10,000 unit run now
it's all about doing sales yeah