[Music]
yeah exactly that's a sybian same with
his Jamaican stuff that you get in
England and they would call it sense
Amelia
you know sensi yeah and it was like this
door you know like probably a really
good indica grown high in a cold
altitude well I can we as kids in
England we'd get like Hydra we'd grown
in Amsterdam and get you high but this
stuff would obliterate you and we would
pay a lot for a little Graham good
what's going on now I know it was a CB n
the whole time VPN is the culprit my
love of hashes TPN you know it's I
really come to appreciate that kind of
annoying stall of them ya know you hit
on the head if I didn't have a thousand
milligrams of tincture in me right now
no that is the thing you know yeah for
anybody suffering from anxiety or
anything like that
see it's EPS so I take the brick press
and I heat it in a natural process just
using boiling water I was talking about
that that around paddy know so starting
materials raw so that's been pressed
already in a different press but
starting material is exactly this it's a
raw material this has never been pressed
or heated so this is a cold extract
product this would be non activated yeah
completely moms in a carboxyl so that is
non psychoactive it know you could eat
this right now and a little bit
psychoactive but but not not super high
levels the minute you add heat in this
process or any pressing process you're
converting in decarboxylate in so then
you've been making it you're essentially
taking off that carbon molecule to make
it bioavailable and then this process
you're just applying about three
for tons of pressure and a heated square
mold it has about 120 grams in it and
you just leave it for about 10 minutes
so the heat can really you know it
really activated I mean you know what
everyone loves about hash does that
activate in principle love it so I like
to leave it about 10 minutes and then
you get it on you get a really nice
break and it's very reminiscent of the
Moroccan style of pressing off it so
anybody that's from that part of the
world or anybody who ever smoked hash in
Europe when they see a brick like this
sliced up they all of a sudden get that
nostalgic little moment of oh shit I
remember that from Amsterdam it's a very
manual process does it need to be are
they're automated I mean it doesn't need
to be I'm not exactly sure how how
automated you could make it to the
beauty of all of this stuff from my from
from my point of view one of the
beauties is you guys is the fact that it
is artisanal and the scalability is
limited yeah you know but yeah I'm sure
yeah I always imagined in my head
because the temple ball process is very
very laborious which is part of the
beauty of it right you're putting all
that intention into it so you know we
could even get spiritual yeah but let's
forget that for a second it's laborious
and I've always thought you know what
kind of machine could you make and it
would kind of be like you would
basically have to replicate the
intestinal tract of a rabbit because all
you need is little poop balls inside and
you put the hatch in one end and the
other end to get little footballs so be
a machine like that like is a gram the
ideal like you know sailing a selling
point for because I'm not you know to me
it's like you know let's call BCC and
tell ya one of the biggest reasons we
are restricted to a gram is because
we're not allowed as a manufacturer of
extracts to exceed a thousand milligrams
in our total dosage gotcha so yeah our
products were now ranging between 600
and 700 total milligrams so you know
maybe we could do one at one point two
grams but
that would be kind of weird so that's
kind of why we're there no extract
whether it's oil
whether it's butane hexane alcohol
anything can exceed the thousand
milligrams in fact it goes with
tinctures as well so you're talking
about this size so nobody can make like
a big bowl you know but the cool things
you can do and what we're gonna start
experimenting with is like mixing so
when you have the traditional carrying
method you get to certain darker types
yeah and then use the vacuum freezer you
get a very blond one yeah so what I want
to do and again the blonde one will have
a lot less CBN naturally yeah there's
just part of that natural curing process
you're getting the CBN but putting that
aside for a second what I want to do is
I want to then braid the two different
distinct colors together and then cut
them so you'll end up with like a sort
of like a floral really uh what is
something different but when you think
about it you can buy as many of these or
pretty much as I mean you can buy two or
three of these different grams so it
makes no sense for you to not be able to
sell a two and a three not brand baller
job whatever attendant yeah no one's
good things like rosin especially that
you know in dabbled products I mean I
know there's a lot of people out there
who would love that and they got used to
that you know be shame or the BCC you
know lordy more closer because it's
across the street yeah I'm gonna do that
I'll be right back
exactly I mean not exactly
the brigade's trick in the California
equivalent the difference the only
biggest difference is the fact that
they're using a dry sift product to
start with and we're using a cold water
extracted product to start right now the
pressing process exactly the same and
that's what you got yeah and you get a
break a chain and this one didn't come
out as homogenized as I would like so I
would probably France and Spain I mean
when we're kids in Spain when we were
lucky we would smoke brick - because the
alternative was what we would call Babu
ha which says bubble and what bubble
refers to is the 2 or level and that was
the type of hash that was routinely
smuggled into the country using ingested
means so they would ingest it in pellets
and then they went of course have to
wait till they came up the other end now
as a consumer you know and they've done
tests in and you know modern times in
fact a few years ago and over 85 or 86
percent of all hash in Madrid had you
know e coli and feces in it so you know
there was that and it did smell like
shit
when we were lucky we had the brick hash
but usually we had to a sash but that
was growing up in Spain for you we did
not complain we did not complain exactly
at this point I would probably know if
this was perfect which it isn't
I would probably freeze dry it or me not
freeze-dried sorry vacuum seal it and
then and then keep it in a in a nice
environment where you can cure up but
you know just a little house for easy
packaging and then a consumers like it
so sorry show show me the grabbed Apple
oh I'm coming too
that's the starting material and that's
the end product and the break and we can
even do a nice little slice of the brick
which is always fun to do and so so the
oh my guess not decarboxylated no it's
not it's all THC a and then what about
the brick obviously it's all THC you
mean just that process decarboxylated
the whole thing um in this regard
probably yeah most of it I mean you're
adding a lot of heat there's 300 degrees
in there I'm sorry so those so those
plates because I missed the first part
you basically boiled the plates yes sir
and then that gets the ones gets a
boiling point then you can make probably
three or four bricks from it before it
cools before it cools down yes you know
definitely the science of it is more
tradition than science but this was the
traditionally now what we do for our
purposes at Cali hash is we don't
actually use this method at all we use a
temple balling method where the raw
material is taken by each person and
it's you know per gram uniquely pressed
by each hash machine each person yeah so
they would start with a product like
this and then you would take a gram
worth you put in the palm of your hand
with gloves obviously and then apply
heat and pressure and a motion like this
I don't overdo hard and do it sit sit on
that out yeah all right pressing hash
and nice somewhere we can cut this break
yeah this would be the traditional
method so here you go you have more or
less a gram you would put it in and this
is very traditional because obviously in
the hubbub all originates from Nepal and
in the Asian continent so traditionally
they would take a chunk and then they
would literally did exactly what we're
doing and then once you get it into a
into a homogenized or slightly
modernized state and you can go like
this you start doing them this motion
and this is really the magic and then
you know if you want to get spiritual
with it yet you think a little bit about
good things and you hope and all those
good intentions get translated into your
your ball of hash and really the best
balls are made with you know quite a lot
of pressure and the guys should get
really good at this you know get get
calluses and you know we're doing 200
these a day you end up really uh you
know exerting yourself and there you end
up with the temple ball it's essentially
it and then the temple ball is uh it's
probably the the main way we produce you
know all of our press material more and
more we're going to start doing Moroccan
style we're just having gotten
rocket style would be this brick okay so
essentially you're seeing two different
press methods by urine and then you
break that into one gram yeah then the
break you would cut it into skin six
quarters right now actually we just
released purple cream to the market and
that's an example of that process has
brick as brick and then cut into grim
squares sorry so you said the brick is
more Moroccan so what's the tempo ball
nepalese whole area those temples but
again traditionally they're not using
water and ice to get their extraction
they're using dry sis so they're getting
the freshest trichomes off the plant and
then pressing them as quickly and
especially as they can
whereas we use cold water and ice to
extract a man sitting process and then
we press that process product so that's
just a slight difference I think they
already are and this plate technique and
you know and I wish there was a up to
speed on exactly what that is I'm not
but I've been hearing rumblings about
this new technique called the plate
technique and I mean I'm assuming it's
dry sip on the large plate with heat or
something and you know allows you to
probably do it more quickly or amounts
but you know the problem with the cold
water extraction is you have to make by
so you take the break out ya little
break I mean this hatch wasn't it very
oily - you can already see this is a
much earlier for much much much well you
know and that's determined by the wrist
this is a cure product this has been
caring for a month I have a massive
amount of the people who won butter
products is just butter it's still 70
percent yeah yeah yeah they're sure it's
just been but yeah I don't I don't and
it's funny because now I have all these
traditional Arabs from Saudi Arabia and
now they're getting used to this
buttered stuff because the reality is
and you see right now I can exemplify it
perfectly as reality is when it butters
as opposed to a super oily product it's
really easy to distribute into whatever
ya whatever method you're trying to
distribute so imagine if I buy this gram
for example from Cali hash and I'm a
tobacco smoker of hash right if I had
this temple ball I gotta sit there for
him buy this and just crumble it and
it's buttered and it has 600 600
milligrams of categories just like the
other one and it butters and it's
crumbles the same and I'm getting the
same effect in rubble it's a tiny little
pre-roll exactly and you know more and
more I don't want that better yeah yeah
actually the pre rolls rolls better
because there's more air in between
exactly and even and then look if you
have a lighter if you get threw me a
lighter
I mean
there you know it's oil immediately and
it does you know it'll boil up
incredibly fast and that's another thing
that I've actually never talked about
really with you Peter is the the whole
origin of the bubble the name bubble
hash you know it all comes from the fact
that it bubbles when you put a lighter
to it and you know and that was
literally the age-old test and I've been
buying hash for fucking 20 plus years
now and the angel dust is to stick a
lighter on it and if you got bubbles you
got a wiggle if you don't got bubbles
you got plant material and fiber and
your average hash that's made from dry
sift out of the traditional markets is
between 30 and 40 percent 50 percent oil
if you're lucky
most of our high-end California made
stuff is in the you know 50s to 70s and
then your premium 710 labs fresh frozen
whole plant stuff is getting 85 and
above yeah you know so it really is the
full spectrum of qualities and resin
yeah in resin count
yeah it's all about how many heads can
you successfully get off the plan
without taking plant material with it
that is the whole goal of hash making
getting resin glands off the plant
without taking plant material with it
that's it and this is a perfect example
I mean this had this hash you know some
people might say oh that looks cakey
well you know what it's actually an oil
buttered product just like how wax will
butter you know it doesn't the Oriole
it's not speaking to the oil content if
you put a lighter to this it immediately
butters and it merely bubbles where did
that come close up of this Peter yeah so
the bubbling you know that and that's
bubble hash you know for the bubble that
it needs to bubble to be called bubble
ha where did that come from was that was
that just flying around that little
temple ball no I just mean this oh you
get out of watch from other words on the
table okay and you see there's actually
a little more bubble going on on this
one as we probably assumed cuz the oil
content looks like a little higher but
same thing this is also accurate product
all of these are cured and as they sure
they butter more that is the natural
process of oil as
so yeah this is that product that we we
already kind of broke up over here and I
can do a bit more to exemplify you know
all of a sudden when you have a buttered
product it becomes a lot easier the best
way yeah someone was smoking a few
joints a day of hash
especially the tobacco smokers and
there's a lot of those traditional hash
people love to mix it with tobacco and
it doesn't go great together
yeah this is just much better and then
you put a lighter to it and you can
really see that the oil content is there
as much as you can say it looks like a
drier product or whatnot
it's just buttered and the oil content
is just hidden what do we mean by
buttered what is buttered is you know
it's comes from wax terminology and
waxes butane made extracts and what
happens with a stabilized wax product is
the hydrocarbons in it so that's all the
fats they butter it's the the cells open
and the actual structure and this is you
know very rudimentary chemistry I'm not
a chemist the actual structure itself
changes and that process what you end up
with is a creamy product that isn't
crystal or clear all oils will
eventually do that regardless I think
you've been olive oil eventually does
that um you know or if you add if you
add oxygen to it you can whit boils in
the same sort of process happens I mean
you can butter an MCT oil by just
homogenizing and adding air um but yeah
sensing when you refer to them in
extracts you referring to the process of
it going from a very clear waxy product
to a creamier looking product and fur
hash it for hash it's when it goes from
that dark oily sticky hash that you
can't get off your fingers to something
that you can literally pick up grab a
corner of and go like this and you still
have your 600 700 milligrams in there
and that's it you know and more and more
it's ironic because that first people
always
refer to this as the traditional hash or
oily your product and of course I want
the oilier stuff and the stuff that
looks ordinary but you know more often
than not I'll get people coming back and
they'll be like you know the ease of
this one is actually getting me to like
this one more so you know in the end of
the day it's you want to satisfy
everybody so we try to replicate the
people they came before us this is the
Nepalese style this is the Moroccan
style and then we know when we do it in
a modern way so it's a little bit
different but yeah now what were you
using your pre-rolls pre-rolls we will
use e there are a butter product or a
raw vacuum freezer product so when we
use the vacuum freezer for our curing
process everything you see here right
now is churned in the traditional way
now doing that gives you more higher
levels of certain cannabinoids that we
love but it actually depletes the
terpenes and we love turkeys who doesn't
love flavors and flavors also have
effects so when you're preserving the
original terpene profile in some of our
raw line we use a vacuum freezer and the
ones it's very obvious anything you see
that it's very white very clear not
oxidized that is vacuum frozen so when
it's still wet by the water because it's
water extracted and you cure it in the
natural process in atmosphere you're
allowing that water to oxidize the oil
and it changes the cannabinoids it
changes the structure of them and
changes it actually creates EBM and it
changes more than that THC ve a bunch of
different things a lot of the things
that people associate with hash and its
effects are those changes what about
flavor flavor you lose the turkeys and
you get actually that one hash in
terpene and that's actually a thing I
know it sounds crazy but there is a
terpene called hashing and it's that
flavor that earthy flavor because I
really I have a hard time describing as
anything else it's incredibly earthy and
barnyard e in a good way and that that's
hashing and that will even if you start
with in my experience if you start with
this to prove turkey hash that's fruity
and it has like those really prominent
either citric or fruity notes either
cherry those ones that are really
prominent um after six months of Kurian
it'll be replaced by hash in by that
point your aged product almost always
turns into that super hashing heavy cbn
glistening almost starting to
crystallize in a way yeah the joy of
this product is that it always changes
yeah this one didn't come out as good as
I was hoping but again it was buttered
what do you mean by it's good you mean
like a visually well yeah you know even
me even though I get actually more
orders for this now I'm still you know
in my heart I just love how it looks
when it's dripping how does this go out
under the Morgan is it in chunks or do
you uh if we were making it for Callie
hash in the lab yeah we would slice it
and then turn it into small little gram
squares oh okay or temple boss Oh
today we predominantly done what is it
ball like they said like still this
collar and this consistent by the temple
ball yeah okay yeah and we've had those
I mean right now a lot of our product
will take it to market it will be super
oily and glistening or just by the
natural process especially if it's the
summer and the dispensary is hot or the
distribution didn't have a you know a
direct route or something you know
there's always these instances where the
product will butter in the process of
getting to market Oh awesome um but yeah
I mean generally speaking we like to get
the oiliest product out the freshest
product out you know unfortunately for
six months we didn't have a lab so up
until a month ago we were wounded Wow
and we were just working off of old
inventory so anybody out there who
didn't we apologize and probably gonna
get better
absolutely we're just a little guys so
we appreciate the little guys support
being the little guy means you don't
have your lap you found another lap so
we're good now it's just it's the
process so Fred loves yes now fred is
gonna be our rosin press room we're
doing we're launching rosin in January
with the pre roll line both things were
being launched at the same time right
now I mean we in fact are testing some
of we can test right now some of them
Fred to product right here I've been
smoking on it all week there's actually
a couple weeks now this is the purple
cream that's currently in cali hash in
the market you can buy this product in
the dispensary on the
the hash product and then we pressed it
ourselves in-house of course you can
press it at home with the heat press
from your wife but that's a whole
different tutorial here you can just you
can just look at me smoking it but
that's right there it's a very nice you
know a beige generally with hash rods
and you're gonna get a slightly darker
color now this was cured in a vacuum
feeds or all of our hash rosin is cured
in a vacuum freezer we don't do it any
other traditional way because during the
during the pressing process of rasa and
you're getting those cannabinoids that
you want anyway so with rosin what we
really are aiming for its flavor profile
over everything because it's just so
deliciously flavorful same thing with
our raw line whereas with our press line
we're really going after those
cannabinoids we're really trying to you
know eventually we'll be we'll be
releasing aged things you know one year
two years yeah things like that focusing
on that whereas the raw line really
focuses on terpene profile like those
runs and it's hot right now isn't it
yeah yeah
anything char you're gonna be good
finish that actually we're gonna do a
cold curing absolutely absolutely on the
rosin and the sauces the part of the
process is a lot of cold curing you know
to do diamonds we have to cold cure and
we'll be doing all of that hmm so it's
just no it's delicious just delicious
yeah yeah
that's the purple cream we currently
have a pressed version and a raw version
but if you buy that at the dispensary at
home you could press it and we're
getting 60% out so Wow yeah and right
now in the market you can it's hard to
find a good gram of rosin for less than
60 70 bucks yeah so buying a gram of
cavy hash for 30 bucks I'm pressing it
at home speaking yeah yeah yeah wait
till we released the Raza well release
it into it well we're gonna try to bring
it as low as possible as over I mean we
are not about gouging or not about
we're not here to make profits we don't
have to to shareholders I'm not
answering to some million dollar if it's
a more labor-intensive process isn't it
yeah yeah and for that reason we have to
charge someday I mean what I can always
assure you is that we are charging the
minimal possible I've never paid myself
a salary I pay my employees well and we
take care of them because they're very
important but other than that none of
the partners who started the business
have ever looked at a dollar you know
and we're not looking at it as a piggy
bank
or some sort of revenue generator where
we're in it to build a really reliable
brand long term yeah I take it very
seriously you know yeah I mean I'm a
very emotional person can you send that
my way sorry yeah I'm a very emotional
person we good when did you decide you
wanted to do go that route we're true
would that be guys like established
Kalle Hodge could you've been three
years ago for a long time
three years ago I came up with the name
Cali ash and started the branding of
kalakashi South but like four years ago
did you say I know I'm gonna I want to
go down this is like when you go to a
camera store Peter a magnificent Peter
who is handling the camera so this is a
rosin made by our in-house passion maker
named Fred and this is made from our
purple cream product or raw purple cream
product that's the rosin it's incredibly
Torpy it has just a berry very fruity
finish a lot of cherry going along a lot
of berries going on and we just place it
inside our lovely puffs go peek
and it's ready to go I buzzed yeah I
think once it heats up it doesn't do
that anymore well really or it's not
yeah yeah you know I was always I was
always against wax I never dabbed until
I realized there is a salt in the Sun
yeah until you could really take solving
this to this extreme level then now I
realize you can take it to anything you
can make with the butane hexane alcohol
product just living with it we can make
solvent less yeah yeah that's the
challenge yeah it's a brave new world
yeah yeah that's a big one that started
again do you know how to do the buttons
on this we do it three times a is it
twice or three yeah you got it like a
quick double strong work Fred yes it is
oh and I actually have some examples of
some other stuff that Fred press but you
know when you press a cure hash product
you end up with a much more oxidized end
product
no is that a bad thing yeah very dark
product you can look at this is the hash
rosin made with I think is actually made
with this but this would be very high in
CBN and it would be incredibly high in
hashing the terpene hash this would
knock you out and you know other than
the intense hash flavor which hashing is
gives you you know it's probably my
favorite thing to smoke now is it super
enjoyable in terms of like fruity
profile no of course not right it tastes
like hash right but if you like to buy
it at if you
the flavor of a good old shoe then
you're like you know this type of care
has wrong about it and that's why when I
met Frenchie again after because I
thought I would never experience the
taste of that 11 old Lebanese hash again
which I did what I won't see the
difference do you see the difference I
mean it's I love it still yeah well it's
the only difference apparently it's more
CBN and the only difference is the bed
with the with the purple cream actually
I had both next to each other right here
hmm
so the purple cream on the right here is
to see is so different on this side you
have its venom bowl a it's done with the
back kids like a boy so with a vacuum
freezer right so this never oxidized so
the trichome even up to the point of
pressing never oxidize that's the only
difference this stuff or this stuff on
the on the other side the same is this
yeah this is Donald a cured product so
the beginning product of this middle one
was white if you buy our purple cream
raw right now it's white even though
most of the oven home right now that you
probably don't like that one would in
the beginning was white but if you look
at the dates on it that was produced I
think a year ago that's why we've had
such issues in the last six months and
that's why when I extend my apology as
well this is maybe me reading into it
but I got one complaint and I take it
very sad very sensitive we got one
complaint someone said that they
actually really was displeased with it
and it was actually the moment most that
they mentioned in particular and this
was about three weeks ago and and I just
wanted to speak to you on this Peter cuz
I took it so badly I mean it was floored
me and so I think this incredibly
seriously this is my baby I like it good
I do thought you get better as my points
oh okay
even today on what fred was packaging i
was really excited about it you know it
was just a cure product where the heads
were all obvious where you could see it
each head individually and we did the
traditional care
this one we left it in raw form but you
can actually see every head and and
they've all oxidized a little bit so
they have that beautiful profile and
that glisten um so you know again some
of our stuff was ki fee and that is
literally the word the person used and I
agree is there a part of this we go the
way we make our hash you know it's not a
it's not a uniform process it's not it's
artisinal is artistic convene and so
that's right and so you know we're
obviously going for consistency you know
it's gonna only get better but in an
artisanal process you know there's that
happens yes you know it happens with one
another you know it happens and that's
it and I appreciate that so I mean and
we again we are the little guy we were
you know we're gonna be here and we're
only gonna get better so it gives us a
trajectory as well so you know I I
definitely want to give a nod to nosh I
want to give him not to seven ten labs
you know they're they're they're
companies that are doing exceptional
work and the stuff in the space there
are companies that I aspire to and I
have no problem to admit that Frenchy
included and you know yeah I know I'm
happy to be part of this community
solvent list forever
those cookies solvent lissa product that
we saw at yeah did you partake know what
saw what product did they use did you
know was it a rasa it was so a do blue
eyes who came over from Spain to
basically run their solvent les okay so
he was experimenting and we had the
history of rosin event where he brought
like his first product that he is like
you know it's like different
consistencies different texture
different processing of a picture of
themselves too
I definitely did and so that's a
pneumatic actually it is a hydraulic
welded bottle jacks this is originally a
bottling jack that's been retrofitted by
a by an industrious person who sells
them on Amazon yeah you know yeah we you
know we're definitely you know this is
all fun and games but in the lab under
the keen eye of BCC and in laboratory
conditions it all changes quite
dramatically you know we don't use
anything with this kind of paint on it
and we all know everything stainless
steel you know we're required to test
everything every step of the way
it is a different different environment
but it is still fun to see ash in
abundance
and free in the wild Romijn bouncing
around this one is this one is a F which
is not as fuck it's Afghani it but this
is one of our more popular streams I
mean people really clamor for this one
this is a an age-old favorite for any
hash head kind of prop it up over here
yeah yeah that's a nice little chunk a
hash now what what is what is that chunk
of hash is destiny so this will all be
sold to medical licensed medical
individuals in the state of California
of course next to some lucky patients
yeah exactly
they still are and you know
with the prices as they are in
dispensaries I'm glad to still satisfy
some of the medical more because I truly
believes and even in Cali hashas case we
try our hardest to get the price as low
as possible and I'm very candid about it
our price to the wholesaler is $12.50
including distribution so after that
point to the retailer excuse me
so that's to the whole that's to the
distributor we sell it for 1250
so they're selling it to the retailer at
1250 all included and that's the low as
we can get it as a company we're only
getting $10 of every of every unit and
then that $10 you know $2 goes to legal
four dollars goes to biomass to make it
and then there's $2 left to go to the
packagers so I mean as a company we're
not even making a profit that's not our
goal we're just trying to establish a
reliable trustworthy brand that that
says something that scans for something
anyway before I get to Ramon it would be
nice if you didn't have to deal with all
that stuff yeah if I could payments of a
salary would be fantastic this is purple
punch this one again like a week ago
this was incredibly oily probably my
earliest one you couldn't get your hands
off it without it being sticky today
it's completely buttered I mean
completely so the air and oxygen does
that well this days you have to take
long no this actually I think I said
about two weeks ago this looked entirely
like that glistening part but everywhere
I mean more glistening than these but
that's the case um usually the more oily
you know might not oil these up like
this one I mean this one will even melt
even more and it's even more butter Wow
really speaks to what I'm talking about
and then you really just it opens itself
up and you ended up with this really
fluffy creamy yet melty an extremely
bubbly purple punch
the more oily the product the faster it
does that in fact that's I would reckon
that's between 70 and 75 percent total
cannabinoids so essentially when you're
speaking about the 70 and 60 and 50%
lunch you're speaking of the ratio
between the plant material left and the
end product and the oil content and a
little bit of planning to do is not a
bad thing I'm a believer I love Rosslyn
and we're really happy to launch Rosslyn
in fact I'm a newly newly newly
converted Dabba names to always make fun
of all you dabbers out there and now I'm
getting Fred a ball the way it was fried
yeah you started pressing my own stuff
and I'm like this is fantastic so you
know there's definitely you know I'm
very excited about that but I'm but a
little bit of phytoplankton a little bit
of platformer a little bit of a little
bit of that stuff in the in the in in
the plant is truly full spectrum right
so if you really are talking about a
full spectrum product that truly
reflects the original plant but is an
extract cold water extraction is the
closest thing and when you're doing it
at those high levels of whole plant
fresh frozen you're really getting an 85
percent cannabinoid with a 50 percent
plant material and lipid and fat by
layers and that really is the for me
it's the Holy Grail coup de Gras the
best half is that where you have to get
the tops of the plates and freeze them
immediately yes and you can you have to
use nitrogen immediately or a flash
freezer if you just stick wet plants it
just takes the tripod think like a
trichome but a lot of people do that
they do it they call it fresh frozen ice
ain't gonna life
no if you're really doing fresh frozen
you're at least spending $40,000 on your
blast freezer so it's that or a nitrogen
how do you ensure that's being done you
have to go to their facility and look
this is never away never take anyone's
word for it and then when you take fresh
funds I don't believe the tops right I
mean they can be anything it can be a
whole plant okay and I like whole plant
um but what's very important is the
speed of freezing because if you allow
the trichome to say
in a state of half frozen half wet it
becomes like a little dick you want that
frozen track home why it's going this
way but you want that thing up you
really do it you want this stock because
then when you're when you're cutting the
stock off of the plant it has that stem
to break the minute you've matched the
trichome head against the plant material
against the fiber of the plan then it's
a whole nother challenge to get it off
so yeah I mean in my experience actually
the best stuff isn't made with fresh
frozen it's made with fresh fresh period
you literally go to your garden cut the
plant throw it in your process straight
to hash and what you get is incredible
results that's a great drip drip drip ID
but it has to be got there with the
right time with the most resonant hair
right and then there's really a lot of
nuance to it because again when you
harvest a planting and I love to do this
things like the trichome you know get a
little Zen with it you know the trichome
even on the plant if you harvest the
plants a month prematurely you're
getting none of the kind of annoys you
want let's begin there so you have a
whole different type of product that's
why some people say that's why that's
why they say the plant literally tells
that it does yeah and when the grower is
looking for those amber heading and I
think the average growers said between
60 and 70 percent amber at harvest and I
agree that's probably the optimal time
because that ambereen what they're
speaking to is the creation of thtve
of cbn of those cannabinoids that we all
love and then it becomes a fully
district full spectrum product some of
your your hash sets you know that's made
with these premature materials or or let
me refer to the to the wax market you
know what happened a lot in the wax
market and this can be cooperated by
anybody who's been in this traditional
market for a long time Joe um good
timing they would literally take
premature plants and blast them and you
would end up with this white clear
product they're basically trying to get
tricone yeah blast them with what
blasting refers to the process of butane
they would blast some of butane and use
beauty and extraction to end up with a
clear end product but what you end up
with is a one mono cannabinoid product
because none of the other categories
have developed and so for that you know
it's always a bit of a trick and then
there's this weird print as this very
not weird there's this Universal idea
and it even falls on me that the cleaner
clearer the product cleaner or better
the product the less oxidized the
product the better the product I am
gonna make it my life's mission to
re-educate the population that is not
the case actually the best cannabinoids
are the oxidized ones
oxygen is an incredible thing you know
it gives us life that allows for all of
this mammal you know fully body
reptilian and mammalian life it allowed
for all the evolution as you know it
from from the smallest things to become
the biggest things but it's the most
toxic element one of the most toxic
oxidization what that refers to is how
the on the atomic level oxygen has one
free-floating electron on its outer ring
by itself so literally any any any other
molecule or any other atom excuse me
that has any space on its outer ring for
that one molecule to that one electron
to go into it bonds and that's what
that's what erosion is that's what
that's what oxidization is oxygen
ironically because it gives us life is
one of the most toxic elements on the
table um it's it's interesting irony and
then when it comes to cannabinoids it is
our releaser it is our natural nature's
laboratory of creating those
cannabinoids that we all love and hold
dear so oxidization is not bad
how did it get such a bad rap wax BHO
did it um they did it because there is a
thing with freshness - speaking of also
it can cause lots of sugar of
oxidization exactly so if you don't want
your wax to sugar a butter like we
referred to before and in the in the
nasan's wax market we're talking 2007
whatever - a 12 yeah yeah what happen -
are a good question on this sauce now
well you know what you know what the
true story of that is shatter is a
longer process shatter involves ovens
that are more call
it's actually much cheaper to make sauce
he's actually just people just maybe she
convinced the market than one sauce
because it's easier than me but you know
blankets and scale Gerda screw ups you
know it's harder to get up yeah Peter
yeah because you want yes they're still
both quasars
so we're not beautiful that way the
stuff that we use to smoke yeah I figure
a bong is not a traditional form oh this
is one of one but everyone that sees it
does seem like it could be yours
yeah I mean I've made a few prototype
things for us like Mike's got well no
and you're holding a 101 oh yeah one
beautiful iPhone case yeah if that goes
viral that pillow
yeah well we need to livestream like
we imagine if you can sell like if you
can sell interstate like Home Shopping
Network like today on the show yeah it's
all really about curating then it's
gonna be great
so what curating oh yeah yeah yeah yeah
definitely I mean there ah I think so
and California is the Holy Grail just
for everybody yeah careful singing on
other states okay okay I got girl her
friends all over the country and the one
thing that pisses them off no no of
course it doesn't what it's like we
can't help it because we evening courier
but you may know it's true that's that's
something yeah we didn't we didn't
create our stigma the people who visited
here created the stigma and took it
elsewhere but wait what's the stigma
like California in terms of being a
pinnacle in canvas oh I miss using the
word a little bit but it's the I guess
affable
no no it's yeah its reputation and the
thing is is that like yes we know Maine
has a very respectable cannabis culture
going back many years and fine growers
in a real caregiver community yeah but
just as the industry ramps up you know
people want a piece of that California
Manager
so I'm packing a little bit of a just no
tobacco notes it's not a well-known cut
to call Scout cake yeah it's just uh one
of the countless crosses yeah for the
countless property without any agent
crosses of crisis put a little bit of
flour in the bottom and wait I'm sorry
so food through this uh friend of mine
drew this okay well I didn't I'm really
pleased to meet you guys be quite wise I
had no idea who Cali hash was and I I
like the bottom of that uh was worried
that you were just like you know cashing
in my if you like you're just cashing
and doing do it as cheaply as possible
you know what cuz I'd never write you
know you know and just like with a lot
of other people who in the session and
and it's really really great to see that
you are you're very subtly rehashing it
but knowledgeable about the different
process these in incorporating them into
what you do and you really care about
that and that you have the legacy
information this is so G that is Grape
Ape uh well so much is nice yes very
Turkey
yeah so what I usually tell people
especially people who who haven't been
smoking hash in years or people who are
who are flower people who are looking to
extend their flower if you pair a gram
of hash with about an eighth of flour
that gram if you're smoking the hash
every time you smoke your flower you may
have a little bit of hash left over at
the end of your eighth but you should
about they should about finished around
the same time so if you pair those
together should make your eighth for
however long in a classroom and should
make it last about twice as long so if
you're getting a thirty dollar gram then
you're normally smoking $40 ace now
you're saving ten bucks right so what I
usually tell people if they want to
smoke it with a bong is only got to do
is take you know a really tiny amount
and I mean you can put as much as you
want on it
point one but if you're if you're if
you're trying to just put it on your
bong and have a nice little
snap small amount of weed on it I mean
again you can fill it to the brim if
you'd like but I'd like to taste my
flower and taste my hash so I make
smaller bowls Inter's packet more often
would that be the same for a pipe or any
Bowl that yeah okay yeah I know people
like the packin big because they like to
pass it around with live West Coast is
snap or snaps it really degrades the
flavor that's an East Coast inning and
if you appreciate the flavor but it was
more communal you would share a bowl
that's right I'm Wes in western United
States where we do snap but when I was
younger we also had we did painters just
a winner
we had these lengths of one in her
little little pipes that were incredible
while you could fit in there was that
much okay actually I have a couple
oh really yeah the chills I box of
chilies are on this metal plate give
those children to people for free when
we do when we show up to dispensaries
kid I have one yeah but they're really
they're just simple wonders it's perfect
for you live in just hash the flour
[Music]
they're so cheap that like giving a
handful of them because if you get a
handful of them you can just leave one
or two of them soaking in alcohol while
you have your one that you're using yeah
yeah we're like a barber and they're
calm locker room yeah exactly and again
since they're so cheap if you break and
who cares if he's very good rest you
know and yeah so when you smoke this
just smoke it like any other bowl
so hand on that one oh if that wasn't
such a death though yeah that one needs
a little love but you know yeah oh yeah
now here's more of a traditional show
[Music]
[Laughter]
that's not a one-hitter is it no
something you share people are the same
so that's actually happening between the
quasar and like a one-hitter yeah
quasars like where's the point for 20
people next two years so we still have
services like the quasar even though you
could pack the hell out of this and pass
around a billion people I mean you could
just keep it for yourself
hash holds it very well it doesn't have
to be fully sealed off so you can hit
this the cherry goes out or you can
snuff the charity with some glass or or
a dish and then leave it on your desk or
whatever and get back to it later what
about a patient ways are like we had
this last time we were usual and granted
part of that had to do with the fact
that we just we work we didn't have the
proper fire to like the the coal well so
we weren't we weren't starting this with
a proper coal but nonetheless whether
you were or weren't and this was
something left over from when you're
smoking on a hookah you could come back
to it later again hash holds up very
well so is this just like a MOT like a
electronic hookah necessary this is luxe
electronic yeah so thank you what's a
coal in there Oh coal its coal powered
yeah okay so it is it is operates just
like a traditional hookah does it's just
the only differences is their mechanism
for it just but it's efficient it Joe
it's yeah I haven't tried the quasar
tobacco yeah
I'm sure works just fine with tobacco we
were trying it which is with hash but
hashes combustion rate is higher than in
tobacco it's just made for ash this is
this device is not being rash oh no I
saw people using tobacco really yeah
yeah yeah no no you're just but other
way around I mean using hash at the back
really is a very middle east thing so
yeah yeah one or the other right so we
can also pack some like strawberry
tobacco and dribble some of the hash ons
yeah so if you were if you were to mix
this with tobacco
it's wouldn't be as important to get a
really hot coal as it would be if you're
just smoking the hash by itself like if
you're smoking have one you have to use
a lot less ash that's it that is 100%
correct yeah so how many people still
like to use hookahs are they still
popular yeah yeah tons of people it's
much more of a younger demographic yeah
in terms of like so if they're older
yeah when you're talking about papers
anymore like in their 30s and older I
think it's gonna be more of a foreign
foreigner type of thing right and people
who have friends are better of from
foreign cultures right but when it comes
to the two younger demographics very
popular across the board a lot of it I
think has to do with you know you're
giving younger people another place to
go right some kid just turns 18 he wants
he or she wants all the places in the
world to go to that's only for eighteen
because they want to experience these
new things and so it's it's very much in
line with that yeah wait sorry I tuned
up night tuning back then you're saying
there are places where an 18 year old
no hookah okay yeah Oh got it got it
good there is and I won't name the
hookah place I'm not gonna burn about
granted I haven't been there in a few
years but I used to be friends with the
owner and I used to give him hash and he
would keep some for himself and then mix
my tobacco for me yeah and you know get
everyone in the hook a place like
prairie dog and like so sorry so is this
how you like when you normally smoke
hash that's how I do it all this is how
you number one yeah yeah this is number
one yeah and then like what's sick I
mean I'm a California kid and so we love
our bombs yeah right yeah no I know I
mean Ella Delphis and East Coast last
company but I'm just saying just it's
very very common for people to own a
bomb out here very very common and if
I'm not using a bomb then I'll be using
add a brick and I'll be smoking rosin or
something like that okay so that's
number two depending on again wait yeah
but across a month you do it with mostly
of us mostly blowing hi baby
ii and i really has a joke like whit
flower yeah and why do i smoke a lot
flan that and rash and Rosen's I just I
like my variety yeah and like even
though I smoke a bong every day I smoke
a dab every day more than one or two of
them and I mean I roll at least one or
two joints a day so what's your nightcap
my nightcap yeah long what the bomb the
bomb because it's will our or flower and
hash both yeah Lauren house together
yeah and then what do you start the day
with so you just started standard is you
know it's the easiest and it's the most
efficient because with a barn when
compared to when you're rolling joints
you're consuming a lot less you're
getting the job done with less so like
if you compare to high you get from a
bong versus a joint you could probably
accomplish something similar to a joint
with like what five or six snaps and if
you were to compare how much product
you're actually consuming in that five
or six s versus what you're putting into
that joint yeah
traditionally we would say it's not a
joints were for growers and dealers yeah
because it really is so inefficient you
really have to be able to burn half of
all of your product indiscriminately to
do joints every out yeah the more you
think about it you really do yeah yeah
and I know some joint in blunt smokers
where they don't even smoke the whole
thing they're so nice give me two I've
gotten to that yeah throw away happened
but it's like as much as I I prefer the
flavor all in the first half
I'll smoke the whole thing yeah yeah and
work so I won't waste because you lived
through the depression no no but I kind
of used pre-roll or joint gets better
it totally improves it's like I love the
resins Greg's my wife and you can make
these and they used to sell them I
forget what they called them she doesn't
make them anymore she's she's pregnant
with twins but hers were killer and I
used to buy them from them they thought
they sold them for like 30 bucks and
they were last two or three days and and
I put it out but as it burned out it it
totally and by the end it was like and I
was a hers world more well I've told her
I'm going this is what I'm talking about
like if you know like and and to fund
and hers were like they were famous for
burning evenly down and then everything
got better as it got down I'm like this
thing is a work of art I'm telling you
and she made each one of them my hand
well that's what I'm talking about great
yeah I think there's a lot of space
companies
yeah and it's a real specialized thing
and it's like a seasonal thing you go
here's the flower the message here's the
thing you're gonna only you know and but
next year we'll do some lemon teaming up
with really specific arrange the market
and what you can go direct to people
you'll be delivering those to people
around the world
Oh see all you true story yeah yeah
efficient autos really done a good job
with there is there really always and
it's just earning their trust here's the
way I here's what happened oh you'll
appreciate I'm sorry
few things last year so I went up with
with my buddy Brett and to the Emerald
cop and it was a Brett reasoner I don't
know if you know her family from mmm I
don't think so there he's actually from
the valley and and and he was like a kid
in a candy shop and you know the Emerald
cup was where you would you know
originally and there's still a bit valid
it's where the farmers would brought
bring their roses down so your house
where else would you be in one place and
and you know I saw and and and he got a
whole bunch it had it all out on the
table and I'm like this and he's like
jotting everything down and writing down
and basically what he was doing with
curating that season's harvest whatever
he had gotten the business model in
there is like totally valid if you get
to know someone on the other side of the
world who cannot come and experience
that harvest and you learn about the
name you curio right before them say
10/10 don't give with all your ideas Tom
well I do I give my ideas or ideas or
ideas because other ideas but even if
you did that and you were arguing right
with them half the time only being a
writer ideas if you leave ideas beget
ideas so just leave your portal oh my
partner
George something that does develop tons
of ideas yeah it's like a tsunami or a
snowball it just it just keeps well I
mean if it's a tsunami in a snowboard
and you have to smoke some more hash
because you're just you know you don't
want to like you know so you know and
and and that is I mean I'm not you have
ideas beget ideas and yeah so what is
that that's just Rajaram reusing yeah
it's holding holding my my cannabis and
so what flour do you like mostly indicas
and indica dominant hybrids what I do
smoke in a sativa typically stuff that's
more real dominant sativa I prefer in
concentrated form over flower form and
if I do sum up the straight sativa in
the flower
I actually prefer to mix it with a with
it with a indica like I really enjoy the
mixture of Jack Herer and OG Kush I
think those mixed together definitely
complement complement each other because
you you get that nice mixture of that
citrusy with that earthy tone and it's
just really really nice are you doing
both does this flower or when it's
flowering what's that
I suppose this flower is like yeah yeah
yeah yeah
well excellent mix I always talk into
wait louder oh my god behind are like
him and he was talking about mixing like
four or five different cultivars to
create like his hash where his tinctures
I thought was kind of cool because he
wants to give somebody a broad and deep
of the spectrum sounded like one
cultivar doesn't have everything or like
noticeable amounts of everything where
you mix a bunch
yeah I definitely prefer it out of all
all right so you said you'd like to mix
Jack and yeah when I was younger I was
actually really into mixing flour
strains together to just just makes up
the terpene profile and flavors over but
the only thing that I a stewardess Oh
everything it was kind of like you know
how when you stick a small a little a
small child in front of like a dirty
machine
yeah and they go and they get one of
everything yeah like that but what we
you know but the only thing that I've
I've desired to mix over the years in
terms of flour like the recent years are
our sativa weapon in the coast just
because it's just it's not that I won't
I can't enjoy it a sativa straight
flowers if I don't prefer it you know
I'm gonna smoke the Teva straight I
prefer to concentrate and then otherwise
I pour it into the highway are there
particular brands of growers that you
like yeah I got a friend of mine he'll
be having his stuff coming out pretty
soon
he owns America farms he's always
produce good products where is he Dave
LA yeah but he he'll have he'll have
some flour on on the 64 market
he's still
and then this jar I'm reusing is
actually with another one named King's
garden I talking to you about the last
time I did that so
Haseena grapes is the cut that I was
talking about but from and unless I'm
wrong on this but from what I understand
because I don't really know these guys
personally is the Hasidic grapes is from
another breeder and that King's garden
got from this breeders so otherwise of
all intensive purposes I think it's
their exclusive but it's definitely
unique cut I just like their product
they make a quality flower and hold
yourself and and that's just about it
it's polity and it's not overly
expensive you know you can get a quarter
like a friend of a friend's company
flower company yeah they sell King's
garden and I think I think they're they
sell if you like 50 or 60 bucks for a
quarter which is very reasonable in
terms of the recreational market I mean
anyone that's been to a recreational
store knows how expensive and that's
that's before you even see the taxes
once they see the taxes the first time
like oh it's like you voted for it
I had ablation for sorry when you're
done by the way here's this twenty five
to forty five percent tax were the only
reason I say the range is so big is
because that doesn't include the taxes
people don't see before it even touches
them like them every level I have to
deal with major taxes and then and so
the consumer obviously the consumer is
dealing with major taxes themselves but
they're not even seeing how much isn't
laying the price before it even touches
them yeah and that information is super
important yeah and really unfortunately
it falls back on the fact that most
people just don't really like to read
stuff and they just they go off of what
other people say yeah so you know but
here we are and we're gonna make the
industry better I'm going to move
forward and hopefully people will amend
64 a little bit more municipalities will
get a little friendlier and it's the
state is a brutal bill the drug dealer
so do you like nausea for instance has a
relationship with sunshine Johnson who's
a a dry for more up in Humboldt than
they actually have a have a you know and
actually I'm a current with sunshine
yeah ain't operating in and and she
grows for them is that something of
interest to you like when I visited her
farm wasn't she has a small farm she's
like honey she'd do an article on the
grower in the hash maker and I'm like
that's a great idea I could think of two
or three actually three cup-like couples
that have that relationship and it's a
really beautiful thing because they each
have their own expertise and they come
together and out of that they make it
totally unique third product Oh a
million collaboration right exactly also
known as a collaboration yeah what are
there any farms that you guys we
exclusively work with yeah our suppliers
are twofold we exclusively work with
project cannabis they have a downtown
facility with 850 lights they produce
all of genetic Mike genetic extra medics
and then we also partnered with a
company up north the garden that
produces in greenhouses but yeah we try
to limit our supply to one or two oh
yeah yeah yeah carry any growing in the
long run you know the Holy Grail for
Callie hash
have a vertically integrated project
where we're actually controlling some of
our biomass creation and we're going to
places like Afghanistan and getting the
actual strings that we want and then
producing things from a vertically we
want really control nature now you're
talking and even once we get deliveries
though we still want to have you know
the and whatnot that that are that we've
produced in California and in other
places but we definitely want to have a
line that's that's landrace people so
where in California would you want to
grow it's a mimic Afghanistan that's a
good question Long Beach unfortunately
unless you're up north then the best
hash is still made in a lot of ways up
north in California you have to just
have a very controlled environment so
you have to have a controlled room where
you can wherever you want it to come
closest to talking give me those Afghani
landraces probably Grass Valley against
thousand feet north of sedimentary
cleanse mine says it's not just a go
it's not just hating landraces though
it's other land but yeah you need I'll
get you Mendoza I'm gonna saying yeah
and what that said it would be easier to
control the indoor environment to have
those different you know or something I
wanted yeah yeah okay um one of the
things I've come to appreciate between
the different methods of growing and
what that does to our end product is
hash makers is that without door product
in the full spectrum from the Sun or
married so when you're using the full
spectrum from the Sun you essentially
you're trichomes they develop in a
different way you know unfortunately the
best hash is usually made from
greenhouse full spectrum solar power
of grown flower I'm a big proponent of
soil grown and in greenhouse grown I'm
using full full Sun spectrum you know
there's nothing better now can you get
close to it indoors yes can you make
amazing half of them to more tender
material yes but we get from two sources
one is an indoor source project cannabis
and the second one is it's actually
Patrick's project
Patrick his corner of Green Goddess and
tied 99 and in Melrose he also has a
bunch of wheat brands including tiny
trees and Shiloh so we get all of our
bio a lot of our biomass from them from
tiny trees in Shiloh and project
cannabis well yeah we're talking with
Wonder Bread right now we'll see where
that leads you know we're always looking
for whoever's popular where is creating
the best flower to partner with and do
collabs
yeah we're definitely we're doing a
loaded collab right now at the same time
as our pre-rolls so they're gonna be
loaded is this company that does very
high-end free rows one and a half grams
you know glass forty fifty dollars a
piece you know so we'll let them do a
little Cali hash collab while we release
our you know for the people joints and
they'll grow specifically for you loaded
nor will partner with different growers
to get the biomass for that again even
after the hash no I'm gonna go a long
time your sheet like him sunshine is
going to be going this is my hash snow
and that's the best I mean there's
strong strings that are just
complimentary and Africa Afghan is one
of them and whenever I can find Afghan
biomass even if it's not from one of my
sources that grows it for me I'll
usually jump on it because I just want
it and another thing a lot of people
don't know and realize that one of the
parents of gorilla glue so Gigi for was
incredibly popular so daddy of Gigi for
is Afghan if you want to have Danny
without getting Afghani just get GG for
on you basically yeah absolutely
you have a very similar profile very
similar in fact it's why I love ya I
don't know the strengths from Morocco
Royale glue anymore
yeah there's the Moroccan the doing what
he do with Khitomer Gotama
ket am
that was one of the strings that grew a
lot of and a lot of stuff that came out
of Holland now when you go to Morocco in
the Rif mountains it's cookies and OG oh
yeah
lemon this I mean even stuff skittles
absolutely I mean so I actually like all
the different clubs but they can't sell
the one another so they every call have
to make you so product is that cool no
it's just like in Amsterdam it's very
great so in Holland
there's the similar laws where you have
to you know in it's just creates an
incredibly good yeah yeah it's like
California circa 2000
yeah okay this and anyone knows around
California mm that's exactly what I mean
[Laughter]
[Applause]
I will get different ones I'm gonna do
what I said I'm gonna get 50 grams 10 of
like the best black the best blonde the
best red the best brown the best cream
so you have five shape what are you
looking for premiere that you'd be shot
are you looking for product shots or you
look this is followers because that shit