so this is all the early stuff like all
the nasty nasty nasties are coming down
this week yeah they're they're either
just harvested or coming down this
week where are you where are you are you
outo this is this is the Outdoor crop
this year this is some of the outdoor
under Nets no sprays or no no just full
sign this was just harvested just
harvested got it got it like this was uh
starting the third week of September the
you know second week of September yeah
somewhere along yeah first week hubbles
came down first week second week Pam and
stuff started coming down dog dog
beaches but yeah see you just and like
there's dog beach tear into one of those
I mean you can mutilate whatever you
want brother like there's plenty of this
I just grabbed handful of something that
was that was there I'm um break open
that bud break it out and touch that
sucker so we have Pam what's the there's
a that's a Pam F2 that's a W's dog
walker this is dog beach number that's
dog beach what was that dog beach number
two that's dog beach number
three um what the difference they're
different phenotypes from the same seed
lot so uh those are the dog beach BX so
it's a backcross dog beach so it's a Pam
and a dog walker there's a mega babe
here there's oh there's the there's the
gas right here so those are the gases
right there they're early gases so like
I said you time get bacon bacon bacon
grease and pandemic are extreme gas
nastiness uh those are look I cannot
those are my seed releases for the end
of the year those are going to be out of
smoking device yeah yeah yeah so yeah do
whatever you want to do man just help
yourself with all your whatever you want
I brought this for you guys to play
with so I also brought you guys I didn't
have a whole bunch of stuff packed up
but I brought some seeds amazing like
Christmas in
October yeah oh where's your little Ste
at so there's a couple seed packs right
here for you so I didn't have everything
packed up my wife one of those some
awesome stuff that are really cool we
can pop some of these yes and so what do
you think of the concept of just out
here so we have autos and stuff that I
just want to keep throwing out here but
then I was thinking of just like if we
pop some seeds do a little bit of
supplemental Lighting in the morning and
at night just to keep them in veg
so I'm going to move this I want to I'm
going to move prob move it's too close
over to that it should actually be we
just put it here and that's where we set
up you get all the plants out here move
is probably like right like here this
one I don't know you know how much so
Sun so how much is your sun rotating I
mean if you put it right here like now
it's in the shade what's your rationale
for wanting to move it in the first
place move it in the middle yeah it
needs to be in the sunniest spot
especially going into the fall because
we're losing Sun as as it as it goes so
if you have to move it over there or
someplace else if this is going to get
shaded out during the winter you want it
in the hottest sunniest spot
possible but what's your big ration out
like the wall got it okay so would like
five more feet away from the wall be
good okay that's all so really then it
can just like yeah why why not just put
it right where this one is and just move
this one over one way or turn this one
sideways exactly that's what I want turn
they're like Legos right yeah basically
you slide it over a few feet in a
different way you know but yeah throw in
Autos would be suggestion for like how
close they should be to one another you
know it depends on the way you want to
do your your protection setup right so
like either a you want to do a
protection like you just want to isolate
this one little thing we put a little
protection like over this thing which is
a good example we should probably do um
yes cuz it's small and easy right now
you know what I mean protection I set
all my all my bamboos up as they were
growing I put a little cover over it and
so so I want to do that but of course
now I know I need so so shade is the
enemy for the most part right so if
they're too close together you're going
to get too much shade right so if
they're too far apart they get more but
then again like your soil temperature
and like them being able to like you
know co-mingle and all that stuff
there's less important cuz you're in
boxes but this particular thing you you
know you're pretty much maxed out on you
know three big bigger plants this winter
you could probably do four to six in
here double the amount because they'll
only get they won't the size they won't
have the light even from seed even from
seed so a you could do one thing you
could go directly seed get your
seedlings started put them out here let
them in the natural light and your
seedlings will grow until they're up to
a little bit more maturity it'll be like
6 to 10 6 to 12 in depending on it Pudo
Auto and then yeah and then they flower
immediately they don't you're already in
that 12 12 so you don't have to add any
extra light or any of that stuff but if
you want them to be bigger and you
really want to want to do that then
adding the supplemental light but then
you got to deal with the cold too so
like autof flowers they don't like being
cold and they'll be really in La yeah
but we'll still be like 40 you know what
I mean for a couple you know in the
night and stuff like that I mean it'll
be 38 40 you know I mean Autos are more
prone to like stall out when they're
cold when their root systems are cold
they do better when they're nice and
warm they're be to be planted in the in
the ground or in in something big from
the start and they're able to shoot up
and use the warmth in the season you can
do Autos they're just not going to be as
as big right you know um some might do
okay depending on their lineage and
where they were put together but in
general a colder like root system is is
a slower Auto in a lot of cases they'll
usually go a lot you know I always
thinking the opposite appear to put the
Autos inside where they'll be warmer
doing yeah I mean that's yeah you throw
those goes under a lot of light right
you put an auto under 18 hours or 16
hours of light I just feel like it's a
waste of the light to use I mean he we
we we we have a we have a 2x4 tent in
there so I was like we put two plants in
there yeah and uh that's just two little
plants you know yeah what do you do with
Autos in Winter I mean is that just
that's what you got yeah you either like
usually autos for me if I'm going to run
a bunch of Autos I'll just run them in
my veg area during my regular veg stuff
if you're running inside stuff and you
got veg so just like in the corner of
the veg area because they're getting the
veg light right taking up some space
there and you're getting budding plants
in the veg space you know what I mean so
that's kind of the way that I use Autos
or you plant them like late summer like
June you know June July from seed you
know what I mean August from seed and
that way by the time October and
November get here they're ready you know
is this ground soft like to where we can
like like just stick this in the ground
for a second just to kind of show
it all right so wait everyone come over
here for a second huddle up Tom you're
our official Clapper can we get a Tom
clap perfect excellent
clap yeah we can set it up over there
yeah just to show something you know I
mean if you want me to put it over on
there I mean we could put it over the
top of those plants well for the
purposes of the
demo soft is here yeah um what is how
high can you go as high as you really
want so I brought the extra Tom where's
the camera yeah I'll talk let me know
any go over there go over
there right
so theoretically you can
go small in the winter
time the smaller is more doable because
you're in the winter
right this mosquito
netting you can order in any size
almost from frakin any fabric store
Amazon what have you sometimes uh here
let me throw up a third one in the
middle just to make it nice and
perfect cuz we like
perfect they're cheap we have an extra
one of these lying around too that we
can use it's dark like it's sitting
right in there Laura had suggested would
definitely keep bugs out so basically
like our enemy are
moths
that show up late
evening and early
morning um they look for the scented
they like sweet plants but they like all
plants but they're looking for that
scent they love the buds they'll lay
their they'll lay their eggs right on
the little the little bud points you can
see them actually and I've got pictures
on my Instagram with like a little egg
on a little leaflet that the the dude
has left from the the morning before um
but ultimately a bunch will hatch from
their little egg
sack usually somewhere in the middle to
lower range of the plant and they always
make their way North you know what I
mean upward you know what I mean so when
you cut down your plants a lot of time
if you have Bud worms and you hang them
upside down you usually see the bud
worms up at the top you know hanging on
the stems looking for the top cuz
they're always trying to make their way
you know up uh they like to hang out
especially when they're really small
causing the most damage inside the bud
along the stem you actually have to peel
open the bud and kind of look at the
stem to see if it's any discoloration or
anything like that if you don't see
because early on you won't see the
droppings you know they're so small and
they're just getting started and they're
almost invisible to the naked eye if
you're not really looking for it you
know so if even one gets through are are
you done like because they because the
eggs contain so many so if you if you
catch so chances are right if you have
if you set up something like this and
you throw it over and I got pictures as
long as you don't have any holes in it
and it goes to the ground I usually
throw some dirt or a couple rocks on the
underside to hold it nice and tight and
pretty right you know what I mean so
it's nice and taut and as soon I grow
them without the I grow them without the
the net until they're right before they
go to bloom so you know how big to make
your Chambers properly you know
does this treatment plus the uh the what
is it BT yeah yes no you don't need so
so my whole thing is I don't ever spray
my flowers with anything period I don't
if I put two flowers on the table and I
told you that this one was sprayed and
this one was not you probably would
choose the one that wasn't sprayed with
something first in general right just as
a natural you know that's that's what we
want we don't want something that's been
sprayed or or or toxified in some way
some of those bacteria like BTS
technically I guess consider safe but
some of the bacterias like spinosad and
other things and BT for that for that
matter I don't know how much studies
going on with um smoking it so it's not
I would never I'm saying spray it up
during veg yeah during so during Veg
it's you're not even all so they're so
the the the budworms aren't even present
during veg for the most part they're not
showing up told you use it the second
you see any uh AES or any indication at
the earliest you're not allowed to use
it later on anyway yeah so so what I do
is I send all my plants into flower as
healthy as possible so before there's
any sign of of anything that grown up
you you can use BT you can use spinosad
you can use sulfur you can use a variety
of things oils different things will
suffocate eggs and stuff like that but
just have you heard so so Delano uh who
we did the soil fundraiser for he
mentioned uh corn starch like dilute it
in water and spray it on your plants cuz
they hate it and then he also talking
papra and cumin they so yeah I always
have people like uh use like cayenne
pepper or paprika or or those different
types of peppers and you can soak it in
the water and make a little you know
your preferred method is profac exactly
so the deal is is you you can spray
beforehand make sure they're healthy and
ready to rock and roll for Bloom but as
soon as they start going into bloom in
my world I'm done you're done I'm 100%
that
everyone is on that same so you so for
for $20 you can get one of these bad
boys at any size that you want you can
take one of these love it hoops right
here and if you have and I don't want
anybody to say like oh well I have I
have you know 10t 12T plants well so do
I I grow a lot of sativas mine are all
9ot 10t 12T as it is let's get a little
C coup you don't want anyone to think
you're only growing like exact exactly
you can go let's put this in a look at
it yeah I have I have I have three of
these across and kind of put together
with no here we got to jam it in cuz I
got dirt on there didn't want to go in
all the
way yeah basically Tom we we can cut to
size cut to size yep oh we love working
with p cut to size right there boom
you're walking in there don't we love
working with PVC right super
easy you make you make sure you get the
bigger roll and you can go three four
five at at my place I've got five or six
deep right and you fill that puppy up
with your six and you you're touching
the ceiling and everything that the
trick with this so it's
downfall is so it doesn't have a lot of
downfalls okay number one it rips easy
that's a that's a problem you got to be
really careful when you're strapping it
down or moving it cuz it does teares you
don't want any tears but if you're in a
heavy fog
area this will collect moisture yeah and
and hold for you w't have the
caterpillars you just have the powder
you don't necessarily have the Milo per
se as long as it
like if like at my place right we have
lots of heavy fog live near the ocean
comes through during that September that
that late Bud finish it fills up with a
little bit of moisture but within an
hour or two as soon as that sun comes
down it's all gone and it has no problem
I have never had Bud rot or powdery
mildew because of the net caused ever
it's never caused me a problem the one
problem I had was when the buds grew up
and touched the net and then the net got
wet and that that area can get burned or
damaged but as long as you got plenty of
air and space it's no problem that's the
only thing that I wouldn't recommend it
if you're in a really wet or moist area
but Arizona Nevada SoCal noral uh any
Dyer so by the way just quickly you're
you're in Northern San Diego County yeah
okay I'm in avocado country over there
and you said a lot of your friends who
are growing at home this year saw
caterpillar so at my place uh I mean I'm
sure everywhere kind P we have more
caterpillars that's like the top problem
okay okay so so budworms Tom you're not
alone budworms are the worst pest they
will decimate crops I've
lost countless amounts of pounds I've
thrown hundreds of pounds in the trash
over the years we're not just talking
weed figure what are the fruit other fru
and crops that you deal with so they're
less damaging to other things like they
chew up leaves and things but these
particular ones are are budworm like
like Seekers they seek this
particular that one that we want and
because it's such a delicate plant and
because they're inside on the stem as
soon as they start causing damage on the
inside that's when the rot starts to
happen it's not it's not because of
weather it's not because it's because of
the caterpillars causing damage that's
oxidizing stuff's getting messed up
they're pooping in there there's lots of
bacteria and it just starts rotting the
Bud from the inside out so the only way
to do it is to stop them from being able
to lay their eggs and I've got pictures
of Mo stuck up against the side here
trying to get through I can't get
through is this the desired size netting
and what is and is like if it was a open
if you had a window screen right okay
you could use stuff like this if you had
to I like using this it's lighter easier
to work with is there is it a size
difference is how do you how do you uh
so it's a mesh size so just Google
Google it's a it's a regular it's it's
mosquito netting is what you want to
Google you know what I mean you Google
mosquito netting you can order it uh or
fabric there's fabric meshes it like if
you go to a Joanne fck here's my
question about this is that do you have
like zero room for error this is a great
method prophylactic but you have zero
room for eror error in case like if one
moth gets in you're in big trouble no no
no so so um I've had one moth get
through a hole I've had a couple things
and you see him floating around on the
inside there like you little fuck you
know what I mean or what whatnot and
damage is so minimalized it's not even
funny and also there if there's if you
what I found is I netted too late a
couple times in years past right so like
I got them growing they started a bud
and like they had already had Ms laid on
them before I had netted I didn't
couldn't get the net in time and the
eggs hatched inside the inside the tent
or inside the little the little thing
but I think that like mating and
pollenization and things like that is is
is a factor and they didn't have enough
time to actually cause a problem because
it was before so I've never had a
problem even if one snuck through you
might have a section where you have a
little piece as long as you're but you
can the cool thing is you see it in the
morning or the next day and you can
catch them because they can't go away
you know what I mean but the idea is if
you don't have any
holes exactly like he there like next
season you're going to be hyper Vigilant
as soon as if you see if you see if you
see droppings you're too late your
season's done you're you're already so
far behind it's not even funny you know
so the the you have to stop it before
also also getting a dino light or a bug
zapper light one of those Dino lights
that zap different mods and things like
that you can get them anywhere we also
it was suggested that we get the uh that
special corn that had the BT the genetic
B corn and grow some of that the idea
was to as as grow up for them over
there to kill to kill the lure them yeah
a lure you know and Monsanto it's not so
doing that and not being able to cover
or would you'd still lose you would
still there's too many Ms in our climate
we don't we don't have freeze we don't
have to they're too pungent like they're
like they're call they're way better
than a piece of
corn you know what I mean I mean they
are a cornier worms but the you know I
don't know if there's
a if there's a particular one in in
general that prefers the Cannabis but I
always call them the budworm because
that's that's what they go after that's
what they destroy see this big one I
just they come from so by the way Tyler
which one should I start on that's this
morning that big green one in there uh
do you want uh
something really tough like n you want
some gas or do you want some some fruit
or something smooth and nice how about
something that's going to make me work
nonstop plucking off okay so then
like one of these are going to be your
sativa leaning hybrids right here uh the
dog
beaches this is my jar or this Pam Dead
Worm dead and dying I'd say fucking off
my plants go with number two or number
three you pinch pinch one of those pinch
one of those buds and check out dog
beach number two or number you like to
drink I'm good I got a yeah I got a big
cooler in there man I appreciate you
greatly thank you sir dog beach number
two or three yeah those are going to be
more
sativa um
leaning more on the more on the fruity
funky side pineapple and
lemon and and so you so this you cut
this when uh the dog beaches came down
the second week of September okay right
you know like September SE 10th yeah
September 9th September 10th something
like we now October what uh we're
October Tom what's the I don't know 12th
or something like that okay so about a
month ago yeah so we also just put 10th
October 10th so about exactly a month
ago these are all early finishing
basically and then what's late finishing
that's still going the bacon grease yeah
the pandemic yeah uh the real dog walker
like my real you know my real dog rocket
crop the real crop of dog walker and um
how what else is out there in the pine
tar Kush they're all still out there and
what do you grow in like in pots and uh
no man I do uh I mean I grow in
everything tell you the truth but like
during the summer I would love a drink
dur have the bubbly water dude I got
your
water during the summer uh we do I do
big outdoor crops in the
ground um yeah oh yeah so what's your
setup you're growing in the ground yeah
for outdoor I grow in the ground nice
yeah I mean I have some stuff in pots
like the random the straggler clones and
things that like don't make the cut or
the ones that I need to just give away
or whatever that aren't going to get put
out but they don't deserve the ground oh
yeah every every year yeah they're uh
there's a couple of those chambers
that'll go up well you want to sit for
the uh make yourself you want to sit on
the couch yeah I'm going to grab a seat
right here I'm going to pick out a
little uh DW right here is what I'm
going to smoke right
here do some face
melon who's whose little babies are
these those are me man those are my
three man yeah I was actually in the
emergency room last night man my huh
they were playing uh nights and my
oldest hit the middle child in the head
with a golf club he didn't block it all
the way he had a pillow and they were
playing nights and he missed it and
sliced open the top of his head thank
God it was all it worth all that
happened it's a life less so uh didn't
need stitches he needed yeah we went to
the hospital and they actually glued
them back together up there sometimes
they'll just um just use uh Staples
that's what they said they were usually
only using the head you know but he had
this hair type that allowed him to to
glue it I'm like thank God cuz oh
that'll be better of a yeah he's four he
doesn't want no Staples in his head you
know oh you couldn't sell him a
staple you want him a staple in your
head buddy like he would know
no so cute and this was the
four-year-old yeah yeah so that's that's
what I did okay so so you're and is this
like in your yard or where you so yeah
for my for my home Garden okay yeah for
my home Garden yeah I have you know so
is it kind of yeah you're GNA have to
send me some pictures all right yeah so
I have a big I have a big like I mean I
got like almost an acre little plot of
where I live where I live and like in
the back area there's it it's we call it
the food forest and there's like 60
something different fruit trees back
there on your property yeah yeah yeah I
planted them all I I put I put in this
you know I've been there this is year
six now so when my when my son yeah
basically some of the first fruit trees
you put in uh I had I had 30 or 40 or so
that I carried with me from um all my
different homes in pots they were my
traveling Orchard until I could find the
place to plot them but they were like
things like uh you know there's some
Hollywood plums and different rare
tangerines like the 88-2 Tangerine how
far a field were these like did they
come from other states no so I'm a I'm
an orchard I'm an orchard specialist I'm
a I'm a fruit tree guy so what I do is I
go and I do diagnosises on home fruit
trees Orchard uh orch commercial
Orchards home Orchards uh we turn little
spaces like this into productive like
food Forest areas like we put like five
to six 10 different trees be our we put
two in by the way that one the uh the F
and the little bugle Bush which is
usually a bush but it can be turned into
trees small it's considered a small a
large Bush small tree so beautiful
flowering um yeah so like that's what
that's what I do with like fruit so we
pick certain varieties that all ripen at
different times and that grow in your
area and we take care of business so
that you can always kind of be pulling
something from your from your orchard
and then yeah in in a in accordance with
that lots of these people who have the
the time and the money and the space
they like cannabis and they want to grow
some of their own cannabis too so once
they figure out that you know we're
friends on that on that regard then they
can usually get their you know garden
set up with some of my genetics so I
oversee those for yes yes well I don't
yeah so like I mean some I do so you
come in selling them your fruit tree
services and you walk out selling them
your your genetics well yeah in some
cases but it's but it's they get both
because it's like it's it's a it's a
thing so like my fruit thing is um like
in the fruit world like I I mean I teach
everywhere I do all kinds of funny stuff
like I'm the fruit I'm the fruit guy
dude like that my my license plate
doesn't save Mr trees for nothing
question not other props in Fr yeah I
know I know about all all kinds of stuff
I work my life nurs so you just
mentioned a specific Plum cultivar what
was it that's a Hollywood Plum yeah but
you it had like a number oh that's the
Tangerine the 88-2 so okay so the tan
like is that like who was that like Brad
at UC Davis and can you talk about like
what you've seen in Fruit breeding
versus like your experiences in cannabis
breeding it's uh so like every year I
get a shipment of trees like a little
bundle of like test out or
something yeah exactly so like you get
Ghost apple or PLU Aries or like you
know neck yeah like the whole apricot
Peach well mostly apricot there's so
many at the farmers market there's
apriums too like all these new hybrid
fruits like apricot Plum crosses and
like these are pollen crosses so they're
not the explanation would that be like
if a dog in a person like had sex and
had
like make it into so like peaches Plum
apricots yeah nectarines they're all
part of the same family is this
commercial breeding or all just like
individuals doing it uh well in a
commercials the ones that I'm talking
about are commercial like there's a
there's a family like the um Dave Wilson
Nursery is a good thing it's like the
zigger family does a lot of things uh
there's a bunch of different families
that are commercial breeders that create
most of the modern fruit trees and grow
all the traditional fruit trees that
sell to all the nurseries around so all
every time you go to like a nursery to
buy whatever you know all the fruit
fruit trees they stock there came from
you know what I mean Dave Wilson Nursery
or Ellie csy cre fruit hybrid will that
make its way into the it does so the F
the difference between fruit hybrids and
cannabis hybrids is it takes like
somewhere between eight and 10 years
eight and 12 years to create a new fruit
variety to make sure that it's good it
takes you a long time CU basically
you're taking a you're taking a plum a
plum flour you know pollen and a peach
flour and you're going to take rub those
together and you're going to that
fruit's going to grow you're going to
plant the seed from that from that
mother plant you know fruit you're going
to grow out a bunch of those and then
out of that you do the feno selection
which one turns out to be delicious
which one and this isn't all of the same
season you plant all the same how long
does it take a plum tree to start fruit
in uh somewhere around you know five to
10 years depending on variety if they
grafted do they need to be aware of
whose uh seeds they're using or whatever
cuz they're treading on someone patented
so yeah they do a lot of the patenting
of their of their variety so they do a
lot of those own so all those like like
the neck the neck the plum or it's
highly IP they they start patting those
yeah um which is cool like one of my
favorite things is uh like the plue
Aries they're they're just they're to
die for plums and blueberries plums and
cherries cherries so like it's like a
plum it's like a gigantic fraking Cherry
with like that cherry Crunch and like
that cherry texture with like the
plum complexity and juice and like all
that extra stuff the plum brings right
and they hold on the tree for a long
freaking time compared to all the other
stuff too and then can you breed that
slightly in the direction of one or the
other like if you're like I like this
it's a 50/50 but I'd love it if it were
like 80
Cherry so they so out of that seed lot
when they made that initial cross right
or whatever out of that seed lot there's
one that leans more this way there's one
that leans more this way and then there
are other varieties so there's like
candy heart plary there's like uh Sugar
Twist there's flavor punch there's all
these other varieties of plary and those
are just variations of in the grape
world my mind is blown by the cotton
candy grape it'sa my my daughter's just
and I'm like sitting there like this is
really fucking good and that's what they
do they come out with these new cool
varieties like the the cool grape that
I'm growing this year that's kind of new
is like the the finger grape they're
like these they look like little fingers
hang they're long and skinny you know
the lady fingers or fingerling or I
forget what they're called exactly but
uh the finger grapes are pretty cool um
but yeah so
like we all every one of those types of
trees has a certain growth requirement
certain amount of cold that it needs
every type of like a like a a fig tree
fruits on New Growth or Pimon fruits on
only the new stuff that's grown out that
year a peach fruits on last year's
growth you know and and that that second
year growth is where your fruit is and
like apples fruit on Spurs so you got
got to know which type of tree you're
dealing with and where the fruit
production is going to happen in order
to not screw up your season and like uh
cut off your you know your productivity
and stuff like that but it's like more
of a you know a lifelong thing it's
going to be you're in the game for so
it's interesting because it seems like
those fruits are much more microclimate
sensitive than like if I took your seeds
I could plant them in a bunch of micr
like Oregon Maine down here in LA
outdoor and it be like I'm going to
express myself differently but I will
still make it what's the hardiest
fruit oh that's tough man um does
cannabis count it's a fruit it's you
know lemons limes grapefruits right are
all pretty pretty tough those those
origin fruits you know Pelos you know
what I mean well but a lemon could grow
in New England so so do you mean Hardy
by
like or like their environment you know
what I mean yeah those like so whenever
I go investigate an orchard like say
somebody has a a house has an orchard on
the property the person dies the house
sits Barren for a few years you know
what I mean they turn off the water the
orchard it just kind of runs downhill
and then somebody buys the house right
then my phone rings you're like yo we
just bought this house it's got an
orchard here A bunch of the trees are
sick can you come help us you know the
trees are still alive they're just some
of them are some of them aren't when I
get to this place 90% of the time
the Bear's lime is alive like a low quat
is alive you know there are certain
trees that are always like you know
among it all they're like fuck and
they're not happy they're like the
microbes that can go does that mean
fruit trees don't survive unless they're
cared for most of them don't really uh I
mean unless they're a wild fruit tree
but most of our modern varieties they're
going to need you know they're going to
need water they're going to need you
know the appropriate amount of cold or
chuah yeah we've been we've been you
know these are these are cultivated
fruits they're not they domesticated
yeah they're very domesticated so I mean
you can plant things and not do a lot to
them and that's what my whole trip is is
like set it up so that it is a natural
natural system so that all you have to
do is just kind of be that that shadow
kind of watching out and do a couple
things here there what are some of the
thing like on those properties you're
like okay I can save about 40% of these
trees what are you doing now like are
you just literally being like let's turn
the the irrigation system back on but
like yeah pretty much what are some
other things that you're typically doing
like so yeah so we we look at like the
conditions like is it are they desolate
desert conditions you know what are the
soil temperatures like what uh how do
they even have water there is it
completely broken uh how hard is it
going to be to remediate but basically
essentially it's get a bunch of crap
that's going to cover your ground put
some clothes over your skin you know
some sort of debris some mulch some
plants some forest floor I call it the
forest floor let's get a forest floor
going and then we need to turn the
irrigation on and I usually you know I
usually recommend like you know a
topical spray type irrigation or some
sprayers of some sort so that we we
complete the circle of life like rain
falls from the sky hits the surface like
drip emitters or or like a like a
sprinkler sprink yeah like sprinklers
are my my so so during the drought and
like the crisis and all these things
like we all these commercial Orchards
all these people shifted to drip right
and they have these little drip rings
and stuff that go to tree rings or
whatever I call those tree Killers you
know what I mean
so in a perfect world like I have my my
thermometer and we can do a test and
I'll show you when you when you shoot
the ground right like number one in
nature where plants grow on their own
and we're not you know you'll always see
a forest floor or a covering you know
some sort of Duff that that regulates
the temperature the moisture levels all
those things the nutritional the the
life levels all those things are
regulated by this Forest material of
accumulation of stuff so when we have it
all cleaned out like this or we have
that stuff and we're just using a drip
emitter right next to that drip emitter
it's dripping and it's watering next to
there it's not as wet or it's dry next
to it's skips places and then beyond it
and in between it you're skipping places
where the water isn't evenly kind of
coating and you think about like a
rainstorm right she rains everything
gets wet for the most part you know what
I mean it's raining where the tree is
where the tree is not not and Beyond and
and Beyond and that is that's the trick
in order to kind of flush out the
contaminants that have been collected on
the surface push down the the
fertilizers or animal poop hydrate that
stuff to keep that first layer you know
evenly moist so that when you scratch in
the soil here it's moist and 75 and you
scratch over here it's moist and 75 but
when it's uncovered the temperatures
fluctuate so drastically from like 60 to
like 140 60 to 140 nothing wants to live
there nothing wants to live without that
AC or that irregularity and then there's
no nutritional elements or homes or
anything like that on the surface of the
soil to protect any of those things that
would be you know wanting to live there
which the plants need to get their
nutrition to cycle nutrients to kind of
keep them together because they can't
freaking move so they need as many
friends and family as they can you know
what I mean around them as best possible
to bringing the party to his house that
I that that was always my power move is
like why don't I just have everybody
come to my house and then I don't have
to move I get to see all my friends and
Y and you're just and you just you know
and that's a plants world you know
you're just trying to accumulate as many
cats over here that can help you out and
do different things and the only way
that's going to happen is if the soil
temperatures don't jump around like an
sob and there's material there that's
going to keep it moist and even and
there's food for fungi and you know that
carbon is returned so should we send Tom
out there with the thermometer to yeah
we can we can test we can test all of
that we can play around but you know um
Tom in a couple months you'll be wearing
some sort of like Tom will have his tool
belt yeah man walk around brother his
tools of the trade ready to I mean these
are these are soil Pro it's my
my it tells me you know inches and
shovels I can take you know dep what
about like other pasts like to also like
keep an eye out for you know pasts and
worms that you might not and obviously
there's a point where like we had I had
several very hungry praying mantises but
they didn't do their
job some will not let it go he will not
forgive the praying man I'm okay I'm
okay they were Ming things I'm I'm okay
with like beneficial Predators more so
like indoors I'll rely on them more so
on an indoor environment like I'll rely
on you more indoors right I want you to
be here in the outdoor environment to
help out on whatever I'm missing but
there's no way to rely on that like when
people say order you know tro or
whatever the WASP is that gets the worms
and stuff I me for outdoor I mean unless
you're that was my question Fly Away F
away that's what I my question is like
some might and it might do some good and
I'm not saying it won't but if you had a
place to like trap them in a greenhouse
or or even just the even something along
those lines you're going be unstoppable
you kind of ensure that you don't have
any of those let me ask you do you ever
do that do you ever like toss a was I so
so like I'll throw a Praying Manis or
two in I catch them at my house all the
time got if like early early in veg if I
have a a greenhouse or a tent set up
I'll throw some ladybugs in there you
know what I mean and it's not for like a
guarantee it's just to increase the my
my my help when I'm not my eyes aren't
on the game and like I said I'm not
going to rely on that when it comes but
I I like I like using I like using oil
sprays like there's like different you
know doctor neem doct makes an oil where
it's like peppermint and Thyme and you
know Rosemary and clove and it's like
this little assortment that works pretty
good and that actually messes with cells
that's what I'm wondering there's got to
be some homemade something that like
with a Pepper or something any harm but
they don't like it sulfur does
everything like if I ever have like a
problem like if I have thrips thrips and
budworms are my two biggest enemies
right thrips are my enemies indoors
budworms are my enemies Outdoors you
know for the most part I don't really
care so much about the the thrips
Outdoors cuz my plants are growing so
healthfully and everything's doing fine
it's not the end of the world but
indoors it can make things you know
pissed off so like sulfur is one of my
favorite things and you can just use
sulfur and it's tough and it's not the
funnest to mix but it works really good
and as long as you're using it in Tom
show them your sprayer you're good to go
but sulfur oil you know spin aad is fine
I know that spin aan when you if you
ever use it in flower and stuff I know
that it's it's Pro I think it's on the
band list for California still and and
it's because it comes we've all already
agreed we're not spraying anything
during flour you know but yeah that's
the thing but you can use spin aad not
in flour and it's a bacteria that kills
thrips mites worms aluan insects and
things like that so if you use it
appropriately I think that that one is
okay uh in oh sorry Tom I wanted to
where's your little thing of worms I
mean you just want to like like I said
you just want to make sure that you're
you're you're clean and if you just did
like a once a week oil spray you know
and then you change it maybe once a week
you did oil once a week could did some
soap and then once a week you could keep
everybody kind of at Bay for the most
part you can make garlic sprays you can
make pepper sprays you can do stuff like
that but none of that is going to stop
that Tom I like your collection
ofs yeah all right so so these are the
ones I I took off my tobacco plants uh
today so I want to see if they're in the
at this guy I think this guy is the same
what do you
think yeah it's pretty damn close man
yep little bud worm there I mean there's
so many different mods and so many
varieties this one's darker and they all
well depending on what they eat
depending on what they eat they'll be
different colors W that's much darker
you know they can be different colors
just by what they're you how they're
cycling or where they're involved what
they're doing yeah I mean like you can
have bright orange and bright yellows
and Browns and stuff um they're all
doing essentially the same thing yeah
his is a you know it's the it's anist
corn corer worm
moth Tom I was going to leave these
caterpillar with you because you are
such a good col yeah he's such a good
host of the
caterpillars he's collecting them yeah
those Bud worm it's like act the Grim
Reaper for plants he he's the
uh he's the collector of caterpillar
he's like the uh the the fertility God
for
caterpillar my little tweezers yes and
I'm going out I need to I swear to you
manip like a good friend of mine he's a
this is his second year growing and he
only grows outdoor and my fingers are
all sticky from prying in through the
bud messing up your buds yeah the first
year he did not put up any any
Nets and I kind of you know I didn't
really push for him to put up the Nets
cuz you won't really know unless you you
learn and know you know so you wanted to
give him a learning experience I didn't
want to be like a dick but I didn't want
to be like you know like you have to do
this but this year he's like he got good
enough and he did good enough last year
he learned and and this year he's like
all right what do I do man how do I stop
these worms I'm all right man this is
what we do I told ready to listen and he
freaking and he set up these killer
Chambers man and he like put these and
he had 10 foot pams in there that are
just just arms are just dangling in
there just like this never got touched
with anything you know what I mean he's
like sitting there he's like I don't
know how you do it triming all this
stuff and he had nothing last year he
was completely without spending money
and it was all because of that $20 net
you know what I mean like all because of
that Tom's emotions have gone like from
the highest highs to lowest lows so Tom
next year when you have those 15 foot
tall plants with massive Thor dude yes I
promise you I'm not even bullshitting
like it's been over
you will appreciate it had we done it
this year you wouldn't have appreciated
it as much that's what I mean you have
to go through it man you really have to
get kicked in the freaking gut dude well
I did everybody has to I have a feeling
I have a funny feeling that even if we
had gotten our IPM guy here when we
wanted to he wouldn't have done that no
it might have even been too late yeah
because I have a funny feeling that we
you know I was in as soon as you start
seeing Palm Pals and and hair start
getting thrown that's when I put up the
net that's right I mean even maybe even
a week before that you know what I'm
saying you know so that you're a little
bit more proactive but they usually
don't seek out those little tiny pom
poms they wait for you to get something
sub for yourself you don't go like okay
week nine they go up you do it by
observation observation and I never put
them up before I'm ready to go into
flower because I've put them up before
early and then they grow into the thing
and then like trying to redo it you
couldn't get the net in time for the
right size you know you're like oh shit
I need six more feet and you're like
then you can't get it you know what I
mean and then you're missing time and
things are messed up and then you you
lose so if you if you wait until like
it's like get that to do like a
TW Vegas you know to just for a few days
just really just overnight to shoot this
indoor living soil grow in parump really
beautiful I was
there Steve Kell's place and in fact you
were mentioning this if you look and he
uses these pots he has this beautiful uh
underbrush for the entire length of it
it's total consistency even though it's
inside with the lights just what you're
talking about I we have to look at it
again to see exactly what that plant is
but it's yeah no I yeah anything that
covers I don't care if it's if it's
living or if it's a
car yeah getting getting back to the
fruit trees so so when you all right you
you like start Reviving but then you
want to bring in that cover layer what
are you bringing in for like someone's 2
acre property that yeah so it depends on
their budget like what do you want to do
is this property like surrounded by big
ass trees that we can use bud were not
an issue what would you want to bring in
bring in a few truckloads of some sort
of bark chips that are good quality you
know bark chip mulch mulch is a touchy
word cuz sometimes like mulch is like
half compost half bark or there it's
like a yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah it's
like more people get offended I just
want I just want some chunks I want some
I want I want a variety of particle
sizes just a chopped up tree of the Bark
for the carbon source and I want the
bark that's what I want I want that
actual carbon that that bark and that
shredded material to actually last a
long time create I thought the but I
thought the bark doesn't absorb water
like the wood on the inside it will over
a period of time once once you walk
through like so if you had like a nice
little bark layer of something that was
a couple inches thick and you're
watering it topically you know the first
thing we always do when we put out Bark
I always tell people go out there and
really overhydrate the area like so that
we can saturate the bark really well so
that the bark can kind of absorb as much
water as it can and then it really start
releasing into the ground and then once
you do that like we start the regulation
train down the hill because it's covered
properly it's not fluctuating in
temperature it's everything's kind of
starting to work work where it is and
the water's actually getting through the
bark and into the into the soil air so
you start really rejuvenating does the
bark take longer to decom uh to
decompose than uh like the inner wood uh
yeah I mean that's what I would that
yeah I mean it takes I mean there's a
there's that sheath and it takes a
little bit of time and you can use the
innerwood you can use the outerwood and
there's no magic thing like I wouldn't
say bu this one particular bark I would
actually prefer a multitude of different
things like ask you wouldn't just want
the bark you'd also want some in
innerwood pie yeah innerwood and i' want
leaves and I'd want some twigs and I'd
want some some different things like
that that were so pretty much everything
you would find on a forest floor exactly
that's why I take the forest floor and
pretty much we want to create a freaking
forest floor and and and if you and I
always tell people too like if if you
have a tree like here and then like six
or eight feet away from it you have
another tree right I tried to tell
people to stop treating the trees as
they're individuals and start watering
that entire space like it's one living
thing like care for the soil like it's
one living thing and if you have a
problem watering where there's no plants
or no trees put a plant there so that
you are forced to water this area so
that you keep that even moisture and
temperature level consistent so that
over time your soil actually becomes
alive and then once it becomes alive
you're stocked with dead bodies and
moisture and all of a sudden it's
holding water water is traveling farther
it's absorbing more like a sponge and
you're using less you can back off on
your water when you make your soil
actually a living thing instead of alive
Dead Alive dead and you lose
communication you lose all these
different benefits that you can have so
it's like retraining people to care for
the ground first and then whatever trees
we we have and whatever trees we're
going to put in are going to jump out of
their skin because they're going to be
able to to fall right into a good place
where they want to be and then also
planting new trees planting them high
instead of planting them down in pits
you know for the most part I mean that's
I'm a big I'm a big believer and pl it
high and it will and it will Thrive and
plant it low it won't grow and if you
look at any like tree that's it's
growing 100t in the air and we can go
out there to that front tree I didn't
see any of those trees out there but
they're big giant trees we can look
right where they meet the ground and
you'll see two things one it'll be up on
a little bit of a mound kind of just
slightly up in a mound and two as soon
as the trunk hits the ground you'll see
the main root crown of the soil right at
the surface of the soil it'll be busting
up the sidewalk it'll be right there at
the surface right where the trunk meets
the ground and a lot of people will
plant a tree too deeply to where you'll
have to scratch next to the trunk of the
tree for a couple inches before you can
find that main root hand and you got a
couple inches of bark that's under the
ground or under the mulch and then that
bark becomes soft and you start rotten
out that cambium and all kinds of
problems start right cuz the bark itself
isn't supposed to be under the ground
that way the root system is but once you
start you're like a slow strangle slow
kill and it can take years it can take
months but you're You're really hurting
your tree uh on on that level so a lot
of people dig them in these big pits
well so if you were on a property
wanting to plant a new tree you'd build
an area up a little bit a little bit I
just wouldn't dig as deep of a hole is
what I would do so I would dig a I would
however big the plant it root ball that
I was planting I would dig it a little
bit more like an inch or two more
shallow and I would dig it a lot wider
so width is more important than depth
but like you're happy with that plant
it's better off there than than another
way that the one thing that I would do
like on like one of those instead of
just having a mound where the water and
everything can just run off in a way
like you plant it up on on a on a little
crown and then three to four feet from
the trunk of the tree I kind of build a
little bit of a basin or a little bit of
a BM just to kind of focus a little bit
of that water at a young age so that
when it's a young plant you catch in
that water and it's not running away you
got a little bit of a burm but it's
actually sitting in a little island like
in that BM and you can fill they did
that they I didn't put that in actually
um uh uh a gardener did not the regular
Gardener but a guy who who knows trees
the landlord over and there was like a
little M and over time it'll wear down
and that's fine after it's done that
because Focus your water in here so it's
going down and yeah yeah yeah as long as
it's not a pit you know a lot of things
and and that's perfect when you're up on
the crown like that that's perfect but
like I said every time you see a tree
that's like out out front there that's
doing really well at any park at any
place you'll take notice like you'll
notice that those two things for sure
and then that third thing is the cover
on the ground is it in a forest lore
situation is there a lawn there's some
sort of regulation of the temperature or
it's extremely thick and was allowed to
get that way cuz there once was
something under it and then that canopy
is now shaved that soil so it's okay
there and then they're able to kind of
get away with murder you know what I
mean but that's like that's how that
gets to that point but it's really
important like just planting your trees
at the right level and then actually
caring for the environment around them
as opposed to them per se you know what
I mean first then you'll have a lot more
success and they'll start doing things
then you got to learn about your tree
then you got to figure out what the hell
kind of tree is is when you should when
you when should you prune it you know
what what's going to pick on it you know
stuff like that but if you've got a
healthy environment and you've got cover
and it's even temperatures aren't
fluctuating around all of a sudden
you've got organisms and micro rolin and
all kinds of things that are protecting
that tree actually sitting on the roots
around the rizosphere things like that
defending you know pathogens because
they're able to and they have those
things and then you have a whole system
of you know microbes that are on the
surface of the soil taking up space so
that when that powdery mildew Spore
shows up or whatever shows up it's
consumed by the other organisms around
it or it's not allowed to take Pur
There's No Vacancy and no sugars for
them it's like the shitty new surfer
trying to show up in a spot and all thef
water like too many stuff like no bro
There's No Vacancy and it it's harder
for it to do so plus by having like a
microbial relationship and having all
those parameters set just in the soil
level all of a sudden the plant's
getting the nutrients that needs at the
right levels that it needs by the right
organisms feeding it instead of us
trying to kind of cut through the system
and then the cell walls of those cells
that build that fraking plant are harder
stronger and you know almost impen to to
insects and things like that plus it's
cycling the sap so it's not having an
overabundance in nitrogen which is
causing the sap suckers there's a
million things that that'll just like
can talk about that a little bit like
the sap going through the plants what do
you call it like a not a vascular system
but a it's uh what do you call that
system they call them sap test basically
so it's like a the xylm the cambium the
flum all those all that stuff like that
is is is just their vascular system of
of the plant itself but so vascular
would be the correct word to use yeah
that's what I would that's what I would
use I mean that's what I was struggling
for vascular I know we have a vascular
try to relate things as much to us as
possible so that we can kind of
understand it cuz we are all the same
system the only difference between their
their their chlorophyll and our blood is
the molecule iron and nitrogen you know
what I mean so they're we're these are
our brothers you know what I mean really
we're all doing the same thing have the
same functions have the same goals just
in a slightly different you know
slightly different things and they
protect us too don't they you often yeah
yeah wait they're what protect us yeah I
mean without it so it's like the sap
tests like they do these sap tests
commercially like you can test the sap
flow and things at different points in
the plant and it will tell you the
amount of nitrogen there's nitrate
nitrogen ammonal nitrogen different
things like that uh and sugars and these
other things and plants that are overfed
especially like chemical fertilizers or
there's an abundance of nitrogen in the
in the system they can't metabolize it
quick enough so they start storing stuff
into their sap which makes their sap
really rich and really delectable to all
kinds of sap sucking insects so you've
got scale and aphids and mites and all
those things start coming to that plant
because it's it's it's over it's
overabundant in these in these nitrogen
and sugars that that are in this plant
but that's why isn't that why cannabis
Farmers like pump the nitrogen it level
it because they want that sap but they
want to find that balance you know so
that's yeah I think that's where they go
wrong honestly I think that that's where
you go wrong as a as as any farmer not
just a cannabis farmer is pumping it too
hard because if you look at any natural
system and the way that plants are
eating normally they're not fed large
amounts in short periods of time FR it's
little fattening up a calf or something
it is different it is different but then
with fattening up the calf you comes
other problems like can like certain
chickens you they can't get up cuz their
breasts are too big or like there's
different things you'll you'll cost
Yourself by doing it in that in that
regard you know um like any of those
flowers right there never had any type
of fertilizer on it it was planted in in
the food forest floor there was some
compost initially put out uh that's
pretty much it it got water uh to the
end you know what I mean and I'm and
there's donkey dicks and junk you're
making you're not making teas not no not
really sometimes sometimes we'll do like
a little bit of calcium like a little
calcium supp I make uh WCA out of
eggshells which is like Korean natural
farming calcium it's just plant
available calcium with eggshells and
vinegar I was going to say you put it in
vinegar and vinegar yeah for a couple
days you you you cook up the the
eggshells and you brown them and then
you mix it with vinegar at like a 1 to
10 ratio and then Bubbles and then what
eventually are are you then sifting out
solid material or you you don't want to
pour the vinegar on I I yeah you sift it
out you pour it into a little strainer
or whatever you keep the liquid that's
your that's your calcium stuff and then
the the eggshells always just go into
the compost pow into the garden sorry
but the liquid is like mostly vinegar
it's pretty much vinegar but it has
extracted the calcium all out of and
changed the molecule to make it in a
plant available form but but you dilute
that a t dute that one to a thousand
okay that that so like yeah so yeah it's
1 to a thousand and I even I even go a
little bit less in some cases just to be
cuz I'm not measuring it perect a squirt
of vinegar exactly but it's so powerful
that it's and it's and it's absolutely
PL available like this so you can kind
of you can fix those you do that
frequently like I I do that usually like
in the beginning when things are getting
rolling and then right before I go into
flow usually I'll give them a good good
calcium you know and usually sometimes
they'll a couple applications or one big
like I usually make up one big like
trash can of like seaweed and like
calcium and maybe I'll throw a handful
of worm castings for my worm bin you
know what I mean just make this like you
know gangster little extract you know
what I mean literally it doesn't sit in
there for more than you know a few
minutes and then I take that and I I
start using that into the garden and I
usually do that like twice in the season
I'll do it right sometime in the
beginning of the year and then sometime
right when I'm like in the start of
Bloom or right before Bloom I have no
parameter on exactly what week I'm going
to do it because every year is different
especially on like the outdoor thing and
every and are the eggs just like eggs
that you've eaten over the past month or
two yeah yeah IAT organic eggs I have
have yeah I I always uh cook them up and
then like crush them into the worm bin
yeah so yeah once they pass through the
worm bin you can kind of get some
benefit that way but they're they'll
last for years just sitting in the soil
or in those things unless they're
getting processed can you over cuz I get
so much leachate from my worms uh can
you overuse that yeah okay I burnt the I
burnt the shit out of my plants slow
down so with my leate like with my leate
I always like I mean I dilute it in
water I it like one to one to 500 or one
to a th I really don't use a ton when I
mix M into something CU I always air on
the side little more aggressive because
I I yeah I know some people can be
really and I've been aggressive but I've
also had some negative reactions from
being too aggressive and then using that
too early in the worm bin cycle so if
you just got a fresh worm bin right and
you just made it like a month ago all
that leachy that's coming out of there
or whatever the liquid that coming out
of there it's really hot and it's much
more strong than usual so I usually
that's what I've been pouring in high
doses on my plants but they look great
care okay good well that's good so I
mean that's not the end of the world I
would I would get more out of it by down
just I will dial it back a little bit I
mean and you shouldn't get like tons
coming out you don't need to water it
every day my worm bin I water like once
a month maybe in the hot months you know
what I mean and it stays I I would like
missed the top a little bit but now I
don't yeah I don't I as long it's
covered in the my if it Mes in the shade
and it's and and it's just it's
basically just this big wagon that sits
on Center blocks with a freaking boogie
board or a piece of wood that sits on
top uh red wigglers and other compost
worms that's I I don't know I don't know
the other ones I know there's no
nightcrawlers but I know that they're uh
is that for a reason nightcrawlers
usually I have those in my worm bit
right so nightcrawlers usually don't
they're not compost worms so they're
they're they do a little bit they're not
as good at composting I guess as I think
they're they usually hang out in the
soil system and those they're better
don't they come up at night to feed and
then yeah but like on like a breakdown
like feeding on like the the kitchen
scraps and like on a rapid Pace they're
just not that's not their Duty as much
they're more soil dwellers they'll do it
well fortunately the black soldier fly
also found the worm bin so it's like
it's like tons of black and the the
worms are annoyed yeah you can tell
they're like cuz they're they're just
like
yeah they're dominant they start
sometimes the ants will get in there and
start attacking attacking worms
sometimes you can sprinkle some Diet
tenacious Earth in there and that'll
help knock off the ants or the topal
bugs War it's war in there but what I
use also is my old mosquito Nets from
the Hoops that I make are used in my
worm bin so I make my worm bin I line
the bottom with a mosquito net and then
I put the stuff in and then I either
wrap the top with the rest of the
mosquito net or put another mosquito net
over the top of it so how do you do it
and then they can't get in no flies no
ants no nothing it's just they're
completely sealed in that and it can
breathe and everything how many plants
are at your place do you wrap is it like
like netting for one or for a few or for
depending on how large depend it depends
so like I do like what's the most plants
that are under one
hoop well legally
six okay H pathetically if you went to
someone's house what would be the most
um how about your neighbor let's throw
your neighbor under the bus well my
neighbor is actually annoying they've
got like 100 foot green house it's all
light up and lit up at night so like my
backyard for the last month just been
like lit up which is I'm like the fuck
but I understand it's all good it's all
good my house is big it's okay um but
how late do they keep the lights on I
was out there last night it was 11:30 at
night dude are you serious I swear to
god dude I swear to God so they're going
for size dude I don't know what they're
going for
bro never talked to them uh but uh yeah
so like you know you in like the tall
hoop right there
I've made them 12 by 12 like you know a
12T long you know not 12T wide but 12
12T long by a little bit wider than that
you know uh probably 10t wide you know
what I mean and then you can do anything
from like a whole bunch of little plants
in pots a whole bunch of little plants
in the ground you walk a couple of big
you do walk in there absolutely you do
let's go big so we can walk inside yeah
you get an extra flap right you get a
little extra so you can fold the flap
and you put ACK on it to how would you
set one of these up and then add some
supplemental lighting like you couldn't
well you could with with that well you
don't you you you're pulling the
supplemental lighting when you go into
flower anyway so you don't need it you
don't need it when you're flowering so
you wouldn't need to have like the N
while you're doing it unless you really
wanted extra protection all the time
from everything which net isn't bad all
the time in the winter you can have nets
all the time cuz they're not going to
get as big right you can you know that
they're going to stay pretty small and
it's going to be more cold and stuff so
you can get away with setting them up
early but uh supplemental light then you
get like a like a couple of like 2x4s or
a couple pieces of wood and you you you
stick some of that and then build a
little do the Sun On Demand lights out
here you know you get a little
LED that much you can get like two
little cheap LEDs you could even
probably get some solar like that's
those solar ones yeah Cheo little things
that would just light up a little bit
and that's you need a little bit you
know close to them and on them to keep
them but in the winter I really I don't
ever do the supplemental I just I try to
run them inside like if you have if you
have a little space inside I do then you
plant a bunch of seeds in the winter
starting now this is when you know every
you know I start doing some of the
winter looks and some of the looks of
things you plant seeds now you grow them
up inside until they're like you know a
foot tall maybe less 8 in a foot tall
right before they sex you just take them
outside and you put them and set them up
in there and then you can pull to sex or
before you know you can you can clone
them and sex them but I don't even do
that I get them up to where they're
about ready to start showing maturity
like they can kind you know like you
should transplant them you know like
fuck I should transplant this you're
going outside you know what I mean so
then they you you get your space back
and you can take those outside and then
you they go into flower and then you get
another six inches they'll double in
size sometimes cuz they're going to
stretch you know a third to you know
double depending on what you're growing
and you get a you know getting a foot
and a half tall
plant with a couple good branches and
then you don't have to have supplemental
light other than like starting them
inside go from 8 foot to a foot and a
half yeah Tom you're you're going to go
from having a uh failed small hom grow
to having the the biggest operation of
fir producing weed that yeah and the
thing is you're not get shipped to New
York Don't Spray anything like people
like
90% of the fraking outdoor weed you're
going to smoke has got sprayed with
something to they springing with
something I mean budw worms are
everywhere I mean I don't know I don't
know how a lot of these get away with
and it's end world let's talk about like
a hemp farm at scale and moths like
what's going what's go what's going like
you got to spray them yeah you don't you
either got so much to lose and there's
not enough so they spray what are they
spraying a BT probably probably flower
yeah I most people are like okay with it
yeah they yeah you have to you don't
have protection you have to but on like
scale on like hectors and shit I mean
I'm sure that like I mean you're you're
going to concede part of it you're
you're going to have too many plants for
the population right but then you have
lights I think that there would be good
light control like those Dino trap
lights those electric lights you don't
want them hanging like right next to
your plants to where it's going to like
fiddle with your I don't think that they
would anyway yeah I don't think they
would anyway but they you start hanging
them in the early spring as things are
vegging and you start killing all the
population early so there's less
breeding going on so by the time you go
into summer and you're going in you're
going into flower you've already kind of
dented the local population in your Zone
on like not as much predicated breeding
you know all this stuff going on that
now you've got less to deal with and you
can run it through the through the
cycles like over there and draw most of
them to that instead of right here cuz
they'll be drawn to that light your
neighbor property and then you can kind
of yeah exactly then you can kind of
light them up on that on that regard too
so you don't have to do do as much
spraying and and you
cowers have like those lights like I bet
you they mean I've seen some that did
that actually had little towers with
some zapper lights on and and things
like I've seen some that did I don't
know what a lot of them do do I mean
here we don't have a lot of huge hemp
Farms that I can go to and see you know
there's more you know other places you
know this the East and you know Colorado
and places like that so I don't see as
many of the hemp hemp Farms but man I
know that like
a lot of people in Humble use the dino
traps for like the big trees and you
know a lot of different types of I have
a question for you do you recommend
mosquito netting for like L like large
commercial grows do you I mean is it
doable so in so in in perum Las Vegas
and
Arizona like during like cool season you
can kind of get away with little little
open Hoops like this it's not 10 and
whatever you know what I mean and we've
we've set up big you know I mean big big
Hoops like that with that and you just
order big big rolls and yeah I mean it
it works it doesn't last as as long as
some things and it's easily torn so like
you buy this big thing and you tear it
at a hole in there it's like fuck you
got to like you know you got to do some
you know but yeah for a cheap like way
to like do it and then as long as you're
reusing it for something else like I use
it for my worm bins or I use it for
blueberry coverage and once it gets tore
somewhere else I change it to some other
type of function you you know what I
mean I try to use the shit out of it
where do you get mosquito netting large
swats of it you can get um well Amazon
Depot Amazon you can at Home Depot which
is crazy yeah you can't you cannot get
it at Home Depot you might be able to
order it on a Home Depot online store
and like order it somewhere and they
might be able to sell it but I've never
you can't go someplace and actually buy
it uh a fabric store stock it yeah like
like Joanne fabric stores like is what
we have around here they fabric stores
they have it sometimes gotcha but
sometimes the amount that I need or what
are they are they calling it mosquito
Char too much at those stores yeah and
they don't have that on hand you know
but I found that Amazon you can order it
on Amazon you can order it uh from fab
fabric stores like fabric should
shouldn't hydro stores and those Grow
shops have it because that's where I go
to get the netting they were smart yeah
you know honestly like it's really weird
like I so the reason why I use the
netting in the first place is I'm a
fruit tree guy right I I'm constantly
constantly over here right there I had
yeah yeah I mean we're constantly
putting stuff over like crops to protect
them Frost blankets uh like blueberries
are a big thing where I use those for
blueberry bushes they're small we can
build a little PVC thing blueberries
bird control like nobody's business it's
great so basically the birds are
swarming above yeah exactly and like
peaches and like you got you got you got
you got june beetles attacking the figs
and the soft flesh fruits the peaches
and the nectarines and big old green you
know Jee bug beetles floating around the
Japanese beetles or whatever uh there's
all kinds so we've always used stuff
like this just to cover fruit trees and
stuff so like years ago like I mean I
planted the greatest crop I've ever seen
I was so proud it was like I don't know
it's like almost 10 years ago or
whatever and and basically I didn't get
any of it it all was budw wormed to
death and this is at a point where you
would have done it if it was a blueberry
tree if I wouldn't I didn't even think
that I was like yeah I'll spray it with
BT or like didn't think about the I
didn't have that problem I never planted
such a big crop the way that I did
outdoors and that was the first time
that I really got kicked in the stomach
and I was like everybody has to go
through that you got you got to be like
fuck and then I'm like I'm going to pull
out the mosquito netting and I've never
looked back ever every year you pulling
you're pulling the the freaking donkeys
that you have you know are you
sold it's all good but I'm just trying
to like to understand kind of the time
frame it's
like kind of trying to go back in time
with the the negative
tests I feel when I let you know that we
have a problem we it was probably too
late I even told him with the first text
I go oh I have a problem and I think the
entire caterpillar and took it off when
I was I bet you you were what like week
three of flower right it was was like
maybe May so that's my question to you
it's like we're already two or three
weeks too late yeah okay well no so like
I said before like they're not really
going after the really small flowering
plants right they wait for them to get a
little bit more robust cuz the the
stench is a little bit more there's more
for their offspring to to consume
there's a place for them to hide I don't
know the exact reason of why but usually
about week as soon as you start getting
some substantial little pom poms on
there you know what I mean like we three
the second you can smell
it that's when it's that's when that's
when they're already ahead of you you
know what I mean so you got a weak you
got a we
of that you know so like I usually like
June like late June in like the first
week of July maybe you know this year I
was a little bit later when do you when
do you
plant I plant from inside and everything
comes outside when it's time like in in
late May early June the things come out
but by the end of June and like the
first two weeks of July where we are
like we already have only like 15 hours
of Sun like Max in the summer you know
what I mean like like some of my stuff
will trigger earlier than that like it's
very light sensitive and Trigger so I
have to cover my stuff a little bit
earlier than some you know where I grew
a bunch of stuff from my buddy this year
and all of this stuff like it's it's
like still going because it's you know
it's so late you know compared to my
stuff you know so um it's it just
depends on what you're growing but you
want to get it like a week or two before
you go into flow right when you're T
usually right when I'm taking clones for
the for the select stuff that I want to
look at the ones that have the best stem
rub the best ones or my mother plants
that I keep every year anyway you know
what I mean as soon as they grow up I
always put those outside in the ground
so they can tap into the Earth and
regenerate I take clones I cover them
the mothers Corner the on those Gardia
or what what are those in the corner
back there a Bogan via the ban via so
don't those attract um aren't those
don't those so they have a Bogan via
Looper it's a different worm okay it's a
different interesting that another worm
will have no interest no interest yeah
it's a different thing
I believe yeah I think you guys are
right like it is the corn worm or it's
an earworm it's a worm that wants to be
inside of a bud it's an actual bud worm
they'll get into flowers or corn things
that roses like like different types
spot to hang out like tight buted areas
that's where they they snuggle right up
in thereal for them yeah I mean they're
yeah it's like Co and all your food is
right there in your face most of most
like worm worms two on the Le on
theide now I remember the one where its
head was buried in the bud and its whole
body was out we Disturbed it yep no I
know all about those brother I've been
through that I've I've sent through my
my dad um you know bummer for for them
but him him and his little little
Covenant of group of people that he
lives with over there they got decimated
this year with worms and they put up the
net too late and I was telling them like
you guys put up the freaking Nets please
put up the net down in San Diego they're
they're in Ocean Beach yeah and I was
like the and they put them up too late
and it was like it like once it's too
late it's too late and when it went B it
was so fast CU it's been happening for
two weeks before exactly so that weekend
when we found that that one caterpillar
yeah there was already 30 of them on
there no I know but it was so beautiful
the plants like they were they had were
looking good they were looking really
good there was a lot of Happiness there
was so much sap so you know they I was
like and they thought that too though
you know that's what they're looking for
so the Cannabis guards really fuck with
your head because they make it like it's
already ruin ruin but you don't know it
you don't know it yeah the way that I
notice it like nine times out of 10 the
way that I'll notice it before anything
if you don't see the droppings and it's
early one of the little leaflets that's
coming out of the bud will be brown one
little leaflet or one little area right
there will just be slightly discolored
and it's not even something that's like
whoo that's messed up it's like that's
just slightly different you know I mean
and then you open that up and then it's
completely rotten
behind is it is are new are new
Expressions coming in cuz sometimes
they'll look cuz they look yeah and
sometimes that's just like maybe the
triones have gone Amber on there maybe
it's something you know maybe it just
got hot it was really hot maybe this
Leaf just got burnt a little bit or but
no as soon as you touch that leaf that
thing will pull right out of there and
then you'll see you can your that bud
will just disintegrate in your hand like
a perfect looking Bud will just like
disintegrate you look inside it'll be
all poop on the inside that's what we
did I mean one of those first on I oh
it's too late and and you're and you're
too late you really are I mean you can
spray at that point and save what you
can but you're you're already sprayed
that sucks I mean is what it is we've
all smoked that for years I mean I'm not
you know I'm not it you know I'm not
better than some kind of bud that's been
sprayed every once in a while but if I
have the choice it's going to be as
clean as fraking that's right you know
yeah you know it's it can be so wow you
know the key is keep it off of the
plants don't let the mosquito netting
touch the plants give yourself some room
always make it a little bigger than your
plants and know that your plants are
going to stretch so don't build it to
like your plant size right near the flow
and then they're going to stretch right
into the son of a bitch always give I
buy when you say little bigger you want
a couple of couple of feet for sure yeah
always get a little more than you should
and if you have a little extra on the
ground that you got to throw rocks on I
always put soil on mine so it really
stays nice you know or whatever but or
mulch or whatever's you know on the you
know but you want you want some extra
lay on the ground to keep rodents out
cuz not only is it going to keep
budworms out but you're going to keep
squirrels you're going to keep rats
you're going to keep rabbits you're
going to keep all kinds of stuff on the
ground traffic from coming in and
chewing on your stems or causing a
ruckus and on a small scale this is the
way to do like that's like you got six
plants you can freaking protect the shit
out of those six plants abs like awesome
right I mean resin stud is the note that
goes along with us right you're making
hash that one no that one that one's dad
the dad of that was a resin stud oh got
it got it got it so that was a plant his
daddy was came out of a out of a big
sword a big population I went through a
bunch of plants with me and my couple of
my buddies and we pulled out this male
that had visible resin dripping all over
him and had awesome stank and stickiness
to him and then that mail hit a bunch of
my stuff and that's the that's that's
just one of the things that's the or I
think that's the what the orchard lady
the bacon grease oh the bacon grease
yeah so there's yeah so you've got two
resin studs going there so bacon grease
wicked witch so sorry bacon grease is
Pam one cross with doyo so that's V
that's version two sorry V2 yeah yeah so
do we have the V1 like uh everything
that I do goes through P every mail that
I collect and and find goes to to Pam
first Pam one first a female yeah my
female my Pam one lady every male that I
find always breeds with Pam one in
addition to everybody else is that your
stable that's your stable every male
that's coming from outside that's not a
Pam that's not every male that I select
yeah that's not a Pam that's anything
that I need to learn about I breed a Pam
one because Pam one doing that because I
know Pam so well yeah it will tell me
everything that that male does right
they'll tell me oh he he passes
structure or he passes is this this
smell or he he gives Frost or he changes
the bud structure or whatever cuz he'll
tell me right away what the hell what
the hell he does CU I've grown so many
different types of Pam and so many
different how did variabl why why were
you drawn to that well Pam is an old bag
seed Pam Anderson yeah it's like she's
like old B seed from the late 90s um
early 2000s kind of old school funky
sativa stuff um that I just had
collected and and when I grew Pam's
mother from that Original
Seed she was really special and she was
awesome and she was Heavy producing and
I was like man I want to keep this plant
around for a little while so I kept it
around for a little while and then I had
it tested matter what environment you
were in or did she just do she's tough
she's colorful she's pretty she's heavy
that's why you like her like so she's
yeah and I mean she does everything that
I need her to do it's the same story
with this other breeder who uses this
black in everything everybody has like
this one thing that you know if you got
something that's that you know that you
use that that teach but the way you're
describing it right now is that you use
it because you know it so well so it
teaches you what the other thing is
doing but then do you then eventually
cross the other thing with something
that's not Pam or you always always yeah
that's they have to test with Pam first
so you're not like fixated on Pam for
smoking and
growing you're using you love it but
you're also using it so it can tell you
about other she's my bar that I can yeah
I can tell cuz she she's so strong like
you're calibrated to her as your Zer
everything that she usually touches she
dominates like in the genetic pool right
she's a dominator literally like
literally a dominates it like she'll
turn everything like like to her
morphological character she really
dominates over fruit I mean she'll
really take over so if you find
something that dominates her that's
something that I like I want told that
that I have dominant totally
domination my daughters look exactly
like me and sometimes you don't want
something that dominates her right you
want a male that like if you want so say
I want to cross this mail with something
that's not pan that is perfect like say
say dog walker and I want to make dog
walker exactly right so I'll cross this
male and if this male doesn't really do
anything and Pam completely dominates
this male and it's pretty much that then
maybe I'll use that mail and that dog
walker because maybe the dog walker will
dominate it too and I'll get what I want
quicker you know what I mean to look at
me mediate kind of just depends on what
you what you want I just want to find
out what the male does and then I can
use him accordingly if I want to use
them you know me so talk about something
recent where you uh so bacon grease that
that's V this nobody has this okay one
other person a guy that lives in Jamaica
my boy uh Rasta Bob he's the only other
person that has that version that is
V2 uh the V1 the real bacon grease is my
pan you have confidence of it doing well
this
I wanted you to get something that was
good that was different I don't know
it's not nervous because I want you to
have fun and that's those seeds are in
good hands I'm not worried about it yeah
F I got plans the stakes are high but
it's just something that's just
different that you can like you know he
could be I so in the breeding of this
the Pam was the so the one I wanted the
bacon grease that I wanted to create and
call bacon grease was with my Pam 15
yeah and that same dad but that was the
byproduct of the project the dad was the
do
yes that's a resin dad cuz I went
through a bunch of plants and found a
resin dad Dosey Do and I wanted to know
you know what he did so but I wanted to
breed him with my pan 15 because my pan
15 is this crazy tall Haze thing that's
just a resin dripper and I wanted to
give it a resin mail to this other resin
thing but in doing that project I had to
hit it to the Pam one in order to figure
out kind of what she did and I grew a
bunch of those out and it's awesome it's
awesome as hell too it's like hard to
tell the difference but that's just a
different mom than my traditional one so
it's version two and then version one's
with the 15 but then once you know what
the dosido male does would you then
cross it with for example a cherrygasm
which you also now know what and for
both of these you know what the males do
yeah and you can justly what would
happen with the females do something
that I want to do yeah I can apply it to
whatever female that I want yeah of
something that's not a cam in our in our
triangle cush got it got it gator bait
all
right so from this project you'll now
breed the Dosey dough with like one of
these other so that Dosey dough fed a
couple things that I'm that that are
going into testing at the end of this
year and what did the do what did Pam
tell you about the Dosey Do mail so that
Dosey Do mail has a more upright cush
structure with more of my cushy leaves
which is what I wanted which right now
they're all in flour they're still fruit
fruit dominant but it has Sparkle it
added resin and it add a little bit of a
of a shorter stature with more of like
the branches are more upright instead of
Christmas tree you know it has this more
I call it the Kush a Kush stature and it
has this more more of a and that's the
OG Kush um version do Dosey Do it's the
Dosey Do
18on cuz it was greasy as hell um I I I
was pushing it up against
the um mosquito netting you know what I
mean moving some stuff around
and it it left such a nasty smear on the
side when I when I pulled it aside and
it was just greasy as fuck I'm like man
that's greasy that's like that's some
greasy that's some greasy you know like
I was thinking about it like it's bacon
grease man that's what it is and old
bacon grease is all white in the pan
just like just greasy and you know once
you get it on there you're never getting
it off it pretty much you know it is
what it is so I just call it bacon
grease doesn't smell like bacon grease
or anything it's very floral very spicy
very I call it I call it smoke shop like
you walk into a smoke shop and there's
like incense and funky things smelling
and kind of this musty dude with Bo and
just this weird
collection yeah a weird smoke shop kind
of smell um very very very very good
uh okay but so as a contrasts this is
the orchard lady which is also a Pam one
cross with Citrus farmer resin resin so
what did the Pam one tell you about the
Citrus farmer so Pam one dominates that
cross okay okay so so it's a submissive
male that yeah he's more he added Frost
like a mofo though so in the cactus
fruit like there's a there's cactus
fruit or Cactus cam some people call it
Cactus cam a bunch of Veteran groups
grow it a couple people around town grow
it um there's several people that have
found Keepers in the cactus Cam and it's
just it looks kind of like the Mac with
the resin uh it really has got this
grapefruit citrus sharpness with this
Mac kind of resin you know profile uh
but to the orchard lady it it doesn't
have that I haven't found any of those
Mac resin characteristics you got the
Pam characteristics in there which is
purples and pinks and swirls of color
and it's got uh more of a Sandy resin
type like like Pam um and she's this
really
grapy um most of the phenotypes are very
grape Bubblegum and sugary and colorful
they're really cool and the branches are
really Stout like you don't need caging
and stuff for most of the orchard unless
you're Lear to let it get 10 or 12 feet
which they will and and there's several
people that grew 10 foot Orchard ladies
this year which is killer um but they
are really firm fibrous branches man and
it's fullon like candleabra manipulate
them do you B you can but you should do
it early with the orchard lady cuz they
firm up pretty but do you do you no I
don't
do you let your plants just do what
they're going to do yeah unless they're
like coming into contact with danger
like if if they're in a smaller space
and I need to manipulate them to keep
them out of trouble then I will do so
but if I have Val was jumping up down on
the couch yet last night yeah outside
over the concrete and I was like let me
so do you top your so you top I do a top
right in the beginning um and then
usually that's when you say the
beginning so like when they get like
three or Four Leaf sets soon as I get
like 6 in or so you know they got a
couple good Leaf sets I'll top it then
so you have a nice low branching not too
low because I don't want it branching on
the ground so you know I usually you
know you know 6 in 7 inches I'll do a
top right there and then I don't do
another one and most of the strains that
I grow are really branchy strains anyway
so just that one top just sends it on
its way to a really nice height is
whatever it's going to whatever you want
it to be like the Pam and like the dog
once it gets say to eight and you don't
you go I don't want any what how do you
keep it from growing bend that sucker
down prune it or bend it so I'm not I'm
a fan of both so but so like if you
prune it aren't you like create creating
a potential opening for something to get
like is it better to bend if you do if
you're pruning it I would say prune
early don't prune late because later you
prune the less activities happening with
your plant the less it's feeding itself
the less it's doing the more it's foot
heal you know the less it's going to be
able to take care of that wound and it's
got too much other 6 Fe that's too late
you got to bend you got to bend it at
that point you know and you can bend it
and you know flop it or whatever no
problem man or weave it you know um I've
put in I've put in trellis Nets way too
late and fully made it work you know
what I mean you know even if you you
know it's not and they like a little bit
of stress yeah but the yeah I mean a
little bit I mean the best honestly the
best the best plants I think you know
just like the best best people in this
world man they didn't come from like
perfect situations right we all came
from torment and struggle in some way or
not I don't say struggle you're playing
but like in some way you have to work
for what you have you
know like if you're like listening
talking to people reading if you don't
have your hands-on experience people's
beliefs you know like about philosophies
about that are all over the map you know
in terms of and so you know at the end
of the day you kind of find have to find
your own way yeah I think you have to
yeah because you can't listen to
everyone man is the rice just a des for
me going to work for you all the time
you know what is the rice just that's my
cheap little one usually there's cotton
or something or usually use cotton or
rice in there so you could put like some
can FY microbes on the rice it's clean
good organic rice you know my celium
yeah yeah yeah throw a bunch of that
random stuff or random seeds use cheese
seeds so which one would you
recommend out here next cuz I think
basically with all we should just chop
all like everything yeah Salvage
whatever you can yeah you're you're
you're yeah you're you're you're hurting
um you don't want to like ingest
anything that actually you know has
molded or got a bunch of the stuff on
there if you got a clean spot or a clean
bud that's not touched I think there are
like just a couple then go for it but
really you're going to have a meager
situation the best thing to do is use
that because it's a bio accumulator so
all that good soil and all that good
stuff that you put fed into it right
it's at least inside of it right so you
can chop that up and use it as mulch or
throw it someplace or you know compost
it son we should we should we should go
to Home Depot and get like a a home uh
like composter no what you need to do
those don't work um what you got to do
like those little T things the thing
with compost man is you got to have like
a you got to have at least a 3X3 3ot
wide 3ft tall pile like Mass right in
order to generate enough heat to start
cooking the stuff to to really do break
it down and sterilize all that good
stuff but if you only build it 3ft tall
and 3 foot wide then after like the
first day or two it runs out of steam
and stops cooking and then you get a
half ass pile that never finishes and
just kind of sits there and that's where
everybody gives up you know in their in
their compost pile so if you build it 5
foot tall and you know 3 foot or five
foot tall what what I do is I got three
pallets or six pallets from Home Depot
right and I put one pallet on its side
one pallet in the back and one pallet on
the side and create a little cubby and
then I make an an identical one on on
this side right and then you pile your
stuff to the top of that you know pallet
it's like four four and a half feet or
whatever and with one side open the
front side open yeah with the front side
open so you can kind of shovel stuff in
there or whatever and you just pile it
up as best you can as it you go green or
you go brown brown and dead green and
wet Brown and dead green and wet so it's
like brown stuff wood and brown Dead
Leaves Brown dead stuff and then like
green is like green leaves or grass
clippings or chicken manure stuff or
what ever you're using that's green and
wet and you know and you do brown and
brown and green and brown and green soak
all that down as you're building the
pile and as long as you get it 5 foot
tall and you know that pallet size wide
it'll start cooking and that thing will
start fraking just over the next two
days or so will just heat up to like 160
180 140 somewhere in there depending on
your time of year and it will just start
cooking that stuff and then you after 2
or 3 days then you take your your fork
and you freaking rotate it over into to
the next bin that you made and that's
the sucky thing about compost is cuz the
only way to actually do it to where
you're not getting Anor robic crap and
like stuff that you can jam your hand in
and like smear on your face because it
smells like Good Earth and is beautiful
the only way to do it is to do it the
right way those tumblers they don't have
enough mass and you have to like add
stuff and they're always this sludge
that like you never want to do it
although I have those tumblers and
they're actually pretty awesome I I I
you have huge ones yeah you get enough
mass and if you add the compost St each
drum is 55 gallons and it's a dual if
you get them the big yeah if you just
have the small the small area and never
heats up and I've been to gets so hot
that's why I love it yeah I've been to
thousands of places and like they have
these things and they just they just
never break down it's just this nasty
Sledge where you don't want to like
stick your hand in if you don't want to
stick your hand in it then it ain't comp
I'll bring it's good I'll bring some uh
next time that's like my judge if it if
you don't want to like jam your hand in
it and like you know then then you're
not doing it right so that's the B
that's the bomb but nine times out of 10
you need that mass and if you do it like
that it cooks really quick you can do it
no matter of what I thought we were
talking about was just like cutting it
and just laying it on there but you're
talking about compost but then it
wouldn't thermophilically well if you if
you turned it into the soil you have to
color you have it's not going to
thermophilic anything no matter what if
you just cut it and lay it down it's
just going to oxidize or break down if
you just leave it on the surface then
the sun will be down lose a lot your
you're saying that's okay even though
you just got hammered with
is you it's okay no matter what cuz
you're not you know you don't got
nothing else you're you're not trying to
save anything jum on anything new right
yeah you don't have anything left and
you know those worms are just protein
and vitamins and minerals and water
anyway so compost the shit out of them
or bury them and throw them in the soil
or yeah chop it up I'd be ascy to keep
cuz I was going to potentially bring
them throw them in my composter at home
yeah for sure dude and then like I said
you got all that good stuff that was in
that soil I'm sure you guys use awesome
stuff right and I mean they they just
loaded themselves up with at least well
I would want to keep i' want to keep the
root systems they just plant right next
to them yeah you could so cut it at the
base y yep um and you just read yeah
redo the and then we can all right so
we'll do the bacon grease is that what
we or yeah I say bacon grease Orchard
lady I mean Hubble I mean they're all
kind of they're all different they're
all different in their own what's nice
and uh like a fruity easy plant would be
Orchard lady probably um a really kind
of a a tasty sweet fruity easy that you
know Orchard lady a more um like the
Hubble and the wicked witch will have a
tiny bit of CBD on board so you'll have
some this is your brand yeah yes sir
family family tree seeds seeds awesome
yeah so you'll have like um you'll have
a little bit of CBD in that wicked witch
that's cool next time there'll be that
that CBD the 3D
skunk Afghan and then the hubbles the
flamingo Ringo so you'll get some pinks
uh pink pistol action in that Hubble
plus that hubbles dog walker so it's gas
with a little bit of this pink CBD
characteristic so you've got you know it
dominates on the THC so it gets you
wasted man and actually it has Long
Carry because you have a little bit of
CBD in there you actually that's Hubble
Hubble's the one that people fall in
love with all the time it's uh one of
the
what I love Hubble man I think that's a
killer one they are the they are the
most they're like the honory ones like
to get going like they're the ones that
are like slower growth at the beginning
you know what I mean but they're
Superior you get a good if you get
phenotype number one I call pheno one of
the Hubble that's a good dog walker D
with some oh my God it's the F1 well
yeah but no you got to you got to grow
them in the phenotypes that'll come out
of that F1 you'll have a couple
different ones you'll have a CBD
dominant one it'll have CBD and like
pink neon pink hairs and it'll be mostly
CBD dominant you know or one to one you
know a one to one and it'll have this
funky papaya Grandma's perfume smell to
it and then like phenotype one is dog
walker dominant which is the gas and
like the chem res in and you get color
sometimes you get pink in there too but
you'll get this extra color but that's
the grease the gas with a little bit of
you know the the pink and a teeny bit of
CBD is in there and that's my favorite
one to find it's like dog walker with a
smidge of CBD and some some color and
it's like it's a it's excellent freaking
Plant Man excellent plant and then there
cut these right
now I mean yeah that's I thought that
was a part of what we were doing we just
get it done um do do you have question
get a fun you like everything you like
gases Exotics and OG's what is your
personal like what do you my favorite's
gas man yeah that's what it sounds like
cuz your voice go you you get a little
excited I like gas man like that's one
thing like the cool thing about Pam is
she's not gas like she is she's got tons
of sentimentals she's really rare she
like phos is garbage but she tested like
kind of unique in the in the scale of
things in their Galaxy so that's why
I've kept her for so long I worked with
her which is funny but who knows what's
real and what's not so I don't have any
like like definitive information on what
she is or where she came from and the
information that I did get was like
there not there's not a lot she's rare
you know so I was like okay good to know
because they yeah yeah so I'm good with
I'm good with that so I've kept her and
she's she's tough she's resilient she's
huge she's resinous she's pretty she
just doesn't have gas but that's
interesting that she's something that
you're not that's not like so so what my
whole goal in life is is like I need to
put gas into Pam but but Pam dominates
everything especially gas which is like
my life's like you
know it's kind of like you know when
like their parents and family know they
have a certain type and then like the
woman they marry is completely off type
that's like you and P but now you have a
mission your mission you're trying to
turn Pam into your exactly so like she
is my type you're trying to force Pam to
be something she out of but like when
she'll appreciate it one said but if I'm
if I had a choice and I could get like I
really great I want BR I want to bring I
want to try to get P the actual Pam
Anderson on when we talk about this be
like I
named
canis I sent her a message I sent her a
message on email or like Instagram or
something like years ago when I when I
was you know when I decided
I I'm like I'm going to name this after
you this this flower if you got a
problem with it let me know but this is
going to happen so you know yada yada
but like you know obviously she's not
going to write back to me but um you
know can't
see if I were be like you got to at
least give me there are many roads to p
yeah that's why I call Pam one too and
like that's why most of the time I call
it Pam one because it keeps me out of
legal trouble in case she like pissed
off that I'm saying Pam Anderson all the
time you know what I mean so yes you
know it is where it is be like Pam's a
common name but she was the most
gorgeous thing when she stands out in
the orchard I mean among other plants
you are like what the fuck plan is that
you know what I mean cuz she's got this
thing about her that's something special
the meme with the guy with a girlfriend
who's looking back at the other girl
yeah yeah oh yeah that's it that's it
Le no I I had a h I had I had I had a
male that I called the Hoff I mean for
Hassel Hof you know I mean but he turned
out to really pass really strong Citrus
TPS I hate Citrus TPS like I hate the
CIT like the Citrus farmer mail that I
got I pulled out the grape one I didn't
want the Citrus one I I pulled out this
this grape cough syrup thing you know
what I mean I pulled up this weird you
know random one from the GDP side
particular uh but the Citrus TS he
passed tons everything it touched he
turned it to freaking orange like bright
orange and like some people like that I
I can't I don't I don't I can't smoke
the I can't smoke orange weed man I just
have it doesn't do anything for me it's
like yeah I don't really like it either
but if anybody's got an orange weed
share with me it like let me know but
I've never found one yet well what what
tpine would that be dominant in uh I
don't I don't know what orange Tangerine
like that that tpine is I mean loning is
you know lemony I mean they got that
turpine in there and it's not lemon it's
more orange I don't there is a name for
that TP uh it's on the tip of my tongue
but yeah I don't know what the Citrus
Citrus one is I mean it's I think it
starts with an O actually aamine it
could be could be ozam get some water
for this dog I could oh Tom by the way
if you're getting more uh bubbly water I
would yeah I have one in here but yeah
like you can notice like all the stuff
that I cross Pam with a lot of the time
is like dog walker
uh there's a triangle cushion Cham 91
there's by the way I just ordered one of
these I I ordered the Amazon knockoff of
the Camco uh carbon water hose filter oh
sweet no that's what I I use those bro
you do yeah yeah for sure I was like I
think I'd be happy having cuz I I'm what
I always have to do every day is I fill
everything up that I'm going to use the
next day cuz I want to let the water sit
for 24 hours that's great dude I use
those all the time there's a there's 50
different manufacturers of the thing
there's 10 different people that make
them you can buy them it clearly sells
because Amazon has the Amazon branded
one sure they only do that yeah only
stuff like my mic stands I have every I
I have uh light stands they're Amazon
Basics Li and it's interesting to think
that they just see what sells and
they're like let's make that let's make
that it's cheating man that's a way to
do it though I
guess it's like SP that brands in to
fuck them
I know they're like we're going to I
hate saying buy that on Amazon you know
but I seriously went to camping stores I
went to fabric stores I went to every
box store I went to every lumber store
nobody freaking carries like a roll of
that stuff and if anybody knows of a
place let me know but I've I've went
through hell over the last year so I
just find it on Amazon you can find
shade cloth and stuff at uh some of
these but not mosquito net that's weird
so weird dude so weird I bet you in
Florida it's different they probably
have mosquito netting more places there
cuz they got mosquitoes know more
prevalently you say oh no it was Pedro
this morning who said he has mosquitoes
down in Orange County and I was like
really cuz I never see we got tons of
them in my house man I got tons of them
yeah they're 30 ft from their water
source so if you got water standing
somewhere there's mosquitoes there but
do you notice that in La there aren't
really yeah there's not a lot of life in
La mosquitoes need plants and soil no
but I mean it's amazing cuz I I come
from the East Coast where like every
summer every summer you're just like my
wife my wife from Rochester New York
yeah I know about that yeah it's like I
couldn't believe that man like you guys
live like this no it's not as bad here
there's not as many but in my house man
I mean I got tons of mosquitoes if
especially if I let drains and stuff
fill up you know I got to use little
it's interesting when it rains here and
just the life that explodes like up in
Tanga where it's just like Aid
vicious eco system and then the r in and
like think about like that though you
look at all the hillsides right and
they're all covered with that native
Shrubbery right that shrubs and all
those little dead plants and like the
native like stuff the native crap
basically that's your soil regulator and
that just sits there with the with
protects the biology gives it that
buffer zone and you look at any Hillside
you drive on any freeway you look at any
Hillside that we're not watering you'll
never see bare ground it'll always be
like native Shrubbery or like weeds or
something will cover that land because
Mother Nature won't allow that to happen
so it's like as soon as it rains all
that biology has been temperature
regulated and protected and it's just
lying dormant waiting for the rain to
happen so it happens like instantly cuz
it's it's fully alive and then you water
it evenly and temperatures and moisture
levels are all even and it shit just
comes alive like this and then death
comes back two month no water and then
everybody goes dormant but all that crap
goes dormant and returns those nutrients
to the surface and protects everything
until the next rain comes and it's just
trippy just to when you just it's so
weird you just you'll never see it the
places you see bare ground and clear
soil is like Australian Outback and like
the fucking Mojave Desert L wild and
yeah but everywhere it'll be covered
with something whether it's weeds or
sticks I mean she doesn't allow that all
right so let's uh you want to grab your
uh she yeah yeah you want to see that
you want to see a cool Shear you want to
use the she let's let's do the cool
let's all right I'll be right back I'll
be right back measure temperatures we'll
time we got all sorts
of afternoon
activities who you got the vest on too
yeah here squeeze that that's an F
that's a Pam F2 this one was very
similar to Mama very very very very
similar of course I you just handed it
to me as I have like wet
hands Sor sorry all right of
course you got to you know molest that
one a little bit cuz it's in the bag and
it's fresh but it gets this weird it
gets weird funkiness too she's got some
that's got some cheese in there that's
got some fruit bunny you know some which
one this was which one that's the Pam F
to that's that one right
there smell that you know and you smell
this
one squeeze did yeah give that freaking
break one of those break it and it's a
nice N I like these nugs yeah the small
sorts of things going on in there so how
long so you what's your like drying
curing
process um since you just finished it
with this well I wouldn't call that
finished I'd say it's in process it's
what we're smoking because that's what
we're smoking um but I like to hang it
pretty much full plant hang you know if
if they're 7f Footers I got to cut it
into three sections because I can't hang
you know seven eight Footers like is
easy with the floor space and stuff so
you got to cut it into like pieces a
couple of pieces but fewer pieces the
better I think keeping the bigger stems
and stuff on there is what I do and then
I hang them I have a couple of big tents
that sit empty that I don't use anymore
that I use big tents big old
oldfashioned like there like a 5x5 a 6
by something just a couple old tents
that I just don't use anymore so I set
them up about you know a month ago and I
start hanging H and stuff in the tents
and they sit in there there's no fan
they sit open and then they're in a
temperature controlled room so like the
room itself is like 60 68 you know it
doesn't get like it doesn't get I would
love to have it at 55 you know and
colder heated by the sun huh by the sun
no I have a little little air
conditioning in this particular space
it's nothing crazy and I can only get it
to about 68 is like the coldest without
causing a problem um so that's where
they sit for
7 to 10 days s to you know something
like that depending on the year if it's
Santa Anna like it was when those came
down I mean it was like it was harder to
keep it you know the the more leaves you
keep on there the more stuff you keep on
there the the the more you can slow it
down so I left more foliage on there you
know during that time uh but yeah you're
yeah s to 10 days they're hanging there
and then they come out they go into bins
big plastic bins and they kind of sit
there and the bins the tops don't go on
the bins but they're on the bins you
know cuz kind of air can kind of get in
there but then they kind of rehydrate a
little bit you know by sitting in the
bins for a little bit and they're in
that same room same temperature and then
I start you know when everybody's asleep
and I'm not too dead I go to trim jail
and I I break out the trim bins and I
set up all my stuff and I get the the
things going and we you know we go to
town and I usually trim for freaking
months man because and I don't trim very
much I mean this is the most trimmed you
ow see it and I just kind of like I even
like Hal trimmed part of it just to make
them you know not look all leafy in the
bag you know but I try to keep stuff on
it through time because I can't get to
it all myself yeah you know has you know
I have you know all kinds of stuff I run
all kinds of businesses I got kids I got
yeah I got to do it and so it takes me a
while to get the trim stuff done so but
whatever
you are you is it you're not do you have
a light you're not putting it out into
no no yeah no so every summer I'll grow
enough like so last summer is like my
seed summer I made all seed and all my
stuff was in the ground big plants for
seed and that that stocks up my seed you
know uh my coolers for my seed and then
that that hurt my productivity for last
year because 90% of my crop was for seed
and then I had to rely on my indoor crop
you know to pull my my smoke you know
what I mean but yeah so this year was
the crop for for setting up the setting
up the season and then now I'll go into
seed and I'll do seed through the rest
of this season and then the winter and
stuff like that I'll go work on my seed
stuff but basically afterwards you're
going to keep it on the vine for as long
as possible yeah on the vine as long as
possible and uh cuz we've seen that even
commercially people are getting into
like selling it yeah yeah on the vine
yeah the old uh the old uh Silver Dragon
cannabis I know that I I met yeah yeah I
know I met that guy up in Humble I
forget his name really cool character uh
really really nice really radical dude
and like he started talking about that
and then I started seeing I'm like dude
that that you know we talked about that
it's it's really cool man he's a cool
dude I really uh we talk every once in a
while he came down to San Diego a couple
times he's a he's a cool dude from the
hills got a little push back from people
what yeah people people don't like stems
and they don't like leaves like you're
making me do your work but no that's not
cool they're like oh like so he's not
selling them care and I get all twig and
no there's a couple of us that
appreciate that you know what I mean and
that's that's that's where it that's
where it is I wouldn't base my whole
thing on it
but definitely is cool oh my God look at
that thing yeah this is the Falco 820
wouldn't go anywhere without
it wow thing is a wow thing is a beast
don't put your finger I could yeah I
always I always wished for a daughter so
that I could strap her boyfriend down
and then take him into the garage and
just start hacking on freaking things
you know cuz I can cut through I mean I
can cut through all this stuff I mean I
can cut through this trunk of this tree
with one one swoop and it it it'll go
through 3 in like cheddar um one of the
coolest plants on planet Earth I mean
planet tools on planet Earth and it
saves my life too cuz I do tons of
pruning it's all push button and I was
going to have to have surgeries and
stuff and it and it completely
rehabilitated me you have good control
on it so you can do yeah so check it out
so you can shorten it down to small
precise rapid cut motion right you want
bigger Cuts you can get it up to Lopper
size right like that and then if you
really want
you have Precision control so you can
just press it and it's got Precision
control so you can really be intricate
it's the same exact freaking tool as my
sidearm here exactly except it don't
take any strength which is the best
thing in the world it's not cheap like
Bic robot arm it is a robot arm it's a
and that's the battery yeah it's a
battery pack I can store two batteries
in here which is cool and the cool thing
about it is I can charge this thing and
like I think I can get up to like you
know somewhere around 24 hours of
constant use you know or close to it
maybe you know more than half a day a
constant use like constant use like stff
it's my best friend I mean one charge
usually lasts me a couple days because a
big tree that normally took me 3 hours
now takes me an hour and a half you know
what I mean it cut my time in half mouth
only gets so far open so is there a
larger version there is other versions
but once if it's any bigger than this
big then I have uh and I got my saws and
chainsaws and other saws like that that
are there but like changing tools and
stuff like I used to have to tools all
the time cuz you can't cut stuff with
this like that you know so saves so much
time let's let's let's give me the
biggest one where's the biggest let's
let's cut it down so you can see it in
action okay let's see here let's just
get this cleaned
up shorten it down so it's
quicker all right you do any type of
pruning or rose pruning or fruit tree
pruning or ganja prun I mean and you do
a lot of it save your life man use a
they have other ones that are a lot
cheaper than this one that are like
compressed air that do a similar thing
you can just pop in a little little
whipp it thing or whatever and uh you
can kind of go to yeah yeah come and
come go to town for a little while you
know and they work pretty good so I
mean sorry home
skillet looks like like a poodle that
got shaved right I'm going to cut it
down to the ground level cuz we want to
you know utilize this right one cut
beautiful nice and clean see you later
brother
you know that's the cambium layer that
Green Layer right in there this is like
your you know this is your your cambium
this is where we do lots of grafting and
stuff this is where we would split it
and I would put you know I'd put
something into this bark if this was
upside down this was the trunk of a tree
and I cut the head off of it and I
wanted to actually graph this plant so
like we're talking like plums yeah
Citrus avocado whatever you basically
cut off the say
here
right say that's a tree right we cut his
head off we want to make this a
different tree and this is a plum and I
want to put a cherry on it you know you
come up here you cut it head out nice
and clean it's where you got a good
cambium there and we take this sucker
and we'll split the
bark just like so kind of rock it in
there give it a good press and then I
can
actually crack this off a little bit and
this is not the tool to use but I can do
it cuz I've done it a million times
super siiz knife and then you take uh
the plant that you really want you're
like oh man I want the I want this
freaking TK on
the on the freaking you make a little uh
it's got to be nice and clean and not be
nice and sharp which is why you want to
use your your grafting knife or
something that's really Mak nice not not
your D knife yeah not the one that does
my digging but the
idea is you expose about an inch and a
half or so of the cambium layer on this
side and you can leave this back side
here you make a little bit better cut
here but the idea since we're not
talking about grafting and then you
slide this hand just like a a little
pencil gently you tape it up yep
gently
and and then on this side you can see it
like and if this was a fruit tree i'
slice this down a little bit more and
really make it perfect but the idea is
to break open that cambium layer
slightly oh yeah you pop you pop it into
the side into this cambium lay so that
the part you cut Falls right in line
with the other stuff and we take some
tape or some grafting wax and we tape
that sucker up and bang this thing would
uh harden off at the right time of year
and would all of a sudden fuse and then
this would be your own tree of whatever
variety you put in using this is the
root stock that's how they graft all
your fruits you know that's one of the
ways they do it's called a b graft so
it' be like if you gave my if you put
like my brain onto a different body
exactly yeah two different plants on One
Tree I'd be like thank you for the use
of your body exactly exactly have the
genetics of both yeah yeah um now could
you do this with weed you can do this
with weed I've never um what was the wax
you talked about there stuff called
grafting wax you can use any wax
honestly I use I've used candle wax
where you just coll light a candle and
you're literally ripping wax on there
and basically you're just sealing up all
the air holes and you want to tape this
really good with some stretchy tape or a
graphing tape or you can use electrical
tape you can use the various things but
you're basically going to push this down
as high as you can to force it against
itself so what about this that you want
to close up all of that in there yeah so
then you would you don't want to put wax
inside of any hole you want to smear it
over the top so that it doesn't like
fall in there very easily how the fuck
do you keep it from falling in it's
thick wax and it and it and'll you can
kind of just smear it over the top so it
doesn't fall you know I mean or you can
use tape and and it's an art that's part
of the that's a part of the skill you
know what I mean it's like taking out a
transmission or whatever there's little
tricks that dudes do that we can you
know get away with things that are like
how the fuck did he do that but no wax
down but you don't want to jam wax into
the cut because then that will seal off
the connection of where it needs to be
touching to fuse together so you want to
cover it so air and water can kind of
get in there and you can use tape to do
that you can use it just depends on what
you have in hand how good you are but um
that's that's a cool little side
Sidetrack thing on this grafting which
is funny um but yeah you can technically
do it with Canabis I've never uh set up
a plant which I meant to for years to
just set up a host plant and Pam would
be a good host plant for that and you
can do it on another species right like
you could graph the Cannabis
onto hops the same family right so I
don't know 100% if it would be
successful but Hops and cannabis are
related I don't know if it's Clos enough
related where we could actually graft it
but they have to be in the same family
they have to be like like prunus plums
and peaches and stuff they're all a
family of prunus you know so um they
have to be in the same family Citrus you
can do it with Citrus you can put an
orange a lemon on a Grapefruit Tangerine
All in One Tree and I a little citrus
salad graft and they do that which is
totally cool but it's all citrus they
all got to be relatives you know um wait
so you could on like the same base you
could have like one arm that's a that's
grapefruit the next arm's a green one's
that orange as you know as many as you
can support or success they sell them in
like four or five graphs already if you
go to like a just a Retail Nursery and
you're like I want a citrus salad tree
or a fruit salad tree they call them
fruit salad or citrus salad you know the
citrus salad will have a lemon a lime an
orange a tangerine and like a grapefruit
or some other type of tangelo or some
random fruit but you have like the
Staples plus one uh and you can buy that
tree for like 200 bucks in like a retail
shop you know and plant as long as with
graphs each branch is its own tree so
each it has its own personality and and
own growth habit and own like things
that it wants to do so you have to keep
them all equal size cuz there's always
going to be one I always say there's
always one big brother that wants to
grow bigger and stronger and faster than
the other two big brothers and he'll
dominate the other ones out of existence
he'll take more of their food their
nutrients and then all of a sudden your
graphs start getting depleted and you
got this one thing that was really tough
so you keep them pruned so that each
graft is about the same equal size mass
and then they'll all play together and
have a good time so they just it's it's
more of a like a talking concept and
like I got this this is really cool it's
a Pastime thing production it sucks
don't plant that tree cuz you're doing
all kinds of stuff and you got to prune
it too much and your production suffers
and it's just like you know it's just
it's a lot of work but it's very cool um
very cool all right so let's see you do
this one all right
That's it man if you had one on each arm
I know Edward Scissor
Hands FAL
a20 and then we can just leave this on
top you put it in here I would dig it in
you know if you want to get its full
maximum benefit but then or you cover it
with mulch or you cover it because if
you just leave this on the surfice this
sun will oxidize a lot of that nutrition
and you won't get its full benefit
you'll get benefit but you won't get it
like you know the the
full the full deal so however you kind
of want to but I would dig it in there
and cover it this is our rebirth yeah
totally um yeah I'm sorry dude I'm sorry
brother well that's okay I mean the
thing is is that this is a lesson right
here taught you man but they also they
did so well up until that point that
there's a lot you take it for
sure yeah man every year is a new
learning experience bro that I learned
something new maybe just yeah I was
going to say right now we could cut some
of these up into smaller pieces and we
can just bury them
later I always make killer poers out of
you know a good stemmer to man make some
killer pokers out of those things I make
a mic stand out of a few just like that
meno dope I got a couple of those we got
these
two can Tom can pull theer I know it's I
know I know you do it man I know I know
exactly how you feel brother Tom let's
do it quick Bullet to the
Head you want me to take it off for you
you take it off you want this well it's
yeah you want see what you got we'll
keep it see what you got here I mean
yeah you keep it so it doesn't fall in
the dirt and get more dirty or
whatever and I'll give you this other
top here I'll give you a couple of these
tops you guys can kind of sort through
those tops up a little bit better see if
there's anything left in there that
one's
toast yeah bang bang just cuz it's
fun how much do those cost uh they're
like it's about two grand for the thing
they're like yeah probably
1,800 save up for that one
uh you can get you can yeah you can get
uh you can get like I said before you
can get the ones that are less um
expensive they're for like $4 or $500
this plant was not here my my Gardener
actually actually some of these look
good it's it has nothing to do with this
let's get that out of here I was going
to say is like here all my fing check
this out check this out let's see what
this says actually while we're standing
here temperature yeah let's see what it
says just for GRS
right it's probably not bad but let's
just see what it says this one yeah this
looks okay this one does look okay this
looks pretty good actually have you been
picking uh
I haven't found any
93 so what does that mean so above
85 110 on the outside of that fabric pot
right there you got 110 right there wow
how hot is it outside right now I think
it's less than 110 oh it's a lot less
than 110 it's like 70 it's like 75
right so so if you you can imagine like
this sitting in the sun it's 110 right
now it's not 110 throughout that whole
thing but everywhere where those surface
roots are everywhere where that that
most action is there where the life is
happening it's it's above 85 degrees and
when you get above 85 Degrees most
plants are like fuck that they start
shutting down they stop drinking water
and then usually above 85 Dees the
workers that live in the soil the
microbes and other things they don't
live there or they don't want to work
anymore so they go to sleep I'm going to
take they go they die they do that and
then being uncovered there's no way for
any of those organisms to really occupy
and live there like efficiently so he's
hungry he's hot and he's not drinking
water for most of the time that he
exceeds the the you know that 85 Mark
and I mean they can they can do okay at
85 but once you start getting 110 you
know 99 I mean it's nothing wants to be
over 100 we don't want to work at 100
they don't want to work at 100 it's
just that's that's just the nature of
the B so I always want to shoot what it
is and these are even the tan ones right
and you're shooting the outside of the
tan pots and those are supposed to
reflect the heat which they do
tremendously compared the others but
that's still 109 right so but they need
the Sun so the the idea is what do you
do you cover it it has to have cover you
have to have that clothes over the skin
to protect it so that it at least has
that buffer zone uh that will drop and
if you look at anything in Earth that's
actually covered with the appropriate
amount of of stuff it'll always be yard
it'll always
be about 60 to 60 to 85 but it'll always
be about 70 5 you go anywhere on earth
right so let's check this out we you had
this straw out here move the straw
aside you're at 82 de yeah right I mean
that's way better than about let's do
this the whole point we I had the straw
in here yeah so that's that's that's
correct so then you're regulating better
can we check out this and you're and
you're below you're below that 85 right
and I mean it's like I said it's below
that down low and other things but
that's that it's this it's it's this if
you feel the soil if you reach down you
can touch the soil and it's hotter and
it's as hot as your body or warmer then
it's got your soil's got a fever and
it's not functioning to where it should
be you know in a lot of cases and that's
beautifully cool ask and it's sitting in
full sun 81 right now where it was 100
100 on the surface we're crushing it
down below but early on the bamboo I had
up and they were really thriving when
they were within the BAM this bamboo
structure I put up they were getting
plenty of Sun
but also it was interspersed so the
leaves were being cooled and so is that
something is that you know was that you
know so when the plants are young they
don't have a lot of mass they're not
dropping a lot of shade onto the canopy
floor right under there so there's more
exposure it's more you know more app to
temperatures fluctuating so if you don't
have a ton of mulch or they're really
young it'll get hotter quicker so having
the bamboo created more shade and more
moisture was able to hang out there for
longer and that was that was totally
fine okay so here's my other question
out here in the valley we reached 117 oh
yeah yeah yeah it was not yeah it was
not pretty was that mine that's not you
right so I was in the same position and
I mean I didn't have any problems at all
I mean granted I'm in the ground so when
you're in the ground and you're at 110
for a couple days the plants can
tolerate that as long as you put water
out there and they they're okay you got
cover you're good the temperature it's
110 outside if you got cover on the
ground it'll still be below 85 it'll
still be right in that habitable zone no
matter what and that's the beauty of it
all and you can go to the Redwood Forest
or the Amazon or any place where plants
are growing or we're not scratch aside
the the forest floor and shoot the soil
and it will always be in that range 60
to 80 60 to 85 always that's where
nature regulates the temperature that's
the magic Zone you know and that's
there's even a book about it called like
59 degre about the for the pl will be
able to respirate it'll be able to do
all of that as long as it's cooled down
below and then every all the organisms
and things that want to live there will
want to work and occupy and do that and
you don't want it too cool because below
that you know below 60 you got a band of
yeah nobody wants to work below it
starts getting cold they start shutting
down and doing their thing it's it so it
can go in the reverse but the
insulation keeps it from jumping around
and keeps it from going either way too
far which is really cool so that's the
importance of the of the mulch like
firsthand like not having it and having
it you can see the difference in in what
the temperature is you know what I mean
and that and that has a great effect on
everything so so can we use that tool to
just cut these big pieces up a little
bit
oh you had one guy on who said that when
it got really hot he sort of was misting
his plants a little bit I would never
miss my plants during the heat of the
day or after he did say that or after or
after about nobody said he did he he set
the he say he goes He above them just
yeah so like that's how you get
powdering mildew problems because you're
increasing the the the the DraStic
shifts and humidity and things right so
if you do it before right someone who
came here no it was on when on your sh
so so like in Arizona I'm from Arizona
originally like my my grandparents
everybody lives out there it's 120
every day I mean just freaking miserable
from May on you know what I mean and
they misting systems and things but the
way you keep out of trouble is it's like
early in the morning like like late
morning tops you can miss done but as
soon as you're at noon or afterwards and
we're at that Peak and the Sun is at its
crucial as Point down and it's said and
you're just especially you're just
you're hurting yourself I think I think
you should if I don't hit
my I mean I'd rather water the ground
which is still cause for concern after
that noon because of the moisture and
stuff but I'd rather do that than spray
the plants themselves just because it's
just such a drastic fluctuation and
that's kind of what happens but when
it's over 110 anyway powdery mildew
really can't live in those high
temperatures anyway so it's kind of
like you know it's not the worst thing
in the world because at high high
temperatures they tell you heat heat
will kill the mil Spore you know above I
think it's above 95 or something we'll
actually start killing the Milo spores
for a certain period of time so if
you're over 110 and you're missing
mildew is not your problem but if the
next day and the day after aren't 110
and it's in those ranges for milw to
take hold you've created you know
problem in my opinion you know that way
so did you see any problems with any of
the crops or any of the people you've
been working with that hit 115 or above
so it's so the guys that had him in pots
like you there was there was an old an
old friend of mine I I call him I call
him the cool old guy but um he he has
bigger pots than that I think they were
like 30 gallon or something they were
uncovered and they were the fabric pots
and during that heat wave the the plants
that were in there really drooped and
suffered and all of the pistols started
to to turn and really had a bad effect
on the plants themselves to the point
where they never came back out of it to
where he had to harvest them
early um the ones in the ground are
going to be a lot more resilient to the
temperatures especially if you have the
the molch down if you don't have the
molch down then you're in trouble it's
going to have a hard time in those
temperatures but they can Toler it they
don't like it they just don't do much in
it so if they if you can just get them
to not do anything as opposed to like
get sick then that's better than than
you know what I mean going downhill you
know so you just on those hot days you
got to make sure that they're well
hydrated in the soil early or later that
that night before Tom's yard is an
example of like this area which is
always in the shade and has the same
irrigation is like your feet sink into
the ground and then over here always hot
it's like always hot and dry and then
you have like some spots it kind of runs
down there so it stays soft here it's
it's totally hard almost we just moved
in so we're just trying kill the
sprinklers on that side for deal with
this I have to kill the sprinklers and I
have to figure out which section does
the and kill those and and but yeah this
is as hard as a rock all right so this
is all little calcium so get some get
some of that calcium give it some
calcium and give it some microbes man
and that stuff will come back calcium
will loosen up the soil structure I love
that it'll give a little bit of
something give some micros you can try
doing something like that yeah you feed
it to I me raw
milk do you guys eat eggs I do I'm going
to got to look up Chris Trump man and
learn how to make the WCA stuff it works
good
absolutely
so so good job yeah so chop up more of
the stuff for you help you up a little
bit this is so much more satisfying than
if we had
to right cut all this I got a hand on my
hip brother we're good show show me the
shears we would have used where are
yours mine are uh well no your what we
would have been chopping with th is like
some something in here brother give a
chop here give me this is all I got yeah
that
works work they don't get very wide
though it would have been
problematic yeah as soon as I got this
man I was I was having all kinds of
problems with my shoulders and my wrists
I couldn't lift things out of the fridge
or pick up my kids doctors wanted to
give me surgery so you know putting a
layer of straw on top of raised beds is
something kind of everyone does but like
would you ever just use like I have so
many uh you use it in the garden too
what I was going to say I have so many
leaves that like can you just put like
what's wrong with a layer of leaves is
that equally cuz I feel like everyone
has leaves what why do people buy straw
people throw away what they should be
using on their land so at my house
nothing leaves my land like in the green
bin my green bin is always empty like I
never put it out on the street for
collection for anybody to take like all
the leaves that come off of the the
plants or the trees or the branches that
I cut or the grass that's mowed or any
debris from the from the land all either
gets put on the ground is mulch you know
if it's nice leaves I always put out
leaves at the end of the year as soon as
everything drops I'll rake up a bunch of
leaves and dump them in my Orchard that
is magic man that's Leaf all that good
Leaf M but then how come so many people
with raised beds don't just use the
leaves around their yard because most
people are afraid of the diseases that
come with the plants that they're using
so like if they got a bunch of leaves
that fell they know it's cleaner right
and they're not they're worried about
the but the the idea that I have in my
mind is yeah obviously you don't want to
put a bunch of disease like directly on
your thing but nature nature is not
stand right over there like nature is
not really picking and choosing and in
most cases the good will always outweigh
the bad if you got a good system cuz
what I do with my leaves is they're dry
and then I let them totally dry out
until I canap World bro so you don't
want to use eucalyptus leaves you don't
want to use U straight pine pine needles
Mulberry great excellent food source or
Magnolia no Magnolia Magnolia is not the
end of the world that'll work too that's
fine if they're really dry they're good
if they're really wet I no no I let I
let them bake in the sun then you're
good then then yeah even if they're
crushed a little bit someone was uh
Pedro this morning was saying he's been
collecting pine needles and I was like
that's that's what I said cuz I I had a
Pine Forest growing up and like else the
pine yeah so Pines emit tannins through
their leaves through their Roots through
their needles through everything that
they create and these they're these oils
that kind of discourage the growth of
other plants you to cut that right there
yes sir um so when you plant underneath
of a eucalyptus or a pine tree or any of
those things it's a constant oil forest
from those trees that are segregating
themselves off so that's why you say you
go to a Pine Forest you only see pine
trees for the most part that was my
opinion plus they're really really
acidic
and adding too many of them can throw
things out of balance but it's really
the oils and the tannins in them but
small quantity small quantity I'm okay
with the small quantity yeah yeah less
than yeah 5% or less go for it no
problem right um not a problem but like
if you're starting to use that as like
your Source all the time or like it's
your main source then hell no don't
don't ever use pine needles like that or
eucalyptus leaves but once they're
really dry and over you know overly dead
and been around for a season or two
sitting there if you're going to store
it then things will lose their tannins
and you can start to turn into carbon
that's usable and I think I think that's
where they're talking about introducing
it probably yeah so if you're going to
take it through a process or something
and then like you know do it in some way
then that's okay but collecting it and
using it as much no I wouldn't do that
yeah that's no good yeah but those are
the two big ones that I wouldn't use is
eucalyptus leaves and pine needles
checking but other than that uh I mean
most things are pretty pretty good and
especially if it's good and dead and
it's been dead a long time you're better
off if you're going to do chop and drop
like I do a lot of chop and drop where
you're dropping green stuff like this on
the ground so talk to me about what
you're seeing here like healthy I mean
th this is looking healthy so some
people say like the the hollow stems is
like Boron or other things um some of my
Hollow stems are some of my best plants
like in a lot of cases where I'll go
through and I'll be like oh you're the
sometimes they have like the most that I
me this isn't Hollow down here it's just
Hollow on the and there's going to be a
little Hollow where the sap is and it'll
lose it you know lose it over time you
know and sometimes they really harden up
but you see all that sap that's kind of
in there and like as I break this
everything in there kind of collapses
too you know so it's it's it's not quite
as Hollow as it kind of appears but it
is hollow and then it's nutrition in
some way I mean towards the end of the
flower cycle it's using a lot of the
minerals and the microminerals is that
what's passing through there and yeah
and that's got it's sending a lot of
nutrition through the
around the outside layer that intern you
should get naked and roll around in this
bed before you go inside you want me to
chop this one you want to save this one
you want to do want me to do something
with this uh yeah this can be chopped
okay I don't want to step out of line
there so so you wouldn't uh use one of
those like mulchers that you could buy
at Home Depot and just like I would but
I'd mulch it into a corner and let it
sit for well yeah okay heck yeah now
well actually why why wouldn't you bury
it in here like you're doing like so in
small scale like if you're going to chop
and drop like I wouldn't do a whole just
slew of just tons of just green stuff on
the ground uh sometimes with like trees
anyway like the bark and those things
like the the raw woods and things that
aren't that aren't broken down this
isn't too much this isn't too much you
can till this in this will turn in a
combo and it's softer stuff it's not
necessarily like a a tree would be or
but if we had like three times the
amount of this I would try to do yeah
I'd spread it out a little bit um just
because sometimes the green stuff takes
energy to break down so if you're
demanding resources sometimes it robs
from other things especially with barks
and different things that are too fresh
it'll steal nitrogen and other nutrients
and things and to its process so just
letting it do its thing satisfying it'll
be better off there a certain
satisfaction it's like when you're you
know done doing a play and you strike
the set um there's a certain s s
that's the noise that like uh like uh
You' be surprised nobody knows that this
I love it matter of fact you could sell
some of those it's insane you know
people should be purchasing those they
should they absolutely I go to all these
nurseries people like what the hell is
that it's like man it took me a while to
realize have a large grow and you're
doing a lot of pruning pruning how much
do those cost about two on are almost
2,000 yeah if you want like an extra
battery and like all the funny stuff wow
yeah so they're no joke uh smaller
version you get a smaller version for
like 500 Tom now we're getting into the
price somewhere in there it's not quite
the same but it is the same it's much
better than that but what's the brand is
this like f FCO is the best man I don't
care need that if you're Fel is the best
Swiss Swiss made gu this thing right
here is freaking guaranteed for life and
the reason why it's also the best out to
the reason why is like you can buy all
these parts at a nursery like every
blade every screw every piece of this
thing you know every it's like DeWalt
all the parts everyone has to stock all
the parts so all you need to do is buy
this once and you can change the blade
for 12 bucks and it's good for forever
again you know what I mean over and over
again um they're the shit they they work
way better than anything else they're
the
shit so I've used everything these are
the these are the best ones do you want
any of these uh sweet compromise buds
for your compost at home so all of my
one thing I'm not lacking is is stuff to
put into my compost all my trim
everything that I take down all the
stocks all the leaves all the crappy
buds all the trim that I would make hash
out of all that goes back into the
orchard onto the floor just goes to the
forest floor CU it's all it's all the
bioaccumulated stuff from my Orchard
anyway it's full of nutrition and that
just goes out to the mold pile every
year I got a
big purple started coming out at at a
certain I don't know what what like if
that was well that's that's what there
that plant was going to do it was going
to give a little purple into it and you
were going to get a little bit of color
and the as the fall approached you going
to get get and worse the veining started
happening which was cool that would have
been really pretty I mean it it still
kind of is but it really would have been
a nice let's pretty thing let's chop
that one too I mean
I I mean I could show you some freaking
Beauties just sitting underneath the net
dude just happy as can be just some
Beauties you
know just like Beauty literally
literally looking at M and like giving
him the finger you know what I mean like
no can you get that one I don't want to
bring the whole yes
sir
nice but yeah I don't care like making
room like I just I I don't want to spray
anything man so we started using those
Nets some people don't like the Nets
they think it you know some people can't
put them up they don't have the space
that too hard to go in no way bro all
right
that's that's what that's what Tom ask
his wife sometimes so this is pretty
much history as well right yeah let's
let's just start fresh I would uh I mean
there's not even anything on here I'll
leave you with a bag or two with that
stuff over there so you won't you won't
be lost
100% I'm sorry dude Merry Christmas
Merry
fucking this this like but this taught
you so much you know I mean like
seriously you're you're you learned shit
you didn't even know you learn you'll
remember next year you be like fuck man
this is how it's done brother taught us
that there's a cool tool that we must
have I'm all I'm all into forensics of
any kind so this has been forensically
do you watch uh investigation discovery
yes dude it's on it's on like 85% of the
time courtesy of Laura she loves them
yeah I think women get totally into like
it's like murder mystery after murder
mystery after murder I don't know if
she's like like plant you you you never
know what's going so what's that one 97
inside 104 on the outside wow so it's
not I mean I mean that's like that's
livable temperatures but being in such a
small space plants are going to have a
hard time yeah I I think in the I mean
for the rest of the year we'll be
fine perfect for the
co so so there's a real both ways but so
there's a real ideal purpose for these
small cloth pots like because they do
tend to get hot and so so yeah yeah um
you know it seems like they're not like
you don't want to keep your plant in
there for very long because it's just
too hot in envir in the winter time I
think is a good time to use those
personally because they keep warmer than
a plastic outside shell would right that
plastic pot on the outside is going to
get cold no matter where you put it no
matter what unless this be a starter
environment that is a great winter pot
in my opinion like a starter winter pot
you can grow small plants in there
easily in the win mean in the summer I
mean I have huge squat and strawberries
growing I mean you can and there's
nothing wrong with that but it's not the
if they're good and people pull lots and
if you've been using it my dad always
says best tool in the toolbox is the one
that works for you that you know how to
use and that's it and some people man
those are Superstar you know pots for
and that's fine so what do you use but
personally I use regular old pots like
regular old black plastic pots and the
ground those are the two things that I
use um period that's what nurseries have
been using for you know 100 hundreds
plus years and I mean it's just that's
just that it's
nothing if you transplant
appropriately then the root tips and all
that stuff all that stuff doesn't matter
it's irrelevant you know what I mean if
you're just growing a healthy plant
you're you I mean the outside of my pots
are root tips and hairs and beautiful
shit when I pull them out of there you
know what I mean it's not it's not the
end of the world and also the thing that
I didn't like about the the fabric pots
the most out of everything was
transplanting them like can't get them
out of there without kind of like
ripping or or doing stuff unless it's a
velcro one and those ones were cool
actually that's what I was just those on
were cool yeah so the velcro ones were
cooler cuz I was stoked on the velcro
versions cuz you can pop that out of
there a lot easier but like I said if it
works for you it works for you I'm good
with that so but that said you can get a
more amable environment in these larger
beds larger beds yes that's got good
breathability the larger situation I
think are way more better idea on that
aspect because wood rots
fabric you can kind of get away with it
takes a lot of time it's lighter to set
up and move ready for the 4 by8 I'm good
with that maybe so if you're not in the
ground or cuz then you're at 4 exactly I
believe that you need the more space
especially if you're growing with soil
you need a bigger battery the bigger
battery means you need a bigger space to
pull from it's not going to get hot and
cook you you is there a big difference
between having a 2x4 and a 4X4 yeah yeah
yeah I mean yeah yeah there is there is
yeah it's a bigger Universe for the The
Life just their squish yeah they just
yeah you just don't have enough I mean
you're living in Mom's basement you know
you have a you have an end right this is
Mom's basement right and this better you
got your own place right you got a
little one bedroom right so you're a
little bit you know what I'm saying it's
a little bit better I mean shoot though
if you don't have to pay rent in Mom's
basement you might be able to get away
with so there are benefits both ways but
bigger is always better in my opinion
see what the great one is
anyway 116
soil is moist in this it's
moist but it's that's that's at
96 and wet so the soil is wet it's a 96
so the even though that there's water in
here the plant can't uptake it properly
because the temperatures it's kind of in
hold mode to not you know so it's and
it's too hot anyway so and you can also
see the plant itself yeah the leaves are
tacoed like taco shells right and when
they Taco up like that tomatoes are kind
of they do that anyway in the sun that's
one of the defense mechanisms but all
plants that kind of Taco up like taco
shells like that are trying to make
themselves smaller minimalize their
exposure to the Sun and try to drink any
Dew that settles on the leaves you know
so they can funnel it to the to the
roots it means they're too hot or they
need more water and those are two those
are the two signs classically and then
you shoot it with the thermometer and
it's too hot and you can see it's
telling you that you know just by the
way that the leafes are cupping in that
regard so things that that tells you you
know but you don't even need one of
these all you need to do is go like this
and if it's as hot as you or hot then
you need to figure out a way to just
just slow it down and and in the winter
you want it actually kind of feels a
little cooler yeah that side yeah yeah
on that side cuz I have shade over there
but and and like I said it work it works
both ways to benefit and to detriment
you know what I mean it just depends
it's a it's a you deploy it in the right
situation it's a star for you you know
all right but every you set up one of
these man you'll get every nug guarantee
it you love it it'll be ugly and you
know but hey you get every nug if you
set up a nice one like this you know
like I do you can walk in there and just
hang out with them and then like at
night and stuff like no bugs are biting
you and shit cuz you're in your freaking
little little mosquito Hut you know what
I mean you can you can work in there and
it's safe and it's clean and it's just
it's just cool and it's not I mean it's
not super
expensive any joke does shift to to be
able to do that it's not no it's nothing
it's really it's makeshift but it's
totally effective it totally works and
Ian it's something like I bought weird
stuff I have real green houses I I
oversee in cool commercial operations I
mean we've I've I've had 100 lighters
and then at home I deploy freaking TVC
P of our the tree here and tell me like
yeah so it's good because it's got cover
right so This Grass serves as your mulch
this is your cover Zone it's a color
that's not going to it's going to be a
buffer it's at 84 so it's below that
Mark right and that's on the surface of
the grass if you go under the grass
which we can't it'll be much cooler than
that so our the leaves aren't tacoing
right they're not really shriveled up
they were like yeah the flowers will
yeah that's normal really okay that's
normal it'll go through a balloon period
it'll shrivel up and set it seed and and
the nut this is where it should be
that's where it should be yeah uh you
don't I don't love when when air can
kind of swoop underneath of a root like
this right like having them at the surf
is where you want it but when air and
stuff can kind of start ripping through
there in other places I would always
suggest add a little bit of something
just to cover that like what a little
bark chip couple leaves straw just don't
pile it up on like crazy but just just
cover it up so air doesn't swoop
underneath that Crown okay and it's not
yeah it will live like this just fine
and you'll see that nature just fine I
just it just eliminates a a beacon for
me personally beautiful uh keep them
extra healthy and you won't have to
worry about
it all right
should we call it a wrap on that this
has been
great I mean look look look look what is
not there anymore I know sad isn't it
but we get to restart get to start
that's the fun part now it's all the
dream start again you know what I mean
and there's a there's a uh look at that
that soil is going to be humming yeah
yeah kind throw some compost in there
turn that up a little bit can I get some
compost from you I mean there's some
like you know like I said like some
people will freak out and be like oh
there's buritis in there and there's you
know you know but we haven't seen I
don't really worry about that stuff you
practice a good system you put that down
on the ground you know you got healthy
stuff I think that you know I don't ever
have buritis at my house and I've do
that every year granted mine's in a food
forest and it's like in the ground but
it's everywhere already as it is and
it's our job to have good cell walls and
good practices to keep it from being
able to penetrate you know so honestly I
don't think that you have any issues
there but I'm sure there's somebody
that'll be like yo hey oh there'll
definitely be some comment I've done
I've done yeah I've done this a million
times this section is where you'll see
the spike in the comments this is full
this is full on like proven you know I
mean over years of time and I you know
it is what it is so do what you do nice
do it works for you man that's all I got
to
say I came out one night and shin the
light on the buds and it was like
Christmas it was like it was it was all
crystals and triom all across the butd
and the leaves and everything and I'm
like I never thought I'd be able to
create this I've seen it many times in
other people's grows I've visited so
many grows but I'd never and it's
finally I know man I remember that
feeling dude I remember I'm like dude I
did this this is better than all that
stuff on the fucking shelf this is
amazing you know yeah it's no it's you
can you can you just got to get to the
end it's these little things that'll
just make you get to the to the very end
I called Peter I'm like I need help he's
like I'm in Rhode Island
there's show you Pi well I told you what
to do or what to look for I did I looked
for them and found
them so here and check this out right
here look at this looks
great hang on second let me find you a
good little bacon grease here in a
couple of these that are coming on right
now
here let me pull up one of these right
here uh and what else do you uh do you
grow uh other uh like there's a there's
a there's another feno type of dog beach
that isn't ready yet that one's a nasty
gas one right there that's a good one
the one but you grow like peppers and I
grow everything brother everything um
beautiful literally I mean I have here's
a couple here's a couple of those I mean
there's a couple tents right there oh
you know there's a little part of my
little you know little thing that that
can you send that that you to him you
know couple of those little things I
don't know if you can see part of those
things send me those yeah so yeah
there's a couple of those where they're
just sitting up and you know just
they're just doing what they do sweet
and that's mosquito netting yep yep
that's big that's like that's easy yeah
I mean that's not like I said man
there's a lot of ways to skin a cat I
mean I'm a I'm a I'm going to put a door
in one yeah you can no you can't just
get an overlap and you just you just
flap it over and you set a rock on it
right and it'll pull it tight and you
can just open it right up man anytime
you want or you can I mean you can you
get creat cretive bro you can make them
tall and skinny you can make them well
there's there's it has to happen because
we get a lot of moths you're yeah you're
you're the here is you it's unbeatable
you're either going to spray your ass
off right or you're going to deploy
preventative measures but this is the
type of solution that I love yes I love
it's inexpensive it's handson it doesn't
compensate for monitoring everything no
no nothing does nothing nothing better
than the farmer Shadow yeah you know I
mean you have to be you have to be
present the love Factor the the presence
you know what I mean that's green thumb
that's the difference between you know
what I mean that is the difference the
fera who you haven't met I don't know
why she hasn't come out she has a good
green to thumb too but but um she's
accusing me of having one now and that's
that's nice well you you will now you
got it you
know you got chest full of stuff man
you're going to be in good shape like I
said you deploy that for everything I
throw all kinds of crap like I set up
these things for random stuff all the
time like for all kinds of stuff like oh
shit I'm going to have to set up a
fucking hoop I just set up a hoop and
like that solves the problem you know
what I mean and I don't have to worry
about it anymore I got too much to do
you know what I mean solv problem yeah
and I got to I want to set up a a small
worm bin too that's easy man yeah help
you with that too that's super easy you
know I know it's easy I just got to do
it yeah it's easy and uh I don't think I
need a tremendous amount of compost so I
can probably
you know yeah man you just use you know
use you buy a good bag of compost do
some compost extract
and I was making teas I can make I've
been make I got so I don't know if
you've ever heard of Organics alive yeah
yeah yeah I have but uh it was their
products and
regimen that uh you were resulted yeah I
was following their regimen looking good
yeah yeah yeah no that's cool yeah I
know those guys they they got stuff into
uh Anderson's nursery down by me when
they were just getting started it was
like one of those new guys and he was in
there doing the rep and I was the I was
the manager at the time uh at the
nursery and uh they ended up bringing
them in shortly there after some of that
stuff the Bigfoot one day all excited
and we put that in that's the bomb Tom
set him up for Success it was set up for
a success yep I make I you know I do
uh I'm really Rob like I said man I do
very little feeding I don't like to do
too much and I just you know you set
them in motion and that's the key so by
the way water those things cuz their
cups are going to get dry we should TR
so part of the reason why I was psych to
kill everything was so we can start
transplanting yeah totally those thing
out of the solo cupt put the chopper
here well there's some well but again
we're still we're putting them into the
bags but those are okay for now winter
time going into fall you're better off
we we've passed the peak Valley exactly
Heat
season also known as the
summer you guys see those trees out
there yes the big ones out there you see
how they were they're up on a mound f
fucking things right there every time
you can say it every time I I can say it
without even looking you know what I
mean no matter what it's like always the
case it
is and in nature in the forest that's
the tree that lives to be 200 or 300 or
3,000 or whatever it is you know that's
the one that was planted amongst the
others that was just in the right little
Hill the right looking at that how old
would you you what is it that is a um
liquid Amber tree um which one the one
out front the huge one yeah liquid Amber
it loses it leaves in the fall gets
really colorful uh it's like our fall
maple tree is our lookalike right it's a
really invasive plant breaks up
everything gets into the sewers it's an
awesome tree though man it's a it
supports so much life it does so much it
really does it's a great tree for like
the middle of the park and everything
but it's a crazy tree they planted a
bunch of these back in the day
especially in LA and in San Diego for
the color and they planted them on the
neighborhood roads and when you drive
down the roads and some of these old
ones you see all these you know cool
colorful things and stuff but DN man
they're just so their roots are insane
and that thing's got to be you know I
mean it's got to be I don't know when
this house was built but I'd say say
that thing's a 70y old tree probably I'd
say 60 years old 70 years old 60 years
old right around there cuz they grow
faster not really B Park how many seeds
are in here uh somewhere between seven
and 15 okay so some are seven some it
just depends on what I had left of
things put some into here and you can so
basically all I do is I take just like a
short cup I put a little bit of water in
I drop the seeds in the top they'll
float and then like 24h hour or 4 you
know 24 to 36 hours later we can
literally just put them right into soil
like that's that's the next stage those
Solo cups yeah yeah
um yeah those hubbles those are uh like
something in those In Those Jeans are
making that thing like slow to grow so
if you germinate them um germinate you
know germinate those ones because three
or three might two might not go they're
just they're honor they're got this
weird they're very selective some of the
land race stuff like it's a land race
trait where they don't want to grow
right away they want to sit dormant and
sometimes those recessive trades kind of
pop up and you know it's just weird a
bad thing because when they take they
really take they take and I guess those
are some of the best like unique plants
you'll find is in that in that Hubble
stuff something a little different that
nobody does so I'll pop a bunch and then
uh but those are also the shittiest germ
rated seeds that I that I had because
those are the last ones there's not that
many I was just giving you guys
something that really good that I knew
would be good you get something sweet
out of but there's not even anymore I
don't have any of at the banks anymore
cuz they're all that's it they're I'm
working on the Next
Generation Um now are you are you
constant are you have stuff going on all
the time well you're not in you're only
outside so you don't have continuous
Harvest I have yeah I have continuous
for the most part yeah cool yeah so a
phone yeah it's my phone I was like yeah
so yeah no like I like cuz I have I have
plants that are you know Seven 8 N9 10
years old you know I have clones that
I've kept for years you know so always
in my like in the summer in the summer
they come out cuz they're old and by
coming out and going into the ground
they can tap into the Earth fully
regenerate and rejuvenate and like a lot
of the old heads have always said well
if we take outside you can rejuvenate
them and I've been just I I fully am a
believer in that like they rejuvenate
them back to freaking brand new you know
what I mean you'll get these big thick
healthy branches and growth and then you
can take the Clones off of that right
and then those will be your new moms
those mom that go inside sitting for how
long the what seeds what are you talking
about those just a plant those just a
plant for the mom yeah so like those
ones will go inside and then over the
winter time basically keeping carbon
copies of that Mom for Generation
there's always something alive because
you can't lose those because those are
making those are those are those are my
flagships and then in the winter time
when even a seed from that will Express
itself slightly differently or nothing
just like that yeah it's just like me or
you if you have 50 kids none of them are
going to be you Tom there's never going
to be another you know so that's yeah
they'll be close but none of them will
be who you know and that's it that's it
will never you can you can get close but
you never get you um so you got that you
got the Clone and then in the winter
times when I do a lot of like
like my seed tests and my quick looks
because it's all quick and small and you
can do things in like one gallon pots
and two gallon pots and I can kind of
give them to all my other friends and we
can kind of go through a bunch of stuff
indoors and pick out the good guys that
we think are going to be good guys to
put outside for the full season and then
we run them full term and then when
they're really awesome either those will
get seeds or those will be whatever
that's that's how they kind of get get
vetted so there's always something going
because I always have to look at stuff
because I've got too many coolers of
seeds that I'll never get to no matter
how much I do it you know what I mean
how many people I invest in like please
do these ones for me and do these ones
for me you know what I mean cuz you
can't do it all you know you can't and
then until they can till we you know we
we really have cannabis Freedom you know
what I mean there's no way to you know
to really do it the way we need to so um
you guys ever pick
these like I'm wait that
one that one's Beyond right yeah the
bright one are you sure
this
one this one's you could take this
one one plan will be completely
different inside compared to outside
they express themselves completely
different you know sometimes it's like
wow this is the greatest indoor thing in
the world you put it outside and it's
like no this is dog shit Tom you should
make sunri and then vice versa you know
so you got it's you got to have it all
the way going you got to go all the time
all right well should we wrap on
that
the Tom Clap the Tom outro Clap the
signature the intro and the outro clap
um yeah and definitely kill this thing
this thing's not going to do any good
besides bring pests in it's basically a
plant that some dude was growing at his
house poorly that he was then like let
me put it in the middle of all your
plants I love it so kill it didn't know
I know he was being nice yeah that's all
but I mean he had it in it'll cost you
and what's this Tom do you remember what
this one is that's in the in the
dark right so you can cut this so we can
use all these things for new plants yeah
that one he
doesn't well you can yeah I'll let you
do that uh okay
oh