sure this is someone that's really
special to us someone that we're really
inspired by uh doesn't get a lot of
light shined on him just because he's
way up there in Washington we don't know
where that is is that in Canada but
here's our good friend Kenny Right Here
Mount Baker Highway we love him the time
he's going to tell us about his farm and
his practices up there he grows
incredible herb we love we grow his
strains grows a little bit of our
strains we got mad love for you Kenny
give it up for Kenny Mount Baker Highway
though
[Music]
good
uh yeah I was like thinking about what
to talk to you guys about and uh
I think like we're all in the
regenerative farming and we're all
growing stuff so we all put stuff in
pots you know
and uh like soil like what are we using
for our potting soil medium I figured
that's a good I talked about today but
yeah I'm up in Washington I don't know
if you guys don't know me but I don't
know everybody here maybe
but I got a farm up in Washington and uh
yeah we have a wreck license and we uh
we do like outdoor mostly and like that
all on the ground
um
yeah we don't do any lights or anything
uh
it's all closed loop pretty much like we
don't
when we started we were buying potting
soil and
it was organic and we just needed
potting so in the beginning of the
season and then the next season the
market crashed or like at the end of
that year
we're like we had no money in spring or
in the next season so
we just kind of went on this like
journey of learning how to like
make our own soil on the farm
and uh
basically what I started doing was I
just I was doing compost and that was
like okay I'm making compost I got
manure
and I got like I was using mushroom
blocks spent mushroom blocks that would
collect at the local mushroom farm
and uh that was going on our beds it was
compost but like we had no money we're
like a struggling direct Farm it's like
me and my sister trying to make it
happen
and uh
so we just like started sifting our
compost with a half inch screen just
over like a wheelbarrow for a full wreck
farm and like
yeah we did That's That season we did I
think like 10 yards or something like it
was a good amount by hand over a
over a wheelbarrow um just a frame and
stapled up you know and so it worked and
we were a little late to the game you
know we learned that year you gotta you
gotta be a little bit ahead you can't
just like make your your soil in Spring
and be ready to go you know
um it was a little hot it actually
worked though I mean
it was surprising we had decent enough
success like you know we grew Fireweed
maybe it wasn't like Top Notch the
perfect soil that year but we we were
able to like have a great farm and like
you know pay
yeah four people like me and my sister
and two other employees the whole year
so pretty good I'd say
and uh
yeah so the next step was
I realize oh I need a lot more soil
because I want to be like sexy my plants
and pots that's like the the goal I want
to have that much soil but for my farm
like
you know I feel like I need to buy 25 to
50 yards of soil realistically to sex
all my plants and four gallon pots which
is minimal to me I'd like to go like
seven but you know so it'll spit
expensive so
um I like linked up with that that
mushroom farm locally they're like
they're certified organic it's really
clean it's just sawdust and um organic
like grains like whatever's like I think
it's holes some kind of green holes
and uh
so it's really clean input and it's like
super ground up already so
uh makes great compost and yeah we just
started taking our our cannabis chips we
chip up all the Cannabis at the end of
the year
and
you would clean out our
cow manure from the cow we have we
started with one cow
and like just like the next year got a
little better like
we've got a little bit ahead of the game
the soil was super fire and it was still
fresh it was like we had it done and
I want to say we had it like sifted in
February or something
and yeah it's still a little fresh so
like
I'm at the point now where where uh yeah
right now I've been turning my my
compost pile
all summer for next year you know like I
already have like a 60-yard wind Road
just sitting in the field ready to go
and uh
you know I I do a thermophilic compost
so that means I'm heating it up and I'm
like
you know it's killing off whatever seeds
and bacteria or whatever I don't know
what to say you know I'm pretty late
intuitive about right how I'm doing it
all and you know you pile up a bunch of
stuff it just gets really hot
it's not that complicated
um
so yeah sorry I'm kind of rambling but
uh
anyways where was I
um
yeah thermophilic compost yeah I get it
going it gets hot I like turn it three
times now with my tractor and then
um on the third time I bring it into
like my covered area
and
uh it heats up one last time and after
that I sift it once it cools down like
below you know
100 degrees
I'll sift it and then
let it let that sit for another month or
two
so
and then I'm rocking it's like March and
getting going
so you gotta if you want to like do your
own soil it's
it's a bunch of work you gotta have a
lot of collection like that mushroom
farm I go every Monday and
I fill up like
four to six yards of mushroom box in my
truck by hand every single week
and then I unload them and I de-bag them
by hand
the fucking shitload of worse but like I
don't I don't pay for soil and actually
I make enough compost that I don't even
I don't pay for compost either anymore
and like
yeah the wrecking's hard like if you're
if you're trying to like set yourself
apart like you need to be have a niche
and like my Niche that I chose is that
you know we're gonna be regenerative and
do a closed loop system
and uh
I just feel like a lot of people don't
talk about like what they're actually
using for soil I don't really know who
most people are using fruit potting soil
you know it seems a little mysterious
and
it's not that hard I think like a lot of
people don't realize they could just
sift their compost and let it sit you
know and then
put that into your stuff like sift it
with a half inch screen and then sift it
on a quarter inch screen I'm pretty sure
that's the
but uh
I could be wrong with this
is like one size
yeah it's really not complicated like
and I run like 10 000 square feet every
year it's a good sized Farm
um me and like uh two other guys pretty
much farming it and
yeah we crash we actually ended up uh to
sift the soil we do like a 60 yard
windrow so we're not doing it over the
the
um wheelbarrow anymore thank you and uh
we made it what's called like a trommel
and you can find these like videos
online it's a little mysterious I'm
thinking about maybe like selling the
schematics for my trauma but it's
essentially like a rotating
screen
that's like on a slight tilt and there's
a frame around it and you just shovel
into it and it's like rotating and all
the solids are kind of like
you know shaking off whatever's on there
and it's falling down the screen below
and then it's falling the out the end of
it into the wheelbarrow all the solids
like whatever didn't fully compost
and it's like super super easy we just
like
work for a whole week you know you're
just shoveling into the thing and
I mean I guess it doesn't sound that
easy but okay two guys can do like 60
yards in a week I mean I think that's
pretty dope
yeah I'm not paying any like
I don't know not paying for like peat
moss peat moss is like yeah
it's from like peat bugs that are
ancient and they're they're not coming
back like it's a
it's a weird thing that we just like
take that out of the ground and
it's kind of importance for the Earth so
like every time you buy a bag of soil
it's like
it shouldn't really feel
because you're just like robbing it from
one place and it's and they just kill
all these microbes that are these
ancient microbes by cooking it up and
he's having
yeah anyways
um anybody got any questions about
making soil like making your own potting
soil with like nothing like anybody
what are you doing with your cow manure
how are you integrating that oh yes
yeah so
after we got linked up with that
mushroom farm and like I do that every
week I get the mushroom blocks
um that's a really low nitrogen Source
it's just mostly wood chips it's like
yeah which is sawdust really
and um
yeah so you need you need nitrogen cows
cows are good for me because I have uh
pastures and
um
ends our defense so like I was like all
right I'm doing some cows and I started
off with a bull and like one bowl gives
you a good amount of manure like a small
farm like one cow you just crash it like
a like a home home size you know and I'm
up to like five cows now
and like
I mean I didn't spend any money on them
either I just like Craigslist you know
free just like keep your eyes out
um your local farmer like Paige like
people are always in a bind like
you know like there's fires or whatever
you can like really save somebody's
animals and like
so I have all these like Gary rejects
because I'm up in Dairy country in
Washington and like they're not like
meat cows necessarily but
um they're great for manure and uh
they're super sweet you know cows have
good energy so it puts a little bit into
the weed you know yeah as it matters
um but I have a a barn out in one of my
fields and uh for the winter time
you know you gotta feed the cows and
like currently I'm not on like a super
intensive rotation
and like the goal is someday to be
rotating the cows through the pasture
like all year and not hang but
apparently we uh we hey the field in the
summer
and we we feed the cows hay in the
winter and kind of like restrict their
access to the rest of the fields
and um they're in this barn and I feed
them hay in the barn and they just like
you know they shit where they stand and
I just tossed all these hay bales and
they move it around and they basically
like cover it up every day and if you
throw like an extra bit of hay and
you're adding enough nitrogen to that
carbon mix with their manure that it
actually like becomes a radiant heat
floor it becomes like a compost pile in
place it's called like a deep litter
system with a deep bedding system and it
works super good the cows like don't
want to go out of the barn you know they
like just want to hang out and like
chill and it smells pretty nice it
smells kind of sweet usually
um once it gets going like right now
it's a little early for me because I
just started here and I'm like two weeks
ago and you know by December it's like
toasty and I can look out there and I
like there's a little scene coming out
of there like Barn like it's like one
side's open on the barn
um and that's really nice because I can
just drive in and grab that manure in
this in the springtime
and pull it out with my tractor and
throw in the window
so that became my nitrogen source
and you know it's really badass soil now
that we're making like
this year I ended up
you know we do everything from seeds
I start stuffing like uh seed cells and
I move up to half gallons
and I just had a bunch of stuff in half
gallons for a long time because things
are piling up you know oh I gotta change
greenhouse plastic this week I didn't
know I needed to like
you know things sat in pots and like I
was just super amazed at like the the
plants in these half gallon pots just
stayed green and just kept going and
they like got like this tall they're
just green and they're healthy and happy
and
so it's really like
it's just not that complicated to make
your own soil and you can sign like
local sources most mushroom Farms like
pay people to take that stuff out of
there it's a lot of Labor especially
because they got to remove the bags
so like
if you're just trying to make your soil
for like you know your home Garden like
man just gonna get a load of mushroom
blocks and add it to your Pile in a long
way like
do it a couple times
um that's like a really cool resource
wood chips in general are super good I'd
say they just take a little longer like
just amplify that time but
maybe three or four times you know would
I say it takes like five months for me
to do my compost system like totally
from like I'm starting to turn it to
when I'm I'm using it
um and the collection process takes you
know however long it takes to collect
that pile
um
yeah but that's pretty it's pretty
simple you know all you need is some
nitrogen some carbon
you can make your own soil like you
don't need perlite
yeah I haven't used perlite in four
years five years like I'm just cruising
like I don't even think about it maybe
maybe if I was growing like in a pot it
would be a little more of a thing but
you know I'm going in the ground like
that's just a small portion of its
existence is in the pot so
but it's cool to make it on the farm and
it feels really rewarding to like just
not be a part of that system and
you know like I'm looking at the ground
here it's all
wood chips like just you could pile it
up and make potting soil like there's so
many struggling Farmers out there just
getting swindled into all these like
products and there's all this Charlotte
Henry and like
yeah
you can just make it all look what you
got
like to make your JMS
if you got the eighth
and you can make your potting soil like
you don't have to have
the fancy trauma you just need a
wheelbarrow and like it's super simple
especially for home gardens like
and it's it's the best I don't know
yeah anybody have any questions anymore
tell us about your chicken systems the
last couple of years your chicken
tractors and all that yeah yeah I do uh
chickens for myself and my family and my
my staff I just do like
like this year I did 120 birds and I do
I just do pastured chicken and you know
I have some thoughts on on it actually
uh
like raising chicken is just a grain
game you know like I haven't found a way
to get past
this uh Industrial
raising chicken like if you're trying to
raise meat birds like I don't know a lot
of people that
aren't on some kind of industrial grain
wagon so
yeah I love chicken I like raisin
chickens and like
in my long-term Vision I want to learn
how to raise the chickens off the
compost pile there's at points of the
compost pile when it turns into a worm
bin
and it's just like a billion worms and I
haven't exactly figured out like how to
time that up with when I have chickens
but
um the way I'm raising them now I
I do uh chicken tractors so I have like
a cage it's a it's a big box rectangular
box and like wake up in the morning grab
a bucket of water some grain and go out
and feed them all right move them
because they're hungry and they
literally come to me and they're like
looking at me I'm like come on chickens
yeah Pull It Forward
they come usually and then uh and like
give them the Grain and um it takes like
no time you know it takes me like
man if I'm in a rush it takes me
four minutes to fill up the bucket of
water grab the grain feed the chickens
and then like
it takes about
it's like eight to ten weeks usually I
think is what people most people do
that's what I I usually do like
this year I raised my chickens for 10
weeks it was like kind of like an indoor
weed club and that's kind of my issue
with it too like
from that perspective of the green game
and
uh we need to figure out how to like
remove ourselves from the grain with the
chicken because like the chickens can
live off of other stuff you know
um
but yeah reason for like
10 weeks and uh
they do a really good job on the field
like they're moving in a grid so you can
kind of look into the field and see like
six months later you can see like wow
like grass right in that grid is really
nice so so I got I have a couple now
like poop so I'll move around and it's
actually like they evenly fertilize
really nice patches of your yard and
it's it brings a lot of Health to the
past year
and that's probably like you know that's
the second most fulfilling thing after
like gravy you know like eating the
chicken
um it's just like damn it really
improves the land but
yeah I can't get past that idea that I'm
just like buying industrial grain too
to improve my land you know so I got I'm
buying like soy-free organic like the
best I can find
um for where I'm at but
um
I'm kind of scheming up uh
a worm chicken plan you know I think
it's easy it's like it's just a timing
thing really and having the pile at the
right time but
yeah raising your chickens are easy I
think everybody should like do it if you
if you can and you eat meat like
I think I raised my birds for 16 this
year a piece and um they're each
all right
like the smallest for about three pounds
pretty good size with the biggest for
like 5.8 pounds like Christmas chickens
and so there's there's always like a
gradient because there's a packing order
um
there's always huge chickens and there's
always like a really tiny runt on
um
but yeah that's pretty much it that's
what's up you can just rent the
harvesting equipment locally in most
areas there's like a Farm Service Agency
you can reach out to like
or a Conservation District is in my area
and it's like nothing it's like 30 bucks
and
and you got everything to harvest like
you know 200 chickens in a day or
something
you got enough hands you can do a lot of
chickens in a day with it so it's really
cost effective and you don't need to buy
it a year
um
I get my chickens from a local Hatchery
I'm super lucky like it's right down the
road for me pretty much
um
but like recently I've like kind of been
looking like there's a lot of really
interesting chickens you can buy like if
you want legs you can get like leg
chickens and
you want breasts chickens you can get
breast chickens and yeah what's your
average cost per pound uh 10.
I'm not uh off top of my head I couldn't
say it but I did 120 chickens at 16 a
bird this year I'm just not sure the
poundage so average at like three foot
three pounds yeah definitely three
pounds yeah three and a half three three
and a half yeah
16 bird so like five bucks a pound
good organic chicken yeah I mean I this
year was the year I was like I'm not
even gonna I've been trying to work it
out like been trying to like play that
game where I'm like I kind of want to
sell chickens as an Enterprise for the
farm you know as a you know Diversified
Farm like some playing around with it
for myself but I just
I kind of decided against it and just to
do it on my own scale because
you gotta put up it's just like you
gotta put up the money beforehand to
raise the chicken and it's an
interesting
it's an interesting gig like
that grain game it's just an industrial
game yeah have you tried breeding in uh
mealworms or uh chronic Soldier fly
larvae or yeah I haven't
um but I'm up by the border I think I'm
a little cold for the black soldier side
yeah you're up in Washington
um but that's kind of why I'm on the
worm thing because I I make a lot of
worms my soil is kind of mostly like a
I mean really it's like worm castings
pure is what I make in the end it's like
really but it's like low nitrogen you
know it's not super high nitrogen with
the balance I'm using and
um but yeah man I I think the bugs like
that's how you feed the chickens the
bugs that's the real ital way what's
your what's your other ideas on to
switching away from grain uh because I
know raising chickens it's such a
intense cost you know
yeah it's tough to like put that money
down every week or however long you
beautiful yeah yeah supporting those
huge great operations and
um and it's tough to find like really
good Organics have you figured out
anything
um
you know with your chickens to kind of
have as an alternative but you will
still get all their tight
not really
um
besides the worms I think that's that's
my like my scheme right now is to
develop like a an idea to maybe um do
like a fence like windrow with the
chickens in there maybe a coop situation
um
but I think really like chickens raising
like meat birds ideally you'd have like
a farm to table
uh or sorry uh
you know Farm to Market Garden of some
sort where you're like you got a lot of
extra produce and you're just tossing it
out
but you recently I've met this local
Farm to me and um they raise Hogs and
they actually grow all their like all
their own grain at this point and they
have they've invested in some of this
equipment where
like they're pretty small I think
they're like 15 or 20 acres and they're
growing like enough grain to feed like a
hundred pigs I don't even really know
how it's possible and they're organic
and they're you're trying to be
regenerative and I think growing our
grains and being slightly mechanized is
probably the the answer
um do they harvest the grain or do they
just let it let it go over and then let
the chickens free range on the fields or
they harvest and put it up and then they
put it up yeah enjoy it yeah I'm not 100
sure how but like
yeah there's they're really cool I'm
actually like
trying to like learn this from them and
uh
yeah because I actually started raising
pigs and that's kind of why I got out of
raising pigs I raised American guinea
Hogs they're these little uh
lard pigs and little black cute furry
pigs and they make like really really
good meat but it's super super fatty and
I would uh I would get all their feed
from a local Brewery
I'd just be like dude like fill up my
garbage can and like they were they're
just trying to get rid of it spent part
yeah and um and rye and we depend with
their Brewing
uh you know mixes of all that stuff and
it was it was like they're happy
together too yeah there's like all these
uh waste you know streams that we can
take and turn into like value for our
Farms I think that's like
like a real big
way to like attempt to be regenerative
is so like there's all these
unsustainable businesses out there
that have access you know maybe they got
extra breweries at the grain or the
mushroom Farms are the mushroom blocks
but like that shit is gold to us and
like you know maybe I worry about like
the breweries having like glyphosate all
over that grain now and that's kind of
also why I stopped doing the pigs that
way and I'm like
you know it's just like a glyphosate
slurry
you know it was like beer I like had
like I like beer I used to like beer but
uh
um
I think like closing other people's
needs is like a it's like almost the
easiest place for anybody to start being
regenerative
you know I don't know like dude there's
so much fuckery out there like just pop
up someone else's mess yeah and then
like
that'll just get you ahead to where you
can like
I don't know I can buy jars to sell my
weed because I don't buy soil and
it's dope
and yeah
I can buy labels I don't buy chicken
so you don't really need that much
actually I think you you did you ever
you have a question behind Noble oh I
just was
what bigger soil building
person might think about
um
yeah poison oak
um but I mean if you're breaking it down
like I'm I do the thermophilic thing and
I know like some people don't like that
because you're off gas in carbon and all
kinds of stuff but uh if you're doing
the thermophilic it
I'd do anything like I I don't know I
I'll put my chicken bones in my worm bin
and that'll get turned into the mix I I
just put everything in
um
you're getting those mushroom blocks you
have to worry about muscle size on them
and stuff like that and there's nothing
best kind of stuff oh you do yeah so
it's like I think it's really important
that you're working with a certified
organic at minimum and
like that's that minimum I like it I
really trust the people I work with but
um the first season that we actually
like made a whole batch of soil
um it was actually the first season we
were like working on getting our damn
pure certification and the den Pier
certification like
you need to have clean inputs is like
the bit is one of the biggest things
about it so
uh we actually yeah got we got a
pesticide tested after we made it and
it was it came out clean so it was like
none detected and so that was really
great it wasn't a big surprise because
we thought you know but if you if you're
going into like some outfit you don't
know like my friend owns the mushroom
farm too so I know he's passionate and
he has really good value so like
just a great fit you know I save him a
lot of Labor I save him
six hours a week you know like it's a
serious thing all year like he they love
me coming to the farm like I'm the most
consistent person too like the other
people come and get mushroom blocks but
like I'm always
you know I'm always there every week and
sometimes it takes consistency to do
that but
I live out a little bit out of town you
know like 45 minutes out of town so it's
like my once a week I get to drive to
town and go shopping so it's like I'm
already needing to do that shit anyways
and fold it in there do you harvest
mushrooms coming out of your bed are
there the watts are still pretty
prolific dude yeah Russian blacks are
the shit they're they're fucking gold
dude like you pile them up and then you
you take them off the mushroom farm and
like they're trying to hit their numbers
and they have stuff coming out of the
incubation room
that needs to go on the shelf and it's
just a it's just a timing game so
there's so much life left in the
mushroom block like
yeah it's it's just full and so like if
it rains like in the shoulder Seasons uh
the mushroom block piles like the
collection piles would just be full like
my my crew like my staff will just go
out and harvest mushrooms and we all eat
good like none of us are eating shiitake
or oysters nobody's buying that that
stuff you know this time of year
especially it's getting a little cold
now but we just had like some good
flushes Springtime is really really
really good
um yeah I mean my shoebox they're spun
like I fill in like
you know ruts or something on the ground
and then there's like oyster mushrooms
and like
if anybody's check check out my
Instagram or maybe look if you haven't
maybe check it out after this there's
like I had like low spots in my garden
where I had like mounded beds and I was
like tripping and slipping in there I'm
like I just want it to be a little more
flat in the garden and I and I just
filled it with mushroom blocks and then
that that year was just like
it's like huge like oysters everywhere
coming up so they're just fine and you
know I see people like cut a hole in the
Oyster was it you that Joey that cut a
hole on a block and like put soil on
there and grew a plant I don't know this
is fun oyster blacks are silly I mean
mushrooms are like
I don't know they're they're fun beings
and
uh
yeah dude if you guys are getting white
russian box dude that's my that's the
shit but wood chips are the shit too
like that's gold
your soil building yeah
yeah good you know find a good organic
Dairy like to get your cow manure cowser
I think like Nick Nick said to me like
some greens are starting to tell me that
like they're the original Korean natural
farmer the cow you know because they
have like this amazing gut that
that the rumen and uh
it's just like fair man did you know you
put grass in a bucket of water it just
smells like cow shit in like a couple
weeks it's the same exact thing
it's not even that complicated but
yeah that's that's what's up with my
farm we just like make our own soil with
mushroom blocks and hay and manure and
it works out really well I mean just do
it early is the biggest advice I give
people like just you'll have a lot
better success if you don't
you know push push it like I was trying
to run a wrecked Farm
keeping flour on the Shelf all season
long which is what I do and I have done
for seven years like not and I've never
like
I guess it'd be nice to run out of weed
you know that'd be actually pretty sweet
to like sell all your weed
but uh you know making our own soil out
of mushroom blocks and fucking hey I'm
just I'm stoked on that it's really a
rewarding thing
and I think like it's kind of
it's a little mystical like you know
everybody just realizing potting soil
it's just a hard hard thing to get away
from is anybody here like gotten away
from potting soil by chance
yeah let's let's have what's your step
um I mean we made our own soil for all
of our beds uh for our farm over in
Laytonville uh we had a lot of big bio
storages that we've been keeping on the
property
um a lot of logs that we had buried with
top soil that had sat for years we ended
up making Google beds with
um we did bring in rice holes and then
we had wood chips from like local tree
cutting different things like that and
um yeah and then just a lot of covered
crops and chopping and dropping and yeah
compost and uh yeah a lot of water
everywhere
um yeah different goat manure we had
chickens we had turkeys you know so yeah
a lot of local inputs and yeah just
whatever we're able to gather on the
land and I mean it cost us next oh and
then uh some actually some old soil we
cleaned up off of a property cleanup
from the organic garden that we uh
integrated into it as you know pretty
basic you know completed soil but
you know after a couple years it was the
most light fluffy consistently moist
soil and it cost it was next to nothing
yeah oh yeah that's what it's about
and like I think when I tell people like
I make my own potting toilet a lot of
people are like wow what do you use for
aeration like they're surprised they
don't use perlite or like gravel or
something and like
yeah I'm not suggesting somebody go
around like their full wreck indoor I'm
like
wood chips off the ground and make you
know do the same thing I'm doing I'm
saying like make your potting soil for
your outdoor farm and plant your plants
in the ground or your beds that's like
I'm really into that and like
the thing about the no aeration is that
yeah it's not like growing in potting
soil it's different you have to be
careful not to over water especially
um especially early in the colder times
of the year
um and you'll if you don't have like if
you didn't let your soil fully cook or
fully like you know let the worms go
through it and
it's done and
you'll know be like you'll know it's
done because it kind of gets to a
certain size and it stops getting
smaller pretty much at the at the very
end of like heat it up a couple times
you turned it a couple times you sifted
it
and then you gotta let it like really
like sit there in a pile and like it'll
just kind of almost shrink because you
kind of aerated it it looks bigger than
it is with that sifting it'll kind of go
down if you don't like really let it sit
you'll you'll find that your plants will
probably do great I mean I
my plans to do great but um
as you're like
by the time you transplant your plant
like you're happy on pot it'll go from
like this much snow like the pots about
that big it'll be like a little muffin
like a little like it'll be almost like
two-thirds the size it'll it'll just
compress a little bit and this is
something I've noticed so
just having your soil done early like
I'm trying to get a year ahead like
that's my goal so I already have my pile
almost collected for next year right now
it's kind of the cycle I'm on and and
that's that's the hard part is like
being really dedicated to it for like
you just have to be it's like you have
to be dedicated like that's like a
couple years I got planned out and I'm
already executing six months ago I
started executing like the picking up
that pile so it's a long game but
but that's like
that's how you do it that's how you like
successfully
improve your land and
close your Loops is like thinking like
what do I what I'm going to be what am I
going to be doing in like two years like
for this soil like
I'm like two in two years I'll be trying
to get two years ahead on my soil pile I
feel
like it um
yeah that's my thoughts on that I don't
know if anybody else has any questions
but
if we're about to like get into some
tunes or something
okay anybody anybody not anybody not
using potting soil for the nursery work
uh yeah maybe do some sifting get get
after it I'd say it'd be really cool to
see
cool
well every time that I'm planting
anything or getting more dirt I'm
missing in like native soil or like
whatever I'm sweeping up leaves are
leopard needles or you know
put a rabbit for a while and I was like
putting wood chips in with the rabbit
and taking the rabbit pods and the wood
chips and mixing that straight in with
the soil with my compost mixing the
native soil into my compost yeah
[Music]
yeah I know and like maybe starting with
like initially starting with like some
potting soil you ran like that's gold
right there if somebody has potting soil
it's clean you know it's clean that's a
really especially around here in the
Triangle like right especially right now
yeah who's got organic potting soil I
mean it's it's hard I feel like it's
hard to like you gotta really trust your
farmer you know what materials you're
gonna get you know like what are they
what are they been spraying on that you
know it's really important to know but
man it's it's gold like potting soil pot
like pots like if you could pick up
pots of potting soil from like some cool
like Alpine glow Farm I would be like
all over that shit like that would be
amazing not the day we'd sell that yeah
um
I don't know I'm sure there's some like
good organic Potter farms around here
anyways yeah
Joey what do you want to do
what's next on the
any time keep going you can wrap it up
you've been loving it I mean I'm I'm a
little out of fuel but like
what are you guys gonna talk about
foreign
[Music]
man the regenerative farmer
I think it's like
you know consolidation has hit
Washington pretty hard just like the
whole West Coast it's it's almost the
same thing it's like they decided to
like screw all the small farmers over in
like slightly different ways
Oliver you know especially on the west
coast here like you guys got distro
issues here and and Cali and like in
Washington like there's just not enough
stores to sell our herb so most of the
far I mean there's not a lot of farms
that are trying to do regenerative stuff
in Washington and like they're kind of
dropping like flies the people that were
in the game and
um just like everybody's dropping like
flies like no matter what you're doing
right now
um
personally like I'm waiting I'm like
every year I'm like am I gonna do that
again like it appears like the price
drops and
the retail price always stays the same
and and that's just hard to like face
every every year over and over again
it's just a grind like
and you know I want to educate the
consumer about like you know why
regenerative you know Sun drone like
pesticide free cannabis is like so much
better like grown from seed like bred by
the farmer like
you know so single Source like making
the freaking potting soil like
I want I want the consumer to to
appreciate that but I just feel like the
Market's not really there yet
and um at all I think it's like five to
ten years away from that I think like
seriously like Nick from Green Storage
Garden and and Josh and Kelly from
dragonflyers medicine are literally
maybe the only people really pushing for
that
in a real way like I'm that they're not
the only people but like they're they're
pushing for it the most I think like
they're educating people on really like
getting the message out
um they're not the only people
um at all but uh
I think we're just waiting for like
Federal changes on like Banking and
whatnot like I can't own my farm because
I can't get a mortgage you know like and
I I don't have
a quarter million dollars in my pocket
or anything like I'm making I'm trying
to make soil
hey you got a question
um I was just gonna say like um
I like the idea of like yeah
adaptability where you start realizing
that maybe this is gone
um but then you kind of wanted to
um
with that Rec industry idea of uh
it's okay we all just smoke that hookah
man I'm like I feel the same way
that's something you were just saying
but oh yeah are you worried about the
FDA getting involved how do you feel
about that yeah I'm like I don't care
I'm like
I just want like something to change so
I could get like an operating loan
almost for my business like to just be
treated like a normal business to where
like if we're like struggling
I could get a loan to like pay my staff
just so I don't to fire everybody you
know like
the second you think like I think I'm
getting somewhere like oh sales are good
it's like then you got two three months
of bad sales and like
it's just that's how the wreck Mark has
been for me it hasn't been like
like I got my wrecked license I'm like
energy full blast social media we're
doing this and then over the years I'm
just like man
ah it's I was I still love I love the
the work but it's just it's just hard to
like yell that from the rooftops and
then they just want cheap ounces because
of outdoors and I'm like this isn't she
bounces man like this is like some this
is better than like all the weed on the
Shelf here like this is a lot of love
put into it and it's Unique you know we
don't I I don't grow necessarily like
what's hot on the market or like I don't
go GMO like I'm growing
something me and my friends bread you
know like something Brandon bread or
Joey bread or tomorrow like
um
yeah like we're very very unique strains
and like it's it's it's hard to it's
hard to be looked at on this wreck
Market as just outdoor or indoor and
that's how the Washington Market has
just it's just that way and Washington's
always been really indoor hungry
um in in the medical days it's just
ravenous for indoor okay you got yeah I
was just gonna almost say like the
person who's like looking down the line
like you're saying a quality is a little
more uh hesitant to just like be like
here's the way you need to take it you
know kind of like what Joey said the
other day about like take everything
we're saying with a grain of salt
because it might be different in your
world yeah so I think because of that
little bit of a hesitation to like say
hey this is the way or whatever
what you see out there like a lot with
uh the internet and YouTube and stuff
nowadays just like tons of people just
projecting so much more multitude of
information that they're like certain
this is it you know yeah so that's why I
feel like disconnected uh the educated
consumer is kind of what I'm looking at
because that they're they're getting
barrage with tons of information there's
like a one or two or a handful of videos
that are along this line because it's
like they're all all the people doing
those videos are also trying to do the
work you know and then and then do the
video at the same time you know yeah
whereas everybody else just like blasts
you with like your Zone just trying to
make a buck yeah there's a lot of noise
out there it's like like sorting through
all that noise yeah I mean it's always
it kind of reminds me of like back in
the day like going on to like forums
like I was on
whatever like icy mag or something like
there's just so much shit to get through
before you get to like the real stuff
and the normal consumers like that's
where they're at they're like you're
there's just too much yeah
I mean there's so much
dank that has no heart out there and
that's a hard thing as like a farmer
that Farms with a lot of heart when I
put dank out there it's like sitting
next to dank with no heart and like in
Washington nobody gets to smell it so
then like nobody gets to know it's just
a kind of a heart crushing industry
um
I mean God I don't I don't even want to
get it under like you know the
depression of
just that
the Cannabis farmer in general is just
like
it's been ground down and I think uh
I think it's I think people just should
do black market I think like as somebody
has been in the rack market for I've had
seven years my wreck license I I think
like
I love I love like my farm and I love
what I'm doing but like if someone's
getting into this right now I'm like
dude just represent yourself and be your
true authentic self
and you don't need to be like licensed
you may you know protection is good like
a medical permit I totally suggest
people carry you know but like
more and more like
there's just like not there's not a lot
in it for the small family farm in the
rec market with the consolidation that's
occurring and I think there's a select
few that are able to somehow navigate it
but it's through a lot of sacrifice and
like it's it's hard for them for us to
do it forever
um I'm hoping for like Federal
legalization like Banks can like I I
could actually like get a mortgage on my
farm and I could maybe get operation
operating them get some more greenhouses
make it my life a little easier or
something like that I probably wouldn't
actually get more green asses
but um
you know kitchen or something like that
yeah
um earlier you kind of said it's about
the long game yeah and I I really
appreciate that thought because like as
we're watching this industry fall like
that as long as you're able to maintain
through it and keep focused on your like
mission in the end all of a sudden
there's going to be a shortage we're
gonna hit a shortage here at some point
and prices are coming up through the
roof I know if your quality is still
there you're at least on the top end of
that yeah if six companies are making
all the weed in California at that
moment is the moment where small farmers
might start doing better you know like
but it's gonna be so hard getting to
that moment for all of us like it
happened in the Brewing industry you
know there was like a big microbrew boom
and everybody's just drank the shoes and
then like it went away and now now in
Bellingham where I'm from there's like
20 breweries it's wild it's like the
Heyday Brewery Brewing is going on right
now so I I see the same thing with
cannabis it's just like
we're gonna get ground down there's
gonna be like a couple people that make
it and like
I don't know I don't know like
like who who wants to be the just shoots
like it's not the that's not where my
values are like so
I'm just trying to like just make the
soil keep selling this flower I had a
good season this year and I was just
surprised because it was just a really
hard year
um
in Spring especially and like I feel
like something's driving me to just keep
doing it which is cool and I'm into it
but
um
but yeah man the Market's hard I hope
everybody's like holding on there and
like you know I got solidarity with
anybody holding onto a bunch of herb
right now on the shelves for sure yeah
but hash is really big I mean I see
everybody kind of running into the hash
Market I don't know about uh California
but in Washington it's like
I'm doing it I mean I just I'm I just
built a little washroom and that's my
plan is people don't judge
resin like they judge flower it's not
outdoor versus indoor with residence
it's like it's resin is it fire or is it
not fire
and uh I think that's a that's a
potential I think that's the best shot
actually a lot of small farms have
especially
um
in in places where like indoors just
heavily consumed and like the stores
want indoor and like that's that's a lot
of people have been taught to judges
that way yeah it's like in the visual
Market yeah yeah
it's rough how did the sativa Indica
thing where people are like to finish a
few lives because you realize that music
just kiddingly you care about the police
you know what I mean or what do you know
what I mean that's what they should
it's endlessly frustrating like the big
the idea of the visual market like we
it's important for sure to have
something that's visually pleasing like
something that we want to eat or put
into our body that looks like ooh that's
juicy like give me that like it's a
steak or whatever but
um but yeah like that's literally all
the Washington Market is like I said I
have to sell my you know stuff
pre-packaged
and like no nobody even does sniff jars
anymore like when I started wreck like
you'd sell some weed and they'd be like
send a sniff jar with it and at this
point like we're like 10 years into
legalization in Washington like
we don't nobody gets no we don't even
fucking do that anymore it's just it's
weak
oh yeah
Echo does like uh break down on their
packaging in like the dream area and
stuff like that you know yeah
um and uh I kind of wonder why I don't
see that more in Washington when I'm up
there turkey and cats you know just like
so you can't open the package is what
you're saying no that's right I think is
insane
um then like why can't you list what it
should like if people understood the
person you break down what flavor
profile they might be hitting off those
servings then at least you could show
the consumer like but here's what it
here's the serpent breakdown of it on
the back but they haven't even gone down
that one they're just like nope you just
have to guess I hope you know this
string yeah actually in Washington you
know I I am able to put my troops on
there on my packaging so you do I do
yeah yeah
[Music]
everybody does something different like
there's actually it is cool in
Washington we can brand our own stuff
like I have my brand it's called Eagle
trees that's my farm name that's the
farm me and my sister you know run and
um
yeah we like Jarred up and everything
and uh we put our like top let me take
like the the top like five chirps and we
put that on there like you know we kind
of art it up our tee it up a little bit
you know make it nice looking so people
know like oh this is an osamine or the
summer scene kind of dominant just put
the dominant Terps on there I don't put
like the whole test but a lot of fun a
lot of places now I don't know if in
Cali I'm sure they're doing this but
they do like a QR code and it'll take
and that'll take you to the test and
that's super cool
um
yeah I've seen that in other places
where I'm just like are you sure that's
really what it is or somebody just tell
you that it's you know it's all in the
honor System and yeah
you know like my my whole Farm is
hammered out like in Washington we're
required to have like every square inch
hammered out but in in the end it's all
it's all on your honor and like it's
frustrating from the perspective someone
who is like trying to play by the rules
and that are set forth seeing how much
of it is on the honor System and at the
same time not wanting more regulation
but knowing the Bad actors can do so
much you know they're just so so I mean
God damn like so much
yeah and uh this guy was saying
like I was like by the time you're
accustomed like those cards is gone I'm
like because we're doing two small batch
you know and then I kind of went down
the lines of like what if that QR code
just took you to a website that was more
along the lines of what to look for to
ask this guy well first of all he
probably ask them about this because
they're going to scan the QR code so one
of you just directed their knowledge in
a different way
it would have to be safe
you know you get something and steer
towards you know hey you know I I like
the the suggestion of something and then
make them know yeah
yeah
it's like it's all about like what the
bud tender knows like really in the end
like
so from like the farmer's perspective
like for my like I think we just need to
be really transparent and almost like
I don't know what else you do besides
like you gotta have the bud tenders come
to like your farm you know like that's
what I literally do I have like every
summer this summer I didn't do it just
because like it was a rough year but uh
I usually do like a summer uh Bud tender
party and I have like all the butt
tenders from all my accounts and the I
just invite their whole staff and we put
on this party and like
you know it costs the money to put the
party on like you know have some food
and like get some rent some tents and
some chairs and stuff but yeah we get to
have like 50 bartenders come through
like three times during the day and like
see what we're doing and get the whole
rundown and I I answer every question
and like
yeah to have them know what the what the
fuck's going on at the farm like
you know if if you don't have your farm
they won't know shit about your farm I
don't know like it's yeah that's it's
important especially to stand out
because
when they go to like a big wreck farm
for a like a huge like you know
corporatized wreck Farm it's gonna be
cool because they're like walking
through the fields and they're gonna be
like oh yeah this is like runs and this
is GMO
but if you take them through your field
and you're like oh this is my this is my
Rolex F5 I've been breeding this here on
this land for four years and I've been
making all the soil it's like literally
meant to grow here and it grows here
super well now and like there's just so
much more of a story to tell you're like
all of a sudden you're like
you're not growing mids you're growing
that fine wine like you want them to
to know you're you're putting something
out there that's actually special and
not just like
yeah not a men's Factory so yeah I think
having people out to the farm is the
shit like buyers like don't be smoking
mirrors like
have them out and show them what you're
doing and like be real like you know
maybe clean the place up but you're
walking by something like
yeah maybe you're like yeah that doesn't
look as good as I want it to look like
modesty goes a long way I think people
like
appreciate when you want to do better
you know as a farmer I think like a lot
of the Farms are just real broad out and
like
you got these numbers we're fucking like
full on canopy like
like perfect and
in the end they're just got all these
dirty little secrets they're spraying a
lot of pesticide and they're like they
got arrested mites and so it's just been
like
a war and
I don't know like at least if you have
an award like maybe you have the
Bloodhound be like yeah we had this war
we sprayed JMS and like we made it with
the mint in the garden here and this is
how we did it it's like
it's just so much more interesting and
like palatable the small farm aspect you
win every time so
I don't think the small farmer has the
option of like hiding anymore I think
like that's where I came from like I was
hiding in a basement growing indoors is
kind of where I came from
and like it's hard to come out of that
for me I think it also creates a sense
of mirror like you're saying about
educating your bartenders and the people
and like drawing them into feeling like
they're part of this family whereas like
you know like if they're all going to
any other dispensary to them you know
unless somebody's would really tie them
into it it's just like going to Walmart
or a 7-Eleven you know like what what to
them seems like some big box company and
so by doing what you're saying having a
summer party and bringing them into the
and let them know deep knowledge like
that allows them to feel like they're a
part of something like that you know
what I mean exactly as a and not even
just like
with blood thinners but also consumers
and stuff you know like the amount of
people you bring into it will give them
that deeper knowledge I think builds
into like the community aspect of a web
of resource aspect yeah
a lot of the consumers are going in and
they're just like what's the highest GHC
contact on the number of flights
and the problem that I see is that is
seriously really what you're looking for
or you know what I mean maybe try to
read the rest like yeah that question
and this is the same conversation like
every
every dispensary or any we every weed
store is having too I think they know
this you know I think it's like
it's not that they don't they don't know
that but
it's just the case you know people walk
through those doors every day and say
what's cheap and what's the most potent
you know what's the best and what's the
cheapest
and yeah yeah exactly and volume and
like
it's just that's just the way it is so
yeah I think like
in my mind I'm like I can't I can't
fight the indoor outdoor thing forever
so the resin show them with the resin
you know show them like your outdoor Sun
grown resin
so fire it's like just impossible to
beat
and uh
yeah show them your farm you know I
think that's like a huge thing like show
them show them what you're doing like
it's just interesting like we nerd the
fuck out on all this like this like this
shit and like
it might be self-conscious about that
but like the bud tenders come out and
they're a lot of times I mean but every
anybody could be a bartender but there's
a lot of like young folks that really
want to be Growers and they want to
learn how to like there's a lot of
people that want to learn how to grow
that start their first job as a
budtender like and they're super
fascinated and they want to like they'll
just eat up the knowledge so like you're
giving them an opportunity and the
access is a really big thing and like
yeah like I do um I do
like vendor days sometimes I haven't
done them that much since covid but like
vendor days are cool like you set up and
you just table you know somewhere like
here like fucking pushkirk or these guys
are doing vendor day here you know like
you really get to meet people and like
that face to face like is really is
really special like
I have this guy who's worked oh he's not
even working for me or he is actually I
think he is now but um he's working like
two days a week for me trimming now but
he uh he just came up to me one day at a
vendor day I was like dude I'm a big fan
of the farm like I'm growing weed in the
forest like I'm going to college and
like I'm out in the boonies kind of weed
and asking all these questions and like
he's like would you want to like trade
seeds I'm like yeah dude and somebody
like traded up and like and now he's
renting space he's not even renting
space for me I'm just letting him like
use a little spot I call him my
apprentice and he like just this really
nice mutual thing where like
like a lot of times this year like I
needed labor but maybe I couldn't afford
it and he's like farming on the property
and he's like he's there he's a hand to
help me you know and so it's just like
being you just meet people by boothing
like just set up a table and sell your
stuff or like you can't sell your stuff
feeling stickers or something you know
it's so powerful
like I'm always giving people seeds too
like tomorrow I'll probably be passing
out seeds and it's just the best it's
the best way to make a connection is to
like
either sell or trade scenes with
somebody like there's this like
interaction and like if I sell you seeds
or give you seeds like I'm in your life
for a minimum of like you know five
months or four months and so there's
just a connection there that's really
powerful and do it you know I think
that's a good thing
got anything else Jerry what do we want
to talk about
yeah wow yeah yeah
can you just watch your hash real quick
yeah
um making some hash lately uh I do a lot
of stuff with like Royal Kush and it's
not even like a very like good yield or
so it's kind of special I feel like it's
good like decently stuff
I made some hash I made some melt I made
some like
this year I grew a bunch of kush Kirk
stuff because it's just the shit
everybody knows like he grows good hash
varieties and
um I brought some EMG sour garlic it's
like a real Sour Diesel hash it's very
dang
um we'll dab that out if anybody's
interested and uh
yeah Royal sour
something else
[Music]
yeah yeah so yeah yeah I'm a I have a
Dem pure Farm like and uh
yeah you gotta talk to Josh and Kelly
you know like that's the first step is
like talk to them and like be like I'm
interested in this and you'll get it's
you get plugged into like events like
this
um
but really making your soil like making
compost I think he's like the biggest
thing you can do because it's the most
like meaningful like
yeah making making your own potting soil
is a huge step like
get get away from that story about
potting soil I think that's a good step
um
but just finding like cool ways to close
loops on your own you know thing like
you know like I know Alex here is like
doing like a human culture bedding he's
making his own resin and it's like
that's like just living it being that
that dude like this is what Chris told
me the other day it's like
B yeah you gotta be the guy that that's
cool like you're gonna be the the guy
you want to be and like embody that so
if you want to be a
damn tier farmer you just had to embody
it and build a Hugo culture start
raising a couple animals to make your uh
nitrogen or start closing Loops for the
mushroom farm that's local to your tree
service or something like get on a chip
drop whatever.com and like make your
spot a drop and just start like pumping
out soil and
um just like just make regenerative
cannabis you know I think that's the
best get in contact with us like the
whole damn fan like there's so many
farmers like
just being in contact and like asking
questions that almost everybody's really
like
pretty friendly I think you know and
like willing to
you know engage if you're engaging I
feel like and
um
but I think
like from a very like Baseline
perspective questioning and being
skeptical of the inputs we use is like
is just super important you know like
you can't just trust the mushroom farm
that it's going to be clean you might
like need a pesticide test that that
soil like sometimes you gotta go a
little extra far like I don't pesticide
test that soil every year
but I might pesticide test it next year
because it's been like a year or two you
know so just going the extra step and
like caring and knowing like kind of
trying to be aware that there's like a
level of contamination in this world
that is almost impossible to avoid but
that we should be striving to avoid it
not just giving up in our Gardens like
it's so easy to be like yeah there's
glyphosate and everything
and throw up your arms but
I think it's just wild like there's a
huge level of contamination so I think
that's what kind of what the damn cure
idea is just like there is contamination
make the most holistic decisions for our
bodies and our Gardens and uh and be
very thoughtful with what we put into
our bodies it's like it's no joke like
you know you can't take anything back
that you put into your body
and um
yeah is that I can answer your question
the best way to become a Redemption
farmer or get certified
yeah just embodying the damn pure farmer
and then then that's how you do it
you're mentioning chip drop and I just
want to say it but if you are it's good
to like let those chips sit on your
property for like a year or so
be really careful because all that took
the aggregated from all over the place
you have no idea that one truck's
probably from like 30 different spots
and yeah chips are yeah a gamble you're
right yeah
everything's a gamble so just recognize
that there's a level of contamination
yeah
make the best decisions for yourself