[Music]
I'm gonna give you a quick update on
what is happening out there in the world
[Music]
so the county so for those of you who
know Jonathan's vet CO and Angeles
Emeralds have been working really really
hard on the county they put in a
fantastic working group together of
people from all sides of the table and
they spent I don't know something like
eight weeks and five six hours a day
really really breaking this down and
they made an incredible incredible
recommendation to the Board of
Supervisors so that those
recommendations are really awesome and I
gotta say there are some parts of it
that people aren't going to agree with
but there are some great parts of it as
well so I think we're gonna hopefully
hopefully see some good stuff come from
the county the not good stuff is gonna
happen - let me give you a quick idea of
what's happened in the county so they're
gonna expect it right now they're
expected to vote on these regulations
December 19th
the reason that they're waiting so long
is because they're not really going to
take any kind of applications for
licenses until like July June or July of
next year so if you are in
unincorporated parts of LA County your
application process is gonna start
somewhere around December January and
you're looking at licensing somewhere
around summer so as opposed to the
cities which are moving a little bit
quicker and are gonna start taking
applications some of them as soon as
some of them now are taking applications
the county is gonna hold off for a
little bit so any of that
unincorporated LA County that stuff's
gonna hold off but you know keep tabs on
it if you don't know what's going on
reach out look up Angeles Emeralds
online and you can get in contact and
get up on their on their sort of
newsletter mailing list and everything
to find out more Angeles Emeralds like
Los Angeles and then emerald like the
green the other kind of green
okay so that's the County oh and one
good thing about the county there has
been a recommendation that was passed
for a pathway for existing operators so
should you or any of your clients or
contacts or friends have that have been
operating you know as legal as you can
in LA County
unincorporated there will be a pathway
for them to get to applications so
that's gonna be great okay LA City LA
City has issued all bunch of regulations
and that's in there they're just in
discussion right now this Thursday the
21st is a Planning Commission meeting if
you want to learn more about it go
online and look up La cannabis task
force you will find as much information
as you can they have newsletter they
will send you out email notices and you
can go and you know participate and
support so that is LA City that's the
short story of LA City where we are
right now West Hollywood was Hollywood
people like rob myself we've been
working very very hard in the City of
West Hollywood to get them to you know
create some really good policy and I
think we've done quite an excellent job
I have to say and I think we're gonna
have some incredible policy here in West
Hollywood we're gonna see on-site
consumption lounges actual individual
lounges we're gonna see on Kai's on-site
consumption for retail we're gonna see
delivery we're gonna see infusion places
so that if you want to have a making
this up if you want to have a cupcake
place and you want to have a commercial
kitchen in the back and infuse you could
do that you won't be able to do your
extractions here probably but you can
certainly do your infusions here so this
city is gonna probably have some really
really forward-thinking cannabis policy
where the ordinance itself the draft
will be read in early November so you
know we got a couple months before we
actually have that but we pretty much
know what's going to be in it so I just
want to congratulate the City of West
Hollywood for doing really an excellent
job and hopefully leading California in
great policy yes
so the question is how is Hollywood
addressing social lounges as opposed to
what with those just in regards to the
state right okay
so the simple question a simple answer
to that is the state is not going to
issue on-site consumption licenses they
will adhere to it but they're not
actually there's no license you can get
from the state for on-site consumption
you'll be able to get that from your
city if your city issues them so as it
relates to its two full Joel its its
standalone consumption lounges like this
is a bar right standalone bar would be
like this except no alcohol so that
would be one way to do it the other way
to do it is if this place as an example
was able to apply for a retail license
excuse me a a consumption license and
somehow worked it out with alcohol
beverage Commission with ABC that's
gonna be the challenge but I think that
the city is gonna have a lot to do with
that the city is gonna come and take a
look at who wants licenses if it's a
hotel bar spa yoga studio restaurant
whatever it is so this is gonna be
figured out but I think we're gonna see
that first in this city and hopefully
they'll set some good standards for the
rest of the the rest of the states so
we're really really happy about that
because we all need let's face it even
though it sounds fun to have one we
actually need safe places to consume if
you're gonna sell you have to have a
place to consume and if you have
tourists where are they gonna go they
can't go to a hotel because it's not
legal there so you have to provide a
safe place for people to consume
otherwise you're sending them back out
under the streets so we don't want to do
that okay finally I just want to bring
up a B 1578 which some of you know is
the assembly bill that was put on by
Assemblymember Rob Reggie Jones Sawyer
who's from South LA and he created a
bill that has already passed the
California State Assembly which is
basically keep Trump and sessions out of
our legal cannabis business it's a
federal non-cooperation bill it's
already passed the assembly we needed to
pass the Senate it's currently in hold
it took in a holding position it's not
dead by any means we're gonna either
know at the end of next week or in
January if it's going to pass through
this
if passes through the Senate we're in
great shape what's gonna happen is at
that time when it whether it's next week
or in January there's going to be a call
to action and we're going to need to get
engaged and start calling getting on the
phone and calling all these senators
from California and telling them how to
vote so if anybody wants to be a part of
that list and you want to contribute
when the call comes
there is a special list up at the front
where you checked in it has nothing to
do with the mailing list it won't be a
mailing list thing it's just so I
actually can have your information and
know who to contact when we get that
call so if you want to be involved you
want to do something sign up on that
list and then I'll hold on to that and
let you know when I get that call
because we really really need to keep
those guys out of our legal cannabis
business once we're licensed they should
have no part of this so just keep that
in mind so that's a be 1578 so that's
coming soon okay
beyond that the state is going to issue
emergency regulations in sometime in
November there's going to be a five day
comment period for that that's it so
once those new regulations come out if
you're interested in commenting you have
five days and then after that it's all
over for at least for a while so keep
don't if you're not on any lists get on
lists and find out when this stuff is
happening so that you could be a part of
it
[Music]