I still think you're gonna see a huge
reduction initially in cultivars that
are in the system because primarily
nobody really holds the same number of
different types of varietals and
produces the number of different
varietals as a craft culture does so a
craft culture and it's rounded
development of cannabis production
you'll have big swaths of it moving into
commercial realm but the people hold
their own libraries of things they think
of trendy and things that they like
historically and things that work for
them specifically and so that population
the majority of those people probably 95
percent of them total don't have a
permit so it doesn't allow them to work
with that population a plant anymore
because those people can't enter the new
system unless they take their plants and
have somebody in the nursery license it
and start to work those directions in
and even then that's difficult because
there's tracking the money as it goes
through so how do you pay and ultimately
it'll be whatever's in the hands of the
people who have the permits right now
and we have a an intake period just like
Washington did we will take plants in
over two-week period that's our
inception point we log every single
plant we ran in the building we roll the
seed stock we log all the genetic and
that begins our whole path for the
future and from that we're supposed to
work it out as we go forward but no new
stuff to just enter the system unless
you're getting it from some other legal
entity where you can then say yes I
bought this plant from this place with
its tracking number that's why the
tracking numbers around the plants not
so much that the people who buy legal
plants when you're at a store by July 1
and you came to a legal cannabis store
you wouldn't be able to get a tray of
plants anymore you can get six total
just six and each one of those has a tag
on it that identifies that that's a
unique plant and so when you're when
you're talking about a tray of clones
which you couldn't buy unless you had a
permit
that'll be one single tag for the whole
hundreds so a trade plunge is called a
lot so say we have two trades we have 50
in each one but we call 100 back so we
can even have three trades in the 33
well close we call it a 99 lot but the
bottom because it's they're gonna count
so you can't even like screw this one up
every single plant has to be trapped in
this component so they're doing it as a
hundred count but if you start having
plants missing they want to know where
they went to in the tracking system and
so regular people that have no permits
just regular cannabis growers consumers
can come into the store and then right
now they can still buy with their 215
they can still buy legal what they can
get in their hands but after July 1 it
is 6 plants period per person per day I
don't they and I don't even know that
they have they're having issues now in
other states where they're having the
law enforcement teams come in and make
repeated purchases through the day and
they arrested all the budtender so one
of the most successful shops in Colorado
and a very great well if you like be
like what we use like say Brittany
patients group is an example something
that's big and established imagine if
they came in and you sold someone in
ounce a couple times in the same day
only an ounce each transaction but they
came back multiple times well not even
to the same person every time it was
just different tenders
well they arrested 14 of them and gave
them felony drug trafficking charges so
it's in Denver are one of the big scene
of a big major Colorado cities so I
tripped out because it was it was it was
a it's an interpretation of how they are
gonna serve on these type of situations
and so ultimately for dispensaries to be
careful you know they or storefronts now
you sell the six to the individual and
that's all they could take with them but
if I wanted as a as a farm to be able to
buy this or meaning as like a nursery to
buy I could go to a dispensary buy six
from a dispensary and then take it to my
storefront and enter it legally into my
system I think we could long as we can
track this movement of plant material so
plants could still make it through in
the fashion but
it's gonna be really tough and for most
people if they get caught with anything
your neighbor doesn't like in they say
hey you got the plants in the backyard
in the cops visit you and they make you
cut down anything but six well lo and
behold the the other 22 you had with the
ones you've been holding on to that
really allows you to have genetic
differentiation and so no matter what
it's gonna be hard to get the same
amount of varieties to this to the buyer
that they're used to because you're not
gonna have half the people I bet maybe
90% of ninety-five percent of the oil
blowers I talk to I'm gonna be permitted
either because everybody's blowing oil
and I got a spot but I'm like but you're
do you have a state permit for that and
no and and so it's it's kind of weird
because there's like a quasi belief that
you're permitted because you're doing
something illegally and no one's
arresting you but that doesn't mean
you're permitted and in a second it
doesn't make a difference what you
believe if you don't have a number it
can't be bought to a store we can't do
anything with it as a farmer if I don't
have a tag on the plant that matches I
can't give it to the lab I can't give it
to the distributor I can't give it to
the the processor I can't give it to
this it has to track in a linear fashion
and so you're gonna have it when
radically compressed group of genetics
and I know I mean I know some guys get
they got some plants and doing their
thing but there's no way that the big
operations even if they diversified an
acre at a time would equal the number of
little producers in the state of
California that used to produce cannabis
we're talking every neighborhood in
California had people grown out of
garages and a lot of doing damn good job
growing some really nice cannabis but in
different varieties because the
dispensaries took it from them and so
they provided just those four or five
pounds per run of whatever it was they
did but there was
tens of thousands of them you know and
so how can any any conglomerate compete
with that sheer quantity people so I
believe you're gonna get a radically
neck-down amount of strains and
availability initially until the they
can then start to multiply what they
want to do from there I'm going to urge
the markets
[Music]