[Music]
okay here at MLG there's kind of a
slight distinction between you know the
licensing side of things and then what I
called the operational compliance which
is kind of my my terrain is it's kind of
there's getting your license then
there's keeping it and not having it
taken away so a lot of this part of the
presentation is kind of a review because
so much of what happened in this round
is like everything we feared from the
last round happened so so we can review
that so I do like to start with let's
remember all the good news in the
positive things that happened one of the
big ones was that you can now put label
THC and CBD cannabinoid content after
final form so the distributor's can can
label it so a significant percentage of
failures that was happening was because
of the label claims so this is a so this
is a big one that's going to help a lot
of products actually make it to market
without going through the loop of having
to real able because every test results
going to be slightly different
they made the exemption for tinctures
containing alcohol so that product type
got to survive
we got distribution to distribution
transfers thanks to SB 311 you have
retail to retail transfer clarification
so that a retailer an owner that owns
multiple stores can contract
distributors to move inventory between
those stores there's expanded events
location thanks to a be 20/20 evidently
for LA it's gonna be 20/20 right before
they get their local events they're like
there won't be any local events till
2020 and you're like no there's gonna be
a lot of them they just won't be
licensed a one another big win and this
one was that you can reject and accept
partial shipments there was a provision
previously that was either you had to
accept the whole shipment or reject it
if something was wrong now there's some
carve outs for if there's things that
aren't accurately reflected on there on
the shipping
FSU can not take those items if things
are visibly damaged you cannot take
those if it's non-compliant labeling
lies because your in taking you can
reject the non-compliant we labeled
goods and if things are past their
expired or best by date you cannot
accept those there's some remediation
for edibles so if you have I don't know
saya ten of blueberries in there over a
hundred milligrams you can actually take
a couple of blueberries out and
repackage it and be like now we got a
hundred milligrams so that's nice
instead of having to destroy it all oh
that's that's awesome there's some
higher action levels for the category
two solvents which will help some more
products make it to market as Josh was
saying lots of new forms it's gonna be
so much fun
filling those out and possibly a little
bit more clarity around some other
things and then there were other things
so I mean we still continue with with
the white-hot white labeling panic and
as Josh was saying like with the
expansion of definitions of ownership
and financially interested parties and
this detail in 50:32 be specifically
that licensees shall not conduct
commercial cannabis activities on behalf
of at the request of or pursuant to a
contract with any person that is not
licensed under the Act very problematic
for people who had white labeling
situations and less that they have a
license they're an owner or a disclose
as a financially interested party many
many people are thinking of many many
workarounds like well I'll go get
temporary event licenses and it's like
yet you still have to disclose the
owners in that situation too so the main
thing is the the thing that I see
overall and the revisions that they're
going through is you see that the
agencies are learning the agencies are
seeing where people are hiding money
where they're hiding owners where they
don't know what they're doing and
they're starting slowly but surely to
kind of like appeal a part of some of
those things some of these become really
problematic
because reactionary regulating is never
good for the long run but you you see
the process and you get to the concept
underneath it and the concept underneath
though this white labeling prohibition
is that if you can call it that is they
want to know who's playing they want to
know who's who
who's the participants they want and as
Josh said the warm bodies who is it
interested in not hiding behind entities
corporations you know not disclosures
whatever it's interesting you know they
in the previous version there was there
was rumor that like 50 32b was gonna get
struck they in the previous version they
had all of these kind of they laid out
the prohibitions of like what they meant
by commercial cannabis activities that
that maybe would be prohibited by non
licensees and this is got to be my
favorite thing if you read the final
statement of reasons it's beautiful
is that when they put that in and this
is from the final statement of reasons
from the BCC it says you know initially
they determined it was necessary to
assist licensees with determining what
types of activity by having these
examples however then they determined
that the inclusion of the examples
crossed more confusion than clarity so
they took them out that doesn't mean
that those examples are not legitimate
examples of what they mean by in
participating in cannabis and commercial
cannabis activity without a license
it just means that they if anything I
would suggest did not want to limit
themselves to only those definitions
that in fact this gives them a more
broad scope of being able to determine
on a case-by-case basis
what they consider to be engaging in
commercial cannabis activity without a
license now the funny thing is it I
don't know if they're just crazy or like
gaslighting us I have no idea but the
agencies say in conversations with Lorri
Ajax the the standard thing that we
understand as white labeling did not
enter their consciousness at all as what
they were
to prohibit so it's it's odd as we
proceed because they're not really
trying to shut down while the the
practice of white labeling as most of us
know it they in in one conversation it
was more that they went into retailers
and still found unlicensed product and
they were like we have to stop this
unlicensed product from getting into
retailers so this was their solution
there's a whole lot of other regulations
to prevent unlicensed rug from paying
out of retail locations so I'm not
really sure that that explanation is
sound but it's it's the one thing that
we know from all of the regulatory
agencies is they're not done regulating
there is still gonna be cleanup they're
still gonna be a new language that's why
I'm saying the permanent regulations are
never permanent because they're just
gonna keep refining this process but in
case just as a refresher anybody wants
to know when you're like well what's
commercial cannabis activity you can go
back to the definition of it from the
business and Professions Code which is
the cultivation possession manufacture
distribution processing storing lab
testing packaging labeling
transportation delivery or sale of
cannabis and cannabis products so any
you know commercial cannabis activity we
saw the technology platform regulations
are stood and carried over so their
reasoning for this was that they found a
number of licensees were engaging
delivery services that were facilitated
by platforms but the use of the
platforms was creating confusion with
customers as to whether it was licensee
conducting that activity or not so some
technology platforms may create the
impression they hold a license and they
determined that it was necessary to
clarify that this is all from the final
statement of reasons so generally they
just kind of you know went a little more
granular this language was in the last
version in October that you know that
they can't sell or otherwise transfer a
good or licensed retailer through the
use of an unlicensed third party
intermediary business broker or any
other business or entity but
you can contract with the service that
provides a technology platform to
facilitate these sales and delivery and
then there's lots of step you know
stipulations in terms of what that has
to look like the products can't be
delivered by that technology platform
that technology platform can't share in
the profits of the sale of those
cannabis Goods or otherwise provide for
a percentage of the portion of the
cannabis good sales can't be provided to
them they can't advertise in conjunction
with the technology provider outside of
the platform and they cannot in the
technology platform can't use the
licensees license number to advertise in
any advertising and marketing that
primarily promotes that technology
platform incredibly specific they're
very very specific about this so in in
because back to that original reasoning
that it was to prevent the confusion of
knowing who you're buying from they
added in a lot of these disclosures that
those items offered for sale have to
disclose at a minimum the licensed
retailers or micro businesses legal
business name and license number
same thing with if it's ordered through
the platform they have to be able to see
the business name and the license number
that they are ordering those products
from before they make the purchase so if
you're on the platform and you're
looking at a product you need to in
advance of getting it and maybe seeing
it on the receipt know what licensed
dispensary is going to be delivering
this product that information has to be
on the receipt as well so so it gives me
good news about that I would say is it
gives a lot more visibility to the
retailers that are actually providing
the products that are being delivered
through these technology platforms so
one of the biggest wins obviously to
delivery was it was the delivery to a
physical address the part that held is
that you can deliver anywhere within the
state of California provided that such
delivery is conducted in compliance with
all delivery provision
I think that some of you probably saw
the League of Cities did the big one
during weed campaign with all these
beautiful cartoon children terrified of
the of the symbol so one of the
additions we saw was this subsection II
just to clarify delivery employees can't
deliver to a school so please don't do
that the kindergarten or one through
twelve college totally fine day care
center or Youth Center so the the
wandering weed site came down it's no
longer up they did it on Squarespace you
can tell by the lot of missing sight
signal so we saw the value that had
dropped previously from ten thousand to
five thousand of what can be carried in
the car at any time that stayed so you
have to have at least two thousand
dollars in orders to be sallying forth
on your delivery route the they had the
cage was clarified that the cage in the
delivery vehicles same as transportation
distribution vehicles now has to be a
fully enclosed separate box container a
cage then no portion of it shall be
comprised of any part of the vehicle or
trailer this is mirrored and
distribution that it has to be this
inside structure there's record-keeping
requirements for locations that stayed
in which is that the history of all
locations traveled while engaging in
delivery has to be maintained for a
minimum of 90 days so that's turn by
turn GPS records for all delivery
drivers has to be kept and kept for
seven years because it falls under our
record-keeping provisions a super-fun
project for a lot of people is going to
be the now you can deliver to Catalina
the thing so good luck
this couldn't be fun there's a lot of
how they do it
a blonde was at the state of cannabis a
couple years ago and I was on a panel
she learned all this problem and get
them access and so what they found out
was that in Washington State and some of
these remote islands that they were
considering state-chartered votes to not
be federal water because you are on
state property
so that's other things about take care
of me not okay I'll not hold my breath
before they figure out how state
chartered boats is gonna work and what's
the fee structure for using a state
chartered boat to transport your
cannabis get some favor they want it
well yeah I mean it's interesting
because they'll have to be that's the
interesting thing that we've had is
there's gonna be have to be other
provisional carve-outs because it's
impossible in some ways to fulfill the
requirements for delivery such as a
vehicle with a cage and stuff when there
is not a single ferry boat that
transports vehicles to the island so
they would have to change all of the
transportation regulations for once you
get off the boat that you can hand carry
it to anywhere in Avalon and so so it's
it's a great concept and obviously the
people of Avalon deserve to have their
cannabis but it's but
in the constant the constant caveat in
everything we're doing is right now I'm
talking about state regulations state
regulations are also a companion to
local regulations local regulations and
state regulations are a companion to
federal regulations and when all of
these things work together then we have
regulated cannabis so while it's fine
and good that now you can deliver to any
municipality in California that's great
certain localities have their own local
ordinances that restrict delivery for
example in the city of Bellflower you
can a delivery driver can only carry up
to 200 dollars at any time yeah yeah so
good luck ok good luck with your $3,000
of goods in your trunk when you can only
collect $200 at any time to be in
accordance with the Bellflower local
ordinance so so I mean it's a much
greater conversation we'll kind of touch
on a little bit later of just like the
problem of synthesizing the localities
with the state is immense and how in how
to keep in mind all that stuff in
general this is just some stuff about
advertising I know I know Wes knows this
whenever you can't find something that
you know is a regulation don't forget to
look in the business and Professions
Code because you can read the entire you
know cannabis regulations of the BCC and
think I don't have to put my license
number on a billboard no way there's
nothing that says that guess what it's
in the business and Professions Code so
that's where you would go to look for
these statutory requirements such as
that all advertising and marketing has
to identify at a minimum the licensee
responsible for that ad with their
license number a technology platform
cannot display an advertisement by a
licensee without a license number
attached to it and in
door advertising company can't display
an advertisement unless they display the
license number so theoretically every ad
anywhere at all times you are seeing now
should have a license number on it
who's enforcing that who knows we'll see
the other prohibition that did hold and
came through from the last time was the
prohibition against marketing cannabis
goods as alcoholic products so you can't
sell or transport kamas goods that are
labeled as beer wine liquor spirits or
any other term that might create a
misleading impression this little
statements from the the final statement
of reasons they felt that was necessary
because since recently passed
legislation prohibits actually making a
cannabis alcoholic beverage they don't
want to confuse consumers by thinking
that cannabis wine is actually wine
so they they took that one away so they
and they extended that so they extended
the prohibition to anything that could
recreate the misleading impression that
the product may be an alcoholic beverage
so for retailers there was the limit on
the sale of non cannabis Goods state
this is a pretty limited definition of
what you can sell in addition to
cannabis Goods a licensed retailer may
only may sell only cannabis accessories
and any licensees branded merchandise so
in your retail store you can sell
cannabis you can sell cannabis
accessories and you can sell branded
merchandise and then you can have
promotional materials they allow that
you can provide promotional materials
which is like informational pamphlets
things that have no monetary value that
are given to you by those organizations
in the final statement of reasons they
are incredibly specific so if you have
any questions about what exactly is a
cannabis accessory it's the the business
and Professions Code actually points to
the health and safety code for that
definition where it's still called
marijuana accessories and and kind of
broke that it has a pretty expansive
definition and that it's any equipment
products materials of any kind which are
used in ten
for use designed for use in planting
propagating cultivating growing
harvesting manufacturing compounding
converting producing processing
preparing testing analyzing packaging
repackaging storing smoking vaporizing
or containing marijuana or for ingesting
inhaling or otherwise inducing merry
introducing marijuana or marijuana
products into the human body it's
beautiful it's beautiful
so in the final statement of reasons
they get specific of what they mean that
cannabis retailers are licensed to sell
cannabis Goods the definition of
cannabis within the acts explicitly
excludes industrial hemp products
industrial hemp is regulated by the
California industrial hit program under
the California industrial hemp farming
act a retail license from the Bureau
other eise's retailer to sell cameras
goods and cannabis it does not authorize
them to sell items that are unrelated to
cannabis
so they're pretty clear you're not
supposed to be selling industrial hemp
products anymore they've been they've
been clear now branded merchandise the
thing that you are allowed to sell they
get specific on that to clothing hats
pencils pens keychains mugs water
bottles beverage glasses notepads and
lanyards and cannabis accessories that
are branded with the name and logo of a
commercial cannabis business that is a
licensed commercial cannabis business if
it is not one of those listed items you
have to get written approval from the
bureau in order to carry that branded
merchandise you have to write to them
you have to send them a picture of it
and they have to approve it before you
can sell that additional branded
merchandise and the branded merchandise
has to be from a licensee sure a bong I
would say is a cannabis accessory it
goes under that definition of yeah
cannabis accessories is a subdivision of
branded merchandise so you can brand
your cannabis accessories as well yeah
that would not be something have the
SBCC about that would not be permitted
because it's not branded merchandise by
a licensee it would be if you viewed the
branded merchandise is and you know you
can't sell Nike sneakers you know cuz
that's branded merchandise or whatever
it it would be that if you wanted to
partner with an Instagram person and put
your name and logo and license number on
that then that might be where you could
get something approved in that way but
it seems that they're being very
specific that the branded merchandise
should be of a licensee this is
something I would ask you know your
friendly neighborhood attorney about
because in that final statement of
reasons when they're saying that
clarification that a retail license
authorizes you to sell cannabis what I
deduce from that is they're saying like
getting a retail cannabis license does
not give you authorize you to sell like
Coke and Doritos like you have to get a
city lease business permit that you have
to it's a different kind of seller's
permit you do that things and what a lot
of retailers are doing is segmenting
their businesses so that you have your
cannabis retail area where you're
selling your cannabis products and then
you have another non lace you know not
part of that area where you're selling
everything else and you can and you can
get your city business permanent and do
your thing there and pay your taxes that
way because of course for the amount
you're being taxed for your retail space
why would you sell Doritos there you
want to sell them somewhere else yeah
I mean if it's a cannabis well it's a
cannabis product at that point as long
as it's a business anything that is a
branded product is a non cannabis
product and they are very specific to
about those branded products it's not
food like you can't make it no no any
licensee yeah yeah so you can sell any
other licensees branded products exactly
exactly because I would imagine that
what you are gonna have is just like you
have manufacturing brands or cultivator
brands that are you know brands and
logos in themselves that they are going
to want to sell that branded merchandise
through retail yeah yeah well claiming
health benefits is a whole other ball of
wax you don't want a tussle with go
ahead
I mean it's a great question in terms of
what enforcement's gonna look like and
who's gonna be responsible and and
that's kind of the big issue I mean
especially for the compliance folks is
it's it's difficult to prioritize or
convince people that this is important
when there seems to be such a lack of
visible enforcement or that it's very
kind of pick and choose nila haystack
but we have had enforcement actions
happen where agencies are going into
retailers and pulling product off the
shelf that's non-compliant and and
they're getting more and more specific
about it my concern is always right now
obviously the agencies are in this
period of where they've got all the
temporary licensed applicator you know
there's a lot going on right now but
once they've been they are beating up
their teams they're having huge staff
increases and next year when they're
bored on a Tuesday
it's my concern as it becomes the new
smash-and-grab because it's like it's so
easy to walk into any retailer any
facility any way and find egregious in
gigantic compliance violations you know
it may not seem like a big deal but when
you start going through their
disciplinary actions and their and the
penalties and fees that they can levy
you know the one that comes up later in
this I mean there's a there's an
administrative fine for record-keeping
that can be as high as $30,000 per
instance of not keeping accurate records
so it's like they have I mean which is
like fear police but it's like it's it's
really is a vulnerable position because
there's just so many nuances and
regulations and interpretations which is
why it's really critical to at this
moment be practicing all of these things
for record-keeping for inventory for in
taking product all those processes and
also building your internal compliance
program your compliance team your legal
team making sure that those things are
in place because it's you know it
they've really got the industry in the
crosshairs in many ways yeah
like we're never gonna see like a
statewide campaign going against branded
schwag being sold at retailers but where
this might come into play is if they get
a complaint about you somebody complains
that you're selling to kids and they
send an agent there and while the agents
there you know they clearly see that
you're not selling the kids but oh by
the way while we're out here we noticed
that you have this unbranded approved
branded merchandise and that's where
they could just come up and cite you
because these enforcement agencies at
the end of the day they're driven by and
demographics and and demographics as to
like what types of discipline and
charges they're able to prove up because
they've got a budget they get it each
year from the state so they need to be
able to point to results and say that
we've you know identified ten thousand
you know infractions over the last year
we need more money because you know we
want to be able to get twelve thousand
infractions next year so you know it's a
roundabout way of saying that you know
they're on the books and and it really
becomes a tool for them to use when they
want to go after somebody but it may not
necessarily be like a statewide primary
enforcement mechanism yeah and in
something that I like to remind people
of is right now especially for licensees
that are really suffering within the you
know the unlicensed market and that kind
of competition where what you have is at
the beginning of an industry beginning
to howl for enforcement as a solution
and I like to caution people to be
incredibly specific about what you mean
when you ask for enforcement because
when you're asking the BCC for
enforcement the BCC enforces against
licensees what the illicit market and
the unlicensed market is a criminal
activity at this point and that is the
wing that would have to enforce against
that activity and we'll touch on this
later but obviously a lot of the problem
in those areas is about pathways to
licensure and how difficult that is with
local authorizations that there's a lot
of folks that would get licensed if the
localities kind of made that
a little easier yeah that is accurate
yes you are no longer supposed to be
carrying CBD products that are derived
from hemp that are not gotten from a
licensed cannabis cultivators
manufacturer producer all of the
agencies have been very clear you are
not supposed to have that stuff anymore
so if there is still a distributor that
is supplying hemp products actually if I
keep on going there's like I will list
the ways in which they tell you across
the board absolutely not honey
yeah yeah I mean that yes it's a
different taxation but in the end that
there were people rampantly created
committing tax fraud knowingly because
they were placing excise tax on hemp
products they're not doing it on
cannabis products it's it's a messy
problem that is gonna take a while
and it's only gonna get Messier now with
confusion around the relevance of the
farm bill and what that means and
different guidance coming from different
places it's it's gonna be an ugly time
so yeah yeah if you have a shop on
Venice Beach that is a non cannabis
dispensary you can sell a t-shirt with a
cannabis leaf on it all day long if you
are a licensed dispensary operating
under a cannabis license and in your
cannabis retail area you can only sell
branded merchandise that is branded by a
licensee so what if you manufacture you
can do that if you're a licensee no yeah
well this would be my question would be
where is this giant is it inside your
store yes so yes so these specific
things that I'm going through right here
is advertising and marketing so this is
kind of like there-there's exceptions
and you'd have to look at them closely
and get granular as there's things that
can happen inside your store that aren't
considered advertising and marketing and
then outside the store is so this
specifically is talking about that your
advertising and marketing cannot show a
depiction of a minor of inflatables of a
movie character of a cartoon character
that in your marketing you cannot do
those they cleaned it up you know and
this is they have some great thoughts
around you know what is appealing to
people or minors or anyone under 21
years of old age this is an important
fact to for anybody that's cleaning up
your old
list if you have had medical clientele
who are 18 years old between the ages of
eighteen and until they're 21
you cannot advertise to those people
that they are not an advertising
candidate we only advertising people
over 21 years old so especially in the
case if you're doing direct marketing so
if you have a text list or you're doing
emails and you haven't cleaned up your
email list and you are direct marketing
to 18 19 and 20 year olds you're gonna
want to clean that up
because the people who used to be your
clientele and you were it may have been
telling them about deals and promos
you're not telling them about that
anymore so the one of the things that
did come through that's important for
record-keeping is that there was this
audience composition data this
mysterious audience comes with some data
that they request and now they have put
in that this your ads show be displayed
and this may seem like a no-brainer but
they're specific now after you've gotten
that audience composition data so and
not only do you have to have it you
really have to have it because much like
other records you have to be able to
produce it immediately upon request so
it's not like let me call the company
and I'm sure they have it somewhere
before you place an ad before you put up
a billboard you have to have that
audience composition data again look at
it closely because a lot of those
companies they do at eighteen plus
you've got to make sure that it's 21
plus on that composition data and they
added this line that used to be my
favorite line for employee training
which is there's another section where
it says and construing and forcing the
the act that any action omission or
failure on the part of an employee is
the licensees fault now they've added
that any action omission or failure on
the part of an advertising agent or
representative or contractor for
marketing and licensing is your fault as
the licensee so clearly is because the
BCC can't enforce against advertising
companies if you get the advertising
company to say hey we just say that it's
21 up can you help me out here it is
your problem if that if that information
proves faulty it is your problem so if
that audience composition data is still
there and I know I keep saying this
every time
we're all gonna do it together we're
gonna stop saying free you cannot
advertise you cannot advertise free
products tub it um no matter how craft
do you think you're being nothing's free
anymore so Dave Dave this is in relation
to advertising marketing again you
cannot advertise free cannabis goods are
it giveaways of any type of products
including non cannabis products so not
only can you not say like get a free
pre-roll you can't say get a free
t-shirt you can't say get a free lighter
you depends where you are it depends it
this is where this is where you cannot
advertise you cannot advertise that that
is happening so they get specific it
can't be buy one product and one product
it can't be free with donation it can't
be contest sweepstakes or raffles this
is my favorite reasoning in the whole
thing is in their statement of reasons
the reason why you cannot have a raffle
is because they have deemed that the
dissemination of promotional giveaways
may appeal to underage people so we
can't have raffles because a minor might
want to do it it might be likely to and
I was like you know you know what
raffles and sweepstakes are appealing to
freaking older people who have jobs and
no money like that to my kid doesn't
care about a raffle election doesn't
even know what that means
that's it there's no I love the
statement of reasons it's brilliant it's
brilliant so so yes but back to your
statement George this their localities
it's a beautiful tear I had I almost put
it in again because it's my favorite
slide the the state says you cannot give
away any free canvas goods yeah the
business and Professions Code says you
cannot give away Canada goods or
cannabis accessories Los Angeles says
you can't give away cannabis Goods
canvas accessories or anything else so
depending on
accessories also a tobacco accessory
does it have to be 21 and over
granular legally I mean that um I mean
that's that's the thing if it is what my
understanding is is if it is in your
store as a cannabis dispensary it is no
longer a tobacco product because you
cannot sell tobacco products you know
it's a cannabis accessory but that would
be I mean that that kind of gets into
that's what I'm saying is it is depends
on the locality because you'd have to
look at local prohibitions like Los
Angeles for example says you cannot give
away anything of any kind including
cannabis so they're like you can't even
give away t-shirt theoretically in Los
Angeles
ya know our you know dinner generally
generally I'd like to caution everybody
not to give anything away ever that's
like just don't do it but but that's
where it becomes critical that different
localities have different prohibitions
against certain things and the thing to
remember is that the state Trump's it
all the localities can have rules that
are more restrictive than the state but
they can't have rules that are less
restrictive than the state yeah
if you're in Los Angeles yes no that's
anywhere that is now the state you
cannot have a contest of sweepstakes or
a raffle
you cannot and that's not just limited
to cannabis Goods that is nothing you
can't offer to give a free anything to
anybody for them I mean I love that
little silly I agree how they keep up I
don't know but yeah I mean it becomes it
because obviously everything cannabis
has been a population of people who are
pretty okay with certain kinds of risk
you know for a lot of years so for every
company it's fine what I would say is
now that they have put in that little
part that any act omission or failure of
your advertising company that may be in
compliance with everything is is the
your licensees issue that's of concern I
mean that requires because I know I know
it's like the new it used to be
everybody's like I know the best master
grower ever and now it's like I have the
most compliant POS ever I have the thing
my thing works too there you know it's
like compliance is a I'm thinking it's a
philosophical concept because it's kind
of like it's it's a difficult thing to
wrangle because it's an ever-evolving
thing so they may be in they may be in
compliance with what the emergency
regulations are but I don't know how
they'd be in compliance with what just
came out and you know few days ago yeah
and gives France so there's there's no
kind of license we can have so which
leaves us in a gray area because we're
not I mean I may have used the term
prohibition through regulation a few
times in my casual conversations yeah
yeah I mean I don't want to go too far
down the rabbit hole in this because I
have a lot more to cover but I would say
you need to look very very closely about
how these things interact with other
regulations because there's the branded
merchandise and then there's no free
products and then there's other areas in
the regs where it's like a
representative of another licensee can't
give anything to anybody in your store
so so it's important to kind of tie them
all together and not just take one spot
yeah yes that's why I just AM like can
everybody just stop trying to give
everything away for free because if you
actually have a transaction and a record
of a transaction and you fulfill
record-keeping requirements and you
carry the taxes over correctly for the
right items in in in large part problem
solved and that's where I just think
about think about the agencies think
about their fears and the fear is
diversion and like who's playing and cry
so it's like give them visibility on the
movement of everything and then you know
they see what they need to see so we we
have this engines the last one for the
BCC then there's many other things to
talk about the child resistant packaging
exit package 14 or whatever you want to
call it this is we we had a shift back
that's wonderfully confusing to package
or not to package that is the question
that's what I say
so the way they put it is it all
cannabis goods sold by a licensee
retailer has to be in compliance with
the packaging requirements those are
described in the CD pH and we'll go a
little bit into that so beginning on
January 1st 2020 you have to do the full
kahuna we do resealable tamper-evident
and child resistant with some
granulations around product type all
cannabis goods purchased by a customer
can't leave the relations retailer
premises unless it's in an opaque exit
bag and then they clarified they added
the clarifying line that the immature
plants and seeds don't have to be put
into an exit bag please don't put a
little cloning next to bags let it
breathe so so those can go out and a
opaque bag so until that date because
that's Dan we're first 2020 this they
inserted the line the child resistant
packaging requirements
may be met through the use of a child
resistant exit package at retail sale
that's the department public health
saying that the business and Professions
Code I mean what they're trying to do is
to comply with what's in the business
and Professions Code while providing
licensees with time to comply with
packaging requirements some of us are
confused because the packaging
requirements were supposed to be
complied with back in July so we've been
complying with them for almost six
months but now they're like you need
more time so this again is it is a
greater you know if there's more clarity
hopefully to come but the thought is
that because they're saying you may
satisfy the packaging requirement with
an exit bag that it would stand to
reason that a product already in child
resistant packaging could theoretically
you leave in an opaque bag but a product
that's not in child resistant packaging
would have to be put in an exit bag most
attorneys I'm gonna guess advising their
clients are going to say put it in an
exit bag because how do you know and are
you gonna take the liability of like
whoops that wasn't actually he's child
resistant I was wrong I mean and as I
shared last time that that's the issue
is that we find ourselves in this Kafka
esque or a Boros of putting child
resistant packaging inside of child
resistant packaging
and and we're hoping on this issue that
with the incoming administration in
Sacramento and you know that possibly
there will be some legislative changes
there's talk about environmental groups
getting involved in Sierra Club being
involved because obviously we just have
an ecological disaster on our hands of
of this this amount of packaging and the
unsustainability and those issues but
for now that's what they have there for
the solution so a little bit that came
out in the CD pH Department of Health
for manufacturers it was interesting I
love that they added just one word just
one word in here which is homogeneity in
terms of the definition and it's
important because this is just something
that from the agency from the department
Public Health there's this kind of the
best because you can tell that they went
on some tours and they were horrified
like they that's what you've read is
you've read it and they're like what is
happening so they put in homogeneity
just so people would understand that
your processes and procedures need to be
developed with the in goal of
homogeneity uniformity THD throughout
not just passing free from contaminants
because they're obviously finding some
some hot blueberries and it's like you
guys got to spread that out across the
board I also find interesting this is
back to the BCC we remember that
designation of owner that Josh was
talking about and they removed all these
specifics out of it and there was a line
in there that was wonderfully vague that
said any individual that assumes
responsibility for the licensee could be
considered an owner the beautiful thing
is they move that line to the CD pH Rex
so that one appeared over there so now
in owners and financial adjust holders
and Department of Health we have the
beautifully vague any individual that
assumes responsibility for a license and
this was one again in the BCC that they
put in there to clarify cause more
confusion so instead of further
clarifying they just took it out and
it's like no more clarity for you so on
the city pH side beginning January 1st
2020 everything has to be child
resistant veiled I'm just going to
through these because I don't know how
many you can read it it's um they get
granular on what that's gonna look like
in 2020 this is the future man let's
live in the present so they did add more
clarification on what is considered
child resistant in response to a lot of
questions that they were getting a very
important thing in cannabinoid content
labeling that I want to point out to
everybody is that with that now delayed
possibility of putting testing results
on after it's in its final form you can
have a distributor and can sticker it
after however they did add that the
manufacturer shall identify a location
for the cannabinoid content label on the
outer packaging of the product so this
is just for everybody who's already been
through a hundred designs of their
packaging now you have to include if
you're gonna have it sticker later you
have to see if you have to demarcate
where they're supposed to put that
sticker some people may have already
done that Lots I've seen didn't they
then put it on there so now you got to
put a spot they they put more clarity in
terms of how to do cannabinoid content
labeling for pre-rolls the CD pH didn't
really realize that they needed to do
that before they were like oh you want
us to tell you okay so now they got a
lot more specific about how about is
expressed how cannabinoid content is
expressed that it's one thing for flower
and then you have an option with infused
pre-rolls that you can either do it in
milligrams or the flower expressed as a
percentage in the additional concentrate
asbestos they got a little because
people like to be funny oh yeah and then
they added this for THC CBD that's less
than two milligrams per package you can
say less than two milligrams per package
obviously companies that are actually
doing micro dosing and want to be
specific they don't have to but you
can't so in the labeling restrictions
there were a couple new things added to
the labeling restrictions because again
they're onto you guys would be being
tricky so the name of a California
County we know Appalachians you can't
say it's from Humboldt if it's can't say
it's from Mendocino if it's not a
hundred percent you can also not use
this
similar name that's designed to mislead
people so you can't say like min dough's
with like a Z is like none of that don't
do it
same thing with candy and candies you
can't spell candy with a K you can't be
like candies but you doing it as you
know edibles had to be an opaque
packaging they also clarified you can't
put a picture on what's in it on the
package it's there's a reason they don't
want it to be visible don't put a
picture of the food inside on it you
can't do the same trickery with the word
organic by putting in making it organics
with an X don't do it just tub it so a
lot of the stuff in the CD pH 2 was just
it looks like a lot more new I think
than it is because they really
reorganize things and moved it around
for the manufacturers you're gonna want
to look at things like the Mannie Master
manufacturing protocol there was some a
lot more kind of clarity and the need
for written instructions for mitigating
identified risks is in there they added
product quality control plan information
in there the GMP s they welcome to the
health and safety code they pointed out
about 21 times in this new one to the
health and safety code I put it on the
list of things I never in my life
thought I would read as a child and now
it's on there so they also added
requirements for a quality control
program this is you know these ones that
are really telling that I've talked to
some people at this CD pH about this
that you know you have to establish
written procedures to document that this
is for extraction that the closed loop
extraction system is maintained in
accordance with the equipment
manufacturer specifications and ensure
of routine verification that it's
operating correctly and continues to
comply and you also have to develop SOPs
and good manufacturing product practices
in a training plan prior to doing it
like prior to producing the s tracks and
any person using solvents or gases in a
closed-loop system has to be fully
trained on how to use the system and
have direct access to the app
workable safety data sheets so the
Department of Public Health was going
into facilities and finding people who
got a manufacturing license and got a
fancy machine and had no idea how to use
it and didn't know you had to clean it
and didn't know how to clean it and it
never cleaned it so they were a little
disturbed so now they're asking for a
lot more information under permissible
extractions they added that co2 gas used
for extraction has to be food grade and
that you know volatile solvents that you
do you also have to use a closed-loop
extraction system please and then they
added a couple of things in prohibited
products about thermally processed low
acid cannabis products anybody know what
that is thermally it's canned food
that's what that is
so canned food and acidified cannabis
products is pickled food so that they're
saying that anything of those things
my understanding of those terms you can
go to the Code of Federal Regulations
and find your own solution but but
canned food pickled food it looks like
they're adding to the list of prohibited
products there used to be you can't
obviously add cannabis to fruit loops
and make that available but they have
added that you can put commercially
available foods into candy or snack food
it as an ingredient but it has to be
used in a way that renders it
unrecognizable as that commercially
available item and you can't list it in
the ingredients to say like M&amp;Ms isn't
my stuff they so this is this is um this
is back to the kind of industrial hemp
thing this is kind of what I call the
death toll for industrial hemp at this
moment is that these three regulations
so in the requirement for edibles it
already had that except for cannabis
cannabis concentrator terpenes no
ingredient can be used unless that
ingredient is permitted by the United
States Food and Drug Administration for
use in food or food manufacturing and
also now has to be generally recognized
as safe under Section yadda-yadda-yadda
so so for edibles that would mean non
industrial hemp because it is
not permitted by the United States Food
and Drug Administration now they've also
added that it for topical cannabis
products and concentrates they shall
only contain well this was a can only
contain ingredients permitted for
cosmetic manufacturing and in in
accordance with the title 21 Code of
Federal Regulations guess what's not in
there industrial hemp and then they
added now that a manufacturer licensee
shall only use cannabinoid concentrates
and extracts
that are manufactured or processed from
cannabis obtained from a licensed
cannabis cultivator how many times could
they use cannabis in the same sentence
they that seems pretty specific that
they're saying if you did not get that
cannabinoid and I don't know that we're
gonna argue that CBD is in the
cannabinoid from a licensed cannabis
cultivator it is not supposed to be in a
manufactured product they also have some
stuff about like not lies Mac
manufacturing preparing or packaging in
a food establishment or as a process
food registrant and also not in a
location that's licensed by the
Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control
which feels like they're kind of
pre-empting some of the coming
consumption areas and you know somewhere
like West Hollywood to be like just so
you know you can't have your facility in
a bar or a restaurant there was some new
definitions about tablets capsules and
orally consumed concentrates which is a
new category that got added they just to
specify because obviously you can see a
lot of people vying I remember that
there's a there's a mint company that
was trying to call their mint a orally
dissolving dehydrated tincture so that
it could have the a thousand milligrams
limit so they created this orally
consumed concentrate which is a
concentrate intended to be consumed by
your mouth and not otherwise edible so
it can include tinctures capsules and
tablets the line that they seem to be
drawing is it a capsule or a tablet is
something that is intended to be
swallowed whole
you drink it like a like a Tylenol or a
with some water there you go orally
consume concentrate is more like a mint
something that dissolves in the mouth
and it has natural artificial flavors or
sweeteners they're saying a tablet or a
capsule under their definition doesn't
have artificial flavors or sweeteners so
take a good look at those definitions
because orally consumed concentrates max
out can be up to 500 milligrams of THC
per package but over 100 milligrams they
have to be labeled for medical only and
can only be sold to medical patients but
a tablet that you swallow whole can be a
thousand milligrams it's makes total
sense across the board so the THC
concentration limits that's what I'm
saying in the 500 milligrams orally
consumed products containing alcohol was
specified that's our tinctures those
have to be in a container little no
larger than two fluid ounces and have to
have a calibrated dropper or a measuring
device that's kind of how they're
distinguishing a tincture from sneaking
in an alcoholic beverage is that it has
to have a little dropper and it has to
be tight so you know like airplane booze
it's gonna be like that for track and
trace system requirement this is the
happiest thing in there I'm gonna say
for manufacturers this brings me so much
joy I can't even express it one of the
things in the entire regulations the
concept of research and development only
existed in nursery the only people
allowed to have anything for R&amp;D and one
of the big questions was if you're a
manufacturer developing a product and
you're trying out new things or new
formulations and how do you know they
work and what's going to happen and
maybe there's going to be some loss
there really was no accountability for
that the CD pH has added this beautiful
line that says one of the things that
can be recorded in the track and trace
system within 24 hours is the use of
cannabis or cannabis product for
internal quality control testing or
product research and development so the
fact that they have acknowledged that
that is a thing that exists is a
beautiful beautiful thing indeed real
quick for the CDFA the track and trace
requirements they did go to calendar
days instead of business day so so a lot
of these reporting requirements are like
when you have three calendar days to
restore when connectivity goes down and
you have to put in all your data you
have to report any change of disposition
in three calendar days that's a long
time especially if you're in the up
north and you have to come down out of
the mountain and get to internet you
know reception and stuff it's gonna be a
challenge
meeting those calendar day requirements
so just when you look at the regs be
very very specific and and pay attention
to win notifications any action is
requiring calendar days instead of
business days
Josh touched on this there was some
additions to the cultivation plan
requirements there was clarifications on
what can be shared and what can't
so things that cannot be shared was like
immature plant areas processing areas
packaging areas in that quarantine area
he spoke of and then there was areas
that can be shared that that were
enumerated he talked about the signed
attestation that states you're gonna do
the requirements for legal use of
pesticides in Los Angeles for example
that requires getting a pesticide
applicators license and an operator ID
for your business so you have to contact
your agricultural commissioner to know
what those requirements are I think much
of this he covered the there was some
new clarifications on cannabis waste a
super bummer for outdoor growers is this
line that stayed that outdoor licensees
are prohibited from using light
deprivation which means that they're
saying you can't even tent your plants
if you wanted to use a non electrical
non light sense from the the best that I
can tell is this has to do I mean and
that they consider this a moderate
offense that can carry a fine I believe
that one is like 500 to $1,000 per
instance and then they determined that I
mean I I'm trying to get through the
statement of reasons that part of that
is that you know you'll get
flowering cycles if you use that light
deprivation technique and then they're
trying to appropriately create scaled
fees and the fee for an outdoor grow is
less than the fee for a mix light grow
so they want to take away that ability
for an outdoor grower to get multiple
harvests it's pretty much what I'm
reading into that because if they did
that then they'd want to pay higher fees
if you're gonna yield more so this is
the one I like to point out just as my
advertisement for why you need an
amazing compliance team is that that
administrative action for record-keeping
is up to a thirty thousand dollar fine
per individual violation if your records
are not in shape that's just
record-keeping there's a lot of other
finds more fun things they change in the
BCC they change the definition of
immature plant that held to anything
over 18 inches so if you're a retailer
and you've got clones and they grow over
18 inches it's not an immature plant
anymore you can't sell it that does not
go for the CDFA they have a different
for cultivation there's a different
definition of a mature plant that
doesn't impose that 18 inch line
inventory reconciliation this was good
news changed from 14 days to 30 calendar
days so now your your describes you
don't have to do your reconciliation
point but for every 30 days the
significant discrepancy definition went
up a little bit to 3 percent of average
monthly sales instead of 2 there was
some clarity oh yeah this was about this
part did stay with the structures have
to be permanently affixed to the land so
you can't have like rolling you know
like RVs and stuff that you're using a
spaces or shipping containers have to be
permanently affixed to the ground the
there was some clarity around pre-rolls
it's nice they've got specific that a
licensed distributor can package and
repackage and label and cannabis
including pre-rolls and that in
manufacturing in addition to the
activities a licensee can role in
package pre-rolls they did add the line
though
to clarify pre-rolls have to be rolled
prior to compliance testing so you don't
test your bulk and then roll pre rolls
and put them out you have to roll them
then test them
then put them out yeah right well it's
you get it because we had it we had a
big issue as people get bulk tested and
then they mixed it with untested and
then their pre-rolls didn't test right
so until until we gained some trust in
this relationship we're having it's
gonna take a minute and track and trace
will help I mean it'll help with the
visibility on those things where every
component is tested and you can kind of
see it better one of the big is so
resampling was a big thing we had a big
issue and we continue to have issues
with testing labs having issues it's so
kind of one of those things that did
they didn't see that coming that um what
happens when a lab loses its license and
they're sitting on all these samples and
you're not allowed previously weren't
allowed to transfer it and have somebody
else sample it and test it so you're
just sitting waiting for your product to
be done and now they allow that if a
licensed laboratory is unable to
competently complete the compliance
testing after sampling you can contract
another lab to test your goods there was
also the issue for a lot of
manufacturers was that they removed this
language about the plus or minus 10% it
used to be for especially for edibles it
was 100 milligrams per package plus or
minus 10% and they and they took that
away which horrified many edible
companies because it meant that they
would have to shoot for ninety percent
so that all of their stuff would be like
you know you know 90 milligrams of THC
because they wouldn't want to go over
the 100 threshold but that seems to have
been corrected in the distribution
section in 5307 point one where the
distributor you can look at it for their
Quality Assurance review any difference
within plus or minus 10% is considered
still okay so that's that okay I think I
did it and Josh touched on the OSHA so
so what so what now now what that's one
thing I have this is my little quick to
do list because obviously there's a lot
of things that weren't handled in the
regulatory process one of the most
glaring ones is compassion and
compassion programs Scott weiners going
to reintroduce his compassion bill this
year is anticipated which was SB 30
for which was to allow for the donation
of cannabis products to medicinal
cannabis patients without retailers
having to pay the full excise tax and
the full taxes on those items so we're
hoping that that goes this also kicks in
the delayed feasibility study that the
Bureau has to undertake under mikasa of
looking into the feasibility of a
non-profit license type which would
create another possible Avenue for the
collective models for compassionate care
for for businesses to be able to you
know focus on the needs of patients in
the medicinal market without taking on
the full you know necessarily fee
structure or tax structure of cannabis
commercial cannabis sovereign nations
was not solved at all in the regulations
they still are like yeah waive all your
sovereign rights and go for it
so I think there's still a lot of work
to be done in negotiating and figuring
out how tribes can interplay and work
with the commercial cannabis industry
sampling is still just a ridiculous and
sales process that was never
contemplated by the industry of how
products get to market and the fact that
you maybe need your distribution reps to
have samples or be able to give it to
people there's a still a lot of problems
in that area that need to be solved that
the regulator's felt were out of their
range of ability to deal with that stuff
because of the prohibition against free
products so it'll probably require a
bill or a new language the there's a tax
bill that's going to be introduced some
people are thinking Lackey is going to
reintroduce the excise tax bill to
hopefully lower the excise tax because
obviously we all know taxes are out of
control
banking is another huge problem and
Hertzberg is gonna reintroduce I think
his banking bill to move towards the
creation of charter banks or some
solution and then obviously just the
glooming gloaming problem of pathways to
licensure they say 99 problems and local
authorization is number one this that
you know some of those questions are
starting to be contemplate
how is this dual licensing system
working out with you know localities and
them trying to get it together and those
kind of complexities of not having those
things interface so that I think I did
it I got through I did it so that's what
I have to say so obviously there's tons
more yeah yeah and I would also say no I
don't what Josh was saying is that there
is nothing in the regulations about
provisional licenses to explain how that
system is going to work when it's going
to start what you have to do all we have
to go off of is the bill text so it's
going to be critical to keep a close eye
on how they roll out their program
they've been pretty mum about it even
with the trade organizations and
lobbyists and all that stuff there's not
a lot of information mostly I think
because they don't know cuz they just
got passed as a bill and they're making
it up so keep an eye on that and also I
would say again keep an eye on what Josh
was saying about trying to get clarity
on how the agencies are interpreting
that how that provisional rollout is
going to go in and when you're going to
be obligated to submit your annual
license because there seems to be some
different messaging from different
agencies where the CDP H is saying oh
you need to do it by the end of the year
and the CDFA is saying oh no you don't
so there's a lot of chatter about those
things so it's critical to kind of go
get those answers in writing who like
Josh was saying in the few seconds we
have next if anybody has any questions
that's fine yeah
not necessarily
those would be things is there certain
limitations of like making sure that if
you can have unlimited brands but that
they're registered DBAs and they're
attached to the license number exactly
right
yeah I mean it seems like there I
remember going in for an early like test
of the licensing software and they only
had about four product categories for
manufactured products so they've been
expanding their understanding of what's
possible and what people are making and
I don't think that there's any
limitation on products well you would
have to look at though is if you are a
licensed manufacturer they did add
language in terms of notifications to
the CD pH where every time you create a
new product a new formulation or release
a new SKU you have to notify them an
update yeah it doesn't have to be that I
think that the main clarifications is a
brand has to be attached to a licensed
entity and in that attachment you're
going to have to make a certain amount
of disclosures and have things in in
place
yep yeah I mean that's pretty much what
the regulations give us is the new
roadmap of these are these are the rules
as they understand them and now it's our
job to find a way to navigate them and
be creative which luckily is something
that the cannabis industry has always
been really good at I would I would say
a talk to an attorney because when
that's why I think it's very important
to look at that definition of cannabis
accessories the original definition from
the health and safety code of marijuana
accessories because in this would I tip
my hat to the lawyers in the room to
read into that further but it describes
a very exhaustive list of anything that
helps you to consume prepare grow probs
so so I would you know if I was a lawyer
which I'm not I would say that cookbooks
hell is is a method of figuring out how
I'm going to put cannabis into the human
body which is exactly what that
definition is and learning how to grow
cannabis is putting it into the human
body so the the hair-splitting part that
it will be is if the agencies are going
to be psychotic enough and I put nothing
past them to say that any book cookbook
blah blah blah in a dispensary has to be
by a licensed company and brand blah
blah blah I don't see that happening I
see it as an ancillary product just like
you don't have to be a licensed cannabis
company right now to make a cannabis
accessory and I believe that those fall
under the definition of cannabis
accessory but ask your lawyer
branded by a licensee well I mean that
would be yeah I mean that would be that
would be the solution if they're gonna
split hairs but I'd my suggestion has
these would be things that we need to go
to the agencies after they're done with
their Christmas break because they're
like don't ask any questions until after
that that we'd want to get further
clarification to see are they seriously
taking it that far or under the I would
argue that under the definition of
cannabis accessory and how extensive
that definition is in the health and
safety code that the cookbook wouldn't
fall under that thank you so much
everybody thank you
[Applause]