[Music]
what is going on in the legislative and
regulatory landscape to start off I
thought it would be nice to summarize
just where we are in the process with
the regulation
you might recall last time we were here
Pamela and I yelling at you passionately
two comments during the 45-day comment
period
Laurie Ajax at one of it was head said
that she anticipated getting about a
thousand comments we wanted I think we
got $4,000 well done people about 1800
of them were about delivery so you know
yep
and so now they're in the process so
maybe max you could help like describe
where we are in that process and what
the next steps are right right so you
know there's two stages two processes
going on right now right we've got the
regulatory process which has been going
on in fits and starts the entire the
entire year and then we also have the
legislative process which we're at the
very end of I'll start with the
legislative process briefly because that
does you know what has just been
wrapping up so bills I have a two-year
life cycle that life cycle starts after
an election and it ends at the following
August or September of the year we're in
the second year of a two-year cycle all
bills had to be passed by the
legislature by the end of August now the
governor has one month has until the
last day of September to go and sign or
veto those bills that are currently
pending so he's taking action on one
bill thus far which was the electronic
funds transfer bill saying that if
you're paying your taxes and you're
paying them in cash you shouldn't be
penalized for that because you're in
cannabis because you don't have banking
access so is a good bill is an easy bill
you signed it that's the one bill he's
signed thus far there's a couple of
smaller ones they got a veto but what
we're really waiting for the big less
the big set of them that Pam's excited
about and we can you know touch on that
in just a moment but that's you know
more of action in the next you know 11
days or 13 days on all those bills
simultaneously we've got the regulatory
process going on we just had a 45 day
public comment period that period closed
what we're now at is a question of will
there be or what will be the next
comments period because there will be
changes to the regulations and when
there are changes and when there are
substantive changes in particular there
has to be an additional comment period
we're anticipating another comment
period either between mid October and
November somewhere around there but the
important date is this the emergency
regulations were only authorized for one
year and so the emergency regulations
that have been in effect since the first
week of December of last year that have
to be replaced by permanent regulations
by the first week of December of this
year and so keeping an eye on that week
from there we're just working backwards
we're working backwards on when the
comment periods will be how much review
there will be because they have to be
approved and finalized by that first
week of December so cancel your
Thanksgiving plans last year the regs
came out the Thursday before
Thanksgiving
MJB I'm JP so every Californian right
and in Vegas everyone was in Vegas on
their phones and the laptops looking at
the regulations and they came out last
time and probably around that time for
the final version to going back to
legislation and you wanna talk about
some of your favorites we talked about
1459 which is I think one of the most
important bills it had an interesting
iteration because it took the shape of a
previous cultivation bill that was
gutted and repurposed yeah so the what's
so important about 15 14 59 is that
temporary permits which is what
everybody's been using to operate on
expire and can no longer be issued as of
December 31st of 2018
that was part of 64 that was voted in by
the voters so what does that mean that
means that the state has how many people
know how many annual permits the state
has issued so far it's a big goose egg
right none so we are nearing the back
half of the year more than the back half
of the year and there's no state permits
why is that myriad of reasons some of
them may have to do with a little thing
called metric that we talked about but
what does that mean is that all these
cities and counties are moving forward
with their process some operators are
currently operating if on the 31st we
don't have a fix to that that either
means that certain operator that need
priority are gonna have maybe 90-day
runway or others who are closer to being
issued more towards December would have
120 days given that we're gonna be at
365 days potentially without any
issuance of an annual that starts to put
everybody in a line that if you don't
have an annual permit you cannot operate
so that grinds the entire industry
chûjô
14:59 would give what is affectionately
being called a provisional annual
license what does that mean that would
mean that if you have a state temporary
permit in your hand by December 31st of
this year you would then be entitled to
get a provisional annual with that
provisional annual you would be allowed
to operate without a vested right but
throughout the process of the year to
get through fire planning and building
sequel California Environmental Quality
Act which will rear its ugly head in
this industry not only are you going to
need sequel level review at your local
level but because the second
discretionary action is happening an
agency is giving you another permit they
and specifically the Bureau of cannabis
control who when you read the
regulations had very robust sequa
parameters they're gonna be looking at
that secret document and if they don't
think let's look at the city of La we
can look at the city of Long Beach and
we can look specifically at the city of
San Diego
none of those cities went through a land
use entitlement process there was no
discretionary action taken by a local
jurisdiction that allowed for some level
of sequel review their ordinances may
have been sequel and reviewed or sequa
accepted for the city of La like to use
the June or July 1 of 2019 sequin that
exists right now but that means that the
BC so you can say aren't you having an
existing facility there are always
exceptions to the exemption that's what
California loves and if you went beyond
your footprint if you did something more
aggressive the BCC you can say well then
we want our own sequel review and in
their sequel language in the proposed
draft regulations permanent regulations
they said you write us a check we tell
you how we want you to do sequa and you
pay us to administer that process
a former sequel lawyer I will tell you
that sequa can cost tens if not hundreds
of thousands of dollars and take six
nine twelve months or longer so this
provisional annual is critically
important it also puts you on the hook
for metrics so the other part about
temporary licenses and why temporary
licenses aren't something that can move
forward into 2019 is we really all need
to start getting on board with track at
rates we're supposed to be doing it
paper versions now every time something
happens into something moves throughout
the supply chain you're supposed to send
a paper manifest or an email manifest up
to the BCC which somehow goes into their
general mailbox and is diverted into the
right at management we're not gonna ask
where those go but you just send them in
because for five years after the fact
they can go back and look at that and
Gary out you enforcement actions them
right now some where they do into a
black hole that can then cause you
issues later
so with that provisional annual you are
responsible to pay your fees for the
whole year upfront you are responsible
did you track and trace and you are
responsible to not let what is happening
in Sacramento and Oakland happen go
through your local land use process do
not think that this license like your
temporary license to some is an
entitlement not to go through the rest
of your entitlement process it means you
are actively engaged in both operations
and both those operations and critical
opportunities that allow you to keep
operating so we wait with bated breath
for that to get passed which is my most
important point yeah also if you're
restructuring this is an important bill
for you you can restructure and then get
a provisional annual without losing your
potential priority status which is also
something important for those that were
operating maybe as a sole proprietor or
as an NBC that would like to convert
potentially have that issue and just on
1459 you know it we cleared this bill
which was a guttin amend it we
anticipate it will be signed because it
was worked with very closely by the
governor's office and requested
initially by the local governments local
government said we don't have enough
time to issue these local licenses to
get through building planning to get
through fire approval so give us more
time beyond the temporary license
process so that's why we do think it
will go and get signed it is for all
licensing authorities but the one thing
there's one thing there that I caught on
you don't have a right to a provisional
yeah if you have a temporary the state
may grant you a provisional but it's
more it's not going to list doesn't be
it sort of like applying for your
provisional it's sounding more like it's
going to be a they've your your temp is
expiring and we will grant you a
provisional which has a one-year
timeline on it and you PI don't want to
be granted a provisional until December
frankly if you can get it because you
want it to last as long as possible but
you know just that it isn't necessary
saying that you're applying for in the
same way it's much more an extension of
the temp licensing process if you are
working with a local jurisdiction we're
I think we're gonna see an uptick and
what the local jurisdictions are able to
do you want to make sure I think with
the provisional annuals that they have a
bifurcated process because this is
something that we're running into with
some of our clients where they try to
unify it for expediency they can't grant
okay you're gonna want them to issue
something akin to a business license
that can be conditioned upon going
through a lien G since we know my
process if they merge them together
they're not gonna be able to condition
them and if they have to make sequel
findings even if you're gonna try to do
a notice of exemption or you're gonna
try to do a mitigated negative you still
have to go through all of those 18
analysis areas that are within the
California Environmental Quality Act and
you may not be able to complete an air
quality analysis a traffic analysis
those two being the biggest in that time
period so if they can bifurcate it out
and issue you something that they can
condition while you go through the
secondary process or
r.fp that's something that you can
engage with your local jurisdiction in
if they haven't quite gotten to the
point of issuance and 1459 is past the
one thing i heard also on that topic was
potentially a registry I think Nevada
County is looking at a registry perhaps
or The Advocate small push for a
registry because do you go get people on
the list to go and say under your
registry you can go and apply for a
state temp have it be non-operational
but having the state temp before the end
of the year gets grants through that
opportunity for the provisional and so
it's much more valuable to get state
temped on December 31st even comparator
trying to start through an annual
license process on January 1
do you know that the BCC last year
issued permits on Christmas Eve
Christmas Day and on New Year's Eve
which I think they will be doing again
which means that I will be spending
holidays at the computer but the main
thing with 1459 was that it took care of
two important issues with the state
which is one that they needed to get
revenue from the license holder since
you don't pay your licensing fee with
the temp they needed to get that annual
license fee revenue coming into the
state and then to was the issue of the
biggest thing with the rollout and track
and trace is going to be getting enough
people to get on it at the same time
right have any meaning so if they just
started piecemeal issuing annuals now
and you're the first person on track and
trace the system is useless because
you're just inputting everybody else's
paper
I mean it's idea that you know you've
got a tracked cultivator going through
an untracked distro to attract or
untracked manufacturer and then nest or
and mix thereof and then you know you're
you're deleting and creating tags and
there's no accountability needs to be
rolled out and so what we've actually
been suggesting and arguing is that
they're you know not not not gen1
actually bore more like March 31st from
April 1 ideally and not not saying we're
gonna be able to get this but there were
should be no more temps in the system
one track and trace gets turned on so
that everyone can be and is required to
be in the system one it does happen but
it could happen but they could turn on
much earlier and have to deal with that
sort of miss max matching the
consequences but I deal a more ideal
situation would be wait till everyone
can actually be in there and I think
we'll find that I mean I've heard that
the state will you know probably have a
lot more receptivity to other fixes and
issues win track and trace is
implemented because issues which they're
incredibly resistant to tackle right now
such as sampling and stuff like that
becomes much more visible and
controllable when there actually is a
robust track and trace system happening
and measuring every single little piece
of everything going around so on the
other top line issues do we want to talk
about 2020 right now well we're at we're
at you just came from all fires but I
was at a fairground
so so a B 2020 by Bill quark is a bill
that's also pending before the governor
essentially would expand the number of
license our number of eligible venues
for on-site consumption special events
the Bureau create the special event
license in through regulations you know
further in the emergency regulations
there wasn't really statutory basis for
it but it goes and helps provide for
additional consumption opportunities
retail sale opportunities however by
statute it was limited to degree of the
consumption itself was limited to
fairground areas and so what this bill
goes and dies is expand the eligible
locations for consumption so it's not
just fairgrounds and district AG
associations it also could be wherever
essentially a city goes and license is
it if you know there is a restricted
access to 21 plus no minors going and
seeing the smoke
a couple other conditions so it's it's a
bill that it's anticipated to be signed
and it will go help cause an explosion
of licensed events but a licensed event
is not necessarily a compliant event and
Pam went to probably well the more
compliant events she's seen just earlier
this week but it was really interesting
to see how a compliant you can do a
compliant event that has what I will say
the version of sampling because you
still had to pay for your sample being
very important and there was one
centralized retailer that everything
went through interesting to note it was
not a retailer that was located in
Sonoma County or Santa Rosa so it will
be interesting to see where those tax
the the tax implications happen there
with a retailer not based within the
county or the city where the event was
handled hmm but you got little tickets
and you went up and you had to pay a
dollar plus the excise tax also a little
weird since sometimes the excise tax is
embedded into the cost of the project
but that is still how it went uh this
will sort of help I think what we've
seen more recently is these pop-up
events that are curved and how does
product get to such an event because it
cannot come from the manufacturer or the
cultivator it has to go through we awake
you see it to go through a retailer so
that the taxes are taken out and then it
goes to the event right so um this will
kind of help streamline getting events
in more locations which may then help
operators to understand that they need
to be compliant while they're doing
because it's if it's held at a licensed
facility that the city allows there's
going to be a lot more robust regulation
that goes within that because it's
unfortunate with the level of pop-up
events that I've been seeing what would
happen if track and trace were truly
online yeah and you had to account for
how these samples got to an event and
didn't go through those proper channels
and just came your repair your
manufacturer and you bring your
manufacturing prod
to a private venue it doesn't matter
that that's a private venue and isn't
then eligible for going through the
event licensed rhetoric that product is
still licensed product and needs to
follow their correct supply chain
something that 2020 does more to instill
an idea that you can have more events
that therefore are responsible I think
also there's other challenges there
though with the special event license in
general terms of the the fee per event
is a thousand dollars and I wrote an
event cap as was in the regulation like
a proposed cap of ten events per year
mmm there was talk about that on some of
the toy 6:41 stuff but not really not
not in 2020 yeah we're still well we're
I don't think we are a statutory cap I
believe it's in I know we're going back
and forth sorry gotcha
sidebar ultimately there's there needs
to be other changes to the event
language and while we appreciate the
fact that this language is being moved
in there there are some just big
questions on how events are NIF events
will work and part of that's tied into
if everything has to be sold by licensed
retailer and move through the supply
chain violations distributor to that
retailer is there what incentive is
there for retailers to take a chance on
brands they don't know if you have to
have purchased that product if you have
to have possession of that product for
it to be at the event at the booth of
the manufacturer or cultivator it's
going to disincentivize you know a
desire to go and allow emerging brands
to go and be at these events
additionally and that's why there was
some discussion and movement on the bill
26:41 earlier this year which did not
make it through I'm it was held in
Appropriations Committee near the end of
the year which will allowed some degree
of farm direct consumer direct access by
licensed producers but even the
underlying issue there is there's just
some structural issues with events
and with running events through distro
through retail that I think we have to
address before we can have a successful
fix like 26:41 or like something else is
just we have a more discussion about how
to make events work supposed to attract
a distributor without the ability to
provide them with a sample of their
products well I do want to talk we
wanted to save some time on this portion
too for any questions that people have
but just to burn through some other
important ones
there's SBA 29 which is the
compassionate care license well it's not
compassionate care license I know they
need to change the name of the thing and
it essentially it's gonna let licensed
retailers go and Disney eight fraught
for compassion if it stays need for
compassion there can be no compensation
for frog has been designated for
compassion but you will not owe your
sales and use tax you will not
Oh your excise tax if it's designated at
a producer level you will not owe your
cultivation tax so there is not there it
is truly a compassionate operation there
is not a way to get revenue to go cover
the costs of doing that but for those
that are either its product that's been
staying on the shelves for too long this
is a way to go and not be taxed on
giving that product away additionally
the compassion license bill SB 829 by
Senator Weiner the bill goes expands
who's eligible for compassion to be not
just people with ID cards and their
caregivers which is current law but
statutorily expands it to be those who
ever have a recommendation and so it's
very exciting the opportunity to go and
be able to give cannabis to just two
recommendation holders and not the
limited ID card holder universe and then
allow businesses not to be taxed to not
be penalized for that compassionate
activity we think this is not the end of
the conversation certainly and we would
hope that some of these you may be able
to be tax-deductible in the future or
there could be other implications and
incentives but it was definitely a big
fight for compassion that we're hoping
we'll get signed in the next two weeks
SB 311 was a distributed distributor
transfers which was just one that
somebody realized this necessary as you
may know the way that the regulations
work now is it's the last distributor to
distribute the test the product has to
be the one to deliver it to the retailer
so a distributor if a retailer wanted to
or if a manufacturer wanted to had a
thousand products and wanted to give a
hundred to ten different distributors
each distributor would have to test that
product rendering it you know
unprofitable so this will allow
distributors to transfer to each other
so that the one that tests it can then
can then transfer to another distributor
so you can have those distributed to
more retailers and and the big question
we have with this one and I don't have
an answer on this is the bill is an
urgency clause urgency clause means it
takes effect immediately this type of
idea of distorted distro transfers was
included in the Bureau regs I want to
say 5307 but I'll have to look later but
it was it was in the Bureau regs but the
question is even though the bill takes
effect immediately
the regulations have not been updated
and so I would not be comfortable going
in advising clients to do these distro
distro transfers with a CoA unless
there's a signing statement or some
other indication from the bureau from
the governor's office they intend this
to go and sort of supplant the existing
emergency regulations and allow for this
activity so you know hopefully we'll be
able to do this sooner but if not first
week of December it would likely be
included
because we'll send the same product to
another distributor the same product
then again the other distributor the
same product so SB 311 that we're just
discussing would go and address that
issue by allowing the first distributor
that gets the product its final form so
you wouldn't be able to nestle use it
for you know flour versus flour or vs
stuff that's turned into carts or
whatnot but the first distro and tests
in its final form can go and keep that
certificate of analysis and transfer to
distributors downstream so that if you
have you know a hundred units up in
Humboldt County then get tested up there
and then move down to move down to
Oakland and then 25 units are sold in
this of Bay Area and those who have to
get tested themselves and then the other
75 go down to LA and then 50 are sold in
the LA area and last 25 grand San Diego
instead of having to test it for
different times it would all be able to
be tested and kept with that first test
up in Humboldt so so so the distro to
distro that's more of a supply chain
question and disorder distro transfers
we're at least solving the issue of not
having to text test it repetitively and
cost-prohibitive lee but you know if you
if you're destroyed does not have a
statewide infrastructure you'd have to
use multiple districts transport fee QA
fee but at least there won't be an
additional test and with the testing
backlogs we've been getting
this will be good to not recreate that
problem they do for non Seaway products
I mean like pre CoA product they can
yeah product then you're just paying a
transport fee and then you're gonna
ultimately pay the CEO a fee yeah
hopefully that distributor has statewide
reach otherwise we're gonna be paying
multiple it all depends on what your
needs are what your target markets are
and what the costs look like well you
can see a pathway for regional
distributors especially in areas like up
north where you might not have
especially when you have smaller growers
or smaller manufacturers where you need
somebody to take that first chance in
the first leg of the visit those are
gonna create a real good market place
for a regional distributor who's gonna
kind of take your product and wrap it
and get it to the next phase of possibly
then going to a statewide distributor it
could save you money and the great you
know expanse of getting it through out
in the retailers throughout the state
state but I think at that first level of
jumping it to getting it to market
you're gonna have real niches for people
to we're gonna do products in the market
it depends on what your footprint is
right when you're first releasing a
product typically you're gonna try to do
it in a market share that you can
control versus trying to saturate the
entire market at first so that's about
business dynamics and growing your
business scaling up as to what that's
going to be like because if you also
then just do a straight to market
strategy and try to saturate the state
can you scale up and provide the state
so some
time's it's gonna be who view to use a
regional distributor to get your name
out there first and then you know expand
to markets that you think that you would
do well in you may not want to be in
every single retailer across the state
you may want to target so many other
questions in the last few moments with
okay
really
let's say there's only 24
Wow
so many operations in terms of
shouldn't there be organized or state or
anyone really
already we're looking at the issue of
the number of testing labs and who can
pass phase 2 January 1 we move into
phase 3
how many labs are prepared to do phase 3
testing right now may wait which one do
you think is is on steep oh that's deep
hill
we might have one lab in the state in
the state that's ready for Gen 1 testing
they'll be clear when phase 2 testing
right now
phase 3 testing or Gen 1 testing adds in
heavy metals ads in mycotoxins adds in
some residual water content is there one
more all the mycotoxins
I want to make sure right now that my
products are ready for January 1 I want
to get phase 3 tested right now so I'm
ready to go and back stock you can't you
can't be prepared for that anticipated
labs that are saying they'll be ready by
January 1 15 maybe how many are we at
now I was trying to pull up the actual
number of labs on my life
err net here's bad expensive and what
happens if this one lab or maybe upwards
of 15 get it and their equipment goes
down and as Julie always likes to point
out you can't then send your sample
somewhere else please note that this
testing lab one of the 15 let's hope or
one on and that piece of equipment which
is so
and we know that expensive equipment
fails ask hospitals they go through this
all the time they're able to send
samples out so that you don't lose the
life right this is everything a bit
distributed distributor transfer period
we'd previously there's no lab the lab
transfer where they can be like ah dang
we're down can you do this no code I
can't is anyone asking for it I mean
some of they're asking for that but it
was also that even if it's the same lab
so a lab like steep hill that has
multiple location yeah the way that it
was they couldn't transfer it to another
of their own location
so hopefully that part gets settled lab
till that lab to a different lab might
just make somebody's brain explode so
yeah absolutely at least in a lab would
be able to send it to its own you know
remote location if they didn't have the
piece of equipment but but as you're
saying yeah it would make sense but I'm
sorry the open the other thing that I
would say is obviously we're having this
huge problem of labs and you send it to
the same lab three times and there's
different results so as much as there's
an urgency to say oh my god we need more
labs
I for one would have concerns of the
fact that they will issue a license to a
lab before it's accredited so
yeah well let me let me debunk that the
highest percentage of those fails was
the label claims right so it's important
to read into that that it's not like oh
my god it's all poison it's that most of
it is not hitting that 10% window right
of label claims which is an incredibly
difficult target to hit especially when
you're dealing with low dose items it
was a 60 60 percent were label yeah 60%
of the fails were of label claim
failures label claim failures can be
from being outside of the percentages or
it can be having a claim of medicinal
benefits or impacts that can that
they're not allowed to go into 60
percent of the 20 percent failures 60
percent of those were label claim some
was ingredients some where there was a
breakdown in one of the things but like
you're saying for the public at large
where everybody only reads the headline
and goes oh my god California is
poisoning everybody terrible opportunity
to bring back our original panel which
is the comment so when those 15 days
come these critical 15 days and you
don't see that they've addressed testing
or any of these other concepts that we
talked about that are so important it is
that they hear from the operators and
the public that says look this is a
concern to us you need to address it
that's like the last time that you have
to be citizen empowering and tell them
you didn't address the right things
right and get in there or we want a
compassion license if they compassion
bill passes and
they don't do a compassion fee reduction
to allow licensees that maybe go through
a social equity program to not pay it
the same fees at the state level that
everybody else pays that's your window
and if we get some of these bills passed
that give you more of a foundation to
make the app then make the app so don't
think it's over I don't think that that
can be understated because it's gonna be
15 days possibly during Thanksgiving
where people aren't paying attention we
need to pay attention it's the last 15
days we're gonna have before we have to
make legislative action to fix well and
and the one thing is that and and this
will feel bit shameless their public
comment period is always you know those
are always times for public to weigh in
and you'll try to do a mass-market
approach and where they are required to
review and respond to comments I'm a
registered lobbyist it's my job as a
lobbyist to go and talk to an heir faced
with regulators and have private
discussions and try to go work on these
questions during the times that aren't
the public comment periods I know that
my attorney friends here also go and
have these private conversations too and
a good attorney will be able to go and
have that engagement but the public
comment period is important but also
having whether it's lobbying or
consultant or legal counsel that is
actually going to work with you on
talking to and engaging with the
regulator's on your questions is
critical as opposed to because because
you know anyone can go and submit public
comments but it's about following
through between the pot comment periods
to hammer your point home is really you
know how to go move the needle we I
think we've all think folks remember the
disappearance of the acreage cap between
the sequent and the regulations that
came out the emergency regs that came
out two days later Monday was their
Thursday it was gone
that's lobbying and so
[Music]
when you can make a delivery order out
of your trunk in a car anywhere in
California that's lobbying yeah I got
the drive-through licenses a bead for
that so you can do it what makes our job
easier sometimes is to see that ground
swelling of support but it strategically
you want to be working with your
consultants with your attorneys and then
also making public comment because it's
the trifecta of not coming together that
that forces action I personally see you
Courtney how would you on time
[Music]