[Music]
on Friday July 13th Friday the 13th the
regulatory agencies demonstrated they
have not lost their sense of humor by on
this auspicious day releasing the draft
permanent regulations that will dictate
the future of the cannabis industry in
California so on that day Friday the
13th what happened
what started 45-day comment period how
many have issued their comments nobody
because we're still reading over 300
pages of new regulations so today I have
brought together this is Alexis DeAngelo
of CCI a and and dr. K Pamela Epstein of
green Weis consulting and Sarah
Armstrong of Americans for safe access
so we wanted to talk about how to
compose an effective comment during this
comment period this is a critical time
for the cannabis industry everything you
hate about the regulations this is your
last chance to issue a well-thought-out
professional specific excellently
written and argued comments to help the
agencies to see the error of their ways
in certain cases to support some of the
decisions that they've made that you may
agree with it's that you doesn't have to
be a negative comment it can be a
positive comment but it is essential to
submit comments during this period if
you have a cannabis business and you
want to file a lawsuit later guess what
if you didn't file a comment you can't
you have to say something about the
issues at hand so I'm just gonna let
these guys talk about it as well to give
kind of some of the salient points of
how you go about approaching the comment
period how you can submit the comments
and the opportunities to do so and what
are the components of a effective
comment hi everyone so one of the things
that is really important is make sure
that you have an entire statement but
also that you have a solution for that
statement just stating what you want
they're just gonna bypass that so you
need to go in with a full statement of
what you want and then tell them kind of
how they can do it because then
actuality they want to know how to do
their own job so we're gonna be doing
that for them I think one important
thing to note is what also did not
happen on Friday the 13th nothing
changed so all of those readapted
regulations child-resistant see with all
of the packaging that we just saw all of
that stays in place so during this
period where were effectively commenting
and telling these regulatory agencies
this is what we would like to see at the
same time we need to maintain compliance
because here in California you can be
dinged for that it could cost you your
annual permit you could be affected at
the local level so maintain your active
compliance now with a lens on what will
make your life easier in the future when
you're commenting and when you're
commenting you want to ask a question
provide a solution make sure the answer
to your question is not a yes or a No
and that you're really facilitating of
response and it's difficult with some of
us being vertically integrated
businesses or a micro business that you
may think that you can ask all of your
questions to the BCC and that you may
think logically that these agencies talk
to one another sometimes the regulations
would beg to differ since owner seems to
be a concept that is not
reversal but you need to make your
specific comments to your specific
agencies that are in control of that
particular part of the supply chain and
then I'm gonna pass it along when things
kicked off in 2005 we had no one to help
us lawyers were very reluctant lobbyists
were non-existence they in fact would
run the other way if you're economically
in a position to hire a lawyer to write
a letter for you or you have a lobbyist
through your trade organization or you
have one of the many things that are now
available to the cannabis community and
the money to access them go ahead and do
it it'll save you some time and I
promise you that you will be pleased
with the results many of you are small
business owners who really don't have a
lot of extra money right now
things are tough so go to safe access
now.org
and right there on our website americans
for acts safe access will have all the
information you need to write an
effective letter all by yourself it's
not that hard state your issue discuss
it say your solution and you're done
don't forget to cite the part of the
regulation who that you are talking
about because there's over 500 pages of
them so put the little section number
and maybe a page number and once you're
done be proud of yourself because you're
now part of the solution that's pretty
important but what's even more important
is if you don't weigh in people who have
interests contrary to yours will there
are I think eleven police fraternal
organizations they have lobbyists they
have lawyers and believe me they will be
weighing in the League of Cities is not
always a very helpful entity either and
they are well supplied with lawyers
lobbyists and policy wonks the minute
you start becoming part of this process
it's addictive
believe me yeah I know it doesn't seem
like it but the idea that you submitted
a letter and then three months later you
look down at those regs and by god they
took out that really poisonous section
that you were objecting to that is a
high it is a genuine high and it's what
keeps most policy wants going believe me
you have lots of trade organizations
here in LA let them know how you feel
about things make sure they write
detailed letters and get on with it
because honestly you are the voice of
cannabis in California the people
running things up in Sacramento at the
bureau they freely admit they don't know
anything so the next time you open up
those rigs and they want you to have
24-hour Mans security which will double
your your security bill every month and
you write in and it comes right out
where you're not just talking alone you
are part of a community speaking with
one voice and that's very important I
know that it's hard to look at a 65 year
old woman and think that anything she'd
have to say would be terribly germane
but I am telling you if you're not at
the table your lunch and in and in this
environment this highly complex
environment if you're not at the table
somebody is going to eat your lunch so
please don't slack off this is your time
but if they don't hear from you this
time they never come again so where can
you comment and how can you come in
should probably let you guys know that
right ah the agencies will take your
comments via email you can call them or
you can snail mail them comments more
you can attend one of the many roadshow
as I like to call them hearing dates
there's one on August 7th in Oakland
there's one on August 14th in Los
Angeles and then on the last day that
you can submit comments which is also
important to note on August 27th there
will be one in
Himeno all of your comments must be
received by the agency in whatever
outlet you choose to let them know no
later than 5:00 p.m. on August 27th and
as everybody has set up here this is a
empowering moment you are the industry
and the industry needs you to speak up
because this is the opportunity for you
to comment not just on the new
information but on anything within the
regulations this is our last opportunity
where they will be evaluating and
updating these regulations in full
moving forward it will just be what the
regulatory agencies are authorized to do
potentially issue new licenses or you
have to go through the legislative
process this is the last time that you
can go to them as the public and they
must respond to you legally as a lawyer
there is a great lineage of case law in
this area that every single comment they
receive they must respond to and they
are not allowed to say comment noted so
if you ask a question if you provide a
solution they have to address it and
respond to it in a meaningful manner as
long as asterisks it is relevant to them
so part of the way to ensure that
relevance is by as was mentioned earlier
being specific you're gonna want to cite
the actual regulation that you are
responding to and offer the citation of
what section what part what is your
comment based on you're gonna want to
explain the problem that you see with
the regulation as written and then
you're gonna want to offer a solution of
how in light of this issue you would
suggest that they actually correct it if
you send them a letter that says you're
destroying the cannabis industry please
go away that's not a relevant comment
that they need to respond to all of the
comments that are submitted become
public record
they will be able to be read by the
public they have to provide a reason for
either why they agree with the comment
or they don't agree with the comment and
why it was incorporated or why it wasn't
incorporated in the the locations for
these hearings each agency is doing
their own series of hearings so the
Bureau of cannabis controlled BCC will
do hearings in Oakland Los Angeles and
Sacramento the Department of Public
Health which oversees manufacturing will
do them in Brea Eureka and Oakland and
the department of food and agriculture
vation will do them in Eureka Riverside
Santa Barbara and Sacramento the as
published the public hearings are only
scheduled to be two hours long so if you
are going to give public comments I
would be prepared to have your comment
written so that if they do not have time
for you to go sometimes they set up
stations they have places there you can
submit but don't only assure that you're
gonna be able to make a verbal comment
when you if you go to one of these
public hearings and it's great to submit
the comments anyway you can to sit on
all channels I understand this is an
incredibly complicated process the regs
are not fun to read some of the
implications are not clear of what the
of what they are so I also highly
suggest that you get connected with
other people who are going through this
process to have those conversation to go
through the language and make sure that
the way you're reading it is the way
other people are reading it to really
communicate and collaborate on these
things many of you are operating
businesses you don't have time to sit
there and read hundreds of pages of
regulations and offer you know really
well-thought-out comments there are
trade organizations and groups and many
people going through that process right
now so if you do have a brand you have a
logo you have a company you can connect
with other people who are who are
writing a large letter and sign on have
a magic logo if they're representing a
comment that you also support
speaks volumes the regular agencies can
see that the industry is in accord on
certain things and that there's a lot of
agreement in force as Sarah was saying
that security guard there was only a
five day comment period in the last
update and they slid something in there
and they had to take it right out
because the industry response and the
amount of comments that they received
was so overwhelming that it was clear
that this was not a good direction so
there is nothing I can say right now
it's gonna be it's gonna that I can
emphasize as much as I'd like to how
important this period of time is this is
the last train leaving the station for
this industry that gets really
complicated after this the process is
laborious as Pamela was saying it's a
heavy legislative lift it is slow slow
processes of government from here on out
this is this is the opportunity for the
public to have immediate and impactful
results based on the feedback you give
the government and the fact that I had
the opportunity to watch laws change
based on something somebody said that
made sense that is a powerful experience
to realize in the midst of all this
bullshit we live in that works sometimes
to give you guys some time frame
knowledge if you have to legislatively
Lobby to get a bill to change these
regulations once they are effective
those even if you're able to make that
change that year it doesn't go into
effect until the following year the
first of the following year these
regulations because we had emergency
regulations they must within 180 days
from the last time we went through this
process with the read option of the
emergency regulations have to have final
regulations
once those are adopted their final so if
you don't like that all of your
packaging for example must be
child resistant and tamper-evident at
the at the actual product versus the
exit bags and that stays because we as
an industry support some of what the
Department of Public Health and BCC are
saying then it stays if it doesn't and
there are others out there law
enforcement for example mothers who are
protecting the children who are you know
alcohol bottles aren't that safe you can
twist them and open them but that is
besides the point
they will comment out so it's not just
that industry is commenting it is your
opposition is commenting as well so
nothing that is in these rigs now that
you like or you don't like will stack it
can't change so comment comment comment
comment I cannot say it enough no
comment is insignificant as Julie said
if there's ever litigation in the future
that is administrative and closed looped
meaning that the only thing that you can
argue is what was said not what was not
said so there's no such thing Madlock
smoking gun all of that does not exist
in the administrative process it's the
agency is only responsible to address
modify what they are told when they are
given the opportunity to solicit
information does anyone have any
questions about the comment period or
its importance the question is that it
is very well what the gentleman is
suggesting is that it is also important
to understand what can be dealt with in
the regulations and what is embedded
into the regulations by statute which is
the there are things that were made
explicit in proposition 64 that the
agencies do not have the power to alter
there are certain things that are hard
wired into the regs so it is important
to know the value of your comment will
be also affected by
there or not these things are covered by
statute or that are off their regulatory
and able to be altered so it's a great
time to have a reading party and go back
and read prop 64 and see what people
actually voted for and what elements are
hardwired into there that may not be
able to be retracted for example an
excise tax hardwired into the system the
the amount and the fact that it exists
so something like a comment that says I
don't like the excise tax you should
take that out you're destroying
businesses and we can't compete with the
illicit market while true may is not
something that the regulators have the
capacity to change because it's
hardwired that would require a bill or
perhaps a lawsuit to question why an
adult use bill has the power to apply an
excise tax to a medical market anyway I
don't know how that happened so so
that's a really important clarification
to know what's in statute and what do
the regulator's have wiggle room
oversight on in the ability to create
regulations around
oh hello you are talking a lot about how
once the emergency ring sorry the
regular regulations are confirmed that
pushed out of mitigating it or barred
from litigating can you expand on that a
little bit I'm not sure sir
no yeah from from litigating we're
welcome to America no I'm what it is is
this is an administrative process and
therefore you are limited in what you
can sue over what claims you can make
you have to raise them for the agency so
if you don't raise an issue during the
administrative process during this
public comment period you are precluded
from telling the agency that they did
not do a good enough job
that's why commenting is so important
and why your comments are important
because if that's what your lenses then
you need to make sure that you have
fully articulated that to the agency's
ability to address it for example if you
want to look at what happened with the
lawsuit against the DEA that was with
CBD that was one of the major issues
that the court had was that they did not
exhaust their administrative remedies by
providing the very intricate comment
that they were arguing over in the
litigation so that's a same or similar
industry situation you have to comment
you cannot sit back and hope that
somebody else provides the comment that
you want to make
titanians they're like a retail so that
type nine is it
making anything that the people do that
use a top-line just as it anybody they
don't have you always have to have a
building so these are land use related
licenses every license has a land use
component now you can be a delivery
service that operates out of a building
that's properly permitted at the local
level but you can't just you know be no
license can operate into residence but
you can't have like a P o box and then a
computer in your room and run a delivery
service this is a big issue for a so we
feel patient should have access to
delivery and one of the most glorious
moments when I looked at the rags was
the language that would allow you as a
licensed provider to deliver all over
not just in the few jurisdictions that
were open enough to allow the sick and
dying to have access to their medicine
in their homes if you want that to stay
in the rags then you need to write a
letter and you need to write a letter
now because not only is the League of
Cities very much against this but retail
operators are not always thrilled either
this is where the rubber meets the road
folks if you want the good stuff you
have to fight for it and you have to
fight hard because your opponents are
well equipped with lots of money and
lots of time and you don't have much of
either but if you care about delivery
please write to the bureau and tell them
how important it is to you because a so
we'll be writing my trade organization
the Southern California Coalition will
be very much writing about this
your comment letter for ease of
reference you want to keep them
continuous right so topic and then all
of your points but as long as it's the
same n in the same agency so if it's the
BCC and you're a retail or a micro
business a distributor sting lab and you
have common any of those they can all go
in one letter absolutely and the
agencies have put out some really great
guidelines that's on their website if
you go to the BCC site the CDFA site or
the Department of Public Health they
have these little instructions the
Department of Public Health is lagging
on the design aspect but that's alright
the information still there the BCC does
a really good job of breaking down how
to do it how to put a heading how to
make the citation how to explain the
problem and and how to provide your
solution and the amazing thing I've been
working with the agencies as well time
with them is they really are amazingly
open in this moment of time to
suggestions they do not know how to do
this events special events that license
type gets very little attention it got
very little revision I think that if you
look at what happened with chalice if
you look at the difficulty that is going
to be forthcoming that the bureau I fail
to understand that part of 64 was that
the people wanted to have direct access
that that special event license type
doesn't entitle you to be a limited
retailer or distributor and now the only
thing they did change was that you have
to have designated areas for that but
then only retailers can come so it's
very convoluted it's a very difficult
issue but it is one that is generally
important to the public I think that's
one of the ones that people universally
want it is universally by the BCC sort
of the redheaded stepchild so if you
have a brand and you want to be able to
get direct to market without
going through a retailer to a special
event and that's been sort of your
mainstay of how you've interfaced with
your customers or patients there's no
allowance for that so I encourage
everyone please reach out to Americans
for safe access there are tremendous
resource and amazing organization for
any operator in this place please reach
out to the California cannabis Industry
Association CCI a tremendous resource
doing a lot of work writing white papers
writing comments helping in this process
Pamela Epstein Green wise consulting
brilliant person we're here to help
reach out thanks for letting us hijack
the beginning of the panel to talk about
this incredibly important time
who's gonna comment everybody and now we
will continue with your previously
planned programming for metric talking
about tracking trees
[Music]