[Music]
we're gonna talk about the end of the
world in the birth of a new world my
name is Julie Crockett I am the director
of compliance for M MLG we do compliance
it's what we do I'm a board member of
the California cannabis Industry
Association I think about compliance a
lot and talk about it a lot with my
fellow panelists here you go ahead
ok I'm Brett Hartman play on I am the
compliance leader for the company dosis
and I also am the owner of a company
called my cannabis trainer and we do
consulting work for dispensaries brands
distributors on helping to navigate
through regulations and my friend and
co-chair of the newly created Events
Committee is CCIA Pamela yes hi
everybody and welcome my name is a
Pamela Epstein I am the owner and
founder of Green wise company which is a
consulting company and a law firm and we
help all of these wonderful operators
try to navigate the heavily complex
ever-changing open to quite
interpretation by the regulatory
agencies of the new permanent
regulations that we have that seem to be
not so permanent as just today because
you know what I love a nice little as we
like to call it profanity cover your
ears if you're not old enough
fuck you Friday is something that is
perpetually happening as I'm sure we
will talk about last Friday we got an
interpretation of where that universal
symbol is going to have to go and this
Friday
we were alerted to the fact that there
is a lawsuit that is imminently coming
for statewide delivery so nothing is
settled but we'll go through it all the
best that we can so I invite you to sit
down buckle up and be excited to learn a
little bit about where we are in the
regulations right now as many of you
know then or may know that in January
the state the office of administrative
law adopted the permanent regulations
and we put permanent in air quotes
because as Pamela was alluding to
they're just starting to change already
and those regulations unveiled
manok a new reality that many of us saw
coming that was pretty similar to the
last draft submitted before and there
were some major implications for for
businesses and operators so I guess
first if you guys want to talk about a
couple off the top of your head of what
you felt were the biggest implications
or impacts of the adopted permanent regs
I guess I personally feel like I mean we
knew what was going to be coming down
the line we we could we could read them
and strategize on them and and I'm used
to just as soon as the regulations come
out it's always a sucky Friday speaking
about that I am NOT speaking on behalf
of Josas I'm speaking on behalf of Brett
Hartman and so I just wanted to go ahead
and put that out there so I was getting
used to seeing a lot of stuff and it was
like seeing goals and and marketing
goals and and personal dreams just kind
of go down the crapper real quick and
where it was like okay you're not gonna
be able to do this and and should you be
able to explain to clients that why you
can't get free product and why you can't
get free swag and why you can't just
label anything and just think that the
BCC is gonna pass it for branded
merchandise when I don't even think
they're even getting back to people
right now so for me it was just telling
everybody's like you need to focus on
your core values as a company your team
and and whether this because things are
gonna get better but we're gonna go
through some pretty dark tons right now
and I think the regulations have put a
squash on a lot of flexibility for
everything from marketing to production
to products and seeing conflicting
information through them all because
like I went through and completely
reformatted the regulations and added a
table of contents and yes it's the Bible
yeah so I think for me it was really
difficult to see the amount of effort us
and the industry are putting into a
regulated market but the way that the
regulations were submitted to a way that
we could read them made them near
impossible to understand if you don't
have like a strong English grammar
background or in and I'm a have a
technical writing background so where I
had to go through there and and make
them to where they were easily usable
because none of this made sense to me
either and luckily I've been able to
read through how many generations of
rags so it's like I was able to go
through it but I see conflicting
information all over the place one of
the most important things to remember is
as clunky as these regulations are as
difficult as they are I remind my
clients and every time I send out an
email and I say this is why we have to
do something
Irie purposefully put that regulation in
there because it should be a dialogue
that you're having when you hire
somebody as amazing as Julie or bread or
myself and my team Samantha is here and
you want to be able to have a
conversation with us right we're all
reading them you have to frame your lens
about what you want to do as Brett said
what is your core culture that you want
to have and to have a culture of
compliance you need to own that and I
think I say it almost at nauseam to my
clients you're the people that you
employ from your employee and even the
the janitor that may because the city
says has to clean up twice a day they
you're their act omission or failure is
your act omission or failure we can see
it when we saw the issue with Sequoia
that lab technician had an issue but
that could cost Sequoia Labs ultimately
their license so you need to be familiar
with these regulations as daunting as
they are as difficult as they are to
wade through read them and then have
that conversation with your internal
team have that conversation with your
external team and I think that's been
the the most difficult lift when these
regulations went active and permitted
people didn't really understand what
that meant they we knew that we had been
dealing with emergency regulations and
changes and we had as we affectionately
called regulatory whiplash where you
know I on July 1
there was fire sale and you had to get
rid of and make sure you had CRP on the
package and now we're back to CRP and
the exit bags or CRP at the product
level and what does that mean for your
company understand that if you have a
deadline on January 1 of 2020 and all of
the product must be at CRP at the level
of 2020 that doesn't mean in in December
you can change your packaging regime
that doesn't mean that the retailer will
sell out of your product by then that'll
have to be destroyed so when you think
about that you've got to think about
timelines and backdating what these what
these dates in these regulations
actually mean I don't know flip side of
that understanding that once we have
final regulations and the regula the
regulators are no longer going back to
these regulations whole-hog trying to
get us to a point where we have
permanent regulations they're gonna
start looking to enforce upon the
regulations and that's a different
ballgame that means when the regulator's
come out there are no longer
fact-finding information they've
collected that data points they know
what you're doing at these facilities
you invited them in you had great
conversations with them oh I thought
they were great we were making friends
they're coming now for enforcement and
I'm sure we'll get there and we'll talk
about the enforcement guidelines which
are not part of the regulations that I
don't think most people have read one
missing manifests can have no no less
than I think six other violations that
are associated with it that affect not
only your license but the licensee that
was involved in that transaction
which could be more than one licensee
and they have fines that are based off
of how much revenue you make divided by
50% times the amount of days that you've
been in business plus they could shut
you down so you're looking at fines that
could be in the hundreds of thousands of
dollars for one manifest so invest in
training and a culture of compliance
indeed I was just talking to my friend
Rick before this where I was taught like
the regulations who were saying he was
saying is it's sort of like having car
insurance where car insurance sucks and
you spend all this money on car
insurance and most of the time you're
like why am i spending all this money on
car insurance but then when something
goes wrong you're super happy you have
car insurance and you're super happy you
have a low deductible and that's kind of
what that culture of compliance does I
frequently call a record-keeping audit
by the agencies when penalties and fines
are in effect is the new smash-and-grab
you could shut down any company right
now with hundreds of thousands of
dollars if not millions of dollars in
penalties and fines just for asking for
their records because in the business
and Professions Code a single failure to
be able to provide a record can carry a
penalty of $30,000 per instance per
piece of paper that you're unable to
immediately produce and not just you but
your staff who's working at the moment
that they happen to come in and ask for
that piece of paper if they are not
adequately trained to do what they need
to do to immediately provide the thing
that was requested you can be looking at
incurring some serious fines we haven't
seen the full muscle of penalties and
fines being exerted but we also have a
situation where the regulatory agencies
have up to five years to levy those
penalties and fines for things you did
in year one so they can go back years
later and go hey let's do a full audit
of what you were doing between 2007 18
to 2019 and many
companies are not gonna be in a position
to be able to stand up to that audit
because there's a lot it's very
difficult in our position is very
difficult at this moment to to really
like you know cry the credo of the
importance of compliance when most
people are like track and trace isn't
active nobody knows there's no
enforcement nobody's checking and and
from our incredibly cautionary side of
it it's like these people are not your
friends no they're not super stoked
about this and it's a huge funnel of
money for the bureaucratic government so
do you think they're not gonna come
around and collect fines when they can
when when the licensing craze dries up
when it becomes more difficult for
people to on board I think they're gonna
be coming and finding do you know things
to penalize on and let's keep in mind as
well that every company that's
functioning is also videotaping
everything that they're doing and
keeping those videos for 90 days so the
new urban legend that I just heard is
the the operator who the BCC comes in
and caught somebody consuming and then
they requested their tapes and then they
reviewed the tapes and then they dinged
them for every time somebody was
consuming on video and then it's
$300,000 in fines
so it can happen but you know there's
also preventative measures one big thing
I want to say because we're talking a
lot of like you must do this and comply
one of your biggest assets that you
control are your standard operating
procedures your SOPs these can save you
they're like think of them as like a
salvation right everything that you do
when there's an ambiguity in the
regulations you do an SOP for that you
base it off of your understanding of the
regulations therefore if there is an
enforcement action you can show this is
what I have on file this is my SOP this
is why I did it this way
agencies let's discuss this this is not
how we read it this is not how we did it
more so to the point when I have a point
of clarification that I wanted to make
my operator wanted to have the packaging
in the packaging date and the
manufacture date the
same date right they were like this is
how we do it at our facility we
manufacture the pens we fill the pens on
the same day manufacture date package
date same date now there's nothing to
say that you can't do that there was
nothing to say that you could do that so
the response that I got back from DPH
when we had drafted an email that said
if our package 8 and our manufacture
date are the same date and we have that
in our SOP and I put do M /p or I put
the M F G and P kg is that enough on the
label and I put it in there and they
said I think that should be fine okay so
I take that email that says you're fine
I put it in with my SOP I date it it's
there it's it's in my record-keeping
therefore if a retail purchasing manager
when my manufacturer distributor takes
this product with them says I don't know
if I'm allowed to do that I don't see
anybody else doing that you say well I
understand that but I have a letter from
DPH that I can show you that says that
this is fine same thing happened where
we wanted to do a foil seal on the jar
of cannabis instead of doing a tamper
evidence seal on the outer package now
what is every retail purchasing manager
used to seeing a tamper evidence seal on
the side of the bottle what are they
gonna do if they don't see a tamper
evidence see on the side of the bottle
reject it and send it back to be
properly labeled with a tamper evidence
seal it is properly labeled with a
tamper evidence seal why because we put
it in our SOP or I had the client put it
in their SOP we guy we sent the images
to g ph g ph said you could have
multi-layer packaging or multi layer
tamper evident as long as the consumer
can tell if it was tampered with before
they get to the product we put it in
there we packaged it up every single
time that shipment goes out in a
distribution vehicle it is affixed with
the letter and the image so that anytime
it's it's threatened to be refused which
will and does happen we have evidence to
support that so that transaction moves
through the supply chain smoothly
these SOPs can prevent you from hundreds
of thousands of dollars of fines taking
it all the way down to a few
dollars or even oh you're right that was
confusing let's make a change or a
clarification to the regulations and as
a former dispensary manager and director
especially during all this transition it
was really difficult to know what you
were supposed to be looking for on the
packaging and we had to go through and
make a checklist of like these are the
things you should look for if it's not
there you know don't and there's
sometimes things fell through the cracks
as far as like we had to be rejected
product that you know I wasn't in the
store so they're telling me it's not on
the lism like well then send it back and
it sure enough it was somewhere on there
and so I mean I feel for these
distributors right now because they're
dealing with dispensaries at all
different levels of understanding of the
regulations and for me is like my heart
really goes out for some of these
longtime operators that are more of like
artisanal craft cannabis because SOPs
are not part of their SOP they don't do
this because it's part of their art but
in order for them to translate from our
former you know unregulated market into
this new market they have to have
something that you can replicate you
have to have something that you can show
and standard operating procedures
usually freak people up because they're
like oh you know like I don't know how
to write these and it's as simple as
it's just a how-to it's how you want it
to be done just click on bullet points
when you're writing it in something and
just make sure you're just going step by
step on there and making sure that
you're you're doing it and a and it's
time where you can walk somebody through
it that's never done it they can follow
the roles and it makes sense so that
you're not missing any places on there
and I think that's where right now is a
lot of companies how did not understand
what it was going to take to weather
this storm of regulations and they've
been hemorrhaging money
everywhere and then you have these new
companies that are going to be that are
starting that have learned the lessons
from everybody around them and they just
start off right off the bat because
they're bringing in executives now with
other industry experience that they know
what it takes to run a business and
they're gonna come in here and pass up
all of these companies right now and I
remember when I got into this industry
five years ago and and where we were at
and then whenever we passed prop 64 they
said immediately like 90 percent of the
companies that you see today are not
going to be here and it's sadly I know
that it's more than that like they're
just not being able to to handle this
regulated market and I don't blame them
a lot of it has to go down to the
culture of the business that you built
before is that a compliant culture it
starts from the top so remember that if
you're the owner of these businesses you
have to want to do this to have your
employees want to do it
training's I can't tell you how
important they are you may think that
your about tenders know what to do they
don't know what you do do you know what
the single scariest thing in the world
is when the auditors come when the BCC
comes what are they supposed to do do
they know who their first point of
contact is do they know that they're not
allowed to not give them access to
information the longer a regulator sits
and waits for them to figure out who to
call and what to do they're looking
they're looking for problems right if
they're just sitting around looking
they're gonna find the non-compliant
product on the shelf does everybody know
that they got to check-in is everything
leaving in an opaque bag right doesn't
matter how small the product is it's got
to leave your retail store in an opaque
bag prepare them do unannounced audits
hire outside companies to come in and
audit your business it is not that you
are doing something wrong if Julie or
Brett or I or somebody else shows up to
help you we're not there to highlight
what you're doing wrong we're there to
highlight what you could be doing better
and to provide you with a mechanism to
get there like Brett said these are
how-to things if you're an artisanal
cannabis company you know how to do that
you do the same thing every time just
write it down they don't have to be
pretty they don't have to look like
these wonderful beautiful SOPs they have
to be usable and workable and if they're
using them and you're training people to
do them then you're ensuring that that
same thing we talked about earlier that
active omission or failure isn't
happening to you marketing I think is
the single biggest thing that may take
people out besides sequa
that they're not paying attention to
when you advertise on social media your
license number should be synonymous with
your logo if you're gonna put your logo
on something you're gonna put your
license number on something one without
the other doesn't work and I think we
can take a good learning lesson from
some of the biggest dispensary arguable
operators in the state if you have six
dispensaries and you do a leaflet that
you put out in the newspaper you do not
put one license number on there you put
all five or six license numbers if you
are saying I have stores in six
different locations if I can leave you
guys with one piece of advice it's don't
be cute with the agencies they don't
think it's cute
be ahead of your compliance make it a
part of your living breathing
organization and if you are the manager
if you are the owner if you are somebody
who is in charge make it a priority for
you because people learn by what they
see see one do one teach one the same
applies here well I was just gonna say
and this is just another point that if
you sell a product if you sell products
in your store like your business is not
selling product your business is not
making a product your business is
supporting a team of people and
inspiring them to stay so motivated
they're not gonna put your license at
risk and it's like as long as you let
people know what to regulate these this
is the boundaries that you must reside
in and you and and and letting them know
that like that their mistakes reflect on
the company not them and that they're
putting your license and you take care
of your team and you support them and
you provide them with better than what
other companies are doing what you're
not going to deal with the turnover
because right now turnover is happening
everywhere in the industry because
you're taking these people that have
been bud tenders for years and now
they're worth so much from their
knowledge in the industry and applicable
experience and
and and and if they're motivated enough
to do it they can move up from there and
I've seen people from other industries
come into this industry and yes they
bring valuable skills and experience
that we need to help polish us but if
they don't understand what it's like to
work in a highly regulated market
they're going to fill their dreams and
their aspirations for their job just die
because all you do is tell people all
day no that's what it is it is such an
incredibly strange and amazing
evolutionary historical moment that
we're in in terms of you know some of
the cannabis industry from my
perspective is you took a culture of
underground activists and now you've put
them in business casual clothing and
turned them into ninjas who have to play
an insane high-stakes tetris match with
the government and like state and local
ordinances to preserve like the soul of
what they were trying to do you know
like it's like this is the part I like
to make clear of like we're in this
weird you know running match with like
fucking target to decide who gets to
have this industry you know and and some
of us are like I got to get more hair
gel and be corporate and let's fucking
do this you know and in its in its the
biggest like philosophical quandary I
have day by day of how do we create the
world we want to create with this
industry like how do we get to sit at
the table how do we get to navigate the
process how do we get to participate in
inform policy which is still being
written and for God's sakes please let
it be written by us like please let it
be written by the people who suffered
and built the
industry not by the yahoos coming from
Varma who are like I've got this now
thanks for warming my seat we're good
let's do this you know it's it's
ethnically insane and questionable that
so many people are excited about making
money in cannabis while people are still
in jail for cannabis crimes it's insane
that John Boehner and the Republicans
and Mitch whatever the hell his name is
and all the excited people about hamper
like let's put CBD in malls you know
that is insane to me while we are still
struggling to get our social equity
applicants operational in Los Angeles
it's it's completely insane so as boring
as it sounds to some people about
compliance in these things like we are
your ninja team that is here to like
sleep dart the agencies and keep them
off your ass you know this is our job
but to your point do not just take money
I have to make the bit I have to because
don't do it you're getting into bed with
people I can't express it enough I know
I know the feeling the urgency like when
it was 20 2007 2017 and he wanted to get
licenses and like hardly any
jurisdictions were issuing licenses it
was like finding the unicorn or the
needle in the haystack more and more
people are coming online do not I
implore you do not collect these
licenses and not be able to operate them
if you've got seven licenses and none of
them are like 50% compliant then stop
getting more please just it's not gonna
help you to if you think that the more
licenses you have that are
non-operational are not functional to
survive a compliance audit because I
promise you that big money that Julie is
talking about they're hiring us to do a
due diligence of your business and I
can't lie I mean I'm not gonna lie
Brett's not gonna lie Julie's not gonna
lie that's gonna do a disservice so
don't just go picking up
licenses thinking like Oh pharma company
come buy all of my licenses that don't
mean anything because I haven't taken
them through the second step of the
process and aren't transferable that was
getting to that
so you haven't gotten them activated
because the end of the beginning is
getting your business license you got to
get through planning and building which
let me tell you is not a two-week ordeal
if a contractor tells you don't worry
we're going to get through this see you
pee in like two months you're going to
be good you're gonna be operating you
you should have them sign their name in
blood and be able to pay for all of the
fines that you will incur for that not
happening but also read your regulations
where you are getting these licenses if
they say they are non-transferable
licenses just like if you got one from
the BCC it says it right on their
non-transferable that word means and I
feel like it needs to be said it means
it's not transferable that you make a
press release because you're also
excited that you got millions of dollars
that you're then putting a flag in the
ground to tell both your local
jurisdiction if they say that you can't
transfer a license and by
non-transferable sometimes they mean no
change of control so what exactly is the
big pharmaceutical company doing if
they're not buying equity in your
business to change control and at the
state level you're telling the state
regulators oh this person's now an owner
in fourteen days from now if I haven't
updated you and they're not added and
they have equity no I've just
transferred a permit and now in a public
record I'm letting you know and these
people by the way are owners and as an
owner anything that they do anything
they have a felony DUI all of a sudden
that could jeopardize your license so I
implore you I get that there is more
money than God
currently circling the cannabis space
being like I Nate just jump at all of
the money that I want to give you have a
plan understand how that plan is going
to be effectuated
and do not think it is that easy to
bring people in to your business to your
baby that you have slaved over and I am
sure that you spent all of your
hard-earned capital and your dollars in
your time getting it to this place don't
all of a sudden let that be squandered
or let somebody come in and take your
business on pennies on the dollar
because I'm promising you good corporate
governance has not been the mainstay of
this business if you don't have good
corporate actions if you don't have a
minute book if you don't have properly
filed statements of information and
somebody else goes in and files one for
you and all the sudden takes over your
company these are real-world things that
are happening when there's assets and be
forewarn the BCC is starting to crack
down I've had this issue happen where if
you improperly add an owner if you
improperly try to remove an owner or
transfer around outside of the
regulations they will revoke your
license and that's not just one license
your license is revoked
therefore forever you are going to have
to write that your license was revoked
and it could jeopardize your other
existing licenses so I just think very
long and hard and strategically and talk
to your compliance people talk to your
lawyers talk to your tax professionals
does there's tax implications about what
selling in air quotes that means or
taking in capital how do you do that but
you know we can go back to the
regulations I just felt like dovetailing
off of what was your speech could not be
better it's just reminding people what
that transferability yes I mean in like
we said it is a it's a living process
and the permanent regulations are
permanent so we have there's there's
hopeful things there's hopeful things on
the horizon we're in the flurry of all
of the bills at the legislative level
being introduced senator scott weiner
has reintroduced the compassionate care
bill which is amazing let's hope that
this governor actually signs it because
it did pass last year but
didn't sign it this would relieve the
excise taxes from donated products from
compassionate care that'd be nice we
also have you know on another huh
oh yeah the excise tax bill is getting
reintroduced to lower the excise tax
from 15 to 11% hey every little bit
helps you have a lot of localities
starting to lower their local taxes
because they're getting the symbol I
mean they're getting the idea that maybe
the really high local taxes on top of
low high with state taxes on top of a
high you know all of it doesn't really
work that well they're seeing the tax
money the tax revenue is not staying
locally it's going straight to the state
level and and this is where a lot of
this stuff is very frustrating to me is
seen where what the fines are and what
the application fees are and what
communities can make off of these
application fees and Oh ton yeah 1.7
million in Pasadena well hot damn they
better for applications once you get
your license they just made off of
people applying but at least is staying
at the local level so I appreciate that
because that's money that's being pumped
in from all over the world is going in
for these Pasadena applications the the
dispensaries are not seeing the growth
that they had had projected to see the
only thing that has grown is their costs
for everything else and that's where it
went back to like the packaging the CRP
packaging this whole whiplash back and
forth situation here every time the the
government makes a decision like this
that they think is so small and so not a
big insignificant ends up costing
millions of dollars costing companies
their jobs I mean they're costing people
their companies and and how are we going
to survive through a lot of this stuff
here is and you have to be willing and
ready to pivot at every turn and and I
worked emergency veterinary medicine
before I got into cannabis and we dealt
with federally controlled drugs like we
regularly have ketamine out and
and hydromorphone and Valium and these
are things that have to be tracked every
single month and I have to provide that
to state and federal agencies and these
are also organizations specifically vet
clinics in Texas don't usually hire
veterinary technicians that are licensed
so since there's Texas A&amp;M there which
is the largest vet school in the country
and Texas is all about you know low
wages and best your ass that's why I
live in California now is you didn't
have to be credentialed anything and you
have people that are literally your
veterinary license does that risk it's
not just your business license your
career is at risk because you have an
employee who's skimming valium off the
top or kind of mean off the top and I've
seen this come back on them and it's
like so I know what it's like to work in
a highly regulated market with compliant
products that you have to track and
trace every bit of it and you're leaving
that trust in some of your employees
that are you know an experienced
uneducated and and and not caring really
what makes a difference in your life you
know this or that and and you're not
taking care of them so I mean I think
this is where it's like truly it has to
be we're not in the business of cannabis
we're in the compliance business which I
mean I know I personally am but
everybody should be doing this right now
it has to be part of your culture and
you need to bring people in and I'm not
pitching any of us here like there's
plenty of great companies out there
great people out there and people that
have just been in the industry long
enough that they know how to to go with
these changes and you need to bring them
in and you need to listen to them
because like I had a discussion earlier
it's like if you're dropping off samples
in a store and you you know I know that
there has to be a manifest in there all
these things but it's like you're not
well they can go back for 90 days where
the footage and then they see you and
then like oh they didn't also check in
as a visitor so they're not on the
visitor log so they may never find out
who the sales rep was they will because
of the harassing the store for saying
who was this and all this and then
they'll go back to them and then your
company is that risk because you had a
sales rep that was just trying to win
that account because now you've switched
them all from
from commission-based - now they're over
because you don't want to file them as a
financial interest party on their so it
it's has to take care of you people take
some time off from selling and train yes
and I just to pick up on that like I was
just having this conversation with
somebody where there's so many micro
things and the companies where they're
like this isn't a big deal and this
isn't a big deal this isn't a big deal
it may not even be something that you do
your dispensary your business could be
robbed and the police are gonna ask for
the tapes and they're gonna review the
tapes and then they see stuff happen and
this has happened where then they see
something else happen again go oh by the
way sorry about your robbery but look at
all these things that you're doing wrong
in your tapes so it's it's incredibly
different and difficult to be under this
level of scrutiny but if you can master
being comfortable under this level of
scrutiny reporting everything having
those relationships with the agencies
just be being an open book you know for
what they asked to see it's like going
through a tax audit you show them what
they asked you to answer the questions
they ask and and on you go that's a
great it's a great situation to be in
it's a great muscle to cultivate and
also what Brett was saying any company
who hires a single compliance officer
and is like we're good we're covered we
do we got compliance like I have a
consultant we're great you're not okay
like well - tough tell them what you're
saying everybody's job in a company in a
cannabis company is now compliance you
are no longer a budtender your job is
sales compliance you are no longer a
grower your job is growing compliance
you know you your growers have like a
ridiculous amount of record-keeping
responsibilities you have to support
them you have to build systems that work
for them you have to make sure they have
the right scales and the right kind of
points of entry to enter the information
so that it's not too hard and it's not
too difficult and you're not giving them
so much pressure that they're in too
much of a hurry that they can't write
down the wet weight for every individual
plant that has to be written down now
you have to help them and then you have
to build in redundancy
big so that's the thing about it is is
like not only do you have to do it you
got to do that like three fucking times
because you don't want any of this to go
missing so if you have to keep a
visitor's log like a lot of people don't
understand that you have to keep
employee records separate from other
records and all of this different
thinking so they'll have them all locked
up and in our spaces right now like I
mean compliance also means it takes up a
lot of space so you have to have
cabinets that are locked you have this
you know and it's like well let's have
digital digital is great until shit goes
down and then you don't have electricity
and then they just so happen to show up
in that moment and the thing about all
of this is and with regulators and I
don't mean this in a bad way is like
learn how to be this is funny coming
from with me for me learn how to be a
likeable person because all of this
stuff is oh it's like subjective like so
if they come in and they don't like your
attitude
those other two things that they didn't
that they saw but they didn't see they
saw and so you need to learn how to also
come at this because they're coming at
you nice as can be because they know
that takes your guard down so you need
to come at them nicest can be as well
and have like like it was already
discussed here it's like I do just like
a fire drill not that any businesses do
that but do a fire drill because trust
me that fire will burn you down worse we
we do so I not not to pitch the business
but we do it Julie does that other
people do it we go and do an audit of
our clients businesses we give them
anywhere from 48 hours to two hours to
zero notice and we show up and I show up
and I'm like okay so today I'm your BCC
auditor show me what your books are
check me in and if they don't track me
and I said why aren't you asking for my
ID do it where is your visitor a lot and
I tell you it's those sorts of
unannounced audits that prepare you and
your staff the best because what Brett
is saying which really thing is you got
a these are usually enforcement officers
or former police officers they know how
to add
leading questions they know how to be
nicest pie so that all the sudden your
employees talking and they're like oh
yeah well you know sometimes I put it in
and sometimes they don't and if we're
really busy then I'll wait till do it
until later and then they're not in real
time and they're just talking so they
need to understand how to answer
questions how to give the correct
information without giving more
information than they have to
and it's practice makes perfect right
nobody is ever a hundred percent
compliant I like to look at this
industry the same as a banking industry
right banks are heavily regulated
industry and when the federal reserve
comes in no bank is ever a hundred
percent compliant but there are some
banks that work with third-party
certification companies and they have a
certification that says we were last
audited on X date these are the issues
that they found these are the corrective
actions we already have in place
and I tell you when the Federal Reserve
comes in to do an audit they may not
give you they may not give those banks
additional fines because what are what
is a fine the finest to identify a
problem and to ensure that there's a
corrective action and remediation so
that it doesn't happen again if you've
already done those three things there's
not much for the agency to do and they'd
rather let you continue on and say okay
well then I'm gonna come back and make
sure these things have been done or they
may impose a date by which they have to
be done versus the corrective action
that you had that allowed you a longer
bandwidth so that you had more financial
security in making those changes so they
may instead just escalate your timetable
versus giving you an enforcement action
so nobody up here is saying that we want
to go in and tell you what you're doing
wrong like I said before we want to
highlight what you can do better so that
when those agencies come it's not a
surprise to you well and I think that a
lot of this compliance also any other
sounds completely not true at all but a
lot of this can aid in efficiency and
cost savings because you're streamlining
what you're doing this is what large
companies do and this is where the
pharmaceutical companies can come in
here and I can they can read our
regulation
the tobacco industry can come in here
and read our regulations and be like I
got this because they already know what
it's like to reside in that and and they
know that areas that they can strategize
on because a lot of these things are is
just like oh it says I can't do this
it did not say you couldn't do that it
said you couldn't do it the way you did
it
now you can figure out ways to go around
it and I you know there's nothing more
than I love to see is like as a kid like
you know it's like you didn't want to do
what your mom or dad told you to do so
you like to figure a way around it to
get what you wanted and like this is
kind of what regulations are to me as
well and and and and thank God like I'm
coming from a place of ethics versus
some people are coming from a place of
greed and selfishness and whatever and
yes I'm sure my husband would say I do
that every so often too but you need to
go through there and just strategize
allow yourself to wipe out what you used
to think that it meant and try to go
from there because a lot of these things
they just help you streamline your
business streamline your finances I am a
huge believer in that the green tax is
not 90 percent of the time the green tax
is up you're late and you should have
got this shit in it's three weeks ago
and that's why you're paying the extra
fee on all this stuff but I'm also
noticing more and more now like security
companies are really wanting to get
involved in this I mean now that things
are legal on a on a state level we've
been able to actually have access to
better companies to work with and
they're not as you know I used to be so
worried to divulge it oh this is a
retailer or this is you know this is our
dispensary and now it's it's so much
better people are less less judgmental
about it but I also still remember how
dispensaries act when the fire and
safety show up before all of this and
and to just come in and either yearly
inspection like they just have to walk
through the place and you would stop
them at the front and you'd be like no
no no you can't come in until I'm like
no I literally have to like it in if
that's how they acted with fire safety
who these guys were like I don't really
care like I'll come through like I'm
I'll wait you know the these inspectors
and auditors are not gonna sit there and
wait because that adds
you there day anyways is there gonna
still do what they got to do it's a
fight that's we all are fine to not let
the men are immediately regs do you guys
like the best wait wait what is the most
well I was gonna say does anybody have
any questions out there does anybody
want to ask a question or just can't air
day
[Music]