[Music]
when Peter suggested the idea of doing a
panel and letting me moderate I was like
I like jumped out I'm like oh gosh for
once I can ask the questions and sort of
sit back and relax so I'm really excited
about it a little bit nervous too but
anyway just to let you know as Peter
said the three licensing authorities
have just finished their 45-day comment
period I know for the bureau we're
looking at thousands of comments that
have come through so that's pretty
incredible that we're getting that many
comments and we're going through them
but I think tonight is a perfect now
that we are done with that comment
period and looking through those regs
it's a perfect I did a perfect time to
get the industry's perspective on what
we should be looking at what we should
be changing and just get their
perspective so even tonight I'm gonna be
doing a lot of listening because I want
to hear from them and how things are
going for them but before we get started
I'm gonna let them each introduce
themselves and then we'll get started
with the questions hi everybody I'm
Samantha Miller I'm the president and
chief scientist of pure analytics
laboratory so we're operating as a
licensed laboratory certifying products
for the retail cannabis market and as
anybody in here who is a manufacturer or
distributor can imagine it's very
interesting to be a lab right now I'm
Gavin Cogan I'm chief branding officer
and founder of Grupo floor in the
Salinas Valley our operations span the
entire supply chain and different
companies operating kind of in a
horizontal company as opposed to one big
company hi I'm Sabrina pendrick I'm
director of government affairs for
Berkeley patients group which is the
oldest dispensary in the country good
evening my name is Michael wheeler and
I'm the vice president of policy
initiatives for flow kana flow kana is a
branded distributor of sun-grown craft
cannabis from Northern California hello
my name is Kristen of it all I'm the
chairperson for the international
cannabis farmers
Teesha our group is we formed to help
empower the traditional cannabis farmer
through research education and advocacy
and I also work with my husband and our
business partners we have the humble its
finest brand okay well thank you so I
you know I have us the first ones maybe
a softball but now that we're looking at
eight months into the legalized
regulated market and I know from the
bureau's perspective for each part of
the supply chain we've had our own
challenges in regulating so I wanted to
get your perspective on how it has been
for you the last eight months and being
in this regulated market and especially
how have you continued to deal with the
changes that come down because we always
talk about the regulator's you know we
keep changing things on you and so I'm
curious how you've dealt with that you
know you have to stay nimble and you
have to be on top of it I think the
worst thing you can do is refer to
lawyers to interpret the regulations for
you instead of as a business operator
being engaged in them in a line-by-line
fashion and I think that's where some
people have been caught unawares at
times where they're relying on others to
interpret for them rather than as I say
as operators actually being fully
engaged in the text of the regulations
but I think some of the biggest
challenges have been to on the lab side
is the the marketing right over the
regulations is is to help guide people
through things they feel are
unreasonable are things they don't feel
like they should have to do and help
explain and understand to them that this
path forward represents one where we're
taking some extraordinary measures
around the protection of consumer safety
because we lack a certain body of data
so I think one of the biggest challenges
has been really been to communicate to
the people who are the users of lab
testing in this current market maybe why
some of the things that are in place are
there in terms of being able to react to
the changing regulations mostly you have
to anticipate when you get an initial
draft of regulations you need to take
them almost as if that's what's going to
be because if you wait until the end of
a comment period implementation then
you'll find yourself probably too far
behind
so I think one of the struggles that
people have had is well I don't want to
spend money I don't have to write in
case this thing changes
let's say there's no heavy metals
requirement for example right I don't
want to buy an icp-ms if I don't have to
so I think making those decisions in
anticipation of what could be while
trying to manage cash flow and and and
capital is it's been challenging as a
business owner yeah absolutely all those
points so the I think probably the top
level thing I would say is the ultimate
goal was to transition people from the
black market to the regulated market and
for as a whole supply chain Enterprise
such as group of floor it's frustrating
talking for example to dispensary owners
explaining to them that the packaging we
have actually does comply with the law
and then getting into fights with them
about why it does or does not that gets
very tiresome so there's a lot of
unknown
I was actually mentioning to you Laurie
before the event there's a lot of
distrust politically there's also a lot
of distrust in our industry towards
politicians and I think that the more we
can you know connect and demystify a lot
of both ends of that be really useful
for us I think the to see a larger
rollout I think this has been less you
know explosive rollout than we had
anticipated so a lot of people spend a
lot of money and a lot of energy to gear
up for not a lot and so that's been very
frustrating I hope to see that evolve
well interesting you mentioned the
packaging relationship with retailers
but before I get to that I would say a
sort of on an overall 30,000 foot view
of this has been the educating and
talking to both the vendors and the
public because we have both basically to
deal with and the public has been very
frustrated with the rising prices and
the taxes and a lot of that sort of the
education around that component and then
also talking to the vendors and and like
some of us we're talking about before
everybody sort of has their own
interpretation on what's compliant and
what's not and
it kind of comes down to you know sort
of making a determination of within the
business of where you know where you're
gonna draw the line and what you believe
is going to be the right thing because
ultimately I think if if the intent is
there and you're trying your best to be
as compliant as you can in your own
capacity then you're doing as well as
you can but yeah so it's sort of just
been a balancing act and making sure I
think the July first transition was
fascinating it was it was yeah you know
it was it was inevitable and I think
that it were really we're in a really
interesting place in California being
the largest cannabis market in the world
and you know having just one chief
overseeing the the largest cannabis
market and trying to fit all the supply
chains and together and and having
everybody talk to each other and making
sure that that it's working and that we
all are on the basically the same page
so it is a heavy lift but I'm really
glad that it's happening and I think if
it's done right if people stay diligent
then it can be done oh it's not entirely
impossible but there's always going to
be challenges and always going to be
issues and then there's also the working
with the local jurisdiction I think has
also been a challenge and that seemed to
bring out a lot of players that had
never traditionally come out to
challenge anything regarding cannabis
BPG has been around for almost 20 years
and most of the community members seemed
fine with it and then all of a sudden
January 1st
there was this outpour of interest
groups that were completely opposed and
it was shocking because I nothing really
changed other than who we let in the
door and tweaking security measures so
that was kind of a challenge I agree
with much as much that has been said
already and you know to not repeat any
of that I would say that it really does
feel like we are all you know we've all
got our map on how to try to succeed and
were each interpreting those words
slightly differently
as we make our way through this dark
forest because it's not there's no path
it's follow the map and that's been the
challenge is my impression or my
understanding of what these words say is
a little bit different than maybe
somebody else's and we've got to do
business together and and that creates
complexities and at the same time to
make a separate different point I think
that we're all able to understand and
measure the success of this growing
regulated market but we're not able to
measure the health and wellness of the
illicit market that we're trying to
deconstruct
and that presents a challenge to me
because I can only understand whether
we're making progress as a regulated
market but not whether or not we are
gaining ground on the illicit market and
so I think that's a lot of really good
lead into what cultivators are facing
especially existing cultivators right we
have a cultivation system that breaks
cultivators in two sizes and scales them
right so you're 2,500 square feet or
you're below 5,000 or you're below 10 or
22 or if you're outdoor you can have up
to an anchor and so California has a 20
year old cannabis industry that's trying
to wrap regulations around a very robust
existing industry this has not been done
before right in most states statute has
passed regulations happen in an industry
is burst right so here in California we
have a whole new paradigm where these
regulators are trying to figure out how
to fit a multi-billion dollar industry
into a linear regulated box so to say so
for existing cultivators were were
having a lot of struggles we didn't we
didn't build our cultivation based on
you know five hundred square foot
increments or 5,000 square foot
increments we built them a lot of times
where they fit in the landscape
and so what we're really struggling with
are these challenges around how to have
12,000 square feet when the licenses are
ten thousand or twenty two right
economically you don't fit into 22,000
square foot license and you don't really
fit into ten thousand because you have
12 thousand so a lot of our members and
the existing cultivators especially the
seasonal cultivators I find are really
struggling with how to fit their
existing operations into a regulated
model that doesn't have flexibility
right it's really linear and the issues
around shared facilities if I have to
have two licenses because I'm 12,000
square feet I now can't share a
processing or a propagation area so we
have lots of providers that have been
working diligently to provide medicine
for patients over the last 20 years that
don't necessarily have the funding to
build new facilities nor do they have
the space or necessarily the land use
opportunities because of being located
rural E and they're on a glans and not
on commercial lands or industrial lands
so you know work we're kind of
constantly trying to figure out how to
fit into a system after years and years
of engaging and being involved in
proposition 215 and SB 420 and feeling
kind of really pulled in a multitude of
ways so it's a little bit of a kind of
quicksand scenario for a lot of our
stakeholders and members so Sabrina
brought up an excellent point the July
1st transition so the Bureau took a lot
of heat when we did not extend the
transition period there was a tremendous
amount of pressure on us to extend it we
did not we did not change our
regulations and we did not extend it I'm
one question two questions for the panel
how did you feel about that decision
and how did it affect your business
operations you know my personal feelings
about the decision were that I had been
approached by some retail operators and
other operators in the industry to to
put my name with those who were so we're
asking for an extension and for
ourselves as the laboratory an extension
wasn't really going to be material one
way or another in terms of readiness or
our execution because we were already
doing what we needed to do for July
first
but what I was seeing was that having to
do with the inventory that was being
held an evaluation of inventory that was
either owned by yourself or by another
party that you're in contract with that
the particulars around the ownerships of
those inventories and the date of its
production in some cases because the
deadlines either weren't understood or
anticipated with respect to when things
were manufactured or harvested and when
they could continue to be sold that I
became aware of certain people who I
personally cared about a lot that we're
going to take enormous losses that could
potentially put them out of business as
small business owners and so as a small
business owner entrepreneur I have a lot
of compassion for those people and I was
I was dismayed that they were having
such a negative impact because I've
known them since my company was founded
eight and a half years ago and to be in
business for eight and a half years or
ten years and suffer that kind of blow
in one that you really can't affect and
maybe it's their own responsibility in
their own fault because they weren't
prepared or they weren't engaged and
that may have been what happened but it
was unfortunate just as from a
humanistic perspective it was
unfortunate to watch that happen for
people you know I personally I would
have liked to see an extension for all
the reasons that you said the I do
wonder though if we had extended I'm
sure this is part of what inform the
decision not to us would it have been
any different another six months hence
right so personally I would have liked
to see extension an extension because I
think that it needs to be a smoother
transition from the
the unregulated to the regulated market
from a business perspective though
anticipated that it would be held hard
and so to that July date
so we amped up for it and there was a
lot of market share to be got during
that period of salt and then lastly just
you know kind of embarrassed by the
Instagram and social media posts of just
all these empty shelves throughout our
state one of the biggest you know
concerns I have is the the lack of
dispensaries in our in our market being
a supply chain company so I hope to see
those shelves filled again and that's
robust market so it's a little scary how
much of a reset it was yeah I agree I
think it would have been delaying the
inevitable if you had just moved it and
there the reactions would have been the
same it I made sure that you know that
the buyers at BPG were in communication
with their vendors to make sure that
they were as prepared as they can be and
and you know how that communication gets
through and whether it's received on
that and I I don't know but I I I think
that it definitely helped to provide a
sort of a process for them because a lot
of them didn't really know what to do or
what was even going on or that there was
even a July first deadline and you know
just and to ensure that we did have
enough products and and you know didn't
lose out on any of that and all of the
testing and Berklee's testing standards
have always been extremely high than the
highest in the state so most of the
vendors that we worked with we're pretty
used to you know meeting those rules
anyways so the testing wasn't as much of
an issue as the packaging and labeling
which also kicked off a lot of
discussions and arguments but I think
that yeah I mean it better to happen now
and to have everybody adjust right now
if this is all it's inevitable and you
know we've been fighting for this for a
really long time and here we are so this
is what it looks like and I just look at
it as growing pains and you know it's
it's really hard to see you know like
you said some of the these own smaller
business owners that just don't have the
resources or the bandwidth to really
keep up with all of
things and find themselves in a
situation where they're not completely
able to comply to the extent that they
can get their stuff online right away I
think a lot of this is a very flexible
creative industry that has managed to
survive through many challenges in the
past and I think that that spirit will
continue on and people can be innovative
and and find a way so I think it was it
was good yeah I would say that despite
preparation beginning in June for the
July 1st changes the end of that grace
period you know flow Cana suffered
significantly in early July as we didn't
agree with our retail clients on what
were the packaging requirements and that
was that was really challenging to not
see eye to eye have us all trying to
comply but disagree about what the rules
said that was very challenging and at
the same time despite the pain that we
felt and what I assume many many
companies felt I would say that I still
salute the BCC for not flexing on that
because this is the beginning of the
relationship of there's an open period
where we all get to talk about what the
rules should be and then we will enforce
the rules and so I salute you for
enforcing the rules when it was time to
enforce the rules and we learned that
this is this is a sort of a weak link
situation a weakest link situation in
the industry where those who and we're
gonna confront it again in the near
future probably when these regs go final
we will have those who didn't prepare
enough and businesses will choose oh
you're not prepared I'm not going to do
business with you right now
and that may be a make-or-break moment
for those who didn't prepare and yet
that is the way this industry and any
industry works
you know it's competition and we can
seek to out-compete each other on
compliance to the state's benefit
and I think a lot of farmers were kind
of caught off guard I mean granted the
transition period was published but
we're transitioning away from kind of a
bulk flour market so traditionally
cultivators have provided bulk flour
into the retail sector and that's how
it's gone into vending departments so a
lot of cultivators weren't prepared for
packaging they didn't have a brand they
didn't have containers they're used to
bringing whole pound units and then
having the dispensary packaged and so
when you're in a position to try to or
have to start figuring out packaging
first of all the timeframe on that is
you know six to six months to a year to
just try to figure out how to source and
how to put together compliant packaging
so as humble its finest we started our
rebrand for compliant packaging in
January and what we what came what we
came up against was that as early as
April the distributors we were working
with were like oh no no we're not taking
anymore product unless it's prepped for
July and we're like oh my gosh this is
kind of crushing because here we have
packaged product that you know should
have been able to be on the shelves
until July and then our our distributors
were kicking it back because they didn't
want to have anything in their stock
right come July 1st that wasn't
compliant so we'd already been doing the
testing and for us it was dealing with
the child resistant packaging component
especially when we looked at pre rolls
we do a lot of pre roll cigarette or
cannabis cigarettes so trying to figure
out how to especially in single serving
sizes manage that CRP component was
really challenging and it was expensive
but we're there and I think if people
didn't plan you know six nine months in
advance they really got caught off guard
with it and so it's it's a yeah
basically have a point person that you
could put on that and the resources to
do it to be prepared as what we found
you know one point to add on I think
that was actually really important about
the July transition that's very focused
on the lab sector was the increase in
testing requirements
they increase in the compound lists
because the phase one pesticide list
really didn't encompass what's normally
used on cannabis and the things that
were usually the most concerned about
finding and so I think that delaying the
implementation of the face to pesticide
list especially would have definitely
been an error yeah that's really it's
really helpful to from your perspective
one of the things as regulators we're
constantly looking at is how we can how
we can make the supply chain more
efficient because it is a cannabis
product is a very difficult commodity to
get to market in an efficient timeframe
so we're always looking at we're also
balancing between retail and supplier
and manufacturer because we feel like
you can't what's good for one isn't
always good for all so I would love to
hear from your perspective on the things
that we can control in regulations can
you point to one single change that
would make the supply more efficient
from your point of view I know that's a
tough one huh
I can go out of order yes so I would say
we're we're on the path to this right
now but it's it has everything to do
with allowing Khoa testing as high up in
the supply chain as possible and then
letting that bulk material that's been
tested and have that Khoa test move
through to other distributors to
co-packers to others who will handle it
and put it into packages or pre-rolls or
you know go through that supply chain
and and that itself would make things
much more efficient and that is much
better than the alternative of the
illicit market where nothing is tested
so I totally appreciate that we want to
make sure that nothing there's no jars
of flour or pre rolls or manufactured
products that are tainted with chemicals
and filth and that kind of thing but no
matter what if it passes a Khoa test at
the
bulk level it is definitely better than
what is being sourced on the illicit
market and so I would love to see that
Co attests for both product be able to
travel with with that with those I'm
going to use a metric term with the
package tag that is assigned to it and
be and be good to go you know what I
think would actually do something
amazing in the supply chain right now is
something that gets used in supply
chains and manufacturing and many many
other industries whether regulated or
not and it's often referred to as skip
lot testing and it's the concept of when
a producer or an actor in the industry
who's responsible for the quality of a
product has demonstrated that over a
period of time that's specified by a
regulatory body that they're doing
things correctly there's been an on-site
inspection there's been an audit of
their SOPs and from a regulatory testing
perspective they're passing and not
having issues that are systemic and that
are related to their their processes and
so in many situations like that in other
industries those good actors will be
allowed to not test every lot if that
was a place based on data that we could
get to from a comfort level to say that
we can verify a producer to the extent
that we can feel comfortable taking that
approach to testing and and approval of
products would be amazing but I think
we're probably a bit far out from that
in terms of having the data to be able
to base those decisions on I would kind
of going back to the dispensaries piece
I can't get into a specific regulation
but just generally I would like to see
some efforts to encourage a lot more
transition from the black market or what
all you can say is the prop 215 crowd
that are sort of waiting in the wings I
I I'd really like I think that our
success is going to depend on how many
outlets and dispensaries there are and
so I would encourage as unfavourable as
this might be to some people a much
lower bar of entry for dispensaries
understanding that there's going to be
problems there but we need to have
access for the public to start trusting
and whining apart
they it it's as a term I use where they
had you before we need more carrots and
less cannons to encourage transition I
know I'll say you know further this is
an industry that we're not concerned
about getting arrested so cannons aren't
that effective they haven't been for
generations so why we think that would
be effective now I think that really
some creativity and how we could
encourage people to participate in the
regulated market at that retail end is
going to do an awful lot to stimulate
growth in the supply chain throughout
yeah I would I would agree with that I
think on the retail end is really about
we're the public facing side of the
supply chain so anything that goes wrong
anywhere it's always the retailer's
faults and we're the lab making but
nobody knows who the love is for the
public ones where the store fronts so
where some of us are and so I think that
public health component and child safety
component is really important to the
retailers and making sure there's the
story I have told a couple times about
I'm sure some people know what happened
with Maureen Dowd in Colorado and she
ate too much of an edible and then wrote
an op-ed in The New York Times about it
and it almost completely destroyed the
manufacturer in cannabis manufacturing
industry in Colorado and they're still
recovering today this happened in 2014
and so things like that happen and so we
need to make sure that we're we're doing
the best of both like protect you know
touching on the the child-resistant
packaging needing to be closest to the
actual product for certain products I
think it's something that's a very
important um which you've heard me say
couple times now different hearings and
also I think some sort of a just
consumer education outreach to take down
take down the illicit market encourage
more people to come into the legal
regulated market and have some sort of
easily accessible map I have
just a quick story my mother decided she
wanted to go buy some cannabis she lives
in San Diego County in North County and
didn't tell me but whatever and looked
it up did a google search and found a
website that lists lots of dispensaries
some licensed some not licensed and she
she told me that she went to a licensed
dispensary in Vista California and I was
like mom no I don't
this does not licensing I don't think
you did and she's went to some place
called the Sugar Shack where they sold
her a 300 milligram chocalate bar that
was I mean the whole thing luckily she
knows enough to not eat the whole thing
and break it up and she said it actually
didn't do anything which goes to the
testing but that whole story I was just
like if my mother who actually you know
has a daughter in the industry and it
kind of knows a little bit about this
and she's 71 year old grandmother now
there must be lots of people out there
that are doing this and and I couldn't
even I was trying to I sent her the
spreadsheet that was on the BCC site
because there there isn't really a place
that I could point to that's directly
like here this is a map of all of the
licensed dispensaries that you can go to
and you know it's tested and you know
this and and all of that and it's safe
so I think yeah just some sort of
consumer information so that the the
people that do want to go to the legal
market know where to go and and can
trust it and then I think I'm just all
of these are really great points but
coming back to Michael's point about how
the batches are configured with testing
from a cultivator perspective you know
we might harvest one batch from one farm
of say og cush and then that og cush
turns into one grand-prix rolls and then
pack of seven pre-rolls and then eights
and then quarters and so those all new
have they all have new SKUs to them when
they go in new track and trace batch
numbers when they go to the distributor
but it's literally one batch of cannabis
flowers so for
to now have to test the single pre-rolls
as one batch the five to a pack as one
batch the eight as one batch as a cost
that we can't necessarily afford to
sustain as cultivators putting non
manufactured products into the
marketplace so if that could be looked
at as one batch because it came from one
farm was harvested at the same time was
one crop that would actually create such
a tremendous amount of ease in moving
these products safely from the farm
through the testing and distribution
model and into the retail so that's one
of the places where we're really
struggling with timing hang-ups and
costs of trying to get a broad spectrum
say of non manufactured products into
the marketplace that's a sticky spot for
cultivators right I actually think that
highlights one of the biggest issues
that we've all talked about along the
way which is the different
interpretations of the regulation text
by different parties and so Chris and I
had an aha moment a few months back
where one of the members of the BCC team
helped us understand that as a lab that
we can actually sample as one batch pre
unpacked flour eighths and quarters all
together as one batch and apply the coa
to all those different SKUs and so in in
certain readings of the regulations it
was interpreted by some people as if
every SKU had to have a specific coa but
in the case of flour which is kind of a
special case with the exception of pre
rolls which is handled differently in
the new draft at least as its as it
stands at the moment we actually have
the ability now to to tighten that up a
little bit into to apply one coa to
unpacked flour eighths and quarters say
that were from the same harvest batch
can we get a memo over to our testing
facility that'd be great 100% i got the
nod well i think what's interesting and
concerning to me at the same time is on
each question I'm finding that
throughout the supply chain you are
interpret
the regs differently and so if you're
gonna reflect back what are what could
we do to make sure and I know you're
gonna tell me I know we got to get
information out but with all of our
other responsibilities do you have any
good ideas for us where we could do a
better job of explaining the regs I mean
maybe it starts with the regs themselves
but you know I think there's better ways
to get the information out and and one
thing that I worry about as we come to
the final leg of our rulemaking how do
we make sure we're continuing to
communicate and collaborate we've done
it a lot getting these regs out but how
do we going forward make sure we keep
that momentum so I'd love your thoughts
on that you know I think there's an
agency to agency component right so a
lot of the operators are are kind of
wrangling multiple sets of regulations
that they have to comply with
cultivators have California Department
of Food and Agriculture open air
cultivators have the water board the
water resource control board they have
Department of Fish and Wildlife and then
depending on how they choose to
transport their product if they have say
a self distribution transportation
license now they have BCC right and and
so how how like as a cultivator we
digest that body of material is really
challenging and then I find that there's
not always the same I don't know if
definition is the right word but maybe
interpretation of specific definitions
from statutes so like we're really
suffering with the contiguous premise
component especially as existing
cultivators that already built out right
how do we fit into that box but BCC
seems to have a little different way of
dealing with contiguous premise and say
CD FA or CD pH so those pieces make it
really kind of a quicksand feeling
because you're not sure who to look to
for answers in some of those cases so I
think kind of more in
agency communication and sort of joint
educational opportunities would be
really fabulous you know what I was
yearning for in this in this last round
of these of the draft regulations and
also actually with July one in lab
there's not a lot of us who are
currently offering I think there's maybe
30 or maybe more licensees now as they
keep adding on but in terms of operators
it's I think it's less than 15 probably
right now and what we're doing is fairly
complicated there's a lot of details and
if we get it wrong we can have a serious
economic impact on a party completely
unintentionally by making by
misinterpreting something to miss
applying it on a CoA that then can't be
amended and so when those transitions
happen I said you know I it would have
been really great from a collaboration
perspective if we could have gotten the
lab operators on the phone with the
regulator's to really walk through what
what to ask from us was in terms of
changes to help us understand the label
claim thing has been a little over the
top to understand what it means what has
to be what doesn't have to be where's
the where's the area of permissions
where's the area of no permissions and
so I think I guess literally a simple
conference call with the lab operators
because we're a small number would have
been amazing and it would have cleared
up a lot of kind of disparate things
between us which affected the
manufacturers and ineffective
distributors because our interpretations
affect everybody in a big way now I
don't I don't think that's totally
doable for everybody because there's a
lot more manufacturers and a lot more
distributors than there are labs so that
may not be applicable for each group but
that approach which may mean maybe there
needs to be more funding for outreach
personnel that are specifically just
about outreach and about giving voice to
that interpretation because there's
there's a difference in having a
discussion like with Elena who's been
who's an amazing resource on your team
to help understand the regulations but I
think there's people who don't feel like
they have that personal connection to
the BCC team or a go-to person and so
somehow we need to create that sense of
everybody knows who to go to and that
person has the bandwidth to answer them
because there there's a lot of us yeah
yeah oh you know California is the
only state that has multiple agencies
regulating one supply chain in cannabis
so that's very unique and you know
obviously causes lots of problems with
interpretation and who is authority over
what and I would say you know something
the CDT FA does that they started a
couple of months ago and they've only
had a couple but they've invited a
couple of operators from distributors
and retailers to discuss the just the
excise tax and and how the tax structure
is paid and what's going on and and we
asked them questions and they asked us
questions and we kind of just have this
sort of informal back-and-forth
conversation so that's been pretty
helpful because that's been an
unbelievably confusing on its own and so
that might be an idea I know there's the
Advisory Committee which is very formal
and and sort of there by law but some
sort of more informal stakeholder
licensee conversation and right now
since there aren't a ton of licensees if
it probably would be easier to do at
this point then you know six months or a
year later when if there's more coming
out as more places and people get online
and I think the other thing is you know
going back to this packaging and
labeling which has just been a you know
interesting transition and our different
interpretations of you know what is
required I think having a general
understanding of because we were in the
position I you know the retailer BPG was
saying that we are we're licensed and
inspected by the Bureau so we're going
to go with what the bureau says and what
statute says and then there's CD pH that
has what they have and then that's with
them I think this also comes down to why
there may have been some difference
interpretation and yeah so I you know
one of the sort of more specific nuance
they
we come down to sort of the you know
statute says everything has to be in a
resealable child-resistant
tamper-evident
it's in one sentence and it says
cannabis and cannabis products and so
that means everything from seeds to
clones and and the seeds and clones I
would say was a very interesting
question because that's what statute
says CDP H doesn't address it you
California to DFA doesn't address it and
so you know we are erring on the side of
caution because we're like well I the
bureau is the one inspecting us not DPH
so we're just going to go as far
conservative as we possibly can and then
and that's what I mean the staff kind of
they're frustrated with me too because
that's sort of how I go I'm like we're
gonna ease up as we realize that we can
but we're just gonna start with the
strictest interpretation but yeah so
sort of the the crossover areas and
addressing those and and who has you
know what are you guys looking for when
you're coming in to inspect the
dispensary when it comes to packaging
and labeling stuff like that I would as
a lawyer kind of shift towards you know
when statutes are interpreted greatly
for the business community by case law
and in case law and forms and different
fact in our scenarios how one would
behave the IRS uses decisional memos I
think that it might not be a bad idea to
do something like decisional memos that
have an expiry date on them so that the
statute says they change those decisions
kind of become but it really helped us
out a lot while we're really the
frontline I mean if we fail state fails
right so it helps us out in defining how
we should go and and I would absolutely
agree one body to making those decision
itself
working with CD pH or working with the
other departments to come up with a
decisional memo that is consonant across
the board so that we can make a decision
for example if I have a cultivation
license can I can i package for somebody
kind of package somebody else's flour or
just off of my farm like it's really not
clear right so and it doesn't have to be
clear and we don't have to wait for
regulators to make that decision but I
think in the interim if the bureau could
just make a decision for right now for
the rest of the
here our interpretation is that would be
acceptable that allows us to mount this
effort without the constant fear that
we're gonna get you know Thor's hammer
on our back and so there's a lot of that
fear of how to move and and if we could
have some clearance on that it's kind of
like an FAQ but it's a little bit more
formal right so so just an idea to throw
out there I think it's been great the
way that the agencies are willing to
travel around the state to listen to all
of us during the public comments and I
think it would be you know there's out
there's a huge cross-section of
companies some which have staffed up to
have policy professionals focusing on
the regs on a daily basis and then
there's companies that don't have that
resource and and they utilize their
industry associations or word of mouth
or you know call the bureau up but it
would I think it'd be great if there
could be ongoing opportunities for the
agencies to in different parts of the
state have workshops that are designed
to focus on their regs and clarify and
educate and I think that probably you
would get a lot of participation there's
a lot of hungry minds
I know it's it might open a new can of
worms if one answer at one venue is
different than another answer at another
venue so obviously not a perfect
solution but I think there's a lot of
people that be interested to come in
here and learn this is what we mean when
we say this so I completely agree with
you it can be frustrating for us just
asked our communication guys on when
people don't when they call and say what
agency do we go to or for us it does get
frustrating because it does even even
internally it's difficult to work with
two other agencies and come to decisions
and and being consistent also it's you
know like you noted we do want to do
more outreach but we're also dealing
with new staff coming on every day and
it's hard to keep them
prized okay these are the these are the
regulations that are in place right now
and and so we struggle with making sure
that we're giving consistent answers and
you're not getting different answers and
I think you'll see once we get our final
regulations it's going to make a lot
easier we don't have the emergency
regulations the proposed and all that so
this is all really very helpful you know
I I could I could keep interrogating
these guys more but I think you guys
want to answer some question questions
of them but I do want to point out that
we did get approval our budget got
approved to have a public awareness
campaign we are going out to bid so we
are gonna get out there and start having
a campaign to inform consumers of who's
licensed the importance of going to a
licensed retailer and also trying to
bring more people from the unlicensed
market into the regulated market so
that'll be something exciting you're
gonna see from our communications team
so we're looking forward to that but
this has been extremely helpful to me
and I really appreciate you guys being
so candid with your answers so I'm gonna
leave it to Peter - all right so we have
a question from the back row yeah Doug
Ryerson small business owner this might
be a three-part question and anybody can
answer it up there but Lori you might
have the best answer we'll see so ppm
levels acceptable at this time of
concentrations the labs at this point
they figure they're safe but are they
really up to FDA standards to federal
standards and pharmacists
pharmacological balance and safety
that's the first one second one is
labeling and packaging wisent Walgreens
and CVS and Safeway gonna take this over
once the feds get a hold of it and it's
going to be in the right packaging it's
going to be you know they're gonna tell
you how to take it you have any
questions when you come up to the store
so constellation and canner grow in
Canada just known like 30% of the market
in Canada they're on the stock market
now
so a lot of these small businesses are
gonna be struggling I'll take a crack at
the FDA component so the FDA has two
pathways to approval right there is the
new drug application and then there's a
botanical drug application pathways
they're both hugely expensive and the
variances that those products can hold
through those approvals are are very low
right so when dealing with a botanical
material which cannabis is the variance
from crop to crop which makes a variance
from product to product tends to be
generally well outside of the range of
what the FDA is going to approve so as
the FDA has drugs or botanical products
that come through their pathway those
products will be FDA approved but what
we have right now is a botanical
cannabis program which is similar more
similar to say our traditional botanical
program for nutriceuticals and single
herbal products on the marketplace and
so I would expect in the long run to see
kind of a similar unfolding right as as
the FDA changes in federal regulations
change and we move into prescribed
cannabis marketplace right CBD will
probably still also have a botanical
whole plant product available even after
FDA products are approved I mean this is
well look at green tea there are there
are very few botanical products that
have come through the pathway there's I
think three today one of them is a green
tea product and I think there's there's
two more that have come through that
botanical product pathway it's a very
rigorous and expensive pathway a lot of
botanical products choose not to utilize
that pathway so I think what we'll still
remember will remain to see is cannabis
as a botanical product and then cannabis
probably move into also an FDA regulated
product so when it comes to safety of
the products and we talk about things
like contaminants like residual solvent
and pesticides
when you see the action limits that are
in the regulations that that we're
currently adhering to they're based on
other other standards that exist so
there's the international harmonized
standards around pharmaceuticals that
have action levels for residual solvents
what California has specified is is in
line with those things in some cases it
may be more stringent in some cases a
little bit less but they're in the same
neighborhood so to speak and when you
look at things like action limits on
residual solvents you know they were
based on the data that's available in
terms of the exposure that workers who
work in environments where those
solvents exist in their working
environment what they can be exposed to
on a sustained basis say in a part per
million level so they want to actually
fact-based standards to say what should
we pull from to make actual limits and
I'd say if you if you read the initial
text around the regulations the
explanation of the regulations and the
justification for how the action limits
were set there was quite a bit of work
and thought and care put into what those
action limits should be on based on
other regulated industries and standards
thank you yeah I'll respond you're good
your cannabis growth can't comment so I
kind of look at that in two ways one one
thing I know for sure about this country
is while there's social justice issues
compassion care issues nothing moves the
needle more than missing out on the
global market opportunity so I expect
that investment to be a big needle mover
in the federal government's position and
that may be a bad thing considering your
packaging question right now are we
going to be suddenly is it going to be
Walgreens
so I'll say this and this is not my idea
that's an idea that I just subscribed to
and that is that cannabis its core is a
connoisseur product aspirin is not you
know beer wasn't until craft beer came
around and now there's this very healthy
craft beer market same with wines and
there's a lot of young upstarts you know
ballast point at one time was just you
know a couple of folks that just had the
motto go get
yeah and they had they have built the
lionheart that that we all love so much
about cannabis people is that we're
entrepreneurs and we're aggressive
lone-wolf go-getters you know and so as
that lone wolf piece starts to fall off
that that go-getter something and this
is gonna stay there and I expect that if
we can do a good job of educating
consumers at the retail level and doing
things like allowing consumers to try
topicals at the retail stand right
something like that that's kind of an
ambassadorship into some normality I
think we can really encourage people to
start to participate and buy into that
connoisseurship I think it's always
going to be something as long as we
celebrate it and don't fall into
marketing just Walgreens style products
I think we can have a very healthy
market and at the same time to Kristin's
point there's always get up at the other
side of it there's nothing we can do
about that
since the industry is mirroring
different industry that we're all aware
of I eat tobacco alcohol I would love to
see one thing as a new person in the
reduction of manufacturing business now
give us a license and if we're bad
characters penalize us but like every
other licensing within those structures
let us get it and have it I don't like
the one-year mark I don't want to see a
five year mark I'd like to see an
infinitum licensing that we're receiving
until we prove otherwise and I don't
know it's it's not been done in any
other states but we should be taking the
Presidents on that because it is a
medicine and it certainly has a very
important place so the one-year mark is
just not satisfactory for some of us
that are looking at this long term and
we should really have that opportunity
as well the second position that we are
wanting to take is the plastic industry
I mean it is a medicine first and
foremost so here we are all drinking our
water out of our plastic right now we're
putting our medicine in plastic which
has been done a lot of contributors to
cancer and other illnesses and
conditions but we are not only creating
an unknown factor by putting our
medicine in that packaging but now we're
adding to an environmental concern with
all the waste factors are the level of
the plastics so it just keeps
compounding and we'd like to see
this industry taken a position in being
environmentally sound in reducing all
the amount of environmental waste that
we're contributing to and again we just
don't know what the long-term effects
are of those packaging principles and
I'd like to see some consideration of
wastes long term and not provoking
anything that could be conditional down
the road okay anyone else all right
actually you can just use that mic yeah
I have a question and a comment
I very much appreciate everyone that's
been here Laurie I've been following you
from day one and appreciate everything
you've done
I traveled from Long Beach today to be
here to actually have some concrete
answers to some of the questions about
I'm a manufacturer about packaging about
child resistant about this and I feel
like I attended another political City
Council
conversation about no concrete answers
when are we gonna get concrete answers
about this is what packaging needs to be
this is what compliance needs to be this
is what lab testing needs to be this is
what happens inside a box this is what
happens at the retail level this is our
lab testing at micro dosing we need
concrete answers or business owners that
are suffering significantly because
these decisions are not being made so
our are the bureau's public comment
period ended on Monday and we're still
going I think we're up over 3,000
comments so there is no concrete answers
other than the current regulations that
are in place those are your that is what
you have to abide by right now so over
the next probably few weeks we have to
respond to each and every public comment
that came in that has to be part of our
final rulemaking package we are then
gonna probably I'm I'm I'm positive the
Bureau is going to be making changes
their regs I can't I can't speak for CD
pH and see DFA but I believe all three
of us are going to be making changes
based on those comments and then we have
to go out we have to draft new
regulations for those changes and we go
out for another comment period that is
the California rulemaking process that
comment period could be 15 days or 45
days and guess what it starts all over
again
we get that comment and then at that
point we have to meet our deadline of I
believe it's December 6 to get the final
regulations in place so the rulemaking
process is a very arduous process I
think it can be frustrating because
people want answers right now and the
only thing we can tell them is what's
currently in the emergency regulation
package but it's also a very transparent
process and it has a lot of public
feedback which is good because we're not
doing anything you know behind closed
doors if we make changes we have to go
out for another comment and and we can't
make those final decisions until we do
that an additional comment period and
then change again so I think it is
frustrating believe me as
regulator we want this process to be
over as much as you do I mean we're just
constantly doing this I were tired of it
we want to just have the answers to
every time we do fa Q's it changes every
time we put out some fact sheet it
changes a couple months later because
we've changed it again but I'll tell you
this as regulators the reason we keep
changing is because we keep getting more
data more information and we're trying
to do things better not trying to make
it worse for you we're trying to make it
better so that's the process we have
right now and so again it's it's I want
to add something to this is we are all
learning right now literally the
industry the regulators I mean the cart
is way ahead of the horse in terms of
California cannabis industry and moving
it into the regulations and you that I
think the businesses and the operators
that are that have been around for a
while and that will you know the new
ones that will continue to stay around
have to realize that adaptability and
flexibility is critical to survival in
this industry in this day and age and
just making sure that you're always on
your toes and and that there aren't I
mean they're literally as you said where
we're following a map but we kind of
have blinders on because we don't really
know what the end is going to look like
but we we know what our overall ultimate
goal is and we know that we're gonna get
there but there I I think there there
should be a little bit of room for for
understanding for everybody for for all
of the the supply chain and for the
regulators and just we're all kind of
moving this horse together
it is a multi-billion dollar industry
and and we're trying to plug this in
backwards so it's not gonna be and I'd
love to jump in here too just because I
absolutely feel your pain
you know I trying to educate my company
to the same points that yes you remember
emergency rigs 1.0 we rolled those up
and threw those away then we had
emergency regs 2.0 and that's what we're
living by right now even though all the
attention is on the proposed regs which
were going through
just wrapped up our public comment
period but that aside it's also an
important lesson I think for us to
realize and we learn this on July 1st
which is that depending on your position
in the supply chain
there's state regs and those matter a
lot but how your business partner next
in the supply chain interprets those
regs those are the real rags that's
right because whatever Sabrina says is
what they require for packaging it
doesn't matter what I think
you know the BCC says about packaging
it's what she says about packaging
because otherwise she's not taking my
product and I think that's that's that
is the most challenging part of all
because that shifts all over the place
well respect our issue is all of those
things you've said but also BCC says
something different than CD pH and this
one wants it inside the box this one
wants it inside the box and outside the
box and they're conflicting and they're
all state regulatory agencies it's not
fair to us as small businesses or even
big businesses to we've seen it in
Colorado where they have to retool and
they have to redo this because the
agencies can't play together this is
what I expected from this meeting
tonight
I expected the public comment to all
come together and this is what we're
gonna do we need this percent variance
on testing we need this on the inside of
the packaging we now can have CBD but we
have to put it on the front of our
packaging what's the resolution to that
we'll take one more question for this
panel and then we have an entire new
panel after this so good evening Sean
Kelly rice oh look in Valley cannabis
Alliance thank you all for your
attendance here a question for Lori
we've had a lot of success in just
calling your office and interacting with
you directly and getting an answer so
anyone that who who has who has
questions call the BCC it you you will
get an answer someone there will give
you an answer and you can actually move
forward so we've not had that problem
I'm on the front line the Silicon Valley
cannabis lines is on the front line
without what we do
none of these suppliers matter we're
trying to get more and more retail in
these cities right now Silicon Valley
only has San Jose it's 105 million
dollar market but Milpitas is coming
mountain view is coming
the city of Santa Clara is coming Josh
Morgan Hill is coming there's a number
of other cities there looking at it I'm
the only person going out there
advocating talking to lobbying these
folks and and and they're great
politicians and elected officials to
talk to can you provide someone that can
go and give a counterpoint to what I say
because when I go in there they're like
oh great this is wonderful Sean you get
paid by the industry who else can we
talk to that from the BCC sometimes I'm
lucky I do actually right behind you
right there Andre Jones our governmental
affairs he's a one-man show going to all
the cities and counties across the state
that's what we need you do honestly I
mean that that would be so so helpful
I'm going to San Carlos and gonna talk
to the rotary and they hear my side of
it and they know what I'm gonna say but
they would love to have someone like
this I would love to have a resource to
grab to go to all these cities and say
here talk to the other side talk to the
state talk to someone that's other than
someone who's getting paid and get the
counterpoint see how well retailers are
actually really doing that there it's
not chaos it's not mayhem you know it's
not alcohol it's it's going pretty well
well in another thing too we also are
developing we know there's needs to be a
lot more education at the local level
it's just not consumer it's just not our
licensee it's also at the local level
we're at establishing a unit a local
liaison unit so we're gonna hire 10
analysts that that's their jobs to talk
to the cities and be that resource
because they also want a single point of
contact now of course we got to hire the
people first and train them so
it's not coming next week but that's
also going to assist you so you can
direct them to a certain person in that
region from the VCC that can help them
out and even forms like this that are
designed specifically for politicians
we had one July 11th at the San Jose
rotunda we ended up getting council
members from Santa Clara Council members
from Milpitas other council members that
actually showed up and we're they're
interested because they want to hear
from all the politicians that we had
politicians come down from Antioch and
it was fantastic so even forums like
this that are maybe not designed for the
industry but designed for the
politicians so they feel in that safe
environment that they can get some of
that feedback because it really helps us
get more retail because that's really
you know it storefront and delivery
because we're woefully you know lacking
in delivery also so can I thank you I
would love to respond to your question
as well real quick because I feel like
this is you know take a an average 50
year old adult that things that they're
healthy and until they go to the doctor
and get a diagnosis that says we
measured your you know your LDLs in your
blood and you have really high chance of
of a heart attack you need to change
your behavior until you can do that
they're thinking they're healthy and I
feel like the same thing is going on in
these communities that think you know
we're not gonna deal with the regulated
market we don't want to touch that right
now but we're also not gonna admit to
ourselves that we have an illicit market
that's going on as well there needs to
be a way to measure what's going on in
communities so that we can point at that
and say here's your illicit market it's
this big it's this valuable and you're
missing out on this much job creation
tax revenue this is this is the amount
of product that is moving through your
illicit market that is untested and and
who knows where it goes to if we can
measure that and begin to have that
information to present to communities
and say this is your this is your status
we would encourage you to move to the
regulated market and improve the health
of your community I think it would be
hugely helpful to
work that you do and and let me just say
that I salute the work that you do
because you're absolutely right without
more retail throughout the state and the
two thirds of the state that has no
retail what we have is we have an
illicit market that we don't know how
big it is but it's pretty healthy I can
tell you that it's a it's a big healthy
illicit market thank you
all right and I would like to thank our
panel we have one more panel after this
let's take a five-minute break and I
also like to thank Lori aids accent yeah
Lori you're a sport tonight thank you I
can't even imagine I don't envy your
position
thank you for working with all of us
[Music]