[Music]
we're going to be taking a look at root
systems in California substrates Koya
Koya and one of the things first we're
going to see is that this particular pot
here will have quite a bit of a master
root on that part and if we go to the
other side
much less that's because in this
particular instance we had a dripper
that was pretty much only on one side
and if we take a look at this one I
believe here we look at it and the root
system is much more even all the way
around and it's not like we had a lot of
different drippers in there is basically
just two one on each side so the
distribution of water was more
completely even in the nutrient system
now what we're going to do is we're
going to take one of these pots and cut
it open we have a machete here because
we're gonna find that the root system
throughout the whole pot is relatively
even you can see yeah I'm in the mother
we're gonna try the saw bit just to get
through this one bit of a root I think
there we're through down to the bottom
and if we can look on here we've got
fine roots sitting all through the
middle of the pot they haven't gone sent
out big roots right to the outside the
edge and wrapped all the way around
we've got just a fine network of roots
around there and that is because the
coiour has such a good air fill porosity
in it and the other thing that it has is
a very it distributes the water very
well it absorbs and move sideways so you
get a reasonably equal amount of water
all the way around it and you have the
roots growing through the inside because
it has that good air
fill porosity I'm happy with this one I
think this is yeah it's got a it's got a
nice look to it you could grow a lot
longer in this because the the root
system certainly has a great deal more
air or room that it could be using in
there and through the middle it would
get thicker I've seen plants that have
grown in a pot a couple of years because
I used to grow roses and you'd have them
in there the root system so thick you
could just barely stick a watering pick
into the media the plants will continue
to grow and have roots and not really
look to go anywhere else as long as you
are providing the amount of water and
nutrients they that they want right
where their root system is and it will
grow that dense if you allow it if we
look at using coiour
versus soil soil the variabilities in
soil are well they're quite there's
quite a bit of it whether there is in
core also though the soil having
micronutrients in it and different
things is is a difficulty because you
never know exactly what you have and
what's going to be available you have
more organics more different chemicals I
guess you'd say it's not really
chemicals as we think of them because
usually think then of manmade chemicals
but these are natural chemicals that
appear in this soil and they will
interfere with the way different
nutrients are available to the plant
when you get into coiour most coiour is
not or shouldn't say most players not
buffered i was gonna say a lot of it is
but if you get it that corner that isn't
buffered the and as a very large can I
exchange capacity very heavily loaded
with sodium and potassium and when you
first start feeding this plant your
nutrients is going to
the the koi is going to start using the
calcium-magnesium on on the exchange
sites or draw it on to the exchange
sites where this potassium and sodium is
and as it attaches the calcium and
magnesium it will kick off the potassium
and sodium and your you nutrients become
out of balance
now potassium is not too bad although
when you get too much potassium it then
tends to inhibit the uptake of other
positive ions such as your calcium
magnesium iron a lot of your nutrients
are on the positive side sodium is the
other thing that gets kicked off of the
the counting exchange capacity it can
actually be quite detrimental to growth
of plants even as low as 12 parts per
million different plants different
species are have different tolerances
for it that's why if you get into a koi
that has been buffered then you get into
something that has already begun to
exchange or change the kind of exchange
capacity getting rid of the potassium
and sodium and already having attached
to calcium and magnesium this will give
you a coiler that has less of a problem
changing your doesn't change your
nutrient system so much however most of
the coiours that have anacs-- that have
been buffered are not buffered
completely they leave a really quite a
large amount of the potassium sodium on
the exchange sites what they will do is
oftentimes in the last part of their
processing give it a huge hit of calcium
nitrate it's a very short period of time
10-15 minutes and then it's washed out
and then dried and packaged California
substrates uses a much longer method of
buffering their product and using a
heavier dose of magnesium and
calcium to do that so we bring the can
exchange capacity much more fully loaded
with calcium magnesium very little
potassium to be kicked off by your
nutrient system very little sodium and
and because we have done it that far
usually it won't won't interfere with
your nutrient system at all other
nutrients that are your you are
providing the plant when looking at
different types of coiour
that you might buy there's quite a range
in prices that you can get not all cheap
koi is cheap and nasty not all the hop
top-end or top price koi is ultimately
good if you need to ultimately all that
worth it what you need to do is know a
bit about what you're looking for
inquire the cheapest of them is going to
probably come without a buffering and
possibly at this stage even without any
washing the EC is going to be 2 or
higher you won't notice anything about
the buffering and until you start to
feed it and then you're gonna notice
that you're gonna run out of calcium
magnesium your plants are going to be
work very poorly they may turn yellow
and and virtually just die in California
substrate score it has a it has been
buffered we have a about 80 90 percent
of the fines have been taken out of it
so that as we looked at this air this
root system that we head down here and
we got the roots all the way through it
that's because we've taken a lot of the
fine material out of the core and you
continue to get a airspace throughout
the whole root ball and so the the plant
can use the whole of the root ball if
you don't have that oftentimes what you
find is you got this root mass and it's
just winding around the outside and it
doesn't really matter how much is he on
the inside it's just not using it
there's no air space in there the roots
need air as much as they do water you
always hear about people saying
something was over watered
having too much water is not so much of
a problem not having enough air is more
so that's they say too much water it's
not enough air and that's where that
comes from that's where that that will
go down to when you're out there looking
for a core you ask a few questions in
some of the very good things about it
there's the fuel amount that have taken
the finer material out of there not many
um they don't do it because it costs
quite a bit to the manufacturer to do
that it takes out maybe 20% of the
volume of the core so right at the
beginning it's it's it costs whoever it
is that's making it 20% more because
they get 20% less - to sell the next
thing is going to be the buffering
process that they use you'll hear a lot
of things about which is better one way
or another trial and side by side side
by side test so the one thing that will
tell you we say doesn't need cal-mag in
in our growing media and we've had many
people try it and grow it that way and
it it actually does not need to have any
a kalmec do a side by side where was
there was a the quality a coiour
can make such a difference in the way
your growth proceeds and you may not if
everything works just the way you're
supposed to just the way your the way
you've planned it to do then you
everything will work out and your plants
will come through and they'll grow what
seems to be the best you could have done
we all have mistakes we all have things
that happen to us is you forgot to do
one thing or another or the wind came
through and blew something over or
electricity went out for you know a
couple hours and enough that something
didn't happen that's when you begin to
know the difference between a better
quality and a less quality the run is
side by side we had one happen where we
had
two rows of plants one in California
substrates one in the local local
best-selling core that was in the area
going through it there was an incident
that happened with the new the nutrient
system and at the end of it we had the
California substrates coiler
all of the plants were sitting there
they were looking happy in the opposing
coiour
there were 50% dead they looked yellow
they looked weak they just brown and
just laying over and it Sun tell you he
run into one of those instances before
that you may think yes everything is
going well if you do a side by side
everything works just the way it's
supposed to you're still going to notice
a difference in a better quality or
coiour it will let your plants grow more
to their fullest capabilities the the
mistakes that happen they will they will
point out the difference between failing
and growing but it's when everything
works and when you do a side by side
then you begin to see the actual quality
and what the coiour will do because a
good quality coil should allow that
plant to outperform a poor quality choir
no matter what the growing conditions
are what happens during the whole cycle
of growing that's why we say with
California substrates feed your weed not
your cocoa give the plants what they
need have a cocoa that allows the plant
to use what you're giving them and not
to be adjusting it because the cocoa
needs the calcium magnesium how I got
into using cocoa and working with cocoa
I started out growing I grew roses first
in in in soil vinaigrette in a bed the
bed was prepared it was it was they were
growing well because we had dug a trench
in the ground we put a tile in the
bottom we put sand over the top P rock
over the top of that then a prepared
soil over that we got the drainage one
we got everything that we wanted in the
proper ways and we thought we were doing
quite well then we went into hydroponics
using cocoa using rockwool and
immediately we came out of this came out
of the ground immediately we didn't
change anything else we got a 20% 25%
change in production and we kept numbers
on this week specific numbers by variety
of roses and we saw the the difference
in growth right away then when they
started were first started working with
cocoa it was kind of the oldest cheapest
nastiest stuff you can find around these
days and we were growing in in using it
it's still outperformed soil we we began
taking water samples and we would take a
water sample of the the drain water
coming out of these every week and we
would send it in and have it examined we
began to notice that the calcium that we
were feeding was at about 200 parts per
million what was coming out was less
than 10 parts per million of calcium so
what we did was we up the calcium by
about 50 percent so we went up to 300
and no difference in the change in the
amount of calcium that was coming
through the core in the drain water and
we went up to another think we doubled
it after that so it would have been up
about about 600 and I say I think
because this was 15 years ago or
something like that and and not
everything is remembered exactly but so
we did the extra calcium again and still
got no difference in the the drainage it
might have went from 10 to 15 percent
but essentially nothing and that went on
for about six months
shortly after that I we began looking at
different ways we could treat koi and
then I left the employment of a
a rose range and went to work for a
courier company and we began looking at
how we could treat coiour
go to the going into Sri Lanka and India
looking at how they made this stuff how
they process this and and gradually
began working with saving materials so
we brought out different grades of
products at that time we were we were
working not necessarily a use core only
but mixing with perlite and having
something that was more open and so we
had a grade that we call the three to
six and it was everything that was three
mils and under had been saved out and
everything six mils and over had been
saved out as a drawing material made a
very nice thing it actually was a little
bit too much on the dry side but it was
through these processes of working out
different different grades of coiours
and what could be done with them and
then also working on adding the
different nutrients into the system
while we were in the country of origin
that we be that we fell into enough fell
into it because it was actually a
process of thinking about and and
running testing and seeing how how it
could be down and how long it would take
so I've been working with koi or in
trying to perfect the way to do it for
10 15 years started back in in probably
1996 didn't really start working with an
acquire company until about 2000 2001
and we've been working on improving koi
or since at California substrates we
believe that the continually improving
coiour we believe also that what we need
to do is take out the things that are
not good for their growth or not
positive in the in the koi or taking out
the fines correcting the the can't
exchange capacity by getting rid of the
potassium and the sodium so that you as
a grower don't have to correct those
deficiencies in the coiour we also
believe that there are going to be
more things that we will have to improve
coiour and it will get better it's a
it's a process of continual improvement
perlite perlite is a a mix in your cocoa
the if you have treated if the cocoa has
been treated properly and come to you
you shouldn't need anything and
California substrates were quite adamant
the fact that you don't need perlite you
need hydro town or any other thing else
added as far as it's giving you air
space if you use perlite you'll notice
that the roots within your your growing
media will tend to migrate to where
there is air but in general where
there's air when you're adding perlite
or other things that add air air field
to your media you don't find nutrient
there if you look again in our in our
root ball
we don't have perlite or anything into
there but we've got root system
everywhere through there that's because
there's air and nutrients there if you
have poor lighting there you're gonna
find the roots are going to come to the
outside because there's air they're very
minimal nutrient because it only then
has the nutrient on the inside the
outside of course is where the pot is
and there's no nutrient out there if you
you would also find that if you had
perlite through there the roots the fine
roots were most year nutrient is being
uptake up taken especially the micro
nutrients the fine roots are going to
gravitate toward where the perlite is
again no nutrient there there's going to
be air there but no nutrient and so you
will find the plant the roots get to
there and there's nothing they can do
except to go back out into the into the
void where the air the air isn't and so
they have to struggle and using coiour
it it works in all all situations we
have indoor growers with computers and
everything around them to keep
everything just the way the grower wants
it to an outdoor grow where we're out
open to the Sun we're growing
nice looking weed got nice sized buds on
it using California substrates coiour
these particular ones are in three
gallon pots the three gallon pots will
grow a very nice plant and it can be
quite large we find that outdoor is it's
a little bit top-heavy if we have a
system of supporting the tops of the the
plants they can remain upright and have
have less problems but we're thinking
maybe the the thing to do is going to be
some larger pot so they they don't get
quite so top-heavy the other would be to
put a stake along them to tie them down
so they can't go anywhere so there are
there are methods to to helping
difficulty like that but it is a very
usable media in in pretty much any type
of a setting if you're under lights in a
in a in a a warehouse or in a plastic
structure it can do whatever you want to
do it can grow as big a plant as you
want the size of the pot is not any any
restriction on how big the plant can get
how big the plant can get is really
based upon how you provide nutrients and
how you provide the water that the plant
needs if you can provide nutrients in
water in short bursts all day long you
could grow a an 8 10 foot plant in a one
gallon pot but the you would have to be
supplying water as quickly as that plant
is using it and you have less and less
of a buffer system so that when the
water is done how long before the water
and nutrient is being is used up the
bigger the pot you have the bigger the
buffer system you have for that plant to
get through an oops thing lack of water
something happens you get you can't get
the water to them Adam
when when they need to electricity goes
out one of the things that comes to mind
[Music]