the state was wonderful enough to give
me my permit on July 11 yeah it was like
wow thanks I had it I had my application
in in November I gave up I was this like
okay yeah so you know this this year or
last year was our first year out there
we had started the whole process in
November of the year before we got
dragged through the mud and hemmed and
hawed you didn't get one cycle of it
yeah yeah I did but going in the ground
on July 13th was you know two and a half
months late and I mean I had given up
like okay it's not happening this year
great I open up my mailbox it's like
this is wonderful this is wonderful this
is so exciting but wow what do I do now
you know I have an order dirt I haven't
you know so how many cycles do you
typically have a year so this year we
did not do any light that situation
Santa Barbara you know didn't allow it
this year so we just applied for an
outdoor permit you know canopy permit
and then they issued my permit on July
11 and then they came out with a new
regulation that outdoor if we did light
death that we had to apply for a
mixed-use permit as if we had
supplemental life
you know it's just like just because
we're manipulating the time cycle with
another black cloth you're requiring me
to have a completely different permit
Wow you know great thank you like
another way for them to make money off
you exactly exactly and you know Santa
Barbara has just been robbed they've
been really rough to deal with us as
have every other county here in the
nation I mean I would so in the next
nine days 3,500 grow permits are going
to expire statewide 3,500 of people who
have been under temporary and they have
no intention of issuing new temporary so
it's gonna be really interesting to see
what happens in nine days yeah which is
when we all want to be planning yeah do
you have any advocates in Sacramento
they're gonna help we yeah we do but you
know it's like the blind leading the
blind yeah
and they have no intention of issuing
you know we're on it every day of
issuing new temporaries
are they trying to just stop it yep
they're using regulation to shut it down
and there's no path forward this is
gonna be an interesting year no the last
two years have been interesting years
well Santa Barbara is not unique in any
way shape or form no they were the most
lenient in giving out temporary permits
I mean they handed out a lot but now
they've gotten Fish and Game Coastal
Commission you know
EPA everybody else involved you know and
none of them know what to do with each
other
our our big holdup out there I call it
the catch 420 we applied to get a power
drop you know for for the field we paid
that seven thousand dollars to to the
power company they but it's on their
schedule then they came to us and said
we can't drop your transformer till you
have your land use permit in place
well then Santa Barbara came and they're
like well we can't issue your land use
permit till you have your security
cameras up and right well you explain to
me how we install security cameras and
make them up and running when we have no
power and you won't even tell us where
you're gonna put the transformer on the
property so we can't temporarily run the
power we can't do anything to that
location and then the Fish and Game is
coming and saying well you know we can
we can't issue and we can't sign off on
your land use permit until the power
company is strong
the power and you have your security
system in place so none of them will
sign the document or be the first one to
say hey you need a land use permit which
we've already been up and running we
already got a state permit we already
got a County permit but now they want
this permit further we have to have the
Indian consul come out do an
archaeological dig on the property to
make sure it wasn't some ancient hunting
ground or ancient burial ground and we
have to pay them fifteen thousand
dollars to bring their experts out to do
this day before Fish and Game won't sign
off so it's the catch 420 they're like
yeah you sure you can do it we're gonna
create a great regulatory process where
this is going to be successful but we're
gonna make every agency out there have
the power to tell you go jump in a lake
yeah do you have a temporary for it
that's an expired a days we have a
temporary permit that expires in nine
days with no permit to give you not in
any way shape or form it's the blind
leading the blind is that the same for
him this hemp have a more likely
scenario to move forward well no no
because they put the Department of
Agriculture in charge of that one and
they were supposed to have their
regulations out but they are nowhere
close so you know we're all prepped and
ready to plant
we actually cracked seeds you know we're
all ready and even that doesn't have a
legal path power in the state of
California the farm the you know they're
supposed to have their regulations done
supposedly by July 1st
they're not even close they're not even
close
so my confidence means that n with a
category three testing we're gonna have
a lack of supply in the market it's
gonna certainly affect that oversupply
problem oh yeah I mean there's a reason
that Rupert where it's booming right now
exactly exactly
there's a reason that you're Mitch but
even the traditional market there's a
lack supply out there right now right
now it's just like back in Paris and
distributors are becoming much nicer to
farmers oh yeah oh yeah and it was for a
long time farmers were just getting
raped you know I mean rate there I have
no other word for it