[Music]
I'm Courtney Freeman and I spent the
last year working on packaging I was
part of the first wave of businesses to
bring lab tested compliant packaging to
market and it was brutal
so I've been through it and I've asked
the hard questions and we put together a
panel here today to try to dig in and
get some more solutions the requirements
for packaging have a universal ID I
shared this little card with many of you
there is a download for top ten
highlights so that you don't have to
take notes on everything I say I'm gonna
go over a few details I ran through my
presentation with somebody and I
discovered that not everybody knows what
tamper-evident packaging is so just just
for heads up guys if you go to the
market everything at the market has
temper evident packaging it means that
you know if somebody has tampered with
your product that's an important element
it is currently very common to be a heat
wrapped plastic it's not necessary we
can use paper so one of the things we're
gonna be talking about here today is is
what inspired me to kind of prompt this
conversation there are many ways to
approach packaging and in this day and
age we've got some serious issues with
the amount of waste that we're creating
has anybody seen the headlines about
China no longer accepting our recycling
anyone yeah okay so do you all know that
we have 11 years before we run out of
our recycling landfills for the
Northeast here in the United States
11 years that's it here in California we
got a little bit more time we're looking
at about 22 years but there are some
simple steps we can take like rinsing
and probably sorting sorting or
recycling for example so that's one of
the issues that prompted this the other
is small businesses
I'm a small business and it can be quite
exorbitant to pay for the patents and
all the testing that goes into child
resistant packaging so we're looking at
how we can create solutions for
businesses as well because um if we're
gonna make it we need all the help we
can get and we're gonna do it together
so this is part of my initiative to
bring a greater sense of community come
together child resistant packaging
h-hour resistant package is one that is
designed or constructed to be
significantly difficult for children
under five to open or obtain a harmful
amount of the contents within a
reasonable amount of time in addition
the package must not be difficult for
normal adults to use properly now I
don't know if you all have seen this
these creative boxes totally adult proof
totally adult proof I spent hours
someone had to show me really
complicated but I'm showing you some
examples of packaging here today it's
really important how these solutions and
that one in particular I spoke with an
attorney I thought if you just had to
use two hands that was child resistant
it's not there's a lot of testing that
goes into it and we're gonna we're gonna
talk about that in a minute
another important issue when addressing
your packaging primary versus
informational panel the primary panel is
the front of the box or package it's
what you will most likely see when you
are in their retail environment the
informational panel is the rest of the
package it's informational the
government warning is there for example
which is quite important but that's
worth noting for those of you who are
not familiar with packaging compliance
all right packaging guidelines one you
may not use cartoons or anything that's
appealing to children this is important
we can look at the tobacco industry as
an example of why we wouldn't want to do
that I think that we all here are
individuals who are you know building
something beautiful with this industry
our intention is not to market to
children but we need to be really clear
about that and unfortunately animations
or
something that potentially can be
misconstrued as marketing to children
THC content specifically delta-9 needs
to be outlined on your packaging
additional in addition CBD so if you
have other types of cannabinoids THC a
for example I you may not want to put it
on the front package the primary panel
because there's going to be testing and
if you have a deviance of more than 10%
that means you could have issues and
you'd have to redo your packaging so
keep that in mind obviously in terms of
poison control we want to know how much
THC is in the package it needs to be
consistent and there's a reason for that
but it's worth noting and just for our
industry players that something could
save you a lot of headache 3 you must
use a minimum of a 6 point font now it
may not seem like a big deal but when
you're trying to cram all this detail
onto your tiny box it's difficult so
just be mindful of that and the
universal symbol that we discussed I'm
going to show you an example here this
is a beautiful brand from Amsterdam this
is outdated packaging this one right
here and you'll see that there's an
exclamation point it says THC alerting
you to teach see but that's not
universal people who don't speak English
or don't know about THC aren't gonna
understand that there's THC in the
package and that they should be
cautionary when consuming so keep that
in mind and then here's another package
from Henry's it does have the California
Universal ID a question that's often
asked if you have black packaging what
do you do with this universal symbol the
universal symbol is required to be black
so if need be you can create a white
space around it or some other color or
you can just do maybe a two or three
point maybe a ten point white line
around the universal ID just to define
it that's an easy solution five required
by the FTC you must list the license
manufacturer part of packaging important
details are how do we trace packaging if
there's an issue how do we find out who
made it how
tracked down so we can take it off the
market this one you may or may not be
aware of but it's important to list your
ingredients in order of the volume so if
you go to the grocery store this is
something you'll see that the packaging
is the the most voluminous ingredient is
listed first if there's any allergens
you should include that number 8 for
edibles you'll want to include
nutritional content as well as any
coloring additives similar to other
products that you buy at the market and
then I want to highlight something that
very likely you don't know okay
employees are required to take a food
safety course if they are manufacturing
or creating edibles so that's something
it's in the regulations for o28 zero
training program that's something you
should be aware of it needs to happen
within 90 days of employment number nine
instructions for use such as the method
of consumption or application this one's
a little tough it sounds simple but if
you have if you have concentrate what do
you do with it right there's many
applications but you need to identify
what those applications are on the
packaging ten the product expiration
date they use buy or the best by date
and this is especially important for any
perishable items that are water-based
I'm producing a lotion right now it's
water-based you to be very cautious
about microorganisms or mold so be aware
of that and then we're not there yet
it's coming but the metric ID so once
we're in this seed to seal tracking
we're gonna need to include the metric
ID that the licensed entities will be
issued okay
that's important to note also you know
the reason that we we are so timely with
this conversation is that July 1st is
the deadline for compliant packaging to
you to go through the retail channels
that are laid
since so if you don't have compliant
packaging you've done yourself a great
favor and being here today thank you
twelve if there's more than one serving
then the package must be resealable and
your serving size must be less than ten
milligrams of THC all right now let's
talk about some medicinal
differentiation number thirteen if the
product is intended for medicinal
purposes or contains more than one
thousand milligrams of THC per package
you need to include the statement for
medical use medicinal medical use only
and by the way you should pay attention
to that because you need to be on point
it's not it's not one of the other and
that's for any products that are sold at
the retail a lot of us had concerns
about that because we didn't feel like
there should be these kinds of
restrictions on on medical for those
that are treating cancer for example
might be taking a gram a day and with
this restriction it means that we have a
lot of a lot of smaller packaging little
pieces of packaged plastic that aren't
necessarily value oriented like we would
find in the market and again it does it
does contribute to our waist
okay fourteen the regulations quote a
required government warning that must be
in bold that's the government wine
this is similar to what you have in the
pharmaceutical industry where your
pocket product comes with an insert and
that's something that we can also
leverage if we need extra space here 15
this one is a little tricky California
Prop 65 so for those of you who are
reintroducing terpenes for example beta
Mersin that's something that you need to
identify on the label it's quite
interesting the research i've done
indicates that beta mersin is is part of
solutions for cancer treatment but
according to California's the the
research indicates that when you isolate
Bane immersing similar to when you
isolate cannabinoids like THC I can give
you a headache when you isolate Bane
immersing potentially it can cause
cancer in the lab in the lab results so
something to note prop 65 you're not
gonna find that necessarily in the regs
that's something that you have to really
go through it to find out and 16 finally
let's address state lab testing for
pesticides and microbials
this is not in the regs so if you're not
aware we had an update to our emergency
regulations in May and one of the things
that's changed is the testing
requirements previously you were
required to have a primary sample as
well as a duplicate field sample and now
that the now this has been reduced
previously it was a major expense if you
are not aware of it and you did attempt
to bring a package that was higher
volume to market it meant that when the
field testing samples are taken they
take your product in its final form in
which case you can lose thousands of
dollars to field testing samples and now
that's been resolved so thanks things
for that improvement that's a that's a
nice evolution
[Music]