[Music]
all right so this is a city County
patchwork as was said on the online
little summary the state has figured it
out sort of we just need the local
governments to do their jobs so I'll do
a quick intro I'll let all the panelists
kind of intro themselves a little bit
more I do have one question after you do
your intro just to let the people kind
of know what you do on the day-to-day
and actually my name is ISA Perez I work
at Meadow we're a point-of-sale company
so we build software for dispensaries
and delivery services so we work with
California retailers across the state so
local government local regulation is
very very near and dear to my heart and
brain and soul and I'm here today also
representing supernova women an
organization that is yeah it's
empowering women of color in the
industry and also advocating for social
justice and equity in cannabis so our
first panelists we have ariana Van
Alstyne and she is an attorney with a
lot of expertise with the regulations
and Ariana just give people a little
brief summary of what you do day to day
to do this patchwork on the local level
day to day I do licensing and compliance
for cannabis businesses all over the
state of California mostly working on
local licenses and preparation for state
licenses and then navigating through the
regulations as they change day-to-day
and week-to-week awesome Thank You
Ariana
next we have Jackie McGowan you've
probably heard her already giving some
of the Q&amp;A portions of the other panels
she is director of licensing and
business development at K Street
consulting and Jackie tell us a little
bit about how you do patch work
day-to-day so hi my name is Jackie
McGowan I work for K Street consulting
I'm a local licensing consultant but my
background is I am a former Wall Street
stockbroker
and when I got into this space I
realized that there wasn't a centralized
location for anyone to go to to get
late-breaking news of everything that
was going on throughout the state so I
decided to use my Wall Street background
and create my own news feed and I set up
540 Google email alerts one for every
city in the county run for every city
and county in the state and then I
decided to dump all of that data into a
Facebook group that I first named
California City &amp; County band watch
because at the time this was early 2016
when we dubbed banna Palooza as what was
going on in the industry at the time
I've since changed the name to city and
county regulation Watch and we have
7,000 members that are all California
residents that was really important to
me
to make sure that the conversation being
had was about people that were being
affected by these problems so that we
could come up solutions together its
California residents and we have about
14 moderators that keep that page
frequently being updated with
late-breaking news and we have probably
about 1300 in individual posts that come
through the group each month and our
moderators are making sure that
everybody is being respectful in that
content and if you're not a member of
the group I highly encourage you to join
and I I do run that but I also work at
the local level in several jurisdictions
and have helped cannabis businesses get
their local permits Thank You Jackie yes
definitely join the Facebook group never
a dull moment home next we have a really
exciting mayor of West Hollywood john
duran giving the round of applause this
is his fifth term 18 years on the
council now so mayor tell us a little
bit about your day-to-day patchwork over
in West Hollywood greetings from the
people of the City of West Hollywood
the women are strong and the men are
pretty we're very very proud of that
distinction we have had cannabis on the
Sunset Strip for about a hundred years
100 cannabis has been part of the Sunset
Strip and the nightlife in the City of
West Hollywood for a century and so
we're very proud and happy of
introducing the first ordinance to
actually get into the regulation of
cannabis in our city my mayorship as a
local elected official like most local
electeds it's a part-time gig so I have
a real job in the day I'm a criminal
defense lawyer that's what I do in the
daytime and my practice I've been in
practice for 30 years has been
representing a whole lot of lawbreakers
first act up in queer nation when they
were blocking government buildings to
demand drugs and treatment for HIV and
AIDS then I was the attorney for clean
needles now which was the very first
needle exchange in Southern California
giving clean needles to junkies who we
were afraid we're going to contract HIV
passing around dirty needles and then I
became legal counsel for the Los Angeles
cannabis resource center in the early
90s it was the very first medicinal
marijuana organized facility on the
corner of fountain and Fairfax in the
City of West Hollywood so I've been
doing this a long time first as a
criminal defense lawyer and now as the
man so really happy to be here with all
of you Thank You mayor and and last but
not least we have Charles Harvey
legislative representative for the
League of Cities it's only his third
month in his position so Bravo to you
being here Charles thank you thank you
it's kind of hard to follow a Mayor
Duran that's
in any event good afternoon everyone
charles Harvey with the League of
California cities I am the public safety
lobbyist for for the league my capacity
of my portfolio extends from not just
cannabis but also working issues
relative to police use of force - sorry
I apologize I'm going on about three
hours of sleep I have a one month old
and a 22 month old and so I'm keeping
very very busy at home but you know I'm
very excited to be here I I told I told
everyone on a planning call earlier in
the week or last week that you know my
goal here today really is to sort of you
know be be a sponge and listen directly
to I guess what concerns everyone has
industry participants other folks and
and really sort of you know develop my
own sense of of where the League of
California cities can can sort of can
help to help to solve problems help to
you know find find solutions that work
for everyone
and as previous panelists have have
talked about generally speaking there
isn't anything that necessarily comes
easy on this issue it's a very hot
button issue people get very very
passionate I understand that and so
again I am excited to be here today and
looking forward to a robust discussion
just before we get into the more
specific questions this is about local
government this is about you know city
to city what what is local government
what does that mean to you what who
really holds the power in local
government so if you can talk a little
bit about who actually has the control
and where it comes from those might be
two different answers to the audience
and maybe one you have in your head feel
free to share both but anyone can go
first I think it depends on the
jurisdiction yeah I've been on the
ground in several different areas where
the sheriff you know is the one making
the decisions and calling it his County
I've been in the opposite situation
where the sheriff has
I answer to the Board of Supervisors
I've been in situations where it's clear
that it's the city manager that is
pulling the strings and and then you
know really you follow the money
whoever is supporting the people that
are making the decisions that's really
who's pulling the strings in my opinion
I want to agree with that that's exactly
that's exactly right I was a proponent
of forming a West Hollywood Police
Department's on the ballot in 1991 we
lost but we lost 51% to 49% so we just
lost and when that happened the Los
Angeles County Sheriff called me in and
said what do we need to do to improve
it's a 14 million dollar contract and so
we gave him a list and one of the things
on the list was that the City of West
Hollywood in 2003 declared marijuana
enforcement to be the lowest level
priority for the city of West Hollywood
and the sheriff said well you know I'm
going to publicly oppose you I said care
what you do publicly I just don't want
you arresting people for smoking a joint
on the Sunset Strip
so can we work together here you say
whatever you need to say for your
election but we're not gonna we don't
want any of the 14 million going into
marijuana enforcement you want to
enforce drug law let's go after crystal
meth that is a nasty drug that destroys
people in their lives but leave
marijuana alone and that's been the
state of affairs since then but I I
agree the city manager he is the CEO of
our city most small cities have a city
manager who runs a government but it's
the power of three it's like you know
the three sisters on the TV show charm
you got the power of three you can do
anything and so I'm always trying to
find two other votes
to make significant policy change and
fortunately I'm in a city that leans so
far left where you don't even know right
so I'm the conservative on the council
and I'm the guy doing cannabis reform
that's how far left we go so it's it's
an exception to the rule it's a little
like solid blue dot
in the middle of Los Angeles County but
we get because we are so solidly left we
get to do a lot of progressive stuff and
so that's why we we passed our ordinance
last year removed a wee ho no I I'm
going to disagree just slightly with
both of you because I think local
government is is one of the rare
opportunities where it is about every
citizen and there's much more of an
opportunity to have your voice heard at
the local government level then there
might be at state government and often
it really only takes a few voices to go
and talk to your City Council members
talk to your city managers talk to talk
to the folks the police department and
resolve the issues as before they get
started
ideally but that is the unique part of
local government that I think is
extremely important for for everybody in
this industry
she stole my answer it's a cop out it
can't do that one so it's interests I
mean it's interesting you mentioned
obviously the citizens a lot of a lot of
California right now like we heard on
the other panels have bands everywhere
80 to 90 percent of California has a ban
on cannabis so given sort of the
differences in who holds the powers at
the sheriff is that the the city you
know is that the mayor is the people
what is the biggest hurdle and finding
out how to infiltrate these cities and
these localities that have bands and get
to the people who hold power when it
differs from city to city how do we
effectively in your own jurisdiction
know oh I am the one that holds the
power or no I got a go to my share
because he or she holds the power first
starters and I'm curious to to kind of
get the actual statistics on on what
you're reporting as far as the number of
jurisdictions that have
that have ordinances prohibiting you
know prohibiting any form of cannabis
maybe maybe canna regs over there can
help out with that I don't know but you
know I think part of it starts with with
education I mean it's been mentioned
before but at least with respect to
cities I can't speak for four counties
necessarily but but with cities you know
there are there are a lot of
opportunities as mentioned with respect
to going to council meetings and whatnot
to try and just directly engage an
office a City Councilmember office or
whomever as far as you know why why you
may think that or why you know that
cannabis is good for for for someone's
jurisdiction or or why you believe the
constituents of that jurisdiction you
know want cannabis where you know when
when a council member or some other
elected official you know might might
see otherwise or has or has already put
you know some sort of prohibition in
place so I think you know it starts with
it starts with council meetings first
and foremost with respect to cities but
but beyond that I mean you know whether
whether it's a social media push whether
there is whether there are I mean I know
we have a lot of opportunities at the
league too to have organizations come
out and educate our members directly and
and interface with them directly in
terms of you know offering their
services and and and what is what what
it is that they believe you know should
take place at our internal board
meetings and whatnot we there are
different opportunities to do that but
by and large I think you know it needs
to start with with the council meetings
and with the with the staff at the city
level as far as trying to you know
trying to just get get the word out or
make your point known from where you
stand and you know perhaps this
gentleman to my right can can give some
more poignant examples but but I think
that's where it starts it has to start
with communication and you want to
try to work with cities it's a lot
easier to work with us then then too
then to fight us I'm learning that every
day that I work at the league so I could
just add to that I'd say first of all
abandon logic right because logic
doesn't work but push common sense and
there's a distinction between logic and
common sense there are 32 states in the
United States now that have some form of
regulation of marijuana the polling on
medicinal marijuana nationwide is over
90% it's over 90% like that debate is
over and I think for a lot of electeds
who are worried about their next
election usually if going in on the
discussion on medicinal there's not a
person on a council who doesn't have a
relative or somebody who has suffered
from some form of cancer or some form of
epilepsy or HIV or all these other
debilitating illnesses that the
medicines in it works it works there's
no more debate around that and and
getting in there to find out what the
real objections are well the real
objections are driving under the
influence
great don't let people smoke and drive
just like you don't let people drink and
drive let's use some common sense and
it's said in politics that rather than a
spectrum of left to right it's actually
a circle and and the left and the right
on this issue I think meet on the policy
perception of libertarianism California
has a very strong libertarian bet stay
out of my life
leave me alone people on the left or the
right seek privacy don't want anyone
else intruding to my private
decision-making that's a really strong
political argument for both the left and
the right and I think that there's a
common-sense way to get to a lot of
these issues from either perspective and
it's just I think takes one heroic
council member I have friends on the
Santa Ana Council there they're kind of
going through it right now and there are
there are suburban communities it's just
not going to you know it's just not
going to happen
gonna get there but that's okay the more
business that comes to West Hollywood
I'm fine with it you know
and at some point they're gonna wake up
and they're gonna say what's happening
what's time but they got a hundred
million dollar reserve yeah well no
kidding because we're doing common-sense
policy over here and if you get off your
point of view and get to common sense
you'd see that this is really not what
you fear it to be I just want to say
that the eighty to ninety percent
statistic that was dropped earlier by
Max was a statistic from 2016 and that
was after the League of Cities was on a
road show encouraging local
jurisdictions to ban since they felt
like there was a gun under their head at
their head mandating them to regulate by
March first it was an erroneous deadline
and a bill was then introduced to
rectify that but we are at right now
about thirty five percent of the state
that either has regulations on the books
or is moving towards creating sensible
regulations and I will just give an
example of like how long this process
takes I've been in Yolo County for three
years and I and day one of me being on
the ground and attending a Board of
Supervisors meeting I went right up to
the opposition which was a group of
mothers who right away I could tell that
they didn't really care about marijuana
in general they did believe that it was
medicine but there was guys with guns
and dogs and they were living next door
to them and they couldn't have their
Girl Scout meetings and I it was you
know solved this problem for me and I
will go away so I did something that I
wouldn't recommend anyone else do and I
went knocked on that growers door and
told him that the laws were about to
change we were passing an ordinance and
he was going to have to move that is not
I did suffer some consequences for that
so I would and I did I did have a friend
that was beat with a baseball bat in rep
and that was retaliation for that action
so I don't recommend that anybody does
that however I never had those mothers
come back to another
meeting we have moved forward in that
jurisdiction we are awaiting the results
of an e ir and we spent as a community
the cannabis community spend about
seventy-five thousand dollars on various
tax measure and supporting local elected
officials that were pro cannabis and we
still don't have an ordinance we are
awaiting the IR hopefully in early 2019
we will have a permanent ordinance in
place but that's been three long years
of a lot of work and I always this that
and the strategy does not always work
but I always make a beeline up to the
opposition immediately I want to have a
conversation I want to know what their
concerns are I want to know if I can fix
them and if they're actually reasonable
you know if there is a reasonable
solution to their concerns or if they
are you know a Evangelist so and you
know this is something that is a
religious thing then that that's a whole
nother thing I actually really want to
see a religious debate on this issue but
it's a whole nother topic I want to see
Bibles come out and I want them to
decide once and for all is Jesus Pro
cannabis or not I really want to see
that because there are jurisdictions
that that's what the issue is you know
but I really I haven't always been
successful in that strategy but more
often than not I have been able to
address concerns and seem like the
reasonable one while you know addressing
them with the council members or the
supervisors whatever the jurisdiction is
that I'm in I think Jackie make a great
great point about that going to the
opposition and finding out what the
opposition looks like and what their
real concerns are because often the the
initial concern presented is Public
Safety well that can mean a hundred
different things and and addressing that
and being willing to listen to what
those concerns are is a helpful way to
get regulations to progress in addition
to that I think that going into a
jurisdiction that
a ban on commercial cannabis activity
the it's often a negative or neutral so
looking at a group of advocates who want
to who want to create a regulated
cannabis market in a particular city or
county and then on the flipside is a
negative of concerns about public safety
or or the children and there isn't
necessarily there aren't necessarily
points made on the other side so going
in and saying not just it's a neutral
that are negative because that makes it
very easy to vote down a regulation but
on the flipside looking at this is this
is how much money is going to be brought
into this city or county this is what
regulation is going to do earlier
someone said you cannot be in cannabis
you can only be in legal cannabis that
is that is accurate but saying look
we're going to turn this public safety
risk into a into a positive and also
we're going to create jobs in this
community and we're going to create jobs
that require degrees and we're oh by the
way we as this particular group are
going to put money into early childhood
education or building a public pool or
whatever that particular community is
interested in but in order to do that
you have to go into that community and
find out what their what their
particular needs are and listen to what
those negatives are so that you end up
tipping the scales and all of the sudden
it's looking at all of this positive and
how can the City Council or Board of
Supervisors vote that down because of
all those positives and the negatives
have been addressed both Arianna and and
mayor Durham mentioned something they
brought up really great points as far as
as far as common sense solutions right
so with respect to cities and and
perhaps all of you know this already but
you know cities are scrambling for for
revenue okay and so when you talk about
you know solutions that
gonna bring revenue bring tax revenues
to cities I mean they're looking at the
past and they're singing like you know
redevelopment gone Enterprise Zones off
the table so cannabis is you know it it
certainly provides an opportunity to to
help build city coffers if done in a
smart way and so I think you know if
there's if there's a way to communicate
that message and and and kind of lay out
the how there are going to be a lot of
jurisdictions a lot of jurisdictions who
are already you know seeing their
neighboring jurisdictions you know reap
benefits you know at this point in time
that are going to gonna want to come on
board themselves so just wanted to put
that and thank you jackie for being
panelist and fact-checker so we're not
at 80 or 90 percent we're at 65 not
great but let's get maybe a more apt
example you know of sort of the neutral
or negative and Charles you're kind of
pointing out like you know we need the
pros we need why is this good why is it
revenue is it jobs so let's talk about a
you know something that happened very
recently with the League of Cities and
there was you know obviously you
represent 482 municipalities there is
this delivery regulation and the
proposed regs where delivery can you can
deliver to any jurisdiction regardless
of whether it has a banner or not
obviously very controversial what are
some of the nose or the reasons why not
or the reasons that are neutral or
negative that the League of Cities is
expressing genuinely what you know
obviously we talk about common sense the
numbers are behind the cannabis movement
you know what is the League of Cities so
worried about with delivery in any
jurisdiction regardless of whether it's
banned or not the League of California
cities contrary to to what some may
think I mean so where we are neither pro
nor anti cannabis that's that's that's
that's never been the case I mean that's
not the case despite what some may think
about the organization with respect to
delivery and and what a lot of our
cities
see as as the cons or the negatives a
lot of it does boil down to to public
safety
for starters as I understand it there
are bare with me I got you so with
respect to with respect to public safety
and we talk about deliveries in
particular we're not going we're not
talking about a retail establishment
that has various security measures in
place to to you know basically account
for all of the cash on hand not just the
product but the cash and so when you lay
out a scenario whereby you know you have
a delivery vehicle going into whatever
neighborhood and you know there are
there's an opportunity or somebody for
whatever reason
however peeps you know that there is
that delivery vehicle is you know
containing cannabis has cannabis I mean
you put our cities there are cities who
don't want to put there they don't want
to have to deal with the risk of you
know putting their drivers that safe
drivers at risk delivery drivers they
don't want to put the you know they
don't want to create situations whereby
there are robberies whereby there are
you know any other crimes ancillary to
robberies where people can get hurt
since this is still an all-cash business
as I understand it that is that is one
of the underlying concerns with respect
to the other proposed reg that that's
still percolating dynamic delivery as as
its called
colloquially where delivery or delivery
driver can potentially carry up to ten
thousand dollars in cash that also you
know pass or be adopted that's only
going to to exacerbate the concerns that
cities have beyond that cities are
concerned you know whether rational or
not they are concerned about you know
delivery drivers going to the doors and
you have potentially let's say a
thirteen-year-old answers the door for
instance oh yeah this this cannabis is
for my grandmother you know I'll just
take that now granted delivery drivers
aren't supposed to
you know hand that over necessarily but
who is going to enforce that when you've
got cash on the table necessarily and
and that's you know I hear that beyond
that I hear that there is a you know
there is I should say the strongest
argument yeah beyond that the strongest
argument against cities and and their
concerns you know that that I've heard
throw out there thrown out there is that
you know obviously there there is a
concern about patients we have patient
patient access is key I will say that
there you know people with cancer
persons that have mobility issues
patients should certainly have access to
medicine that is a conversation that I
will you know say right now I will be
will I'm willing to engage anyone on and
willing to go back to you know to my
colleagues and say hey look you know we
really need to discuss this issue every
single proposal that we've seen on the
table this year as it relates to
delivery so it from our vantage point it
shows that that patient access is not at
the forefront of the delivery issue okay
now that you know the city's just
specifically are they worried about
license delivery operators doing illegal
activity so bright you know obviously
they've put on all the work and money
into getting a license are they worried
about those delivery operators are they
worried about operators who do not want
to do it legally I think they're just
concerned in general there are some
cities that are concerned just in
general about how does that get enforced
and you know how feasible it is is it to
enforce you've got law enforcement
telling community or telling our city
officials that you know we're not going
to be able to enforce you know these
delivery provisions and if stuff goes
bad so goes bad in our you know
community from a licensed from a
licensed operator from another community
that falls on us ultimately to handle
and so there are some cities like West
Hollywood like Pasadena like others who
are more than capable who feel more than
capable of handling delivery in their
communities and by all means we want
them to to be able to have that that
that option to to
for that to two operators do any of the
other panelists have any thoughts on
delivery and sort of this idea that it
can't be regulated even though there's
regulation in place and lots of money
and licenses that delivery operators are
going through to try to do it the right
way the league yeah well and Charles
please don't take any of my comments
personally I appreciate you actually
coming to the table today to have a
discussion and hopefully we can work
together and open the league's mind and
and change this adversarial relationship
that I do feel that we have I don't feel
that the league is is pro or anti
cannabis I think that they are Pro easy
route which is a ban and anti the hard
route which is education on regulation
and the delivery issue is sort of
bringing this adversarial relationship
to a peak when the stop the wandering
weed campaign began which was introduced
by the UFCW you guys signed on in
support of it on Friday of last week
that campaign came down off of their
website and we don't know why but only
after 86 of your members signed on in
support of the stop the want laundering
weed campaign the stop the wandering
weed campaign was a cartoon and we're
not allowed to use cartoons because we
would be marketing to children but yet
they used a cat a cartoon to to rail us
and showed us driving up to schools and
and dispensing cannabis to children and
as if any licensed operator is going to
go through all of the local and state
legal hurdles to get licensed to then
then to children was offensive it was
repulsive it made my stomach turn it
still makes my stomach turn and yet we
have to turn the corner and figure out
how we can you know come to the table
and figure out a compromise and I keep
hearing oh well we wouldn't have this
issue if it was just about medical
really um I I don't know I mean because
it always goes back to local
control Oh what about local control does
do local governments have control over
Norco is being delivered to a home do
they have control over alcohol being
delivered and making sure a child
doesn't answer the door when that when
that package arrives seriously so why
are they so about local control when it
comes to cannabis and you know the more
that we regulate this the less children
are going to get access to it and that
is a reality the but and then to
conflate the two issues of dynamic
delivery and 54:16 D there are two
separate issues yet we got smeared and
and there isn't another campaign to
correct that right so let's say that
maybe now the league regrets this
decision to support that campaign but
they're not going out to those 86
members and saying hey we screwed up you
know the damage is already done and it's
ya know it's it's seriously offensive
and um I don't know how we're supposed
to write and so my issue with the league
has been you can say you're you're not
anti or pro all you want but you went
out with like just a campaign with a gun
to the heads of the cities back in late
2015 and early 2016 and no one has gone
out with that same energy to teach
jurisdictions how to regulate that's
what we need go ahead Charles and we're
gonna do Q a very shortly so okay well
let me just say that let me just say
that with respect to to the last issue
you mentioned yeah we had that timeline
cities had that timeline local
governments had the timeline to put an
ordinance on the books and so you know
before my time but you know I understand
that there may have been conversations
that if communities did not want
cannabis yes to put an ordinance in
place that prohibited cannabis in their
communities the otherwise they would be
preempted and so as with anything local
governments or anyone doesn't like being
told what to do and so
with prop 64 as we know there's
divergent viewpoints on this but yes it
was a patchwork of in a sense whereby it
allowed for locals to have a retain
reasonable regulation Authority and so
with respect to the wandering weed to
stop wandering weed I don't have a
strong answer for you I was out on
paternity leave when that happened I was
probably the last person to find out
about that I never actually saw the
cartoon that's it let the panelists talk
I got you in the Sun I never actually
saw the the cartoon but the the point
remains it just goes to show how how
much cities are concerned that they
would that however many of them would
sign on to it and I don't think you can
separate out 54 16 D and dynamic
delivery because at the end of the day
if both are adopted and I suspect both
will be you know it is a public safety
issue that cities are going to have to
deal with local governments are going to
have to deal with it who feel in
ill-equipped to be able to handle
deliveries and so I mean that's where I
think the education you know is
necessary I'm not saying it's easy if it
was easy everyone would do it but that's
what needs to take place if in fact you
know we're gonna get to a place where we
can have our local officials you know
he'd whatever it is that their
constituents supposedly are saying to
them I mean this is an election year
right so if you want to you know talk to
them you want them to listen to you
I mean constituents have the power to do
that I mean are you guys listening to
his constituents he's not gonna get
voted out are you are you willing is the
league willing to engage in a
conversation about real education for
cities and counties and and sitting down
at the table with the cannabis industry
if it's if the league is not pro or anti
can we can we have that conversation I
don't I don't think it's too late we
still have 65% of jurisdictions to to
educate and to to get regulations
through and I think it's possible the
league can be an ally in that
than a hindrance I make no make no
commitment as to the result but I'm open
to having a conversation with anyone
about you know how the league can you
know help educate members or how the
league at the very least can facilitate
education between industry
representatives and local officials I'm
happy I have a solution real quick what
I would like to see the lead do I would
like to see the league start with every
jurisdiction every one of their members
that passed Proposition 64 beginning
with a survey on what yes meant in their
community okay
that is where we've gone wrong is we
don't know what yes meant in every
single jurisdiction does it mean that
they want home deliveries does it mean
they want retail locations does it mean
they want commercial cultivation
manufacturing distribution all of that
or did they just vote YES for social
justice purposes we need to figure that
out in every community and then you
regulate from there Thank You panelists
my question pertains to the sales tax on
cannabis sales do you feel it was stated
earlier that a lot of the illicit shops
are not paying any taxes on their
cannabis sales do you feel with it being
a mainly cash industry that the licensed
shops are paying their true amount of
sales tax or do you feel that there may
be some false reporting and tax evasion
going on first of all in order to tax it
requires a vote of the people because of
proposition 218 so in the City of West
Hollywood we will probably have on the
March 2019 ballot a proposal sponsored
by the council to ask the people to vote
you know in its acts so taxes city
governments can't just impose a tax you
actually have to go to a vote of the
people and obviously if the tax passes
overwhelmingly it kind of tells you
where the people are the people are
saying we want this tax it shows you
that they're strongly in support on
issues of tax evasion I think that any
time you're dealing with cash and we
have a lot of cash businesses in West
Hollywood we have a lot of bars and
nightclubs that they also deal heavily
in cash every night there's always the
opportunity for tax evasion
but they're smart they don't want to get
caught and wanted up like Jimmy Hoffa
sitting in a federal prison so you know
I think we just have to trust that
people are going to comply ultimately I
can't speak specifically to what any
individual business is doing in terms of
tax evasion I can tell you that our
clients that we're working with so hard
to get licensed and that that process
takes can take a year or two years or
three years if regulations aren't yet on
the books they are constantly asking
questions about how what taxes they owe
how the best way to pay their taxes is
my advice is always to go and talk to an
accountant because I am NOT an
accountant but they are looking to be
responsible in paying their taxes
because they work that hard to get their
license they don't want to then turn
around and lose it because they didn't
pay their taxes yeah I think a big issue
is how high the taxes are I mean they're
not the same taxes that you have for
other industries in the same city in San
Francisco they don't have a tax now but
they want to go 1 to 7 percent so you
know there obviously can be always the
evasion but you know the taxes are
breaking people my name is Dale Shaffer
I'm working with Jackie and I want to at
least start the the question is sort of
a dialogue inside of the League of
Cities do you have a discussion group
that understands that every nook and
cranny of the state is having deliveries
happen right now with large amount of
products and large amount of cash do you
understand this industry is up and
running and we are trying to to work
with you and other power brokers to try
to bring this regulated that right now
you are the enemy and we don't want you
to be so we're trying to reach out to
you like Jackie did at a group you're
the person we've got to try to please
but you're the people holding keys that
are taking us out regularly and does
your organization want to work with us
first and foremost I don't think that
anyone is ignorant to to the fact that
there is an illicit market out there
right and you know all kinds of
operators
are acting illegally and yes that is a
that is an issue that that that
legalized operators you know and they're
gonna they're fighting they're trying to
contend with as far as the league goes
you know I came into this panel
expecting to be recognized as the bad
guy you know I want to find ways or you
know at least yeah I want to find ways
to work with with industry I mean it
starts with it starts with conversations
and and and civility there obviously
there are there is a lot of again
there's a lot of passion and there's a
lot of there's a lot of of I should say
hurt feelings based on whatever may have
transpired in the past both leading up
to and and since the passing of since
the passing of prop 64 and so I mean I'm
only speak for myself in terms of what
what I am willing to do I'm certainly
willing to have a conversation with you
further conversations with Jackie and or
whomever else wants to to see what sort
of bridges can be built and and we can
just hopefully go from there okay
can I jump in on that question so I've
been a member of the California League
of Cities for 18 years and the National
League of Cities and I just want to say
this is not intended
I feel like Switzerland between the two
Thank You panelists here but but what I
what I will say is the California League
of Cities exerts a great deal of
influence in Sacramento on legislation
they do not exert a great deal of
influence on local government we are
members of local government and what
happens a lot of time is the people who
are really actively involved in the
California League of Cities come from
small conservative towns around the
state and the big city council members
don't participate yeah it's very rare
for me to see a San Francisco supervisor
or a Los Angeles City Council member at
illega City's event they just don't
participate so what Charles are saying
is correct they are supposed to be
neutral I
I would suggest that you all this
morning here tonight she's going to get
my card I know come to the City of West
Hollywood Santa Cruz Berkeley San
Francisco San Diego Los Angeles
encourage us to ask the League of Cities
because we're all members to let us
sponsor a panel on reasonable regulation
at the annual conference of the League
of Cities I'm gonna hold you to that
mayor I'll organize it for you yeah
there we go hi everyone my name is
Joseph chicas I'm a director of
government affairs for cannabis advising
partners my question was really relating
to equity and transparency in the
decision-making for these applications
because what we're finding is that as
time goes on more and more of these
decisions regarding licensing across the
board are becoming more and more
political more and more personal
interests and competing interests and
conflicts of interest are going into
those decisions so how do we work
together to improve equity and
transparency and the decisions that are
being made at the local government level
so that the best applicants can really
be the best or can have their foot in
the door rather than the person with the
most contacts or the most contributions
toward a political campaign so when we
looked at this very carefully because we
did not like the first-come first-serve
method and we didn't like the lottery as
we you know didn't want either of those
so we instead developed a merit-based
system and I gotta say when we were
first starting to discuss this all of a
sudden every pet cause that I am part of
was suddenly seen a great influx of
cannabis dollars going into all of my
pet causes because that is the way that
you know politics works so we were
cognizant from the beginning that there
was going to be an attempt to try to
curry favor us from the electeds on our
Council so we developed a merit-based
system where the applications that we
have 300 applications that have come in
are being reviewed by a seven-member
committee none of whom have any interest
or business interest in fact I only know
one of the names because somebody after
accidentally told me that this person
was on the committee but the five
council members we have no idea who even
the seven committee people are they're
reviewing the applications they're going
through it on various criteria I wrote
them down innovative business model
connection to West Hollywood business
operations social equity product
offerings design concept security plan
and experience in the industry those are
the criteria came up with a point system
and these seven women and men are going
to go through all 300 applications and
they're going to make recommendations to
the business license commission who then
gives them one of the what I call the
golden tickets
you know Willy Wonka reference one of
the golden tickets and then go out and
find a location somewhere in the city
and then only if all of that people are
unhappy they think something went awry
is it appealable to the council so we
have intentionally tried to keep
ourselves away from the decision making
to the greatest extent possible
ultimately we have to have some concern
because it's where the electeds we have
to you know we're responsible for
everything but we really try to create a
system where we're out of the evaluation
to avoid the appearance that these
golden tickets were for sale in any
which way so that's a system we've come
up with I think it's unique at this
point if we're still in the middle of
the process and we expect that those
licenses will be handed out at the end
of October or early November and then
we'll be in the process so I I'm hoping
that what we've come up here as a model
ordinance that other cities will
replicate it as a way to make decision
based on merit rather than just
happenstance or first-come first-serve
and just a quick follow up mayor
specifically because the gentleman asked
about social equity is there anything in
place to be assured that these will be
sustainable models I'm assuming in the
applications they'll have all the
criteria set including social equity is
there any report that will be given out
quarterly or yearly is there anything
holding these businesses accountable to
the the criteria that they applied with
to make sure that they continue that in
the future yes yes and it'll be like a
lot of the other adult businesses in my
community I have a lot of adult
businesses have a lot of bars and talk
book stores have a lot of businesses
that you know
people consider not worthy of business I
got them all I'm we're happy to have a
bit story and the way that we regulate
that is using our code enforcement but
there's a commission a business license
Commission who has oversight we did not
want to grant any permits that ran with
the land meaning we didn't want to give
something that ran with the land but
rather goes with the operation and
that's why it's a business license
rather than a permit there's a
distinction there's a distinction in
terms of what it is that we're giving
and how quickly we can take it away
thank you well that wraps it up this is
an incredible panel thank you again
round of applause for all the panelists
Valjean Ariana and Jackie thank you
[Music]