[Music]
in California we're about to launch upon
a very regulated market so we've had
medical cannabis for the last over 20
years and if you've been cultivating
cannabis in the state of California
hopefully you've been operating as a
non-profit collective and there is a
particular business corporate
organizational structure and kind of
financial model that one needs to follow
so the first thing that I always
recommend to folks who are growers
people are operating under this
nonprofit collective model why that
matters is because none of this is fully
regulated today none of this these
businesses are not fully legalized
commercial cannabis activity that
doesn't really launch until January 1st
2018 and even even on that date we're
still under a transitionary period so I
sort of think about it like businesses
are operating growers are operating in a
quasi legal environment where you're
legality is hinging upon are you this
not-for-profit collective cooperative
sort of business or entity structure
which creates a solid sort of step1
foundation so step one get compliant now
make sure that your operations are in
order now so that one can comfortably
interface with their local county and
various other agencies and departments
both on a local and state level to
pursue what is ultimately a state
license so visually it's sort of like
we're going on work you're going down a
road you're taking a path really you're
not on any sort of you know it's as if
you're out in the desert and you're just
we've been just sort of driving around
and once awhile you see like you see
dirt roads and
that's today where you want to be is if
you're a grower envisioning what type of
cultivation state license do I want and
so maybe going on the California
Department of Food and Agriculture of
astray lated market with that state
license and local permit and everything
that involves that you know will speak
about that's that's where I need to land
because a year after the state issues
notice of the first cannabis license
right the furthest state says yeah we've
issued our first official license so
maybe somewhere around 2019 2020 you can
no longer operate as just a non-profit
collective you need to have both the
local permit and a state license so for
anyone who is cultivating cannabis today
in California it really is about getting
very clear on what are the steps that
take takes you to that state license if
you want to operate in the regulated
legal market and so it really you know
while it's not always fun to sit down
and have very involved conversations
with lawyers and accountants and your
business partners or yourself about the
the this type of kind of strategic
thinking in a very challenging you know
still being firmed up set of rules and
regulations from different agencies type
of an environment but those sorts of
very intentional meet like meetings
amongst partners or as a grower oneself
making sure okay I know what I mean I I
haven't I
where I want to go and then taking the
steps to get you there is really
critical it's like you know when I see
people who are really kind of confused
about what those next steps are the you
know it's it's getting clear it's yeah I
guess it's trying to help get them
organized and getting clear on that you
know I just try to think about like
really practical advice because you've
got laws that are in place you have
shifting laws that are still kind of
being figured out and so you know how
does one organize how does one plan in
in you know these really next six months
year and a half two years and the best
way of doing that is sitting down
figuring out what's knowable what's not
knowable and almost backtracking okay if
I want that state license then I know
that I'll need to have and that involves
something with the state waterboard and
with the Department of Fish and Wildlife
and these various agencies
oh geez here's here's what's required to
the CDFA that I prove in order to even
apply gosh it says I need to have this
particular type of corporate entity and
let me read these regulations that say
how I need to operate my facility what
this new track and trace system is what
the state taxes are you know what oh
gosh what what are all the taxes that
are involved because of a large majority
of people who are cultivating cannabis
in California and certainly people that
you know we've worked with over the
years are are not familiar with all of
those state regulatory agencies and are
not you know certainly not familiar
because we've not had such a thing with
you know what does track and trace mean
what will it mean to function in a very
regulated environment and instead of
turning your head away from I just don't
want to look at that because that's all
new and confusing and not what I'm used
to for the last 20 years or more
instead turning and looking at it and
honestly it takes a level of courage you
know to look at okay this is what I want
to do I have to take that leap and get
some good information and
take move and take those steps forward
so you know it really is kind of like
crystallizing those steps as much as
possible and so you know once you think
in the world of the state regulators
okay well you know you've got federal
law state law and then local right
cities counties so where's my physic
where's my facility located if it's an
indoor grow facility or an outdoor in
what city or county in California and
there are 540 total separate local
jurisdictions so what do I need in in my
area well there are 540 total
municipalities in the state of
California and you'll need to have a
permit from that city or county and so
in order to get that type of a permit
there are a number of items that will
almost surely be required so are you in
the right zone is it does the city or
county require that your outdoor
facility be in a particular type of Ag
land or if you're an indoor grow or is
it allowable in a certain manufacturing
area or not at all and that's a
challenge that many many operators are
facing and many interested operators or
entrepreneurs are facing which is still
a vast majority of these cities and
counties have no pathway to permitting
they don't have their zoning rules
figured out they don't have the business
permitting process figured out and
that's just the nature of being involved
in an emerging industry so on that front
what percentage of the cultivators that
you work with are doing everything right
right as it pertains to state
regulations but are kind of going to be
screwed by their local the vast majority
at the moment and the reason is most
cities and counties are still in their
local political process so one of you
know it just is honestly by virtue of
the nature of regulating a really Bo
Hemanth of an industry and having a very
thriving industry for the last twenty
plus years and most cities and counties
they're little political kingdoms
themselves each of those 540 cities and
counties has their own local politics
and their own issues and their own
looking at this industry and other other
things to factor in that make it more
challenging or very easy like a desert
hot springs in some of these desert
cities that very much need the revenue
from this industry or established
counties like Mendocino or Humble County
who acknowledge that there is a thriving
cannabis industry or little one-offs
like West Hollywood that really believes
in this industry for the medical
benefits right so you have that extreme
and then you've got cities and counties
who are saying we've had a very
contentious relationship with this
industry or we don't know what any of
this means this is all scary and so then
you know you're seeing a lot of local
advocacy you know at City at City
Council meetings at County Supervisor
meetings and a lot of folks kind of
coming out of the green closet advocacy
organization saying look this is not
scary the status passed assets'
comprehensive set of laws with the
medical and adult use cannabis
regulation and Safety Act don't freak
out municipalities you know they're all
these state agencies that will deal with
the really meet of these issues and your
role which cities and counties this is
their role is really just to deal with
zoning so we're in the city or county do
you want what particular types of
categories of businesses and you know
that manufacturing cultivation
distribution in what areas and so it's
were really in a process of Education
and a lot of our clients don't have
local permits they are trying to figure
out or they're in the process of
applying for or through various
strategies depending on the
municipalities are are moving in that
direction or are in process but there's
it's a it's a problem it's one of the
challenges of what we are facing right
now
[Music]