I think over the last two weeks having
experienced
most of the pain points of the panel my
direct self with my own two hands then I
think that it's you know it's a little
bit more somber and a little less
exciting and there's a lot more reality
and I really wish and I hate to burst
your bubble Peter I really wish this was
a packed house because everyone needs to
hear it and and this is this what I know
we're filming it but we also have a
bunch of people smoking weed outside
that if they will but if they want that
cannabis and they want and they want it
easy and they want to buy it from
northern Californians they want to buy
it from a heritage growing region you
know we have to talk about how this
cannabis is going to get down here we
have to talk to about how we're gonna
work together cultivators to retailers
we're have to talk about how cultivators
have to you know have to adjust we have
to talked about retailers adjusting we
have to talk about distribution
adjusting we have to talk about legal
adjusting you know there's all of these
different things that you know there's
just Minh to make and it really sucks
because the lives of a lot of these
cultivators hang in the balance
you know a lot of us are either two
weeks away or two weeks past a big loss
and so we don't have time to fight it
out so we were hoping this would be you
know sort of a distilling of some of the
retail climate in this area of what
we've had to deal with as in order to
Northern California cultivators coming
down into Southern California and and
and the the the introduction to the
retail market and how it is that we
could do this without as much pain so
before you know I go up here is uh one
of my favorite people on the planet you
know some somebody that you know when
they showed up at a meeting at a
Mendocino cannabis Policy Council
meeting you know four years ago
we were like oh damn there now that's
pro you know we have a chance and
hezekiah you know showed up for us and
you know informing the CGA it was a
really big rallying point for the
Northern California farmers to feel like
we had a voice in Sacramento it was you
know it was the first introduction to
policy for a lot of us and hezekiah
coming from a long background of
environmental advocacy work up in
Sacramento it really made it easy for us
you know it made off shit nothing made
it easy all right
sorry okay it gave us confidence how's
that sound and we were outspent a
hundred to one on on most bills that
came through the house for the first two
years and we were victorious on most of
them we had you know put it this way
being outspent to that to that degree
and to be able to get the victories we
were able to eke out for the small
cultivators in Northern California to be
able to exist in this current framework
wall we had people like Shawn Parker
putting millions of dollars to advocate
that Camel Harris that the only way to
stop narco trafficking was to put it in
the hands of four four large
corporations and let that let the big
boys manage it because we were fucking
up as small batch cultivators and we
were cartel and we were evil and we were
water extractors hiring surveys from
different water authorities to create
this you know the stigma around what it
was that we were doing and so we've had
a lot and hezekiah sat up there every
day meeting new people that we were
running from and he was up there in the
face of it was really really proud to
have him you know by her side or at her
head or wherever he was but um that was
great
[Music]
all right look I did take a hit of
tarantula before I came in here and it
did have sativa Keef on it okay
okay yeah right okay after the panel
this is Bobby Bobby is a I mean okay so
the other day we were trying to figure
out how we were gonna do this thing and
quite a few days ago and Bobby stepped
up big time right he's my new Bobby big
time I had one before now this is the
new one
because at the end of the day he has a
business that he is is trying to you
know navigate all of these hurdles and
go through all these loopholes and he
was able to go to his comfort zone to
say hey you know what I believe what it
is that you guys are doing enough to let
you guys figure your shit out through us
for this event and if it wasn't for
Bobby this event wouldn't be going on
right now if it wasn't for somebody to
step up and actually was doing it like
that she wouldn't happen you know I'm
saying like that that's big time and
thank you so much Bobby that's like yeah
no no thanks for ya anyway and then we
got Eric man Eric is is like is number
one here he goes you know Long Beach I
met him and with Susan saw res you know
helped her to what she was doing in Long
Beach for a long time
see for distribution getting in he he
actually threw the first cannabis event
in this space so when I found out that
he could do it and Erin hooked us up
with the spot I was like man we can do
it here so that was really great as well
Eric and then we got a chance to hang
out the other day and he's been
introducing me to different people and
I'm when I found about you know that he
could be you know handling the
distribution on the panel and that he's
had his own trials and tribulations in
Southern California he is going to be a
wealth of information for us all to
learn what's really going on around here
and then we have Ariel Clark who is who
is like what I heard is the gatekeeper
to Santa Monica but not only the
gatekeeper Santa Monica is there
somebody that has been holding a really
sacred message around you know around
equal justice and around around native
rights I mean I we met at a at a Native
American sort of like rights panel which
is something near and dear to my
because every gram of cannabis that has
grown in the desert is done with stolen
water and they're piping and they're
going to be shipping in water from
outside of that region it does not
belong to them right right now they
might have a thousand foot deep well you
know but but soon enough that water is
going to be coming from Northern
California and and all of our water is
going to be shipped into the desert to
large-scale commodity as it grows it's
going to be produced at around the penny
made two cents three cents a you know a
gram and and you know we need that
message going forward an aerial is you
know like stress interest and in
protecting those rights and and you know
and and I definitely believe in what
you're doing
and thank you for protecting us in this
event because there's our law firm at
the end of the day that's that's who
we've got to ask so thank you so much
Ariel and okay so basically here goes
and starts what we figure we'd run
through right now is sort of like
cultivation to distro right you know
that's that's that's a pain point
initially a lot of you know a lot of
district companies that aren't distro
companies a lot of people you know
myself included you know I was like
alright what are we gonna do I'm gonna
try to figure it out I'm not cultivating
this year so I'm gonna try to I'm gonna
try to play distro oh my god what a
fucking nightmare because I got to meet
all of these people that said they were
distro in or distro they were attempt
permits in a possible joint venture with
a guy in a warehouse with a bunch of
other guys usually like five or ten of
them stacking their license or or their
jayvees to act as distribution so as
cultivators it's been really hard to
meet the right distro so like going down
the line I would you know kind of like
let's see the easiest way for for a
cultivator like one of these cultivators
that might be out here to enter into the
legal market to come in through
distribution like how do we get how do
we get to that basic point how do you
know how do we trust a distributor i I
think the first thing that you need to
do is understand what a distributor is
and what a distributor isn't because in
California for the first time alongside
Nevada
we actually have distribution licenses
inside of a cannabis supply chain what
that means is if you thought back to the
world of Colorado or Oregon or
Washington they don't have distributor
licenses they have transporter licenses
and that means that they don't have the
right to buy the product
so distributors in a normal supply chain
which California is the distributor is
the one who buys the product issues the
PIO to the grower buys the product and
then sells it to the stores
that's what distributors do so the best
way to figure out if you have a real
distributor is ask them that question if
they understand that they're a real
distributor and there's plenty of them
and then you look at the way
distributors in this industry have
broken out so it used to be that
everybody was a distributor now you
basically have three types of
distributors you have distributors who
are really the brands distribution arm
into the market you have distributors
who are logistics only distributors
meaning that you do the selling for them
and they'll just deliver your product to
the store and then you have full service
distributors who do all of the selling
and all of the picking and packing and
all the distributing you just deliver
them the finished product so they'll
test it etc so those are the three types
of distribution I'm curious some of the
folks in different places in the supply
chain what you're seeing from other
distributors people ask me all the time
what are your competitors doing and the
answer is lots of different stuff at the
same time and if I had to spend time
trying to figure out what everyone else
was doing I wouldn't have any time to
work on what I'm doing so I'm curious
what you guys see relative to what I
said well I think the key to success is
to focus on your own business so good on
you for that worrying about what other
people are up to is oftentimes misguided
in my opinion Justin you know you
I took Eric sort of heard how do you
trust a distributor I heard what's the
easiest way to find a distributor and
and I'd question whether or not easy is
the right strategy there you know the
easiest thing is not always the best
thing the easiest thing is to drop your
price and find some
to take it from you that's probably not
the right way to do this in fact it's
existential for folks trying to survive
at a small scale you know when and Eric
you mentioned sort of the three types I
think those are three great meta
categories when we mapped out
distribution we came up with 16 sort of
archetypal distributors broken into
those three main categories but there's
a lot of different ways of approaching
distribution I I think though that the
question at the end of the day Eric and
I can disagree about a lot of things and
we have a lot of fun doing that at times
but I think that question you know the
first question I'd advise and and the
first question I ask of distributors is
how many sales accounts do you have
what's your volume what are you moving
and if it's well I thought you were
gonna do that then cool I'll get my own
license and by the way I'm not a grower
I'm not a licensee currently I grew up a
grower and then cut my hair and learned
to tie a tie and now it's growing back
because fuck politics at least for the
moment I don't know we'll see
and so you know I see it sort of from an
outside perspective and and I recognize
that when I say don't take the easy path
sometimes you have to like that's that's
the nuts and bolts of making ends meet
and so to sort of hedge against don't
take the easy path I'd say don't get
attached to it
stay flexible stay on your toes sell as
little as possible if you're selling low
just cover your bills the market is
going to change and grow this will not
be a simple commodity market two cents a
gram will exist but so will
differentiated pricing cannabis flower
is not a commodity it's not
interchangeable and so it's going to
recover it's going to bounce back there
is a lot of room to grow especially as
growers build cooperative supply chains
which I'm gonna talk a lot about today
and and increase their confidence
markets run on confidence there's a lot
of market forces that we can talk about
but at the end of the day confidence is
a very important market force and and I
think we need to have more of that and
and I think this dialogue is a great way
to do that well I love to infuse a
retail perspective into the distribution
discussion if you're a producer out
there who's wondering how to make that
happen
go to a respected retailer and ask him
who are you using you know we have 40
maybe 50 distributors who we work with
and five to ten of them are actually
professional outfits
you would be amazed at the the way that
people drop the ball just being able to
to fulfill your promises to deliver
things when they're supposed to be
delivered in the quantities that they're
supposed to be delivered the proper
items that are supposed to be delivered
it's it's it's quite basic business so
focus on the fundamentals that's what I
would recommend and I would just say
from a legal or regulatory perspective I
just kind of echo what everyone says
you're you want to make sure that just
kind of generally you find partners that
understand the rules and regulations are
license you're asking questions about
their ability to follow up and do they
understand tax structures do they
understand rules so you know getting a
good laundry list of initial questions
and then making sure that they're
licensed and that you've got the
appropriate contracts in place I thought
I'd take a crack at one of the questions
that or one of the suggestions that
Hezekiah talked about and that is how if
you want to get your products market how
do you get it to market and III think
there's a couple frameworks that we can
learn from other adjacent industries
when you think about brewpubs for
example and craft beer it feels a whole
lot like craft cannabis so how do they
make money well generally the way they
make money is they supply to their
community and their community starts out
as a brew pub there's just one
restaurant and then they decide that
people really like mine so I'm gonna
make more and then they figure out that
well now I'm producing for a whole bunch
of other people cuz I just know how to
produce so what I'm gonna do is produce
with these seven other guys and we're
gonna pay somebody to market that and
get it to a bigger market right but
that's the way you should think about it
start start with your own confines and
go from there because the harder it is
going to get harder as
you move away from your home base that's
where that's where leverage doesn't work
anymore right you need the scale or you
the distance is gonna get in your way so
if you would generally want to think
about you know I I know it's hard for
there's a whole lot of people in the
same place go find a place that's close
by that your relatives live in and see
if you can supply them with their
cannabis but find out one place first
and then a second place and then a third
place go right to the customer because
that's who's ultimately gonna buy and
frankly in this business right now and
for the foreseeable future it's gonna be
the hard part is getting to the customer
and so since Eric followed up I'm gonna
follow up too and what he said is
exactly correct go to the customer
forget all about the distributor forget
all about the retailer love you both
go meet the people who love your
cannabis get to know them social media
has broken down the geo geographical
nature of the the brewpub model to some
degree obviously you'd still have to
have the cannabis to consume it but you
know physical realities do still matter
to some degree but get to know consumers
talk directly to them there are so many
different kinds of humans and it's so
exciting how many humans there are and
all different they love all different
things get to know them find the people
that love exactly what you're doing and
love your story and the partners will be
there to get it in the supply chain and
so I do think Eric hit the nail on the
head go to the consumer
farmers knowing consumers the people who
make things knowing the people who
consume things is really good for
Humanity in general and it's especially
good when it comes to cannabis so as the
retailer or do you get consumers saying
hey do you have this brand and then that
sort of gets you thinking about that
brand of the brain and then yeah
absolutely I mean if a brand has really
has really garnered a following sure and
if they're distributed exclusively
through a single company you know that
definitely draws our attention so like
heads was saying you know if you believe
in your product there is someone else
out there that does - there really is
and you just got to find those people go
to them drum up demand
roots and before you know it I've got
consumers asking me to stock it well I'm
gonna go stock it very simple all right
so we jumped ahead a little bit into
retail but I like no it's good we're on
a journey here okay we don't want to
fill up at gas at three-quarters of the
tank gonna wait till we get in a quarter
all right so the idea it's a journey
it was the best journey analogy I could
come up with at the moment okay all
right so anyway so brands right so you
you you form a brand right you want to
have you know five different strains
going into your brand right because it
meets the brand ethos you want to have
sativa sativa hybrid how you know what
you want to go down the gamete and you
have to get them all tested your your
your your licensing sort of you know
multiple small batch you know strains so
you have to see you have to test so
you're looking at like five thousand
dollars that you know to test as a brand
how is a distributor you helping
alleviate any of this force a creative
in Northern California sometimes we grow
to keep genetic diversity I mean we'll
keep you know eight to ten strains going
and if we draw if we get demand for five
of those and then we have to test all
five of them that that puts us out so
how how as a distributor could you see
easing that pain of testing so brands
can even get into the marketplace to see
what put what performs well so the main
answer the main answer is the real
answer which is writing a check for a
lot of the products at once right so
what we do uniquely as opposed to if you
go directly to the thirty stores that
we're gonna put you in they're gonna
write you different checks and they're
gonna clear at different times trust me
in this business a quarter of they're
gonna be checks the rest of the bags of
cash and you're gonna get them at
different times the point is we're gonna
give it to you all at the same time so
that you can test it in as big a batch
as you can test it in because you said
five thousand dollars
our tests cost $500 so if we can do one
test for a bigger batch that's the best
way we can help you do that correct but
but the other thing I would tell you is
I I would teach you that you want you
don't you want to do them in cycles so
that you have a batch you don't want to
necessarily do the way that a lot of the
rooms in LA look two years ago which is
they have you know 25 different strains
in the same room now I see them they're
two strains in the same room so is does
that mean you don't have it you just
have it at different times you just
adjust to the situation yeah I mean the
hard truth is well a this isn't the
distributor's fault this is the
regulations fault we need to do a lot
more in the state capital the regulatory
requirements with regard to testing are
bad not in that they test for things and
keep consumers safe but in that they
force us to test in a way that costs way
more than is absolutely required to keep
consumers safe one of the big reasons I
got involved in the policy side was to
make sure that people had good clean
cannabis to smoke because heavy metals
are not great and other things that come
from those types of pollutants so this
is a regulatory problem first and
foremost secondly I would say that we do
need to start coordinating our crops to
match with the regulatory requirements a
little bit better 50-pound batch size we
should be growing 50 pounds that doesn't
need to be necessarily all that you grow
but at least grow one or two 50-pound
baseline batches that you can get into
the market at a more cost-effective
price a pretty typical brand strategy
that I'm you know advising maybe seeing
succeed I don't know it's really hard to
gauge success this early on but you know
you've got your two workhorse varietals
that you grow your big batch of that you
can get into the market at
cost-effective and then maybe you have
six small batch varietals that are
coming in behind that and let's be fair
fifty pounds is a relatively small batch
to begin with in the face of some of
what we're seeing emerge these days so
it's not necessarily all on the
distributor to bring that cost down is
the bottom line some of it is going to
require continued organization and
advocacy there are things that the
growers can do to to help reduce those
costs as well and I mean
the end of the day I think we all need
to do a much better job of communicating
again directly with consumers there is a
cost of growing California's most
sustainable cleanest agricultural
product and that cost is going to be
reflected at the gram at the 8th at the
half ounce level frankly I'm willing to
pay 50 cents more a gram to know that
there was nothing funky that went into
that but we need to make sure that that
is commonly accepted and understood I'll
mention the word again cooperatives I
think we need more cooperation between
producer and consumer as well and more
of an open dialogue there so we
understand where the cost of the product
at the retail point is going in the
supply chain there's a lot that can be
done I just I wanted to piggyback on
what you're saying Hezekiah and I really
like this idea of it almost sounds like
reverse engineering like what are the
rules and regulations what do we have to
navigate through and and and folks who
are in different segments of the market
understanding those rules now granted
they continue to change so much it's
like you're like standing on quicksand
so at some point they're gonna firm up
and of course they're gonna be tons of
changes over the years but you know when
we're talking about how do we get to
solutions a lot of that is about
information knowledge knowledge sharing
through cooperative associations through
trade associations as much as we can
come together as a community and share
information so you know things like
maybe this is the way I should approach
this issue or how many strains I should
have in this room or what kind of issues
might I come up against when my product
goes to be tested so you know my kind of
my hope for us all is more information
sharing so thank you for this thank you
for what all of all of we all do and
many people in the room who are involved
in the discussion and sharing the very
valuable information just a touch on the
the information about these regulations
and such getting out to consumers I
really view it as more of a
responsibility of all of us
retailers myself being a big part in
that and organizations like CGA or the
SCC or whomever that's out there
interfacing with regulators you know
it's it's important for the end consumer
to know
and I've got all of those touch points
tens of thousands of touch points so I'm
doing what I can
it's tough it really is so that leads
perfectly into my next question which is
we're going into retail okay so what as
a retailer could a distributor do two
E's and I'm not talking and I'm not
talking about the transpose and the
manifest and all of those things like to
drive traffic for the brands because at
the end of the day anybody will do
anything to get you the right legal
material if you're driving traffic and
if we're selling cannabis so what could
the distributor do to help you in brand
education and getting you more SKUs that
you feel are working better and being a
more dynamic relationship between retail
and distribution I would say first off
it's not about getting more SKUs it's
about doing one SKU really really well
start start there and move you know
expand as you can hold your promises as
a distributor you know like I was
mentioning before we've got about five
distribution companies that are really
really good at what they do and the rest
are a pain in the ass to work with
because they don't they don't follow
through on what they're saying that
they're gonna do so number one is just
learn the fundamentals of business and
keep it simple and do it really well I
mean I really can't emphasize that
enough you know as a an online business
I essentially have an e-commerce
business the more marketing that you do
for yourself
like has was mentioning earlier get on
social media and really drum up demand
for your own product that way people are
already salivating a little bit when
they hit my website you know and once
they do hit my website give me really
awesome like 2018 product shots that I
can put up
give me lab tests that are really easy
for me to display give me product
descriptions hell if you're a farmer
record a video standing in front of that
plant on your farm and I will put it on
my website in the product description so
the end consumer can see exactly who the
hell was watering their their flower you
know so
I think it's just all of those things
and keeping it simple you know one thing
not a distributor or a retailer but that
I think is relevant to this conversation
you know as I'm reintegrating into the
business community lovingly known as
sell more weed and I'm allowed to say
that now which I wasn't allowed to
before last time I did it it's been
about five or six years since I've been
in the game but you know frankly strain
names don't mean anything the consumers
are totally confused by it we've got
40,000 strains at the end of the day
there's probably 400 actual chemo types
I don't know somebody can argue with me
later I love to have this fight it's
there it's really good fun we have this
really really strong sense of pride in
our craft and we want to tell people all
about all the distinctions and the
varieties and the diversity and that's
really important but right now we're
also struggling with something much
bigger which is the fact that we have an
entrenched and mature market that
unfortunately hasn't been regulated so
most consumers probably don't know that
they're getting cannabis from an
unlicensed retailer they probably don't
know that that's supporting an
unlicensed supply chain they probably
don't know that it's untested that it
hasn't met those requirements we just
talked about and so as we're looking at
bringing several brands this being one
of them several cooperative brands mind
you I'm only going to represent
cooperative cannabis from here on out
because I believe Humanity is competing
itself into extinction so you know as we
as we move forward with this we're not
advertising the farms the varietals the
strains so much as we're advertising our
retail partners these guys are out there
on the front line we need to the general
public to understand that they are the
gatekeeper to good clean sustainable
cannabis it's just the way it is that's
a fact from now on and so yes of course
the video of the person watering it is
great but what about a map of places to
get sustainable cannabis what about
little stars where every retailer is and
so well you can talk about them I'm
gonna stay away from talking about them
frankly
and so you know this idea of of
highlighting this new emerging market
and and trust me I've got one foot not
one foot a part of my heart is in the
old world a lot of my family most of my
friends have not made this transition
and so it pains me deeply to say that
what we need to do is focus all of this
attention on the licensed marketplace
because I do think that there was a lot
of injustice embedded in our so-called
legalization initiative and I think
we've got a lot more work to do but the
truth of the matter is it is what it is
I'm a pragmatic realist and at this
point we need people to be going to the
licensed stores that's what's going to
drive the market that's going to make it
so that people care about our varietals
and care about our Appalachians and care
about all of that stuff so as we look at
we will be acquiring a delivery or a
distribution license expecting
operational in March and as we look
forward at our business planning and and
you know it's really about highlighting
the retailers that's what we want to do
to help make this thing work I want to
say thank you for that and I want to say
that that's dead correct right that's
the magic the business is about the
consumer and the consumer has today too
many ways to get cannabis in the wrong
way so it my estimate of the size of the
California demand market at retail is
between 15 and 20 billion dollars a year
right now we're on track to do 3 billion
of that through the white market Channel
that means the black and gray channels
are between 12 and 17 billion dollars in
size just in California Eric can I make
a humble request when it comes to
semantics can we describe it as
regulated and unregulated as opposed to
black and white are you okay with that
I'll tell you why it needs to be this
way
because there's a gray market and in
order to get to gray you have to see
black and what if we have red
unregulated and criminal you you like
that better much better like mountains
better I really do okay I was just
thinking about this today because I'm
writing it on paper and my preference
would be to preface it by saying this is
an economic term and it means something
to economists and I didn't make it up
okay okay so would that go criminal on
black unregulated on gray and regulated
on unregulated well I mean you never you
know you don't know that you know
there's not that's not true at all
there's not there's not a big moonshine
market today there's a lot of people
that are considered criminals that
aren't they're just broke so yeah they
can't afford to get regulated that
regulated market is a beast okay so I'll
just clarify when I use these three
terms regulate it's pretty clear right
regulated means you have a license and
you can prove that you're following the
rules unregulated means you would be if
that was attainable criminal means you
have no intent of participating those
are the three camps that I see I
actually have seven categories and big
into archetypes but we'll stick with the
three all right now I want to talk about
differentiation in the marketplace and
how that's going to happen from the
distribution and retail level and what
you need from us so meaning how do we
honor Appalachians how do we honor Sun
and and soil grown cannabis Sun star and
Moon grown cannabis as Swami would say
you know so how do we get people to buy
ugly weed that isn't but to them they're
used to vertically integrated indoors
filling this in the shelves of their
retailers so the answer is tell a story
tell it about the grower tell it about
the product tell it about the experience
that you have when you use the product
tell them about why it's great product
tell a story write a brand needs to be
built and brand I have three heard of
definitions of brand that I like number
one a brand is what they say about you
when you leave the room number two is a
brand is the difference between the
product cost and the retail price that's
brand the whole thing is brand brands
build tribes so if you want a following
you said it you need a following he's
looking for brands that have followings
that's what great brands do they have
followings I used to be in the beer
business and I'm gonna tell you a funny
story Narragansett beer was my brand and
I would go out and sell beer we we've
had three partners and we said for the
last 18 months at the time that I was
there we're gonna go to 50 bars a week
each so I would go to our after bar
after bar and I would if I walked into
the bar and they didn't have our beer I
would try to sell it if they did have
our beer I would buy six or eight of
them I'd line him up on the on the bar
and anybody who wanted a beer I'd try to
give him away right do you know that
there was one type of person who I could
never give a Narragansett beer to anyone
want to guess who that was no plenty of
women any other guesses no no they were
grabbing two at a time the bud drinkers
you couldn't come all set no really it's
a free beer nope I'm good I'm good I can
afford my own beer I can I'm good anyway
that's a tribe when when you so the
final definition of brand is you have a
real brand when someone won't accept a
free version of a competitive product
that's a real brand okay so that's good
for what another tasks you hear this is
another thing we have to do what are you
doing to help create a differentiation
in the marketplace I'm saying like we're
telling the story I mean we're here
where it's non-stop we feel like we tell
our story
all they were in the grocery store
telling our story to each other we
practice rehearse our story we are so
storied it's ridiculous what are you
doing down here to help us create a
differentiation in the marketplace and
this goes from distro and then what can
distro do for retailers and then what
can retailers do to the consumer because
at the end of the day you know yeah we
can put it on social a lot of us don't
go on social you know a lot of us just
grow really good weed and so it's like
what do we do when it gets to you and
it's really good and how do you create
that differentiation in the marketplace
or I'm not saying how do you think how
are you helping do that let me start
from the retail point of view it's
really about like Eric said crafting a
narrative if there's not one that
already exists and it really extracting
it from your your you know your
producing partner and and then taking a
chance and putting that out there and
really standing behind it fully you know
and sometimes you have to take risk
right there are you were talking about
Appalachians Justin you know how do we
really be make that a known thing well a
distributor a distributor can call it
whatever they want a cultivator can call
it whatever they want but it doesn't
matter unless your retail partner is
standing behind you and what you believe
so if you are a manufacturer out there
producer out there you've got to find
someone who's willing to take that risk
with you and really carve out a niche in
the market and and the people who take
that risk are the people who create new
beautiful things and create movements so
a lot of it is risk you know it's it's
really taking a chance and being a
godforsaken entrepreneur it's what we're
all doing out here you know some few
things again not a distributor a
retailer but I'm gonna apply in any way
there's a lot of different ways to tell
your story I tell my story to my close
friends oftentimes with laughter and
tears I tell my story in the legislature
with a lot of strength and confidence
and I tell my consumer my story to the
consumer with a bit of lightheartedness
and brevity and so keep in mind that
marketing is this particular
type of storytelling and the the second
and most important thing in my opinion
is truth truth in all things but truth
in advertising not all cannabis is great
even if you're great grower some
cannabis is just not awesome and that's
okay there's a there's a place at the
market for that too the the number one
thing that we can do to damage our
brands in my opinion is described it as
top shelf when it's not and try to
charge top shelf prices for it when it
doesn't warrant it in my opinion only 1%
of the flower grown a year is the top 1%
of flower
that's just how math works I will pay
more for the top 1% of the harvest I
will I connoisseur I've been smoking
well not gonna get into how long I've
been smoking because I'm pretty young
but for long enough to know the
difference you know I don't want to get
a sore throat no matter how pretty it
looks if you didn't flush it I'm gonna
get a sore throat when I smoke it and so
you know really being honest and and
there's there's actually a law that you
mentioned the appellations law and
there's a few words in there that you
know they weren't there originally and i
put them there and caught some flak for
it but standards and practices in my
opinion if we don't have clear
agreed-upon standards with which we can
reference our story and fact check
ourselves then it's just a bunch of
marketing drivel and who cares let's
tell the truth that's what cannabis is
about and truth in advertising truth in
marketing is what's going to make brands
distinguish themselves in my opinion and
to be clear that standards and practices
under the silo of origin don't make this
a pain point discussion can I jump in
with another suggestion you guys are
trying to figure out how to tell your
story and and and hezekiah got on the
right track when he was talking about
different things at different times in
different ways one of the most important
things that a grower needs to figure out
is whether they just want to be a grower
or they want to be a grower and
a brand because those are different and
if you just want to be a grower go find
a bunch of other growers and get
together and find one of them who wants
to build a brand and use all their stuff
[Music]
that's Ocean Spray that's that's exactly
what a co-op is I didn't want to
prescribe it if you don't want to do it
as a co-op do it as a different way the
point is there's lots of ways you could
do it it has a kinds of co-op so do it
his way but but don't try to do it if
you don't want to do it and don't be
confused if you're not getting it right
if you're not spending any time on it ya
know be having a brand's being a public
figure being a public figure is tricky
especially for underground growers I
mean let's just be real if especially if
you want to have a personality driven
brand like it's a lot of work and you
know what at the end of the day there's
not gonna be 50,000 cannabis brands that
emerge from California that's how many
growers we estimate there were there's
probably going to be a few hundred maybe
a few thousand but at the end of the day
a lot of growers working together is how
we're going to build the brand Network
that's going to to make this market work
yeah please do
please
coming from that perspective of I have a
collective 64 and in order to maximize
you know our resources and pool our
cannabis and we need to have one brand
but here we are faced with this stupid
regulation that's that might just
sure so the the regulation that she's
talking about I think it's five zero
three two which basically disallows the
languages non licensees cannot be on a
branded product a non licensee cannot
give specific direction to a licensee on
how they can put together a product so
basically kind of puts aside this white
labeling arrangement and a lot of other
things because actually taken to any
sort of logical or legal I mean frankly
analysis that section would mean that
you like they're their issues with
contracts so question whether you could
even enter into a contract for a lease
right so you have to own the property I
mean the whole thing is kind of
outrageous our firm tons of other firms
lots of organizations wrote many lengthy
pages about why this section is very
problematic hopefully this will get
kicked I wonder if the reason why we saw
it written as such is really because the
agencies really want to see more
transparency and that's really what
they're going for so we made some
proposals as to how we can kind of
change the language but in the in in the
case that you're talking about if you're
talking about sixty licensees then you
are a licensee right so that yeah I
don't see that you would have a you
would have a problem were I mean and I
don't know the specifics of your
situation but if everyone if you are all
licensed you would not be impacted by
the way that section is written from
what I know of what you're describing
would that be yeah would it be true if
that if the brand didn't represent all
of the farmers but the farmers were
selling through the brand can I do you
mind if I just jump in here because
she's dead on this isn't gonna fly it
doesn't fly because it flies in the face
of normal licensing everyday business
whether you're talking about the media
industry or or toys or candy right so
it's it's gonna go away but let me just
say one more thing I can show you how to
defeat it right now just give a share of
your stock to everybody in it one share
you call them an owner and they all
the license yeah yeah yeah basically
basically if the rule if the rule goes
as is as drafted give me a call and
we'll share with you the the way to get
around it which is like what's the point
of the rules if we're just trying to
figure out all these ways to get around
it but okay if that's your system like
we were saying earlier then we know what
your game is and we'll give you what you
want to see you know but I agree I don't
think that I I mean we if we're to we
passed I mean my god Hezekiah like we
like worked on this whole statewide
let's regulate the industry program over
all of these years because we care about
the cottage industry because we care
about the small medium-sized operators
because we care about diversity in the
industry because we care about women and
people of color and opportunity for
people to create wealth that have you
know all of these like you know
wonderful truthful beautiful things that
make our heart sing and make us wake up
every day and do the work that we do and
this is just another example of
regulations really kind of dampening
that hugely and potentially pushing a
lot of that side because then you have
smaller or just brands or smaller
operators who can't go and get a license
and enter the market but as I was saying
there you know we'll figure out
workarounds and hopefully all of the you
know letters and lobbying and
dissatisfaction that we have all
expressed in written and many other
forms will will you know we'll see some
changes in the rules I I want to bring
something up here and you know it's
something that I do often into in life
which is why did that happen and and I
and I'm gonna try my best not to be
negative here but but its bordering on a
slippery slope there there are people
who are lobbying for this there are
people who believe that since they have
a license everyone else should be shut
out there's a tendency in regulated
markets to see barriers to entry as a
good thing because it solidifies your
control of your place in the market
there was a very clear understanding in
2014 that there was an environmental
crisis and a public safety crisis caused
by the lack of regulation for cannabis
what I moved to Sacramento to do was to
try to add a third to that list which
that there is also a small business
crisis real hard-working Californians
are also in crisis because of the lack
of regulation we did a pretty damn good
job but we could have done better and
the reason that in some ways that I'm
shifting the focus that I am and that
I've been so focused on conversations
direct with consumer is that we need
Californians to stand up for other
Californians we need everyone to realize
and recognize that our small business
owners that beautiful diversity that
Arielle outlined of all the different
boxes and even the people who don't fit
in any boxes they have a place in
cannabis we didn't do a good enough job
of making that message known we didn't
do a good enough job of making that the
consensus but we're not lost yet we're
not done yet we still need it we need
every single person to tell ten more
that there is a small business crisis we
are losing a wealth of value frankly and
there are people who actually see it the
opposite they see their wealth through a
controlled market I see the wealth as
something that we all need to share and
I think all of you do - that's probably
why we're here together but there are
there are folks who don't and so do
always remember you know the parable of
sheeps and wolves clothing and all that
their weight their the other way just
remember that that different people have
different motivations and different
intentions so something that I was gonna
open it up to questions yeah I just have
one bit of good news before you open it
up for question but good news is that
the guy that we just elected governor of
the great state of California is a small
business guy he ran on small business
his Blue Ribbon Commission report had a
small business clause in it where he was
protecting the small business owners so
he hasn't been in a control position
like he's going to be in in January but
I think there's good good things
happening on the horizon for small
businesses in California I don't think
any large politician actually has all of
our best interests at heart but he was
you know he's good he's good he's ish
anyway
I'll give them a nish ok so does anybody
have any pressing questions this is like
some of the best minds in the biz and
they're like right in front of you I
mean we we've had they think three
successive years of bills we've never
actually gotten it out of the
legislature the the reason being I mean
when you talk about it it really does
depend on what type of research you're
talking about I guess just to be clear
when you're talking about research on
human subjects you're talking about a
very hyper regulated activity that we
don't actually have the authority as a
state to do when it comes to research on
pesticides it's all going like all of
the research that doesn't involve
consumers is exploding right now and
it's amazing but when it comes to human
subjects we just don't have the
authority at the state level I'd like to
jump in and say something yesterday I
was in Las Vegas for the day at a
medical cannabis symposium and it was a
symposium with doctors and researchers
from around the globe who are doing
clinical trials involving cannabis and
it was really eye-opening it was
probably I would say a couple hundred
folks and everyone would present their
research and talk about what they're
doing in their respective country and it
was interesting to hear about the
barriers in the United States to
research because of the scheduling of
cannabis versus how things are in Greece
or Canada or some other countries and it
was really wonderful to have an
opportunity to also talk with these
researchers and doctors and talk about
how they can bring from a you know
factually based perspective and through
what they find through their research
how they can help create policy change
internationally as relates to cannabis
so that we can see you know a really
well informed conversation around this
so I know that doesn't speak to
California but I just thought it was a
quite quite a wonderful gathering of
very smart minds that also showed
how little the medical community how
much research is is is limited because
of the status of cannabis in so many
countries and certainly the US and and
how that that community of brilliant
intellectual healing folks are really
just kind of at at their infancy so I
hope for for that we entered into a new
research model this year which was
exciting which is a community driven
research project and the CD RPS and
people from UC Irvine and a few other
universities are actually saying that
seems viable and they weren't worried
about the you know the schedule of
cannabis they were saying this is really
a community driven research project
they're doing you know herbarium
pressings and testings but it's it's you
know it's by the community for the
community that it serves so you you
usually can't do it on the whole so you
can't from what I heard from these
scientists is that you can't do it on
the whole plant you can do it with
certain compounds and depending on what
the university research and institution
allows and what the applicable laws are
so it's very limited and then there's
oversight by the feds so they show up to
these doctors uh you know research
institutions and look through everything
and make sure everything is a hundred
percent you know legal to the extent you
know that that whatever is required
one or more chemicals whose isolation
processes extraction processes I mean
there's distillation there's a number of
extraction methods you you turn the
plant into a bunch of individual source
chemicals and/or multiple chemicals in a
compound and then research those can I
ask a question I want to know what
everybody including you Justin learned
in 2018 what what did you expect but you
didn't see or what did you not see that
you expected to see in 2018 you only get
one answer i I learned what I
articulated on the last question that
some folks see barriers to entry as a
good thing I I spent three years
prepping for a bill that we ran that we
ultimately lost because the industry was
split on it it was a bill that would
have allowed for sales to take place at
an event like this it would have allowed
growers to directly showcase their
products and sell them directly to
consumers I spent you know in 2014 I
started the conversation with the
narcotics Officers Association of
America not joking sat down with their
lobbyist and said yeah what's it gonna
take to get here by 2018 I thought we
were there we had local government on
board we had law enforcement on board
and you know what did it
a group of retailers not the Southern
California Coalition by the way these
guys were solid couldn't quite get on
board to support but hey you didn't
fight us which honestly like we can
disagree but the fact that we were lined
up fighting with other businesses it was
a real wake-up call for me I you know I
grew up in a different world I didn't
grow up where unrepentant self-interest
was acceptable I grew up in a world
where unrepentant self-interest was
immoral so that's what I learned in 2018
I don't know if I'll earn this but it
was certainly reinforced and that's that
nothing happens unless you make it
happen you know you've got to get out
there and and you've got to be
relentless about it and you've got to
get in front of the people that you
really don't want to be talking to and
and sway them be persuasive and and
don't give up until you get what you
want
simple as that I mean I guess I learned
I wasn't as smart as I thought I was
thanks Michael no I mean things came at
at me this year I mean that this shit
comes at me every day and always has but
this year it came at me from people that
I didn't think it was going to and you
know people that have had the
opportunity to come together for the
longest time seemed to do the cut the
nose despite the face thing and so I I
feel like this year I learned I learned
who my friends were you know and and you
know and I and I and I'd be nice Hockman
I learned I don't know it was like
there's like an encyclopedia of what I
learned this year I haven't stopped
learning like just just this week just
this week I learned how can hard it is
for a small batch cultivator although
all the shit we've done for the last
three years to figure some of this stuff
out just to get enough cannabis to maybe
pay a week's worth of employees into the
retail market was for us and that wasn't
that that was a laundry list Bobby thank
you because Bobby had the opportunity at
many times to say dude I got a business
to run really like you know that's it
you know good good model I'm sure it's
gonna work
you know and
watching how these brands enter into the
marketplace and and what we've already
had to face with the Herculean licensing
with building and planning being against
us our own community against us our own
growers our neighbors against like all
these things and then to and then to see
that like just to get a few grams to be
able to smoke outside which you're not
supposed to smoke the crab's is so idle
but whatever happened here today
just to have it happen here was I mean
it was ridiculous and nauseating and
tiring and I want to go to sleep I want
to take a nap
Michael wants to take a nap Bobby
probably wants to take a nap and anybody
who's involved in the process so I
learned a lot about what we're really
facing you know so yeah I I learned the
power of politics and politicians and
local government especially I you know
when the mmrsa when when all those and
we was about to pass and then it passes
and then okay so what's the new
landscape how do people run businesses
you have to have a local permit to get a
state license okay who are all these
local what are these local offices who
are these elected officials what's the
building and planning department
what you know how do you like pulling
permits dealing with in the Bay Area we
dealt with that but in most of the rest
of the state you're not dealing with
local elected officials than these
smaller little offices to go through a
whole local entitlement process and it
is incredible to me that still I think
70 percent of local jurisdictions aren't
even issuing business licenses for
cannabis companies and that in the 30
percent that do it's usually incredibly
expensive incredibly politicized you
have to be so well capitalized I mean a
snapshot of the industry I had a coffee
with our the director of the department
of cannabis regulation in the city of La
this last week and I told her snapshot
of the industry the dispensaries in the
city of La that are operating right now
most of them are struggling because the
illegal shops you've got the people who
are waiting in line for licensing and
you just kind of go down the line
and it's struggle struggle struggle
struggle struggle and yet who are the
ones that make the choice for people to
get a license yeah it's the voters and
it's how we vote on these issues but we
voted overwhelmingly for cannabis but
then we also have communities who say
yeah not in my backyard so whether it's
through you know these neighborhood
councils or other kind of local groups
or the kind of local established offices
themselves no a lot of challenges
getting through those gatekeepers
so really seeing into in the City of LA
into this whole political machine has
been incredibly eye-opening as well as
in other jurisdictions across across the
state so really the power of the the
power of all of that mind blowing brain
exploding my biggest learning is how
quickly the cream rises to the top how
quickly in a time of turmoil a time of
change a time of indecision and the time
of unknown the cream rises and you know
as as my partner former partner used to
say when the snow melts the shit shows
the snows been melting for a while in
this industry and just like everything
else it's starting to become clear who
your friends are who the good people are
right anybody could be good when things
are going well right it's the hard
decisions the ones where you have to
make a trade-off that are the ones that
determine whether you know how to make
the right decision and then it turns
into cottage cheese
and off to the top it goes into the
fridge where everyone enjoys it and then
everyone's like we're gonna turn the
rest into cottage cheese so if you farm
I mean that's a long-lasting tarantula
[Laughter]
all right is there anybody else that has
another question I mean come on sure so
first distributors are doing it
themselves so direct distribution
logistics only distribution where the
brand might have a sales team in the
market initiating the sales but then
when it comes time to deliver it and
collect the money that's happening with
third party outfit and then full-service
distribution which is you just drop your
product off at a warehouse and the
selling and the testing and the delivery
and the retail relations happens with
that third party distributor I'm gonna
give the mic back to Hezekiah I was
gonna see if you guys wanted to hear a
poem so you know this is something I
were a little bit ago actually a lot a
bit ago thinking about legalization and
thinking about what it would mean
anything is every bit as relevant now as
it was then so even as felons my friends
have grown and there's no telling when
the change will come home sometimes I
can't see through the haze and smoke
sometimes I can't breathe and it makes
me choke and there's no telling when the
change will come home but I'm feeling
that it's soon and it fills me with hope
shit
fuck it I lost that you guys I'm sorry
we'll have to get high and do it outside
well that was really kind of you
all right so even as felons my friends
have grown and there's no telling when
the change will come home that's what I
want to reiterate though is there's a
lot of really good people that have done
time there's a lot of really good people
that have had their lives ruined and
shattered and as was noted 70% of
California still doesn't have
legalization seventy-five of the hundred
most populous cities are still living in
those shadows most of the cultivation
communities are still living in those
shadows when I started this work I
realized that there were about 53,000 of
us there's less than 1,700 people who
have been licensed I want you all to
realize that we have a lot of work to do
the change hasn't come home we're lost
we can't see through this haze and smoke
but we are gonna get there if we do it
together and that's why I really want to
underscore the importance of cooperation
the importance of working together and
this isn't just about cannabis like
we're on the verge of extinction you
guys our planet is dying and we are
killing it we are the reason for all of
this we're going to need to work
together if it's going to get better so
let's go get high and take that first
step and get started now if you're
sowing clients no pressure though if you
don't want it that's a perfect segue
into a raffle
[Music]