[Music]
now once a good morning to each and
every one of you to the incredible
organizers the activists the advocates
the community members the retailers the
distributors the manufacturers the
cultivators to each and every one of you
for bringing this together at this very
very amazing event now if you were to
ask me perhaps 10 years ago that I'd be
keynoting an address at the cannabis at
a cannabis conference on a haunted ship
I would have asked you to give me some
of what you were smoking you know and if
I thought that our former attorney
general of the great city of California
would be here also to mr. Bill Lockyer
in the house right over here let's get
up for the Attorney General Bill Lockyer
a great businessman himself also to who
understands the the incredible benefits
of the cannabis industry for the great
city of California in the nation but let
me say this we are at a very critical
time a very critical moment in our
nation's history where our essential
human and constitutional rights are at
stake it's time that we double down on
what we believe that the cannabis
industry in California carries the
bright green promise of good high wage
paying jobs a boost to our state budget
and growth for our local labor
organizations right now as we all know
as we've known for a very long time the
federal law puts cannabis on the list of
narcotics right next to heroin as well
as cocaine on Schedule one which to me
and two I know everybody on this ship
right now and everyone across the state
of California thinks is utterly
ridiculous and observe considering how
many states today have actually
legalized cannabis either for medicinal
or recreational use and that total today
is 29 states across the country as a
result cannabis accounts for more than
half of drug arrests in the United
States now I just want you to let that
sink in just for a moment because in
2016 alone in 2016 alone there were more
than 600,000 people charged with
cannabis violations now growing up in
Logan Heights for those who are from San
Diego or who live in San Diego I watched
the impacts of the United States has
failed war on drugs unfold before my
very own eyes families torn apart and a
promising futures that were cut short as
law enforcement disproportionately
arrested poor people and poor people of
color for cannabis crimes my neighbor's
my friends even some of my family
members our nation's kafka esque federal
laws against us plants or the beginning
of an extremely toxic relationship
between communities like mine and law
enforcement it is time that we put an
end to this unjust practice by electing
real leaders at the federal level who
are focused on D scheduling cannabis as
we know it today and if you want and if
we do want a government that will truly
improve the human condition for all
individuals regardless of who they are
regardless of where they come from
regardless of the hue their skin
regardless of which god they pray to or
who they love or yes even their legal
status if we want a federal government
that truly improves a human condition
for all individuals the rest of the
nation as well as our senior senator
from California should join California
in pushing for racial justice and
demanding reforms to our broke countries
broken cannabis laws system as we know
it today now we had a senator who's
going to be here today and we had a
conversation where this morning at
senator Steve Bradford
I've actually called him Steve EB
and he has a measure that is sitting on
the governor's desk which is Senate bill
12 94 which deals with the issues of
equity with regards to making sure those
individuals who were caught up by the
unjust laws and by the scheduling
scheduling one of cannabis have a real
opportunity to be entrepreneurs
themselves and have a real opportunity
to be successful in the cannabis
industry because for those who may not
know I've always been a strong supporter
of green energy and that learners should
be being clean renewable energy in
California today a governor signed my
law which puts us on a 100% pathway to
clean energy by the year 2045 with the
largest economy on planet earth that has
legally mandated 100% clean energy for
the great state of California we are
moving this state the fifth largest
economy in the world towards a green
energy space well we'll have high wage
jobs renewable clean energy well it's
not just about green energy in the clean
energy space but it's about green energy
too in a new renewable space which is
cannabis as I know it as we know it
today the twin pillars of an economy are
the fifth largest economy in the world
today and think about this we are the
largest sub-national in the world to
legalize cannabis both medicinal as well
as recreational use and we're the
largest economy in the world to commit
to decarbonize the grid by 100 percent
legally these are going to be the twin
pillars if you will of our economy and
we need to make sure that we're
inclusive but we also need to make sure
that Washington DC gets its act together
in California we demonstrate to the rest
of the world that cannabis can be
legalized and a just safe and profitable
way now I know we have a lot more work
to do
starting with working together to
stabilize and strengthen this growing
industry even in a state like California
where the rest of the country receives
70% of our exports for starters we need
to make sure
that existing small cannabis businesses
are able to grow and flourish in their
own rights to avoid a hostile takeover
this industry by extremely very powerful
corporations we must focus on building
solid banking infrastructure so business
owners aren't forced to risk their lives
every single day carrying thousands
hundreds of thousands of dollars in cash
just to pay their taxes that's like a
Kafka novel once again we are we have
legalized constitutionally through pop
64 the recreational use of cannabis but
the same time many of your lives are put
at risk every single day because the
federal laws and we don't allow for the
banking to actually occur now I'll be
your champion and your voice in
Washington in the US Senate to put
cannabis on track for for federal
legalization so we can stabilize this
industry and put people to work and I
will be your advocate here today have no
doubt about that
so as long as it is incorrectly
classified as a schedule 1 drug the
industry here in California won't be
able to stabilize or grow for more than
20 years our cannabis industry has been
forced to operate as we know in the
shadows prop 215 the compassionate
caregiver Act of 1996 hoped to change
that by legalizing the MIS the medicinal
use of cannabis in California but the
lack of local cooperation made this in
fact to some degree a toothless law even
with the passage of Prop 64 the federal
government is still threatening
businesses who comply with state law
only to get caught in the vise the vise
grip of federal cannabis law enforcement
we have a Department of Justice headed
up by Jeff Sessions who has made it very
clear that he will do everything within
his power to shut down the cannabis
industry now there is a confluence of
intersectionality on the issue that we
care deeply about the right to breathe
clean air into our lungs the right to
drink clean water the right for our
families who have been here 10 15 20 25
years to be legalized in the greatest
country in the world and to not live in
fear live in the shadows not knowing if
at 4:00 in the morning there'll be a
hard knock at the door with ice agents
or young children feeling the fear of
anxiety young children not knowing if
their mother's or Father's are going to
pick them up after school I was in
Oxnard yesterday at an elementary school
fifth graders 5th graders and these
young boys and girls at this school were
incredibly precocious so intelligent so
smart with huge dreams and aspirations
their parents many of them actually pick
strawberries in Oxnard in batura County
citrus and Piru Sunkiss lemons oranges
limes
and they all talked about Donald Trump
and I want to be respectful for any
folks here who may be supportive Donald
Trump but I don't think there are any
always any they'll come out of the
closet
you know today but that being said these
fifth these fifth graders were so
intuitive to what was happening in the
country today and I can say this
Republican or Democrat that I Drive a
lot of my although I'm a former assembly
member the state senator today just
recently until just a few months ago the
leader of the California State Senate
your state Senate along with my good
friend and colleague the former Pro Tem
himself Bill Lockyer it's a very small
very illustrious club only handful of
individuals who ever held that title I'm
not as political as people think I am in
terms of sitting with political
consultants and sitting with pollsters
would have you cetera I watch and I
watch constituents and the people I care
deeply about and on November 9th 2016
the day after the election when you saw
young kids as young as kindergarten
crying crying because who was elected as
president I don't recall any children of
any Republican crying when Barack Obama
was elected presidents the United States
in fact I don't even recall any children
of any Democrat no matter how left how
liberal that Democrat activist may be
crying when George W Bush was elected to
the presidency United States but to have
children crying not from joy but
actually from deep fear who was about to
possess the most powerful office in the
world and what it meant for them and
their families
when you have young children crying
that's what drives me in my
decision-making right there so when you
have a Department of Justice that seeks
to make sure that cannabis stays
Schedule one and seeks to divide our
families and to make sure that this
industry does not grow and it's not
successful and we're not going to do
banking we're gonna make sure you stay
in the most
position possible in terms of just cash
only this is why we need the right
leadership the right leadership like
with my good friend Reggie Jones soya
right here who will be one of your
keynote speakers has been a great
champion for all of you in our state
capital folks like Rob Manta who will be
here later on today from oak town from
Oakland
Stevie Brad for who couldn't be here
today as well as of Carlotta who
couldn't be here at all today as well to
folks like roberto
robert garcia that's why elections are
consequential they matter they make a
difference let me finish up here in the
first quarter of this year alone
cannabis brought into our california
state budget
sixty point nine million dollars
mustachios just rounded office of
seventy you know sixty point nine
million dollars and we expect the excise
tax of bringing more than half a billion
dollars by the end of this year we can
invest these critical dollars in
improving our education system expanding
law enforcement resources and building
an economy that works for all of us not
just for some but for all of us
what we're building here in california
could become a model for the rest of the
nation we're cutting a path for for
other states and our federal government
to follow it's time for real leadership
and we'll bring this industry out of the
shadows so we can get to work achieving
the economic growth this industry
promises because we know that the status
quo is not working the same ol same ol
is not working the status quo in fact is
too dangerous it's not sustainable and
it's a result of weak leadership in
Washington DC let me show you this
finally this is why because passing 215
medicinal use of cannabis and passing
prop 60 for recreational use of cannabis
and everything else that we need to do
in California this is why we must remain
America's exceptional example a beacon
of hope and opportunity in a very
uncertain world that we're not going to
allow as California it's one electoral
aberration
reverse generations of progress at the
height of our historic diversity our
scientific advancement our economic
output in our sense of global
responsibility that's our role to
advocate to agitate to organize to make
sure that we are respected and that
we're legitimize that we are a true
pillar of the economy of California so
folks can come out of the shadows and
they can grow their businesses and be
successful and we have an inclusive
diverse economy that benefits everybody
not just somebody not just those at the
highest economic strata but actually
improving the condition for all
individuals regardless of who they are
and where they come from to each and
every one of you I want we shoot the
very best today in a very successful
successful conference as you engage in
so many critical issues they're
important to the vitality of this
industry not just for California but for
the rest of the nation
because as California goes as you know
the rest of the nation will follow
especially Washington with that god
bless each and every one of you have a
wonderful conference take care much all
right thank you
[Music]