I'd love to just start by going down the
line actually you guys change order in
my view but starting with she kind of
who is who in your mind is your target
demographic and what's the main product
you sell to them and what are the trends
you're seeing in terms of growth decline
and whatnot good morning well I am a
cannabis farmer up here in Northern
California Mendocino County and
primarily my farm just produces top
shelf flour from my own brand for other
brands and so that's my my priority so
flour consumers would be my number one
target audience at this moment obviously
I do sell my biomass and my shake to
companies manufacturers who turn that
into various things but my primary
concern is having my flour sold yeah
what what what percentage of your
harvest goes to or I guess you said your
shake but so all the flour you keep for
your own brand sales and then what how
much shake is going out for white label
I just did a calculation for last year's
harvest and we had about thirty percent
of our income was from shake from last
year so you know it's a significant
portion it's kind of interesting to see
in the end of 2019 and this so far in
2020 the shake sales shake buyers have
gone way down I'm not getting thousands
of inquiries every day from shake buyers
like I was in 2018 20 beginning of 2019
I basically paid my bills by selling
shake like really I could have just
turned my flower into shake and sold it
faster than I could have sold flour back
then so you know the times have turned I
now I'm getting calls multiple
voicemails every day from some random
guy who works from some random company
looking for flour so you know
looking for flower to white label or
flower with men or are canta flowers
brand on it yeah well so just to be
clear I operate Mendocino generations
which is a group of fifty farms a lot of
those farms have their own brands most
of those farms sell their flower to
other brands and me personally I sell my
flower probably 75% of my flower goes to
other companies who put it in their own
branding and then the other portion of
my flower goes into my brand which is
called Arkana flowers so yeah there
they're putting it into probably some
portion of pre-rolls top shelf pre rolls
that are made you know exclusively from
flower as well as putting it in their
branded jars and such
got it Chelsea who's your target
audience
who's your archetype my my demographic
is definitely boomers it's interesting
because that it's it kind of derived
naturally out of how kind of my whole
company brand started my first product
was just something I made for my grandma
it kind of got this award and all of a
sudden the public knew about it and I
had to create the business at that point
so like I was saying the first product
being specifically designed for my
grandma who is you know a Jehovah's
Witness very not cannabis friendly
especially just given her age her
background and so that that naturally
derived kind of who my target audience
would be and like right after we won our
first emerald cup I remember the
Sacramento Bee did a write-up about us
and you know like it was in the print
version buried in the pages tiny little
font and yet you know 200 boomers
probably busted out a magnifying glass
to read my email address and just blew
me up and so that's kind of how we got
started just serving our local
Sacramento community
and taking it from there but the way it
links up to what we're doing now with
the delivery service is that those 200
original customers which you know we're
all older people all people with pain
all people who were in the process of
getting picked off their opiate regimens
they they're kind of the customer Bates
that I still have a deep loyalty to so
when kovat happened and it became really
unclear if people would be able to still
have access especially being an older
generation more vulnerable like maybe
even going out to do curbside isn't an
option I knew that I had to like quickly
get a delivery on board and to start
making sure that they could get safe
deliveries at their homes so the
delivery service I partnered with offers
contactless delivery they got it
approved through the BCC you know
emergency regulation style and so we're
able to they're able to go to my website
but they're familiar with by my products
and another other selected products
curated and get that delivered to their
home with no contact with the driver and
that's that's how we're working at HLC
we were talking yesterday about
compassion programs as well in
California is that a part of what you
are you able to utilize that and save
some tax money and that type of stuff um
so what I do is if I hover have any
inventory that's getting you know within
four months or so of its CoA is
expiration and they I just shipped all
of that inventory over to compassion
programs and so we're in the process of
doing that right now we're gonna
probably be putting out about like 300
units of the deep skin into various
compassion programs around the state are
you seeing that there's a need I'm sorry
can you elaborate on the mechanics of
because compassion is recently back
right so can you explain like when you
say we're gonna give it like
whoo-hoo-hoo are you giving it to is a
profit
no no just just normal retailers as long
as they are prepared to deal with you
know the meticulous of properly
documenting these transactions they can
do it and they don't have to pay taxes
and you don't have to pay taxes and the
the patient doesn't have to
pay taxes or what's the taxes I I don't
I'm not an expert
I have someone who figures that part out
for me I'm just trying to get people
taken care of
I like it given away product Julie I'm
pretty sure that that was recently
amended correct you don't have to pay
taxes on compassion products I can speak
to a little bit if you want to so we had
some product that had expired the
testing you know the test expired and
last July and we were not sure what to
do with this stuff and at that time I
was in contact with with a a man who's
called sweetleaf Joe and right and he's
been calling everybody really and so so
I had like started down this pathway of
trying to figure out how to is about six
pounds of flour and the tax rate is was
at that point one hundred and forty
eight dollars per pound right so in
order for me to donate that six pounds I
have to pay over eight hundred something
dollars in order to donate it it cannot
be donated unless I pay that tax and
I've already lost six times whatever the
pound price could have been plus
trimming it packaging it labeling it
testing it etc so now I'm out somewhere
around eight grand just to try to donate
some flour and personally as a farm like
I can't really do it and I don't know
what to do with it but either way I have
to pay for it I have to pay for it to
get destroyed or I have to pay for it to
get donated kind of a tough one have you
tried making any donations recently yeah
so this is still in the process so I'm
not totally sure what's going to happen
I were still kind of all figuring it out
cuz that's what I was under the
impression of the beginning that it was
like
oh we're gonna donate this and it's like
we get to write it off well not really
so well we'll see I I think over the
next like month or so I shouldn't have
an answer about that okay Mike do you
wanna talk about your your target
demographic with your solvent list hash
got a better more than more than happy
to so both of our brands are are
targeting the market at large we don't
wanna you know pigeonhole ourselves at
all we definitely are interested in the
over 65 the boomers we're really keen on
them I loved what you were saying
Chelsea I love your brand where you're
going I was so awesome the passion is
obviously there and your trajectory is
noble so you know those things are hard
to come by now in marijuana business so
it's awesome to hear and see that yeah
Kalli hash is definitely it's a it's a
solvent less hash brand it's geared for
the market at large
we're definitely keen on you know the
older people the younger people
all the people more importantly our new
brand hash hash lab line of products is
gonna be all solvent less based
therapeutic holistic non combustible
products where I think tinctures mostly
right features sublinguals topicals all
of those things but nothing combustible
so nothing you're gonna be smoking so
really gearing towards the medicinal
side of that of the industry and really
making a stark contrast between a
lifestyle brand and a medicinal brand
and what those two things are and why
they're different and they're very
different and you know as we evolved as
an industry the medicinal side is only
gonna grow in importance and volume and
all of those things Tamara I wanted to
ask you a quick question
now that I have you I love your company
by the way fucking amazing very
expensive but very amazing we are you
work you mentioned that the the volume
is growing in
in some of the smaller purchasing
products I phrase that the lower
pricepoint
thank you is that the race to the bottom
of the weed competition that's currently
happening or no actually in the street
there's a real feeling that there's a
real race to the bottom when it comes to
the flower brands just heading it out I
did it's all about who's got the most
money to withstand the most time and and
in total me it's so holy I want to get
your take on that so so it's funny it's
funny that you say that because actually
I do agree that right now one of the
biggest indicators of six success is
less on the demand side and more on the
supply side like who can just get
product to dispensary shelves better
than anyone else in the you're
definitely seeing within the flower
category so what I was pointing out in
the slides was specifically around the
surge days right the the days where
people were stalking off that's when you
saw a surge right along with those surge
days in the lower price point products
the under $20 products right which
indicates that people were we're
stocking up right on they wanted they
wanted more to stock up on right they
wanted more more in their back pocket at
home right in case you know they ran out
right um also anticipating for
potentially larger or you know more
consumption which I as I mentioned
earlier was definitely the case with me
overall not within those specific search
days but overall we're definitely seeing
more of a race to the bottom and I
wouldn't quite yet call it a race to the
bottom it's not Oregon right or where
Colorado is out either you know I think
California on the flower site still has
the you know second ice price point out
of all adult use markets okay Nevada
being higher but but you're definitely
seeing more value brands coming to
market right I mean Condesa and just
launched Baker's and you know we've seen
an old pal obviously taking a lot of
share
within the manufactured goods I don't
think that you're seeing you're not
seeing such a race to the bottom and so
we're not quite there yet but what what
is interesting within cannabis is right
now a lot of the pricing isn't so much
consumer driven in fact a lot of what's
happening at retail isn't really
consumer driven um you know we're not
really at a point yet where consumers
are walking in a dispensary saying I
want Kiba blueberries and then the
dispensary says I don't have cuba
blueberries and the consumer turns on
and walks out right right now a lot of
what's moving at retail is primarily
driven by the supply side and what you
said right it seems like so much of
what's moving is just dependent on who's
got the money to put it on the shelves
and you know what 100% I mean not not
that consumers don't really have an
influence right now they do but we're
not fully there yet you know we still
have a lot of brand development to do as
an industry I'm in terms of you know not
just brand awareness but also obviously
brand loyalty right now a lot of what
moves at retail is very much driven by
manufactures ability and I'm sure all of
you sitting on this panel can fully
relate to this manufacturers ability to
scale and get products on the dispensary
shelves as a manufacturer my biggest
challenge to date is distribution I'm
sure you know about the distribution
industry in our in our sector here it's
it's a shitshow you know yeah it's
ridiculous and I mean I don't see it
ever coming to a stability it's probably
the last sector of our industry that's
gonna stabilize so you know for the 15
20 % of gross you know it's just not
enough for people you know it's just
it's it's yeah so until we get people
that are managing accounts properly and
right now as a manufacturer I have to go
in and manage the accounts myself which
is infuriating you know because it's the
last thing I want to be doing I want to
be making products that's not my job but
to ensure my prep brands you know
relevance and prevalence in the market I
gotta go do it so you know it is it's
frustrating I want to ask one quick
question time in your opinion how do we
negate and the flower side of things
what's happened in washing
what's happening or again how does
California not go there on that route I
mean the elephant in the room of your
graph was all of the other states were
trending downwards you know and I see
and I sit you're absolutely correct
California was it we were absolutely the
only one trending up so how do we
maintain that how do we not become or
you know Washington um okay I'm gonna
turn off my video so we don't get cut
off again so we didn't I didn't I don't
think I showed a state-by-state view of
price points I may have laughs I saw was
just the three states year by year trend
up or down and then Washington anyway
but on the price point side though um
you know obviously a lot of that has to
do with supply and regulations right so
with or again specifically you know is a
bit of a free-for-all market right where
you know and and actually I'd be
interested to hear Chelsea and she has
speak to this but specifically Jeb but
we had you know in Oregon they were
handing out cultivation licenses like
there was no tomorrow right so you just
ended up in a situation where the market
was flooded with supply and and you know
it's also a good you know great growing
region right as is California but but
you know so so the light licensing is a
huge part and on the cultivation side
can we throw taxes into the mix what
role they play and then of taxes right
so California has some of the highest
taxation out of all states which in
general is gonna continue to impact
consumer purchasing right I mean you
know we saw with the launch of adult
youth sales flower the flower category
took the biggest hit right and that's
because with the launch of adult you
sales right I'm in January 2018 in
California a lot of consumers you know
the prop 215 like longtime consumers
they were like you know for a part I'm
not gonna
what am i friend but like f this you
know and you know this is California we
know exactly you were defined cannabis
and have never had a hard time finding
it and so before a number that was
really interesting to me you mentioned
that California still has the highest
price for four per gram of marijuana is
that is that is that a fact and how are
we in relevance to Washington or Oregon
say not the highest and and you know I I
should have actually included a slide
for this and didn't but and I could look
while we're on the caller taking a
second but if I this is amazing I think
if I remember correctly California
second and flower price to Nevada okay
so so and I and I believe that's I'm not
sure if it's with or without tax you
know I'm I'm tempted to say it's without
tax but I know Nevada has some of the
highest prices by far in fact I think
the by the tourist market of Vegas or
tourism Vegas you know I mean in general
highly taxed market right but California
because I mean I don't we can get into
why California so highly taxed but I
don't know that that's the purpose of
this call and I'm sure that you guys
have heard it it weighs you know you've
heard it you know you we've all
exhausted that subject but and also you
could probably touch on it a lot better
than I did especially none of us make
any money
[Laughter]
yeah it's a marginalist business right
now I can I can play speak for everybody
here you know as a craft producer and a
craft manufacturer it's not a it's not a
it's not a profitable enterprise you're
just out there trying to maintain your
brand keep relevant keep in the
marketplace and if you're doing that you
doing great and you know that's my
opinion that's all we're doing City of
California is your most expensive
employee yeah absolutely so just quickly
chia-you you had mentioned kind of you
as a supplier to other people in terms
of your trim and even some of the flower
Mike you're sourcing from farms to make
solvent less extraction and Chelsea is
Newell's based on solvent or solvent
list extraction that can you both talk
about developing and maintaining
relationships with suppliers of raw
material and kind of the good the bad
the ugly of finding quality suppliers
and reliable suppliers and consistent
suppliers and and go yeah I've actually
had really good luck with my suppliers
when I first started manufacturing in
the legal market we were sort of saying
ethanol extracted crude because we
mainly work in th CA and CB da so we
were sourcing ethanol extracted crude
that was made at the facility where we
did our manufacturing and they were
getting their material pretty much
exclusively from like southern on Bolton
Mendocino so you know it was pretty soon
I'm a little bit jealous of you Josie
because it sounds like you have an
easier time than me I'm sorry to hear
that man yeah yeah and it's funny is
I've never used the same source twice
because I'm always just shopping around
but uh so yeah so we had the we had that
we had the the crude that they were
making there and then they something
about a fair hazard
they wouldn't improve their extraction
any longer because of something about
the way the building was put up and so
so I had to go get it from elsewhere I
ended up getting from blessed extracts
the next time through and then the most
recent batch of products I made Wes it
had run out of what I needed and so I
actually called up Shannon Hatton
she took her flower over to a processor
and had it turned into crude and it was
in my hands a week later yeah I wish I
could say all that beautiful things like
you just said she'll see what I can I've
just our stories it's been terrible I
think it's a little bit more challenging
as a solving this producer because we
really have to be so careful about it is
you can't remediate there's no
remediation and solving this product is
your remediation you can remediate rosin
you can't remediate
you can remediate any of you really it's
either clean 100% so you know we've had
a rough time with it to be honest now
we're reduced to just finding it from
one specific lab downtown that's 900
light facility I know is super clean and
they are all the water but up north I've
had a real hard time with it because a
lot of the ground is contaminated even a
lot of these heritage farms and I'm and
I go back in the industry to the
traditional side of things these three
generation farms unfortunately a lot of
them are contaminated and I've learned
the hard way I mean I've had to shut
down my 80% of my northern production
because of it and the biomass up there
is much better and sun-grown biomass
makes much better concentrates always i
abour using lab are you talking about
chemicals are you talking about like
heavy metals more than anything heavy
metals fucking heavy metals lead what's
your process
what's your process when you go out
north for checking the cleanliness
before you make a large sale how do you
do that at first there was little
processed tongue just by and then I
would end up you know taking a loss now
we have a really stringent process in
place it's um we you know we don't even
trust cos because a lot of the times the
biomass were purchasing the only see a
way I get because the only person by law
that's required to do a stay-away on
biomass is the last user of the biomass
so essentially I am getting COS of the
flower and a lot of times it can be
indicative to a point but not truly
indicative because I'm concentrating the
product so I'm not only concentrating
the product I'm concentrating the
contaminants as well so even if I didn't
pass the Thresher if the threshold was
was I didn't pass the threshold on the
flower or the biomass there's a good
chance I'll pass it once I concentrate
it so you have to be very careful in
fact the stuff I use now has to be zero
mmm and you know non determined on
everything on all 400 different things
so if there's even a little number there
on the on the CoA list I just oh can you
tasks in the field here they're things
you can do it no no it's a terrible
process it takes a week I gotta pay even
for the R&amp;D side for full panel I'm sure
everybody here knows it's a it's a bit
cheaper but down here best case scenario
600 700 800 and it's a week to wait it's
a real pain yeah it's a real pain
that's why I'm really limited and I wish
I could do what josy does more because I
do have a lot of contacts you know
traditionally that's what I did I would
go where the best biomass wasn't and
that's what you know led my my my
process now it's led by other factors
unfortunately and and the biggest one of
them being is the cleanliness and I say
unfortunately on the other side of it
now I recognize that we were consuming a
lot of shits I'm glad that you know the
other side of me is thankful that I'm
not smoking level all the time so you
know does it matter to you if it's
indoor green out of green out before
when I say sun-grown
that's what I mean it's it's the
difference between anything I was grown
in a in a controlled environment using
the Sun as opposed to using a controlled
environment if the lab now the lab stuff
and I and I you know and people are
gonna disagree with me on this I'm sure
but in my experience what I'm looking
for in my concentrate is an incredibly
oily long a long trial
long cannabinoid molecule and if you
look under if you take your concentrates
and you put them in a microscope that's
really interesting you'll see exactly
how all these categories are connecting
and how they're you know and distal it
looks different and cold water looks
different and co2 extraction looks
different and butane looks different
they all have their own little
differences um whereas what I'm looking
for is the longest possible molecule and
generally speaking when you're using the
Sun you're getting a much more developed
tripod when you're using doesn't matter
what system you're using indoors it's
just never gonna be the same thing argue
back and forth about this but that's
where I land on this one in fact and the
market doesn't really resemble that
because in the outdoor stuff even if
it's very very well maintained
you know these glass enclosed
greenhouses it's still cheaper than my
my lab grown biomass down here a upwards
of a hundred dollars down here for a
unit which is crazy compared to what I
used to pay so yeah a lot of challenges
prefer the Sun growing I wish I could
just go up north and shop like I used to
but yeah it's it's it's processed I'd
love to talk to you
Chia about potentially getting some here
biomass though now that I have you here
we're making deals right on the webcast
I love it but yeah if I could if I get a
permission to contact you after this
I'll reach out and we can North in fact
we're expanding up north this next year
so we're very keen on solidifying some
supply lines up there so just quickly to
take a little change of pace I want to
bring Julie into the conversation so
Julie can you talk about what's top of
mind for you and your clients and what
kind of fires you're putting out and
whether Cove in nineteen has created
different fires or that's the same
business as usual' fires so the good
doctor dr. Julie Crockett yeah sure yeah
my
amazing she's my you know target market
is actual licensees and operators
because I I'm a compliance person so you
know my whole reason for being is to
help people navigate through all of
these systems and building their
compliance program dodging all the all
the proverbial bullets of being a
licensed operator and this beautifully
over regulated system we have here in
California and yeah the code was
definitely I mean I'm I'm busier than
usual now it's been a very interesting
time for operators both with I think
anytime that you have to shift your
operations and take on new processes
especially during a crisis kind of as
Chelsea was saying about like the
delivery that she got paired up with
there's so many people who just jumped
to making curb-sider jump deliveries or
jump to doing contract free delivery
because it seemed logical that you would
do that to protect people without
necessarily taking the stops of getting
the right authorizations to do it or
documenting those processes or changing
their SOPs or training their staff on
new protocols so it's kind of you know
always the after-the-fact stuff like I
find that generally except for
incredibly forward-thinking operators
who are really committed to compliance
them to gate which isn't a lot
necessarily because obviously you guys
have different concerns and you're just
trying to survive and you're trying to
get on shelves you're trying to run your
business
usually compliance doesn't truly come
into it with any sense of earnestness
until one something goes wrong and then
they're like oh my god we have to make
sure that we can dig ourselves
or you get that notice to comply or you
have to you know deal with a crisis so a
lot of times I'm brought into it either
in the midst of a crisis to try to
unravel it and get folks out of it or
you know in in the better case scenarios
where it's kind of slow and steady from
the gate and we get to really lay the
foundation but kind of like anybody
navigating their business they think one
of the biggest challenges with
compliance is you know kind of like it's
failure from the gate there's so many
things to comply with you there's gonna
be shortcoming somewhere so it does
become a lot of prioritization of what
are the most important things that we're
gonna or what's the the most evident
thing that you're going to possibly have
enforcement upon or issues with so
during this time it's been a lot of you
know even extending it out to safety
protocols and employee training and SOPs
and protecting people and even bringing
in aspects of HR and labor labor
relations because there's a lot of
businesses that have been trying to
navigate you know what are the impacts
of the federal payroll protection on my
business if you have over a certain
amount of employees or you know how any
whatever your local ordinances are what
is required of you in in certain
deadlines and you know the cannabis
industry is always under intense
scrutiny period and then now with the
addition of being deemed an essential
business it's kind of amplified that
scrutiny because it's a really
privileged position that that also we
don't want to lose for the industry so
if we start having a rash of people who
are getting sick or businesses that
aren't being responsible it's kind of
that aspect of we all need to do our
part to support the industry don't you
know to make sure that we all get to
maintain this you know with great
power comes great responsibility and
that part of you know being an essential
business at this time but you know a lot
of a lot of the the main focus a lot of
the shortcomings that I see with folks
happens and primarily in areas of
documentation because when you're in the
middle of a crisis notifying the
agencies or documenting your processes
or keeping your training logs up-to-date
aren't necessarily top of mine and that
there are so many timelines and
requirements built into the regulations
of if this happens you're supposed to
tell these people within this amount of
time and and I think like I was saying
day to day that stuff isn't really a big
deal and you're not saying a lot of
divorcement on it but the issues
typically are when one thing goes wrong
and then you get kind of that magnifying
glass put on your business that then the
agencies start discovering more and more
and more issues so it's it's that kind
of where you know the Pandora's Box gets
opened once they kind of start digging
in there and I definitely think that
operators should be preparing for the
fact like you know we've been going
through a lot of these tumultuous times
where there's a lot of demands on the
agencies themselves where we're getting
people temporary licenses for getting
people provisional licenses for trying
to on board these vacancies and my
scenario is always the board on a
Tuesday a couple years from now where
the agencies aren't bringing in tons of
tax revenue or licensing fees and they
really start to lean on levying
penalties and fines as a way to generate
that state income and they have a huge
amount of breath in terms of where they
can choose to do that and how long they
could do it for they have up to five
years to turn around and let be a
penalty or fine so all of these friendly
visits they've been having where they
come in and people are like it went
great they were nice they didn't say any
I've started to see people start to get
notices to comply four to six months
after that visit so they come and
everything's great and you think it went
great and four months later they're like
oh by the way when we were there in
January we noticed XYZ and you have 30
days to correct this or you're going to
lose your license so so my you know
we're all in this together but I like to
remind people like it's friendly as they
may seem these people are not your
friends and that you you really have to
be you know
cya is the word of the day in terms of
making sure a lot of the way that we do
that and we do cover your assets is
through through documentation through
training logs and through meeting you
know at least the basics of the rake of
the regs so to get to I I'd love to take
these kind of general ideas and get down
to some concrete examples so does anyone
Chia Mike or Chelsea do any of you want
to lie down on the doctor's couch and
and and unburden your souls about a
compliance issue you're currently
dealing with are you gonna question you
about her not particularly myself now
hahaha and maybe we can throw the M word
into the discussion the dreaded a met
rhetoric yeah and is that another like
auditing of that you know is that
another big shoe that's gonna draw on
operators everyone knows you know in May
they show the ability to package so this
seemingly infinite grace period we had
about 30 days to onboard your existing
inventory Kim James
in on May 1st where now every package
has to have a source so so the state has
decreed that anything that exists at
this point is in the system and if it's
not then you're gonna have a much harder
time putting it in the system at this
point you know obviously that came out
with new guidance on the day of that
change in terms of how to do seeds and
phones and tissue cultures and they got
the addition of a new little button in
the tremendously ridiculous workaround
that was previously there that you like
called your cuttings trash and turn them
into packages so we did see you know
that ship the next ship that's coming
they just released the notice for June
that now all the testing results are
going to be in metric and products won't
be able to proceed through the system if
they don't have in in in metric testing
results attached to them so again that
impacts some people's old inventory and
I think like I was saying there's all of
these regulatory notifications that are
required where right now you haven't
seen a lot of enforcement about it you
haven't seen a lot of divorcement about
you know report not reporting if you
have more than a three percent
discrepancy in a 30-day period for
example or a five percent discrepancy if
you're a manufacturer but we have to
know that metric is a gigantic data
collection system that's being reported
directly to the state so as their
analysts have more time to be able to
look at that system you will see people
start getting close and some people
distorted already of seeing something
anomalous and your metric data but you
will see people start to these are in a
system and following
up on that like I know October's in
Oregon for example that if you do
something in your metric it's fishy
you'll get a call in 24 hours weird like
you need to explain this so I think
though those screws are starting to
ratchet down in that kinda you know
educational period we've all been in
where the real forgiving and people are
still figuring this out is winding down
sorry I have one more question for you
we've been talking a lot about the
compassion programs especially in
California and how people want to
utilize them but I'm wondering people
won't utilize them if they're if they're
confused about how to integrate it into
metric is it clear how to do that do you
know like how to take advantage of those
programs and not get in trouble doing so
yeah I think pre it's not that there's a
lot of limitation today that the bill
was written so so especially some of the
confusion comes from when a product in
its life cycle has to be designated as
compassion so so my understanding and I
could be wrong because I have been
talking for this so deep at that level
is that you you can't midstream suddenly
decide that your product is
compassionate that a lot of that
designation I think in the intent of the
bill was that you're supposed to know
from the gate that a cultivator supposed
to be like great ok I'm going to
allocate 10% of everything I'm making is
going to go to compassion now obviously
that's ridiculous and operators should
be able to designate at any time that
they want to donate that product and I
think right now some of that is
happening in case-by-case basis where
you're able to work with the agencies to
get that product designation change but
to truly
reap the tax benefits of that I think
you have to know waived earlier down the
supply chain what the intent is of that
product but and it's kind of like the
old days if we all remember when they
were composing the regs and they were
going to have separate medical and adult
use trails and they wanted you to know
from the gate well this I'm growing for
medical and this I'm going for adult use
and because we've kind of obliterated
those lines in in California it's it's
nonsensical at this point to try to
preserve those we ran into that issue
with kovat as well where certain
localities were considering only keeping
medical cannabis retailers open which
which was insane because we're like you
destroyed in this unification and that's
still a tax granting perspective that's
still I think one of the ones like the
highway robbery aspects of the
regulations is when they combine the
medical and the adult use the fact that
a 15 percent adult use excise tax was
applied to medical products is such an
egregious
ridiculous sin in my mind something that
I still hold out hope someday gets
unravel because it was never in our
medical program it was never the intent
and that was an adult use tax that
shouldn't be applied to medical cannabis
hey Julie two things first of all I love
that you're an activist first and
foremost that's fucking awesome you rock
two questions
firstly what point along the supply
chain will a biomass need to be Co aid
in these new regulations that you
mentioned is it going to be much earlier
on because currently my understanding of
the regulation is that it's just the and
the end producer the end manufacturer of
the biomass needs to coa that biomass is
that going to change now with what you
mentioned yeah I know it wind testing is
required for it so you see in
yup day they went out there's a whole
little grid of you know kind of win
organized fun system it's like our own
time machine we get to experience like
late eighties technology everyday so
wild I want to play like you know pong
on it as well but so so there are
obviously any point in the supply chain
where you work required to have testing
at that point so for cultivator moving
you know raw mass out to a manufacturer
that doesn't have to have a test it's
only where you would have had to have a
final compliance test to move okay
that's so great thank you for answering
that I thought I was already getting
worried um second thing I wanted to
mention was I did get a visit from the
BCC roughly three months ago and we had
exactly the same thing you say there was
a great meeting maybe one or two issues
on the packaging of the labeling but
stuff we were amending no problem should
I expect something negative to happen in
the next two months there are things
that they pointed out to make sure that
internally you're creating a corrective
action plan you're documenting that and
you have that documentation of what went
wrong how you fixed it when you fix it
what you did because when you do get a
notice to comply and a notice to comply
it's a very scary looking document a lot
of people to respond to it seriously it
can be expensive because you want to
bring in your legal team to draft the
letter to make sure you get you you know
not to the agencies but it will make
that response if you do get one so much
easier if you already have all that
documentation yeah we fixed it here's
how we fixed it and everything's fine so
so I think that's I mean that's a
so that everyone is developing at this
point is to get really comfortable with
the exposure and with the interactions
with the agency to be able to show like
here's my process here I'm documenting
it logs are on point you know and in
that once you have kind of that
documentation it really gives you that
sense of security and in same thing with
how we use metric like I always
encourage everybody to blow up that
notes field in metric when you're making
adjustments when you're making changes
whatever you're saying because the whole
question is if the agencies ask you
about something four months from now do
you have enough documentation on hand
that you're gonna be able to go oh yes
of course I know exactly what happened I
you know destroyed that we have here's
the weight ticket um you know whatever
it is that it's easy for you to have
that recall and have that documentation
of you know pretty much just proving
that you followed the correct protocol
and it sounds like you're saying that
the state never forgets compared to like
buying insurance like you pay for your
insurance all the time and most of the
time hopefully you don't need it but
it's that that you know because the
agencies have so much discretion and
because we don't have enough clear data
yet on their enforcement priorities or
their enforcement practices it really is
kind of like a needle in the haystack
thing of like well maybe they're gonna
show up and have a huge problem maybe
with that and we don't really know in
the in I think for the you know to keep
operators from having ulcers and anxiety
attacks and an already challenging
environment
that's one of the ways in which
compliance can be really comforting like
I know where my binder is I can supply
those those records and in and also not
being like a gerbil in a wheel like
having a really clear sense here's what
the regulations require of me I can
check all of these boxes I can I know I
have this documentation that they ask
for in same thing and then you don't
also don't have like software companies
trying to sell you the jillion dollar
software for a bunch of stuff you don't
need because you're like here's my kind
of course this is what I need covered
and then you know once you kind of have
that sense of security that you know
your baseline is pretty good then when
you get the kind of like like Michael
was saying like then you get into what
you really want to be doing which is
like creating new products and thinking
about how you make stuff and finessing
your processes rather than spending so
much time just on these like basics of
is track and trace working and am I
gonna get in trouble today you know
really can I ask you a question have you
heard of it I heard a rumor that CDFA or
BCC was going to do virtual inspections
during this Cove of 19 time have you
heard of anybody getting one of those
the old I haven't heard of anybody
getting one unlike an enforcement visit
yet but I have heard that they may do
some of those for things like I mean
this is what they're doing in Vegas for
example for onboarding of licenses or if
you're adding a distribution vehicle and
they want to inspect it I've heard about
them using it for those kind of aspects
like if there's something in the license
as a renewal that requires a inspection
to look forward but I haven't personally
bought wouldn't put it past them heard
of somebody having like hey we need to
come look at your facility so put us on
face time and walk us through yeah I
just you know how
would work out you know for for me on a
farm that would be really interesting
and hard hard to do I think yeah and I
agree with you
like I would way rather be out there in
the garden and my hands in the dirt then
on the fucking computer pardon my french
doing metric entry all the time like
that's ice I do all that for our farm
and it's endless and it's really
ridiculous and you know and when you
were saying on this on May first when
everybody had to enter all that data to
like the original source thing I was
actually trying to just make a transfer
from a distributor to come to my farm
and the system was so locked up because
it's so archaic that I could not get a
transfer manifest finished that day
because of the fact that everybody was
in the system trained to finalize all
this stuff so it was making business
really difficult just for regular
transaction to happen when the van is
literally like on its way here and I
could not get the system to work so
hopefully we moved past that
I don't have any big surges in that
system like that again but yeah I was
really challenging day just quickly Chia
as our resident plant tagging expert can
you give an update kind of a State of
the Union on the sensibleness or non
sensibleness like tell us what you have
to do in relation to tagging plants from
clones to juveniles to dine plants to
whatever and where you see it going like
what what are the conversations between
cultivators and CDFA in terms of moving
in a more sensible fair direction mm-hmm
like are there crops
yeah I'd be happy to you know I think
just to touch on what Julie was saying a
moment ago about documentation the way
that I create a lot of documentation in
the metric system is I call them you
know I will email them or call them
about
tiny minut things and then they have to
send you an email back that says yada
yada do this that and the other thing so
that's the documentation and then I also
do put a lot of notes in the notes field
to protect myself because like you said
with so I have a nursery and the
cultivation license so there's a lot of
you know little nuances within the
nursery side of things that are really
challenging where I if I want to make
clones right before I had to call them
waste from a plant then I had to go in
and create an item then I had to go
create clones from this nothingness
basically it was very weird like seven
steps to get to creating clones and then
you know you can clone you can tag one
tray of say up to a hundred clones well
the thing that's challenging in that is
that there's a lot of stuff to pay
attention to you know you have damping
off you have you know things die things
don't root whatever and that in that
process but then moving them through the
system gets even more challenging
because obviously you're not gonna put a
metric tag around this tiny little stem
and like clog up your tray with all this
stuff you have one tag on the tray well
as soon as you move them into you can
transplant them into dirt then like you
don't have to put a tag on it and I
started doing that in the beginning
because why do extra work if you don't
have to well the problem is that as you
move those plants around and you put
them somewhere in the greenhouse and
then you you know things get confusing
they get lost
really easily and like what is this
batch attached to that and you know
there's a lot of tagging going on so I
spend a lot of time creating
spreadsheets of tags on my own tagging
system that matches up to the metric
tagging system so that I know that this
thing is related to that number and it's
insane my own waste waste of time
basically and then on another note so I
have my cultivation Anna have my nursery
if I want to move
plants from my nursery which is
literally one foot away from my
cultivation on my own farm I have to
have a distributor on site come to my
farm to move the plants which they don't
actually touch them they just have to be
here to sign the paper that says that
that happened otherwise I have to have
my own distribution license which I
don't I can't afford that
I don't want that I don't want a vehicle
I don't want to have to pay extra taxes
I don't want to deal with all that
bullshit so I have to find a distributor
and and make that happen like within a
you know convenient time frame that like
today for instance I have a distributor
coming here right after this call that
is gonna pick up the last of my cannabis
from 2019 so I'm thinking okay well how
can I utilize the fact that that
distributor is going to be on site at
this time well maybe I should figure out
real fast which plants I need to move
from my nursery to my cultivation and
make an extra transfer document have
them do that on site so things like that
are just completely wasted times just
for clarification Shia are are the
nursery and the cultivation the same
corporate entity are they two different
so it's the same company just that how
those licenses interact where you know
they may be they may have gotten
multiple you know small licenses okay if
I get all of these different small
licenses but they failed to get a
nursery license and a processing license
so then you're in a horrible pickle
where you can't have the immature area
from one license serving up another
license without that nursery license and
you can't be processing all that
cannabis in the same space if you don't
have a processing license so you'd have
you know people who already went through
the whole licensing process and then
realize
is that it doesn't it doesn't work you
know in terms of how you're lighting up
that system and having to go back either
you get those additional licenses which
is its own you know very difficult
process or having to process
individually each and feed them from
their own immature plant area which is
also a ridiculous and terrible solution
and not to mention you know like all the
the accounting and you know the time and
the hours that it takes to if you had
all those licenses one person is going
to have to track all of those
transactions through the whole system in
your own system it takes so much time to
to manage all that you know my husband
is that is the cultivator he does all
the farming really I mean I make it look
pretty and and do all the metric stuff
out there but you know like there is no
way no way even a 2500 square foot that
those Cottage cultivators can do this on
their own back in the day was one farmer
did his whole thing he did it from start
to finish on his own that was it right
maybe he'd bring in some people here and
there to do the harvesting whatever
these days you know I have to be a
hundred percent I am the accountant
I am the metric person I do all the
sales I do all the collections I do all
the bank you know everything myself and
I barely even get out into the garden
and when I do you know it's wonderful it
feels good but you know it's super
frustrating and you know on the
cultivation side like we have we've been
doing this this is our 22nd season of
cultivating here on my farm or well
nineteen on this farm and you know we've
we've seen it all we went through like
you know growing up I went through the
Reagan era of like hiding under the
trees of the helicopters everywhere you
know we've done all that cultivated
literally in platforms and trees and hid
stuff in the bushes and
on the side of the hill in order to have
this lifestyle and as soon as there was
a pathway to move into legalization we
took it every single step of the way
and I've seen it all we've done
everything we've complied with
everything possible in order to you know
live this culture and this is our
lifestyle cannabis is my life it's been
that way forever I want to continue
doing this I want to pay taxes I want to
be recognized I want to be in the legal
market but it's so difficult and it's so
challenging and it's so stressful that
there are days me and my husband turn to
each other and we were like can we move
to a freakin tropical island tomorrow
like I don't want to do this anymore and
it's because of all these little things
that we're talking about that are so
ridiculous and over you know just over
regulated there's way too much stuff
that needs to happen and I understand
like let's try to keep stuff out of the
black market sure like that's that's the
point of the metric system right
ultimately you know there's a lot of
workarounds I see a lot of people doing
really weird stuff asking strange
questions on this you know like mindo
can action Peter you were asking about
that this is a forum that we have on
Facebook where a lot of people in
Mendocino County and Beyond go on to ask
advice and share information and and all
that on the network and you know nobody
really knows what to do and how to do it
we're all just trying to help each other
through it and you can call a thousand
times and you'd get a different answer
every time from somebody uh metric or
you know you call BCC and nobody has an
answer for you you call CDFA because
like for instance I got a letter saying
from CDFA saying that metric gosh I
can't remember exactly what it was at
this moment but that that I needed to do
something in the in the metric system so
I call metric to ask them how to do it
they say we don't
we were talking about who sent you that
letter CDF I sent it to me so call them
okay so I call them they say we never
sent that to you like what am I supposed
to do here
you know I'm trying I'm just like
backpedaling all the time to try to keep
up with what I'm supposed to be doing in
the meantime I could be spending that
time money and effort like making my
brand better getting more contacts and
dispensaries like you know there's a
million other things I could do with my
time so long story I have a question
about how do you manage this these
challenges in this pain across the 50
farms under Mendes yeah so Mendocino
generations is an alliance of about 50
farms we we have fluctuated over the
years we started in 2015 out of
basically desperation of like how are we
as heritage cultivators gonna survive
this tsunami that's coming we know
that's coming
so we aligned together to try to figure
out ways to support each other like you
know everybody says we're all in this
together so I live in a back-to-the-land
hippie commune basically and I have a
couple neighbors who are also about the
same ages age group as me and my husband
and and they wanted to kind of move
forward in legalization as well and they
saw us sort of paving the way locally we
had you know we got like the twelfth
permit in Mendocino County we we always
kind of got right in the front of the
line for things and so folks were like
asking my advice and trained to to get
help moving down that road and and you
know there's a lot of folks who were in
that older age bracket in our group in
the very beginning that they were on the
verge of retirement but they'd been
cultivating for 40 45 50 years some of
them and they're teaching their children
to do it and and so the next generation
is coming up but these this older
generation sort of decided and realized
as things started moving forward that
they couldn't do this and they did not
want to and they backed out
so our group has sort of changed in
numbers over the years but here we are
with somewhere around 50 farms and and
those farms you know they're on their
own they're their individual we're not
necessarily always pushing and promoting
we've tried different things like we
tried putting different farms flower in
one brand as the Mendocino generations
brand that turned out to be kind of a
nightmare on a lot of different levels
it's hard to keep track of those things
but really we ultimately are pushing and
helping you know get the sales going for
people helping them find good contacts
reliable manufacturers and distributors
all the time and promoting that Sun
grown Sun grown flower so does that
answer your question yeah it's it's been
a challenge you know people are trying
to move forward and I think people
really really want to do this and
they're standing and lying down at
planning and building and in Mendocino
County trying to get you know their
buildings permitted and their things in
line so they can actually get a license
and get a permit and that's not
happening it's really not happening we
had a surge in the beginning we have
somewhere around two hundred and fifty
some odd lice or permits in Mendocino
County and that number has pretty much
just stayed you know it for the last two
years we haven't really seen new people
getting permitted but yet they're
getting that state license they're
jumping ahead and getting the state
license because they've got like
preliminary approval from the county and
the county is just so far behind they
cannot possibly you know right now
they're closed down I can't get an
answer and I have deadlines that are
coming up for myself for permits and
licenses on various things so and you
also mentioned earlier that you're
seeing a rise in embossed sin of
cultivators and Julia and these are also
these are people who are trying to
transition into the legal market
haven't been successful yet and I'm
wondering Julia you are you seeing any
of that with people that are trying to
move in but the process is stalled or
slowed down for them and then the hammer
comes down on them well I mean I'm down
here in LA so the whole thing is a slow
process down here
you know it's trying to get the next
phase open and you know you certainly
know I mean anecdotally I know people
who have been waiting a very very long
day and you know expressing frustration
and and I mean and other things that
heartbreaking is like especially down
here is there is a kind of ease of you
know there is a there's a draw and
appeal to the illicit market because
it's so much easier it's so many ways
you take they are doing that especially
with cultivation like you're doing why
yeah the people you know the heartbreak
and the promise of what prop 64 was
supposed to be it's supposed to mean
both as that kind of legitimacy of
decriminalization and as a social
justice bill like just the whole thing
has been heartbreak after heartbreaker
but not really panning out that way and
even the protections and smaller family
in all of it that we thought was you
know what many people thought they were
going to get out of that bill and and in
some ways to like the I don't know what
the right word was impotent and
misguided you know enforcement efforts
in some way or just like the historical
blindness that prohibition has never
worked it's never worked it's never been
a thing and I do hold out like try
like and naive perhaps feeling that I
believe that in you know maybe 10 years
or something
I do think eventually cannabis will be
no different than almonds or lettuce or
anything else like I think that I think
that we'll get there and the reminder
for the people who are going through
that process right now and who are doing
the licensing is that you know we are on
the front lines of combatting so much
prejudice and stigma and prohibition and
fear in the minds of regulators who you
know these are the same people who you
know in their minds put cannabis as a
Schedule one on par with all who think
like this is a huge social ill and
realizing like where the forces are
coming from and the training and
indoctrination that they've received you
know thinking that we're going to take
any opportunity in the license industry
to divert to the illicit market where
you know where those of us who are
operating know like you're not you're
not gonna desert out of metric like
nobody's gonna put anything in metric
but there's been gonna try no peace
nobody nobody would even get a license
who really has you know in and in that
like how hard it is to try to do it
right at all and in how little help the
industry is getting so far you know in
terms of the fact and especially even
right now again back to kovat it's a
very difficult time because because the
public narrative of this time since
being deemed essential is like well
cannabis is booming and everybody's
doing great
it's been very difficult to get any
sense of of relief from the agencies
during this time for you know people you
know here we are in are like Gio was
saying where people had license renewals
and local offices are closed and it's
difficult to move these processes along
in the state's perspective is like
you're doing great so yeah on track
failure licensing key let's do it and
there's no grace period there's no
extension of deadlines there's no tax
relief and then even from a legislative
perspective of all of these you know
things that we were still trying to push
it push along because legislatively we
know like last year there's still no
trade samples like all trade samples
bill failed there's no tax relief for
reform and and there's not gonna be
because now every single bill at the
legislative level is put on hold and
lost it directly relates to covin but
then it's also restructuring that the we
are yeah we're doing it and it's just so
heartbreaking because we're like we're
like the were like like the abused child
that just can never like impress their
parents and we just keep showing up you
know to try to you know to try to help
him sin it's so it's so absurd and I and
I like to like jump forward and look
back on it from my future historical
perspective where it's I will
about this shitshow that is California
regulated California cannabis so just
quickly were we're on the we're on the
home stretch and I want to give people
an opportunity to draw attention to
something that they think the California
cannabis community should pay attention
to you said Jie I want to start with you
can you talk about some raids and busts
that have been going on recently in your
neck of the woods okay so yeah so
meanwhile those departments are still
active right those guys are still
busting people and some things are for
good reason there's some interesting
things going on and up in our area in
the Colville area there was recently a
very large bust that they had been
trying to bust for a while they didn't
really quite have a reason to or you
know I just hadn't thought it started
and there was a missing-persons report
turns out it's tied to this big bust
that just happened there and you know
these are illegal operators and you know
they they even some of the covilh
residents have remarked lately that that
operation has cleaned up the
neighborhood because it's very tight and
and nice-looking it looks like a legal
operation from the outside and you know
then we have these other folks for
instance in Humboldt recently where
there has been some oh there we go
yeah Peters got it up there um so
there's been some busts recently in
Humboldt County and northern Mendocino
County where some of these people have
been trying to get licensed they have
been in line they put in an application
they have like done the things that they
need to do and for some reason they
can't move forward maybe it's they can't
move past the Department of Fish and
Wildlife maybe they are not able to get
that piece of the puzzle finalized I
have a neighbor for instance who has
been waiting for his local permit for
two years
there is zero reason he should not be
getting that it's just that they have
over 2,000 applications sitting on their
desk they've approved 250 of them
they've denied about the same amount
what's going on with the rest of that
stack and in the meantime those people
are obviously gonna keep cultivating
because that's how they pay their bills
that's how they live they're not gonna
go get a job especially not right now
and you know so then you have the
helicopters flying around they're still
busting people they're still drawing
maps with circles on them saying you
know these are the targets we're gonna
hit this summer and those people are you
know they're family folk they they've
been trying they've been doing this
forever they would like to be in the
system they would like to pay taxes you
know they want to do that but yet they
cannot and so those busts have been
happening and and that's pretty
frustrating for somebody like me who is
regulated and and licensed to watch my
friends and neighbors get in trouble for
something that I almost feel it's like
you know when there was the fires and
your house survives and you and your
neighbor's burns down you have
survivor's guilt it's kind of a same
thing I feel bad for those people
they've been trying they want to do it
so yeah so there's some of that going on
Peter um I don't know too much detail
and I don't know I haven't had any
personal friends necessarily get busted
in this year but um you know I'm sure
that that's going to happen
unfortunately hopefully they'll leave
the little guys alone and go for these
more large egregious things especially
ones that are on you know forest land
and and publicly and some things like
that like they used to do Mike anything
top of mind for you down here in the the
the LA world hold on wait let me unmute
you okay and Mike and Mike you're you're
someone who in the midst of all of this
is actually launching a new product so
not only is it a challenge to launch a
new brand a new product line which we're
doing but expanding Cali
has been a challenge as well the only
way we've been able to expand
traditionally is by getting out there to
the dispensaries faced you know face
time and obviously that's been
impossible so it's really been a
challenge um so yeah launching hash lab
is we haven't launched the product yet
we're probably three weeks out and no
and no trade samples either right
samples and but the minute that that we
are you know we're gonna it's gonna be a
much less aggressive rollout you know
whereas traditionally we would have
approached all 50 retailers that I
currently have product in now I'm gonna
target 10 to 15 and and roll it out a
little bit more trashed a little bit
more a case but that's just you know
just being cautious we're also moving
facilities so you know there's a lot of
internal reasons for that as well but
for us we're such a small guy I mean we
are like the definition of small and
every way I never took investment from
anybody the way we got to where we are
today is by partnering with like-minded
people from the traditional space you
know I'm not part of the new wave of
marijuana thank God and so and it's
actually played to our advantage right
now not only did the consumer recognize
us as being heritage authentic but now
we're picking up the pieces from a lot
of these these guys I mean I'll give you
the perfect example from my point of
view a year ago I couldn't find a lab
space for less than $12 a square foot
now I have over 250,000 square feet
available downtown for roughly between 2
and 3 dollars I mean so it's like it's a
vastly different market than it was six
months ago and I'm sure you've been
everybody here and Chia especially can
appreciate that you know you to survive
in this in this industry have to be so
nimble so lean and nimble is the phrase
I like to use a lot and and a lot of
these big guys don't have that ability
and they're just hemorrhaging capital
madmen you know even Ken Destin was
mentioned earlier I mean if you look at
their ballot that they're at their books
you know it's it's it's a murder scene
I've never seen so much red in my life
so you know in the end
today you know who's gonna be there in
the long run I don't know it's anybody's
guess at this point but what I do know
is that when you're operating an entity
with zero debt and you have you know
market share and you have customer
loyalty you know I think you're in a
better position than maybe these bigger
guys that might have more market share
but they have incredible amount of debt
they're answering to investors from Wall
Street investors from God knows where
else and the plug can be pulled at any
time and they're beholden to the capital
markets which are gonna dry up in the
next year which already are dried up so
you know I think all of us are
positioned much better than those guys
right now so I think I want to leave it
oh man no the little guy is King right
now and you know and long live the
little guy and so if people are watching
and are about to go into their
dispensary should they support the
little guy please support we just
launched our critical line and that's
how we actually are expanding in this
environment it's by launching other
product categories under our current
brands well aren't you the whole new
brand is gonna be challenging I don't
deny that but the way we're surviving
right now like for example we just
expanded our product category to include
pre-rolls so we're now we have infused
pre-rolls and I don't know Tamar you
still around I can't see you in my
videos but the BDS analytics numbers
that I just that I used that I almost
frequently cite or 2% of the general
market is cold water extract
30-something percent of the general
market is pre-rolls
or whatever ten percent was it whatever
it is but the point is it's a much
bigger portion in the market you know
Kelly Hodge was very specialized in the
beginning so we had a very very limited
market and so the way we hope to grow
hope to survive hope to expand going
forward is by using that loyalty to our
advantage using our customer base to our
advantage and slowly developing new
product lines and new categories that
then our people appreciate and again our
our branding is all about cleanliness
all about solving lists so we're hoping
that resonates with the consumers and
our tincture of our new brand tastes
amazing I know time when I was talking
about taste earlier so I'm very excited
to hear about that because all the vast
majority of dangers out there
tastes a little funky so we're really
happy it's not flavored it tastes like
it's all that's in it ingredient wise is
hash and MCT oil and you know in
specific curing methods to get different
formulas there's some more nuance to it
than just that but essentially that's it
so you're the flavor profile your gain
is very benign they're very soft creamy
almost you're getting a lot of the hash
Sheen the pepper you know those those
terpenes you're not getting any alcohol
obviously that's only MCT oil you're not
getting any any additive flavorings no
you're talking artificial strawberry or
whatever people are that so yeah you
know pina colada
ya know and teach their own but you know
we really I'm a big believer in
authenticity purist you know and really
does not complicating things you know
minimal amount of ingredients simplicity
they keep it simple kiss Chelsea how
about you are you launching are you guys
do you have any new products in the in
the works and can you talk about your
you guys are small do you have outside
investors I don't want to talk too much
about the funding thing that's getting a
little into the weeds but um we
definitely are launching new products I
had done a one-off test batch of a bath
soap back in like November we entered
that into the Emerald cup and it won in
the CVE category and we'd so we've just
finally done like a full size production
batch for the market of that and that
started going out to stores like three
ish No about a month ago actually
and that was that's been complicated it
with kovin that I think there were a
whole six weeks or so where we didn't
sell anything because our sales people
were all not able to do any face-to-face
time there was a couple weeks where I
called around
to buyers and they were they were in
quarantine I guess they thought that
they had had exposure and so they were
isolating for two weeks and not involved
in the operation and even stores that
we're doing a steady throughput just not
being able to have that in-store
experience has really impacted sales but
just quickly is that the bath bomb yes
so that was the original the first run
packaging it's a little bit different
now but yeah that's oak is it a ball
chelsea no no no it's a it's a salt so
it's a Epsom salt Thank You Malayan
blends yeah I should probably put more
than happy to put a word in for you
Chelsea I've got some great relationship
and I didn't get stuff on their shelves
just with the phone call so yeah okay I
really appreciate that yeah that'd be
great so we're all so we're planning
over the next like six months to drop a
massage oil that is a variation on our
original formula but just instead of
being designed to absorb super fast it's
designed to do the opposite to stay in
place on the skin for a long duration so
the actual massage can occur and then
we're getting into so part of that
funding thing it's taken care of it
comes with a part and our partner has
big machines like gel encapsulation
mission so we're gonna actually putting
out a line of mixed botanicals with
select cannabinoid profiles for you know
addressing various specific issues but
like I was gonna say a nutraceutical
yeah so it's cool that they have toys
you can play with and and make
interesting products out of that excites
you yes very much so
and she
any any new are you guys all flower and
pre-rolls or you uh yeah actually I have
a line of topicals that I've been making
for about 15 years that I'm hoping to
launch this year ice we were trying to
do that in March but that didn't quite
happen so maybe we'll get that together
by this coming winter we had issues with
manufacturing space as well but yeah I
just continuing flower I have a crop in
the ground right now so light that will
be out in about six to eight weeks we'll
have some fresh goodness so looking
forward to that and and they're there
any new genetics you're running this
season or is it all same as last year
yeah we will have some new things we had
a new strain this last year called
pineapple cheesecake and just I was
really happy to hear about the taste and
the flavor being like the number one
thing that we've got a ton of great
response on that people love the
pineapple cheesecake
so excited about that and we're also
moving into working with the
manufacturer that we're gonna be making
some specific some RSO basically for for
the market which is something that you
know are are they based in Mendocino as
well are they local no they're actually
in San Francisco and they also they have
a delivery service as well so it'll be a
great way to just you know
direct-to-consumer they have a great
they already have a good consumer base
for that product as well and so anyways
I'm looking forward to that just
providing some some real medicine you
know we're all about medicine people and
and you know better living through
cannabis is our motto and then whatever
that takes you know whatever people need
really it's interesting to me that
you've been making topicals for fifteen
years and then the nightmare that is the
regulated California market it is
difficult for you to on board them into
your business yeah the challenge is that
it's you know I maybe I
a little witchy and I make every batch
is slightly different and you know like
it's hard to have consistency and I also
don't want to give my recipe away
honestly that's that's been my challenge
it's like okay if I if I work with
somebody then all of a sudden they have
my recipe and and honestly I don't think
it'll turn out the same as how I when I
make it there's something about the love
and the magic that goes in right but but
but it but it but it but but pre
regulated market you didn't have to work
with some you could just do it yourself
and sell it or give it away or sell it
to your friends or whatever
mm-hmm yep and I you know we used to do
a lot of events these farmers market
things and I sold tons of it those
people love that stuff
but now I just kind of been holding back
on it it's you know it's a challenge I
one thing like Michael was talking about
is like the contaminants right I know
that my cannabis is clean but what about
the other herbs that are going into
there I haven't gone forward to test
that in a concentrated level and that
makes me nervous honestly they're
organic and so is the oils and all the
things that go into it but what yeah and
you know what are they testing for we're
we're testing for so many other things
and cannabis that that we hadn't looked
at before so my whole thing we've never
failed a test for any pesticide or heavy
metal we infuse whole herbs that are
organically sourced from you know your
usual suspects star botanicals and
frontier and we've never had a problem
so yes well the traps don't fall into
the beeswax chaff that's the bad one
just quickly uh last week or the week
before we had Wendy from space gems on
and and she was talking about you know
having to find different sources for
things given the lockdown coronavirus
and then her big fear was you know
she'll get ding not for the extracted
cannabis oil but from adding these new
organic you know non cannabis
ingredients in her in her edibles yeah
it's a concern for everyone so anyway if
there are no last words I think we can
wrap on that anyone know I was just
gonna say support the small the small
companies I think everybody can agree on
that when you go into a dispensary go
for the brands that come straight from
the you know the source and and don't
get these large brands you know I mean
they deserve the shelf space too of
course and and competition is wicked out
there but the small farmers and this
this is where all that product comes
from for all these products as you can
tell from this conversation so
supporting those the small operators is
is king
thank you I also just wanted to say that
you know a lot of times in the industry
people are like well how come the
tobacco industry can do this or how come
the alcohol industry can do this or the
rights and the privileges of other
established industries and a lot of
those came from having incredibly strong
well-developed trade unions and lobbying
arms and as much as it is so difficult
to be a small operator it is critical
that we all band together through the
trade organizations and through the
political acts
to try to carve a path for us to be able
to survive because as we've seen there
the agencies and the governments are not
going to do the industry any favors that
they do not fight tooth and nail for so
that's one of the reasons why I've been
so involved in the state trade
organization and trying to work with the
local organizations to try to push that
stuff through because we really have to
get those those those changes made to
carve out a place for the smaller
businesses as well because though it
can't just be the well-funded gigantic
companies who are sending their
lobbyists and to fight for their needs
and there truly is power in numbers when
the smaller operators band together and
and flex their political muscle so just
quickly on that can everyone give a
shout out to one or two local or
statewide trade groups that they think
are doing a good job fighting on their
behalf Chea
well locally we have the MCA which is
the Mendocino cannabis Association which
is you know had been three or four
different organizations that have now
combined efforts seeing that everybody
you know was fighting for the same cause
ultimately and that's you know might as
well just combine efforts and make
things happen from that level I'm so
locally done that's been one of the best
advocates on on this small farmer side I
think in LA it's it's all about the
retail scene Oh Mike go ahead Mike oh so
I think down here in LA it's obviously
manufacturing is a big thing down here
but it's really the retail sector so
really for us it's kind of forgetting
their name now a well there's you see be
a Southern California coalition
Julie any others yeah welcome yeah I
think glocca was the what's the one but
now they're part of Southern California
Coalition I believe in you CBA has been
a really strong advocate for retailers
she CIA like I sit on the board of CIA
that's a State Trade Organization
California cannabis Industry Association
I've been deeply involved with them and
they've also created a coalition of all
of these groups and meet you know
frequently because obviously there's a
lot of fantastic local trade
organizations consumer trade
organizations obviously Americans for
safe access and California normal have
been huge for for patient advocacy but
the the big magic is how do we get all
of these groups working together and
stay in the same thing because that's
where you get that kind of force on par
with you know the work has been done for
years for labor unions and even starting
to work more with those existing unions
in terms of labor and other other areas
where it's like generally we're all kind
of wanting much of the same things at
core which is you know protections for
smaller operators protections for
workers protections for social equity
and keeping that a priority because
that's a lot of the reason this got
pushed through in prop 64 was this idea
of you know reinvestment in impacted
communities and and making a place both
you know for the smaller operators but
also for you know that social equity and
and I will say too just that you know
the operators that you know the
regulations were written by people who
don't know didn't know anything about
cannabis and they're enforced by people
who don't know anything about cannabis
really yeah it has always been the job
of the industry itself to educate both
the legislators and the enforcement and
the consumers and ourselves it's really
our job to be the people who are is
Laurie still the head of the BCC or some
[Laughter]
it's ironic I actually live in the city
where the BCC is headquartered and I
can't so Chelsea give us a local
organization that that you think
represents the local Sacramento
community well okay I don't think we
mean I could be completely ignorant on
this there was probably one of delivery
services that rings a bell there's
probably one for distributors there's
definitely not one for manufacturers and
kind of as a whole the group that touts
itself as representing the industry
really only represents nine specific
retailers and no one else so what I
really appreciate what what's the group
that touts itself
we call them the sac nine but it's nine
retailers all owned by the same people
family it's it's connected to that
Ukrainian guy who got like arrested I
don't know okay okay all right on that
note we will we will call it a day
I appreciated everyone and let me cut to
this is what we have been tuned into
buzz on the street with a bunch of
operators data analysts and compliance
experts so I appreciate it and with that
we will kill the livestream thanks
everyone