[Music]
we've got an all-star panel packed up
here and I'm excited we have a testing
facility owner we have a doctor actually
representing patients for the first time
I think in probably a year but we have
the owner of kirova which according to
BDS analytics is the number one selling
edible at the moment congratulations we
have Andrew DeAngelo of Harborside and
flourish and Andy D amico who is a
cultivator in Monterey County so a lot
of these business owners have different
types of vertical integration want to
touch a little bit on that but first I'm
going to let each speaker introduce
themselves hi I'm Don land I'm a chief
scientific consultant that steep hill
labs I started off with a separate a
competing lab we merged in 2013 I've
been near the business since 2010 I'm
also a professor of chemistry forensic
science and biotechnology UC Davis where
I still have graduate students doing
research not on cannabis and I'm
required by the university to tell you
that I'm not here representing the
university animus because they still
have a ancient approach to that so I'm
here representing steep hill founder of
Medicare I've been in the business for
14 years now filling old our doctors
have seen had over half a million visits
in these 14 years we've learned a lot
from the patients who are suffering and
getting better from the medicine and I
definitely would like to represent their
force here Danny Noonan I do Korova we
produce and distribute edibles and flour
all over the state of California been
doing it about eight nine years now and
apparently I'm doing pretty good
according to BDS analytics
I'm Andrew D'Angelo one of the founders
of Harborside we have a dispensary here
in Santa
in Oakland and we have a farm in
Monterey County
Andy D'Amico a founder owner of day
dreamers medicinals and Pacific reserve
nursery which is a large farm in
Monterey County thank you and I'm Jackie
McGowan I didn't even introduce myself I
am the director of Licensing local
licensing and business development at K
Street consulting in Sacramento I also
run a Facebook group called California
City and County regulation watch we
currently have 7,000 members that all
reside in the state of California that
was important to me when I started the
group that and we debate regulations
every day all day it's a very active
busy group you may have to have me add
you because I do believe Facebook is
shadow banning my group at the moment
just like their shadow banning the
bureau so I don't feel like I'm alone
there and I I want to do something a
little bit different I love the way that
Laurie ran the panel but I want to talk
a little bit about each of the panel
members up here's past the topic today
is the path forward and I don't think
that we can actually assess the path
forward without touching a little bit
about where each of these gentlemen have
come from so I have heard Don's name in
the marketplace for a very long time I'm
definitely curious how you made the jump
from being a UC Davis researcher into
the cannabis space yeah well you know it
was it was pretty simple there was a
local entrepreneur that wanted to open
something in Davis we had a mutual
friend he approached me hired me as a
consultant originally it grew into much
more of an interest for me we got a
person reverend dr. kim rhonda cesar
involved who's been doing terpene rich
herbal medicines for 50 years and that's
basically what cannabis is the terpene
rich herbal medicine you may think of it
differently but ultimately that's what
you get and so he was he
is incredibly knowledgeable of how other
terpene rich medicinal plants were being
used and regulated and tested mostly in
Europe because the United States doesn't
do a whole lot of that and so we set out
with the goal of at that time nobody was
requiring testing there were maybe a
half a dozen testing cannabis testing
labs in the world
and our goal was to make sure that every
patient and consumer now was able to get
tested medicine that they knew was safe
and effective and had the right stuff
one of the early examples that I can
tell you we had a mother of one of these
uh dravet syndrome children who had
figured out that high CBD was working
for that kid she got some stuff she
brought it in to us said this is not
working I was told it was high CBD we
tested it there was virtually no CBD in
and it was THC and they were giving this
to their kid and that really solidified
it for me Wow thank you and gene
Talleyrand
I know that I haven't met you until
today but I've been sending children
your way because I had heard in the
marketplace that you were one of the
very few doctors that would actually
recommend to a child so I'm really happy
to meet you and thank you for that and I
would love to know like how you made
that dive when no one else was
recommending the kids wasn't difficult
sigh I was trained in family medicine at
UCSF so used to seeing kids have been in
the pediatric emergency room and so kids
are patients and I was looking at this
as I started out and family medicine and
kind of transitioned being in San
Francisco to complementary and
alternative medicine is there San
Francisco's a diverse place the Bay
Area's and there's are a lot of people
using alternatives to your
pharmaceuticals and I felt my role as a
doctor should be to observe what they're
doing and guide them with science rather
than say no
you have to use the pill or you have to
go to surgery that's the only way here
and cannabis was just one of those
things that they were using I became a
believer when patients started throwing
their opiates away in front of me and
having a struggled with patients seeking
opiates have them throw them away
in front of me just convinced me that
this was truly a gift to us and we
should exploit it as that and and and I
have a lot of people benefit so I've
seen a lot of not a lot you know a
handful of kids go through using
cannabis with the ups and downs that Don
described and very excited to see more
regulation here but also concerned that
access has come down so there are
patients suffering again Danny this
industry is incredibly flexible and is
remarkably able to pivot on a dime when
the regulations changed in 2017
prohibiting you're number one at an
edible product to the thousand milligram
edible you pivoted and and were able to
become currently the largest edibles
selling company in the state and I would
love to know how you did that
it wasn't easy you know everybody's on
an even playing field right now and as
hard as it was to see the high potency
go away I mean I had you know medicinal
patients that were using high potency
edibles to do things I get off of
opiates and I had you know even kids
that you know where we're using this
stuff for very valid medical reasons and
I watched these people turn everything
around
now unfortunately I feel like they're
kind of forced into an illicit market or
or other ways of finding it and even
where so even for some of the veterans
that were helped by my high potency
edibles we can't even we don't even have
a compassion program that I can give
them even a hundred milligram you know
packages so that's a little unfortunate
but you know in this industry you have
to be ready to pivot and you know I mean
you do a pivot on January 1st you do a
pivot on July 1st I don't know what kind
of payment we're gonna do in January 1st
2019 but you know you just got to be you
got to do your best to be ready for it
and same thing like I was saying on the
July 1st things you know what everybody
thought was compliant and then turned
out wasn't by the time you're putting
your 10th sticker on a package to make
it compliant you know you're gonna find
a way to do it right you know so it
wasn't easy but what we did it adapt or
die Andrew I have a tough question for
you so I am gonna preface this what did
I do
okay I'm gonna preface this by saying
that I have nothing but eternal
gratitude for Harborside I am a patient
and my father is the one that convinced
me to try cannabis as medicine and he
drove me to Harborside and sign me up
for your CBD class almost five years ago
and I you know I owe you like so much
for that
however there's been a lot of industry
rumors and speculation about the CDFA
issuing their programmatic e NR e IR and
2017 contained inside that report was an
implied 1 acre cap on cultivation four
days later the state released their
emergency draft regulations and the one
acre cap language was omitted one month
later your brother published an op-ed
and Leafly arguing in favor of large
scale cultivation that an almost read
like a confession during the legislative
session of 2017 to 2018 flurry spent two
hundred and ten thousand dollars
lobbying the Department of Consumer
Affairs the Department of Food and
Agriculture are besides spent another
two hundred and fifty seven thousand
five hundred dollars during that time
that's almost a half a million dollars
in lobbying can you tell me how much if
any of that money was used to lobby
against the one acre cap in the
emergency regulations well first let me
tell you what we've done for small
over the last 12 years of Harborside
because I think a lot of times when we
get into the weeds of an issue like the
one acre cap and Steve has written that
up at and you know I don't have a whole
lot to add to his statement on the one
acre cap where you know obviously
flourish is our company and it does lots
of different things besides the grow
cannabis but what we've done for small
farmers have been really remarkable over
the last 12 years because we've been you
know as all of us understand the retail
is the end of the supply chain and in
order for the upstream of the supply
chain to be healthy you have to have
some powerful engines downstream that is
sort of driving throughput right so
we've done an enormous ly good job of
doing that with small farmers to the
tune of about 200 million dollars that
over the last 12 years we put in the
pockets of small farmers not big farmers
not giant companies not CVS not big
tobacco
not big alcohol small farmers 200
million dollars they've used that money
to grow their businesses they've used
that money to help their families raise
their kids put food on the table we also
have had a program where we've issued
micro loans for over ten years now to
small farmers not big farms they don't
need micro loans small farmers ten years
ago that's all there was with small
farmers even today most of our cannabis
only 10% of our menu is vertically
integrated today so we gave micro loans
to farmers up to $50,000 so that they
could improve their farms and and scale
up and grow more cannabis for us a lot
of those loans were never repaid I'll
have I'll let everybody know that did we
say there's some conspiracy among fault
small farmers to rip Harborside off no
we moved on to the next farm knowing
full well that you're going to micro
loan some of those loans are going to
fail not because the farmers trying to
screw Harborside
it just failed it failed something
happened it failed so we didn't get paid
back did we stop doing it no still doing
it still doing it
we also had a program where we gave
legal protection to small farms not just
for transporting transport docks but for
the farm itself to the tune of twenty
five thousand dollars if they got raided
and busted we would send Henry
Wieckowski down give him twenty five
thousand dollars to protect those
farmers so Harbor sides done a lot for
the small farmer we don't believe in the
one acre cap I don't think that's the
way to protect small farms and keep
arbitrarily high prices in the
marketplace you want to help small farms
waive the licensing fee for them don't
charge them any tax or lower the tax
lower these barriers to entry where you
have to have a handicap bathroom on a
farm that hasn't had a handicapped
person on it for 50 years
really let's lower the barriers to entry
these let's have a fund I gladly give a
certain portion of every dollar comes
across the counter or every dollar that
I send to a lobbyist to answer your
question gladly given percentage of that
to a fund that can help small farmers so
that they can get licensed or help them
if their farm burns down in a fire
happens happens a lot right now the
whole state's burning down we haven't
taken care of our planet so these are
the things we've done yeah where we
don't think the one acre cap is the way
to do it
did we I have no idea I I don't think we
spent any money lobbying that it was not
really something on our radar you know
these these we are only cultivating on
three acres on our farm right now three
acres so I think there's more creative
ways for us to empower small farmers we
need a supply chain that has small
medium and large producers
so that we can make demand meet demand
and that we can have innovation and you
know I've been advocating my entire
career for a level playing field for
fairness and for small family businesses
to be able to keep buttering their bread
with this plant and I absolutely will
continue to fight for that in my role is
on the board of directors of CCI a and
as a thought leader in the industry and
Harborside will keep sourcing from small
producers we we value artists and
producers and local producers and we use
them a lot so that's a long-winded way
of answering your question I don't feel
that the question was answered actually
I have no idea if any of that money went
I have no idea I don't that's not my
role Harborside or flourish have
anything to do with the one acre cap
language being removed from the CDFA ZAR
not really no not really
ok Andy yes so when I googled you yeah
the number two results that came up was
that you're a San Jose firefighter and
you were raided in Santa Cruz County
Monterey County Monterey County yes
in early 2017 correct um I would love to
know you're now a large-scale cultivator
a nursery owner and edible maker how has
that arrest hindered you or helped you
to achieve where you're at today well
first off it was an arrest but they did
get I did get raided it was right when
we were in a big transitional period
from small scale cultivation going to
large scale cultivation right and it was
time for them to knock on some people's
doors who were successful in the
industry and who were known in the
industry really really what got me in
this industry to back it up a little bit
is yeah I've been a firefighter here
right here in San Jose downtown this is
this building is my jurisdiction right I
know it inside
now been a paramedic for 20 years I have
never had a serious situation from
cannabis 20 years as a paramedic alcohol
pharmaceuticals that's why I have a job
okay so that's right that's really what
got me in this industry you know so
that's an important thing for everybody
to know is 20 years running calls down
here in San Jose I remember one person
bad experience unedible not Korova right
took that patient to the hospital within
an hour situation handled right alcohol
pharmaceuticals I could go on for ever
in regards to that in regards to me
getting raided it really allowed me to
take it to the next level you know I was
successful moving forward with the whole
situation educated myself never had a
charge on me I had two hundred thousand
square for you to cannabis at the time
in Monterey County I was out there
alongside with Harborside and we fought
that battle you know and coming from the
fire department I always had to hide you
know hi you know what's going on here
and it really allowed me to take it to
the next level be on a panel like this
and represent the industry you know in a
really positive way and educators a lot
of people you know in regards to what
happened why did I get raided and how ro
I overcame that you know and it really
allowed me to push it to the next level
sounds like we got a new social justice
warrior yeah that's well thank you yeah
um
so everyone here represents some
different facet of the industry and you
know we are in flux at the moment regs
are changing day
and I want to know with everyone's
experience what has been your greatest
challenge in 2018 2018
well category 1 pesticides has been a
pretty big challenge not having an
action limit setting it as setting the
limits to be the limits of detection
which are going to be different from
different labs means that a really good
lab with very high sensitivities is
going to detect those pesticides at much
lower limits and we have lost customers
that go to worse labs who don't detect
at those limits and I've talked to
several other labs that have that it's
also an issue because at the limit of
detection
you have your worst signal-to-noise
anywhere else on your operating curve if
you're operating at your limit of
quantitation you have three or four
times the signal annoys that you do at
the limit of detection so the chance of
making a false positive or a false
negative for that matter are
significantly less what most and every
other analyte on list has an action
limit ISO and other accreditation
requires that the lab be able to
quantitate at that action limit and that
means you got to have the right signal
annoys and that's the way to do it and
that's why all the other analytes are
doing it and that's the way that
category 1 pesticides should be and
we've had battle after battle with
clients and regulators about why that
really doesn't work in this kind of a
system and so that's that's probably the
the number one that I would list is I
think that the state should have
regulated the labs prior to regulating
the industry at the same time you can do
both you know the so regulators are in a
tough position right and I understand so
the Department of pesticide regulation
really wants to push those limits down
as far as they can
testing cannabis isn't the same as
testing spinach I'm afraid and so
there's a little more dialogue and a
little less adversarial attitude would
be much appreciated from the labs
towards the regulator's for sure but in
in in general they're in a tough spot
you know they're learning on the fly
they got a lot of people talking in
their ears telling them different things
and you know I think we're moving
forward in a good way but I'd say that
that is probably the the biggest issue
that is still on the table okay Jean
speaking for the patients I would say
their biggest concern is they're happy
that regulation is happening so that
they don't buy THC thinking it's CBD
theirs they're upset that the shelves
were empty July 1st and that the
transition wasn't smoother they're upset
that there's a lot of people talking
about billions of dollars and they're
suffering and there's no medicine for
them it's hard to explain to an elderly
person who's heard about CBD why she
can't find CBD on the shelves that's
reliable and as she enters into a
dispensary the staff knows everything
about getting high and nothing about
helping her arthritis or her cancer it's
tough times for patients but on the
other hand it's it's good that we're
regulating good and bad growing pains
yeah Danny I first off would have to
defer to like the first panel was
talking a lot about the barrier to entry
into retailers and the confusion or what
not of interpretation of the regs and
what is compliant and what is not and
put a lot of distributors or
manufacturers into a position of trying
to give almost legal advice to a
retailer you know with an asterisk I'm
not an attorney so I think that was
tough and then at the same time a lot of
the the labs you know I mean there's
obviously
and turnaround time issues I mean
there's what you know less than 20
operating in the state for what are we
five hundred or so retailers that's
tough and then just the differences from
one lab to another you know there's
obviously issues with with the standards
at each lab is getting as well as the
methodology that each lab is using so
you'll have the same exact sample go to
two different labs or the same lab for
that matter and get vastly different
results so I think that has been the
toughest in this kind of transitional
period that we're in has been the labs
and compliance you know mm-hmm
interpretating and ER for retail it's
taxes I would say is the biggest pain
point for our customers our patients and
and just for for any heavy consumer of
cannabis right now the taxes are pretty
brutal and most heavy consumers are
probably not in the legal market anymore
and that's contrary to what we're all
trying to do here so it's been very
counterproductive I think the local
people and the local control has also
been a big big big problem
the League of cities and counties if
anybody is here from that group I'm
coming after you coming after you anyway
knowing you in that fight wrong you
can't have all this power and all this
taxation and then don't license don't
create ordinances create these barriers
to entries and certainly don't do
anything on the enforcement side so I
think that's also been a very big
problem and and and there's probably
many others I could mention but but
those two things have really disrupted
you know I'll mention clones you know
clones the limits on clones of really
torpedoed that business for retailers
and and that business is either moved
into the gray or black market gone b2b
for the most part we're still able to
carry a few for the home growers and for
the patients and we'll stay committed to
doing that but
it's tough it's tough to be in the clone
business as a retailer right now
definitely I would say from a
cultivation standpoint is the unknown
you know we've out in Monterey County we
started at a tax rate of $15 a square
foot you know a year later drop to 5
right but for two years we paid $15 a
square foot you know and it really broke
a lot of businesses out here and then
all of a sudden it changes to reality
but in the first place why did we start
where do we get that initial number
right and we had to fight through it and
it was tough you know now testing
obviously is tough batch testing stuff
you know a 10,000 square foot license
which produces 2,000 pounds annually
we're having to do 50 tests on the same
batch that I run my same protocols on my
same integrated pest management on even
the same strain right and when we're
having to test that one batch at 10,000
square feet 50 times it really creates a
big bottleneck you know and getting
product to market is important because
it has a shelf life you know so testing
variables airs been tough the unknowns
been tough connecting local and state
regulations has been tough you know but
we're all pushing forward I appreciate
events like this where we can all talk
about it
Monterey County we got together we
showed numbers we trials tributes and
stuff and we had a change which is
important because we don't want to break
this business we want to create it you
know and really get product to market
which is the most important thing so you
know I actually do want a second
Andrew's tax comment that is brutal is
even from a manufacturer point of view
you know with the local governments
taking 10% of gross I mean there's not
too many businesses that
do that and sustain that on top of their
license costs and and everything else my
biggest concern when the the emergency
regulations came out was the July 1st
deadline for the M &amp; A marketplace that
and I was so hyper focused on that that
I just didn't even see the testing
bottleneck coming as a consultant I was
you know really worried that we were
gonna have an oversupply in the medical
market and an under supply in the adult
use market since that seems to be the
way that this is trending and now my
biggest fear is this December 31st of
2018 phase 3 testing requirements so
I've been really staying on top of the
labs and calling them every week and
trying to figure out where the labs are
at currently we have 33 licensed labs of
those 33 23 are conducting phase 2
testing 11 of those are ISO certified 15
of these 33 labs plan to have phase 3
labs by January 1st
some are saying they may do some R&amp;D
before then but we are a hundred and
twenty-four days we have a hundred 24
days left in the year and not one single
lab in the state is currently conducting
phase 3 R&amp;D testings so there isn't a
cultivator or a manufacturer in the
state at the moment that can try to
prepare for this that is my biggest
concern for the next year seeing that be
implemented I think is going to be a
catastrophe but I also want to know you
know if you guys agree with me or if
there's anything else that you fear for
the next year of implementation starting
with you well I keep hearing about labs
being a bottleneck steep hill certainly
is not in a bottleneck right now we
seventy something percent of our tests
are turned around in five days ninety
nine percent in less than 10 days
and we're not turning anybody away so
it's but we do not yet have heavy metals
testing and our history has shown that
if it's not required by the state nobody
wants to get it tested until well we
didn't have we had you know people
showing up in June to get ready for July
and so we're planning on being ready at
least by December for sure but we've
only had a handful of people ask us to
do heavy metals testing at this point
but we're looking at it we've so we do
heavy metals testing in Maryland and
Pennsylvania and Hawaii already so we
have the method we actually have the
instrument in place a little
infrastructure to put behind it but
we're not getting a whole lot of
requests for that and we're not turning
anybody away and if you can't wait 10
days for your results that's our
ninety-nine percent limit but generally
speaking five days seventy percent do
you feel that the December 31st deadline
should be implemented for Phase three uh
I don't know why you would not if the
labs weren't ready you can't you can't
handle the entire state what if you well
we're not going to be the only people
that are doing you know heavy metals for
sure it every lab is in the same
situation until it's required and
believe me I worked I did testing when
it wasn't required anywhere in the world
for many years and you don't sell much
testing so nobody was stepping up to pay
extra for pesticide testing at Halon we
actually required you to get pesticide
testing we put it in free with your with
your potency test because nobody would
buy it right and we could only afford a
single quadrupole mass spec so we didn't
get the kind of sensitivities you would
need for the limits you have now at all
but at least we were doing some testing
on it I and so right now I would say
that every lab is probably in the same
situation there might be a couple one or
two folks that want to do a little R&amp;D
testing are you gonna make the outlay
for the instrumentation and the people
and the training and the infrastructure
when there's only a couple people a
month that are even talking to you about
it and not much less offering to pay
what it costs to do that kind of stuff I
don't know I think there's no reason to
not
implement regulations I've been all
about getting regulations in place since
the very beginning because you know here
you know what do we know we know that we
used to see all the time stuff claim to
have high CBD not have hardly any CBD at
all we saw that time and time again we
had people claiming they're not using
pesticides and then we do these random
tests but somebody else is collecting
samples in LA basin 45 samples 41 tested
positive for pesticides all right you
tell me you don't need testing testing I
tell you you do I'm just saying
regulations the way to go everybody
needs to be on the same footing people
that are willing to cheat can't get away
with it if people that are willing to
cheat get away with it and the people
who aren't willing to cheat are forced
to cheat to compete right and so you
drive some people that would do the
right thing and to doing the wrong thing
because they got to compete with people
doing the wrong thing so I I'm a full
supporter of regulation okay I am too
but you know it's also damned if you do
damned if you don't
from the patient's perspective there's
access but the patient also needs to
know if there's THC V in the product and
that's not required patient needs to
know what terpenoids beta carry awfully
nit is an agonist attaches to the cb2
receptor it's it's gonna be critical for
medical use not required so there are
issues with testing I don't want to
create a bottleneck but we also have to
think about the the safety of the
patient as well as the efficacy of the
products out there and testing will help
us with that so it's important to
realize that as part of the MS we move
forward you know I see the January 1st
to phase 3 really that means heavy
metals as far as I can tell you know
from my point of view at least and the
thing with heavy metal is is if there
was a lab doing heavy metals right now I
would be there tomorrow because these
grow processes are three months well
here's September you know you got to
change things around and most of the
nutrients set that I've seen people
using are
heavy and arsenic and I don't know I
don't there's no data that I can found
about how much arsenic will be left in
the final product at different stages of
growing so in my opinion the time is now
to start heavy metals testing and if
there's anything I think people have
learned about testing over the last
eight months is that you got to be ready
and you know if you see shelves are bare
January first because you know because
all the all the cannabis had arsenic in
it obviously that's an exaggeration but
there's a good chance that you'll see a
lot of issues and a lot of cannabis
being destroyed just like there was July
first so please somebody start doing
heavy metal testing so do you think that
phase three should be implemented yes I
do even though I see even though it
scares me I agree I wouldn't have
changed July first you're not gonna
change isn't gonna happen until they
make until they make it you know in my
opinion so I definitely do think it
should be implemented Andrew you know I
feel that I feel the same way as Danny
and one thing that might help is if if
we can have a little flexibility after
these events occur and give maybe a
little bit more opportunity for for
remediation or other solutions so that
it's not a total loss for people but I
you know I I agree with what Danny said
on this and I acknowledge it's hard I
mean we don't like it but I do I do
think that looking at both sides of the
ledger were slightly better off if we
implement yeah definitely testing you
know a positive thing in this industry
you know the products these days and a
lot of us just education is cleaner than
ever right I mean I've seen it I've been
cultivating for twenty years and really
getting out there and the educational
part of it the cannabis is cleaner than
ever we are an enviro organic certified
farm you know we have two hundred fifty
four thousand square feet we have clean
practices
run organic cultivation practices for
ten years and still get dings on testing
that don't pass you know and it's
inevitable you know I've worked as I'm
born and raised in Santa Cruz I work
with SC labs since day one you know I've
done stuff with Hale and C pill all the
above and you know it's it's finding
that fine line inconsistencies you know
because it's it's inconsistent right now
you know and it's it's a tough position
you guys are in you know when heavy
metals come to play you know we use an
organic nutrient line which we're gonna
have to regulate that we're gonna have
to almost to be honest if you go back to
synthetics because that might be an
issue that we're considering right now
you know some of our teas some of our
sprays of bacterias on it that help
fight pass tests positive for micro
right and we're held to such a high
standard it's like our practices are
changing when we ran enviro organic
certified farm they're getting so
strenuous and so strict we might have to
back off that a little bit you know
right wrong or and different you know
we'll adapt and do what we have to do
but we got to take all that into
consideration
you know the labs are changing we're
changing we need some leniency the false
positives are there you know from a
cultivator standpoint we haven't in ten
years anybody on my farm used something
that is on that list but I've had
negative tests okay so for me to lose a
batch for that it doesn't make sense
there's got to be a better false
positive retesting policy because
especially for the first year or two
because we're all learning right now
every one of us up here even though we
have 20 years experience across the
board it's reality it's totally changed
you know and we're trying to be above
board with it
leniency in regards to that is reality
you know the cannabis is clean our farms
clean we have this
coming to our farm the county coming to
our farm when we get a negative test and
we say hey we don't even know what that
is there should be a retest policy and
not have our cannabis confiscated
basically you know and that's something
that's that's a reality out there get
that done we gotta get that done you
know and so we have advocated we I'm
sorry to cut you off no I'm just saying
it's tight out there you know we're
trying to produce a high quality product
we're out there trying our best we're
taking it to a whole different level and
approach and well III agree I think so
the example I like to cite back back in
I don't know 2013 we came up with my
super duper residual solvent tests right
my volatile organics test that we
started applying we applied it to I
don't want to say whose cup it was but
you can guess that back in those days we
applied it to a cup there 140 something
concentrate samples were submitted and
all but three failed and the three that
did that didn't fail where water hashes
right so anybody who was using solvent
wasn't getting it out
two years later same same cup same test
same number of entries they all passed
right once the industry was given the
information from testing that they could
use they knew it now I'll tell you what
we see chlorine chlorines been banned in
the US since 1988 we see chlordane all
over the place it's in the soil and it's
in the water we see it at really low
hits but it's above our limit of
detection by the rules set in place if
we can see it we gotta call it a fail I
don't think that's the way it should be
there should be an action limit and
anything above that action limit is
failing and everything below is not the
other thing we've advocated for is
multiple testing we actually started out
with two tests and and we were so
pleased except that then we were told oh
no you can't use we're not publishing
that second test that you just look at
that make sure it's okay and then throw
it away well you got two tests right
first of all you look at a plant an
outdoor plant or an indoor plant if it's
depending on the lighting but an outdoor
plant even in the sunshine the top of
the plant is about 30 percent more
potent than the bottom of the plant
and so you now you're mixing you got
fifty pounds how many plants is that 25
there's a huge range of true values you
pick out any one bud right so sampling
is key but certainly big batches you're
gonna have more variability but if we in
most testing industries the minimum
number of tests you would do on some
kind of failure like that would be three
because with three you can get a
standard deviation and you can look at
the statistics and say am I sure that
this is really over this limit and you
can use a statistical test to do that
right and that's the way that's done so
I would advocate for a minimum of three
tests not people look at me I'm a
testing lab you're just trying to get
the money I'm sorry I'm trying to get
accurate results right
not a testing lab but our research
showed that we needed eight samples
forget Oh for the potency yeah for sure
because it's so heterogeneous yeah yeah
three is the bare minimum but people
don't want a paper - oh the only thing I
can say about the thresholds is so a it
shouldn't be a limit of detection it
should be an action limit so that's a
limit of quantitation at the worst right
but the threshold there is no science to
justify the threshold in an inhaled
product so people are guessing there's
you know the amounts that people consume
are you know I don't know how those are
estimated so these things are estimates
now I don't know how to set those things
usually there's data that you can rely
upon in this case there is no data and
so I feel for the people that have to
come up with those limits some of them
work really really hard I'm sure all of
them work really really hard but there
is this tendency or attraction to just
be better safe than sorry set the limits
really really low and not care that that
makes it really expensive and it makes a
lot of you know it makes it expensive to
do the test it makes it expensive for
the people that are failing right and it
makes it expensive for the patient right
and is there
balancing that
the need for safety and not being sued
against you know the needs of a
marketplace that has to move forward God
I'm glad I'm not making that decision I
gotta tell you and you know along the
the pesticide lines I had a lemon poppy
cookie that I had to actually pull from
the market and everything and just not
even put it out I couldn't find lemon
zest to pass a cannabis as a side test
I just couldn't find it I tried sources
I sourced organic I source everything
and it couldn't pass a cat to pesticide
we've tested the extracted essential
oils of other herbs and found nasty
stuff in it yeah so an extract but the
lemon extract has a bunch of ethanol
left in it so it's it that it the
standards for lemons are obviously much
different than the standards for
cannabis and you know this is another
issue right where cannabis is treated
much differently even much differently
than highly toxic substances like
tobacco and yet and and yet you can't
put lemon zest in the thing and it's
just you know it feels like a quagmire
it is a quagmire it's crazy you know
well I'm really surprised to hear that
most of you agree that phase 3 should go
into effect and I really hope that the
state gives us at least six more months
to get the labs prepared for this you
know what I feel actually occurred was
the January 1st testing standards were
almost ignored and we had that 2017
clause you know so most of the product
that ended up on the shelves for the
first six months was untested and I
think that a lot of labs sat around
twiddling their thumbs for that six
months and probably burning capital
because people weren't being for yes yes
but because the industry wasn't being
forced to use you and they had this
loophole and a lot of
your labs not yourself we're probably
burning capital that they plan to use to
reinvest in Phase two testing equipment
and then Phase two hit and we didn't get
that reprieve from the state I think a
lot of people thought we would and now
what I'm seeing in the industry is labs
that are actually asking their their
their clients to fund their expansion
and they I know some people that have
actually done these deals and they've
said you give me two hundred and fifty
thousand dollars and buy my new
equipment and I will make sure that you
have priority and there are brands that
are signing up for this and you know it
is what it is I know Danny you've been
offered that as well and you turned it
down and you know being in this type of
environment and understanding like why
we are where we're at I think is another
reason I'm advocating for an extension
you know let the labs catch up the labs
yourself excluded we're sitting around
twiddling our thumbs for six months of
the year I think that waiting for the 33
license labs to actually say that they
have the equipment and are ready but
also giving the industry another six
months to utilize some R&amp;D testing would
would would be a good buffer it's not in
statute I but I still don't know what
the avenue is to sort of advocate for
that but but maybe I'm alone in in
thinking that this is a solution what
solutions do you see that the state or
the industry could advocate for to make
this next year a little bit smoother
than than what what has occurred in the
last eight months well so first of all
if if you tell me I got to buy my
equipment in November of 2017 or 2018
and nobody's really going to be required
to buy that test for me until I don't
know July of 2019 I'm not going to sell
anything that
so I'm still in the position I've got
the outlays I've got the training of the
people I got the infrastructure I've got
the lease on the instrument on panel
that and I'm not getting it and that's
why the labs are waiting till right
nobody's asked like I tell you there
aren't that many people asking us for
heavy metals we were doing some work
with an x-ray for fluorescence but you
can't get the right you can't get down
to the right limit so it was only kind
of preliminary stuff but the icp-ms
we've got it we're going to get it set
up it probably will be set up you know
and just a matter of weeks and like I
said we've got the method operating in
other locations so it won't take long to
get it going but if God is there people
that really want heavy metal testing now
come to us and prepay for your tests I'm
not asking you I think there was a time
when our sales department was trying to
work deals with people where they would
buy their own machine and we'd run it
for them or something I don't know I
mean these labs are in the same boat as
the rest of us we can't just go to a
bank and get a loan you know what I mean
so I understand you know that I just
wasn't gonna do it well plus kind of
ownership issues and I don't really know
what it you know equipment donation
means or if the bureau would not you
know look at that as obviously we're
here because the 45-day comment period
just ended I'm pretty sure that most of
you did submit public comments what are
you hoping and praying that the bureau
ends up implementing that out of the
comments that you suggested I already
said the main one which was the category
one pesticides changed to an action
limit instead of a limited detection
that's a big one
the idea that labs are responsible for
all label claims in the language of the
law or the regulation I don't know what
that means so if somebody claims that
it's got a calorie count on the label
are we responsible to verify that the
calorie count is right
or the niacin levels I mean I don't know
what it's written in such a way that
it's very difficult for the lab so it's
made the labs into the policeman we have
to look at the label we have to
understand the label we have to
understand what the terms on the label
are meant to mean and what legal
ramifications there are for making those
claims which claims are you know you
have all of our businesses in your hands
yeah exactly and we don't want that
right we don't want to be deciding which
like I don't want to be the time I
didn't either but we feel like we give
you results you tell us what tests we
want we'll give you the results and you
verify that your label says what's on
the COA that should not be my job
and I don't want to do it and you know
I'm not gonna be very good at it because
there's it you could make any claim you
know on there and we're gonna be we're
not we're not in that game so that
what's the second big one other than the
category ones that I I would like
changed for labs multiple tests but
nobody here wants multiple tests cuz
nobody wants to pay for multiple tests
you don't want to pay for the tests you
need so you know gene I know you were
very involved in in issuing comments and
suggestions to the both all three
agencies I assume yes yep yeah
well we were concerned that they were
you know the gathering of data on phyto
cannabinoids and terpenoids
as important and maybe you don't have to
put every single one on the label but
the state should be gathering that data
because they're gonna be kicking
themselves for not doing in the few
years once we discover that they were
critical in as medicine and not included
on has something to collect as well the
idea of this that patients who are sick
don't have money and get make them to
jump extra hoops like get a state
medical card for no apparent reason
pay money for that just just still
trying to figure that one out why why
the state really needed
you know I don't know that there's
necessarily something that I want to see
go through but the eliminating the CRP
packaging thing and requiring exit bags
I think is absolutely ridiculous the
exit bag requirement is doing nothing
but filling our landfill and nobody puts
everything back in the exit bag come on
yeah you know so and in an in reality
like I don't know anybody that was
complaining about having to put stuff in
CRP packaging they put took the one
thing that everybody was cool with and
changed it for some reason
you know so I would say I mean we could
list 10 million things you know from
being able to give care packages to
low-income patients again or just
samples to each other so we can learn
about each other's products and figure
out if we want to carry him or not or
how to improve them and give each other
feedback like any any other supply chain
but you know generally I want more
people in the legal market and less
people in the black market and and that
that's consumers and that's producers
and that's growers and we have to lower
the barriers of entry on both on all
sides of the supply chain for for all of
us and whether that be you know making
sure we are not over packaging things or
making sure that were you know having
different thresholds for testing that
are more reasonable or whether it is you
know having tax rates that that that
make us feel good about contributing to
the state into our communities but don't
cripple our businesses and drie people
underground so and to take something
pretty simple we've made it very complex
now let's start moving back to simple
and that's going to be a process over
years of work but you know eventually
it should be a pretty simple exercise
for somebody to engage their
endocannabinoid system with external
cannabinoids it should be a pretty
simple thing to do I mean we got a bar
over here serving alcohol we don't have
a bar serving any in cannabis here we
got a long way to go we got a long way
to go even in our own event yeah and
these conversations are probably 10 more
times productive if we could all take
that he has before we come up here and
and talk to each other instead of
drinking alcohol which is gonna make is
probably a little more contentious so
you know so that's the world I'm trying
to create we're trying to create
together and and and and that's what I
would say to that yeah and I agree with
Andrew it's keep it simple you know
we're out here trying to recreate this
industry take it to the next level
create clean products for everybody and
I could tell you right now someone who's
done this for 20 years we've done that
you know the cannabis the quality the
cleanliness it's it's changed and it's
from the mindset of growers whether it's
even the black market unfortunately we
all know about that but the cleanliness
is better there and it's better all
around and it's all due to education and
people trying to get the next level
but let's not create so many roadblocks
where we can't create this product to a
patient where they can go to a
collective and be able to afford it you
know I was very big in the high CBD
medicinal products from a co2 extraction
standpoint and I couldn't keep that
company viable you know and that's one
thing that gets me is the emails I get
from these patients who relied on this
product and as we spoke before they
can't get it there from all up and down
the state wanting to drive to Santa Cruz
to get that product from me you know
because they are not able to get it and
that's not our goal our goal is to allow
them to get it give them whatever
financial assistance whatever we need to
get them that product because they rely
on it
they depend on it and we've created
something where it's very hard to get
that product to these patients and I get
there's change
that'll be a little bit more lenient and
flexible keep it simple until this
industry is more established because
we're all learning and me at the farm
every single day right next to
Harborside every single day
they're just curveballs thrown my way
you know it makes the fire service look
like the easiest job in the world
seriously and I work right here downtown
you know and it's crazy you know I never
thought it would be like that you know
and hey I'm a firefighter and I do
cannabis I like helping people
you know I've helped a lot more people
with cannabis than the fire service and
people probably don't understand that
and I've been a paramedic for 20 years
frontline I've had more people than
gratified by the CBD the medicinal
cannabis than I ever have in the fire
service straight up you know and that's
enough set right there and that's why I
can sit here as a fire captain here and
be like hey you know I can finally stand
up and have some pride in this industry
you know and it's real you know and
we're all here trying to make it real
trying to create it longevity get it to
the patients and all we're asking is for
simplicity let's not stereotype the
industry you know and accept the change
that's going on and it's not easy you
know I mean it's I could tell you you're
more than welcome to come to my farm and
see what's going on but it's it's a lot
of work you know I mean I can't even
tell you you know even yeah it's you
could feel me can't wait to go back to
the fire station but you know it's all
about the patients you know we want to
keep it real with them and allow them to
be able to have access to this product
you know and they don't right now it's
hard to get it to so we got to fix that
system you know whatever it may be so
again the title of this panel is called
the path forward and going into 2019
right now we're about to wrap up the
legislative session for the
any bill that has not passed by Friday
will be dead and we will be revisiting
you know some of those ones that failed
next year I have what probably is going
to be considered a pipe dream but it's a
dream nonetheless and that is that the
industry actually works together on an
omnibus bill you know everybody from
patients to employers to small growers
to retailers you know I would love to
see our industry actually mature and
stop fighting each other at the Capitol
I work at a lobbying firm and I've only
worked there for a year now and I don't
do the state lobbying but I hear all of
the drama and I really want to see our
industry actually come together and not
waste their members money fighting each
other I think it just makes us look like
children and I want to know from each of
you up here because you all have a lot
more experience and a lot more time that
you've spent in this industry is this a
pipe dream or can it become a reality
and if it can become a reality how help
me yeah I'm going first again okay well
so pipe dreams are common in this room
I'm guessing I've got a few my own yeah
so so it'd be nice if everybody could
work together you know unfortunately
politics are politics and when you have
limited resources and humans competing
for it's politics and man I stay away
from that as much as I can but I can't
right so I leave what I'd like to see is
is maybe a little simplification lower
some barriers I'm also of the opinion
that the barriers now are so high
especially for the small growers they're
all just going to stay in the black
market and and that's going to be a
struggle for those that do go into the
legal market because now you're not I'm
playing on an even playing field I don't
think that the public is going to you
know have much appetite for guys in
uniform
arms with guns busting heads of 20 year
olds again I don't think that's gonna go
down so I don't think you're gonna beat
them into the system with a stick I
think you're gonna have to lower the
barriers put a carrot out there try and
get people involved and like you said
have a collaborative I think having the
having the regulator's and the
department there are I gotta say there
are some people in some of those
organizations who are not happy that
cannabis is going this route and I think
that affects how they interact with the
folks that are trying to make this
business work and that I think that that
can be done better I think there can be
a more collaborative approach to the
people who are already in the system be
collaborative and not adversarial to
those people because you're not being
adversarial to the people outside the
system it looks even worse to those
people you see people getting crushed
and so on publicly or whatever in the
you know when they're already in the
legal system and now they're they're
outside of it looking in as an should I
got to pay a bunch of money hire some
lawyers to figure out how to do all this
pay all these fees and then they're
going to be calling down my throat in an
adversarial situation when I'm just
trying to get up and running so I think
the collaborative approach as much as
possible I think there are a lot of
people in the cannabis industry who do
have good hearts and do want to do
what's right for the for everybody
unfortunately you can't do what's right
for everybody so how do you how do you
find that balance so finding a finding a
balance somehow is what we've got to
work together on but I agree
I'm all for unity but I don't think
it'll work unless we're we understand
that there's two consumers here there's
the recreational consumer who's
concerned about smell and taste and cute
names and there's a radical consumer
that's concerned about milligrams does
active ingredients consistency if we're
going to work together we've got to
really see that there's two different
consumers here and if we can do that
then yeah we can work together I you
know unity is always best but really
there are two paths and I agree with
that
however at the same time I I'm a big
proponent of all uses medical use
whether you know it or not you know but
I but I definitely agree there are those
that you know are looking at one way
those that are looking at it another can
we come together I mean yeah
will we you know I don't know I mean I
don't think I don't think the the
cannabis user is who voted Prop 64 in
who voted YES on it I think it was non
cannabis users that were probably just
tired of hearing about it on his leave
but you know the amount of opposition to
64 IO however felt a little bit
different I saw it as a step forward no
matter what and you know work out the
kinks later I think it's gonna be real
tough real tough to get everybody on the
same page because everybody's not on the
same page so yeah I think it can't
happen but I won't hold my breath
[Laughter]
well I certainly hope it happens I think
it's important for us to always remember
we're in the same community together and
we're all on the same team and you know
what we do there's an element of
commerce to it and unfortunately we live
in a time where greed is the organizing
principle and and things are very
competitive and and sometimes that that
that leads people to treat each other
contentiously but and it's very hard to
get a state of this size to agree on
anything I mean it's we have one-party
rule in this state and the Democrats
can't agree on anything so it's just
very it's very hard time right now for
unity and
general in America and I'm hoping that
cannabis will solve that problem is is
is the more endocannabinoids systems
that we can trigger with this plant
hopefully the more unity we'll get over
time I mean it's it's the medium is the
message at a certain point but IIIi hope
we can stay connected to each other and
care and love one another and treat each
other with respect and disagree
agreeably as much as we can it's very
important yeah that's exactly yeah you
know it's just educating yourself on it
you know what are the pros and cons you
know out here is is huge transition you
know the black market of cannabis a year
ago to where it's out right now and all
these people including Harborside who's
really set the standard you know and
allowed us to really take it to the next
level you know me as a small cultivator
in Santa Cruz to where I'm at now out in
Monterey we keep our same practices we
just took it to that level because I
felt like I could help more people that
way you know and have a larger scale
farm I go to their farm I know what's
going on in other practices I know what
they're doing at that farm and it's
legit you know it's it's a great product
and if you buy that product I know it's
good you know so it's got to grow
because we have to be able to supply
these guys like the Korova who need
product you know who need good quality
product and sometimes these smaller
farmers you know he can't go around to
eight different farms that's when you
get in consistencies when you can go to
one farm and purchase and run your your
product line off a farm you're gonna get
more consistent product you're gonna get
a better quality product you know and
you can actually you know allow yourself
to grow and create and take it to that
next level so there's a place for large
scale and small scale just like any
business out here you know and people
need to understand that you know I've
gone both ends of it and I think there's
pros and cons to both of them it's just
really understanding it and no harm no
foul for cannabis you know if I had a
joint in my paramedic drug box I would
probably be
number one medicine I could use for
these patients out here who are taking I
walk into a house and they just dropped
ten medications on me and that's like
why are you taking all that well this
one helps this one but I have to take
this one cuz I take this one and
literally I look at them all in cannabis
could resolve it no harm no foul you
know and I'm not even a consumer of
cannabis but it's it's there it's real
and people just have to understand it
and accept it and and the reality is
it's the most beneficial thing out there
and the cleanest product out there so
coming home the paramedic and I think
also along here along your original
question the coming together I think we
do see a lot of people coming together
with a common goal when it comes to
local municipalities right now and the
reason they're doing that is because
they had to they knew they couldn't
without getting their local government
on board with what they were all trying
to collectively do they can't be a part
of the regulated market so I did see a
lot of you know retail alliances and and
stuff like that
I'm coming together locally which was
good to see so I think on a smaller
scale we are coming together it's just a
question of if you can go larger scale
than how you know okay well we're gonna
wrap it up with my questions and we're
gonna open it up to the audience you all
have to go help make medical cannabis
work for a number of different reasons
we do have significant health challenges
we have an opioid epidemic medical and
adult use are going to be working hand
in hand the supplies the way things work
the way we interrelate we're working
with the same sort of compounds we just
have different customers so just just
think about that we're gonna be solving
some big problems here and everybody up
here as definitely is contributed more
than their fair share in trying to
accomplish big things so you're a lot of
this is entrepreneurs we're all trying
to get our business started we're
frustrated we're all going through these
catch 420s keep moving forward with the
catch for 20s raise the bar as much as
you possibly can you're eventually going
to have patients who are going to be
relying on you
and that's just the way it's going to be
even if it is the adult use or if it's a
very significantly serious patient I
guess my question here is I'm very
interested in taxes and what we're
trying to do is we're gonna try to
figure out how we're going to be able to
subsidize some of these clinical trials
that we need to do they're very
expensive as a drug developer we have a
problem with a billion dollars a
essentially a billion dollars in order
to develop one drug we now have a broad
spectrum compound that that is going to
be very much contributing to a reduction
in our healthcare costs overall as well
as well is really affecting a very some
crisis that we're doing in health care
so the question is for each of you given
your experience in the industry what is
the what do you think will be the best
way for us to bring a bring on the
doctors bring in our our scientists get
our get our get our folks that really
have to dial into and take their
expertise and then come in and help this
field we do have a problem with getting
patients coming into this field and and
and coming into a dispensary and and and
being able to say yes I need help so
that's really a question that I have
what do we need to be doing in order to
make that happen because there's a lot
of people suffering and they're not
walking in dispensary and they're not
accessing this medicine the way they
need to and and and what do we need to
be doing to encourage that process I
feel like we are doing it currently by
legalizing and making it a little more
socially acceptable even though to
Andrews point we have a bar and not a
Deb bar it is becoming more socially
acceptable and I and I feel like people
are talking about it more than they were
it may not be where it needs to be but
but I do think that we're on a good path
as however I think the state combining
medical and doll use was the worst thing
that possibly could have done so we have
no medical program and that is I think
the root of the problem in California
but as far as getting people to
be okay with using it as a medicine and
going into a dispensary I think we're on
that the right path there got to make it
affordable you know you got to allow us
to get those products out there you know
I mean I had to shut down my whole
medicinal line and all these emails we
get is people can't afford it now
because insurance doesn't cover it right
so you got to come in there and pay for
it right and it's for what it costs us
to get product to market right now
unfortunately it takes it out of the
rain for these patients right where they
could go get vicodin for a $10 copay
right so you know it's bang for the buck
unfortunately that's what drives people
right
you're gonna go spend $60 $70 for a gram
of high CBD cannabis or you go through
your insurance Medicare whatever it is
and here's 30 vicodin just call a phone
number and get a refill right so it's
getting that to the collective's like
the Harborside you know emails all day
every day right now is where's all the
CBD you know the reason is it takes it's
very it costs a lot of money for us to
create CBD it really does I've done a
lot of it you know and unfortunately
it's too much we can't even get it to
market right now right you know CBD a
gram is a day supply according to Rafael
and the children right so $60 a day is
not doable for the patient you're
absolutely right it's got a drop
tremendously oh yes at the point where
they are paying 20 cents for hundred
milligrams that and I think that comes
from educating the industry and having
the industry advocate for increased
grows to reduce the cost the CBD right
now CBDs more expensive than THC yeah
but it you acquire more of it than th
see for the segment for efficacy so and
we're not going to be able to do that if
we have something like a one acre cap no
not going to be able to do it I'm sorry
you're not so I
there's a lot we have to do one of the
things I'll remind folks at least at
Harborside every product at every ratio
that you could get before January 1st
you can get right now at Harborside you
want to transdermal patch we have a
transdermal patch one CBN we have CBN
yeah you want CBD we have CBD the
products are still there yes they're a
lot more expensive and that sucks but
the product is there ok
you could come in the harbor side and
you could talk to one of our consultants
for 3 hours and not buy anything and
learn anything you want to learn so that
access is there it's free come in well
we'll talk to you about cannabis all day
long we love talking about cannabis I
will show you lab reports will will give
you materials from steep hill you know
it's it's it's all right there the
information is really quite accessible
for patients right now it's confusing
some of it it contradicts each other ok
but there is there is information that
was sativa indica I mean I go into every
store United sativa and indica what is
that what does that to do with anything
porno McLean is all content doesn't have
anything to do with the shape of the
plant right I think every every flower
you buy should come with a with a
complete terpene breakup the only way to
know it makes it it looks like you know
in because that treats you like a sativa
and vice versa
you cannot tell by looking at it that's
my tag yeah next question hi thanks for
everybody for being here tonight and you
know teaching us a lot about product
compliance but I'm actually here tonight
to talk about a different type of
compliance a bit more important to the
my right side of the panel here
that's tax compliance and I think it's
actually a very interesting thing for
all of us to be thinking about because
we're the medical aspect of the product
is extremely important and it was an
important thing that helped us get it
legalized I think the thing the real
motivator was the money and the revenue
that the state and the and the cities
for the for California instance can make
and as we know that the numbers that
we're getting are not reaching the the
revenue that they thought they were
going to be getting and I think the one
thing that it's not being talked about
is the lack of tax compliance by the
taxpayers within the industry and it's
not due to a lack of trying it's just
that the state has made it so difficult
to follow the regulations that my
studies have shown at least on the
dispensary side of things that a very
very very small percentage of them are
calculating their taxes properly and
it's ending up shorting the cities and
the state might have a question yeah my
question is really about what you guys
feel about the importance of tax
compliance because it's not something
that's being talked about and I'd also
like to before I finish invite Andrew to
long beach on the 13th of September
where the League of California cities
will be meeting further let's go down
together and be educators love to you
know on your on your tax question I
think the state kind of put certain
operators in this position by making
distributors collect tax for other
people's businesses and I think a lot of
people have probably used that as
capital almost have been basically
trying to build themselves and bring
themselves to compliance on other
people's money and they are gonna pay a
brutal fee for doing so I think it's
what 50 percent off the top plus another
ten there's something along those lines
but I I feel for those guys but I do
kind of think that the way that the
state has laid out a tax and tax
collection
has kind of made that a reality has made
that a thing you know yesterday was the
first time that I actually saw a
compliant receipt from a dispensary one
that was charging the tax embedded in
the item and not subtotal into taxes out
at the end and I yeah there is
definitely a need for tax compliance
there's also a need for the CDT fa to
actually be transparent with the fact
that they're projections are are are
significantly lower what they're
reporting is a combination of sales use
tax which was not a part of their
estimates and if you want compliance
from our side we need transparency from
the state side too so you know it kind
of goes both ways
hi my name is Jim koffice I'm from Santa
Cruz we were happy to to facilitate
helped facilitate this organ this event
we're green trade we're a coalition of
mostly small cannabis operators in Santa
Cruz County to to Jackies a point about
the ability of the industry to come
together we've seen it on the local
level where we for the last year and a
half two years almost have tried to
bring players together manufacturers
resellers distributors cultivators it's
been difficult to show them where their
shared interests are but we've been able
to do it fortunately or unfortunately
the shared interest right now is getting
a license and at the local level that's
depending upon your jurisdiction that
can be even more cumbersome more onerous
than at the state level so I'd encourage
everybody to pay attention to what's
going on at their in their local
jurisdiction taking my hat off as an
industry wrap I'm a 50 year
consumer and I never had a medical card
I purchased all my cannabis or received
all my cannabis through what some people
call the illicit market I preferred it
having grown up not too far from here I
prefer to call it the traditional market
and the tradition that the traditional
market you know there were some times
you got bad product but it was all built
on trust and for the most part you know
your trust was well-placed and and I
didn't suffer any major consequences I
don't think from yet you know my
consumption of untested unregulated on
licensed cannabis for 50 years now since
January you know the cost of that same
amount of cannabis is is crazy the other
thing is that at age 71 I'm now kind of
looking at using cannabis for
therapeutic purposes and so for the for
those uses I do want a tested I want to
know what the dosage is I want to know
as much as I can about that I'm
wondering if there is a if there's a
conflict between the adult use market
and the so-called medical market that is
unresolvable I'd like your thoughts I
think there is no medical market right
now and that's a problem it's all adult
use right now you know and the medic the
actual medical patients are suffering
because of it but they can still come in
if they're over 21 and get the same
products that
before they're more expensive but 100
milligrams right capsules and tinctures
you have to go to capsules and tinctures
yeah right right
understood that's forcing the medical
patients to go to the traditional market
yeah that's outrageous that's outrageous
that's crazy that's outrageous
we're forcing the sickest of the sickest
people to consume the worst of the worst
product so we just need universal health
care for cannabis patients on it yeah
hopefully in our lifetime
hopefully yep well this has been great
thank you guys so much
you're definitely experts in your field
and pioneers paving the way I look
forward to another year of working with
you all thanks Jackie the class Jackie
you think's Peter thanks for putting
this together guy yeah
education you know it's fun thank you
all for coming and have a good night
[Music]