[Music]
my name is Joe and I'm with Sisu
extracts out of Eureka we are a large
toll processing facility for biomass
trim smalls we also move bulk flour from
Humboldt County down to the rest of the
state I work in sales and procurement I
make sure that we've got enough material
to feed the machines on a regular basis
as well as getting the oil out to the
cities and bringing that money
ultimately back to my farmers like Miss
Lindsay here and just keep everything
moving down the chain hi I'm Vanessa and
with left coast ventures it recently
merged with Soul distro we manufacture
distribute and into all retail locations
across California and I'm responsible
for the Northern California sales team
I'm Lindsay and my husband Ryan and I
own Aloha humble I'm a farmer he and I
have been growing cannabis together
since 1998 we moved from the Midwest and
we've been living in Northern California
since 2002 and we have our brand Aloha
Humboldt and we do whole flower
pre-rolls we also do jarred eights and
we're moving into having half ounces as
well and we saw our biomass Joe here and
it's been a wonderful relationship yes
uh-huh we do collaborations with peak
and we're also working with the Humboldt
herb Council so we are we have upcoming
collaborations we've actually been doing
collaborations with peak since 2016 so
why don't you guys talk a little bit
about the relationship between
cultivator
manufacturer and distributor in today's
California market sure and I think it
would just make sense to go along with
the time line so if you just want to
talk about right up to what you produce
and then I'll jump in right up to what
we produce and then we can describe the
handoff yeah my my year starts in
January you know as a farmer we start
popping seeds in January and we also
keep Mother's of genetics that we've had
for years we have a bubblegum strain
that we've had since 1998 growing
together
it's a heirloom strain from the Midwest
and we still grow it on our farm today
so farming is an extensive process you
know there's vetting new strains
figuring out what works on our farm and
then you know ultimately giving love and
attention to all of our plants all
season long and we have greenhouses and
full season so we do two runs in our
greenhouses and we farm with lunar
cycles so we harvest our first death in
July and this year it was really nice
because we we harvested under a lunar
eclipse we had some extra help and we
were able to pull down our greenhouses
all under the full moon at night so we
keep the temperature under 70 degrees
while we're harvesting to maintain the
highest tripping profile that we can and
you know it's it's a really long season
and once that happens and we we harvest
and we process and we replant and and
then we're kind of gliding then in July
and at that point is when we're doing
processing of our pre rolls and we're
drawing eights
and Ryan and I have done most of that
process ourselves and then we'll have
you know other pieces to the puzzle so
then we have trim and we have you know
the smaller buds
and you know that's where we can come in
and do collaborations with other
companies and so all of our packaged
branded goods are sold through up north
Humboldt distribution and they've been
really great to us our pre rolls are
manufactured at Tru Humboldt and then we
work with a couple of different
extractors and
been really wonderful for us this year
and you really have to have big
partnerships because you can't do it all
yourself you have to have a distributor
to move your product to market because
farmers can't do direct-to-consumer
sales so having relationships with other
people that you can trust
they have transparency and integrity
means a lot to the farmer and it's
sometimes hard to find so where where
her at world would end with trim it'll
then come into my world in that same
form and we basically work for farmers
and distributors have finished goods
like both of these ladies and so when
her trim enters our system we go through
a pesticide testing process we split
every load up into 50 pound batches and
do a micro extraction using acetone this
allows us to see the concentration of
pesticides at a crude oil level which is
about half of that what it would be in a
finished concentrate product so is the
way we pre-screen materials and I can I
can tell you after multiple rounds of
testing the lady here produces
absolutely fantastic non-detect material
which is rare even even in Humboldt
County it's rare to hit full non-detect
it's very difficult the standards are
incredibly high
so we searched for material like this
and then goes into our extraction
process which involves cryogenic ethanol
extraction falling film evaporation
degassing d volatilizing and d tarping
of the oils and then we go into thin
film distillation to produce a finished
distillate oil which is what you
commonly see in vapour cartridges it's
used to manufacture edibles and a
variety of other things but I'd say the
line shit really goes out in paper cards
like yours and from there we'll take the
finished distillate will recombine with
cannabis derived terpenes to produce a
formulated oil and then companies like
sole distro here who manufacture
finished brands will purchase from us in
bulk we also handle transportation from
the farm to us from us to the buyer and
then we bring the money back to us and
of the money made from her oil we
returned 70% of that total back to the
farmers and our farmers trusting us to
go through that process and timeline all
the way to payout is what has really
allowed our company the opportunity to
grow so your
according to your clients specifications
the oil buyers distillation as a process
is really really consistent it's like
water filtration there's not really a
bunch of different water filtration
methods we kind of as far as
formulations absolutely so typically
when working with a buyer like these
guys in fact very much with these guys
we send out 12 sample formulations from
three different cultivars and allowed
them to select from those and then we
chase down the rest of the source
material to generate that terpene
profile and then we do the the actual
formulation and blending in-house that
way we have a completely finished oil
ready to go so that when they approach
manufacturing they can load in their
feedstock load in their hardware and
just go right to production immediately
and not have to worry about sourcing or
selection of all those things we kind of
remove that burden to let her focus on
farming and let these guys focus on
selling because those are both much more
involved jobs then our position is kind
of a mechanical industrial approach to
most processes all different forms
correct we're looking for a variety of
materials basically all materials with
over three to five percent THC work well
for us as long as they're compliant with
state regulations the majority of the
farms I'm dealing with by number
definitely come from Humboldt Mendocino
and Trinity counties we've been through
around 200 farms and around 150 of them
are from that three County region that's
really home base for us
we do however source from outside the
region as well because also the
cultivation in Humboldt is seasonally
limited because of the mountainous
climate and because of actually having a
real winter unlike some other parts of
California that stay relatively warm
there are lags in production that cause
us to go source in warmer climates so we
do work with farmers throughout the
entire state basically from yeah
biomass of varying quality and with
different generally and I think she's a
great example of this the farther you
are from humans the better your chances
are humans have created quite a few
problems and the regulations facing us
from a pesticide standpoint are the
toughest that you can imagine in
anything cannabis on the Shelf stays
cleaner than any foods you can go buy at
any lovely grocery store it's the
testing is absolutely Carl I've spent
I've spent close to twenty thousand
dollars in testing on her farm alone in
the past one or two seasons it's
incredibly intensive and these guys have
to work an enormous number of creative
ways to get their product completed and
finished without without using something
somewhere along the line that's
inadvertently contaminated whether it be
a water stream coming from a spring or
the neighbors spraying but yeah Humboldt
County we find much more clean material
and down south we find significantly
more material but higher contamination
rates because they're surrounded by
industrial a very timely question we're
definitely very concerned I mean I think
especially if you've gotten to Kansas
you probably got in a lot of people did
when it was medicinal the thought is
protecting people helping people
actually the opposite of getting sick
right so we're not concerned you know
about marketing just because it doesn't
affect our products right clean products
I'm but it is it is very sad and and we
want to reassure people that
double down on making that good stance
PQ well I think that a lot of farmers up
in Humboldt County have for the longest
time been using these practices that
give you clean tests before they were
required so I think for us when when
there is this all of these changes and
new testing and you know there's always
the hiccups with needing new tests and
maybe relabeling and things like that
but there is never a concern that our
flower or a trim would fail because
we've always used practices that are
environmentally conscious and I think
that it'll affect the industry it could
affect the industry in a really positive
way because when you look at the testing
and the stringent testing that's done
you're like Joe said finding the
cleanest products in the legal market I
would be much more concerned to go and
get you know your cartridge from your
friend down the street because he's not
going through the heavy metal testing so
you don't know what kind of material is
actually in what you're getting and
that's scary to me so if you're doing it
for a health reason or for just
relaxation nobody wants to have lead in
their distillate so it's pretty
important
well and I think I think there's really
clear correlative evidence that shows
that there is an agent being used in the
black market as a cutting agent that
turns one jar of high potency distillate
into two jars of medium potency just
allowing you to make twice as much money
its primary function is to look stable
and firm at room temperature and because
that's a mark of high potency distillate
the opposite is true with everything
that we do we need terpenes with very
low viscosity so we can get a good flow
rate so the cartridges can function
right so you can get a great vapor rate
and vapor production rate given the
aperture size in the cartridges so this
material is not present in any licensed
or permitted facility at all it's the
exact opposite of the effect that we're
trying to generate and it's really used
to rip people off so the the reasonable
response is that we could see to this
from a regulatory perspective are
significant enforcement on cartridge
manufacturing the heavy metal
contamination is a real issue and
there's there's an issue with that
across the board and it is difficult to
find clean materials and the testing has
to be rigorous to make so regulations if
anybody wants to add vitamin E acetate
to the testing requirements you
absolutely can we'll spend the money to
do it it's not in anything on shelves
this is really occurring in the black
market I think the most reasonable
response that we could see would be
governmental measures created to help
clamp down on production and transport
of this bad material and really allowing
cannabis legalization into multiple
states the black market will continue to
exist until there's higher quality
better price product available
everywhere and the best way we can get
there is allowing legal companies like
these folks who put a lot of time and
effort and enormous amounts of testing
into producing something that meets all
of these regulations you just have to
let them go do their jobs and if these
guys are making it for you you have
nothing to worry about because we know
when we put cannabis in people nobody
dies and there's really folks out there
in the black market who are responsible
for this
but I know a few months ago there was a
real lack of biomass available are you
is there gonna be enough for your needs
so this is the whole game in extraction
lots of people have built really really
big extraction facilities and I referred
him as big guns but they're all out of
bullets I think a lot of people are
running out I think there's also very
specific issues coming online with
metric metric is online and big
operators are using it now they had a 30
day window in which pre-existing
materials could be brought in and now
that that walls completely closed down
they can only operate with fully metric
compliant farms and fully metric
compliant distros with fully metric
compliant materials and so because of
that a lot of the loopholes are really
kind of ending and there's a significant
now we're not it's not impacting us as
hard because we have a really
spectacular farmer Network throughout
the state
our tradition of paying farmers more has
gotten us more farmers and so we've
built our business to be a hundred
metric compliant from the beginning and
because of that when this change is
occurring it's not negatively impacting
us in the same way but I don't think
that's the major sentiment the industry
I think a lot of people struggle with
finding consistent supply of both flour
and trim across the board everything is
in scarcity right now and harvest is
right around the corner
the soul disco is really unique company
he started manufacturers you had
products on a quality products and
brands on the market and that you were
distributing yourself and then you
opened up the distribution so it's kind
of like the retailer like you guys there
has their own products you know their
own growth but they're also selling
other clocks a great question yeah I
think we're really really careful how we
curate our portfolio we want all the
brands actually feel like family so it's
not like three P Alvers you know
in-house brands at all on most of the
brands we manufacture and some some of
our in-house brands most we do
manufacture and distribute the few that
we just distribute we treat them the
same we love them just the same we
really curated the portfolio so there
would be something for everyone and no
one would overlap so there's no fighting
between the brands for shelf space at
all we believe there's room for everyone
in the industry but we want to make sure
we highlight the best brands the
cleanest brands for sure as well as
sustainable when it comes to other
ingredients trying to make sure those
organic healthy more wellness
there are four more grand than there are
a great question
it's definitely highly saturated and
honestly people will tell you cartridges
the most are some of the most saturated
part of the market yeah so if you go
into a new buyer meeting spoiler they
probably don't want to hear about your
cartridges and so if you I mean
obviously one of the things we do is
partner with good people one of our big
brands and the brands that we work with
closely together is Marley natural and
part of that brand it's started by the
Marley family with us so started part of
it is giving back to the community
working with smaller farms farms like
we're in the black market getting into
the legal market helping them through
mostly in the Emerald triangle right
this is why we get along so well
my answer is all cannabis Drive charts
so it's really just the highest quality
as possible obviously marketing has
something to do with it but on it
honestly you have to be real transparent
good people I think people especially in
Northern California I can speak for
mostly can see if you're authentic or
not so we're trying to bring healthy
amazing products to the market support
the community that has been around us
and
I don't currently um I'll do what needs
to be done of course we got a C
competitive but that hasn't been an
issue I've come across that much
recently there's only so much space in
our brain you know for brand so we have
a lot of space but I see you tonight so
what are your feelings
I think that I think that there's going
to be more consumer education behind the
whole the holistic approach of flower
and also of working with people that use
cannabis drivetrains and doing things in
really environmentally and community
conscious way and I think that people
will start to value more where it's
coming from and there are a lot of
brands out there but if you are
authentic you don't have to be in every
store but if you're in the right ones
that align with your brand then I think
that you can reach the consumer that
that will value the small farms and
sun-grown flower that's the point
[Music]
and I think budtender education is
really important too because there the
door the doorway to the consumer so if
these bud tenders can be more educated
and I always like to bring up the
analogy of wine and and beer and alcohol
and you know right now I feel like the
market is really ruled by the THC
percentages and milligrams and
everything is all about is it higher you
know Kenya is it the cheapest for the
most THC milligrams and for me I like to
think well I don't like to go to the
store and buy moonshine and drink
moonshine because it's the highest but I
think that if you can have a more
educated approach to your products and
know where it's coming from know that
there's value in in what's going in the
intention that's going into your product
and who's growing it and and what their
intentions are I think a lot of big
companies have a lot of just finance
based intention and and small farmers
don't yeah we've just had this
conversation
the difference between all of us are
existing simultaneously in both she is
producing crass flour and then producing
a byproduct commodity of trim and then
selling it to me which I further
commoditize by refining into an oil but
then I receive a craft product of
terpenes for the blending and then they
formulate that into the flavors and
representations they would want to
attach to one of their brand lines and
then they craft a finished product and
again it produced a craft product that
has gone through and its quality focused
it's not like this quantified THC high
higher THC lower cost it's a quality
that's really what we're focused on and
what we've seen - again our product
lines like 16 different brands of over
hundred SKUs but what we've seen
specifically in our flour our Marley
natural brand is that we will only work
with small local farms right that are
just sustainably purchase organic in all
other senses of the word and I think
that the farmers you can probably speak
better to this but it seems like the
farmers are more worried they know their
quality right it's more worried about if
a big company's gonna come and rip them
off and try to undercut them right and
so the goal is never to do that to
support the people that are you know
giving you this quality product
obviously a lot of them have been in the
community a lot longer than some of the
newer companies and making sure we all
rise together you know it's interesting
because I hear the same thing from that
as important as the final product it's
the process
how you get there it's our culture it's
you know my husband I knew that going
into the legal market was going to be
incredibly difficult Humboldt County had
has the most stringent process to be
compliant we removed for greenhouses
fixed a rock slide you know we started
with 43,000 square feet and we had to
scale back to 28 and it's because we
needed to fix things that had been done
on our property in pre legalization that
it was not environmentally sound so
we've taken all of that ya know our farm
is grandfathered in under the legacy you
know pre 2.0 so we are not able to
expand we we're in we're in the middle
of nowhere we're on the top of a
mountain in the middle of the forest you
know we're very far removed from any
well I drove down today and it took
about six and a half hours it's not a
bad way to end your day one of the best
aspects of our jobs all these folks out
there especially folks who are headed
into the compliant world and have the
capacity to both understand acknowledge
and create everything required to move
through regulations they also tend to
create really beautiful wonderful places
and solid communities around them so one
of the best parts about my job I don't
get to do it as much as I used to but I
used to everyday be in the field driving
to farms like hers honking my horn at
gate offering people cold drinks doing
everything we could to get these guys
attention and then when they let you
through the gates you come into these
beautiful forested hills that just break
with breathtaking views sometimes all
the way to the ocean or giant redwoods
horses and cattle and like great dogs
everywhere it's really heaven up there
it's really nice and the weather is
mostly nice especially during the
working season and there's really good
people around I refer to him as high
quality cooks
everybody everybody's weird but
everybody's capable and also really
really hard worker and not just in the
dirt right like also now with the
paperwork metric and regulation like if
you're coming from black market you work
your ass off to do it and you should be
rewarded for that you should definitely
be part of part of the party you know I
went into an independent wine shop a
couple of months ago it was not here
actually I was visiting my brother was
in Florida I walked in and pieces of
paper telling the story and the history
of that cuz of the wine of the winemaker
it gives you a connection to what you're
doing and what you're consuming and
especially when it's something like
cannabis you know is giving you a lifted
you know different experience and
perceptive change it's really good to
connect with the origin I think anything
you're putting in your body - or on your
body you're gonna be wanting to make
sure it's high-quality and hearing where
it came from always helps with that I
think it circles back to education
though what you were saying it's really
hard I mean if you can imagine part of
Education about genders is on us right
which is great it's like one of my
favorite parts of the job honestly but
they're the ones really on the front
lines telling the end-user what they're
getting but they only have like a couple
minutes at our register so it's hard to
get the right info across and also does
anyone actually want to read like
paragraphs about all of our farmers like
I wish they did but it doesn't seem to
be the case unfortunately so you have to
marketing wise figure out the snippets
that try to buzzwords like points to get
across
you know this is the challenge but
crazily I keep thinking about it all the
time because it's a challenge that has
to be met one way or another because the
large players the big commodity
producers are there and they're not
going away and they and I know this
because I covered them they have their
story there's a lot of different
qualities of each you could say a lot of
things right we know this from marketing
going to the grocery store you can say
natural you can say you know so I'm it's
if you care like in about like
researching making sure you're going
with brands and products that you can
trust really but I think then you also
have to try to do if you ever try to do
we have a lot of unique products the
other people don't have coach Crean like
psychoactive body wash no one has that
or Delta eight rich cartridge is
different THC they're reviles right now
by everybody I'm one of them and I feel
that what's really exciting about an
opportunity where I get to work in a
system like this because some of the
products we feel like Marlee naturals
for these guys are interested in caring
well we're not carrying a full paragraph
cuz you're right there's a lot to read
there they do help carry the farm name
and the genetic originators like we have
some really exciting stuff coming down
the pipe with some really original local
Humboldt County genetics blueberry
muffin done by some local guys out there
it's lovely and so when we can share
that information like Aloha here is one
of the best branded farms in Humboldt
County she's got beautiful packaging
she's everywhere all the time the colors
are great it's clean its professional so
it's really nice is when you see her
name on her package and then you see her
name on another brands package and then
you see these brands crossing places you
begin to become familiar with this these
farms and these entities both its
cartridge manufacturers and extraction
houses and farming it's the way we
support each other and then when these
old school folks have seen her name in
two or three places and their name in
two or three places in our name in two
or three places and all those things
were good we can kind of have a rising
to the top of your best players out
there so it is important to tell the
story in a brief way that connects the
whole supply chain because the bummer is
when you bought wheat a long time you
just got weed from Brad right you
couldn't you didn't know the strain you
were getting was necessarily true but
exactly and so today we can know that I
want to smoke weed that is grown on a
beautiful mountaintop around bears and
eagles and then it is extracted at a
Tier one lab using the best you know
GMP processes available and then
assembled at a final place supporting
brands and families who are going to
stand and be in the industry for a long
time and have been here for a long time
and then when you have that complete
story and if you consistently make
choices in that realm
you'll consistently contribute to people
like this and that's what I think those
folks who've been around for a minute
would want to see it is important to do
that education because there are a lot
of big companies the big guns out there
that are trying to use and tell the
farmer the small farmers story in
perpetuity with with working with them
or without working with them and I think
that there's a lot to be said with doing
the education and finding out like are
they actually still working with that
farm are
are those people still involved with the
collaboration instead of just seeing
that these bigger places claim natural
or or whatever like you do see in the
grocery store and seeing if it actually
trickles back to the farmer that's like
authentic yeah okay so we have a lot of
exciting things going on I have always
loved to do food and wine pairings and I
think that there is a whole other aspect
to cannabis for these new newly can i
curious you know baby boomers and people
that are you know maybe not used to
smoking because it always came with that
paranoia of it being illegal and now
they can come and check it out and they
don't want to have something that's just
gonna you know be so strong that they
feel uncomfortable and I think that
there's a lot of ways to educate through
events where you get together and talk
to people like this we were involved
with a high dining event at Joshua Tree
last September on the full moon and they
paired our blueberry cookies with a rose
a and a Moroccan dinner and it was a
really really amazing experience the
dank Duchess was there we had you know a
bunch of other great educators roaming
educators they say so you get to come
and have the wonderful curated meal you
know have like welcome CBD spritzer and
then have the wine paired dinner and so
we're doing more of that with
so it's um it goes vote so that one only
had five milligrams and the whole dinner
because the trend is to go away from the
dinner you know if you want to you know
yeah well it's so strong especially if
you're not used to consuming and and you
know edibles there just can be so so
strong so it was very light and it was a
very small group so that the host could
really check in with everyone and then
I've been working with this woman named
Cara and she does food flour future
we've done an event down in Venice Beach
and then also in San Diego and she does
pairings so it's not infused and she
just pairs the cannabis with the course
and so we're doing an event with her on
October 5th I'm down in LA and then
we're also doing an event with the herbs
Somali a Jaime Evans and she does the
pairings with the wine and a
three-course meal and so they're
actually going to be pairing three of
our strains with a course dinner well
right now we've been on our farm for
about four years growing out to her for
much longer but every farm is so
different so we're at 2600 feet and so
it we've been really trying to find what
works on our farm so we've done quite a
few more strains than we normally would
but we're doing white Tahoe cookies
which we've really it loves loves where
we're at and then we also did some
forbidden fruit we've done golden lemons
and we're doing some more blueberry
cookies and it's gonna be paired with
with three different courses and
ultimately it just gives people the
chance to kind of delve into the terpene
side of cannabis because amazingly they
paired Jamie paired arose a with our
blueberry cookies and you know you do
the side by side you know comparison and
the bouquet the scent was so similar it
was really interesting I was actually
quite surprised that it was really some
it was really similar so that is really
fun and you know we're working with the
Humboldt seed company and
we're also working with Hendrix farms
we're developing some we're Fino hunting
this strain called the liliquoi so we'll
be doing more of that and we also are
doing the vanilla frosting that was with
happy dreams farms and humboldt seed
company and yeah we've got a lot of
exciting strains oh yeah definitely we
we collaborate all the time yeah so yes
so for the live live resin yeah so the
humboldt herb council a really good
friend Rob Gale of mine we're doing a
collaboration with him this fall and he
hasn't chosen what strain he wants to do
yet but I'm really excited to work with
him and and like I said we've been
working with peak for a long time and
they do an Amber it's a full spectrum an
amber oil so it's a little different
what did you want to get out of just the
back it's a great event for new
beginnings you know great great place to
meet people
mm-hmm so excuse the voice first
question was what are we excited and
then what you want to get out
yeah honestly expansion and innovation
we're in like all aspects of that so
when it comes to obviously we
manufacture distribute portfolio brands
so each brand is really working on a lot
of new really cool unique products
haven't seen on the market and then I
would say we just launched a new brand
my in your head by Mickey Hart the
Grateful Dead yeah so just bringing on
like really cool stuff and then looking
for new products expanding our current
selection new brands potentially
expansion maybe some vertical
integration some good stuff and then
yeah just trying to be kind of the
leader in California for distribution
manufacturing like just quality products
and the right people to work with and
then um out of this event I love this
event it feels like reunion like I'm
just I'm just excited here um so mostly
other than like I'd like my voice back I
love talking to everyone yeah cuz I was
talking you know um yeah and there was
might have been and some joints involved
just maybe so definitely in joints
involved um so yeah it's just the
networking right the talking the like
seeing friends and communing with
community right like this is these are
the people we're really really lucky to
be in this so it's nice to have a kind
of a moment to step away and have a lot
like gratitude for like what we get to
be a part of
number of retailers here that you were
expecting like the retailer presence I'm
so much like Oh business-wise yes
hopefully we connect with lots of
retailers call me um um yeah there's a
good I'm out I mean it's really big like
the first one where you guys are the
first one like so much smaller
it's beautiful event they did a great
job but it's a lot bigger right so they
have a lot more rooms to get around to
um but yeah there was a ton of retailers
come through and coming through and it's
really nice to see them and then to meet
people that haven't met before as well
because it really brings both norcal
socal together yeah so first question
was what are we up to in the next year
well I think we're all living in dog
years so the next year is actually like
seven years every of weed business time
so I'll give you like the next 90 days
yeah we just added 4,800 square feet to
our distribution and post-processing
manufacturing space and we're building
out a significant white labeling
department to fulfill cartridges for
these guys a personal life goal of mine
is being fulfilled on Friday when I'm
shipping out my very first order of
cannabis Terp distillate for the Marlene
Naturals brand I spent three years of my
life with the Bob Marley legend albums
stalking my CD player so there's like a
big deal for me we're actually doing
we're doing manufacturing and
formulation but they're actually doing
the manufacturing and packaging and
compliance testing so we produce the
formulated oil and they produce a
finished good from that and then sent up
for compliance testing and distribute to
retail so me and all my guys up in
Humboldt County and our fine farmers
will be contributing the THD intervenes
needed for the Marley language which is
kind of a dream come true like I can't
believe this is my real job ya know it's
currently available in a store near you
um yeah so come get it but obviously
there are some new things that we can
yeah maybe not talked about but that are
coming yeah yeah no no it's good it's
good it's great lots of new things I
said innovation new products but yeah
it's very exciting it is dog ears and
it's really exciting to see see that
come online
awesome and what were you doing at the
show
really these are these are unbelievable
hunting opportunities the especially one
of the things the show does its
controversial but it's really worth it
from my perspective is limiting it to
only licensed industry professionals of
certain license types in the beginning
they had one day where was licensed only
and today is you know everybody
yesterday it was easy to move around and
what I would say is I've been to a lot
of conferences right to shake 10 to 20
hands to find someone who is the type a
type of person I'm looking for of any
type here it was really running 50 to
100% you know we move bulk flour bulk
distillate cartridges and we're about to
start working on pre rolls
chances are if you work in the cannabis
industry I can interact with you in some
way you either have flour knead this
tool it need cards or need one of those
things where you retail some of those
things so the number of connections that
can be made per hour in here is really
high and I would say one of the
important things for me is I just have
to remember to keep moving there's so
many interesting people just like this
like we've been hanging out for 30
minutes and I haven't talked to an extra
nine people because of that and who
knows it sounds like the show is doing a
better job of filtering out you could
say they're extracting the best out of
the industry and it was a really great
event it was really well produced it was
mellow the food was good
the spacing was fine the size of the
venue the number of people here was
really good and really just a quality
and caliber of people wandering around
you can absolutely have a 21 year old
gal smoking a joint sitting on a seat
next to the CEO men men I just saw that
like just a moment ago and just casually
having conversations so like the most
extremes of everything or baeble here on
the professional side it's been huge
thanks for having us