[Music]
what happened last Friday just to ruin
all of our weekends is that the
Department of Public Health clarified to
somebody that in the new regulations
when they said that the universal symbol
has to be printed on if the packaging is
separate it's a separable from the outer
packaging the universal symbol has to be
printed on inhalable products
parenthetical shatter dab wax things
like that so we all went sure okay that
makes sense because you we're gonna
print it on the little container that's
holding the shutter dab wax inside of a
box got it get it good everybody's doing
it and then they said oh no no we meant
then it needs to be printed as well on
vaporizer cartridges on the vaporizer
cartridge itself calling the cartridge
the package of the oil not the thing and
many of these guys have already heard my
rant about the use of an Oxford comma in
the regulations which is in the
regulations it says cannabis
concentrates you know suppositories
capsules whatever vape cartridges comma
inhalable products a parenthetical
shattered a blacks and when they put it
in that second part in the regs they
didn't put tape cartridges comma in
Haleyville products shattered ad wax
they just put inhalable products
shattered a black and so the argument
happening now is that might be what you
mean but Department of Public Health
that is not what you said and we're
trying so hard to read and understand in
the English language in the use of
commas and all of these things I guess
so Julie's get the comma woman and I
love it because I use that argument in
our letter and then my argument is that
there is a difference between a product
and a container of that product I cannot
use the oil that is in the pen without
the vape car
I cannot and
the BCC tells me I cannot bulk oil test
the oil before it goes in to the vapor
cart I must test what the final form of
the product so unless the product is
both oil and then the container is the
vape pen cart which is not at all the
way that it is set up in the regulations
then there is no way that that vape pen
cart is deemed to be a container and if
I'm gonna get out my crystal ball I'm
just gonna tell you guys yeah that's
where it's going yes we're gonna have to
put universal symbols on cartridges I
have no doubt they're gonna bring back
the little stamp maker is gonna lobby to
put the stamps back on the edibles so
you know the difference between a
cannabis chocolate and another chocolate
we're gonna go all the way down the
rabbit hole because especially since if
people in Laguna Beach are getting see
ups to open a CBD store and they're
gonna sell vapes guess what your law
enforcement is gonna want to know on
visual perception is that a CBD vapor is
that a THC vape because now we're
starting to fork into CBD good THC bad
this is what's happening in the THC
stores but the CBD stores they can just
go wherever they want does it matter
that they're selling real CBD or snake
oil to people that they never mind but
you just go right ahead with the FDA
says that you can't have CBD and food
products but that doesn't seem to matter
in the city of LA where the DCR stay in
your lanes sometimes is something I like
to say issued guidance that you should
as a CBD business register so that you
can pay the taxes to the great city of
Los Angeles what but put yourself on
notice ya know this makes sense to me
because it's like okay at a certain
point in time you have to know as a
regulator or as a business owner or
whoever is that you start just a rabbit
hole issue here it's like okay so you
want to stamp the cartridge with the
cannabis warning label and
and so people just get covers for them
and then we just create another industry
of a cart covers and like you know how
easy it is to take a sticker up a glass
cartridge yeah and you know just put a
like a slip on over it it's like
everything the thing is is that people
are gonna use cannabis and people are
going to buy cannabis and people are
going to sell cannabis and so why are we
getting caught up in this is not even
all of it from the CD pH and the BCC and
the DCR there's more information and it
it just creates this where the industry
that is growing the fastest isn't the
cannabis industry it's the cannabis
regulation industry and now we went from
a state that did not embrace it to the
extent that they should had even though
we are the largest producer and now
they're seeing the tax dollar revenues
from this and I'm gonna be honest with
you on the political side of all of this
stuff is there is neither party is after
our true like goal here and that when
politics get involved it just means that
more money goes to bureaucracy in this
right now and you know I was excited to
see some big wins this year and I know
at a moment's notice we could find out
that cannabis you know the president
said that cannabis is fine now because I
mean we here rent more ridiculous stuff
every day every day and so you live in a
very volatile industry but that's also
why a lot of us are in it like we can do
redundancy other than our records any
other thing back to the inconsistency in
the regulations with the vape pen issue
is that also there was no reconciliation
of the size or the color if you're gonna
put it on a vape pen write that half an
inch by half an inch if you want to look
to where gph says well organ does it
working gave a very specific I would
dare say one of the best visual guidance
about what they want their packaging and
labeling and they downsize this the the
sticker that they would put on a vape
pen cart because it was smaller and DPH
has no way
to say that they don't know what is
currently happening in this industry
they have been to manufacturers they
have been to dispensaries I have sent
them pictures on behalf of my clients of
their products to clearer compliance so
when we talk about the inconsistencies
in the regulations into Julie's point no
this is where we're gonna end up what
we're fighting over today is the grace
period is the amount of time that it
will take to ensure that they're one of
the largest growing segments of this
industry isn't shut out that all the
sudden consumers don't get vape pens
because there is no access to the vape
pen market because no kimono vape pen on
the market today in this state is
compliant because we didn't know the
intention of of DPH so that's really I
think an important to note when you're
looking at this issue is where we're
going where we are and why we have to
continually fight and on a united front
be consistent in our messaging as an
industry because as Brett said you know
the political powers are not there to
help us and if we as an industry are so
fractured that we're fighting one
another and on some issues some parts of
the industry or aligning with law
enforcement and League of Cities and
then others are not we we look weaker as
the whole and I can't ever say it enough
high tides raise all ships and if we
want everybody in this industry to
succeed then we have to be kind to one
another and not be throwing one another
under the bus when there is more than
enough problems that we can share in
yeah and it is it is important to
because we are like you're saying that
one of my favorite recent stories is I
don't know if you guys know Cody bass up
in South Lake Tahoe who runs a
dispensary and recently got elected to
his City Council so that's the kind of
change when stuff gets interesting is
rather than just say oh I don't know the
politicians aren't on our side we can be
the politicians that's when the
interesting change starts to happen we
can show up at the city council meetings
we can show up at the town halls we can
take the seats on those advisor
councils and that is how we affect
change is not by sitting around and
complaining and watching what's
happening and having it at be something
that's happening to us this is a living
evolutionary process that we are part of
and we can change it does anybody have
any other regulatory questions when I
gave you a very high level I love her
statement here and what she's saying is
something that I harp on all the time
and Pamela you were just discussing here
is that like if you see another company
that's making a competing product like
no they're not there's enough space for
all of us here everybody has a space in
cannabis right now as long as you know
you do it within compliance and and it
drives me nuts to see this this breaking
each other down and putting each other's
business all out there when everybody
has business everybody's trying to do
their their best and which is
frustrating because we know that they
could come back on any of us in five
years and say oh well you weren't doing
it back then so I appreciate you saying
that cuz we do yeah we all need to work
together and that's something I say a
lot as well nobody in the cannabis space
is your enemy is your competition they
are all your allies the fight that we
have right now is if the people who
built the cannabis industry and are from
the industry get to participate at all
like my admite perception of the enemy
is Pfizer is the enemy it's who gets to
do this and that's what we're fighting
for that my understanding of prop 64 a
deeply imperfect regulatory document was
because people were ready to
decriminalize cannabis activity they
were ready for social justice and they
wanted to preserve access and those are
the things that we are having to fight
the hardest for is for those core
principles to still be a part of this
while everybody's gone into the opposite
reefer madness of like corporate money
insanity of like how do I race fastest
to burn down all the houses around me so
that I can be the first unicorn in the
cannabis space you know and I say all
the time I the thing that gets me out of
bed in the morning I have so little
interest in one guy making a billion
dollars in cannabis I have a hell of a
lot of interest in thousands of people
making having well-paying highly skilled
technical jobs lab technicians growers
transporters manufacturers reintroducing
a viable middle class to American
economy that's interesting to me that
gets me out of bed in the morning
because 20 years ago I could live in New
York City and work at a bookstore
part-time be an artist and that was that
reality that economic reality has been
eviscerated from the face of our planet
you know that we this is what i view the
cannabis industry as is an opportunity
to restabilized the economy in these
much-needed ways in to treat like the
pain in the suffering the economic pain
the classist pain the racist pain of a
nation that was built on suffering and
exploitation and we are standing at the
crossroads being like ok so it is this
gonna be like a cure in a treatment for
this suffering of where we came from or
is it gonna be the next corporate
bullshit that's gonna go the same way as
everything else and continue to add to
the suffering of the world and this is
the choice that we have to make I think
we get to have dinner soon or something
right let's do that are there more
questions yeah I definitely agree to
that I was like our enemies are so many
different things but oftentimes our
enemies are just is purely judgment
judgment of other people's life actions
here and it doesn't have to do with its
cannabis or any other thing like that is
that humans we need to do a lot better
job of not
giving a shit what our neighbor is doing
as long as they're not hurting anybody
then at a certain point in time where
we're losing our middle-class economy
we're losing our our education all these
different areas is being cycled back
into just because it's highly regulated
the things that we have to do we're
spending tax money and areas that we
didn't think we were being taxed you
know they say that here in the US we
don't we have cheaper taxes and we have
cheap ourselves like no you pay for it
it's in the price of things it's just
going to pay for all these other
regulations that take to get you there
and we've got to support the consumer I
think the consumers the person in the
room they legitimately is the most
marginalized I if you go into a store
just to buy an eighth of cannabis it is
upwards of $90 $90 a week
cannabis is taxed at 30 to 50 percent it
is one of the highest tax commodities
that there is and higher than cigarettes
and alcohol which kill you by the way
and cannabis does not that this is
legitimately medicine for some people
that they cannot get and they cannot
afford got vicodin and a hydrate or
vicodin and opiates there are five
dollars and fourteen cents when you go
to the pharmacy so if your medication is
five dollars and 14 cents and you'd
rather get off of it and get on to
cannabis but your insurance company
won't cover it and it's $90 per 1/8 it's
$100 to get CBD at Lake cannabis CBD AG
into one pills are $90 for account of
less than 60 it's it's uh it's
incorrigible that the industry is out
for this hundred and twenty five million
dollar payday that we're bringing in
capital and we're not screaming from the
rooftops that the taxes are too high
because there is nobody to sell it to
you if they cannot afford to buy it and
so if you are spending as much time
supporting these legislative efforts
then you will have no market share to
speak of because nobody will be able to
afford it that's why we've seen the true
medical market in cannabis be decimated
I worked with
parents that were already spending $1200
a month for their child who has epilepsy
and now it's over 3,000 or $3,600 a
month when they can find it and it's not
the same as it was before
and so we've we have lost the medical
market and that's why I got into
cannabis like cannabis saved my life I
had epilepsy for years and I haven't had
a seizure in four years now because of
cannabis and and I forget that at times
like this is why you got into this
industry is to help patients and to work
with doctors and bringing down stigma
and that is a huge part of what we're
still fighting here stigmas going down
but at what cost
recreational people can't afford it
either
and like a medical is so important and I
have migraines so I'm with you bright
like I can find my medicine I have
clients that I'm able to you know
procure product from but that's not
everybody's situation clearly but I'm
not just talking about medical the
medical market is truly suffering but if
the recreational market if the adult use
market can't afford to pay then the
entire system collapses so I sometimes
gets cast in in a way where we're
because medical is so important and it's
suffering more I want you to understand
that if you have no customers the rest
of the supply chain doesn't matter so it
is your problem because I have operators
that will say or I've heard operators
say well that's not really my problem my
problem is running my business you have
to have a market and we will have a
resurgence of the black of the illicit
market if we are not careful in
protecting the the taxation issue also
just you know fun little facts if a city
charges you a tax to operate that is not
then attacks that you assess to the
customer that is your tax to operate
your business that allows you to make
money is I think that's a real important
issue that when CDFA comes and starts
doing these audits it is actually not
lawful to pass on that tax so when you
write a receipt and I have seen this
happen the
is a sales and use tax the excise tax
that somehow is applied at the retailer
which its first have already been in the
cost of the of the product so you've got
sales and use tax excise tax city an
additional city tax and then the final
cost that last item that lasts like oh
they charge me five dollar five percent
gross sales receipts tax that's your
company's tax that is not the consumer
tax be forewarned we're gonna see
lawsuits surrounding that either from
the public to those operators or fines
from CDT FA all right cannabis ninjas we
have work to do
we have food to eat music to listen to
people to talk to and thank you so much
to future cannabis projects for having
big we wish you great things
[Music]