[Music]
so you want to talk about brands in
cannabis in 2019 I feel that for not
coming from Koreatown collective which
is a recreational adult use cannabis
collective the brands are really out
there way too soon ahead of the curve
way spending way too much money you can
take a canned essent that has a
multitude of billboards now that's
competing for billboard time with Mad
Men and how they've tried to brand
themselves they're basically Outsiders
coming into a cannabis world the brand
itself I think will be and people will
understand the brand when we actually
have delivery services working and when
people call in telephone and want
something they want a consistency if you
want Heinz 57 ketchup you want Heinz 57
ketchup if you want a coke you certainly
don't want a Pepsi to show up at your
door and that was kind of where the
brand's can really get their foothold in
the taxi world start really is turning
into CVS you like I stock the store and
I look at price points I mean I got to
have something for every single person
because we're on Melrose the tour buses
stop right in front of our store people
get on and off the buses all day long
besides selling apparel and things like
that for people to go home with they
want a pre-roll they want to edible they
want different types of things back in
the day people wanted their flower and
your flower business was probably 60 to
70 percent of your business now now it's
vapes and edibles
and people are going crazy with it
you've taken away the stigmatism of
having to like smoke a joint or a blunt
when people can smell that odor and if
you babe
that odors knows to stinks you're not
going to get into your car and smell a
vape pen like you're gonna smell like I
was smoking to join him on a car so it's
a totally different thing you've taken
away that stigmatism the CBD source like
took away the hurdle of you don't have
to show your ID to come in and you get
to ask a lot of questions and then after
you're prepared you can leave the CBD
store and then go to the THC store and
get whatever medicines you want to go
and not feel intimidated because you
don't know anything can you give me some
nuanced differences like the
interactions with brands and
distributors representing brands today
versus a year ago or two years ago I
have to tell you this brand these brand
these brand owners distributors they're
horse I mean they really are they are so
busy trying to do anything they can to
get into koreatown collective they're
desperate to get there because you're
not a brand if you don't have any retail
place to deliver your brand especially
in cannabis space you can spend all the
money you want and put all the orange
billboards or red billboards you want
around town and unless you get someone
to come in a retail store and buy your
product it's just a money pit so it
seems like what I'm hearing is everybody
is going for market share and they will
do anything to show sales and market
share I would say that's a very good
point that you've just said there
because you take someone like you're
spending a lot of money you take a brand
like select they did exactly what you
just said
they put were able to put a lot of sales
on their books whether they're
creditable sells or not we're not to
judge but they were able to turn around
and sell themselves for nine hundred
million dollars last week he did a great
job I mean he did what he was supposed
to do
so kudos to Canton for that but that's
really what it is but until these brands
realized the stores are their flagship
places to do business they're going to
spend a lot of wills and they can spend
a lot of time getting people to come in
and brand ambassadors and some are cute
some are have a sense of personality
someone can really sell product
somewhere educated and unless you can
get someone to come in there and support
your product I can tell you I don't have
the time to make you a brand anymore
it's not like it was back in the day I
can remember when Kiba first walked in
my store and we did all our own edibles
and things like that and the Kiva girl
was just awesome and we took keep it was
one of our first brands that we actually
brought into her store that was like
2015 sort of like four years ago and
they're still there but they support
their brand and that would be the best
advice I could give a brand to do is
support your brand coming to your store
support it and educate the patient I
can't educate everyone by by myself and
it's going to be knowledge that's going
to give everyone power
[Music]
there are some small brands that are
doing better jobs than the bigger brands
I will tell you because we're a very big
partner of packs so in the packs fillers
have really become there like a lot of
small boutique oil companies and we've
become very close with them and as the
everything is evolved the past year
those little vapor companies have paired
with farms or whatever and I spend more
time working with the smaller farms and
those site business is bringing for each
other than I do like the big like brands
such as condesa and things like that the
flour is just not there some as far as
like Kaneko or who makes edibles Dixie
makes a great gummy I mean some of these
companies are really having to step up
their game and they're probably hiring
like real chefs to come into their
kitchens and cook and then you have to
just know how to work with the
distillates to make it taste right but
you know those type of brands will
really will do okay what kind of give me
the percentage of people walking in the
door who are looking for specific brands
versus people just saying I want all can
you recommend what you like
that's what correct on Melrose with all
the tourists and the recreational people
people walk in and like whatever we
recommend most people coming say they
want an edible and most of the edibles
we have are brand names whether it's
Kaneko it's Kiva big Pete's pussy punch
so we have those name brands you see the
billboards they known the names so a lot
of times that's very very easy to do
it's the same thing with the vape but
the vape companies they had such a
problem because when 2018 came around
and all these they probably didn't know
it through the party so much of their
product got into the black market and it
was counterfeit and whatever so some of
those brands you now know that do the
oil companies you're not going to pick
because you don't know if it's real or
not I can tell you that if I have a
product to my store it came directly
from the manufacturer so I know it's
quality but there are some really great
brands that came out like ocean which is
live resin parts
everyone's come and stepped up their
game in the oil game and now if people
just like I almost like price wars
because there's such a glut of it on the
market are you gonna put it into part or
you can put it into an edible and then
you have your flower that took so long
to go through the whole chain by the
time it gets into a jar and into
patients hand it's probably was
harvested six months ago which it's not
fair so now that THC medicines now may
be CBN because it's degraded so how I
don't know how they're gonna fix all
those things what's on the one hand you
mentioned you know brands spending a ton
of money that you think they're
overspending but then you also said that
the the tourists coming and recognize
the brands from the works just really
from the food not these flower shops
they're not seeing that they're not
understanding the branding that's going
on in front on these billboards they're
so busy trying to make a lifestyle pose
or a picture or whatever they're not
doing anything to educate the consumer
and sometimes the consumer needs a
little bit of Education because nobody
wants to walk into a store and be so
intimidated you can't ask that first
question I mean I know in our store
where I'll say if I'm the one waiting on
the client you know what brought you
here what are you looking for how can I
help you please that everyone has a
story everyone has an ailment everyone
has something or they have a friend that
has a problem so and that's the whole
thing so for me I don't need a brand I
don't need a brand could come tell me
that and then make up some cockamamie
name you know but I can tell you that
the market shifted when you're asking
about that where eighty percent of the
people were connoisseurs in cannabis now
eighty percent of adult use users twenty
percent of us are out there they're
still no we want a specific thing to
smoke we want a certain terpene taste
we're in a certain profile that we're
looking for I don't know how we're ever
gonna get over that hump I don't know do
I go out and create a brand that caters
to that twenty percent I'll let it take
off because I know that if people know
that Janice put her name on it that it
can go in a box and we can sell it and
it'll be what you want because I
wouldn't have done it
do it right sorry just to clarify the
20% we're talking about the highly
educated people it's now 20 percent of
highly educated and 80% have they don't
know and you know the whole markets
change where was an 80% was a medical
user 20% was a recreational user you
know now the whole market is like
flip-flopped so now I cater to the adult
your shoes are we sell tons of pre-rolls
people come in you know whether it's an
ocean pre-roll or Coast pre-roll or kid
that's apparel no one cares you know and
knowing how people what they're using to
do their pre-rolls not realizing that
that's a great place for them to make
money that I would put my best foot in
my pre-roll some of these other people
that are new into the business they
don't they put their trim and their
trash into their pre-rolls
and that's the easiest way to get
someone to your brand it's through a
pre-roll so in any kind of retail market
I think of like beverages and coca-cola
and Pepsi kind of controlling they're
very powerful
so as companies become more powerful
they throw their weight around in not
the nicest of ways so my assumption is
this industry is going to go to a point
where you're going to have these the
chains of you know one it's gonna be a
jury I think you're trying to get to
where are they going to start paying for
shelf space in places to be in stores
and or own their own stores and yes the
reason we have not done that yet is
because I'm more concerned about how the
IRS is going to treat that income coming
in because when everything going into a
cannabis store gets taxed differently
for the 280a than anything else and
until they can discern whether someone's
gonna pay me shelf spaces that rent so
it comes off my rent is that consulting
money to me because I have 12 years
experience in your doing that or it's a
discount off a product and now I don't
have to pay as much taxes there that's
what one another one of those things
that the legislators and things like
that they need to get strength this
whole tax situation because they're
burying us alive
I'm not Al Capone I'm not that's what
the 280 II was started from the night
ladies were the cocaine dealers I'm not
that why am I being treated like I'm a
criminal was alright so yeah I was
basically there are two groups that
could become powerful and throw their
weight around one is a retailer that
becomes the CVS or the Starbucks of
cannabis another one is a brand that
becomes a big dominant brand which maybe
wants to they want to extend payments
like that brand can change try to do
whatever let's do the brand has no legs
unless they have a relationship to
retail and they can get over it you can
tell me how they're going to get over
that hump when they figure it out please
make sure that I know to be successful
yes they need me I do not need them and
they really have to and I don't hate
being like that because I really like to
be the humble person but they those
brands need the retailers and by the
state not issuing the licenses going
back full circle all the way and by the
states on issuing those licenses and
keeping the pre icos and the regular
stores and even municipalities that
voted to have licensed dispensaries and
now they're not only 80% of the city's
only 20% of the city's the state of
California are actually licensed to have
legal cannabis they're just shutting it
off so there's there's a lot more brands
than there are retail spaces right now
so you had mentioned shelf space between
our brands currently
is there a trend of brands now pain yes
where do you see that going I say going
in to be a big mess everything
California when it comes to politics and
Wilson Texas is going to be a mess yes I
could see a huge trend for it it's a
question of how someone operates a
business as to how they're going to
incorporate that into the business some
companies such as a kaliba wants to give
retailer support whether it's software
support consumer support put in their
umbrella ambassadors to run that I mean
there's other ways to do it now how that
it's gonna go full circle back in a
brand can get over it if they just own
the retail space like incandescent why
don't they just buy a retail store then
you have your hub and you can go out
from wherever else you want to go but at
least you have your orange flag
somewhere is med men a nice player in
the space does amendment doesn't bother
me in this space do I like their
business model and do I like the way
they handle things no not particularly
like have they sent the street teams
outside your shop so you try to poach
customers I don't have that but I've
seen them on the streets doing that and
I don't know that I've seen their street
teams out on the streets as much as you
know they were I think they have their
own internal problems to deal with
they've gotten themselves into a
quandary because you know they spent a
lot of money advertising whatever and
they took away the money probably from
their operating costs you know and doing
their day-to-day stuff but I think that
they've bitten off quite a bit and they
have a lot of shareholders to answer to
but like Mad Men is gonna have to answer
tell our shareholders so are some other
companies that are busy running to the
north to get this money and you know
they're investing a lot of quoting
renderings renderings of business plans
or renderings of structures and things
of that sort so I hope it doesn't put a
black eye on the people that have been
here for a long time but I guess we're
used to fixing whatever you know happens
and occurs
that's why they called us though the
pioneers right so you have all these
companies that are raising tons of money
to basically play a long game have you I
don't know if it's necessarily to play
the long game I think from in their mind
they're playing the long game we're
gonna build market share maybe lose this
in the world this is in the world of
social media where the long time is a
minute
it's all relative I guess right but you
seem more slow in study
it's just how I was brought up I mean
it's like using Canadian yeah I still
own a hundred percent of Koreatown
collective we own the CBD store we'll
franchise out some of those the others
CBD stores are coming into other cities
right now as we speak but no so in
addition to your own house brand because
I think a lot of the talk in the CVD
world is it's so crowded with all these
brands and I don't know which ones are
good which ones aren't so give me some
brands that stand out for quality in
your quality beside to elevate CBD
skincare I would say the PABA in
Berkeley they brought their stuff into
CBD world bloom farms made an excellent
tincture the antidote itself we're
coming with our own brands because of
the manufacturing being able to have
beauty manufacturers behind us we're
able to bring all these different things
it's the question of looking for how to
use CBD best like if you're gonna do it
a topically you want to make sure you're
using in a topically place where your
ports can absorb in the CBD and it's
useful to you as far as tinctures you
want to find a company that came into
CBD world for a reason iris are one that
comes up to me because it's a botanical
line of teachers that they make it was a
very natural move for them to come into
CBD world because now they're pairing
CBD with their natural and central oils
when you're dealing with your team
internally what's what's your head of
compliance trying to
hammer and drill and everybody's had for
us our biggest compliance issues are
getting our products in the door
everything you have to have a manifest
and invoice a tracking number and it's
educating our distributors to bring and
have properly documented products that
are coming to the stores where it's my
employees my employees don't have the
problem because everything's given to
them we're ready to go on the shelves
it's like going to CVS when was last
time you went to CVS and you were
standing by the aspirin section and you
didn't know the difference between a
leave Tylenol motrin or whatever but yet
you went in a cannabis store and you've
got four different edibles once two and
a half milligrams one's five milligrams
once in milligrams but yet the cannabis
story you have someone telling you which
one you should take and how you should
take it and how she should use it but
CVS did you have that same thing at the
Tonto section who's going to have a
greater success rate of getting their
client over the headache CVS or me know
me because I educated all right but all
right so from a compliance perspective
it's not really your internal team it's
more the company it's where I literally
it's like running a relay and you're
handing the baton so the baton has to go
from the person that was in the nursery
to the cultivator to the manufacturer to
the retailer
so all that had to match up my in-house
staff once they put their they have
their IDs on they scan their you know
their barcode to come in and out
everything is set up for them oh it's
just like regularly going to CVS and
them explaining products and you
selecting the products you want there's
not a compliance problem on their side
okay unless I'm missing the question
what yeah so it seems like all the
companies that come in to deliver
products some of them are totally on top
they have all their rights and some of
them had they have to go back it's just
rejected I don't teach anymore
I reject what percentage of people
coming to the door to drop product off
our get an a-plus on compliance people
now coming to me if you had asked me six
months ago I would take 10% we're
complying now everything coming to me I
bet you we've got to like 75% are
compliant now I have a lot of people
still new people trying to drop me
products or samples and things like that
and most of them don't even get a
conversation because it's not compliant
product I don't know how that's in the
future it's gonna end up in the track
and trade system that's not my job
thank God and what I like the top they
cannot match they try to do a mass batch
and then they break it into flavors or
whatever and they don't realize that
each flavor it's a distinct unit product
SKU so each one had to be tested to
comments that product SKU it's not just
indica sativa hybrid is the main branch
and they can all have the same SKU now
if you make one flavor one grape one
green cracked one blue drink each one of
those subsets needs to also have asked
you are you going to be doing delivery
yes we are we're setting it up we're
first launching our delivery we're going
to partner with someone and it'll be
like top tier stuff so they can get a
lot larger amounts and then we'll roll
out right behind that world roll that
where you can get deliveries from k-town
direct and that's where your brand's
that's where your loyalty that's where
all 12 years of everything I've done in
my community will make me different than
everyone else because people will trust
what I put in the back also on site
consumption when they finally approve it
for us we would go next door we're next
door to hookah bar so we've already
spoken to because you know it's like
five places on one lot so we've already
spoken and because I ended up being the
mayor of my community block I just like
said you have this in that you know they
don't run the hookah lounge really in
the daytime I said you got this part I
got my part and shook hands and just
wait for the licenses to come out for
the city of Los Angeles which I don't
think will be anytime soon
20:20 know
Gregg is great and Gregg and I have a
lot of the same ideas
we both had each other's backs when the
people just kind of push those aside we
say to our own stuff he's awesome hits
awesome what he's done for the refinery
the micro license he really helped so
many brands at the beginning especially
in 2018 when they needed to get brands
and they needed a place to be format for
a distribution and he took to that and
it's like right now all of us were doing
certain things that made us unique and
pioneers for all those years but every
one every one of us kind of recreating
ourselves and break down his niche I'm
sorry to say my niche went over to CBD
and making other things because I could
operate and think in that space because
that's who I am
so we created I found a I found a void
and I I just drove a truck through there
there's something to the idea that for
that last mile distributor really
knowing that market really well is an
advantage I think that Gregg is really
good at what he does and he's gonna know
his products of what it is and I do
think it makes a difference that last
mile but I think the brands have to
remember they're using Gregg for that
last mile distribution they still don't
kind of come back in there and support
Gregg Gregg doesn't have the time to go
make their brand in other spaces you
know I'm saying yes he can to get the
product there and get it there because
he has to travel with it they need to
support Gregg you know and if that Gregg
can be more successful Gregg can be it's
gonna make them even exponentially much
more successful so are you seeing this
as an overall issue which is kind of
what I'm hearing lack of support from
the distributor is why disturbia I only
take Brandt's out into my store if
they're coming in to help support but I
can't do it anymore they have me with so
many jobs and so many hats it's just
hard it's hard to keep up with emails
it's hard to keep up with everything
I mean they've made a miserable space
they took something that I really used
to like have fun doing and I would go
through and I get
products and create it I would create
products I would have edibles right so
we were always making the chicken and
waffles and sauces and we are going into
contest we didn't even ask we were
winning just because it's what it was
and our concentrates and they've taken
that away they've cut our arms off the
politicians the government legislators
law enforcement although I have to say
my law enforcement for me they've so
supportive of us we had a robbery and
they were like the detectives kind of
like looked left in the lead detectives
said no she's our girl she's our
legitimate shop and we're going and it
was and they were there and they checked
up on me every single part