[Music]
today we're discussing the newly
released draft permanent regulations
that are currently in a fifteen day
comment period so to start just so I
understand how many people here are
retailers are in the retail space
all right and how many are distributors
distributors correct good
cultivators in the room thank you any
testing labs here today okay good but
see manufacturers in people
manufacturing okay great
and then I know we have some POS
companies some people who work for
advertising and branding firms and then
my compliance nerds in the back so I
will admit what I'd like to preface by
saying one that this isn't everything
that's in the regs in the newly released
draft it kind of is to help maybe focus
your attention on certain areas
obviously there's some big hot-button
issues that everybody is talking about
and then there's also some more granular
interesting little tidbits that they put
in there that also have consequences so
part of this is we're just going to talk
through some of those changes
highlighting those changes the possible
impacts and hopefully give you some some
fuel or inspiration to draft some
meaningful public comment in this very
short period of time we have how many of
you guys commented on the last set of
regulations actually submitted comments
okay so the interesting thing on Friday
October 19th these revised regulations
were released we have until Monday
November 5th at 5:00 p.m. to submit
comments so that's 12 more days from
today a special No
for this round of comments is that only
comments addressing the newly proposed
changes are accepted so you can't go
back and still comment on the old things
that didn't change so you really want to
identify when you're looking at this new
language where a change happened because
that's your that's your crack to get in
there and insert public comment on those
aspects so you can comment on the newly
proposed revisions and you can also
comment on the new documents and forms
and other things that are glorious that
they've introduced so in order to not
have this just be a completely
depressing experience I tried to start
with some positive aspects that I
gleaned from some of the changes that
we're good there were good wins that we
had one of the biggest ones I think for
the industry is going to be that they've
changed the sequence of labeling so that
distribution can now label the
cannabinoid content THC CBD after after
final product so a manufacturer can
submit their packaged labeled product
with everything except that cannabinoid
content to a distributor and after
receiving that certificate of analysis
then they can put on the THC CBD if
you've been seeing the headlines that
one in five products is failing in
California everything's poison oh my god
65% of those fails is because of label
claims is because the THC CBD is not
coming within that 10% threshold and so
now we would hope that about 65% of
those remediation efforts will be
eliminated and people will just be able
to label it after they get that final
test result another big one is that the
BCC in the Department of Public Health
have agreed upon teachers being a thing
and being allowed to be part of the
industry so they've changed the rules
around alcohol alcohol content for
tinctures so this is now an allowable
product category and they're actually an
agreement which is fantastic when that
happens
thanks to SB 311 we now have distributed
distributor transfers that are possible
so the test results hold and you can
distribute a tested program product and
transfer that between multiple
distributors so you don't have to test
it with every single distributor that
you should happen to be work
with great win there's expanded events
locations thanks to a be 20/20 so now it
doesn't only have to be on a fairground
with local authorization we have
pathways to have more public events for
retail and consumption we can now reject
partial shipments this was like you know
maybe not a very exciting one but it was
pretty great because they had it before
that either you had to accept the whole
shipment or reject it if something was
wrong with it so now if you get a
shipment and some of the product is
damaged you cannot accept it if you get
a shipment and part of it is not labeled
correctly you cannot accept that part of
the shipment and as a retailer you can
take in the rest of it that'll help the
supply chain a little bit there's now
edibles can be remediated through
repackaging so if you put in your batch
of you know blueberry chocolates and it
hits over the limit you can actually
repackage it so that you can put as many
would actually meet the requirement
instead of having to destroy that that's
pretty great there's some higher action
levels for the category to solvent so it
kind of gives a little more wiggle room
there in the testing things and there's
lots of new forms
we love forms it's great the BCC has all
of these instructions that they give on
notifying them about this and notifying
about that but they never really gave
much methodology to notifying other than
like send an email to info of BCC and
maybe somebody will see it and a lot of
these forms have to do with like the
licensing procedures because they
probably saw a whole gambit of quality
and and presentation and form so in a
lot of ways it's it's really good that
they're systematizing it it should be a
lot easier going forward there's going
to be a lot more clarity and even with
the sequin I'm it's provided Los Angeles
was a morass with sequa because the
process in LA has been so slow they've
now laid out clearly what everyone's
expected to give with respect to sequa
and those forums like I mentioned and
begin are part of the material that you
can comment upon so if you I'm not
covering the contents of those forms in
this presentation but you would want to
look at the content of the
forms and if there's aspects of it that
merit a comment you will want to do that
so in the greatest thing maybe is more
clarity I don't know some in some cases
yes in some cases no but now we'll talk
about the other things the other things
in there so one of the biggest pieces
that came down is this expanded
definition of ownership surprise you may
be an owner of a cannabis company and
not know it the language that was added
in one section is that any individual
entitled to a share of at least 20% of
the profits may be considered an owner
this is important because a lot of folks
were using passive involvement to claim
that they weren't owners and so this is
really going to affect a lot of the
large management groups out there who
are managing multiple retail chains if a
particular jurisdiction has a cap on
ownership per city in many cases I have
included the statement of reason that
came from the BCC sometimes just because
it's funny like some of their statements
of reasons is one step up for because we
said so so and or lots of times it's
just like this is just additional
clarity if it's ruining your life it's
fine so so some of those you'll see I
included like what was their reasoning
that went in cases that they did it so
it's extending upon that this is where
it starts to get really interesting in
that designation of owner so they put in
this from any individual who assumes
responsibility for the license so this
can be somebody who's managing or
directing the business in exchange for a
share of the profits it can be somebody
who assumes responsibility for debts it
can be an individual who is determining
how a portion of the cannabis businesses
run including non plant touching
portions of the commercial cannabis
business such as branding and marketing
that's interesting that's an overreach
we'll see and then also an individual
who's determining what cannabis Goods
the commercial cannabis business will
cultivate manufacture distribute
purchase or sell so this is this is
where it gets interesting in a lot of
the discussions that are happening
because
can theoretically incorporate a lot of
people and there seems to be a
discretionary aspect of it as well so
when it keeps going like when it's an
entity they want to get down to I want
them to have a t-shirt made that just
says until only individuals remain which
is going to be my new motto for the
cannabis industry itself just say can we
just take it back the individual and
anyone who's been going through the
license licensing processes probably
experienced that we've had a couple of
projects where we've had to go up six or
seven levels of corporate entities until
they get to the warm bodies it's it's
Las Vegas casino style regulations they
ultimately want to know who's going to
be profiting with these businesses where
is the money going and that's along with
the expansion of the definition of
ownership came the expansion of a
definition of financial interest holders
some of these were super surprising you
know that they go down to receiving a
portions of the in profits is employees
who are doing a profit share with their
own company landlords who have entered
into lease agreements who are taking a
piece of your company consultants who
have taken a piece of your company
attorneys and accountants who have taken
a piece of your company part of this to
me is super exciting because we're gonna
see all of these interesting companies
that have been taking a piece of a lot
of people's companies and they're gonna
have to be disclosed as financial
interest holders and that shouldn't be
surprising at all because that's the
guidance the state's been giving over
the last nine months when disclosing
these financial interests you know
unambiguously they've gave us advice in
writing over the phone that you know if
anyone's getting a percentage of the
revenue if anyone's getting percentage
of the profits if any time there's
percentage based compensation that's
like the red flag triggering that you're
financially interested
state wants to know who you are as a
financial interested party you're not
getting live scan but the state wants to
know who's profiting from these things
absolutely and even if even a
salesperson who's making a commission on
sales is considered a financially
interested party and if that commission
you're getting or that portion of the
business exceeds that twenty percent
threshold back to surprise your own own
because you're now profiting more than
20% based on your business so conflating
those two when an institute has that
financial business the the Bureau is
going to decide in some cases they may
decide that you do fall under the owner
through their definition of owner so
while there's different requirements as
Aaron was saying of the disclosures you
have to do in terms of live scans and
whatnot as an owner and just being
listed with your information and
identifying features as a financial
interest holder it's possible in
disclosing those financially interested
parties that the bureau is going to
receive review it and say actually that
person is an owner and and shift that
and the same thing with the financially
interested parties they want to get down
there to the flesh-and-blood person
until only individuals remain it's you
can't be an entity they want to know
every person involved with that entity
no matter how many layers the entity
goes back and and just with anything
throughout these licensing process you
know failing to disclose or having the
appearance that you're trying to hide
something that's usually going to be
worse than what you don't want to
disclose if they think you're
intentionally trying to deceive them and
in that understanding of seeing that
interest that they have in who where
who's where's the money coming from who
is involved who are the parties I
believe has a lot to do with the second
area of white-hot panic which is this
white labeling issue that has come up
which is the the the sentence all
commercial cannabis activity shall be
conducted between licensees and that in
the extension of this they get a lot
more detailed on that you're not going
to be conducting commercial cannabis
activities on behalf of at the request
of or per with the contract with anybody
who is not licensed under this act so
this obviously brought a lot of fear up
for people because a lot of people's
models are based on white labeling
relationships with non licensed entities
and brands that there's many reasons for
this I'm some of the issue that we see
is what and this will kind of thread
throughout is that you have the industry
in my opinion is responding to
large and sometimes egregious operators
who are operating unlicensed under the
protection of saying I'm an on plant
touching brand therefore I don't have to
tell you who I am I don't have to get a
license and I don't have to be held to
your advertising regulations so in a lot
of these cases it seems like an action
on the bureau's part to be like nope you
want to be a cannabis brand you have to
play by the rules of regulated cannabis
there's been a lot of celebrities who
want to attach themselves to Canada
cannabis brands and and the overarching
guidance from the state and again I'm
not shocked by seeing it in policy now
is that they don't want unlicensed
people engaging in commercial cannabis
activity they don't want licensees going
beyond the scope so you know I spent the
last two days in Anaheim with a lot of
smart people who were all you know
discussing solutions for this issue
obviously this is if this is an area
that desperately needs some comment
because I think in trying to take out
one piece of it obviously it's it's
compromising the way that a lot of
smaller businesses are functioning in
this space so what we need to offer here
and this goes into how you craft a
comment is a meaningful comment is the
only thing that the agencies have to
respond to so if you just say hey you're
ruining my life and why don't we just
deregulate everything that wouldn't be
considered a meaningful comment you have
to actually cite a specific section the
specific regulation say state what the
problem is and offer a solution so
luckily there's lots of smart people
working on that but don't necessarily
depend on them to do it you should
submit your own comments there's been
everything suggested from maybe they
should have been a new license type that
would cover brands and IP and an on
plant touching aspects with 15 days and
them up against the line of expiring
emergency regs are you know chances of
that happening are slim or
as some eloquent people thought it might
be as simple as the addition of some
language saying that all of this is you
know this is fine and good except in the
cases in which the person is a financial
interest holder so that you could extend
that information in terms of who is the
person it benefiting from this and that
they want their name attached to it
their information there's an interesting
model in ABC liquor that could be a
possible solution as well which is a B
893 in 2015
sponsored by the California craft
brewers association created this thing
called a beer brand registration so a
beer brand registration was a document
that a brand would send even if they
were contract manufacturing to say hey
we're brand here's our information
here's here's what we want to do we can
only dream of the day as cannabis people
that you could get something as sweet as
this when you read what it is in the
business and Professions Code that all
they have to do is register the band the
brand with the Department upon filing of
the registration you can be sold without
any further action from the department
you don't even have to wait for them to
say it's ok you just send in the letter
and it's fine you go for it that would
be great so I mean this is an example so
there are examples from the alcohol
industry of even for the brokerage issue
because some of that stuff of financial
interest holder and unlicensed parties
goes into that broker model of the
middleman who is arranging deals and
making that problematic and in the wine
industry you have a wine broker license
which is you register they have your
information you're listed with the state
I'm a wine broker it's interesting to
look at
Nevada's model where Nevada has the
agent card anybody who's participating
in any way in the cannabis industry has
an agent card they get live scan their
informations there and it seems like
this might be something that would
satisfy the state's interest in knowing
who are the players what is your name
where do you live you know and where is
the money like where is it coming from
and where is it going so those are those
are some of the existing models we have
to point to to say hey is that simple
and something like that
could be something like beer brand
registration could be easier than the
creation of a license type which is
causes them panic and fear or you know
something that may not satisfy their
needs of the information disclosure that
they're after so another big topic was
the technology platform regulations so I
mean in short form we can see what
happened is that some unlicensed
operators advertisers tech platforms
were you know doing very very large
scale businesses benefiting from the
commercial cannabis industry and
sometimes the non-commercial cannabis
industry and in claiming that because
they were not a licensee they were
outside of the domain of the regulated
sphere so it seems that the Bureau has
come with a very specific Smackdown for
some of those business models so this
piece of regulating technology platforms
was another with an was another big one
this was their statement of reasons was
that the Bureau has found that a number
of Bureau licensees engaged in delivery
services that are facilitated by
technology platforms however use of such
platforms has created confusion in
customers as to whether a bureau
licensee is conducting the commercial
cannabis activity so moreover some
technology platforms may create the
impression that they hold a bureau
license and so to clarify this and avoid
this confusion the bureau decided to
throw down this section 54 15.1 shall go
down in infamy that a licensed retailer
or micro business can't sell or transfer
goods through the use of an unlicensed
third-party intermediary business broker
or any other business entity so that's
you know clarifying so unless you know
there are things you can use a platform
you can use technology we're not having
to be Stone Age and go off the internet
but the number one is clear the licensed
retailer licensed micro business did not
allow for the delivery of cannabis goods
by the platform in the delivery
regulations delivery
they have to be employees of the
licensee that was pretty clear so that
one you know we got that this is a nice
one the licensed retailer licensed micro
business does not share in the profits
of the sale of cannabis Goods with the
technology platform service or provider
or otherwise Prasad provide for a
percentage or portion of those cannabis
Goods sales and and this shouldn't be
surprising to the extent we're still
recognizing medical cannabis because a
lot of these commission-based
lead generation contracts and the
medical community are just wholly
illegal with other healthcare providers
it should be you know in the healthcare
context it's all done unlike flat fee
fair market value arrangement not based
on like per capita or percentage of the
sale and we saw a similar thing in the
events language when they did the event
that no event coordinator can make a
profit of the sales off of their
business so it's kind of kind of trying
to create these clear contracts where
there's a fee to use it that's the same
for everybody and not that there's these
individual profit sharing agreements
this one is fun as well number three so
the licensed retailer can micro business
can't advertise or market cannabis goods
in conjunction with the technology
platform service provider outside of the
technology platform and shall ensure
that the platform service doesn't use
their license number to advertise on any
advertising we're marketing that
primarily promotes the services of the
technology platform so when you're
driving around and you see an ad just
for a technology platform with no
license fee attached or with a license
number attached that does not belong to
that look that delivery platform this is
what they're calling out in this prin is
problematic that the delivery platform
cannot be the predominant thing
advertised over the actual licensed
retailer who owns the license number so
that is going to throw a wrench in a lot
of the billboards all over California
we'll see these these ones this one is
nice as well that the licensed retailer
micro business has to ensure that the
following information is provided to
the consumers that the product
advertised for sale discloses at a
minimum the licensed retailers or micro
businesses business name in license
numbers so when you're on said platform
and you're just buying products and you
have no idea which store it's actually
coming from what the state is saying is
that that retailer the actual retailer
with a license number supplying that
product has to be visible
this one this 4a is important because
this actually is not just deliveries
facilitated it says any cannabis Goods
advertised or offered for sale so this
also would incorporate advertising
platforms that are advertising products
without a licensee and license number
attached that's no longer okay and then
this B is interesting as well placing
when you're placing an order through
that platform you have to be aware of
which retailer it's coming from and
their license number prior to buying the
product so it's not that you go through
the whole system and it's this blind
process where I'm on platform XYZ going
through it and I bought a product and
then at the end when I get the receipt
I'm like oh this actually came from this
dispensary you have to know before you
buy the product which dispensary is
actually supplying that product there's
a lot of where you go I mean it is
interesting in this case because that's
what I highlighted at the top I mean
there's a where the onus is placed is
something that I like to look at but
it's the licensed retailer micro
business has to ensure that it's it's
visible enough so that makes it
interesting that you then begin to
question the fine legal minds of is it
not the platform's responsibility to
make sure that information is visible or
it's the retailer's responsibility to
make sure it's more about consumer
safety so consumers know where
they're getting products from and if
something bad happens with a product or
or if there's some other you know
non-compliance that's a threat to public
health you know the the BCC has a record
and they can go up that trail to nowhere
where the product came from yeah it does
I mean and that's something I like to
remember is that as much as like the
Bureau of cannabis control is that you
know the agency we're kind of most
familiar with maybe in the industry that
they're housed under the Department of
Consumer Affairs and the Department of
Consumer Affairs like you know reason
for being is to protect consumers from
deceptive or misleading advertising and
and in public safety and those aspects
so a lot of when you're going through
the statement of reasons one of the
things that comes up consistently with
the BCC is that there was confusion
around this and when people are
reporting how is this person doing this
they don't have a license I don't
understand I don't know where this
product came from that's what they're
responding to is that visibility on the
consumer side of Who am I getting this
from where do I come from and ultimately
it's going to be important for the
industry because when we move into you
know the our litigious future and you're
dealing with product liability consumer
reliability all of that information has
to be a parent for the consumer of who
did I get this and where where did it
come from and I think it goes back to
their overarching theme with it which is
they don't want unlicensed people
engaged in commercial cannabis activity
so it's it's really showing that these
technology platforms aren't the ones who
are the licensed entities aren't the
ones who are filling orders aren't the
ones who are delivering they're not
doing commercial cannabis activity the
onus is to make sure it's clear to the
public to the customer
where they're getting a product from and
I think a million like we said part of
it I think is the reaction of the agency
from the response that they've had when
they've when they've made outreach and
enforcement efforts or requests of large
technology platforms that their response
was well actually we're not under your
purview so have a nice day that they
went
and get my pencil I honed in make that
not the case so I will always give
diplomacy goes a long way just maybe
don't pick a street fight just yet
so and this is the last piece of that is
that even on the required sales invoices
and receipts again that you have to
disclose that licensed retailer and the
life already there in the delivery regs
yeah like that's exactly that that was
in record-keeping requirements anyway so
just let's keep talking about delivery
because there's two more things on that
the other aspect of delivery I didn't
drop the slide in here and but but one
of the things that did stay is that you
can deliver to any municipality
municipality whether or not they have a
ban that piece is still in there
the state is hanging tough they believe
that it has you know access must be
preserved so we'll see what happens with
that what the League of Cities response
is going to be we'll see but the BCC is
sticking by it they did make some
alterations to what we've been calling
the dynamic piece of it which is that it
had gone up in that revision to that you
could carry $10,000 worth of product in
a delivery vehicle you could drive
around the block until you got a call if
you get if you got an order within half
an hour while the rest of the industry
goes through extraordinary security
measures alone delivery driver could
make an order in their trunk in the
middle of a public road they got some
responses about that they got some
responses so they've scaled it back a
little bit so now it's the the you can't
have value in excess of $5,000 at any
time in a delivery vehicle and that the
value of the goods carried in the
vehicle that was not received in
processed by the licensee prior to the
delivery to partner in departing can
exceed three thousand dollars so pretty
much you have to have if I'm doing the
math right because so many of these
things hurt my brain uh you have to have
a two thousand dollar set of prepackaged
orders to leave and you can have three
thousand dollars of additional inventory
in the car as a delivery driver
you can't do multiple stops yeah so you
can leave with those $2,000 of orders
set and then continue to get orders on
the fly I mean look at this section
carefully there's still more
record-keeping requirements and the
inventory log requirements and and
there's more finesse to how this has to
go down but but this is the amount of
retail cost
it's the retail value of the products in
the car
oh dear what'd I do okay okay so another
beautiful one is it a vehicle used in
the delivery can't have any markings or
other indication on the exterior of the
vehicle that may indicate there a
delivery employee maybe not have been
the best idea ever to be like the Geek
Squad driving around being like come
over I got weed so so they're saying
pretty much please don't drive around
advertising your vehicle industry this
part is interesting there's been some
confusion around this fully enclosed box
was added to clarify that no portion of
the enclosed box container a cage can be
comprised of any part of the vehicle or
the trailer this is also mirrored in
distribution vehicles because what was
happening is people you know got a
Sprinter van and they dropped a cage in
the back and they're like it's a cage so
the the state is clarifying for better
or for worse that the security on the
inside of the vehicle has to be its own
cage like that it can't you can't be
using the sides of the car or caging of
in the vehicle itself it has to be a
distinct fully enclosed little lock box
inside of it also has to be bolted to
your vehicle so I mean there's again
read the whole thing cuz it that that it
has to actually be bolted so but but it
can't be that you just put welding
inside of you know the back of it so you
open the door they want that secondary
thing so nobody just cuts through your
door opens the side door and there you
go oh so this is a this is a new big
record-keeping piece for delivery
some technology platforms that I know
are ready for this which is great so at
all times you had to identify where your
drivers were so if the BCC walked in and
they go where's all your drivers you had
to be able to pull it up and identify
them on GPS immediately now you also
have to document the history of all
locations travel to by a delivery
employer why while they're delivering so
they want in that history that
turn-by-turn history of where they went
and what they did and what their route
was now falls under that 90-day
record-keeping requirement so when
you're looking at your GPS you know
delivery platform technologies that's
gonna be your new question is do you
have turn-by-turn
you know coordinates that are stored for
90 days for every delivery driver and
where they went and what they're doing
and that helps with that dynamic piece
as well because again I mean so much of
what we're up against is obviously like
in an industry such as this that is
pervaded by so much stigma and fear the
way we get out of this is through total
transparency they want to know who it is
where's the money where did you go what
did you do who did you talk to what were
you wearing they want to know everything
that we're doing so this is just another
clarifying thing and there and another
record-keeping requirement I love this
one so much so wild transportation by
means of aircraft watercraft drone rail
human powered vehicle or unmanned
vehicle is prohibited you can now
deliver to Catalina just so you know you
can distribute to Catalina they threw
that one in there it's gonna be
interesting because obviously to go to
Catalina you have to pass through either
federal airspace or federal water yeah I
don't know if they did I don't know if
they did and I'm also loving the fact
that like I there is not a single auto
ferry that goes to Catalina so if you're
trying to fulfill your distribution
requirements with a distribution vehicle
and you can't put your truck on a boat
to take it to the island somebody's
gonna have to hand carry which isn't
allowed
with the venom who leases that boat and
does the Coast Guard know who that is
and you know it takes approximately like
20 years to get a vehicle like
authorized on Catalina they don't like
cars can be married so I don't know if
there's an available compliant
distribution vehicle on Catalina but I'm
sure somebody will figure it out because
as I always say if the canvas industry
is one thing it's wily and smart we will
find a way
now that they've given us permission
we're going to Catalina we're gonna go
um this was another doozy for some
brands I'm sure this came under the
marketing cannabis good there's
alcoholic products you cannot do it
anymore doesn't matter if they have it
or not you can't advertise them as
cannabis beer or wine or vodka or
anything there's a spirit wine or beer
we're done obviously this just this
entire you know businesses are decimated
in this confusion so it'll be interested
in saying that you know and this again
comes down to that consumer affairs part
the claim in this case is that it's a
matter of confusion and they don't want
consumers to be confused that this non
alcohol is cannabis beer maybe is
actually beer
some of them out there are using terms
like hoppy water rocky waters
sparkly water so I mean but that will
also I imagine be a matter of
interpretation of you know again like
when you were saying what are what are
these terms of knowing like how much
confusion in is like if it's a can with
a pop top and it has hops is that too
close to beer for somebody or what is
the interest behind that so a lot of
people are working on that
talking to the agencies because part of
this process too is just getting more
clarity from the agencies what are they
afraid of who's behind it who's lobbying
for what and like how do we fix it so
this is a lesson in kneecapping your
sales 101 which is some other additions
that they made this part has you know
been of concern to me for a while
obviously the the state kind of put
forth this thing on the sale of non
cannabis Goods in response to a lot of
it was the CBD hemp products and saying
like no no all you can sell
cannabis Goods and cannabis accessories
in your shop they've now expanded that
to cannabis Goods cannabis accessories
and brand it in your own branded
merchandise I'm not sure if this is
their intent but it seems crazy to me
that you can no longer sell Jack Herer
is the Emperor wears no clothes in a
dispensary you cannot sell educational
books about cannabis in a dispensary
you can't sell nog Champa and adds
mystery this this prohibition and this
is just my personal concern is that in
an industry where on one hand now we're
allowing delivery to go to any
municipality regardless of a ban and
then you have a retailer who is only
allowed to do cannabis transactions
period and cannot enliven that retail
experience with any other cultural
commodity that they may want to include
in their store you can't sell crystals
you can't sell art you can't sell
records you can't do anything except
sell cannabis cannabis accessories and
your own branded promotional merchandise
add a brig would be an accessory because
you use it to smoke but a book on
cannabis would not be an accessory yes
we can register as a cannabis accessory
but that is an area where I would
desperately encourage comments and
clarifications from the agency because
I'm not sure that they're I think the
intent is one place but the fallout is
another I mean obviously lots of
operators segment their space in their
business so they have their cannabis
space over here and then they have a
regular retail space over here because
why would they pay taxes on you know jit
on selling books and incense and stuff
when they don't have to within their
licensed premises but it is I mean
obviously you guys know there's so many
beautiful amazing you know experience
oriented dispensaries that sell you know
essential oils and others a you know
just in other aspects that aren't
necessarily cannabis at all but
encourage you to make the trip and go to
this place it's also it
tax strategy for retailers because
separate streams of revenues aren't
counted for i 280e so a lot of retailers
have adopted holistic wellness shops
within their retail space or or another
you know type of business to have that
separate revenue to make rent and other
things employees deductible and just you
think this clause is this is a direct
reaction from this ccc to people selling
CBD stuff okay so they're basically
throwing the baby out with the bathwater
just because they yeah that one so
because you can't sell him you also
can't sell doritos it's all gone you
know and and it and i think that's a
challenge especially as brick-and-mortar
retailers work to distinguish themselves
as a destination in in contrast to
delivery models where it's more just
transaction airy you know good because
it's that question of why are people
going to make the trip ultimately and
that so much of that usually has to do
with the education the experience and
the ancillary things that are there so
they also added some definitions one of
them is the promotional materials which
you know is they had to add that for
clarity because distributors are allowed
to transport them and retailers or it's
the one thing you're allowed to give
away is his promotional materials and
it's a very limited definition it can
have no intrinsic or secondary value a
battery is not a promotional material
lighter is not a promotional material
it's literally the flyers and
information that goes with the product
you know they also like because they
love to insert themselves in processes
created a new definition for branded
merchandise so that is clothing hats
pencils pins keychains mugs water
bottles beverage glasses notepads
lanyards cannabis accessories if it's
not that it other types of merchandise
approved by the bureau so there is this
process now of approval of having your
branded merchandise that has to be
approved by the bureau i would like to
challenge all of you to troll the agency
by making up the most ridiculous branded
merchandise and submitting it for
approval
every day I say I can think of all sorts
of crazy things I want to propose so
they outlined this process for branded
merchandise approval so if you want to
sell something that is not clothing hats
pencils pens keychains mugs water
bottles beverage glasses no Pez lanyards
or cannabis accessories you have to
receive written approval from the bureau
before you sell it so you can't start
selling it I got this great idea start
selling and then send it you need that
approval in advance you have to send
them a picture of the item and and get
written approval and to sell the stuff
so and I love their statement of reason
they clarified that the approval has to
be obtained in writing to avoid
confusion about whether they approved it
so you're going yes I believe that is
the definition of Ouroboros slice snake
eating its own tail just like so you
know just in case you thought there was
anything you could advertise for free
please just stop saying free just
eliminate it from your vocabulary it
doesn't exist they double down more in
the in the readapt of the in the first
proposal we got this edition of the buy
one get one free free product with any
donation and contest sweepstakes and
raffles no go and now they've included
you shall not advertise free cannabis
goods are giveaways of any type of
product including non cannabis products
so now you can't even say come to the
store and get a free t-shirt come to the
store and get a free later you just
can't say it like there you go
well discount coupons I would say is not
buy one get one free as long as you
don't think I don't get one free on that
coupon that's not what it is it's not a
free product with a donation yes but you
will run into other issues because there
are other issues with advertising the
price of an item as I understand with
cannabis like you have to parse these
with the rest of the advertising
regulations because there there was
other specifics about things that and a
lot of this runs into because we like to
keep it complicated you also have to
look at your local ordinances for what
advertising is like there are certain
local ordinances that will prohibit you
from advertising price showing a picture
of a cannabis plant like there's certain
things you cannot do in advertising it's
very restrictive again I would encourage
everyone to try to be as compliant as
possible with advertising because if you
look at models like Nevada and they're
incredibly stringent advertising
restrictions we're much like our branded
merchandise here every single
advertisement in Nevada has to be
approved by the bureau by the agency so
I don't mean I would imagine every
magazine is a quarterly because I don't
know how they would have time to like be
like approve every single every single
advertiser has a registered agent card
every single advertiser has to be
verified as a licensed business so there
if if and clearly from looking at the
technology platform language Laurie Ajax
got her hands on some of that Nevada
regulations so if they just keep going
they're going to get to the advertising
part and we might see more stringent C
in those areas
they did not put any language in about a
fee for those so we would hope that's
just incorporated in the licensing fees
which also went up yeah so we'll see so
stop saying free there's no free samples
it doesn't exist it's not a thing I
always love to point out there's some
discrepancy it kind of is like a deep
dive because if you're a Los Angeles
person you know the BCC says you can't
get free canvas goods to anybody now
that's been extended a little bit or
actually that that's you cannot provide
free canvas goods except for in the very
limited medical card scenarios business
and Professions Code says you can't give
away any amount of cannabis or cannabis
products or any cannabis accessories as
part of a business promotion or
commercial activity and Los Angeles
Department of cannabis regulations says
you cannot provide free samples of any
type including cannabis to anybody so
you're not allowed to give anybody
anything in LA you cannot give away
branded merchandise no did I understand
in Los Angeles free samples
but in LA free samples of any type
including cannabis good ha ha that's a
different story all together I mean an
extra bag is now a mandatory thing that
you have to give everybody I don't think
that they considered that branded
merchandise but that would be an
interesting clarifying point to make
with them to say do you have to have
those approved considering that it's
something walking out the door um I
always it I always think though from a
legal perspective I love this definition
the in the definitions of free cannabis
Goods it says it means any amount of
cannabis Goods provided to any person
without cost or payment or exchange of
any other thing of value that's an
interesting phrase to make of like what
is another thing of value because I
would think that there may be an
argument somewhere that like getting
somebody's email address is a thing of
value from a business having somebody
join your you know membership VIP
program is a thing of value I don't know
that anybody's really gone down that
road of arguing that
but it's there and just remember that
it's there so if you were worried if you
were interested in compassion or equity
programs they added equity one word
there there goes for all the comments
about compassionate used obviously SB
829 the Weiner bill passed in Senate
wasn't signed by the governor so we
didn't get the tax relief for compassion
programs the bradford bill SB 1294 did
get passed in sign the cattle board can
a California cannabis equity act of 2018
which gives a fund to begin to help to
facilitate local programs I mean this is
an area of interesting confusion for me
and implementation as well to say that
in addition to the free cannabis Goods
which is giving to the the card holders
in the city that a licensee may donate
cannabis Goods in the use of equipment
in compliance with any local compassion
to use equity or similar program so it
could be that this is yet another
indication of where we need to work at
the local level for having those
compassion programs and equity programs
actually clarified and implemented since
it does seem to give us some sort of
ability to to interface and provide
services to those populations so
continuing the how's everybody doing you
guys doing all right
yeah we're good there's so much I want
to say I mean short answer no there are
manufacturing and distribution companies
that are getting or contemplating
getting delivery licenses retail
delivery licenses so that they can
compliantly deliver product to their own
staff because that's one of the areas
because the state has felt so shackled
by this no free products aspect and that
the entire back end sales process was
something that was seemingly ignored
there are really difficult mechanisms
that people are going through in terms
of those basic questions of sales how
does the manufacturer seeking a
distributor entice that distributor to
work with them when they can't give them
a sample you know until it's gone all
the way through the distribution chain
and been approved so so obviously
everybody right now is doing all of
their crafty work arounds and thinking
that they've managed this system but my
concern is that a lot of those
workarounds will be incredibly difficult
once track and trace turns on because
there's not going to be a category for
oh I gave it to my staff you don't for
or what did I do so so those kind of
fundamental aspects of the supply chain
how business is done how how employees
get educated about products like it
would be preposterous in another market
to think that you go into a wine bar and
you ask the wine guy
what do you recommend they're like I
don't know I'm not allowed to do I have
no idea like there you go let's read the
box like that that's so so I mean
obviously we're in a where
a process of baby steps but that's
that's well well they wouldn't come they
wouldn't come for free they'd come you
know documented and build and put on
your you think because you need paper
for it yeah it's in the manifest the
very interesting thing that I find is
that and this is where some of the
agencies are ahead of others the scene
ETF a the tax agency actually has a
really good descriptive tax scheme for a
product that is given to a retailer or
buyer and consumed it never makes it to
retail they seem to recognize that that
scenario exists in there like and this
is how you deal with the taxes for that
but like many things I mean in cannabis
and in LA like the tax agency was way
ahead of the regulation they're like
absolutely you can pay us for that so so
it's and honestly I mean honestly that's
what people hire like lawyers and
compliance people to do is to be like
how do I map a compliant process that's
gonna stand up to track and trace that's
gonna satisfy the state's requirements
and that can actually allow me to move
things through the supply chain you know
in in the right way I mean the concern
that I have now and then I'll keep
moving through because there's a but the
concern that I have now is and not just
because I'm a compliance in song but but
it's difficult for people to prioritize
compliance when they're just trying to
survive like where obviously everybody's
just like I'm just trying to keep the
doors open I don't have time to make
sure that I'm papering this process
correctly or whatever but as friendly as
the agents may seem when they come to
you know check out your place I like to
be like these are not your friends they
have five years to to levy penalties and
fines against things that you're you did
day one the tax agency has said they
absolutely will go back and audit year
one the record-keeping requirements for
cannabis companies went into effect
back on January 1st so everyone that was
feeling that they had all this lead wag
is really all well track and trace isn't
on so I can do that I'm gonna bring in
this product I'm gonna do that when they
show up and they're like okay we need to
review your records on it like for this
year you know that's just it's the
question is like what position is that
going to put you in and we'll get to it
at the end you'll see the the
cultivation Department put in their
penalties for record-keeping the
operational penalty for working without
a license maxes out at five thousand
dollars like if you if you're operating
without a license it's a severe
infection obviously you can get your
license rug whatever but the fine is
five thousand dollars in the
record-keeping section of administrative
failures the max fine is thirty thousand
dollars per instance so they are not
kidding about record-keeping and it
sounds so boring don't say it's it's
it's the hardest thing in this moment to
convince people that this is something
you should be thinking about I I think I
think I think it's never too late
this is I think that this is you know
the final regs aren't final this is
always going to be an evolving process
it may be - it may be too late I mean
it's not too late in terms of I think
everybody should comment on it it should
be on record your voice should be heard
it's a public record they need we have
to document our existence and our
feelings but but one of the things one
of the glimmers of hope that a lot of
people are looking to as well is in
November we're gonna have a new governor
and we are gonna have a governor most
likely that really supports the cannabis
industry and supports efficient business
so that you have the option of where
this regulatory tweaking period will end
you know this isn't over by a long shot
there's 70 bills that are gonna be
introduced on cannabis in January you
know or more probably by the time we get
to January there
a huge amount of legislative change that
can happen as well and that's kind of
the more master strokes that we need is
somebody to go in and really correct
some of the things that were caused in
the drafting of my cursor I mean anybody
knows me like one of my big pet peeves
is like Alma was an adult use bill with
a 15% excise tax that got combined with
the medical program and put an adult
excise tax on medical goods how that
happened I don't know like but it but
that should be undone and there's a lot
of areas where people are working you
know to change those things the other
thing that I'll say is that like you
know for this very moment we're sitting
in right here these are not the rules
these are still the proposed rules you
know so we still have 12 days of
comments a new introduction of a draft
so I mean it's it's incredibly difficult
I understand as operators to be like one
of those it you know you're trying to
make packaging and they keep changing
every aspect of it which is the next
thing we'll cover really quick it's
difficult to be that responsive but it's
also you know that it's it's
unfortunately the the race that we're in
is having to be that that nimble so you
may have seen that CRP is back sort of
not really often so they kind of entered
this halfway thing where so now prior to
January 2020 it has to be tamper evident
but it doesn't have to be child
resistant or resealable unless if you go
to the Department of Public Health where
if it has multiple uses than it does
have to be resealable and then ask we've
been starting in 2020 it's going to have
to be that resealable tamper-evident in
child resistant so until that day the
Department of Health says you can meet
those packaging requirements through the
use of an exit bag ah this is kind of I
was talking to somebody from the
Department of Public Health about this
because it's almost like you know we had
the environmental argument of like oh my
god it's too much packaging or the
industry's not ready and this is
terrible and then we have the oh my god
I don't want to do exit bags or why
don't we just do it that way and now it
seems they just did all of it at the
same time they're just like great
now we're gonna have literally literally
all cameras goods purchased by a
consumer can't leave the present
premises unless they're in an opaque
exit package which prior to January 2020
has to be resealable child-resistant and
opaque so now we find ourselves in the
Kafka esque world in which child
resistant packaging is going to be put
in a child resistant exit bag to leave
in store so all of our worst features
are being realized and then after 2020
you know you can have tote bags so and
and they did clarify that immature
plants and seeds don't have to be shoved
into an exit bag so that's nice please
comment on this please do i I mean
anybody that was coming at this from the
oven
Peter the future canvas project had it
had an event we're talking about the
becoming ecological disaster and lack of
sense that it has that in a state where
we outlaw plastic bags and straws we're
like but we're gonna package this and
now honestly now that the problem has
been even duplicated like and it's
difficult because as I was talking about
to to the Department of Health is the
last thing I want is more onus put on a
retailer who has to have both tote bags
and exit bags and be like is this child
resistant I don't know which one do I do
so putting it all in X advice fine but
but it's super messy it's super messy
and there's a lot of there's big
packaging lobbies that are the kind of
drove that has changed it was gonna be
exit back so it was gonna be like you
know what we'll just do exit bags and
then the packaging god the lobby was
like Whitney packaging you think and in
it's complicated but again this is one
of the I had I had a great conversation
with the Department of Public Health
about unfortunately we're up against
this timeline because the emergency regs
are going to expire they need to have
permanent regulations and we're going to
have to continue to work on them I think
for the packaging at least from the
Department of Public Health there there
seems to be this kind of openness to
this is an area that's going to require
more nuance than we have time for it is
not a one-size-fits-all solution my
pie-in-the-sky fantasy I think the first
place for us to really pull back
packaging is not gonna be on edibles
because there's just too many freakishly
terrified people who think you're
they're gonna eat a blueberry and jump
off a balcony or something but is in the
flower market because the flower is the
part that's just insane to think that
it's all being prepackaged in this
incredibly onerous tiny little bottles
and stuff and in one of the arguments
that I've made to the department's is
even in the pharmaceutical model when
you go to CVS the big drug companies
ship bulk powders and pills to CVS and
the pharmacist fills your prescription
and puts it a little bottle and gives it
to you and that is a tracked and traced
process and once we have track and trace
I think that is an area where we will be
able to eliminate a huge swath of
packaging because once they have
visibility on every single gram of
cannabis its moving through the system
there is no reason we cannot return to
that system and for years I've been
talking to them about when they think
about products moving through the chain
they're thinking about beers and
cigarettes and they're thinking about
things with these with shelf lives and
just standardized processes and in the
case of flour I keep telling them you
need to think about a tomato you need to
think about how many how many people do
you want to touch your tomato before you
can seed you know and when you go to the
grocery store you don't just go up to
the guy at the counter and be like I
want a tomato you like to see the
freaking tomatoes you like to go I like
that Apple you know that that is an
experience and again that's one of the
possible distinguishing things that
would that would support
brick-and-mortar retailers and the
ability to be like I want to go to the
store because I want to choose the exact
you know the exact flour that I want to
try and they seem receptive to that but
who knows you know we'll see but I think
that's something I think that's an easy
win because the other thing is from the
public safety perspective if a kid gets
into a bag of flour and eats it who
cares like nothin's
gonna happen they're gonna be fine yes
well it this is a big question that I
have in terms of where that liability
lies because if they show up in your
retail establishment and you have
improperly packaged labeled products on
your shelf they may seize it they can be
like this is this is not right in terms
of when we see you know they've moved
from the friendly-like tariff sheet
warning to like certified letters now of
like notices to comply so they've gone
to like stern letter writing but I think
in January we will start to see the
actual levying of penalties and fines
for first summer I mean the most
egregious things that they've actually
done fines for so far has been when
people don't allow you if they if you
don't let them in you will get a fine to
be like no he can't come in but I mean
this is why internal compliance programs
are so important because now that
they've added this aspect of you can
reject a shipment if it's not packaged
and labeled correctly it suggests to me
that some of that onus is going to be on
the retailer because you've never should
have taken it you shouldn't have
accepted that product if it's not
labeled correctly so this is why
everybody should have their packaging
and labeling checklist for when the
product arrives you sit there and you go
through all those labeling requirements
[Music]
yeah it is a lot cheaper to work with me
than to have that moment but but but the
other thing is they don't give you a lot
of time those notices to comply say you
have 15 days to inform us that this is
fixed not just tell us how you're gonna
do it it's 15 days to say it's done the
products gone stuff is disposed this is
how I corrected it yeah and not just say
it
and don't just say like we did a
training it's like you have to document
oh it's like there's there's all sorts
of aspects of that so I call this the
CDP headaches because if you notice in
the CV pH regulations the Department of
Public Health manufacturing they were
just confusing as all get-out because
they did this awesome thing where
instead of just putting all the
regulations in one place they put Astrix
ha's for the parts that weren't changed
and just didn't print them at all and
then if it was added than it was in blue
and if it was removed it was in red so
you you know you got you got all these
calls of people being like oh there's no
more security requirements or whatever
this is great and it's like no no you
got to go back so literally you had to
have the old version and the new version
to figure out what changed and then go
back and reference the parts that
weren't changed so my first ask for them
is could you please just put it all in
one document because that would be a lot
easier there's a lot of stuff in there
the the packaging was the kind of one of
the biggest ones that's getting the most
attention for this you know when win
2020 kicks in there's gonna be all of
these packaging requirements that kick
in and and even a new labeling piece in
2020 which is if a package is not
intended to be inhaled or are the ones
that are intended to be inhaled and
aren't or topicals and aren't child
resistant after opened it has to say
this package is not child resistant
after opening so if you were worried
about your labeling real estate now you
got one more line to stick in there they
did get a little more clear on the
definition of child resistance because
people were just like is this baggie
okay and so there is a lot more clarity
in terms of what they are going to
consider child resistant I loved the
addition that speaks so much this one
word that came in the cannabis product
quantity equality of homogeneity because
homogeneity is like the bane of the
industry right now evidently the testing
labs are telling the manufacturers you
guys are not good at homogeneity it's
causing a lot of problems in testing so
there's a lot of indications that the
Department of Public Health is really
drilling into those good manufacturing
processes and making sure that people
really know how to make a food-grade
consistent product in the master
manufacturing protocol you know they
kind of inserted a little more
information about that homogeneity word
coming up which is mitigating through
against the potential for adulteration
through incorporation of incorrect
amounts of cannabinoids unintended to
green ingredients hazards in the product
quality plan potential for misbranding
through incorporation of ingredients not
identified on the label or the miss
labeling of product I didn't make a
slide for that for this but they they
now reference out to like the federal
FDA regulations for ingredients for how
you mark artificial ingredients natural
flavor these kind of aspects of what are
the federal requirements for disclosure
of those ingredients because you know
people who are like it's cannabis and
both are you have to kind of get a
little more clear on a lot of those
aspects you all will manufacturers out
there will soon be very familiar with
the help and safety code if you're not
already they've added 21 references to
the health and safety code now pointing
out mostly it was you know they they
articulated in their in their summary
that it's they're revising the good
manufacturing processes to provide
greater clarity to the process and
documentation required when making
cannabis products and and really went
deep on on pointing to the health and
safety code on on 21 different points
saying you need to follow these
guidelines for how to meet these
requirements of good manufacturing most
of it is in that 402 for Oh groans
building and manufacturing premises
section that's the section that has the
lion's share so this was a big one that
a lot of people I know missed because it
seems simple but it's super lame um in
my opinion they've changed the language
from business days to calendar days in
the case of things such as if you lose
connectivity with the track and trace
system and the system goes down for a
couple weeks and you have to log
everything is put on paper and you still
have those three days to insert all your
information those are now three calendar
days not three business days so if
connectivity comes back up on a Friday
you're gonna be paying overtime for the
weekend for everybody to insert all of
your documentation so in many cases and
especially I'm thinking about farmers up
north
these were tight timelines anyway of
having to report every change in
disposition of your flowering into track
and trace within three days and now
those three business days are three
calendar days so even something as small
as that has a huge impact on these
timelines a lot of it is that that track
and trace training now is required in
five calendar days of issue license
issuance so if you get that license on a
Friday two of your days are done
if you're not working through the
weekend so it's it's really critical yes
I there they did not I mean it doesn't
look like they don't know if they had
they did not add a definition of
calendar day in which are exempted from
those calendar days so again if I may
highlight a really simple one for
commenting to say why why are you doing
this the thing that I love and I wanted
to drop it in advisor and halftime is
that there's there's a in one of the
instances where it's the agency's onus
to respond to something there's is in
business days so the industry has to
function on calendar days but the
agencies get business days so it does
seem a little unfair what time is it I
don't know down the clock okay okay I'm
almost there
I think so there's so much in
cultivation
there were some other clarifications
that were made one of the big ones was
on areas that cannot be shared by
multiple licensees again people who have
been doing licensing licensing this may
not come as a surprise but it's
additional clarification was made of
that you cannot share these areas and
then more clarity around shared areas
that have to be contiguous and and what
the designation is for what's happening
there this has been something that many
of us you know who have undergone the
audits from them have seen coming they
added in cultivation plan requirements a
signed attestation that says you're
going to contact the appropriate County
Agricultural Commission Commissioner
regarding requirements for legal use of
pesticides this is when the CDFA has
been coming with the county AG
commissioner
they want to know do you have your
applicator license and your operator ID
so all of the cultivators have to be
going you have to get your you have to
take a class you got to read a book you
got stuff you have to get your
applicator license in your operator ID
and the fact that they have now gone to
put this into signing an attestation
just say you're going to do it means
that they I mean they're seeing a lot of
non-compliance in this area that people
are dragging their heels and
doing it and this was the one I was
talking about the importance of
record-keeping just to look at that
section in the administrative actions on
record-keeping the licensee can be
subject to a citation and sign which may
be issued as a notice of violation of up
to $30,000 per individual violation for
record-keeping for engaging in
commercial cannabis without an
unlicensed or with an unlicensed person
that's five grand for record-keeping it
can be up to thirty thousand dollars per
instance so that's my ad for compliant
more fun stuff this is great so we all
knew that the temporary program was
expiring on December 31st what is kind
of interesting news in there thing is
that once the new proposed regulations
are accepted in early January the bureau
is no longer accepting temporary license
applications when those go under facts
so pretty much in this interpretation of
this we lose the last possible three
weeks of December to hope that you get
that temporary license application in
and you can get that you know New Year's
Eve thing so they're not they're not
gonna accept that there seemed to be
some confusion Laurie was speaking at
the event yesterday and she's like I'm
gonna be doing licenses and we're gonna
take it to the last minute you know em
so we'll see
cuz what it says is that they're not
gonna accept it so we'll have to hope
that those those temporary licenses get
in because obviously if you do not have
a temporary license by the end of the
year
you do not qualify for the provisional
license program so
especially finishing sequa and stuff
like that that will become a very long
process for those who are not able to
operate through that process and make
any income until they get their annual
permit that's bad
goodbye teen plants market so the the
BCC introduced a new definition of
immature plant which is anything over 18
inches I have a lot of questions about
this one because they say it's necessary
because they didn't have a definition so
they made one up doesn't happen to be
the same as the CDF phase definition so
that's cool so my questions around this
would be if you're a retailer and you've
taken in some plants and they grow tall
what do you do with them you have to
destroy them you can't give them back
you can't sell them to anybody yeah you
know I can't send them back to a
cultivator to have a nice prosperous
life as an adult plant so this you know
for that that market of you know teenage
plants that some people like that's too
bad and goodbye this is actually sort of
a positive thing the 14 day
reconciliation was replaced with a 30
day reconciliation so that mandatory
track and trace requirement of
reconciling every 14 days is now at
least once every 30 calendar days and
there was also a slight rise in the
definition of a significant discrepancy
in inventory it used to be $5,000 or 2%
of your average daily sales and now
5,000 is struck and it's 3% of your
average monthly sales sorry it was
whichever is less but they took out the
5,000 so so now it's just 3% 2% yeah or
2% or whatever's left like it just
they're just making it up somebody's
like a lot of people were responding to
this one added to premise this location
that shipping containers not affixed to
the land or not any are no longer
permitted as a structure is not
considered a permanent structure modular
buildings not affixed to the land
structures that rest on wheels or any
structure that can be readily moved
there was some
panic around this because they're like
oh my god all the pods but part of it is
it has to do with that a-fixing nature
and when you read their statement of
reasons it just makes me laugh because
you know somebody's doing it when you
read it you're like they saw somebody do
that with just people with trailers that
are like moving stuff around and being
like now we're over here and now we're
gonna put it over here so their main
thing is like when you submit a premises
diagram
those structures need to stay where they
are you can't move them around so
there's a little more clarity around
pre-rolls
that that you know it had said that they
could do it now it's just a little more
clear that the distributor can package
repackage label and re label cannabis
including pre-rolls for retail sale as
we were discussing there's more
questions risen because you're like
whose brand is it is it there Brett what
do you do what are you labeling it with
I have no idea but an important part in
the lights in the testing sequence to
mark here is a licensed tribute can't
process it but can roll it if it you
know has that and that they have to be
rolled prior to the compliance testing
so it's not yeah boo boo yeah because I
mean I have really interesting questions
on it because like when you sample when
you take a representative sample of free
rolls out of multiple packets of
pre-rolls you can't then repack those
packets into full carton so you're just
destroying like all anyway it's it's a
lot of I suggested
wouldn't you think wouldn't you imagine
that that would be the case but like as
we've seen with some recall efforts and
stuff like that is there concern is that
people are getting stuff text tested and
they're mixing it with other stuff and
then that final stuff is not clearing
testing so I mean this is this is a ripe
area for comments it makes very little
sense that if a bulk cannabis bag passes
the COA and then you roll it that then
you gotta test it again that is I mean
this is where Jenga is the big the
clarity that needs to be had around that
because while you're able to do that
activity if you're a distributor who's
buying bulk flour and rolling it exactly
whose brand are you releasing it as is
or you do in gumming because they're I
would imagine there's multiple
arrangements there some you might be
doing it for another existing brand some
you might be doing it in-house and then
are they going to consider that crossing
into manufacturing it's like war that
there's a lot of questions around this
yeah processors gathering stuff let's
call it stuff yeah at the bottom of a
container or sifting it weak we not not
they're allowed to roll that but I don't
see where they can do
more than that right if they grind it up
and send it downrange to the distributor
says he can't process but he can you
take that crappy flour they sprinkle
little keep on it me rolled up I'm just
trying to see what that line of
manufacturing yeah no and especially if
you know there's the aspect of people
doing infused fuels which is you know
that that has to happen in the
clarifications we need yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah right yeah yeah I mean
honestly it's like it's it's you know
the long story short is like California
jumped the shark on regulations and we
made so many regulations and now they're
learning more about the industry so they
have to make more regulations to cover
that part of the industry and it's
getting down to every single activity
and as I said we're a wily bunch and
we're gonna exploit every loophole there
possibly is to be able to stay alive so
so it's constant it's like this game of
whack-a-mole where it's it's you know
we're gonna see a lot of that I mean and
if I had a magic wand and could wave it
I would have said like can we start with
four regulations that's like you know it
protects testing taxes and public safety
and just be like let's work from there
and it'll be great but you know now we
have this to contend with so it's a lot
of yeah I mean that's a baby I mean I
remember I remember long ago going to
test the the first like lice the first
when they were testing out the online
licensing portal in their product
categories for cannabis was like five
things and you're just like you guys
have no idea do you like they didn't
know there was no like they didn't know
that I mean it the the maturity in the
sophistication in the ingenuity of this
industry is baffling to them of how many
applications there are and how many
things they've had to it you know
inventive
what do you do with you know what do you
do with a breath strip like what do you
do is a tincture that goes under your
tongue and it's a capsule there that
they didn't know that we had huh
yes exactly we don't want it there there
was a big you know this will help a lot
in testing is that you know there was
there was the issue of you know people
of sampling you know the lab shopping
that they want to not happen where you
can't send samples in multiple labs at
the same time and take the results that
you like but then we had the problem of
what happens when a lab goes down or if
a lab loses their license or if the labs
a really expensive machinery breaks and
then your products are stuck in this
laboratory pipeline and there was no
mechanism for labs to transfer that
product to another lab for testing or
for you to be able to have another batch
sampled so they've corrected that I know
the big ask from the testing community
again for these regulations is going to
be about Co a remediation because right
now if there's a typo if they got the
name wrong if anything happens the
agency is like you can't fix it you
can't talk about it it's no good so even
if you submit something and they can't
read your handwriting because of the
prohibition on communicating with you
with that once that process has started
they can't even be like what is this say
like what did you write down here so
it's a some of that will get cleaned up
everybody across the board is gonna get
to do OSHA training yay 30 hours of
general industry outreach course is
gonna happen
good for you OSHA so the main point is
like you know be sure to comment it's
absolutely essential for your business
it's great to get your your voice in
there if you need help commenting
there's incredible trade organizations
you can get with your local trade
organization see CIA is gonna be doing
comments locally there's lots of trade
organizations and groups and collectives
and there's lots of smart people who
will help you um I'm gonna give you
these these this PowerPoint and then I'm
gonna try to create a hot list of just
like again these are
main things that I would go after it's
it's a real great time to team up and
and work collectively to draft these
statements letter it's it's it's great
for to have a whole lot of individuals
submitting feedback it's great to pair
up and have these NASCAR letters of get
every cultivator you know every
dispensary you know to tag on and create
group statements but it's incredibly
important that the agencies know that
we're we're seeing this we're reading
this and the real-life impact that it
has on your business because those are
sometimes the most compelling things for
them is when you explain what the
problem is and how this how this you
know harms your business or your ability
to function in this thing when you're
commenting always remember to comment to
the right agency if you're a micro
business don't send your cultivation
issues to the BCC they do not forward
they don't send it on that you make sure
that you're aligning the regulation with
the agency that issued it and that is
who you're commenting to I think I'm
done I think that's it yeah yeah
that increasingly creates a backdrop of
increasingly 87 or something very close
to that so the question is you can post
this on the licensees and that's great
but what happens on the other side I
mean there has to be enforcement yeah
yeah I mean one of the things that it's
important to clarify is that the
regulatory authority of the agencies is
over licensed operators that's who they
regulate that's who they enforce upon in
terms of an unlicensed operator that's
an illegal activity at this point so it
is on the local law enforcement working
with local law enforcement in the local
agencies to kind of work on those
aspects you have
language yeah there's an interesting
language shift that reminds me of it I
had it in there the importance of a
single word we're in one of the sections
that used to say the formation documents
and now it says all formation documents
where it's like where they just slip
that in there like they don't want a
single contract side deal something
that's related to that business not
submitted and and again I know it's
ridiculous and I know lawyers are
expensive but like this is a critical
time to be looking at having good
contracts with people having good
distribution contracts good testing
contracts because the question is going
to be what happens when something goes
wrong like the question of is that the
retailers whose problem is that that
would be something you can note you
should negotiate in a distribution
contract to say if the BCC comes and you
delivered me non-compliant product guess
who's gonna pay my bill you are you know
that those are the things that can be
negotiated obviously for a smaller
operator it's tough because you don't
have a lot of power to be like darn you
I'm want this but you're gonna want to
negotiate those good contracts because
one of my big fears is what's going to
happen next year when they start levying
penalties and fees and that you don't
see the cannabis industry cannibalize
itself in lawsuits because everybody's
going to be blaming everybody else for
what they did and no this is wrong and
this is your fault and whatever and
that's the stuff that can be clarified
through that those contract processes up
front yeah
um I mean it's an interesting if I
convinces its own like wormhole you can
go down they did make an exception for
kind of educational events that was put
in that don't require a license when
there is no consumption there's no
retail sales there those aspects this
seems to be an allowance for that to
happen and then I mean in some of the
rules around some of the events that do
have consumption in retail are I mean
how anybody's ever gonna my favorite one
in there is that every bit of product
that comes in on the transport that is
transported by a distributor is supposed
to be physically checked by the event
organiser licensee before it comes on
premises so load in for high times is
going to be like a week ahead of advance
yet you can only get a permit for four
days there's something so it's gonna be
a little rough like a compliant we
bringing product on site when those
those aspects are so onerous I mean that
kind of gets into an interesting terrain
of like yes there's a way I mean and
that's the other thing too I mean the
things did a lot of people panic about
in these regulations when you talk to
the lawyers they're like yeah because it
cuz again for them it's just a matter of
I mean that's what we do all day long is
just going like this is what we want to
do and here's you know here's the
winding route to get there and making
sure you're covered yeah
when I asked Lori about remediation when
you know the testing labs wrong my guys
are doing informational testing online
we know it's clean the testing lab -
surveillance wait a second I don't know
that I'm clear yeah uh I mean there are
a lot of conversations about that it's
uh I mean part of the issue again is
it's always like with with any
regulation you know my motto is always
like follow the money follow the fear
you know where you're like who's paying
for it and what are they afraid of so I
mean one of the issues with testing and
in the labs are super frustrated about
this as well some of them is because the
thing that they want to prevent through
these aspects is lab shopping they don't
want you you know shopping around to get
the results that you want but but one of
the issues with like say a really really
effective lab with really really
sensitive equipment who's doing an
amazing job is there's gonna be inherent
lab shopping because if there's this
threshold and you're you're you know
solvent or whatever is gonna be detected
at this lab but it's not gonna be
detected to this lab because their
equipment isn't as sensitive that lab
shopping will become inherent because
and then you'll have people gravitating
towards crappier labs because they're
not gonna see the things that maybe
you're there so you know some of that
the increasing of the thresholds I mean
a lot of labs I mean one of the issues
that we're up against is looking at
phase 3 testing coming in and not even
knowing is anything gonna pass you know
once heavy metals come into the effect
it will come into effect because this is
the part where we're gonna discover like
what are your devices leaching what is
your packaging doing to your product
what are giant metal machines that
extract your product putting into your
products you know that and in that if we
were you know again my pie-in-the-sky
fantasies I would love to see the state
subsidizing and funding testing labs to
be doing phase 3 testing right now so we
would collect the data to know what is
gonna happen when January 1 hits in in
and then we would love to have a counter
thing that was like and while we're at
it let's look at the amount of heavy
metals in a banana you know it's like
we're like what are we up against no
matter what the state requires you if
you can rule you have cartridges from
China kept each out in real time and
that's one of my big concerns for the
industry itself because there was not
long ago there was a law office holding
a continuing learning class for
attorneys on how to see the cannabis
industry and it was a very long list
from things like from product liability
to DRAM laws to you know that they're
gonna come after the budtender who
served the person the cannabis that got
them in an accident before so I mean
this is most of my daily concern for the
industry is not against enforcement from
the agencies it's against enforcement
from litigiousness crazy people out
there like the prop 65 lawsuits that
that are that are that we just now that
we're out in the open there's a target
painted on us and and and protecting
yourself from that is is ridiculous I
mean and in and it's a really hard time
right now and that's as much as so many
people to industry feel like there's
just all the lawyers trying to take
their money it's like this this is
survival you know and it's if you're
gonna survive through this incredibly
difficult transition and then I boot I
do believe that there are greener
pastures on the other side once this
settles
and if you can make it through this I
always described it as the violent J
curve you know we're in this free fall
horrible graph just plummeting down and
then like a phoenix a few will rise you
know from the ashes who can like
withstand all these all the demands
being put upon us
we are a technology firm and we in that
processing equipment for the industry we
bust out we then have to change our
business model
[Music]
yeah we did we didn't cover that before
and I can have like an offline
conversation with you about that of just
but I do think that that's one of the
ones where you know as soon as that
white labeling piece dropped I could
hear like the whirring brains of
attorneys everywhere being like we're
gonna do this we're gonna and in part of
it we were talking about is
understanding the source of what they're
after and part of it is they want to
know who's behind these companies where
is the money coming from who is
disclosed who are the financial
interested parties and bring them into
the gap so so part of the work that
we're gonna have to do in this comment
period and and with the agency is is
clarifying giving them the information
they need and what do they need to see
about this business arrangement to make
them comfortable to know that it's
happening to know who's involved because
it does seem ridiculous that you know
because then you do I mean that's what
everybody's thought is is then you'd
like is the nutrient guy and the you
know light supplier and the equipment
supplier and the POS company
incorporated in this and part of that is
that it's sloppy language and it's not
finessed and it's not clarified enough
right now to know who is truly
incorporated in this I mean I would say
talk to your lawyer cuz I mean when I
talk to the lawyers they're like it's
fine like well we got this you know so
but it but it requires navigation and
there's no way to know in this second
because these regulations aren't
finalized and they're not and they're
not established and so that's the
clarity that has to be asked for from
the agency yeah
we do notice that in the BCP regulations
5425 yes
that is a potential problem because it
gave instructions on consumer data yeah
that will one per keeping and super
recalls how are you gonna reach a
customer if you're not yeah preserving
that data but really believing is the
issue and the language
it's removed from the defense
I I think I mean I've run into a couple
of missing sections where I'm like
you're referencing something that
doesn't exist so I think that my guess
is that because it seems to be referring
back to record-keeping and that the
record-keeping part isn't there yet
so that's like where we're gonna you
know that yes I think it'll come back
because there was something I pointed
out to them previously because there was
those extensive directions of what to do
if it was a medicinal sale but they
didn't have any record keeping
requirements for an adulterer sale and
then they expanded it to both and then
they took the whole thing out so I think
they're having some you know evidently
they're spitballing fuckwit there
there's definitely another draft coming
no maybe I mean we're like tick-tock
what's up yeah yeah cuz they'll be like
it was already there you knew about it
when they were burnt if they took it
after they've been changed or which
partners have to be less stage between
that's the least submitted to hug and
the release of the whale last December
yeah don't ol you see those final
regulations yeah yeah and that's a
difficult place to be as a business to
be like don't make any decisions order
any packaging or do anything until they
come out but but I would encourage you
like please reach out to you know your
communities your the people who you
brainstorm with me our agency other
agencies anybody because this is just
it's a really trepidatious time it's
rough this isn't even this is not even
half of it of the changes that are in
there this is all I could fit into this
amount of time there are more little
beautiful explosive nuggets dropped into
those regulations so so I mean I implore
you to please like sit down with people
have a little study group and go through
the ones incredibly specifically that
pertain exactly to your business type oh
yeah and we are there is a discussion
tomorrow night a future cannabis project
is hosting like the next wave of this
discussion with Jackie and Pamela and
hopefully me I'm we're gonna do it and
elected officials might be there so we
can just continue this conversation
because I also think this is the way we
get to solutions is by talking through
this and going through the scenarios and
seeing like that all the other impacted
things that one change might trigger so
it's in Venice at the townhouse and the
basement speakeasy it's great it's gonna
be awesome the informations on future
canvas project just could go get all the
information you can get yes
yeah that's one things that we were
talking about earlier is I think we
might see Jarrett but but we've talked
about like there is a beer brand or wine
broker license there's models and the
liquor of industries in the spirits
industries for just having an agent card
a broker license registering as a brand
so that you'll give those disclosures of
who you are and your background
information but you but you don't
necessarily I mean they make it sound so
easy where it's like you want to
participate go get a license and you're
like great yeah um the other thing I'll
say I'm probably gonna do a whole
separate piece on this later but this is
my like cause of the day um the type s
license shared facility licenses was
invented six months ago to date guess
how many Type S licenses there are zero
never happened there is a there is a
pathway for small businesses which is
called a shared facility there's a
pathway for the air B&amp;B of cannabis it's
called shared facilities and none of it
has happened and part of it is it needs
action on the local level for them to
understand how to authorize it on the
operational level to understand how to
make your facility compliant as a Type S
it has the state level where they are
receptive and they're ready they just
like are like we need the local
authorization and it was one of the
dreams of like this is how small
businesses can actually get licensed in
function by registering with a type s
license type which would give you a
license as a shared facility participant
and that's a process we're working on
building play playbook for that to help
push that through but I do see that as
an inroad to help with people getting to
this pathway and licensure through
shared facilities and it just isn't
happening it's crazy I just went to look
into it the other day and talked to DPH
and they're like you know there's none
yeah I'm sure they did yeah I mean we
didn't talk about it here but I know in
terms of the comments that was a great
deal of concern people have in terms of
what's being disclosed about you and
we're people knowing where you live look
go ahead there's like a whole other
thing the CBD market there like the out
there market is kind of a spectacular
wonderful insane thing of none of its
okay none of that's okay it's like the
greatest example of just cuz everybody's
doing it doesn't mean it's alright the
state is being very clear about those
but it is kind of like a whole separate
conversation of like outside of the
scope of this I mean anyway I would say
it gives me great concern when once
Big Pharma has a stated interest in
controlling the CBD market I would be
quaking in my boots a little bit if I'm
just like I'm great I'm doing CBD
so if once those laws if they go into
effect they will have conflict with
state laws again which is something
we're already in the middle of yeah well
I mean California is its own world and
that is a side conversation but I mean I
would also look into the fact that the
state just issued pretty clear guidance
on CBD and the DCR just asked everybody
to register for a fee TRC to self CVD
like that doesn't make sense
so thank you guys we have to cut it off
we've call me okay we'll talk we'll talk
[Music]