[Music]
I'll just share a little bit of a look
back a reflection on the current state
of our cannabis laws and regulation and
then and then talk about what the future
might hold again my name is Rob Ponte I
served in the California State Assembly
I represent Oakland Alameda and San
Leandro I'm probably most known for
having maxima Colonus in my office
where's max max is here somewhere
there's max so I mean this is the man
who wrote the MCR essay and spent
thousands of hours and in meetings you
know working it out with with
stakeholders and I've I feel like we've
come a long way in a short period of
time and we're still not where we need
to be but I think there has been a new
mood and a new openness among California
state legislators to address cannabis
policy like any other policy issue that
affects our residents it affects the
people of California affects our
businesses our patients our environment
our health and safety and and and that
is good because when we when we were
working on this issue back in I think it
was 2014 in the fall and then throughout
2015 that was not the case we had a lot
of legislators who this is a bit of an
exaggeration but not really when I would
say hey I have this cannabis bill I'm
working on I'd love to have your support
I'd like to explain it to you and let
you know what it does how it's good for
California how it's good for the
environment how it's good for patients
that was good for safety and they would
almost put their fingers in a cross and
back up slowly and say that's the
cannabis bill I'm a no on that and it
was just any mentioned of cannabis seem
bad and and and because it carried this
stigma right and so through our work and
I say our because this has been very
much a team effort between a number of
legislators who sort of lifted up the
original M CRS a work it was
Assemblymember Joan Sawyer assembly
members would
somebody member Cooley and a bipartisan
group Assemblymember Lackey who worked
on this together with myself to really
do something groundbreaking to to do
something that hadn't been done in
twenty years to provide this regulatory
regime in the state of California for
medical cannabis that we hadn't had
since the passage of the Compassionate
Use Act and this had been something that
had been tried it wasn't it wasn't for
lack of trying had been tried multiple
times and it had failed multiple times
and one of the reasons that I think we
were able to succeed was because we we
set about to address this in a different
way rather than have one coalition of
stakeholders on one side that had
traditionally been together largely the
League of California cities and public
safety folks on one side and have sort
of our patient advocates and and and
Labor and Industry on the other we
decided to work together and invite a
big table and say anyone who's
interested in making our cannabis policy
better stronger more effective working
out the kinks and doing something
historic you're welcome to come to this
table and put your best ideas forward
and they will be considered they might
not always be implemented or included in
the final piece of law but they will be
considered and and and that's what we
did and that and that's that's where max
came in that's where someone else you
may know in the cannabis world who's now
working who was on my staff at the time
on she so came into play they both
worked hours and hours listening to
everyone and tried to get to try to get
the best piece of legislation possible
and we we slowly made progress we we
kept moving past hurdles where in the
past legislation had fallen down and
failed and either failed in committee or
gotten held and then we finally got on
the verge of the governor's desk and
then when you're close to the governor's
desk that's when he gets engaged and he
started looking more closely at the
legislation had his staff get involved
and they had some ideas that they wanted
to include as well and so we were able
to have a discussion with the governor's
office and then in 2015 we got the MC
RSA passed and that was exciting because
they didn't never been done before and
that was exciting because it had been
done in a way that had never been done
before with with a coalition working
together side by side and that group of
legislators and stakeholders I think
continue to be committed to to to the
approach I think that the approach drove
the result and allowed us to do
something unprecedented and and we want
to continue to do that and and we felt
that we made a significant contribution
to medical cannabis policy in the state
of California we knew it wasn't perfect
when you do something that big it's
impossible to get it right just right
but to get it perfect it's gonna have
unintended consequences it's gonna have
components that that are intend to do
one thing but don't accomplish that
there'll be some blind spots that get
revealed where you expected it to do
something but it's something else kind
of squeezed out the side and then you
gotta be committed to the ongoing work
to fix those challenges and we have and
we a big part of that is you you know
you're the experts you're on the ground
you know how the law impacts you impacts
businesses patients the environment so
that feedback loop is critical to us and
a lot of legislators say we want to hear
from you and we really want to hear from
you to share with us what's needed next
in the next iteration to you know move
towards perfection of our cannabis
policy in the state of California I came
at this from a certain perspective I was
chair of the assembly Health Committee
at the time I've been on the assembly
Health Committee my entire time in the
legislature I saw this as an important
issue for patients that that that voters
for whom voters had approved access to
cannabis as medicine and I wanted to
make sure that that was high quality
medicine that it was tested that it was
reliable that those with compromised
immune systems weren't put at risk and I
also came at it as a representative from
Oakland who as you know there are many
pioneering cannabis leaders from my city
and and so I wanted to work with others
to try to get the right policy but but
you know this wasn't something that when
I ran for the legislature back in 2012 I
thought I would be working on
I'm proud and glad I have but really
relies on being the next policy
components rely rely on you and so fast
forward one year from fall of 2015 and
fall of 2016 and in literally a year we
get the M CRS a past and then we get
prop 64 past and and so we're a year
before we didn't have any medical
cannabis regulations and adult use
cannabis I was not legal now both are in
effect and so that's a lot of movement
in a short period of time and the prop
64 was based on them CRS a but it had
some noted departures from our work and
I supported prop 64 as well and you know
definitely I there I do have pride of
ownership but not that much pride I was
I was I was fine with the overall
approach and I think prop 64 brought a
lot of people behind it whether it be
you know patient advocates or those in
the industry themselves or social
justice folks criminal justice reform
folks folks who believe that what it was
that the war on drugs was a failure and
it needed to be fixed and addressed and
there needed to be some changes going
forward and and that brought a lot of
libertarian folks who thought that the
government shouldn't be deciding whether
or not you can use adult use cannabis
since you're an adult and and and the
the election showed that the the numbers
were strong was 57 percent throughout
the state of California and and so now
we have adult use pass as well and we've
been trying to roll out the regulations
every year I'll be working with the
bureau we've been always trying to
improve and strengthen and build on the
work that we we got done with MCA RSA
and and prop 64 I have a bill that's
right now on the governor's desk that
would help speed up the process for
expungements and reductions in cannabis
crimes thank you
maybe the panel beforehand was talking
about that and other issues I know
but you know my view is this is a
substantive right that was given by prop
60 for the people of California voted by
a supermajority that not only going
forward will cannabis be legal but that
it has a retroactive impact and and it
should be able to it should change your
criminal record and that that conviction
that had been haunting you and chasing
you and following you around and making
it difficult to get housing and make it
difficult to get a job you should no
longer have to deal with that but the
process is burdensome it's confusing
it's costly its time-consuming and a lot
of folks aren't taking advantage of it
because of those reasons because they
need to take a day off from work and go
to court and file papers and maybe have
a lawyer and they need it for they need
to even know that the right is theirs
that it's something that that they enjoy
and they can pursue and I think this is
somewhere where government should be
able to step in this is sort of a
classic good government role where the
right is already it's already been
decided that individuals deserve this
right now now make it so and use the the
power of government use use that use the
fact that the DOJ has a database where
they can search for all of the
qualifying cannabis crimes and they can
do a data dump literally and provide it
to the district attorneys who can have a
chance to review them and challenge them
if they like and if they don't then
these crimes should be wiped or reduced
and that should all just be done by
operation of law and so the governor has
a few more days to sign this bill I'm
getting nervous because it's not because
he has to the end of the month and he
hasn't done it yet but I think he sort
of takes he dresses bills in in sort of
thematic groups and so maybe he hasn't
addressed all of the cannabis bills yet
but I'm but I'm very hopeful for that
one that one is is it's a bill that got
a lot of support including support from
law enforcement folks and others and I
think it's just it's a bill that will
really help achieve social justice it'll
show that government can work for the
people and it'll it'll make people's
lives better who are hurting because of
these these convictions and so
I'm proud of that bill and I hope it
gets signed by the governor so I got my
fingers crossed
thank you you know we also I want to
give a shout out to Fiona ma I know she
may have been here earlier or may be
coming but we worked for a number of
years together first of all I'm a big
supporter of her she's gonna be our next
treasurer she's forward-thinking and
open-minded and she embraces the
cannabis industry and wants to create
better solutions and make the system
work and she and I have been in
particular that's worked together and we
wanted to do something that I thought
was practical and simple we set about to
do it last year which was to take away
that 10 percent penalty on the non EFT
tax payments because the cannabis
industry can't pay through electronic
fund transfer given the the federal
overlay and the the cash bit business or
the all-cash nature of the business so
that bill actually we tried again this
year and that bill is signed it's the
law there's no more 10% penalty for
paying tax payments in cash I think that
provides equity and fairness it
encourages our cannabis businesses to
pay their taxes which is a good thing
from from the perspective of the
government and businesses so we got that
bill passed and we're excited about that
one that I regret we didn't get passed
which I really feel was necessary and
I'm open to seeing how we address it
going forward but was that was the
three-year reduction in excise taxes and
and a complete moratorium on the
cultivation tax we're we're in a time of
transformation right now you know with
with laws going into effect in in
January of this year and the new regime
being implemented we wanted to encourage
as many folks as possible to move from
the black and gray market to the
regulated market that's what this whole
proposition was the proposition of of
the MC RSA the the proposition of
proposition 64 it said come out of the
shadows come into the light embrace a
regulated marketplace where you follow
all the rules
and if you do you'll be a business just
like any other California businesses
creating good jobs paying your taxes and
for being fully compliant with the law
and in order to do that we need to make
sure that our businesses aren't undercut
by the gray and black market where
they're where they're not paying their
taxes whether we're there
they're undercutting based on cost
savings because of because of the cost
of compliance that they're not following
and in order to do that for temporary
period for three years I thought it made
sense to reduce the taxes too to invite
and encourage and spur along that
migration from the black and gray market
to the to the regulator marketplace but
not all of my colleagues agreed and it's
a it's a legislature with it with
multiple branches of government multiple
members in the legislature not a
monarchy and we weren't able to get that
done what I was excited about was that
was a bipartisan effort Assemblymember
Tom Lackey was the co-author along with
me we got a good amount of support along
the way in committee and it got held in
in appropriations on the assembly side
so maybe we try again on that or maybe
we sharpen our pencils and roll up our
sleeves and decide a better way to do it
a more effective way to do it but you
know in the discussion part of this I'd
love to hear what your thoughts are on
that bill and and and what the future
might hold one other thing that the
legislature wasn't ready yet for yet was
protection of medical patients in the
workplace I was ready for it I I think
it makes it's common sense it's
practical that a medical cannabis
patient like any patient using medicine
should have their status as a medical
patient protected and should be
reasonably accommodated obviously if we
had some components in there where you
know in safety sensitive jobs it
wouldn't apply and and and this is an
area where the state of California would
not be the first to do this other states
have done it including red states and so
we need to catch up and we need to do
better by our employees because right
now the incentive is to not use cannabis
and instead to use things like opioids
which we know we have an opioid
epidemic and that cannabis can be a
safer healthier alternative so what that
tells me is that while we've made
progress while we're we've moved the
needle while our trajectory is heading
in the right direction where we're not
able to do everything that's necessary
yet and I think sometimes it's
incremental sometimes there's a there's
a time and a place for for each policy
and maybe this year wasn't the time for
that but but but maybe next year we'll
be and so we have to continue our
efforts and you know meanwhile we're
dealing with a federal administration
that's tough on cannabis that makes it
harder to make the progress that we that
we need you know I always thought that
maybe with a different president we'd
have a rescheduling or addi scheduling
that we'd have more openness to to what
states are doing and in deference to
states rights more along the lines of
the Cole memo but even more and instead
of a you know a retraction of the Cole
memo which is what we have and an
attorney general who is hostile towards
cannabis so the federal overlay it makes
things tougher and the schedule one
nature of the drug in the eyes of the
federal government makes it tough and
and so does the fact that there's no
banking that makes it very difficult for
our businesses to be to be successful
and to thrive so for sure choppy waters
ahead challenges ahead but my reflection
is the the appetite of the California
Legislature is is growing to be
supportive to be open-minded to try to
craft solutions to try to fix problems
in the cannabis space to build on what
we've done with a lot of
self-recognition that we didn't get it
exactly right that it's not perfect that
it needs to be improved and the way to
improve it is through the input of you
you know you literally telling me and
some member jones-sawyer and assembly
member wood and Lackey and Cooley what
needs to be done next so I'd love to
have our discussion include some of that
if you have some ideas about what
what California who prides itself in
leading on so many things and I think we
are leading on cannabis what else we
need to do to sort of cement that role
as as leaders in the cannabis space so I
want to thank you for all that you do I
know it hasn't always been easy to be in
in the cannabis world
I think it's hopefully it's getting
easier although the regulated
marketplace is not something I guess
you'd put you put the label easy on but
it is but it I feel like it is necessary
when we want to support our good actors
and and it's bringing as many people
into the regulated marketplace as
possible and sort of sort of shed that
stigma for good and keep working and
building on on creating a more perfect
cannabis policy in the state of
California so with that I'll end my
remarks and just say thank you for the
opportunity to be here with you thank
you for this state of cannabis
conference I was here a couple years ago
and seems like it's growing and and and
we're always getting better thought
partners and engagement and look forward
to your questions into our discussion
thank you
[Applause]
homeland security issue that happened
with the transportation company two
weeks ago jr. about that so wild rivers
transport was taking some cash somewhere
that it needed to go and they got pulled
over by CHP and then they got they let
them go and then further down the road
Homeland Security came and got him and
took their cash and now they've retained
Matt cumin and they're they're suing CHP
so you said there that you know we've
got some issues federally have you heard
about this workaround with Homeland
Security apparently isn't held to
Rohrabacher far so there's some money
there to come and do some enforcement
have you heard about this you know we
had a bill that I think would have
helped with that and this is where I
need max back in my office
Assemblymember jones-sawyer we were it
was sort of a almost like a sanctuary
state approach to to cannabis we're in a
place where like California where we
legalized medical and adult use cannabis
there would not be that ability to sort
of refer or tip off or communicate with
the federal government because it's
legal in the state of California similar
to what we've done with our sanctuary
state for our undocumented friends and
neighbors and and and and immigrant
residents so maybe something like that
would help address something like this
the the problem is is something that
well hard to hear is not shocking from
the federal administration and it might
be something that is susceptible to a
state fix along the lines of the Joan
Sawyer bill that I was working on with
him last year one thing I'd like you to
address is I haven't heard much talk on
is our friends at the League of Cities
sending out a thing you're gonna have to
ban or you're gonna leave your lose your
rights to control it and this the state
is going to control it and now some
ungodly number of municipalities and
counties and so forth have complete bans
is there something at the state level
that might go I think we've learned that
it's way way easier to ban than to unban
and you know now with 80% of the cities
and counties having bans how does the
state legislature look at that and is
there any help fix other than the
regular thing of you know changing
hearts and minds one of the the key
components of the MSR CRS a that allowed
it to pass and it was part of sort of
the grand deal and the grand bargain and
then later was adopted more or less by
prop 64 was this idea of local control
so the League of California cities had
had traditionally been able to oppose
legislation that did not have strong
local control components and and and
those bills died and so we believed that
that in putting the MC rs8 together in
2015 we would not be able to get a bill
passed and signed by the governor if it
didn't have a local control component
and I think that's an absolutely
accurate assessment it's not guesswork
you know they would have the league
would have gone strong opposed law
enforcement would've gone strong opposed
and legislators would have followed so
we would have had nothing there was also
a component in there that we had to fix
when we came back in 2016 which was very
unfortunate because it was unintended it
got into the language and it helps spur
this sort of urgent call out to locals
to to BAM because they thought they were
gonna get preempted by the state and the
state was gonna act for them if they
didn't act and so that was unintended
that's part of the when you know when we
do something this big you don't get it
up always get it right into some
imperfections that one had consequences
and and when people decided to ban it's
hard to reverse it's better when you
start from a place of no action and you
can decide a course either their ban or
adopt
I think what we might be able to do and
so this is a huge issue right
we have don't use cannabis we have state
licenses but then we have a lot of
places that are banning all or some of
the supply chain in a cannabis
marketplace a lot or nervous about
dispensaries maybe more okay with
manufacturers or testers maybe even
cultivators but with a little more
worried about dispensaries and so this
sort of the full supply chain in the
marketplace that's needed is not robust
enough and and so we've had a number of
sort of roundtables to think about what
the solution is to that you know one
thought I had was it's weird if a
locality if the people have voted to
have adult use cannabis but their
representatives their City Council or
their supervisors say we should have a
ban that seems like a you know attention
a problem a conflict prop 64 to be fair
and mtrs a did say that locals could ban
and so so maybe that's the way that gets
harmonized and the eyes of those folks
but I think one of the things I had
thought of was also having a sort of
model template for locate locals to use
so they like I think people get
overwhelmed like I don't know anything
about cannabis I'm a city council member
I came because I would cared about
public safety or I cared about
development projects or I cared about
parks cannabis is new to me it's just
easier if I just ban it like some of my
neighbors are kind of worried about it
and I don't have to deal with them when
I go to the supermarket or the soccer
sidelines at the soccer field those are
all real examples for me when I was in
the City Council not not being afraid
but seeing people in the supermarket and
on the sidelines at the soccer field and
so easier to ban but if they had
something that said this is what the
state proposes as a good solid model
template that you can adjust and tweak
and make it work for you but it but it
addresses some of the key issues that
highlights the the key components of
what you might have so that they can
have a starting place and they could
work with their attorne their city
attorney and their
to get it right you know that's so this
idea of providing tools to locals to
help them get there because I feel like
they get overwhelmed and I know that
there are some efforts you know max I
guess this is this is the maxilla
keynote but max has been working on had
been working with a number of locals on
on just that you know getting into place
a regime and that supported it had the
right safeguards and and guardrails
around cannabis and maybe that's
something that could be helpful as well
but it's we're in a tough spot because
it requires reversal of bans right again
if we if we had no position instead of a
banned position it would have been
easier but I am open in and you know
we've we've pulled together some people
some of our thought leaders in cannabis
policy in Sacramento to talk about this
don't know that we've exactly figured it
out but I think that's an area that
needs to get addressed and we need to do
something in the next legislative cycle
so if you have thoughts or others have
thoughts
that's something the problem is on our
radar the solution is it's not something
that where we've arrived at yet hello my
name is Alfonso I'm a Content producer
and I am looking to get a public service
announcement campaign where social
equity and a more accessible industry
for for people now is that something
where you could assist in directing me
and getting some feedback and maybe
getting those ideas to certain areas
like in Los Angeles or up north or down
in in those areas that where that
message might be best received happy to
talk to you further I mean this is a
component that kind of animates the
whole cannabis industry this idea of
equity and social justice and providing
opportunity to particularly those
communities that have been harmed by the
prior
approach and policies towards cannabis
and we're working on things at the state
level to help address that on the
regulatory side as well I know the
bureau and Laurie Ajax's are is working
on some things we've had some
roundtables about that we have a bill
that would provide 10 million dollars to
support equity coming from the state
we've had ideas around incubators and
sort of this idea of a golden ticket if
you if you go through an incubator and
you take certain steps and you're from a
community a disadvantaged community that
has that have been harmed in the past
you would be able to have more direct
access to it to a license
Oakland's done a lot on equity maybe
gone a little too far in some ways but
this the spirit is right so you know I'm
right in the heart of kind of this
equity discussion in Oakland and and I'm
happy to talk to you more about it hey
hi Assemblymember Bonta first of all
thank you for all of the work you've
done max of course and and all the other
legislators it hasn't gone unnoticed we
know where you played a role in this so
thank you so god there's just so many
fixes that need to happen in in the pin
policy and the regulation side and all
of it so instead I want to look a little
into the future and ask you what your
thoughts are on public consumption we
have an issue even here at this event we
have issues everywhere with people out
smoking tobacco right and they can't
smoke cannabis out again of his event
and it's not just here it's anywhere I
mean it sounds like a little bit of a
progressive policy but by some token
it's working in Canada right in Canada
if your medical card holder you can
smoke right on the street now people
hopefully can be responsible about it
but nevertheless that is available and I
and do you are you guys looking into
that at all is that too far down the
road or do you think that California
could eventually come around where we
could somehow figure out a safe way to
have public consumption
despite the lounges that may open in
cities right just for everybody for my
crystal ball if I looked into it today
I'd say probably not next year I think
it's it's a number it's it it's it's an
iterative process
well you need to take one step and then
take another step to get there it'll
prop 64 did not allow for that and so
part of what voters just voted on
included not having the the public
consumption a that you refer to but we
have the Assemblymember bill quirk bill
which allows for use in more areas and
again there's a local control component
if the local if the city agrees on it
and I think I think people need to see
that use can occur beyond sort of
personal use in your home and can occur
in certain at certain events for special
events and see that the world keeps
turning in the sky doesn't fall and then
you do a little bit more and then the
same thing happens but if you go in one
big step all the way to public
consumption then you know the fear
monger has come out and the horror
stories come out and I think it's a
little bit harder so I think it's a few
years away I thank you so much for
coming here you've raised so many
important points I want to just raise
two first of all taxes as a cannon
longtime cannabis patient I'm losing my
patience with being charged an
exorbitant
syntax for a medicine that I actually
really need I do not do sales in the
black buy product from the black market
anymore but I'm one of those people and
I'm a longtime a cannabis trade
journalist in this industry but I can't
afford it anymore so I'm going to be I'm
gonna go back to narcotics or black
market or nothing or something like that
so and I'm kind of so upset about it
that I may become a full-time consumer
activist on this subject because that
the tax regime the patchwork the
layering on affects the entire food
chain in the entire cannabis market I
just wanted to say that as a comment but
I'm wanting to ask you about what is
called an extinction event
people have used that term in California
I believe that California's cannabis
legacy is in great part tied up in the
future of the North Cal region I've
spent a lot of time up there talking to
farmers covering it and you know when
people talk about an extinction event
it's like a really serious term and I'm
curious what goes through your mind when
you hear that and I'm also curious if
you have a sense of where the
legislature in general is at with the
idea that this entire region may go
through what is being called an
extinction event or what BDS analytics
says will be three extinction events and
I'm curious what you think about that
and also what the solutions are I
believe there was just a bill that would
have allowed farmers markets that wound
up in suspense and so there seem to be
solutions that will help those farmers
help that region help the future of this
state and California's legacy two great
points let me take the the first one
first about medical patients and taxes
you know that's kind of where my heart
has always been in this discussion is
with patients and you know with someone
dealing with chronic pain or or a child
dealing with seizures and and making
sure that they have access to the
medicine that helps them and makes them
you know feel better and and addresses
their their their symptoms and their
challenges and so to the extent that we
have a tax regime that makes it
difficult for those patients to to
receive them at the medicine medicine
they need I'm very open-minded to making
changes and taking action that can help
ensure that I think there is I mean I
think there's a sales tax exemption
right for card holders
right right so yeah it's something but
it's not it's not a lot I mean the
extinction event that worries me that's
disturbing
that makes me anxious that's not
something that we ever wanted or an or
intended I don't know if it's true but
the fact that it's being discussed is a
problem and you know we always wanted
folks who had been longtime members of
the industry who operated in in in the
great gray spaces because California
hadn't yet regulated or made it lawful
to be able to migrate to the to the
regulated marketplace to the lawful
marketplace to be able to embrace that
marketplace and be successful
participant in it for many years to come
that was always the idea and that was
the intent and you know the the mom and
pops the small farms the the growers
that had been there for multi
generations yeah yes and so so the fact
that that's a that that's that we're
dealing with that makes me want to talk
to you more and and figure out what we
can do to avoid it so I'll stay
afterwards I'll give you my card and
this is the time when we're preparing
our legislative package this is the time
when we're actively soliciting input and
ideas and then we introduce our bills
early next year so I want to learn more
from you thank you may be related to the
extinction concept if banking is not
available
typically what goes on is those
businesses with larger resources and
larger contacts are able to get by and
small businesses without banking just
disappear and get crushed there was some
discussion this morning about banking
the only way most likely way that gets
resolved in California is that the
federal issue has to get resolved and
there's pretty much no way forward other
than that I'm wondering if you agree if
you think there are any other pathways
to resolving particularly for small
business people in California
for it to get banking support and be
able to use banks in development of a
business which is required
III don't know if the federal fix is the
only fix but for a long time I've said
that's the best way we're going to
address this and we have tried and and
scratched our heads and put pen to paper
and and a mad imagine and reimagined
other possibilities you know credit
unions I know
soon-to-be treasurer of Fiona Maas been
working on this current Treasurer John
Chung has been working on this Senator
Hertzberg and I had a bill working on
this this past year I'm open to the
possibility of a creative fix to it but
I don't know what it is and I think the
the best way the cleanest way the most
impactful way is for the federal
government to act and so you know that
that's not easy to hear right now given
the constitution of the federal
government and who's sitting in those
those decision-making seats but it
doesn't mean that that's what the future
holds it doesn't mean that things might
change
you know this November and they might
change again in two years so you know
real change could be two years away in
an ideal world but that doesn't create
any comfort right now but I've always
felt that the federal government has to
act to really make it clean and to
provide the protections that businesses
deserve having said that I don't know
all the answers and if you or others
that you're working with have a proposal
that you think could work in the state
of California I'm all ears and and and
if that can provide relief to businesses
that need it faster then I think we
should try state-owned public banking
what do you think about doing a public
bank for California which I think would
be a way to like circumvent the federal
restrictions in terms of getting banking
and banking cannabis businesses cannabis
growers what do you think about the idea
of doing a California statewide
public bank I think the statewide bank
idea is a good one generally I think
it's trick
and you know I think people who don't
know about South Dakota or north dakota
I think folks point to North Dakota a
lot smaller and a lot different than in
California and even if we had a bank
that that allowed cannabis proceeds and
revenue to be banked in it at the you
know a state bank doesn't get FDIC
insurance I think I think no maybe the
state provides that that you know
something similar in terms of that sort
of insurance or guarantee and then is it
is it susceptible to a federal raid and
saying you know these are all you know
the federal government in our eyes this
is all criminal enterprise the state of
California it might be might be state of
California bank but those revenues are
from in our eyes criminal enterprise and
we're gonna raid it and take it and it's
gonna be subject to forfeiture you know
I think that's something that this
president would would love the
opportunity to do but maybe there's ways
to protect it maybe there's ways around
it the state bank idea has come up many
times it's something that max has has
spent some time analyzing and looking at
others are as well if there's a way to
do it from a policy perspective then I
think I think again we should we should
try I think politically it's really
difficult the the rest of the banking
industry gets really nervous when when
the idea of a state bank gets brought up
so you know I was just curious if
there's been any talk or anybody's
approached you around helping with some
legislation around the annual fees with
BCC you know we're looking at like a
hundred thousand dollar annual fee once
annual licenses become issued which you
know could be some time which could you
know move into the next legislative
session you know the idea that yes
you've got to recover costs because of
implementation
I feel like this first year I mean I
mean there's some talk that it will come
down because the you know it's not gonna
cost that much to continue regulation
but a hundred thousand annually is an
unbelievable amount of money even if we
do over two and a half million a year as
we do it's still just a very huge amount
of money and
to be paying an agency I mean you pay
that for a liquor license but you can
sell that liquor license in ten years
and I think we need let you know
legislation to to help operators make
that happen I'm just curious if you've
heard of anything or if you would
support that I've definitely heard of
that you know when we were talking about
taxes and sort of this this three year
moratorium on the cultivation tax and
the reduction in the excise tax part of
the conversation included want to help
with the licensing fees those are very
burdensome as well and maybe some relief
there could help and so I think that's
an area where we can explore maybe that
may be because the the tax approach
didn't work this year maybe that the
licensing fee approach could could work
next year with with some reduction some
relief to our businesses I'm open to it
and and I think that that's that's an
area that we should explore and and see
if we can make it work to help our
responsible compliant businesses be
successful
thank you everybody appreciate it
[Music]