here in California is there an
acquisition spree in terms of rolling up
for example retail yeah they're starting
to be I mean you're starting to see
players are saying we want to have you
know 15 20 30 stores which you know you
people talked about a couple years ago
but there weren't really that many
people that are practically speaking
able to to do that from the standpoint
of what the the multiples are there
there is no you know magic formula so
you take the way California operates
it's much different than most states you
have it where it's municipal by
municipal legislation so for instance in
Los Angeles you essentially had the 135
pre ICO retailers that were here that
were licensed and then you had you know
500 other rogue operators that were
spread across the the county now those
135 should have some sort of insulation
attach them in the know the state in the
city are certainly making an effort to
try to find the rogue operators and shut
them down so if you have one of those
135 those those licenses are valuable
because not only you know do you have
the ability to operate where the state
should grant you your annual license
when the annual license is really start
getting doled out in a faster pace but
you also should theoretically have first
bite at the Apple if if Garcetti decides
that he wants to expand the program or
cap packer decides that they want to
expand the program in Los Angeles but
you look at you know a city like San
Diego they've already made their
determination on how many they're gonna
give out we don't see any you know
additional legislation coming forward to
expand it so those licenses are a bit
more valuable because it's so finite and
we don't think there's any you know path
to issue new ones the the big x-factor
right now is what new towns coming to
market you know in San Diego does
Carlsbad or Oceanside or you know Solana
Beach or Del Mar do they start opening
up and it's become valuable because if
it does then it dilutes the market share
away from the city from you know the the
number of licenses that are already out
there and the same thing is true you
know in the Bay Area you know we are
some was talking about the conference
today you know the Oakland had such an
advantage for a long time and that
advantage is larger yeah and they lost
it yeah it was largely squandered
because they didn't you know move
forward with legislation that was that
was still appealing so when as an
investor or someone that's looking to
buy
asset like that you've got to look at a
the addressable market B you have to
look at you know how easy is it going to
be to expand that market see you've got
to look at who's gonna come in and
attack that market from the outside do
you need to look at you know how big the
state market is and can you actually
start selling away from it whether it's
through delivery services or other
things and then you got to weigh all of
that so and then you also need to weigh
whether or not the company is profitable
in the first place it's easy to say okay
well we're gonna call it like a three
times revenue multiple we're gonna pay
for an asset but if that company is
losing money then you have to decide
whether or not you can actually bring it
to profitability and if there's even a
multiple due to be paid to those
companies or whether it's just better to
let them die and start fresh so you know
what I'm seeing as far as you know kind
of standard metrics on retails is
probably one to one-and-a-half times
revenue on an annual basis