there we go all right so we have
proposed regulations for
certification of comparable to organic
standards for cannabis in the state of
california
uh anybody want to give their actually
scott i'd just like to start with you
give me your thoughts so i read it
before the podcast
and it seems very similar in nature to
what we deal with in agriculture
i guess to be clear and concise is um
yeah we work in the organic sector but
i'm not an advocate of organic
certification
um you know we've worked for large-scale
organic farms that use glyphosate right
in front of us so
casually you know so to me
i view it as um uh
unnecessarily restrictive which will
keep you
into a certain type of problem set
so i don't believe that it's not
necessarily that beneficial it's it's
unnecessarily difficult to navigate as a
farmer
and i think it's a far better goal that
is community-wide
we determine a new category that has
merit with
the the public that we inform them on
like living soil or
like what elaine is doing with
biologically complete
because you know there's certain
products that we use
that are too much of a hassle to get
organically certified because of
intellectual property on how they're
created and how the nutrients are
chelated
and they're perfectly fine but because
they're not stamped you can't use them
but if you do use them
you don't have pest issues and don't
need pesticides
so that's kind of the problem of it um
you know i i'm not a big advocate of the
entire process personally
and i think it's better to just farm
really respectably
and don't worry about a label to confine
yourself further
to further regulation and and um
scrutiny
you know i was i was excited to read it
because you know you always want to see
the positive
but you get to about page 30 of the 66
pages
and from that point to the end it's
punitive
it's these are all the punishments and
costs you will incur
if you do not comply with this and
there's only like maybe 10 pages
of material that directed you on what
they wanted you to do
and then it really referred to addendum
lists of
licensed products that had been
certified by somebody who paid
to be able to be in that position but it
was
the half of the document is punitive
and so i read it and i said to myself i
said you know i was gonna go grab
uh i wanted to go for this because i was
like hey this would be beautiful we can
create this beautiful situation it's
accepted people understand it
but as you go through it you realize
that
it's it's it's another punishment and an
extraction in pricing
and so if you if you start your
certification program early
it's this much but each year you go
forward and wait to begin the program
it increases the cost of the actual
program so
it's if you're not a first adopter
you're going to get
taxed two or three years into it and
there was there was costs on it that was
confusing but it was
the lesser the greater of a hundred
dollars or 25 percent of your gross
and so i'm trying to understand how they
intend to extract the monies from you
and how they will structure the fees
and it gets to the point where it
started making me wonder did i want to
even go through it
exactly and i was somebody that was
really like hey you know this is
something that could be positive because
it could give
us some form of recognition in the
in the agricultural world as a clean
product because we have such a stigma
even though we're really the cleanest
products in the market
which is the ironic part but being
certified does that mean you're not
going to fail a test though i mean you
can be certified whatever
and get a heavy metal fucking or a drift
fail and so then what you know and is it
going to cause
is it going to get more money because i
don't know what certification
has got fetched more money because the
price of wheat is the price of weed you
can add value
there's a story behind it you can get
more volume sold
maybe but is any certification
saying okay boom now you get this much
more money
now yeah not yet so if you compare it
to what's going on in the industry
already with dragonfly earth medicine
doing the dem pure certification and
then you have envirocan
um and then there's clean green there's
a series of different certifications
that are being offered lydia
i'm sorry what's broner's cert sun on
earth
yeah that one as well exactly and so
there
there's multiple options for what's
going on in the industry
um i really like dragon ball earth
medicine the
kelly and josh really have it together i
really like everyone that runs with
their crew
um just as a personal aside but you know
you have people in the industry that
have been in the industry for a long
time that respect the plant that are
here for
for reasons that you know go far beyond
just trying to make a bunch of money
and run a large uh scale process but
you're going to be seeing
are adopters of this just like they're a
biodynamic you know there's there's
people that are doing organics people
are doing biodynamics and
in regular you know the regular ag world
and it's a small percentage even still
and so just like you guys are saying
from a laboratory perspective just
because something's organic doesn't mean
it passes you know people go through and
they get organic
products to make their edibles like i
was mentioning earlier and they can
still
fail the testing requirements that are
um you know that are put out and
mandated by the state
for cannabis products to get to the
market so it's one of those things where
i do think it's really important that if
you have
any interest in the game you should
definitely be looking at the ocal
proposed regs you can make comments on
it until july 7th
which i encourage anybody that has a
commentary about
that specific topic to please you know
submit it because they really do seem to
listen
is what i've noticed in california um
but you know whether or not someone just
decides to adopt that or not doesn't
necessarily mean that their product is
going to be better or
worse than another person's and then
additionally as we're watching the
appalachians project
unfold you know that started years ago
um and they still haven't come
into a reality with that yet um you know
terroir and
you know the amount of plants that are
actually grown in native soil versus
those that are not which is
um you know a fairly large swing between
the two
um it's just something to really be
considerate of
you know again like those organic
certifications they can cost hundreds to
thousands of dollars you know
the amount that they're going to be
taking off your back end when we're
already dealing with such
difficult taxation issues in the
cannabis industry anyway
and whether or not that's right for
somebody's business is a personal
decision
but i do think that it's it's
interesting that after a couple years
they finally came out with it
um i think the naming convention is
pretty interesting that they're actually
using the word
you know um organic certification
um through the state of california's
department of agriculture and so i think
that you know
at least as within the realm of this
conversation it's going to be
interesting to watch all of that
come into reality no matter what it
looks like yeah
i yeah one of the hydroponic facilities
we work for has an employee that's a
lobbyist
and they're actually very active in the
ocal and so i think what the organic
people need to understand
is that they need to be as active in
their own certification as their
opposers are
and i would start there in real life
it's mostly
paperwork though it's not a lot of
testing i mean they do check to see
where you store all your shit but i mean
my farm was certified organic i went
through the whole process
to do farmers markets many years ago
and it's just a big paperwork thing you
know they come look at the farm
go right on you know but other than that
there's no soil testing that they did
at least you know through any of the
processes i went through so i mean
it's watered down at best
so uh have we have we covered the uh
organic certification standards for the
cdfa
yeah i think kevin had the best
description of the first three pages are
definitions
there's nine pages of what to do and
then 33 pages of how much it's going to
cost you and how much
trouble you're gonna be like i think
that tells you most of what you need to
know right there