[Music]
coming from the philosophical background
I thought it might be fun to talk about
whether permanency is a valid concept in
relation to California cannabis
regulations considering that really in
the grand scheme of things this is just
another little tiny seed of evolution in
the process that's going to be dialing
in regulated cannabis in California this
is what we're we're at I mean to talk
about what has just happened is that on
Monday December 3rd the three major
agencies of California cannabis the BCC
Bureau of cannabis control the
Department of Public Health and the
Department of Food and Agriculture you
so there's no further public comments at
this time as many of you know we were
gonna have totally peaceful happy
holidays in blissful ignorance of what
the regulations were going to be they
weren't going to publicly share them
until after January when they became
active but they changed their mind
because you know a lot of people wanted
to know what it said so they could
prepare for when they become immediately
active as soon as the OAL approves them
so that is why we're doing this now
because now we know what it says so
we're starting to sort it out
the oal has 30 working days to review
the regulations that were submitted so
if they use that full time they have
until January 16th we're imagining it's
going to be about January 16th is when
they will become active and the role of
the oil is you don't know it's the
Office of Administrative Law is to
confirm that to the regulations proposed
by the agencies is actually in alignment
with statute with what was in what was
in mikasa what's in the business
professions code those things have to
align so there is a small possibility
that the OAL
find something that they decide is not
in alignment with Mikasa and and strike
things or reject them but there's not a
lot of anticipation of this happening
the general anticipation is that the
language is in there now is what we'll
have to deal with when in January when
it kicks in
until that time right now the emergency
regulations are still in effect and will
remain in effect until January 16th when
the new regulations take effect
immediately
upon adoption so there was lots of
adjustments lots of things that were
proposed it carried over we're gonna
have Josh is gonna talk through a lot of
the things that impacted the licensing
aspect of those regulations so Josh
singer my person the presentation is
going to be a little bit of an update on
what's new for those of you who are
submitting licenses
starting with we're just gonna do a
quick overview of this is not exhaustive
this is just a number of the changes
that took place in this some of these
are actually we're first put in June
some of them were putting in October
most of these were not put in in the
most recent change but we're gonna talk
about them now that we it looks like
they're going to go into the permanent
regulations so I'm gonna do a quick
overview and then just go into more
detail on each of these first of all the
BCC decided that they did not like
everyone submitting their own procedures
for review and instead has chosen to
create these forms these were initially
put together in the first round of
permanent regulations in June and now it
looks like they're going forward with it
it's not most of you I think know about
these but that's where they're going
number two they took out more recently
in October they took out the waste
management procedures so those of you
who have already prepared those for your
annual application it
doesn't look like they're going to be
going through those number three there
were some slight but significant changes
in the definitions of owner and in what
needs to be disclosed with your
financial interest holders number four
the license fees at least for the BCC
changed and thank God for that because
the previous licensing fees did not make
any sense
number five and I'm sure a lot of you
are very interested in this and want to
know more we're gonna go into a little
bit more detail on the expiration of
temporary licenses at least what we know
right now number six there are new OSHA
requirements for applications to all
three agencies and last with the CDFA
there's a very minor change in the
premises diagram requirements and in
pesticide requirements so let's go on
and talk a little bit about the forms we
put up the section up there just so
anybody who wants to look at this after
the presentation can take a look but the
basic idea is that they replace the
regulations regarding the procedures
that needed to be provided in the annual
application with forms instead of
everyone submitting separate procedures
for your non laboratory quality control
procedures your transportation
procedures all of these sets of
procedures that they previously asked in
the annual application instead of
creating your own and then having the
state get back to you and let you know
that they want this or that and whatever
it is they want those procedures they
created forums it would have been a lot
easier if they told us about these forms
for the very beginning but this is a
trial and error process for the state
agencies and this is how they're doing
it at least for BCC one thing to note
within these forms while the general
topics for the different forms are the
same as they were previously what
they're asking for in the forum's some
of them are surprises there are in clear
regulatory basis for what there
so you have to take a very close look at
those forms when we went through them
we'd noticed that there were some
subjects that it didn't occur to us
would have to be in the procedures and
they stick them in there so you have to
be careful a lot of people win think
that they have to submit certain things
in those forms and you do so read those
over carefully now for those of you who
previously submitted your procedures the
question is what do you do now that the
regulations changed so since these
original forms came out in June what
they did is initially they did not give
anybody bounce-backs asking you to fill
out the forms until the very end of
August we have a bunch of clients who
submitted way earlier who did not hear
anything about the forms there is no
question that you had to look back at
the forms or do anything after the very
end of August the state started telling
anybody who submitted annual
applications again from the BCC they
started asking you to refer to the forms
and they had this legalistic provision
in their letter that said wow we have
not finalized the permanent regulations
just yet we do want you to use the forms
as a framework for what you're
submitting to the BCC and we tried to
since many of our clients had already
submitted procedures we try to adjust
their procedures to just meet what was
in the forms but going forward you're
going to have to submit those forms in
the order that they ask so everyone keep
that for those of you who have not
submitted your annuals keep that in mind
for those of you who have submitted your
annuals but have not gotten any bounce
back you're also probably gonna have to
put them in the forms so get ready for
it moving on does anybody have questions
about the forms yes
so if you if you submitted about a month
ago
eventually I at least unless your
procedures are perfect I think and it's
very at least from what I've seen not
everybody who thinks that their
procedures are perfect they aren't but
yeah so you can download them online
they have it within the the package that
was released on the BCC website they
have the forms that they're downloadable
and JC Penney's for instance before you
could start working with them
right thank thanks for the comment
you're absolutely right it would have
been nice had they done that and again
you're asking specifically about these
forms and that was a good idea so
everyone had the same templates at least
the same structure for these forms they
took your comment to heart and I think
probably many others and they did
something about it now the problem is
transitioning for the people who did not
submit those forms moving forward why
are they going to happen we don't know
exactly how they're going to integrate
those two things but hopefully they'll
create some sort of wave you just wait
you have to wait until they get back to
you and know and they'll help you I want
to get onto some other things but I I
for you specifically I would wait and
see how they bounce it back to you
because they have different depending on
the stage that you submitted they're
gonna have a different request for what
you submit moving forward so it depends
when you submitted if you submitted your
annual if you haven't submitted your
annual my recommendation is as part of
your annual you use the forms right but
if you submitted previously at least the
stages that I've seen are people who
submitted before September they were
asked specific questions and if they
were in the forms or not in the forms
they just asked them to address them and
the procedures they had four people who
submitted after September the BCC asked
to you can still use procedures but to
use those forms as a framework for what
you submit moving forward I think
anybody who hasn't submitted they're
annuals yet I highly recommend you use
those forms it's gonna make it a lot
easier for you going forward okay
removal of waste management procedures
this was kind of surprising and
interesting and there's a discrepancy
between the different agencies so the
BCC took out all the specific
regulations related to waste management
procedures they left in the requirement
that the waste is all unrecognized
recognizable but they took out the
specific section related to waste
management procedures and in the FSO are
the claims were that they were redundant
with the non cannabis regulations and
the cannabis waste requirements so
that's where the BCC stands we've
submitted numerous annual applications
and they all included waste management
procedures it looks like going forward
the BCC is not asking for that now I
don't know why the BCC thinks that the
current the regulations outside of
cannabis and deal with it but the CDFA
and the CDP age don't agree but it seems
that there is a discrepancy between
those regulations so those of you
applying to CDF a and C D pH you guys
still need to have some sort of waste
management procedures those applying to
the BCC I would definitely I think it's
absolutely best practice that have those
procedures in place but they do not need
to be submitted with your annual
applications now the interesting stuff
with new owner and financial interest
regulations we from the very beginning
have been telling all of our clients
that there's gonna be very few if any
ways to get around disclosing your
owners if you have owners setting up
multiple layers of corporations is not
going to hide the individuals who are
running those entities and now the BCC
and to certain extent the other agencies
have made that clear in their
regulations all of those entities need
to be disclosed and they need to be
disclosed until they get to warm bodies
so if you think you're going to submit
multiple layers of entities and they're
not going to ask who the individuals are
who owned those entities you are
mistaken
and we've already seen this even prior
to these new regulations the BCC was
asking who the owners were who owned
those entities and if you went to
another entity they said what about that
entity and when you go to another entity
they ask about that entity there is
going to be very little way to get
around that so my
recommendation to anybody who does not
want to be disclosed you are not going
to be able to make that work I don't see
any way that you're gonna get around
that so people are going to have to come
to grips with the fact that those
individuals are going to need to be
disclosed now sorry go ahead
so what you're referring to is LA
Regulations not the state regulations
they do not you can you can they at
previous efforts to try and limit and I
even specifically retail by previous
efforts to try and limit how much an
individual owner can own did not go
anywhere what did and my the one
exception I don't wanna go too off-track
is people who are cultivating with the
CDFA you are only allowed to own one
medium cultivation site you cannot have
more than one medium cultivation site so
keep that in mind yes
so that's a different question which I'm
about to get to financial interest
holders so what's now changed with the
financial interest holders is anybody
who had any profit sharing whether it be
employee or there are a lot of people
who tried to come up with different ways
to hide their financial interest holders
whether it be someone who who had some
sort of profit sharing relationship a
landowner who didn't want to own the
license specifically but wanted to get
some sort of profits from it those
relationships are no longer hiding the
financial interest holders anybody who
has a profit sharing relationship with
the entity that has the license has to
be disclosed now that's not the same as
an owner disclosure an owner disclosure
you have to do an owner submit oh and
they do a background check if your
ownership share is less than 20 percent
and you're not an officer director or
someone who's managing the day-to-day
operations then you are simply a
financial interest holder which means
that you need to disclose who that
person is you do not net that you do not
need to go through that background check
but you will need to be disclosed you
will need to provide your driver's
license number and some specific some
other specific information anybody who
had takes on new financial interested
holders has a required notification to
the agency that gave you your license
and you will need to make that
notification and send it over to the BCC
I believe it's now 10 calendar days if
someone can correct me I got confused
one was 14 days the other was 10
calendar days I think they switched it
to 10 calendar days yes so if they're
getting any profits
so that's an in so the interesting
comment was that anybody who has
employees who have some sort of profit
sharing relationship if you have twenty
five thirty employees and they all have
a profit sharing relationship you're
gonna have to disclose all of them and
this is gonna be a process I don't know
how that you know comes out in specific
details but according to these new
regulations everyone needs to notify the
BCC about anybody who has this profit
sharing relationship my recommendation
to anyone in here who was not aware of
that I would definitely have it on your
radar and either now or as soon as those
regulations are officially implemented
make sure you make that notification to
your specific agencies and those
financial interest holder requirements
changed in all three agencies so any
anybody who has a state license is gonna
have to make that disclosure license
fees so the CDFA and the CD pH my review
those did not change very much there
were some additions in how you calculate
your annual revenue and I don't think
there were changes as much as
clarifications and having it in writing
exactly how that calculation is supposed
to be made with the BCC I I there were
I'm sure there are many people in this
room who were aware that the BCC license
fees did not make very much sense there
were very large intervals and very large
fees but for example if they had they
used to be I think two point five to
seven point five million dollars in
annual revenue for retail shop and the
license fee would jump
I think forty or fifty thousand out some
outrageously large amount so is to the
benefit of the license holder to shut
down their shop for a couple of days to
make sure they don't hit that revenue
amount because it was such a large fee
disparity the state the BCC fixed that
and now they're smaller intervals I
think that the in general all of the
license fees went down slightly I think
they realized that they were unrealistic
it's part of the trial and error system
but for those of you who are very
worried about that I think because of
the
narrowing of those intervals you're
going to be benefit it's gonna make a
little bit more sense I don't think
anybody likes paying the license fees so
I'm not going to say it makes complete
sense but it makes a little bit more
sense than it did previously and all
just for the record the section there
has all of if you look in the red line
you can compare them and see them I
didn't want to go through each separate
license category but they're all in the
regulations yes yes if you pass the most
threat I think the most threshold
I don't recall exactly what the amount
is now but and it depends on I guess the
license category you're in but it's all
you know 7.5 and higher you're gonna hit
that amount in the license fee so I can
tell you based on the applications they
always have the highest threshold and
higher and that's what you're putting in
the license application all right
I would definitely it for whatever
reason that's not clear in the
regulations I would assume the highest
category they can't make up the amount
you're paying so it's gonna be it's
gonna be that highest license fee
expiration of temporary licenses again I
think I don't think this is new to
everyone this was initially in the this
was one of the big items in the June
release but the temporary licenses no
new licenses or temporary licenses can
be issued after December 31st 2018 now
those of you who have not submitted your
application for your temporary license
it might be too late for the CDFA is a
little bit slower I think it could be
very unlikely for some of you who are
still applying to the BCC or the CD pH
you might be able to get in but it's got
to get in today in order for them to
issue it before the end of the year so
everyone has to make sure that they are
doing that again that applies to all
three agencies now the reason that this
is interesting is there's interplay
between the temporary licenses and the
provisional licenses in order for you to
get a provisional license this new
statutory creation from I guess it was
in the summer this provisional license
where you are going to pay your license
fees and you go on track and trace and
then you will have a year license it's
it's I guess it's provisional license
because it's only a year but it's more
than your temporary license and it's not
a regular annual license in order for
you to qualify for those you need to
have a temporary license you need to
have submitted your annual license and
you need to have gone through the full
sequa project and report and submit that
now the area which is a little bit
uncertain is that is whether or not your
annual license needs to be in before the
end of the year now I've never gotten
any indication from anyone that that was
the case all that needs to happen before
the end of the years you need to have
your temporary issued moving forward I
would pay close attention to that but I
was on a call with the c-d-c DFA this
morning and that was the one agency I
was a little uncertain of the BCC and
the CD pH I think already made it pretty
clear that you can submit your annual in
the beginning of next year the CDFA
there was a rumor that went around
saying that maybe you needed to submit
your annual before the end of the year
according to the person I spoke to from
the CDFA that is not the case you can
submit it next year your annual and
still qualify for the provisional
licensing now that was with the phone
call so don't take that to the bank just
yet
I'm waiting for it to see it in written
form but pay close attention to that and
for those of you who haven't submit your
annual make sure you're ready to submit
that at the beginning of next year so
that way you can move on to your
provisional licensing okie dokie the new
OSHA requirement
all three agencies have the exact same
text and is written right in the slide
if you have more than one employee you
need to make an attestation in your
annual application that one supervisor
and one employee who have successfully
completed a Cal OSHA 30 our general
industry outreach course offered
by a training provider that is
authorized by an OSHA training institute
Education Center to provide the course
so planning in advance that regulation
is a clear change you have to make that
attestation that if you haven't done it
yet you will be doing it in the future
so please put that into your planning
CDFA the new premises diagram
requirement now this is gonna be a very
specific detail but I want to throw it
out there you need to have an area for
segregating cannabis or non manufactured
cannabis products that are subject to
administrative hold for whatever reason
you have issues with the state agency
and they put any of your products on
administrative hold you need to have a
separate area not necessarily a separate
room by a separate area to put those
products this is specifically for the
CDFA I there is no comparable provision
that I've seen in the other agencies but
specifically in the CDFA regulations you
need to make sure that you have that
lastly new pesticide requirement this is
not new but they put it into the
regulations so that it's clear you need
to have an attestation that says you're
going to contact your County
agricultural commissioner and make sure
that the pesticides you are using are
legal for those of you who have not done
that I would reach out usually the
county agencies at least LA County has
been very nice they have people who are
in the field working on this you can
reach out to the county and they've been
very helpful to us in talking to them I
would reach out and for cultivators make
sure that you are only using legal
pesticides lastly and not in the slides
for those of you who are concerned about
illegal grows I want to remind everyone
that the collective sunset is expiring
or the collective sunset is sunsetting
so those of you who are concerned about
people who are in that gray area where
they were operating as a collective as
they have been for the last ten years or
whatever it may be they those those
collectives are no longer going to be
able to legally operate which means that
the toolbox for both state
state enforcement agencies and often
local enforcement agencies got much
bigger so illegal group whoever is
operating illegally is gonna have a much
tougher time going forward that does not
I I I'm not certain the exact day it was
based on notification of the initial
regulations or the the notification of
the first license that was issued that's
when the one-year expiration began and
I'm not I'm pretty certain January 9th
all right so this is not coming directly
from me from hearing from the crowd is
January 9th the collective sunset so
hopefully the state enforcement agencies
will take that under consideration as
they move forward and hopefully that
provides them with more tools to shut
down the legal shops and grows and
whoever else yeah so the the collector
exactly under collected under the
collective program and 215 when the when
mal curso was drafted and passed they
had specifically in there that one year
from the the notification
one year from the notification of the
first license being issued that there
would be the collective you can no
longer operate as a collective and you
would not fit under the collective me me
all right and with that unless there are
any specific questions I don't want to
take too much more time I'm gonna pass
down to Julie
[Music]
[Applause]