thank you for waiting
I'm Jeff watashi and i will be
moderating a discussion today
can you talk louder yes I can no problem
okay I'm the host of the cannabis hour
on kzy excellency
that's a bi weekly radio program focused
on all things cannabis and I'm also the
owner and operator of wildland cannabis
we are here today in the farmers forum
so check us out if you get a chance I'd
like to thank redwood remedies and soldi
Mendocino for sponsoring this panel
Maynard Kaminski our videographer Jake
Martin Wagner and KZ YX for the audio
recording this panel is part of cannabis
on the coast and the proceeds from this
event are benefiting the Mendocino Coast
Children's Fund and a special thanks to
pebbles here for helping to organize
this event in this panel today so thank
you very much we are gonna get started
and we have a great group of panelists
here today I'm honored to be here with
this group of community elders so thanks
for having me and I can't wait to hear
you share your stories today I'm gonna
go through and introduce everyone that's
here first up is pebbles an outspoken
teen inspired by the Montgomery Alabama
bus boycott pebbles TripIt helped
integrate public lunch counters in Tulsa
Oklahoma in 1960 throughout the 60s and
Beyond she was a peace activist against
the Vietnam War and the draft and
supported a woman's right to her own
body freedom of choice sexual freedom
medical freedom and a just world based
on equality she was there as a
co-founder of CMI the California
marijuana initiative the first statewide
initiative of her personal freedom in
1972 as well as a part of the 1978 San
Francisco marijuana initiative leading
to the double assassination of
supervisor Harvey Milk and mayor George
Moscone three weeks later in retaliation
it was the end of an era the 80s and 90s
epidemic led to the Dennis Peron browny
Mary voter approved prop 215 in 1996
race to use obtained possess and
cultivate medical marijuana but not to
transport it
dr. Todd of me Korea testified in court
on her behalf the cannabis is a drug of
choice historically for migraines and
that she uses it legitimately
pebbles is the migraine patient cited in
prop 215 pebble spent a decade
litigating the right to transport
marijuana for medical purposes prior to
prop 215 after 10 arrests in eleven
years with prosecutions in five counties
and jail and for for transporting
cannabis as medicine before the law
changed she appealed all convictions as
unconstitutional while a Mendocino
County resident pebbles TripIt prevailed
and won three things one the right to
transport medicine you can legally
possess two the quantity standard and
amount reasonably related to one's
medical condition and three at
retroactivity pebbles co-founded medical
marijuana patients Union in 2000 and
developed a working relationship with
Sheriff Tony Cramer and DA norm virome
for many years pebbles is senior editor
and token female columnist for skunk
magazine and is calling for an elders
council to preserve and protect the
cannabis culture as we exit prohibition
Thank You pebbles for being here today
so next up I'm going to introduce Cecile
Cecile cutler also known as Anandi was
brought up in New York City and moved to
San Francisco California drawn by the
Summer of Love in 1967 her journey to
India in 1972 changed her life
when she returned to the US she moved to
Point Arena and learned how to grow
cannabis she also learned yoga and Tai
Chi and was a teacher of Tai Chi at
Marin College for over 25 years as well
as Mendocino Community College in Fort
Bragg her Tai Chi source book was
published by
Munroe she also worked in publishing as
a book designer at Simon &amp; Schuster
as a masseuse drawn by the love of herbs
Anandi was searching for the magical
formula an element of healing massage to
relieve pain as well as to write or pain
as well as psoriasis well all kinds of
things that I that people who tell me
the problems okay to that end she
presented her original combination hemp
sap a concentrated compound made from
the whole hemp plant the herbs are
listed in combination with cannabis
which enhances and quickens healing
cannabis is my inspiration at her 90th
birthday celebration last month Ananda
was the inspiration her accomplishments
and lot Lajja tippity a life well-lived
for the greater good she describes
herself I'm not who I was I'm nobody and
that means everybody I'm a citizen who
loves herbs thank you and we also have
RJ also known as Richard Jorgensen 2020
is the 50th anniversary of Mendocino 's
own cultural icon the prototype invented
and manufactured by two local brothers
Phil and Richard Jorgensen it is
unbreakable brass and in and it is an
all-in-one smoking piece including a
hood multiple holes in the bowl cleaning
access storage space and a poker the
jürgenson lost control of prototype
after a 1986 of paraphernalia law made
it a federal crime to export metal
smoking pipes after a long hiatus
Richard and Phil have regained control
of the pipe and are again manufacturing
it in Mendocino County Richard is an
avid archivist with a vast Museum of
documents and artifacts telling the
story of the 100-year demonization of
the cannabis plant with an emphasis on
the back to the land movement and how it
helped to jumpstart the solar industry
in the Emerald triangle his cannabis
culture collection contained
hundreds of books magazines and news
articles that are culture and cat
eccentric and is reputed to be one of
the most inclusive sets of original
articles and documents on the American
youth counterculture in the world thank
you for joining us today's panel is
about amplifying the voices of these
community elders and listening to the
stories of their experiences here in the
Emerald triangle so I would like to ask
our audience members how many of you
live in the Emerald triangle raise your
hands
yay awesome and how many of you grew up
here we have one and how many of you are
visiting from elsewhere great well it's
great to see a mix and thank you to
those of you who came from elsewhere to
hear our stories that's really great how
many cultivators do we have in the group
great I just like to know that so thank
you all right we're gonna get started
I'd like to begin this the same way I
start my interviews on the cannabis hour
and that is by going to each of my
panelists and asking what is your
personal relationship with cannabis so
pebbles would you like to start hmm Mary
Jane a mile for him I see marijuana as a
friend basically as a close collaborator
and companion that understands me and
treats me very well when I'm down the
herb whips me huh when I'm to agitate it
calms me down when I'm a consumable
since almost me and I love all parts of
that look of the plant but the leaf
that's when I was mine made me busted
with was the leaf so I believe in that
too and root team
is the new thing so I believe in mother
nature I revere mother nature and
cannabis is at the center of my life and
has basically shown me the most
wonderful way of life beautiful pebbles
Thank You Cecile what's your personal
relationship with cannabis in 1974 when
I started to be a grower and pack water
into the woods on my back
I was also practicing yoga hatha yoga
and it helped me with my practice and
during the course of growing I read High
Times magazine and there was an article
on the goddess zy z IH u a she is the
goddess of marijuana purple marijuana
and lo and behold in my garden when I
was growing one year there she was all
purple and so she became my spiritual
guide and it's not something you can see
and no but I felt that she kept guiding
me so that I learned to make herbal
products and continue to grow many years
and had many associates in Point Arena
who grew along with me we had a natural
food store and many of us grew plants to
finance the store and the building and
we had a motto and it was food for
people not for profit and we would be
we'd have meetings month once a month
and we bring our herb and we trimmed it
at our meetings
and it was a very very open time and I
learned how to be involved in a
collective so I felt that this was all
the guidance of the spiritual side of
the plant which is a science now that
many people call planet spirit medicine
and every plant has a spirit or maybe
more as people have spirit and the the
spirit of marijuana has supported me and
loved me and guided me and helped me
develop as a human being
hmm so that's my relationship with the
herb I love her for me my awakening to
this magical plant began in 1968 and the
rock concerts were just coming onto the
scene and large venues they've outgrown
small clubs and and I was fortunate
enough to to go and see band called
Vanilla Fudge and they were the warm-up
act for for Jimi Hendrix and the
experience and at the time I was a a non
cannabis smoker I was a 3-2 beer drinker
because that's what it was in Colorado
and then a few months later I had my
first experience with
and we part took a bit before going to
my next concert and life has not been
the same since I got to say and I don't
know if it was a band or if it was the
plant but it was the little-known band
that had never performed before in the
United States and they were flown in at
the last minute and as the story goes
they would bid $1500 in the band it was
the last time they were an opening act
it was Led Zeppelin and we didn't know
what happened we weren't sure if it was
the the magic of the plant the word that
was the band I think it was a
combination of the two but this began my
journey and I started realizing after
experimentation and it was a really big
deal I mean it was like so hidden to to
be smoking cannabis but once I realized
then that there was something really
wrong here why is it so illegal why were
we lied to about this and so for me it
it pulled back the veil of illusion that
I had been force-fed that this was a bad
evil plan and and I realized well if
we're being lied to about this what else
are we being lied to so it kind of
became a truth serum for me and still is
to this day it allows me to to see
things a little differently to put a
different spin on it and just so
grateful to to have been exposed to the
wonders of this magical plant and I do
believe that the future of this plan
because it is a female plant I believe
the future is for this I don't like the
word industry I think it's good I think
it's a feminine future that we're
heading into I hope it is
and I love hearing what you all have to
say about your experiences what cannabis
it sounds like it's very spiritual for
everyone up here so I'm glad we all
relate on that and I feel that way with
my own personal relationship with Hannah
missed you so I wanted to ask all three
of you when you change Mendocino County
did you come as part of the
back-to-the-land movement or was that
anything that was present in any of your
lives here and we can just bounce around
you know the first person who thinks oh
I was part of a collective we were
renting and living in a warehouse a
twenty five thousand square foot
warehouse in Berkeley and wonderful
things were happening there we were
manufacturing electrical generating
windmills back then nobody was
generating alternative energy and the
Landlord decided to double our rent and
we were planning on moving up to
Mendocino at the end of our five-year
lease but this has happened about three
years into it so we radically
accelerated our moving date and didn't
quite have the infrastructure that we
were hoping to have but we it was a
crash landing but we walked away from it
but the back to the land movement very
much spoke to me in fact that's a large
part of my collection it was the
dissolution of the Summer of Love and
everything that was happening in the Bay
Area which was the cultural hub for the
youth movement and many people and
thanks to the Rolling Stone magazine and
High Times and mother of news and so on
go to the country
buy some inexpensive land and build a
house in rural garden and and we came by
the thousands and many of us are still
here wonderful things have happened as a
result of it so that was very much part
of the back to land movement I came to
San Francisco because my hippie daughter
ran away from home and that's living on
Haight Street and so I came to and so
and I also had experienced the wonderful
green herb in New York so I was already
a pothead or I would like to say that it
was the second psychedelic part the the
the not the entertainment part but the
the transforming part that attracted me
very much because one of my experiences
when I had a marijuana pipe full of very
good weed was I hallucinatin a temple in
India and I had never even heard of such
a thing
and so I I felt the expansion of the
herb and so being in in San Francisco it
was very natural for me to to want to
expand and then when I came here back
from India I went I took a ride
I bought a postal van and I lived I went
to the dunes to meditate with my herb
and I realized that I had to live here
that I was attracted to the ocean and
the
possibility of growing grass in my
backyard and so I guess that is why I
came I I tried to move here in the 70s
when I was a landless back to the lender
and that was not feasible so I
immediately stored it as the place to
return to which I did 20 years later in
1994 and two partners of mine agreed to
sign on as tenants in common I really
recommend this because each person owns
an equal part or the demand for three
markets they cannot confiscate your land
without the other people agreement
presumably you have the trust of those
people so you can feel very secure in
this period of those pendants they take
it away you know you had too many
violations civilly and so on and so I
was able to secure a place in the 90s
but in the 70s
I am indicee know just couldn't
accommodate someone as grassroots it has
myself and so I went to San Francisco
and got in with Dennis Peron and Bernie
Mary in that crowd and introduced myself
or linked to cannabis that way with the
people who were organizing labor were
responsible for organizing prop 215
which is kind of where I came in because
all of those years I was getting busted
for the default decade it was because of
what I was introduced to through them
and my commitment of course is above all
to the plant but after that my
commitment is to adjust society and that
means
to the cannabis community and the
initiative didn't cover the
transportation and in fact it didn't
cover cultivation in the very beginning
they just had possession obtain some
possession
well that isn't enough that brings up
the miracle pounds and where is that
coming from well the Bowery Corral in
Santa Cruz she is here amongst us in
spirit said include cultivation or I
won't support it and they said okay
Mallory you got it and so they included
the cultivation but I didn't have such
access on transportation I was just
getting busted all the time and there
was a concept that it had the clinician
of smuggling you know going too far so
the lawyers extent along the cultivation
and so on it was incumbent upon somebody
to challenge that and the lawyers had no
interest in challenging them especially
when they saw was me who they would be
representing because I had my own
opinions and so I had to go it alone
often but that worked out better than
being represented by the Warriors who
simply couldn't couldn't keep up with my
principles and I had a principled
approach for instance after the
transportation was allowed the court
said it's an implicit right well that's
going pretty far
just nobody ever asked them what do you
think about that and they said well of
course you have to be able to carry what
you can possess legally and okay yeah
she's right and from then on it was
kind of in my ballgame and the lawyers
came forward to say they wanted to
represent me but I feared that they
wouldn't and that's why I went on to do
it myself and one of the things is this
1993 it's called a cert petition when I
went through the state courts got denied
in every level you have to be jubilant
about losing so you did to obtain iron
and then I went into the federal courts
and they have a procedure where if you
raise constitutional questions you can
go as high it's the US Supreme Court and
if you only raise statutory you know
what the statute says that you can do
they stopped you at the appellate level
in the state court so nobody ever gets
to go further because they know exactly
what they're doing and they stopped
almost everybody so I was the Challenger
and the court agreed with me that tells
me that our community needs to
understand that the court may be way
ahead of us they just have not been
asked the questions by the people who
have a case a proper case uncritical I
need to say this one more thing I'm
critical of the wires because they're
too timid
they just think I'll need something
conservative something they'll never go
with us for how do you know you've never
asked them the Liberals have never done
anything and they may be more or less
equal and they just be a matter of the
times and how are you bringing a case
but my own community did not want me to
do that they wanted the lawyers to
handle it but I could see the lawyers
were not
and in one case that were talent that
one of the patients to to be exempt
Elva música is a extreme patient she
couldn't easily die from the brain tumor
so she qualified and as a necessity
patient but most of us are not necessity
patients we will not die or go blind
without it and that's what a necessity
patient is so wouldn't have covered any
of us any of the rest of us and so I
tried to go in there and with my own
brief that would be adopted alongside of
the others in my own current said we
will do nothing to enable you to foil
that and because you will make us losers
they didn't understand that now the
problem is were already so close to
losing we need help and years later the
lawyer came to me ran across the parking
lot to tell me you know we were wrong
about that and we appreciate that so
what I was actually during all this time
when the back-to-the-landers were making
the difference in the country and paving
the way for the rest of us an on forests
and there for acquittal sit jury trial
and you know just those are broad
shoulders
well that was happening I was doing my
best to be prepared for the cannabis
future that was going to be better than
what's unfolding right now Thank You
pebbles and I actually loved the group
of panels that we have here because I
see that we have several different
experiences and perspectives we have two
people that were out here growing
cannabis living the cannabis lifestyle
and we have pebbles who was down in a
more urban area fighting for us to have
these rights that we have now everyone
here contributed in their own
to make up the community that we
currently have and something that I
wanted to make sure we covered today it
was all of your opinions on what is
going what is going on in our community
as we move out of prohibition and into
regulation hopes and fears how you would
like to see this all play out what are
your opinions of what is going on right
now and most importantly how we can
preserve our values as a cannabis
community as we move forward so whoever
has the first thought feel free to jump
in I never thought that when
legalization came that that it would
look like it is unfolded where we are
today not sure what I was imagining to
look like but after having done a fair
amount of research on alcohol
prohibition I mean that's kind of a
somewhat of an example to drug it kind
of messes with your consciousness a
little bit depending on how much you
consume that had a about 12 year ago
have a shamanic and once that was lifted
then huge industries was created it was
already a huge industry right it was
already a huge industry in people making
their own bathtub gin which really
fueled the Jazz time period but it
really wasn't a good template for for
cannabis but as you look around it
really weren't too many good templates
nicotine where tobacco never had any
prohibition so
can't really in its a it's a drug and
it's destroyed and continues to destroy
thousands of wives a year
unlike cannabis which which doesn't we
now know it's a medicine so where we are
at today I mean I just the talk this
weekend is I just found out about it but
Flo canna is gonna be on featured on 60
minutes tomorrow night which I kind of
grew up watching 60 minutes and it was
you know really important TV show and
the whole family would sit around Sunday
night and watch 60 minutes and so for
them to come here to Mendocino County
and to be documenting our story is is
fascinating and I understand Casey
O'Neil is also gonna be part of the show
so that's exciting to hear can't wait to
see it it says the electricity comes
back on bet yeah you know predicting the
future is always a pretty iffy I've
never been very good at it but big
industry certainly has shown up and I've
seen personally so many mom and pops
happy to fold up and and sell their
property and move on because they just
haven't been able to afford the
licensing process or figure out the
paperwork and so we've lost a lot of the
the culture that came here in the late
60s in the 70s and 80s that Hill I'm not
sure of paving the way is already a
metaphor but did a lot of the groundwork
the many of us benefiting from just some
thoughts on it pebbles you want to jump
in
I feel like it's a time warp we are not
experiencing something that is normal or
smooth in any way we're just like this
and it's nothing like the people who
imagined just cut the punishments would
be the next phase impunity bet there's
nothing to do with this innocent benign
herb and the people who are associated
with it that's our crime is the
Association we have the right to
associate the First Amendment says so
but but then his reality is that it's
the most popular plant drug on earth the
most lucrative and we were the
caregivers the caretakers the stewards
of the plant and the environment all of
these decades are the ones that have the
upper hand that is being taken away they
are trying to steal the knowledgebase
through these regulations that make no
sense the regulations that would make
sense is that they went to the people
who are to be regulated and sat down
with those people and said let's have
some kind of a roundtable here and come
up with something that we can all live
with they did not do that they created
their own concept of the green rush that
was going to come to the county and
imposed it and I think they're about 300
people in in Mendocino County out of
what 10,000 families and wine waiting
for that proverbial permit
and they're toying with us because we're
in between prohibition and a just
regulation reasonable regulation or
in-between there were nowhere near and
they have put in place five different
agricultural commissioners to employ it
but they all quit or been fired within
days every single one of them it's you
know it's it's proof that they're doing
it backwards one of those air
conditioners what's his name just just
walked away it's Italy they just are
just not doing it right there they
should go home the classrooms up they
should start with what exists and work
from that and his idea was the opposite
of what's going on now and I feel that
regulation has put us as interpreting as
a community we are very vulnerable under
this new policy which is to go after any
and all permitted Gardens
judging whether 300 come out of 10,000
and that's because we're waiting to see
how if it opens up that there's anything
to help us survive that the purpose of
that is to basically take it all away
from us to leave us very reduced in our
power they do not want to share power
with the cannabis community which we
want to do that's why we were sharing
our knowledge we'd love to do that we
have 40 years of heritage and hand on
experience and then
taking advantage of it because they
don't know the time of day they think it
will work this other way and I think
we're showing them that it will not work
but meanwhile the corporations are
coming in and the corporations were let
in by the government that 5-year plan
that's input up 64 just disappeared
that was the leg in just disappeared
and so the corporations went in ahead of
the basic regulations and they are in
place right now many of our own people
are getting ready to settle and so on
and it's when you're in a hole what do
you do you you reach out for hands to
help you out and I feel that's what the
community needs to do we need to talk
about this hole that we're in that
they're putting us in in the world I
want them to put us in because we don't
know what to do about it that will be
effective so I'm suggesting there were
there a few of us who've been talking
for over a year about an elders Council
that will guide the ship that's coming
down whatever it may be something very
grassroots community-based
that was structure you know the dreaded
idea because we don't have any we don't
have a voice a cannabis voice and so
there are four of us who matured montz
them who have agreed to take off a plan
and a skeleton of what an elders council
would be basically it would help
preserve the culture enhance the culture
and great you know developments as they
come through and give to the community a
non-biased
with no agenda kind of truth you know
right now governor Newsom has given the
order or
to the national guard on the Mexican
border to go up to the Mendocino County
forests and rid the force of the people
who have unpermitted grows well now that
they've moved out of the forest into the
general population they've removed the
forest land as a limit so any
unpermitted grows our target now there
was a letter in the ABA a few weeks ago
from someone in at seven plants he was
crying he was so furious as he told his
story they came after me for one
additional planet and they took all my
genetics years of genetics and woman is
saying only than hundreds only thousand
so there was one there were 65 plants
it doesn't mention along with seven and
so it's because they're preserving their
interest to keep control in this
transitional period of time so it's in
our interest to get control of ourselves
you know to start with who we are have
emails is the easy way to go and just
how do we imagine doing this and maybe
monthly you know gatherings of people in
each other's homes where you can toke
and bring the music back and having our
culture since only take it that way but
something that would move out of
prohibition where we you know haven't
don't talk to each other in so vents
it's I feel the plant will take this
will guide us to the best place and that
the arguments are on our side and there
against those who are trying to keep
control well they never earned it they
never did anything to came along and
trying to steal it and we can't let them
do it
well I have ideas as well and I didn't
know about some concepts but the first
thing I think is missing well the world
is in chaos and many of our systems are
flowing down and we're seeing them all
we're seeing them all decaying and
breaking up and we know what they are
and primarily it's our political system
and so we're trying with what is said
here to break into a broken system that
has to be repaired I do feel that there
is a mistake that has been made right
along and and we need to have a real
green movement that this plant is an
agricultural plant and it needs to be
taxed like tomatoes and everyone can
grow it and that and of course there's a
medical division and that is a
specialized unit but but really there
are many intoxicating plants that are
already in use as agriculture you can
buy your hemp a you can buy kava you can
buy well other things but I know that
there are many many more and all of
these plants have a healing side and
Anna medicinal side and we need a green
like the Green Party of marijuana so
that we think of it as an agricultural
plan it is definitely honest farming it
definitely has the benefits of home life
with a family that can support its
children and not be have any kind of
criminal and we have to work to repeal
any kind of federal law that is still in
existence while that law was in
existence and while the politics are
broken everything is corrupted in in a
way that makes makes it go industrial
and package and and confusing and and
there's no education to dealing with the
amount of products that are here and
basically what we're dealing with
something that can grow like tomatoes or
mint or or lemongrass or oregano we need
to be able to have that kind of freedom
and it is a it is a linked to the
freedom many of us have been political
activists and we've seen freedoms
continuously have to be brought down
brought to its level of what it is right
now our freedoms have taken away by
playing this political game we really
need a green movement it is agriculture
we need to keep using that word and we
need to encourage growers and educate
them and as a matter of fact it is
happening in Willets I know in limits I
think there's going to be a very large
hydroponic marijuana grow that is
commercial so there's there's definitely
a need for it to be an agricultural plan
that is popularized with medicinal
specialties I don't see the political
game it is too corrupt we see how it is
right from the top all the way down to
the bottom with lots of paola and lots
of corruption and and that's misleading
we where farmers and and it's natural
for us to create and grow to grow and
create products from our work when this
was called the New World
all the new colonists who came to the
new world were given seats to grow to
grow him and you had to sign on if
you're gonna come to the New World and
you're gonna become an ant farmer and
people didn't till they didn't and back
then the big drug was team okay
remember the Boston Tea Party politics
taxes we've really lost our way I want
to bring up a dear friend of some of
ours here in the room
Julie Terrell Oh has been campaigning
along with Scott magazine's updated
she's calling the green Renaissance and
I think that's a great word use and
something to think about rather than the
Green Rush it's a green right we need to
look closely at that well I think that
um politics is belongs to them if you
guys made this year ago I would have
denied it but I think it's very clear
and the culture belongs to us and we're
putting way too much energy over the
years myself included into 20 to
influence their politics when the Gordy
got this plan that the they'd been
nurturing for years pretty much going
forward as anticipated much to my
surprise our input since we didn't have
any effect on prop 64 we he dropped out
and did not contribute from night from
the 2010 election to the 2016 election
and six years after Richard Lee's we
just didn't do it we were fighting
each other over nuances we am not
unified well enough to pull off anything
like a unified action and that's where
we have to start with ourselves I'm
thinking that I'm gonna pass this around
this is the invention of the century
this is a prototypes all-in-one what's
it's brass is unbreakable brass you can
put a truck over it
Richard and his family produced it and
there are lots of other little
inventions like this that are just you
know unnoticed I recognized that we
could bring to gatherings that we have
you know that thing that covers a fight
so that the herb doesn't fall out it's
just like a little rubber band and and
three turns out well five had five holes
to begin with in the beginning was the
one with the the heat shield on to keep
you from burning your fingers because of
morass so we in our factory we called
this one stake sites and it took getting
ripped off by by somebody with a lot of
money that saw us selling a lot of these
on Telegraph Avenue and he ripped us off
and put him in it he had a he had an
idea to capitalize on the culture and
the pipe sale he goes I'm gonna itch the
name tomato in it and put it in a tin
can and seal it up and put a tomato
label on it see he just he made a cheap
gimmick out of it and
back then we didn't have a name it
wasn't called pole pipe we had a we had
a name and called contrivance we were
trying to figure out what it was that we
we knew what we had but you know boy
coming up with a label is really
important so it took getting ripped off
for us to put our heads together and to
reach out and pull in a few close
friends and we did and immediately we
created synergy and one of the guys came
up he meant to say prototype and he
accidentally said prototype and we went
that's it Eureka
of course you didn't have the internet
back then yeah so it took a long time to
figure out navigate the legal system and
and we did though but it was a mere slip
of the tongue
it was reaching out creating synergy
with like-minded people and you know
this this guy we just knocked him out of
his orbit because he had a lot of money
we didn't but we were clever lads
forgive what my point was other than
this this one's a lot older than that
one this would go back to probably about
73 74 and it's still the improvement one
this is a 1.0 that's its repoint oh and
so basically the three points hit it
actually has two new patents on it that
this one does not have and we have a we
have a 50th anniversary in the wings
our 50th is Wow right at the end of old
compass it's gonna be our 50th
anniversary we should give them get them
a fundraiser because I think it's the
oldest truly mendocino based invention
in the cannabis culture I might be wrong
but in my knowledge of what's going
around nobody has even come
close to the 15 years the prototype is
stuck it out and they're having trouble
just like any small business defendant
this small business all over again so I
really feel like we should give him some
space of the Emerald triangle
centrality and the 50th anniversary of
what a brass pride because there's glass
everywhere when you go into spark
there's nothing but fast they take me
money over here in on the bottom no it's
an anomaly we're a 50 year old startup
one of many treasures that you brought
with you today
so would you like to take some time to
talk about your wonderful archival
collection yeah okay if you twist my arm
no I did I did write something up okay
which I could breeze through it pretty
quick yes please um I'll go something
like this in 1970 my older brother Phil
designed and fabricated a unique smoking
pipe pulled out and it was called the
contrivance and we knew that Denver was
not a place to launch this business
because nothing was happening in Denver
and in 1970 the laws were very very much
a red state and but San Francisco is
where the totem drum of the
counterculture was being beat and so
that's where rolling stone was and
that's where the that's where it was
happening and so he moved to San
Francisco to launch this pipe dream and
as soon as he could he called me up and
said you know it was a long-distance
phone call telephones were kind of a big
deal back then every called me up and he
said I got a small warehouse space Rick
why don't you come on out so I came on
out and and
I just gotten my my draft card number
and back then there was a very unpopular
war going on called the Vietnam War and
I've got a huge box of goodies but
there's just no longer all but basically
the Vietnam War was the United States
had only been in it for 1415 years and
the country has been a war for a
thousand years of exploitation but
anyway we were the latest the French
pulled the Americans into it and the
wars always need young men and so it was
a big appetite and so they created a
lottery everyone's birthday went on a
ping-pong ball went in a big hopper and
your fate is determined by the Pick of
the draw and I had a lot of friends who
got pulled out pretty early and you
could either leave the country go to
Canada or Mexico or you're up and or you
could go to you could go to college or
university and I chose that one I didn't
want to leave the country anyway
mine was the last thing pong ball pulled
out Wow that meant I was never gonna see
service so I didn't need to stay in a
place that wasn't fulfilling me so I
dropped out and I moved to San Francisco
to also chase the pipe dream and it took
a few years of making a lot of mistakes
we made every mistake you could for a
young star we knew nothing except we
were clever young lads that were just
resilient and just kept going back and
you know you fall down you get up and
you learn to walk you through crawling
and so forth so I was about six years
before we really started figuring out
our price points and how to set up an
assembly line in the Bay Area was very
good to us it was a very creative place
to be and I'd already told you the story
about getting knocked off by day yeah by
the tomato and so we we created synergy
we pulled in a couple of new partners
and that we all had skin and the
so again Berkeley was an exciting place
to be San Francisco area we
incorporators we created the corporation
one of my partners Larry Todd too many
people know him as dr. atomic he was a
cartoonist and he was published with
last-gasp in San Francisco and he was
good friends with you know the creators
of the furry freak brothers and fits the
cat and all of these other really
curious fun to read publications and it
really helped to normalize the hysteria
around cannabis marijuana as it was
called and so meeting him was a game
changer because he could not not create
incredible art and I had one of his
comics right here with me so this isn't
him but this is like furry freak
brothers everyone knows the furry freak
brothers natsume no dr. Tommy with dr.
atomic was absolutely epic and anyway
you know he he took our graphics
department and really started doing some
incredible things and some of his right
behind Tim there is it's called the
classic a mansion and that's a scene
that many of us recognize we don't exist
what's that oh it's it was out of memory
it's just it's an iconic image of these
up in that allows you to build your own
specifications you only get two
inspections is supposed to one for every
process along the way so anyway business
was was looking up and we started doing
trade shows and I started traveling and
setting up shops and you know you go to
a new town and you you look for somebody
with long hair or bell-bottoms and you
know hey it's a record store in town is
there a waterbed store in town and you
know you'd have to seek these things out
and every once in a while you get lucky
and find a place that would sell music
or posters or water beds and beanbag
chairs and maybe they had a small pair
of music so I got to see firsthand this
this culture sprouting up around the
country and there was a lot of fun doing
road trips and trade shows and festivals
and so forth and in time we started
advertising in magazines and we used to
I started off in Rolling Stone magazine
but then they they stopped doing that
and so the new kid on the block was this
one here called high tides so this is
your first issue right here pretty
amazing and we started we started
advertising in
times and Larry was doing our incredible
graphics and sales really started
picking up and then on a national level
there was a change in presidency and we
had a a president in there by the name
of Jimmy Carter and we were all thinking
the legalization was right around the
corner his son ship that declared
publicly that he was smoking pot in the
White House you know were everyone's
like yeah it's gonna happen with that
happening but Dennis strange thing
happened a guy by the name of Ronald
Reagan this this former actor and former
governor of California created this
political machine and before we knew it
Carter's out and Reagan's in and things
started getting really nasty and they
indeed crafted this rather draconian law
on exportation of metal pipes and we'd
had a good run we fight you know
legalizations around the corner we're
gonna we're gonna set this one out we'd
already taken a lot of arrows in the
back being up here and then say no
County our local City Council really
wanted us to go back to Berkeley and the
County Board of Supervisors really
wanted us to go back to Berkeley normal
wanted to come and represent us because
we were kind of a high-profile company
and we didn't want the big attorneys to
come in we thought that we could handle
it and so we created a petition and we
started going around to events wherever
people were gathering and we got people
to so we got several hundred signatures
on a petition and we went and of the
City Council and we convinced them that
that we were good for the community and
we packed the council chambers with
everyone that believed in us and so we
got grandfathered in and they wouldn't
let anyone else in but they drew the
line
right behind us so that was kind of
interesting but in 86 this new this new
federal law came into place and we we
let someone run the business for us with
you
you know once again with the agreement
that we want back in when legalization
is at hand well this guy changed his
mind because it was only a hand shaking
and you know shame on us but so he made
millions and we watched it from a
distance not very far cos he stayed in
Willows and he made many millions of
dollars and it was it was kind of tough
watching and so that the dog that was in
there so we we let go of the business
and in 87 and we had no idea that would
take another 30 years before the tide
was gonna turn in California anyway and
so strange story is this guy ended up
getting that we turned the business over
here and up getting evicted from the
very shop space that we used to occupy
in fact it used to be our building and
so he got evicted and and we're back in
there making these pipes again he let
everything lapse and we were able to
regain our name through the federal
trademark office and we're proto like
once again and it's it's it's a quota
you know popular song it's been a really
strange long trip but you know we're in
it for the long run and you know two
generations and the story is still
unfolding and while I wasn't just
sitting on my hands
I'll try and wrap this up for you to
speak real quick here but I I'm just
gonna read this one here it's 2018 well
right now this is marks my fiftieth
anniversary with the plant and well
let's see if what he said a lot of this
so I don't think I need to say this at
all so what I have been doing recently
though is is I saved everything when I
sold the business and it turned out to
be a really fascinating thing my mother
started me on this wonderful ride by
leaving this publication out my family
used to subscribe to Life magazine and
so if she left us out for her two
teenage sons to read on the dining room
table freedom it is but this is the real
this is a real magazine
towba 31st 1969 so I had no idea that
this was gonna you know direct my life
and I don't think she knew either
because she didn't leave it out there
for me to get into the in the
independent so I kind of owe my my
collection passion to her because she
used to I just want to show it to the
camera she was quite the archivist in
her own right and so I started just
collecting things that related to the
culture and I didn't know how much it
was until I was able to get a a room and
display it all in and I just kept
bringing it in by the box load and I'm
like good God and so it took a few years
to start moving it around and putting
together a story and the story is the
emergence of what can be known as a
counterculture those those of us that
were principally baby boomers
up in the in the 50s and the 60s and
coming of age and it was a turbulent
time and what was you know this is this
was the peak of the 60s and three months
after this was Altamont
and that was the the death knell and you
know this is August of 1969 and so the
all the youth you know this came out in
68 this came out in 1970 sorry and what
they're telling everyone here is if you
don't like the way things are go buy a
piece of cheap land doesn't have to be
in Northern California might be in
Tennessee it might be in Iowa because
the culture was everywhere it wasn't
just in Northern California so in the
the ads in the back of these are the
best because people are reaching out
they're saying looking for like-minded
people to buy some land together with
share raising our families together with
and so forth thing you know I always
dreamed the building the geodesic dome
and so be I know a lot of people that
came here to Northern California as a
result of these events it's a result of
this publication so it was it was a very
seminal piece in the another seminal
piece was the Whole Earth Catalog which
came out in 1968 and this was like this
was an Internet because for the first
time it gave people access to to books
and tools and ideas and gatherings of
like-minded people and this this had a
really good run this this ran from 1968
until 1960 1994 that was their last year
that they published and oddly enough I
was the Internet that that caused them
to stop
this is a good time to inter interject
sinsemilla
tips was the primary educator of the
cannabis
from 1980 to 1990 and then on to 2000
and he wanted to be here we invited him
and he said they need to make their
wishes his best but he is basically here
in spirit and then also the
o'Shaughnessy's editor friends are no
listen valiant he was supposed to be
here and it's enabling he was he's the
one who kept the medical culture alive
without o'Shaughnessy's we wouldn't
really have had anything all this time
magazine covers the culture although
that came writer and we don't have very
much because it's a hard life and it's
usually done by poor people like Fred
Gardner puts out this tabloid newspaper
because he's poor and that's just all he
can never afford to get the job done
this is this group of people especially
the publication's the editors are
long-suffering central people in our
community like virtually nobody else and
you have the archives to to show that I
think I feel that writing things down we
should do more about so as to save it
otherwise like we talk goes into the
ether it's very hard to pick up the
thread from one weight or month to the
next but when you write it down you have
a record of it and sometimes you get
somewhere in books and Mohsen Thal was
saying to Dennis
Peron you don't have to sell weed you
know you can do things legitimate Lee
and he opened up a publishing house and
was the only one who actually sold weed
books all of those decades and he
survives
when you go into a court of law
write it down you don't laugh you out of
the courtroom that you don't ever
written down we have to change from a
handshake culture to ones that do the
basic the basics that you must do in
life to trust the people you work with
legally binding because you don't have
to know them very well yes it's on the
paper what you agreed to you don't have
to go back and forth we have a real
problem like that
a huge problem with that because it
weren't anything to be written by cops
okay that the cops are not the problem
our own community knowing what each
other or saying and doing is the problem
keeping an agreement making each other
accountable that's the problem and as
we're moving now into this new era in
our community we do have a great need to
preserve these stories and it's great
when we find people like Richard who has
been saving these objects for so many
years and now it's about how do we take
these objects that he has in these
publications and how do we share them
with the greater community and how do we
share cecile stories and how do we share
Pebbles stories and Fred stories and
Douglass's stories and everyone else's
stories and make sure that they don't
get forgotten as we move forward into a
new time so I'm wondering you have the
idea of the elders Council I'm wondering
what each of you think about ways that
your generation who has paved the way
for where we are today can interface
with the younger generation of community
members so that we can make sure that
these stories get preserved it's so
important to share this knowledge
because I think that the younger
generation doesn't have the same
experiences that you all have had I can
speak for myself I'm a younger
cultivator we don't have the knowledge
that you all possess and it's really
important that it gets preserved and
something that I love about the cannabis
unity is it's a multi-generational
community I have many friends in Colo
that are in their 70s 80s and 90s and
they share their information so freely
and it's so valuable but it's not
possible for every young person to
interface with every elder in Mendocino
County so how can we do it it's an
important conversation to have and
cecile has an idea I have any idea well
just because because I developed a
product called Mendocino himself and I
brought some samples for people here who
attended our and December 8th there's
going to be an herbal conference in
Mendocino and I will bring my product
there and and I've we've had other ones
other years and there have been other
Mendocino educators there so I teach
people how to make some of my products I
teach them personally or that I write
them or or by the way as we all know on
the internet YouTube has how to do
everything right you can learn how to
make any kind of product and I'd like to
just say a word or two about some of the
products for people here that they can
make themselves one of them is if you
soak butts in olive oil and make Sun tea
like on the window sill if you leave it
there for three weeks
butts in the olive oil you then strain
out the bud you have wonderful sleep
medicine which you you have a half a
teaspoon of the olive oil bud mix which
I call bud mix a sleep bud you can put
it on a cracker or take a directly or
put it on a piece of toast and the other
product that
is being used legitimately by people in
the ophthalmic community is marijuana
the whole plant which I use and also if
you soak it in alcohol and make an
extract out of it that extract will keep
the pressure in the eye down and is a
glaucoma remedy it is not put in the eye
it is taken constitutionally so by
educating people on home herbal use we
can all popularize the Agricultural
herbal use that is medicinal that you
don't have to buy in the store that we
can make for our families and teach our
children how to do we're nearing the
time at which I know we wanted to take a
short break okay so we're gonna take a
short break if that's okay with everyone
here sure sure okay and then we will
reconvene in ten minutes
good Mary good good so we're gonna take
a short break if you want to get some
water use the restroom stretch your legs
and then we're gonna come back we're
gonna chat some more animal do some Q&amp;A