hi guys we are sitting here on the book
we de booth on the spannabis in
Barcelona this is Carrie hi Gary hi mica
and this is mica and what are you doing
here what year from Austria yes I'm from
Austria I'm working for the IBEW kana
I'm here for connecting people also for
the CBD business for getting certified
products for patient-focused certified
products and yeah I'm also connecting
with fo veda and and as I know as far as
I'm concerned as in your country
cannabis is not legalized medicine we
have only medical cannabis in form of
spray and removing all drops but not
like in Germany with flowers yeah in
Germany we mean while we can have
flowers in the pharmacy which is quite
cool we even have a dream burst
sometimes and but it's expandable so
yeah what about Austria yeah Austria is
going a little bit backwards in the in
the legalization process yeah they want
now that also CBD product getting under
the noble foods and so it's also
complicated in Austria for the medical
cannabis right now so what do you I
think it's a quite different situation
in Germany all the investors come from
Canada from the US yeah it's it's the
biggest as you say the biggest and
fastest raised business and Austria is
miss missing this and yeah hopefully
we're working also with together
governments to talk to them that we get
in the other direction but don't you
think it's quite crazy because on the
other hand you have all those legal CVD
but you have those clone businesses even
though where people make millions you
know you are freaking clones in austria
don't you they are till now till now yes
but the new government tried to prohibit
the clones so we had now in October a
changing of the CBD product so now it's
a big confusion Austria what is legal
what
but as you said the other the clones and
also CBD flowers are legal and quite
difficult so you still can make good
money with the legal cannabis laws yeah
man and as for a gherkin are you doing
that the AG economy argh Akana is a
patient-focused non-government
organisation we are helping introducing
people patients with medical cannabis we
have talked to us we introduce them to
doctors we make information events and
also we created a certification process
for CBD products on the European market
we want a price on the eye CPC for our
work in December in Austria and yeah
this this work we start now for whole
Europe and it's getting bigger and also
companies want to get certified from us
to get honest certification so you in
the legal CVD business and you know in
the state's this one is I think in the
United States and Canada this is very
different because in Germany cannabis as
a medicine is legal now
but the grassroots movement cannot
invest anything because it's mostly big
pharmaceutical companies or big foreign
companies moving in because you need
millions to be on the legal market
before you have a product on the market
you need millions in Austria it's better
when you have any attempts growth CBD on
a smaller range and open the shop and
so legal CBB bathroom
oh wow do you think good is not any good
yeah you're right but I think the
problem is with the mr. cannabis market
you cannot compare cannabis as a
pharmaceutical product it's not it's not
possible so cannabis should be
differently cleared for as a
pharmaceutical standard because always
the compounds with the interaction fact
and all the the the workflow of terpenes
cannabinoids and altogether neither a
separate classification of the product
and not as a certain as a pharmaceutical
brother that's that's the wrong way
where we are looking for and also the
investors and governments that's my
point of view
yeah Germany it's also kind of yeah
everybody is waiting
that also you know smaller businesses
can invest at the moment is really
hurtful because CBD is kind of not
illegal but it's not as legal as in
Austria we cannot really sell CBD but we
only killed sell supplemental products
and you have a lot of CBD like coffee
shops in Austria I saw that in Vienna
in the main street they have like coffee
shops or CBD Bartha that I cannot say
because I'm living now two years in
Tenerife so I moved I moved to Tenerife
so but I I follow all the news in
Austria but my base is in in Tenerife
so what scares me in Spain it's even
different than in Austria and in Germany
yes we have more different than Spain we
have the social gaps we can enter
official in social gaps as it's only
half legal kind of it's not no it's not
legal it's also a gray area in Spain and
as we know for local people but also
Barcelona is more touristic for in for
Tenerife as you know for our collapse we
use it for our own people and not for
for the touristic what do you agree if I
say it's a little bit in the Europe it's
a little bit like in the US that it's
like in the European community we have
27 States and we have about 25 different
laws about cannabis or a state system of
cannabis is really this is really really
strange but I think the fewer of us will
understand it if they compare to their
situation maybe 10 years ago you know
they're very little few states where
cannabis was legal there very few states
where it was totally illegal then we
have those states where it's like
half-baked or halfway go and this cap is
at Arctic
yeah I agree with you totally okay and
how is prepare well the fair for me it's
the second time at the spannabis and
yeah it's a quite big fair quite busy
now and yeah my job is done for today
and I will leave now to some social caps
to meet also business people and yeah I
will do a little more work for weakness
you know I I work for weakness in
Germany since a while they they make
them whether they have an ice block I
can write for because I like to write I
hope you read my articles for months ago
of kasnia
and yeah we trance gave me great
opportunity to open up a block but
writing about cannabis since Mariana
calm /te and I still have I doubt I want
to work on the wheel on the perineum we
have the first proof so come and check
me
of course yeah I'm a nickname they're
half as bad you're making no I'm not a
patient
I was medicated are you soon guys