[Music]
difference between style and fashion oh
you can't teach style
well you've sent Laurent said
whereas fashion is an art that's not--
notoriously difficult to keep up with
because trends change seasonally style
is impacted by much longer lasting
factors style is affected by religion
politics culture subculture weather body
type profession upbringing and lots of
other things so Bravo yes that's what we
think too so this is a fashion in beauty
panel and beauty is sort of at the top
of this food chain because it's about
looking good about bringing beauty and
aesthetics into the world so we want to
talk about why it's important you may
notice this is our first and only to my
knowledge all-female panel so whoo
[Applause]
now one of the things that we wanted to
do is we really wanted to talk with you
about it so we're gonna go really
quickly everybody's gonna just tell you
who they are then we're gonna start
talking about fashion and it turns out
we have some different points of view
about it and then we invite you to have
your points of view and throw them in to
so we really want to participate with
you so I'm gonna start by letting my
panelists speak for themselves hi my
name is Debra Lindquist
I'm an eco-conscious clothing designer
I've been in business for 35 years next
month and I work with a combination of
organic sustainable and recycled
materials so the reason I'm here is I am
working with vintage cashmere and
vintage leather and I applique different
kind of iconic symbols on these things
but I've decided a few years ago that
the you know the hemp leaf was pretty so
I started to applique my leaves on on my
cashmere so I also work with other kinds
of fabrics like the sustainable mo doll
and my very very favorite sustainable
fabric is hemp I started working with
that in around 2004 I put it on the
runway when mercedes-benz and smashbox
were partners in LA Fashion Week and I
ended up putting a
wedding dress at the end of that runway
show which ended up in the USA Today
newspaper in a story about industrial
hemp so here's my wedding dress on my
model at the finale of my fashion show
in this industrial hemp article I think
that was about 2005 so I've been in this
for a long time my mission is to really
inspire people to care about the
environment I'm really concerned about
the planet and the people who live on it
and my business is focused on
sustainability for that reason I hey
guys I'm Brandi and I am from Canada I'm
here from Toronto and I'm the founder of
Evo beauty we have been around now for
five years we are a non cannabis
cannabis company if that makes any sense
and so I started the company with a
mission to break stigmas and create a
more conscious future and that was so
important to me when I started the
company because I started the company
while living in a woman shelter so you
can imagine my life is drastically
different five years later and and
recently I just sold a part of the
company to Aurora and so they're our
partners in the cannabis and sector and
cannabis was just a tool in our vast
tool belt to create a more conscious
future which is why I say we're not a
cannabis company and there were four
main pillars that I was focusing on in
creating a more conscious future and it
just so happened that cannabis was a
tool that addressed all of those and if
it was lavender that could address all
of those I would be in a very different
room right now but um those four pillars
were social justice which i think is a
huge huge huge component of cannabis
that is often not spoken about enough
and another one is the excess use of
animal by-products in cosmetics is huge
and also the excess use of plastics and
then also transparency in the cosmetic
world as well with I'm actually watching
somebody put on their lip gloss right
now do you know what's in that
oh good good good but it's often a
challenge I'm in cosmetics that you're
unsure of what's in it I'm so I'm being
from Canada you just heard them talk
about the man who is up previously
talked about the regulations and how you
literally have to put on a marshmallow
suit before you go in and you know who's
getting in and out you know who touched
that plant you know every single thing
about that and that provides a lot of
transparency to non cannabis consumers
who really the consumer of Evo beauty
are not cannabis consumers in fact most
of them are not for it yet and so we
were addressing that as well and then
towards the planet we were actually able
to reduce the use of plastic by 45% by
reinforcing our plastic with hemp fibers
so and cannabis is just a tool that we
use but we are not a cannabis company
and then we've really leaned on our
partners at aurora and others in the
industry to be the experts in that area
and we just provide a new platform
through our mass distribution in Canada
the US Australia and the EU as well and
we're we're partners with Sephora as
well so it certainly gives us a
different different type of consumer to
introduce them to the magic of cannabis
that isn't in the capacity of smoking
hello hi my name is ELISA marques a
stage name miss Marquez I'm a burlesque
performer and I'm the artistic director
of a show called marijuana madness it's
a live show that combines burlesque live
jazz music and theatre to tell the true
story of cannabis prohibition during the
Jazz era so all the music in the show is
music from the Jazz era the tail of the
show tells the story of cannabis
prohibition and how it targeted jazz
musicians the racist roots of cannabis
prohibition during the 1930s I've been
doing I'm a professional dancer who has
been focused on burlesque for about the
past seven years about four years ago I
decided to start implementing cannabis
into my burlesque acts as a form of
cannabis advocacy to try and change the
stigma
what people think cannabis consumers
look and act like so I actually my form
of agna advocacy is actually wearing
cannabis on myself in my costumes and in
my acts I'm partnered for marijuana
madness with a great organization called
grass-fed and they provide amazing
cannabis live events their approach to
cannabis is more like a fine wine
tasting so all of our events are fancy
we encourage people to dress up the it's
a smoke-free environment so it's also a
very health conscious company also at
our events
it's a smoke-free environment that is
only vaping and micro dose edibles and
I'm very proud of the show in the sense
that is the first live event and
burlesque show of its kind that only
doesn't focus on cannabis in the
storyline but also provides a cannabis
speakeasy where you can actually consume
cannabis at the live events and she's
proved uh performing tonight at the
after-party yeah whoo me and the band
will be performing on the top deck
tonight's we'll be performing some of my
cannabis themed acts so be sure to stick
around for it it's gonna be lots of fun
hello everyone my name is Whitney Bailey
and I'm CEO and founder of apothecary
brands and actually came to the canvas
space I guess differently than a lot of
other people five years ago I was a
senior vice president at entertainment
company but I had a health situation I
was diagnosed with anxiety and I tried a
million different drugs that my doctor
prescribed to me and none of them worked
and offhand
she said why don't you try cannabis and
actually I was in shock and awe because
Nancy Reagan had told me to say no to
drugs
I wasn't why would a Nancy lie to me I
said and I did a lot of research and I
learned a ton about the space but what I
did not like after coming into it was I
didn't find a lot of things that spoke
to me
spoke to me as a mother as a female as
an executive as a member of the you know
the community that I I was in and also
when I looked at the other people that I
knew used cannabis they were all a lot
like me and they kept their wine in the
wine fridge and they kept liquor and
bars and they kept cigars and humidors
and we all kept our high in cannabis and
a shoe box out of our beds
and I was like why why is that that
compromises the experience it
compromises to me the use of it why am I
saying that this medicine is so useful
to me and now I'm going to put it in a
place of shame underneath my bed when
it's not safe it's not kept in the
humidity and I decided you know like any
any high-quality single mother to quit
my job so my house and start a company
and that's what I did I started
apothecary three years ago
and since then we went through the
canopy Business Accelerator we've raised
seed around and we've been in sales for
almost two years now we're doing 140
percent up from last year and
encouraging people to think about the
way that they store use and imbibe
cannabis i'm janine moss i'm CEO of anna
B and we have a luxury line thank you
a luxury line of fashion accessories for
the sophisticated cannabis consumer we
have a table right over there so you can
learn any of everything there so let me
just ask another question of you one
thing I want to observe is the character
of the audience changed a lot here I
have to observe that there's a lot of
women here now and much fewer men so men
go on you for being here welcome to our
fashion world let me ask you do you how
many people in here are thinking about
oh I have a business and I might you
know I've got an uplevel it I want to
pull in fashion how many are interested
in that okay nobody practically a couple
people good on you our people is our
investors in this room well I what do
you want to figure out how to wear your
how to fly your freak flag better so all
of those things any other thoughts out
there just shout them out things you'd
like us to make sure that we cover that
you're interested in about fashion ok
it's on us then all right I'm gonna kick
it off with the question but honestly
think about it because we'd really like
to talk with you about how we can be
helpful to you and so our first question
my first question is we heard a lot
about how cannabis came into businesses
there are businesses and now they've
incorporated cannabis but how can
fashion influence cannabis then the the
cannabis industry is is it important is
it not important should we be thinking
about it what do you think let's start
with each ask each of our panelists how
they think fashion can help us in moving
this industry forward ok fashion can
help move this industry forward by you
know people embracing I think for from
my point of view I'm working with hemp
so in the very beginning I when I first
started working with hemp journalists
would say things like well how can you
be making sexy clothes out of hemp
when it's kind of scratchy and shapeless
garments and boring kind of clothes and
I was making bustiers and I have a kind
of burlesque connection with miss
Marquez I was doing Pussycat Dolls so I
was doing their costumes and I took it
all the while I was doing bustiers
before I did them for Pussycat Dolls but
I started putting my hemp into bustier
is like in a wedding dress kind of theme
so they were so confused at first and
just didn't know what to do with me and
they decided well we'll call you the
sexy eco designer which was fine with me
instead of the dumpy you know eco
designer so it's kind of you know
there's a stigma to
how this material could be used for
instance you know I'm not familiar with
it well gee look at how drapey and
lovely and and sensual this fabric is in
terms of really wearing the the leaf
which I've put on things some people are
a little afraid of it because they don't
want to be stigmatized but I think it's
a pretty leaf and I applique flowers on
things and it's just another leaf I like
maple leaves too and palm leaves so you
know as a plant I think it's a great
plant it has so many uses from the
industrial point of view of hemp and to
the cannabis point of view for medicine
and so on so does that answer your
question sure for now so again how does
how can fashion help us move this
industry forward fashion and style and a
focus on that so I think that it's in my
opinion I think my answer kind of
crosses over just fashion and beauty and
style but I think cannabis is really
similar to Buber in a way and if you
would have said to me you know ten years
ago hey B you're gonna get in the back
of an unmarked car with a man driving
you're not gonna talk to him who's gonna
take you to where you want to go just
trust him I'd be like no I'm not getting
the back of that man's car but today
like I took an uber here and anytime I'm
in Vancouver which is like the only city
on the planet that doesn't have BRR I
don't know what to do with myself it's
hard to live without Oh BRR now and I
think that it's very similar with with
cannabis as well so from our perspective
we actually did a survey in April in the
US and it was between Sephora we were
part of their accelerate and so we did a
survey with 2000 Sephora consumers and
we asked them and you know how do you
want isn't important to you to reduce
the use of plastic is it important to
you to reduce the use of animal
by-products and animal testing and is it
important to you to have transparency in
your ingredients and across the board
everybody's like yes but then when we
said would you have cannabis in your
products across the board the majority
of people said like
No and so I think that if you're
addressing people's problems in any
industry then it's more likely to be
able to progress that forward and it
will take some time to break the stigma
but we've now done what they have asked
in the products to address their
problems and then can then say surprise
it's cannabis and I think that that also
helps break the stigma and it also helps
move the industry the cosmetic industry
forward by addressing those problems
that there are major problems to those
people whether they believe in cannabis
or not jumping off of what you were
saying Deborah Pussycat Dolls is a great
example actually because you know back
in the 2000s and Pussycat Dolls were a
thing BCA's we're like quite as
fashionable as like now you see them all
the time
and I think with fashion it's important
to note the trends of things and how
people like you know Lady Gaga or the
Pussycat Dolls like being a professional
dancer that's worked in the commercial
industry
I see how the Wardrobe they put on us
you might wear in a music video and then
all of a sudden it becomes the next
trending thing as a burlesque performer
that's what got me so excited about
using my platform to promote cannabis I
started looking for costume pieces that
had pasties or you know a g-string that
had a cannabis leaf on it couldn't find
it didn't exist create it at myself now
I see at other places so not to like
tout my own you know but like as a
burlesque performer it's very exciting
to get really creative obviously I'm a
bit eccentric
my hair color kind of shows that a
little bit and if I can encourage people
to be creative and eccentric with their
own wardrobe because I'm wearing a
cannabis leaf on my head that makes me
pretty excited I personally think that
fashion has the ability to really help
us distinguish this space
I think we have the ability to bring new
people into the cannabis space by
broadening out what we see as cannabis
you know if we work here Tim here
ago people were much more you know
thinking about stoner culture we got you
know college kids smoking behind the gym
and that you know stoner guy who can't
remember all these stigmas and
stereotypes over here but as we have the
ability in fashion in the way that we
present things the way that we brand
things we have the ability to really
broaden out and make people feel more
comfortable in this space because
personally for me I want to be selling
you know cannabis not only to you know
the people that are already in the space
but I want the 45 year old white woman
in Kansas to feel welcome here I want
the you know 65 year old black mother
who has arthritis to feel welcome here
and we need to be able to show them you
know this space as where they are meet
them where they are and we have that
ability through cannabis just in the
same way as cannabis is not one size
fits all what I smoke might not have the
same it is no benefits for you as it
does for me my anxiety works with
sativas not indicas you know everything
is very personalized and we have the
ability to bring that personalization to
people through fashioning the way that
we present this to them and open them up
to the plan so fashion makes things
accessible to so one of the things I
believe from what you were all saying is
you know fashion it's been democratized
used to be that it was this rarefied
thing and only the very wealthy could do
it and then there was tars a you know so
there was a it's really been
democratized I think every American
anyway has gotten quite used to good
design so panelists what do you think's
not living up to the good design you
know who where are we in the evolution
whether it's kind of its packaging the
design of the products that can the
consumers you know where are we where do
we need to go let's start over here I
was just having a conversation today
about how you know as much as we work
and and do I think as a community try
our best to put our best foot forward I
think that we still have a lot of
objectification of women and a lot of
the billboards that you see on the side
of the road I saw a picture today of two
women's asses with the Cannabis you know
company's name on the back and I'm not
naming any names but I feel that that's
absolutely ridiculous in this space
where we have more female CEOs than
anywhere else that we feel comfortable
and objectifying women in that matter
[Applause]
but we're talking about women being one
of the fastest growing groups coming
into this space that's how you want to
welcome them in and all the people who
said oh you know we're scared of
cannabis and this is what we're showing
them I think that you know as a
community it's our job to be able to
stand up and say you know that's not
what we want to stand for and I
understand that there's a range that you
know just like there's pop off and Greg
ruse that there are gonna be brands that
fall between the range but I just think
that that is just unnecessary and people
have to stand up and say so or we end up
with more of that so there's the
objectification of women which we pretty
much object to because we all clap but
what about the other things like stoners
and big joints and you know what do you
think about what else you're saying
anybody well I can't say from what I was
speaking about earlier about marijuana
madness providing a cannabis speakeasy
we have chose specifically to make it a
smoke-free environment so there aren't
any bongs there aren't any big ripped
joints you know that sort of thing and
not that I don't enjoy those things but
I do think it is important to really
showcase and provide people with an
experience that's not that typical
cannabis culture stigma that we
associate from you know like we were
saying earlier the Cheech and Shawn
movies which I love but remember that
was a parody and when you take that
parody and make that your real life
that's that's not doing anyone in the
cannabis industry any favors
so I wish that we could say the same in
Canada and it is very rare actually that
we have female CEOs or female director
roles in cannabis in Canada and which is
interesting because it is the country
leading cannabis right now and so I do
kind of understand a little bit of the
sexual ization if we're I don't agree
with it like I feel like I don't have
that opposite opinion but I do also
agree that if that there's there's a
long way to go within that and I think
that in changing and who's sitting on
those boards and not saying that it
needs to be women but it needs to be
people there that are there for the
right reasons and actually something
that I don't know if this has to do so
much with fashion or answers the
question or not but kind of going back
to the social justice and fashion has a
huge part and cultural changes and it
has a huge part in societal like uproars
and how we can change things and we
definitely use fashion and beauty to to
like protest our opinions in a very
positive way and so I think that some of
the things that we need to focus on is
changing who's in the room and what
we're talking about and one of them
majorly being a social justice I'm on a
panel in Toronto tomorrow morning that I
am on this panel with a man who now is
the CEO of a cannabis company which
awesome but he was also a police officer
in a ranking role that put most of those
people behind bars for marijuana crimes
so I think that there's an interesting
aspect there to be addressed and I think
that fashion and beauty is a really cool
platform to be able to and kind of I
don't like the word protest because I'm
certainly that sometimes has a negative
connotation to I'm being angry and
that's not necessarily how we progress
and move forward either but I think
fashion and beauty has a really strong
space because it's on visual and so I
think that it depends
that have like positive opinions towards
cultural change and societal change and
I think that's when we start to see less
naked houses on
on Billboard's Deborah do you want to
talk sure well I have a sustainable
fashion brand eco-conscious and when
there was a German when finally there
was terminology for what I'd been doing
for quite a while since 1983 actually it
was probably around 2004 and all these
names for what do we call this we call
it green we call it sustainable we had
eco friendly eco conscious ethical so
back then it was about to change the
world people were jumping onto the green
bag bandwagon like it was you know the
next greatest thing sometimes not really
being true to all of it there was green
washing like oh I'm doing this but I'm
not really doing this so you know there
are many aspects to a sustainable
business it's about you know the product
the materials use the way you process
that the your production methods all
comes down to carbon footprint but the
main objective is to save the planet
right and keep our environment healthy
and keep ourselves healthy as people so
in the last decade what's taken over
something happened we had an economic
crisis and everybody decided that well
we're just gonna buy fast fashion so it
gained a gigantic foothold with mega
brands giving us options of new fashion
every day in these big stores which you
probably know there four of them I won't
mention their names because we all know
them but they've taken over the world
actually and they've created so much
chaos and so much unhealthy conditions
for the people who make the product and
also just it for the environment in
general because it's really true the
butterfly's wings do affect the world as
a typhoon halfway around the world
small changes being really big results
so now after so many businesses have
been operating in the shadows for 10
years a lot of my friends have dropped
out because they couldn't make it retail
stores have closed so here we are back
again talking about sustainability and
interestingly enough it's involving
that's involving cannabis and it's
involving half
at least for me I'm the Brent you know
I'm a brand basically so I'm really
proud to say that what I do out of out
of hemp is is really high-end fashion
it's you know wedding it's it's really
feminine sustainable and it's not
overtly well it's sexy but it's not
overtly sexy not like those you know
billboard you're talking about I know
exactly which one that is
I'm a little tired of all that you know
let's just let's be beautiful as women
and we can have all that you know as
part of us as well but you know think
about the greater picture you know what
are we really trying to do here now jump
in on that real quick just I like to
what you just said about women are
beautiful because I think not
necessarily butts are not beautiful but
its context and context is everything
and so what you're describing is very
different than you know what I do I'm a
burlesque performer absolutely sounds
like porn you know what when you see it
it's the same thing difference between
the objectification and sexual ization
yeah in this space and you know because
when you show that without you know
you're not showing their face you don't
care about that person you're not
marketing to you that girl you're shit
there's some weed off the back of her
ass yeah exactly I just wanted to throw
that what you're saying it's not
objectification of the person because
the person when you do your burlesque
because you're you're the the person
what what's amazing about burlesque is
it's a woman's choice right to utilize
sexual ization in her performance in the
way that is parody is comedy what I love
about burlesque is because as I get to
use that sexual platform to make people
reflect on their own insecurities about
sex in general and that's a big reason
why I loved bringing cannabis and so
that too because just like sex has a big
stigma and people are very uncomfortable
with nudity and that sort
Thayne so are people really
uncomfortable with cannabis but yeah I
totally agree with you guys on all the
objectification I just wanna they're out
their butts are beautiful in the right
context so we've heard about social
justice ecological sense the sensitivity
we've heard about gender parody and
there's a movie have have you all heard
about the women of weed Mary Jane's the
women the weed movie so what's great
about that I'm in that movie show a
little piece what's great about that
movie is that she set out to find out
whether women in the industry had these
things in mind and you guys clearly all
have those things in mind and so maybe
it's a new industry because women have
such a leadership position in cannabis
now maybe we have an opportunity to
create a new industry that has that
those kinds of sensibilities so the
question then is if we do have that
opportunity how do we make it real what
do we have to do to keep this going I am
really eager to answer that question we
need more men in these seats the fact
that there is more women in these seats
now than there was before unless men
that's what we need we need to all
encompass be working towards one goal
together not have the women's panels but
have women on the panels because they
deserve their spot there and they earned
it and we need to stop say forgetting
those things and be all one together
working towards a common goal I think
that's how we really get there so propel
it by bringing men into the ideas that
were putting forward is what you're
saying and men have some amazing ideas
too like I'll be honest my board of
directors is primarily men in fact
solely men and that's not something I'm
proud of it's just that they really
earned their spots there and really
moved this movement forward and we are
our offices on Bay Street in Toronto
which is like the wall street of Canada
and they're coming in for one purpose
which is to make capital gains in the
kind of
industry and I'm okay that they're
coming in for that purpose but when
they're sitting around our boardroom
table they're coming in and saying hey
Bea tell me about me - what's that
tell me about women in cannabis tell me
your opinion on this cannabis ad and I
think that having those mutual
conversations together is a really
really big movement in that direction
and and it's it's unfortunate that a lot
of men exit the conversation when it's a
panel of women I you know before I
talked about the fact that you know
there's more female CEOs and cannabis
than any other industry in the US but
that number has been you know trailing
downwards
I think young by 10 percent without that
26 percent yeah and then also when you
look at it those are not the companies
that are getting the majority of funding
they're not the ones who have the money
to buy the billboards and I think that
it's important that we have a seat at
that table and I you know I talk this
not just for women but also for people
of color because if you haven't noticed
I am a woman of color and there's just
not enough of us here in this industry
having a word in this industry and you
know we come from communities that would
be disproportionately disenfranchised by
war on drugs and we don't have a seat at
the table either and so being able to I
think to have those conversations you
know and at a higher level being in that
c-suite where those decisions are made
become a very powerful thing and so you
know to piggyback on that I think that
it's great that we're here I love the
fact that we have so many women I want
to see them have more power so how do we
help everybody in this audience get a
seat at the table what do you have to do
how are we gonna help them and how are
we all gonna do it anybody I have any
ideas
I think as far as the ethics of the
advertising you know maybe reach out to
some of these organizations and get the
message out that if you wanted maybe
educate what is you know and every and
anyone have change in like you said and
as far as Brittany talking about the old
man of CEOs and this is the judgment
call at all but I think that's
unacceptable because there's just as
many women that have before that have
earned the right you know to be there
and they're not so that's that's
unacceptable and I think when you stop
accepting it and I know it's difficult
you know obviously it's a situation but
that is one step forward I think you say
it's not acceptable better
now one thing I've read in a lot of the
statistics is that women don't want to
be CEOs as they start climbing up the
ladder I mean it inhibits you and your
family life it means something to be a
CEO culture that makes it ok I think
that when we are in charge we're allowed
to set a culprit corporate culture that
allows it to be ok that I'm a single
mother so yes within my company we have
you know ability to have family time we
have work-life balance and those sort of
things I think that when you give us the
opportunity to be in those seats we want
to be there don't believe the hype that
we don't want to be in that seat I want
to be but do you think it is gonna give
us that opportunity they're gonna go
here have that opportunity we love you I
sold my house when I started the company
I'm like I'll be a CEO by myself until I
get the team behind me it took me a
while to be able to get there but I
raised every penny of that first seed
around in order for us to get us off the
ground and I continue to go out there
and pound out the payment doesn't make
it easy I'm raising a bridge around
right now but is it worth it every damn
day because I get to set these you know
these standards and I get to be the
company that I think should be there and
I get to show the imagery that is
diverse and shows fashion it shows
people of all walks of life using
cannabis in a way that I think is
responsible and medicinal and so that's
the powerful benefit of being there how
many people want to do that create
companies that have these kinds of power
of policy but I think we also have to I
don't want to be the most unlike person
on the panel but we have to make a point
to that women have had less time in
business and I mean I am a feminist to
the most I started my company while
living in a shelter there due to
domestic violence I know the sacrifice
and and what it takes to start from
nothing $15 and raising money and
selling part of my company to Aurora
which is male CEOs and they actually
what they did and this is why this is
why the men are in those positions right
now is because they recognize their
privilege and they
is that they had the power to invest in
a young female CEO and let her guide
where that money is going let her decide
how that billboards going to look and so
the fact that they came forward to that
point to do that I totally I embraced
that I will take those funds from the
male CEOs and position that properly so
that we can give more opportunity to
young and female CEOs moving forward but
that's not gonna happen overnight and so
it's going to take time and men have had
historically because they've been in the
workforce for so much longer
historically they do have more
experience in this space it doesn't make
that experience better it doesn't mean
that they're better at their job at all
but historically they have been in those
positions much longer and so if we can
utilize that power together I think
that's really how we get ahead because
most females don't have the capital
funding they got 2% of VC funding last
year alone I'm really really grateful
that I'm part of that 2% and so I want
to use that to be able to create
positions where more women can have
those tools and ability but it's not
gonna happen overnight I'm glad you
brought up that number because I think
that that's you know becomes the key is
why you see so many white male
businesses you know being able to
survive and thrive is because they're
getting that funding when women are
getting 2 percent of venture funding and
women of color are getting point 0 2
percent so we have to do five times
better to get to you I mean do you and I
order of that money and so they're
holding that money and we don't have the
access to and it allows us not to be
able to build those brands so I mean I
understand I closed around as well and
that doesn't happen as you know as often
but if you look at they think the normal
number for a white male CEO was to raise
3.6 million and there's only been 18
women of color who ever raised over a
million dollars so I think that you've
got to look at where that money is
coming from as where that power play is
as well and that's gonna change so I
asked the moderator I have to bring it
back to fashion because this is a huge
issue but you know is fashion the way we
can do it I mean as
that the are those in rows like women
have been enabled to have a historic
role say in marketing right they let us
be nurses they let us be secretaries and
then we became marketing people we've
made our inroads and now we've had
enough time that we have the economic
knowledge we have the money now greatest
transfer of wealth in history to women
that's happening right now and we have
the education right so we're there is
fashion like the Trojan horse can it get
us in fashion and beauty or does it have
a role to play here I think business is
business is business so whether it's
fashion or beauty or cannabis or
whatever it is it's business you all
agree okay do you agree well I think we
have to design our own lives you know
and we have the opportunity to do that
and we do that every day with our
choices so you end up with something you
say I didn't want this I don't like this
situation I'm in it's like but you made
decisions all along the way you know the
universe provides you with the things
that you say that you have so in in
terms of fashion I think that you learn
to you know project yourself in a way
that you want to be seen so you have
choices you can buy this you can buy
that you know make your choices
carefully buy buy less and buy better is
my motto you know buy from people like
me for instance booth right there so you
know we have to decide that we want to
you know create more interest in what
we're doing by it does depend on how we
look you know how are you are you
presenting yourself how did we end up
looking today when we came to this panel
discussion we dressed in a certain way
because we decided we wanted to look
this way so you know those those are
choices you make every day and that's
what fashion does you make choices you
might try something new you might try
waist-high pants that's scary and then
we're belt you know which I've done
recently it's wow that's crazy so I mean
the trends are the trends but you
can make them relate to your life by
trying them out doing the best you can
with it and having a good time with it
and it's like it should be something
somewhat fun so this leads beautifully
into my next question it's gonna be my
last one before I turn it over to you
okay good I'll keep mine
that actually having a brand for
bringing in the school the industry to
represent
even a game-high that we get
we're putting our team together
trying to figure out what type of intro
to use for a shirt
are we getting corporatecat or exercise
really
to make this and not like you know
showing booty legs like industry
what the heavy selling soda for the
women
so really cat-back we need more candles
those chairs as women because
I have one little thing to add to that
just have to consider your the brand you
know you are the brand how do you want
to look how do you want people to see
you and then you make choices
accordingly and so does your partner as
well I think an important point too is
knowing who you're marketing to I
yeah I want to talk about marketing
because like clearly that billboard that
we've addressed is not marketed towards
women but it's a huge billboard they had
the money for it and it's in their
interest to sell to men and that's where
when you're talking about having these
conversations I think it's really
important to talk about sex and talk
about how sex is utilized in marketing
so much and explaining why that's not
okay and I think that for me I I think
what we take from fashion and bring into
the space you know besides the idea of
you know not just plant we're talking
lifestyle we're talking broader context
across the board is really being able to
target in on a demo as a business I know
very clearly who an apothecary customer
is it's not just all women it's not just
all men you know I'm looking at you know
men and women who are medical users are
urban professionals or females who are
between 30 and 60 who are making $75,000
a year more that's my target it's no
longer you know I can just put out
cannabis and people are just gonna run
just cuz it's there so I think that in
the same way that in fashion you know
Forever 21's talking to somebody in H&amp;M
talking to somebody
you're starting to see that distinction
within this space and I think that it's
really parody what's happening in
fashion well if you know who your
customer is then your brand doesn't it's
not about you it's about what you want
to mean to your customer I think let's
do some questions I've got more but you
probably have better ones so I'm just a
little curious because I think sexy like
that was something that brought up a few
times and I think sexy can be more of a
state of being or an emotion that's
invoked like I've seen your I've seen
your products girl you you're killing it
but it's something that's sexy it
invokes something right right so how can
you or how do you go about
creating your personal brand as well as
maybe you have something that you're
actually selling clothing or whatever
how do you do that without going too far
what what do you think is too far I also
teach burlesque classes and I the
brand's / my burlesque classes is called
empowerment in heels and with that
what's very interesting is I've found
that a lot of my students have been more
empowered by taking sexy photos of
themselves and posting it on Instagram
where once again it comes down to
context they feel empowered by you know
being a part of the burlesque show cases
I provide to my students that's not for
everyone
not everyone wants to get up on stage
and you know put that much sexiness out
there but that's what's so interesting
about burlesque is really you can't go
too far with it because it's based on
your own comfort and watching a
performer embrace that and really
channel that through their performance
based on their own comfort ability is
amazing to see so I think with each
person it's different I think we
shouldn't criticize each other for
posting a sexy selfie or that sort of
thing especially when you're
incorporating that within your brand as
long as it's a reflection of yourself
and you're embracing it it won't
in my opinion come off the same way as
you know when they're probably deciding
this idea for the Billboard all right
what are we gonna do alright we'll get
the okay yeah
all right let's I've been in front of
plenty of photographers I've done plenty
of shows with producers that have made
me feel uncomfortable and that's a big
reason why I decided to start producing
my own show I'm not a female CEO but the
nightlife industry in LA is
predominantly male and so to produce my
own show to make sure all my performers
are performing in the safe environment
is really fantastic and yeah it's sexy
as hell but we're embracing it you know
so I think as long as it's organic to
you and you're not doing it for likes or
just to sell your products like the
billboard
and you can't go too far as long as it's
like organic and real I think it also
goes back to um who your target audience
is so it depends who and why you're
building that brands the biggest point
being why you're building that brand and
who who you want to address within that
and what your mission is is and like
where is that line of sexy to achieve
your mission in an authentic way yeah I
think that that's a really important
thing to consider and I would say to
along with your audience is who you are
right you what and and that's true about
all brands they're sort of entities unto
themselves but it all starts with what
you care about what your values are and
then how they're going to relate to the
external world so start here first it's
a question that I'm asked a lot and have
been recently so I'm very interested to
sort of get all of your take on it but
is back to the percentage I think it's
thirty six percent of executives female
executives within this industry and I
wanted to know why each of you thought
that that is the case obviously we know
this is a new industry and more
inclusive but I wanted to because I
think you all come from such individual
places that it'd be interesting to to
ask why you think this is the case and
let's just say that number has gone down
to 27 percent right now personally I
think there's a couple of things in play
there I think that in the cannabis space
right now there's a lower barrier to
entry you know everyone knows the
difficulty was regulation and license
and all those things but on my side as
an ancillary business there's a lower
barrier to entry there's not a lot of
older legacy but companies that have
been around so there was more open space
for me to be able to build a brand there
and so that was very beneficial and and
helped me want to get into the space I
think that because you know the the
industry and some ways is new there is a
lot more opportunity for females to jump
in and start their own companies in the
space but I think that if you look at
the numbers it also says that
you know a lot more of the females are
on the side that don't need regulation
so we're doing consulting we're doing
ancillary side businesses we're not as
much on the on the plant side or on the
dispensary owners side which is why I
think that those numbers can be
misleading at some times I really agree
with that I think that the numbers are
misleading in a lot of ways I know in
Canada and for example there's one
publicly traded LP founded by a woman
that's it and I think that the number is
decreasing quickly ten percent that's a
huge decrease and I think that that's
happening because we're separating
ourselves in some capacities I don't
mean we as in women I just mean in
society we all of us men and women are
separating ourselves and not working
towards the same common goal and also
women in these positions we do
experience a lot more challenges than
say a man would because it is a boys
club and so often and when you come up
against those challenges you make a
choice you either exit or you continue
moving forward and you figure out how
you're gonna move forward and sometimes
you have to sacrifice and in fact not
sometimes you do have to sacrifice more
than your male counterparts and that's
challenging and it actually also and
there's a statistic that showed that men
are based on their potential and women
are based on their performance so you
have to continuously day in and day out
outperform your male counterpart and
that's tough as shit in this industry
right now because this industry is
moving so quickly it has so much capital
behind it and so to be able to compete
under those conditions are difficult and
so I you know if of course some people
are not going to want to keep up with
that rap race and there's no no harm in
that at all and but I think that it's
going to get to a space where women do
have more of that funding that we're
going to be able to see more women in
that seat and we're not we this is not a
great thing I think that it's and like
I'm not for this it's just something
that I'm observing that a lot of that
funding is going to come from men
because they're currently holding those
funding because
and so until we start working together
and start dispersing those funds into
more female CEO hands we're not going to
see that change happen and that's going
to take some time and but but it's going
to happen and I'd like to add just one
thing I alluded to before which I think
this is a super historic moment in time
never has there been such a new industry
with the potential of this industry that
is come along when women are super
educated have the business acumen of a
couple of generations now and have the
financial wherewithal to participate so
if we can marshal all of those resources
and take advantage of this right now
think it's a huge opportunity hello
thank you for this panel I think this is
great for all of us to hear especially
as a man who works in female centric
industries I own a birth center and work
a lot with midwives so I came into Los
Angeles making sure that my entire staff
management wise was all female because
I'm not trying to attract men with girls
and booty shorts but we're also trying
to try trying to educate men on how to
transition their business from a
male-dominated one to a female centric
one whether you're just trying to
attract that marketers trying to have a
more balanced so I'd like to hear how
can males from this kind of standpoint
and in a male centric how can they
transition better into having female
centric kind of demographics being
attract and not look disingenuous by
having I mean I allow my staff to dress
any way they want some of them dress you
know in a in a way that may that might
reflect on me negatively saying that I'm
telling them to dress this way even
though that's the way they want to be
and I'm trying to allow them to express
themselves in the way they want to
collect tips in the way that they want
to attract business in the way they want
to and also come from a place of
Education but we're talking about it
being a male centric so how do males
transition better and really empower if
they have that ability to empower anyone
to come up into this and show a better
kind of
a better marketing tool that isn't just
looked at as disingenuous to say it's
just about sex I think it's about being
true to your brand and to yourself and
to your vision and then inspiring your
people to join you on that journey and
defining what it is that's my thought I
would you came back up okay go on I
would say you know to make sure that
your you said that your staff is mostly
female but as you're talking about the
advertising play that you're going out
and when you're doing your pamphlets and
leaflets and everything that's going to
touch that public facing that you have
women sitting at the table with you on
on those things being able to have those
conversations because there's some
things that are that you'll read that
are different than how I'll read it how
I read it has a mother how I read it as
a woman and you do I completely agree
that you want to avoid the idea of
tokenism or you know throwing those
little bits out without having a full
well-rounded idea of being a female
focused business so I would just say
make as many females welcome at that
table and listen to them when they talk
that's the key yeah and I think it's an
important to mention that not all women
have the same perspective um and have
the same perspective and like let's not
divide ourselves further like what you
were saying like it's really
conversation to conversation like don't
be afraid to ask questions I find so
many people fearful of asking me about
Birla's because they're ignorant to it
and they're like shy about it and so
with anything like I feel like as long
as you have a conversation with open
ears and dialogue about it it will only
benefit in general when I came to Los
Angeles my patient base was 19% female
we're currently at 63% which i think is
a completely different switch than most
dispensaries not only in California but
in the nation because I was a track I
was trying to attract that demographic
cuz I felt they were underserved feel
like there wasn't a safe place for them
to go to feel like their needs were
being met
and so because I come from another
industry that is so female-centric it
was like well I really wanted to embody
as much of that as possible but as you
try to go outward of just my four little
walls and try to give like you know I
they do all the marketing I mean my
management staff does all the marketing
they do all the graphic design stuff we
decide as a group but it's mostly like
they have as much veto power as I do
over what we have for marketing you can
tell that they've pushed more towards a
medical model now that isn't necessarily
attracting this kind of newer
recreational user it seems like its
attracting kind of an older demographic
because that's where they think it's the
most respectable way to come from a
female to say this is what they want but
we're also trying to bridge past this
okay females aren't just about just
about fashion they have needs of
Education they have needs of kind of
like so there's all these diverse needs
and even trying to get the females
inside of my own business to say well
sometimes we do need to attract the
fashion side of things sometimes we need
to draw outside of just this medical
model so that we don't look disingenuous
as a female run business so that's kind
of the balance I was trying to create
all right so we're just at a time so
what we're gonna do is the panelists
we're gonna first we're gonna ask you to
go onto the brittania deck after this so
if you have more questions for specific
people they'll be out there I want to
point out that at 3 o'clock is an
awesome panel on cannabis and fitness
with real luminaries you're gonna want
to see it
and I just want to thank our panel for
their incredible insights and for being
so awesome and for you for participating
the way you did thank you everybody
[Applause]
[Music]