it was just like with nitro pack right
everybody says nitro pack I I get a guy
flying to talk to me and so because
Humble Connie's Big Timber region
there's a company called Simpson timber
their massive timber company a
multi-state timber company so the owner
that the timber company comes to me to
get cannabis info so that he can
understand what's house cannabis gonna
affect my world so I chop it up with him
and then he brings in people from other
industries to talk to me but he brought
a guy in that dries all the lumber for
like Pacific lumber in Louisiana Pacific
and I'm talking with with talking lumber
fire us worth the lump but he does like
Purina dog food and so we're having a
conversation he goes when's the last
time you opened a bag of dog food and
saw mold on it and I said never and he
goes that's because we dry it you see
any nitrogen in that shit and I was like
no when he goes because you don't need
it
he said nitrogen is for people who don't
know how to stabilize product he said
from professional dryers from people who
are drying global level drying as an
industry you're not drying it right you
said it's stabilization bringing the
levels down and for me doing outdoor
biologicals has a higher hold ability so
when I do pro bio pot outside I have
less of an oxidization degradation than
I do if I run chemical so if you're
doing outdoor organics it seems to hold
longer as a comparative where I get less
oxidization and so if a variety is
moving like crazy not as important but
if you got to sit on that stuff for a
minute and it starts to gold at all
you're dropping dollar value and so
people say well your nitro packet
buttman nitro packing adds complexity
and money and as soon as you crack it
the degradation after nitro is fast and
so I'm talking to this guy that owns
this massive company from the East Coast
the Carolinas and so he flies out to
chop it up because he and I were trying
to come up with modular drying chambers
that we can set it farms in the hills so
that the farmer could control the drying
of the product and then people use the
word curing the curing is actually a
process and it's not just holding it
it's actually a process of holding at a
specific temperature and dropping the
humidity by 15 points over a multi-month
period and so with that multi-month
period on a computer Grady
is what allows this product to actually
stabilize and sustain for time and so
the you would be able to take the
product rough bucket put it into your
drying chambers we were looking at
solarization so that we didn't have to
you because he can't use Jenny's up in
the hill a lot of these farms don't have
grid power and so I said look if we
could come up with containers that were
sealed that were climactically stable
and then we could have solarization now
we could deliver them the farmer could
now use this to hold the product because
I worried about the farm is sending
their product all the people to work
with so you had a lot of these giant
manufacturing facilities that are like
hey give us your product and we'll do it
and I'm like these guys can't even roll
weed like I'm straight up they came in
roll weed and I'm like you and it
doesn't define you but it sure gives me
a pretty goddamn good clue of how much
pot you've touched and so when you can't
handle it at the consumption level how
are you supposed to handle it at the
production level and so I'm like I
wouldn't let you do it and so I realized
there was a need for farmers to have an
ability to hold their varietals and hand
themselves but not use antiquated
technology and then to have HEPA filter
scrubbers so that you didn't have
pathogenic issues while you're holding
it and then once the facility had the
ability to do your processing because an
humble most of the farms are off-site
processing how do you take the product
now and then you just put it on they
wanted to do buildings and I said it
won't work you'll have to move it too
many times put it into a container that
they can then haul onto the back of a
truck and bring the truck back down the
hill drop the container at the facility
it sits in Lots under metal tag like you
do with you when you're shipping
overseas and that way it's been sealed
that's been sealed
it's Solarize you have digital gauges on
the outside that you can check the
maintenance so you know the climactic
situation inside this way when they're
ready to do the actual processing of it
from that point forward they can then
crack it and what you have is really
high quality product ready to use and
that is where we were working on it but
it's trying to get the price points
right because as the margins keep
dropping in cannabis everybody who came
into cannabis had a price point of it's
going to be 2,000 a pound then the next
group comes in it's going to be 1,400 a
pound
and then and and now these guys are like
look I told you I was gonna give you 14
for your outdoor and I need to give you
seven and so all of a sudden I'm like
wait a minute if you have to drop the
number by half you guys are gonna go out
of business in a minute and I wouldn't
want to give you any of my weed I don't
want you to touch any of my products if
you're going to go out of business
because what's my product gonna go and
so a lot of this is I'm working on all
this R&amp;D with all these companies to
mess around but it's a matter of getting
some stabilization to occur in the
industry so that you have companies
they're actually going to be here in a
year because half these cats I see how
gonna be here in two months and
especially with legalization coming in
we're like careful State come in they're
gonna scrub you right out and so the
problem is on these processing
facilities I think if all that materials
there and they come in they're not going
to shut you down and let you move the
product they're gonna shut you down and
seize the product and so that's
something I couldn't recommend to a
farmer because otherwise what you're
doing is you Center them down the road
to get screwed and it's it's a lot of
this stuff on on how do you get the
end-user to be able to get those price
points to where cured cannabis would be
at these upper echelon whether it's
indoor or outdoor bio or or chemical all
of them can deliver ultra high quality
product there's no question we can get
high quality for many different
methodologies but it's all the secondary
production how was it processed and and
how did you stabilize it those are some
of the next issues that you deal with
and that's not part of what I'm working
with is just what I'm working with with
companies that are coming in saying hey
can you help us mess with this and try
to figure out what do we do because I
need the farmers that I'm involved with
to be able to have the crop grow it out
have a known destination but have an
ability to hold it on their own property
safely until it gets trucked out yes
until the disturbed get rid of it
because like I said all these guys are
popping up and popping out and I watched
a couple distributors come through last
year when someone's the company was
doing this one I want to mention their
name man they ripped the number of
people off and I mean it was nutty where
the rivers of cats got robbed and then
all these cats come to me and they're
like what's my recourse and I'm like
well you don't really have a legal
recourse because they've already dumped
the company in there out here you want
recourse you have his old
recourse and I can't recommend that
really unless we're whispering in your
ear so it's problematic because most
people aren't from the old day and so
they don't see it the same way and you
wouldn't recommend that anybody new
because that's something that they're
completely uninvolved in and unaware of
hata yeah and you can't make any
mistakes and you can't put yourself in
these terrible positions and so
basically you just get screwed and I'm
watching guys getting peeled for two
hundred pounds at a time you know that
the the extractor was supposed to take
it boom extractor disappears all the
stuffs going extract this business is
out of here home he's moved out of the
area a new company picked it up and the
new company says we're not picking up
any of the debt we've washed the debt
wears on my product we don't know but we
wash the debt and it's exhausting you
know and so a lot of it is trying to
find cats you can work with and trying
to figure out how do you work because if
we work in capacity and some in
sometimes tight sometimes loose but it
lets us have an ability to continue
going forward because once you really
start to see the level that's coming
it's going to be mind-bending and when
they come in and start to whack this I
want to make sure that there's pieces
that existing appellations are existing
regions la has regions that are existing
that an own spots of production people
that are known for production
proprietary methodologies strains
selection and secondary post production
handling processing all that stuff has
value because nobody's just going to
come in and just take it over it's just
that they're going to come in and
they're going to come at you with
aggressive pricing and then lot egde and
so we'll start to see it with genomics
where if we don't develop things that
work for us then they'll develop things
that work in Kansas and Nebraska and
they'll be able to grow cannabis in
those regions that have high heat and
high humidity because they'll find the
cultivars at work and then they'll be
able to use other terpene methodologies
to enhance this for all the edible
markets for the for the pen markets and
um suddenly our markets getting
truncated and minimized and for me I'm
just like I just brawl it out right now
as hard as I can and run as hard as I
can and I just don't make any mistakes
by teaming up with anybody that's shady
and anybody that's like you know we got
big money I'm like you got big problems
because in our world
we never just threw money at problems
like that I've never seen money wasted
so much it's crazy but I'm like how did
you make this much money if you were
this stupid and it blows mind that's
lucky and I'm like it it's real because
you weren't you were brilliant in a
field but now you're taking it's called
I was I was a salvage diver for a while
right so I said do underwater
construction and you don't take data
from one table and extrapolate it to
another because you yes your residual
nitrogen's aren't the same and so all of
a sudden you start to find out you're
gonna die underwater because you took
data from one thing and applied it to
another you don't have to do that in Nix
gaslighted so I look at this and I'm let
me get this straight
you did something here and you're gonna
apply it there and it's gonna be the
same that's crazy and we've seen it
every day and I'm almost grateful to
some respects because it allows some of
us to realize don't do that and run as
fast as you can but at the same time the
money's so attractive to people who are
desperate that they believe that these
guys with money are going to solve the
problem is these big new super
distributors with all these massive
facilities are gonna solve your problems
I'm like these guys only got four stores
they're moving to how the hell are gonna
move 11 metric tons a week to four
stores and I got people that actually
say this to me I got seven acres outside
like what are you gonna do with it I got
a store that's a good store do you have
because it better be the best store I'm
playing an earth because you know
because nobody's moving nobody's moving
a hundred thousand nobody's moving a
hundred thousand miles and they have a
flower market not distillate market
because in their mind they're you know
and I'm just like I thought catching
this that this is very directed and and
you and you have to utilize individuals
that have careers in cannabis because we
understand market yeah we understand
what people want to buy and we
understand that people are fickle and if
you don't have product twice they find a
new dealer
so they'll they'll come to you once
you're gonna any fly now I'm out right
now all right I'll hit you again they
hit you twice I'm out they're going
somewhere else and if that person
satisfies the deal and doesn't good you
coming back you got to go and
reestablish your whole distribution base
and that's something I don't want to do
you know so what I'm what I'm doing now
is just doing some travel and and I'm
getting to meet people there in similar
situations where we're all trying to
chew our way through the system and our
teeth are worn flat because we've been
chewing on it for so long already if you
have shiny sharp teeth
you're too new I want to see a broken
tooth I want to see a couple of broken
what I mean the chipped one where you
fell on the ground and got kneed that
lets me know that you at least
understand the ups and downs and then
what it does it puts you in a more
cautious position to where you're not
gonna run headlong right into failure
and then it lets us work with people
that are similar Minds you know and then
we have new facilities that are coming
online and it just lets us say listen
these are the things you need to be
aware of and if you want to mess with me
mess with me and if you don't don't
I'm building a whole new facility but
it's not I'm getting into cannabis for
the first time in my own goddamn life
all I'm doing is creating new
methodologies so that I can keep up with
the pace of technology so that as it's
moving it's just that my lawyer always
says be the leading edge not the
bleeding edge and so I I touch as much
tech as I can I touch as much scientific
shit as I can and because I got the
message so many different University
people and I do projects with
universities on an intellectual sharing
level it allows me for them to say hey
this is what we see this is where the
problems are and then it lets me get
awareness I wouldn't get you know and it
just helps it helps educate and I need
it because otherwise I'm only as good as
I am and I don't and I don't think I
know the whole industry I'm not a master
of distally that's not where I spent my
time