[Music]
so I'll do a quick history thing here
all right really really it starts with a
gentleman named EJ gold back in the 70s
he had the ISO two that he sold in high
times and that was only in there for a
brief time because the DEA came after
him and shut him down because he was
openly promoting it as a cannabis
extractor he was also promoting it for
extracting hallucinogenic cactuses and
so they didn't take kindly to that so
after the ISO 2 was gone in the mid 70s
there was like a 20-year gap and then in
the mid 90s I started getting into
herbal extraction we came out with our
coldfinger units and a friend of mine
lathe adat he talked me into starting
eating labs and he he started selling
our cold fingers and high times but we
consulted lawyers and they said you
cannot advertise it to do anything
illegal in fact you need to have a
disclaimer so we came up with a
tongue-in-cheek marketing campaign where
the top of the ad said warning not to be
used for your legal purposes which it
was kind of a tongue-in-cheek way of
saying you can make hash oil with this
thing and they sold like crazy and high
times and that's kind of where it
started with our little cold fingers and
then we just started making them bigger
after that all right so the whole idea
the cold finger was in 1995 there you
couldn't really buy an herbal extract or
the only thing available was the sock
slit which is you know an analytical
tool a distiller extractor and I looked
at the design and I didn't like it
because you had to force these vapors up
this tiny tube to get on this condenser
way up here and it took too much heat so
I came up with a cold finger which had
the condenser and the basket inverted
right above you know where you're
boiling the solvent and then I could I
could get a distillation cycle going
without even boiling solvent or vacuum
and that's why that's what started it
then I had a chemist friend he said well
if you're gonna get in the extractor
business you have to get into co2 that's
where everything's headed so within two
years we had a very rudimentary co2 unit
which I used at one of the very first
dispensaries in San Francisco and like
97 and it just kind of went from there
and by the time everything's started to
take off then we had waters on the scene
and that was that was my first
competitor my good friend Shawn okay
thanks so I remember moving towards the
co2 extraction side of the business not
from the ethanol or anything and from
that side what we've done is we had a an
automated instrument that would allow me
to take the extracted vessel and change
temperature and change pressure on the
fly through programmability and having
something called a flow meter which
allow me to know not only the pressure
and the dense pressure and temperature
but would give me a density reading and
I could tie that density reading right
back to the pump so rather than just
pumping it you know some indiscriminant
pressure and temperature I could
actually say I want to be at 100 milli I
own one to be under grams per minute of
co2 at this certain pressure and
temperature and so I could start to to
now start up at subcritical and take off
the terpenes and then I could collect
the terpenes while it's still running
and then move it up to you know to you
know 2,000 psi and in 35 degrees so now
I could change that and I could take off
the cannabinoids and then on the
backside we were able to have three
collectors and at that time
Eden only had the one collector and at
the time so then I could I could collect
three different things and I remember in
Denver Fritz coming over and saying and
since I just kind of look in the system
I said ah I'll tell you all about the
system and so we went through and
probably was a half-hour 45 minutes and
Fritz looked at me says I was gonna make
one of these and people said they would
never buy one so and from there what we
were able to do is
the early days it was moving from 2,000
psi and maybe 15 hours down to 90
minutes and from that time other people
took up the challenge and now 5000 psi
and how many grams per minute can you go
it's a lot faster enough and everyone
moved up in inline well I mean we do all
kinds of different ranges now I mean we
can we've gone up to 15,000 psi that has
no bearing on cannabis but other things
like astaxanthin and nicotine are best
done at super high pressure and then you
have the fractionating separators that
he was talking about but so astaxanthin
is what makes shrimp pink and crab and
lobsters red it's a it's like a red
compound and usually it's extracted from
algae and that's that's it's algae that
gets eaten by smaller animals and then
it gets eaten by the shrimp and the crab
and but it's it's it's it's like a
really powerful antioxidants especially
good for your eyes I've talked to a lot
of people whose vision has come back to
normal form using astaxanthin it's kind
of considered a superfood right yeah
there's yep so they're there growing
this algae and pools and then drying it
and co2 extracting it yeah Hawaii and
Israel makes a lot of astaxanthin they
kind of dominate the market the market
is expanding I used an analogy last year
when I was here at this convention
speaking with a see that you know the
cannabis industry is last year kind of
gone from kindergarten to junior high
and now we're in our like awkward
adolescent about to graduate from high
school phase right as far as the tech of
it goes and you know now that we've
gained more legitimacy you know John
John was crazy because he had a
corporate gig and they were one of the
first companies that really were
reputable and from the pharmaceutical
industry to say hey there's something
here we're gonna we're gonna get you
know our funny PhD and then push this
stuff to these guys do we make a lot of
money off of them but you know as far as
like cannabis companies having access to
hire people of John Prince's caliber we
didn't have that until a few years ago
and so you know what you did is you had
is the advent of the internet directly
correlates with the explosion of
cannabis tech and the fact that in
California we had such a large
marketplace with an abundant access to
cheap material for people to experiment
on really allowed people to proliferate
different times of different types of
technology and then as it got regulated
now we can poach people that are
intelligent that you know have spent
years getting a scientific background
that aren't gonna go to federal prison
now to go work for a cannabis company
and so I think you know what while co2
was was it was a safer option because we
lived in a quasi gray zone right so I
had a company with 55 employees at the
time that I bought my first watters
machine that was in a major commercial
thoroughfare of Scotts Valley City and
you know we had the police department
through and the fire department through
but we had no we had no permit no
license and so you know can doing butane
extraction or ethanol extraction was a
whole dicey ER game right now and I
think that that's been one thing where
you know recently it's not that co2 is
out of out of popularity anymore it's
that people are feeling more comfortable
doing alternate forms of solvents than
they used to and though there always be
a place for co2 100 percent just like
there's always going to be a place for
hydrocarbon and ethanol they all provide
different value and can help create
products either easier a different array
of products for the combustible
marketplace you know for a combustible
product like crumble which has waxes and
paraffins in it using a light aroma
aromatic hydrocarbon is a lot easier to
get that texture than using co2 or
something that revolves high amounts of
pressure you know co2 and ethanol are
equally good at extracting a crude oil
that is going to be used for
distillation but you know the the light
aromatic hydrocarbons usually are lend
themselves towards a product that
doesn't require a lot of further
refinement where as you know ethanol or
co2 are gonna be terrific but oftentimes
to get a consumer product you're gonna
need to do a little bit more refinement
of those products yeah I would say that
it's anytime I'm talking with the
customers more on the side of what are
they trying to make so you start off
with what you're trying to make and then
you back up to the ingredients and how
you need those ingredients to be able to
be able to match that form
elation for a certain medical situation
so for example if I was to use some of
the lighter hydrocarbons and I would be
using propane
I might even choose propane over butane
because it's a lighter product and it's
and it's a more pure also the other one
is tetrafluoroethylene so people call
that freon it's not freon but it's
that's a trade name but having something
that's light like that is also not gonna
it's gonna lead the waxes behind like
propane it'll have less of the explosive
it won't explode because it's freon use
it in refrigerator and then as I'm
moving forward towards some of the other
organic once it's it's co2 plus s and
all its co2 plus propane it's it's a
mixture the hybrids we're in the early
days with all the regulations and stuff
no one was doing in the experience now
you're starting to bring in the people
that have the years of experience of
what you can do with the plant and how
the variety changes with each one of
those components I mean how do you make
sure the watt what's the percentage of
waters at five percent eight percent is
the particle size a certain particle
size for different things and so each
one of those and now you're starting to
see the non extraction so I would call
it concentration it's a big picture and
then you have separation versus
extraction extraction is liquid liquid
like making coffee when you pick apples
that's a separation you're not actually
doing it you're not actually extracting
the apples from the tree so if you're
making what some people would say bubble
hash I would say you're you're able to
have a trichome that's cold and you
would take it off and then if you have
the ones that are the the pure trichomes
or the different sizes and then you
might have something that starts off at
25% but when you take off those
beautiful trichomes and you keep them
intact that's a whole different product
and now you're still left with you know
ten twelve percent of something you can
extract another way so you're you're
actually taking different parts in doing
hybrids so I see companies now with with
three you know cold ethanol at Mightiest
60 degrees or minus 40 degrees and then
you see a couple of co2
a couple of propane's you see a couple
of tetra fluoro ethane x' and you'll see
a mixture of everyone because they're
big enough now they're making different
products starting off with a formulation
I kind of feel like I'm on a panel with
two of my ex-girlfriends too so intimate
with the machinery you peddled over the
years you know I think Fritz what one
things kind of cheating for me is you
know back in the 70s and 80s you know
you were doing herbal plant extraction
but what led you to that point and what
were you using it for back then well I
mean it basically started from two
things number one I had a girlfriend
that worked at a health food store and
we got really into herbs and then the
other thing was you know my actual
degree is being a science journalist or
a science writer and I've I've had some
articles published and I did one about
shaman pharmaceuticals do you remember
that Dennis McKenna and all that I was
so fascinated by that that I had to have
an herbal extractor and then I couldn't
find one to buy so I made my own like
Here I am today but I I mean I guess I
kind of owe that to Dennis McKenna to a
large degree with shaman pharmaceuticals
was such a fascinating concept and the
concept in a nutshell was this company
would send researchers into the
rainforest if they found a shaman from
to two different shamans from two
different tribes that used the same herb
for the same thing they brought it back
to the lab and studied it and tried to
make a product out of it and two of the
people involved with that was Dennis
mccannon and dr. John Pierce oh I think
he's in cannabis now and he goes by the
handle dr. Jay I don't know if anybody
knows him but anyway they were like
early guys with shaman pharmaceuticals
and I got to know them and and you know
one thing led to another and Here I am
where do you guys see the industry
especially on the extraction tech side
of things five years from now any
predictions or any trends that you see
that are playing out that people might
not be aware of well I think it's going
to be driven by corporatization I mean
it's inevitable and it happens to every
industry so it it seems like at some
point there's going to be giant co2
extractors like the hops and
she has that you know that will we'll
probably make like an okay product but
it'll be super large-scale so it'll be
like the equivalent of Budweiser or
something like that and then they'll but
they'll still be the micro brews the the
smaller boutique operations that make
the higher quality product whether it's
with co2 or ethanol or hydrocarbons I
mean they're all valid they all work and
they all have their place but you know I
think you're gonna see the giant
factories and you know led by GW I guess
I don't know so on the on the on the
things that are are unique I think
you're gonna start to move towards more
of the of the hybrids so in my world I
think it's a hybrid that when I have a
product that has rich and trichomes
and I knock off most of the trichomes
and now I'm left so I start off at 25 or
35 percent and I have THC ve or I have
some of the unique ones not just the THC
and then from there that that's a
separation so now you've concentrated
something and then from that concentrate
you can start to make unique products
where you can now do an extraction and
pull off things that you want when you
want them and how you want them so for
example I have people that I work with
that I'm pulling off the monoterpenes
and then I'll pull off the sesqui
terpenes and then I'll pull off the
diterpene so that I can pull them off
when I want them and what I want so I
don't have to do any a whole lot of
post-processing I'm doing it during the
extraction process the other part that
that we've seen
I know if Fritz and I have seen is that
when people were doing the extraction in
the early days they were just flowing
3oz co2 around and around because it was
a closed system what I found more more
recently is if I'm doing a static where
I like making a cup of tea I can hold
the pressure at a certain point let it
soak there like a cup of tea then moved
to flow through again and pour that
often so rather than the old days with
the where they would decarboxylate
before because they felt that it was the
more greater solubility I can now take I
at them can now take that soak and have
the same
ratio of the acids and the neutrals that
come off so now you can cut the time by
a quarter or a tenth of the time and so
then you can decarboxylate afterwards
the other one I see is moving towards a
separation with with either Sonic so
hybrid of you know altro sonic assisted
microwave-assisted and then some of the
new water technology where you can I can
actually it they them can actually
modulate the pressure of the water to
knock off the trichomes and knock and
knock open the trichomes like an
eggshell but leads a plant cell intact
and so now what you're doing is you're
modulating the pressure of a separation
to be able to do thinking with water so
you're not doing in extraction you're
actually doing a separation then you
then you separate the biomass from the
water and the oil by just centrifugation
so you can see use a decanter horizontal
centrifugation spins around the outside
and now you're left with the water and
the oil then you go through a vertical
centrifuge at 6g and now you now you
move the water from the oil so we're not
what you've done is a two-step process
like the oil industry or like the food
industry or like the dairy industry
where you're able to separate the waxes
from everything without doing an
extraction so it's more of separation
and back to the other point of as far as
which one you choose it's formulations
to be specific so I deal in analogies
because that's how I think and so if I'm
making a yellow cake that's very
different from making an angel food cake
when I'm making a yellow cake I can just
crack open the eggs into one bowl put in
sugar put in flour and now I make it a
yellow cake if I make an angel food cake
I got to keep the yolks away from the
egg white because I have to have the egg
white and I have to make that fluffy so
I have to separate the egg whites from
the yolks oh that's that's like co2
where you're modulating or like anything
else you can modulate propane by the way
you can people are saying oh I just have
one thing know you can modulate propane
because they're all super critical fluid
extraction so I see the the world coming
to
formulation specific like Fritz says
there's one thousand two hundred and
fifty you know leader vessels doing co2
in two hours down in Kentucky
I mean that's that's that's a whole
different process and so to say the
third one and that is in line so like
Fritz and I have done for years and that
is you do the co2 and in a multiple
fraction you pull out the waxes in the
first collection vessel then you have a
separate vessel that then cleans up any
remaining waxes before it goes over to
the second third now by the time you get
to the second and third vessel you don't
have any waxes so now what you're doing
is in-line dewaxing that creating
cannabinoids from yeast it's threatening
it's a menace
but yeah it's coming for sure
everybody's wondering about that so
there's patents out there and and the
one kind of Florida the ones out of the
UK also so that's called biopharma and
we've been doing that for years where we
we don't actually need the plant to be
able to make things an example of that
was um tax all so tax all used to be
taken from you trees we would cut down
these yew trees from small amount of tax
all that was used for breast cancer and
we were taking down forests and so what
they did is they found a way of making
synthetic tax all and that's why you
have all these things breast cancer the
other one with yeast is that you can
make one specific cannabinol based on
having the starting material see BGA or
some of the precursors for that and then
you make th CA synthase and that makes
THC a you have CBD a synthase you have
THC v synthase for something that goes
before that so it's just a matter of
doing that yeast so you're making one
specific thing so Albany molecular
research up in Albany New York and with
some of the other people has like 20 or
30 of these things going but that's how
you would do biopharm but but you're not
gonna you're never gonna have what the
plant makes for partial spectrum or
whole spectrum you're not going to have
that it's going to be a single component
that's used for an additive or it's
gonna be something else but it can never
have the same capability as the whole
plant do is be input material for a lot
of edible products and teachers and
topicals right like
it's it's threatening to a degree from
just a whole holistic traction
standpoint but I don't think it's not
it's not disruptive it's not wiping out
the commercial extraction market people
aren't going to want to you know light
up a dab torch full of some synthetic TV
anytime soon or it's not going to be as
as enjoyable of a consume of consumable
experience right as as a high-grade
extraction but yeah it'll be interesting
to see as if it comes and you know
ultimately if with all these taxes that
we're facing in California if it brings
the price down on some products it might
be a good thing I think I would want to
know if I'm consuming cannabinoids that
are grown from you so let's maybe get
some new packaging regulation around
[Music]
you