[Music]
so today just a little brief background
what's up here is a little bit about the
endoc canabo system and what you realize
is we don't know much about it it's only
been discovered in the early 90s we know
very little and there's more and more
that we learn every single day so that
was part of the calculation it's a
fascinating biological World it keeps
getting broader and more and more
interesting as we learn more about it
its key function is to regulate the
body's balance so you hear the word
homeostasis or a system of balance and
really that's what the endoc canabo
system does it's a series of receptors
and molecules that are activated for
mood regulation sleep regulation pain
regulation inflammation and it was this
critical part of the body that was never
taught to anyone in medical school and
still isn't today so it's uh quite
amazing and fascinating as a scientist
that you're thinking about the Forefront
of how to regulate the body's key
functions and you hear all of these
ailments that can be treated with
cannabis and you wonder why it's because
that endoc canono system is so critical
to what the body does so it's just know
that it is regulating your equilibrium
and you're trying to find the right
mixture of cannabis products for
yourself to balance yourself
out so um I like this Slide the most
because you'll see all the possible
ailments that are on there around the
circle and you'll see things like
anti-cancer anti-inflammatory bone
growth and what you'll notice about the
circle is THC is not in there so that's
probably most interesting is that all we
hear about in the media and everyone has
talked about for a long time was
tetrahydro canaban or THC and it is
perhaps not the most interesting medical
molecule inside of cannabis and it
really is all of the molecules at once
that makes medical cannabis special as
opposed to a single molecule like
Marinol or just
CBD um so that is you know the reason
that we're all here today is if it was a
single molecule that could be effective
and it could be isolated and used as an
efficient therapeutic in a
pharmaceutical sense we wouldn't have
medical cannabis interest like that but
many patients speak of the whole plant
products as being Superior and really
understanding all of the molecules the
plant has to offer is what makes that
unique so it's very different when you
offer to the body here is a whole host
of molecules and this is your body's
choice to choose which ones it wants to
balance itself uh a good analogy is
probably if I have a piano in front of
me and I just pound on the c key a lot
that's kind of like hitting one receptor
with THC but when I say here is the
whole plan I can play chords I can play
really nice tones much more pleasing to
my ears and the body kind of feels the
same way when you offer all the
molecules at once from the plant so
understanding what's in the plant how
that's going to be effectively delivered
to the patients and which combinations
of those molecules are best of interest
to which patient population is kind of
the complexity of medical
cannabis so that was certainly what got
me interested and then I got to kind of
dig through all of these wonderful
molecules and what you'll see is there's
predominant ones called cannaboids that
we talk about mostly THC um but there's
a whole host of other ones there's tur
beans which are related to the smell and
the sensory perception of that and also
have physiological activity and then the
anti-inflammatories of the flavonoids as
[Music]
well and some people you know hemp is
just another version of cannabis it's
all cannabis so marijuana and hemp are
two different legal definitions and I
won't get into the details of that but
I'm happy to explain it to anybody it is
technically the same plant split in two
different legal Parts flowers are
marijuana stock stems and seeds are hemp
but the same plant kind of produces all
those beneficial molecules so hemp
products are very beneficial that means
you could get them from the Cannabis
products that you have on the store in a
medical sense
[Music]
too so what are cannaboids so synthetic
cannaboids are things like spice we hear
bad things about those we don't want to
talk about those phyto canabo are the
ones that the plant makes so what's up
there on the screen are the canabo acids
these are the actual molecules that the
plant
makes you'll hear more about THC and CBD
but those are processed canabo you have
to heat the plants natural molecules
before you form the neutral canono in
THC or
CBD the the way the plant does this is
it takes two precursors lolic acid and
janal pyrro phosphate stitches them
together to make CBG acid which is the
common intermediate uh that the plant
utilizes to make its other cannaboids so
it depends what the genetics are and how
they're expressed but it will start with
CBG acid and go either to THC acid or
CBD acid sometimes CBC acid but we don't
see much of that uh in any of the plants
out here today you may see trace of CBG
acid depending upon how many copies of
the enzymes are there to produce THC
acid or CBD acid so those are all
different cannaboid markers that we can
watch and there are people working on
developing High CBG strains so it's not
converted to THC or CBD and there is
also interesting medical benefits from
that as
well so how do we go from the cannaboid
acids to the neutral canab oids it's a
process of heat and I'm often asked
what's the right temperature
theoretically it happens at every
temperature it will happen at room
temperature it just take till after
you're dead so it's a really long period
of time so that's the smartass answer
sorry about that one but the um most
effective temperatures are typically
boiling water we'll have uh have this
transformation happen in about 12 to 24
hours depending on exactly how you do it
so if you're sautéing butter at home
double boiler is probably the best way
and longer is typically better than not
um that is the the technical definition
of the process is called
decarbox so cannaboids are what most
people talk about but in 2011 we started
testing for tpin um and those are the
other things that make each of the
unique plant differences out there so
what we saw was three different plant
varieties all had the exact same canabo
profile the same amount of THC and next
to nothing else yet they gave very
different physiological responses they
smelled very different
something else is here causing this to
happen what was that and those are what
chemists called tpin so when we started
it was entertaining to me other labs so
they're just trying to charge you for
another test there's nothing useful
there um today I think it's one of the
more popularized words they call it
turpy or turp sauce or crazy things
around the word tpin and what we're
recognizing is that these are important
for um the Entourage effect so what
makes medical cannabis special and
different are these molecules also going
with the cannabinoids that really help
everyone benefit from the medicinal
power of cannabis this is just an
example of one of the profiles that we
provide and it's kind of like a chemical
fingerprint so you can see if the bars
are longer or shorter on different ones
and you can start to look at a label and
understand what medicine is going to be
of most interest to you as a patient so
it's additional information for
caregivers to provide or for patients to
understand which version of cannabis is
right for me it's not just THC and it's
not just the most THC it's not just CBD
either so single molecule isolates are
very very different you want as much of
a whole plant in your product as you can
get in the end and tpin are a key part
of
that but they're very very complex the
word tpine represents 20,000 different
chemical molecules in the plant kingdom
plants use them to talk to each other
they use that to talk to their
environment and they often use it to
ward off p through predators so
sometimes they're irritants right so
some people create an allergy to
cannabis because the plant saying leave
me alone I'm just this helpless little
thing standing here in the environment
they're not making them for our benefits
but more for their own benefit to
survive and thrive in their own
environment we're fortunate enough to be
able to harness them and utilize them
tpin can be used in things like tape and
they can be as complex as taxa which is
a breast cancer medicine that comes from
a Pacific UT tree so it's a a vast world
of chemistry and it's very fascinating
what we know is a little bit about
single molecules by themselves so what I
wrote up here is you know Pine has a
pine odor it may be useful as a Bronco
dilator so that might open the Airways
for an asthmatic if they were to inhale
some of that it may also increase
absorption and up the intake of THC
through your lungs so what we don't know
very well is how these things all work
together so just because I have a little
linu that may be sedative does not mean
this brain that has a little linol will
put me to sleep there might be other
things that counteract that there might
be other things that really change that
we don't know what the whole complex
picture looks like so I do believe tpin
hold the future in terms of tailoring
medicine for patients and really helping
them understand what's going to be the
right product for them but we cannot
make marketing claims of that type today
if someone says I really know the secret
sauce to telling you everything that's
too far ahead that's the cart in front
of the horse and drives the scientist
crazy but makes the marketing people
happy so I'm definitely on the other
side of
that so what we were able to do is take
both canono and tpine data and look on a
vast survey of thousands of different
strains over were 2,000 in this data set
and really start to compare them by
their chemical fingerprint and what we
wanted to see was what was different
about them like what are the names what
is Inda and sativa and what really makes
sense so what we found out was THC was
not the differentiator there's THC in
everything and it it averaged out to be
about 16 so we're seeing unfortunately
some Labs say that there's 30 even 40%
THC in a plant that's not happening
that's a bad lab so or they're doing the
math funny or they're not doing things
in an ethical fashion and if you're
going to extract that you'll find out
the hard way that you never got anything
out of that and it's not useful to a
patient to just say here's a lot of THC
it's what's the right product for me is
that produced in the same fashion every
single time so we had witnessed people
changing a name in a dispensary or what
I feel is immoral and unethical is to
say to an insomniac this indicia strain
will make you go to sleep how can you
make that claim and how can you tell
that individual that when you have no
idea if it's going to work for them that
way they go home they try cannabis
they're awake till 5: in the morning
they say cannabis is not right for me
and they think that all strains are the
same and now that person who could find
great benefits is unfortunately misled
and misdirected and thinks that cannabis
doesn't work for them that was a big
problem for me and I think it's
something that we need to clarify so
what this data shows in a bigger picture
is that in a perfect world if all those
claims are right we'd see sativa hybrid
and indica what we see is this Continuum
and the smear and a bunch of stuff up on
the corner so all the colors together
here really indicate that you can't say
one Inda does this and a sativa does
that it really means each plants its own
unique version and that is a
morphological description of how long it
would take to do flowering or grow times
it's not indicative of what the medicine
is going to be like to that patient in
the
end um we took a smaller subset of that
with just five names at a time to try
and discern are there even tighter
groupings of those things and a small
study with Jack hair found at 30% of the
time it's misnamed but it's not even
Jack hair at all so it's a very distinct
chemical profile and you could see it
clearly in the data that it was misnamed
and abused and you'll see some of these
names cluster like harleyquinn because
it's so distinct and different but other
ones are are kind of all over the place
and you can't put much stock inside of
just the name you really have to know
who's doing it and
why the major tpine differentiators by
the way were terpinolene and Nal they
were the ones pulling Jack hair and
train wreck up to the top they prevent
in m and linol and lanine pulled things
to the right and this was a methodology
called principal component
analysis so what we saw with just four
names this was W Jack OG Kush and Sour
Diesel and we looked in California and
Washington that you see there is a
little bit of some of the clustering if
you look at it in 3D though you'll see
that it's kind of scattered and isn't
that great but what you'll notice was
something as popular as OG Kush it goes
across like the entire thing so who
knows which OG Kush you had so kush or
OG whatever good luck um you know it
maybe some person or some Cult of ours
are special to a certain dispensary that
might be something you can can rely on
but if you go to another state or you go
somewhere else and they say I have the
best OG cush around it's probably not
what you've seen here um and that is
important to a patient and to doctors
recommending those things so they know
what to consume and they can rely on
that right now we have no
standardization of the naming and really
what we need are producers or
cultivators if there are cultivators
here you can build a brand around
consistently producing the same product
every single time and putting your name
on your OG Kush so our effort would be
to authenticate that and validate that
you're doing that the same every time
you can then talk to doctors to
recommend that to certain types of
patients and we can kind of Advance the
ball down the field in terms of how we
can raise the level of play like and not
just call it whatever we want or a
flavor of the week it's not really going
to help anybody get to where we want to
go so there are there are an enormous
amount of product types that go along
with Canabis so what we've seen is
there's a a lot of different molecules
can be up to 200 that I've just talked
about in terms of tpin and cannabinoids
that you can see and then you have all
these product diversities so whether
it's just the flower material or if it
was some sort of trim that has very
different composition is it heat that
was pulled off of that and that
concentrations different or was it made
into an extract or a derivative product
for oral or sublingual use all of those
deliver different types of medicinal
benefits to different patients and you
have to understand what you're ingesting
in which manner to know if that's the
right medicine for
you so let's see so it's important to
understand how can this be variable or
the same so when you talk about
cultivation pushing that in the same
direction every single time you're
trying to control something natural and
wild its idea is to be diverse and not
consistent and uniform but it is doable
so controlling the temperature humidity
nutrient cycle lighting you know phase
of the moon we're not sure what they all
are but there are a lot of L of things
that go into making that reproducible
every single time and that is doable the
Dutch do it they've been doing it for
years it's just as a matter of
sophistication and paying attention to
the products that you produce when you
talk about an infused product it becomes
a little bit more different how is it
extracted what may or may not be left
behind was it fully DEC carboxilate or
not and what other you know molecules
might be present in the end extract or
are not present that were there from the
flower material that creates another
type of experience for the patients as
well so how am I consuming it is one how
is it made is another big one and anyone
looking to make products you just have
to keep doing the same thing every
single time so there are ways to
standardize your product and improve
your value and that's the best way to be
I'd say a provider of medicine to people
out here who would find benefits from it
don't change the formula don't do
something different once it works for
someone let them rely on that and then
you're going to be in far better shape
as a brand and the patients are going to
be better off too
so I've got um so which ways might you
consume that this is important for
doctors to understand and for patients
what's my consumption method flour
material and concentrates you can do via
you know combustion um vaporization is
becoming much much more popular the
vaporization is lower temperature less
destruction of certain molecules a
little bit more friendly to the airway
but it is the best way to ingest the the
molecules directly so it's kind of like
injecting them without having to go
through the needle process so you get
the right molecules in the bloodstream
directly sublingual does the same thing
it usually takes a couple extra minutes
but you'll get THC and CBD predominantly
in the bloodstream that way topicals not
so sure all of those are going through
the skin or if you're really getting a
good amount of that it may be more of a
surface action might help with
inflammation or arthritic types of pains
but it might not help you know head
pains depending upon what's going on
your concentration in the blood just
doesn't get that high oral Pro like
products though go through the liver
first so they go into the stomach
they're absorbed at different rates and
then the liver transforms that and makes
different molecules than just THC so it
actually makes the molecules that you
fail in your urine test if you're
driving um but that molecule that it
makes it's called 11 hydroxy THD is five
times more active at the canono 1
receptor it's a very different molecule
so even if I took the same amount in
inhaled or orally I could get two
drastically different responses I could
have two different side effects it's not
really THC that's doing the activity
when you take it orally nor CBD so
that's something the medical community
is not fully caught up on and a lot of
the research is not on those metabolites
unfortunately so but it's important that
if you're looking for what am I going to
get and how long is it going to last and
is this the right stuff for me that you
understand that there are some
differences and there's not one product
fits all for everyone it's a very
individualized thing
so we'll do so how the concentrate is
actually manufactured is a key part of
what goes on in terms of medical
cannabis products so you're seeing more
people say I have high Purity CBD or I
have high Purity THC well High Purity
THC is Marinol and we've already said
that that wasn't the best thing that we
want how do we keep it more like the
plan so there are a variety of like
extraction methods right dry sifting
water extraction for bubble has Co
hydrocarbon extractions ethanol
extractions all of those will form some
extract but all of those extracts are
very different and all of them have very
different compositions so most of the
time you've lost a lot of Turpin if I go
and winterize it where I add ethanol
make it cold filter that off and
evaporate the ethanol I've evaporated a
lot of tpin as well so I have no way of
controlling the product composition or
reproducibility of that it's just not
going to be the same every single time
I'm going to get some canabo base with a
little bit of fats or other stuff that
went with it it's going to be a very
different product than what you got off
the plant so there are people trying to
introduce tpin in different ways I think
that we'll see more and more of that uh
coming in the future but how you do that
which ones you have is it reproducible
and is it still safe to ingest I think
there still question marks that the
regulator is looking to catch up on but
we'll hopefully get broader diversity of
products out there and what we did was
we looked at concentrates in that same
fashion we did to all the strains and
you see that most of them are all the
same and really that's because they're
pretty much just the cannabinoids and
there's no tpin
left when you compare them with the
flowers you see that all the
concentrates are over here and the
flowers are over there so there's a
little bit of overlap and when you look
at it in 3D they're not on top of each
other but what that says is concentrate
products are a different type of product
than the flower product so the goal
should be how do I make the concentrate
products more like the flour products
and we're not we're not not seeing a
whole bunch of that just yet but I think
that that's that's coming this is an
important picture that you tells you I
don't want just any old concentrate I
want to really know what's the
composition of that concentrate it used
to be here is my goo don't you want to
buy it from me I'm sure there's a lot of
CBD or THC in there I think we're moving
past that we we certainly need to and
we're headed in a much better Direction
Where We could look at a broader scope
of molecules and understand this is what
a standardized product really is
um so in in terms of like understanding
for yourself as a patient if you're
providing for patients like how how was
this product formed what is the
homogeneity of that product in an edible
product so chocolate products are
excellent because it's easy to get the
THC distributed uniformly throughout it
if I have drink products or topical
products that are higher viscosities or
other types of products that don't mix
well like say cookie batter like do I
have a lump of my concentrated one part
did I cook it with the tray a little
crooked and now this brownie is twice as
thick as the other one making sure that
every single unit has the exact
concentration and has the exact same
size is going to be critical as
regulations come about so I did hear a
little bit the comment I don't like
regulation unfortunately I do um I would
say regulation is good in terms of
making sure we stay safe and within the
right bounds and give us clear
guidelines and rules to operate by if
they're too restrictive they're not good
if they don't exist then it's not good
as well cuz what we see today is a lot
of pesticide contaminations which no one
that's sick should be exposed to
unregulated products I can tell you that
with John's Hopkins researchers we
studied a broad diversity of infused
products 87% of them were not within the
label like spec that they put on the
product so you don't know what you're
getting 87% of the time when you orally
take this product thank God it doesn't
kill you but it's definitely not what
you're going to want and then it might
also not be that experience that someone
benefits from and therefore for they're
not going to be a cannabis consumer in
the future it's pretty simple to work
with a lab and have some tests to say
I'm on point my products are definitely
consistent how do I make sure I've got
the same concentration in all my
products that's going to be the way that
your brand succeeds today and I think
that's kind of the important thing for
entrepreneurs out here to
remember so in summary what the
profiling tells us was the whole idea of
indiga sativa hybrid telling you a
physiological effect is a misnomer it
does not work that way so what specific
plant and which composition causes these
reactions for which types of patients we
don't know yet today but that's the way
that we have to look about those so
we're hoping to start a new dialogue and
a new way of classifying those to really
make it much easier to understand and
don't rely too much on the name um but
you can trust your nose there are ways
to say I know that this smells the same
as it did the last time it looks visibly
the same color I didn't get the bait and
switch I'm more likely to have it this
one if it's the same profile and it's
just more or less then you just need to
take less or more so it's not bad to
have it at a different concentration as
long as it's the same composition um and
what that profiling tells us is tpin are
really
important so um and this is the the part
that no one likes to talk about but this
is why regulations are important how do
we understand what's not on the product
so cannabis doesn't kill people but some
of the stuff that may go along with it
actually could so it's important know
that that's not there and when you have
patients who are immuno compromised or
you know undergoing chemotherapy
treatments or exceptionally weak and
frail they cannot afford to be exposed
to pesticide contaminations it's just
not it's not in their interest and it's
not good for anybody um what we kind of
looked at in this picture is there's uh
stop work orders in Washington and
Colorado but back in 200 end of
2012 we did a small study with a
handheld pipe and a glass water pipe as
as well both with and without the
filters that you see there which are
coconut carbon and cotton and what we
determined was rather alarming that we
looked at these molecules that are known
pesticides or cultivating agents that
are put on the plant ones a plant growth
regulator up to 70% of what we put on
the plant could be introduced into the
Airways and into your lungs so if you
are you know combusting and inhaling a
product that has pesticides or plant
growth Regulators on it you're literally
injecting those things right into your
bloodstream so we don't set daily intake
limits on vegetables because you're
inhaling them we set them because you're
orally ingesting them so there's an
absorption and there's a toxicity limit
that goes with that we don't have those
for inhal inhalation products in
cannabis so that was why we did the
study to see how much you could be
exposed for what you're looking at
getting that way and how do we set
regulations about when these things
should be applied and how much should be
there so it's important science that
needs to be done before we understand
how we actually set the regulation
now that we know these kinds of things I
think more of The Regulators are saying
so how do I fix this problem what should
I or should I not allow on these
products and it is a matter of what am I
using the product for in the end and
which ones did I put on there
fortunately most of the Regulators are
going towards products that did not have
any intake limit thresholds things that
we've deemed exceptionally safe like
cinnamon oil or other types of natural
products that you don't have to worry
are you know harmful chemicals that
would be exposed to people so that's
starting to Trend in the right direction
but it's still going to be a little bit
longer I won't put a time frame on it
but it won't be tomorrow till that
problem's
fixed and our goal was absolutely like
how do I put this information on a label
how do I inform patients how do doctors
patient providers and patients
themselves get to understand what's in
their product so there's a variety of
different labels these two are flowers
and this one's an edible product but you
can see as as much information as we
could put put on there was was placed
there we modeled it after the
nutritional facts panel um we have one
of these on our website and you can
certainly download a large version and
it explains all the little components
and the different pieces that are there
but the goal is to Pro provide
information so with a label like that
you can say these are the top Turin I'm
used to seeing these are the product
types that are working for me no matter
what name you called it I still know
what I'm looking for as a
patient and
yeah for those of you who are really
sharp in looking at that label you'll
notice that it wasn't the simple sum to
say THC acid plus THC equals this amount
of Maximum THC available so it's um
based on molecular weight so you're
going to lose a CO2 molecule and THC
actually weighs less than THC acid so
there's a little algebraic equation that
I put up there it's pretty simple when
you think of it there's just 133% of the
weight is gone as CO2 so 100% THC acid
would be
87.7% THC and it's important to know if
you're a processor and you're looking to
say where' all my stuff go why did I
lose this weight it's supposed to you
know eliminate but it's important to
know how that math is done so that your
lab is giving you the right values that
you can look at and that you're kind of
comparing Apples to Apples when you're
looking at labels at a dispensary um so
I fortunately you can learn the math for
two molecules cuz CBD weighs exactly the
same so you only have to learn the math
once but it's um it it's pretty simple
and most of the labs should do that
right but we don't see them all do that
right so unfortunately you'll see other
labs just sum the numbers to make it
look larger that's to try and get the
marketing height behind that but it's
really not an accurate representation of
what you're going to get and won't lead
you to an accurate dose understanding or
dialogue with your
doctor
so um and really in general I hope I've
been impressed upon you that it's a very
complex world with cannabis I think
that's part of the fun and excitement of
it at least intellectually but it's part
of the challenge when you're a patient
trying to find the right product for you
or if you're a product producer or
patient provider how do I know which
products work for which patients we
really don't know today so I'd encourage
diversity and lots of different
creativity what product types that you
think are good what things you like to
see in them and really you know I I
would think that we're not going to hurt
ourselves with more product diversity
and it's about knowing that your
product's made consistently and that you
can educate about it and that's really
the the bottom line I think in the
end and and basically that's that's all
I have for tonight and thank you guys
very much for your
[Applause]
attention thank you so um I'm a lawyer
and I represent people who own
processing companies and whatnot up in
the state of Washington okay I've been
also asked to represent K in um
California the question I have is I I
don't entirely come from this sector but
I know that we're seeing almost um a
deregulation up in the state of wash
with um medical marijuana being
eliminated as its own class and it's now
being sold in the same place as the
recreation not yeah you're seeing a
transition where they're folding the two
systems together so medical will be
folded into the recreational system and
they'll be through the same stores then
same dispensaries in the end but you'll
charge the patient differently based on
their medical status that's correct
however with this trend and with the
fact that you're talking about uh
products medicines that have very
specific remedy uh uh what's goals
whether it's an inflammation or cancer
or whatever are you seeing at this point
along the west coast poast with
California Oregon Washington are you
seeing sufficient analysis similar to
non-cannabis products to understand the
medicinal nope consistency no no simply
no no we see very inacurate testing they
don't have the labs regulated well
enough especially in Washington three
Labs have folded up in Washington
because of what's going on up there and
the regulator has not regulated the labs
to be accurate so you cannot get good
information about your product with an
inaccurate lab and you can't know any
medicinal benefits from that if you
don't go further and then we really
should not be making claims whatsoever
even if we are working with a good lab
it just doesn't work out medicine well
you can get good standardized medicine
if it's clean and it's the right one for
you but it is a little bit of a patient
has to kind of figure out which one's
right for them based on a dialogue with
people around them so it is trial and
error and that's all that we're left
with as the best for today there's no
this is going to work for that I don't
it may work for that most likely it
could but it's not a guarantee that's
the best that you can do and I'm not a
lawyer but so my question is in relation
to previous question too what are the
Dutch doing to um to stabilize it and
make it more consistent what we do us
okay yeah so the question is what what
are the Dutch doing that is different so
theirs is a federally regulated
medicinal chemist like medicinal
cannabis program the cultivation of that
is standardized like a pharmaceutical
product so the cultivator had to prove
that it was consistent and the same
every time within a very narrow window
they over pressurize the rooms the
methodologies they use to clone and
propagate are different than what we're
doing and they religiously tested and
made sure that it was the same every
single time so it was I mean expensive
facility was kind of one way of looking
at it it's not cheap to build that but
they tested where were the lights how
high were they in the room was the Lumen
difference the same across all the
plants and was I really really
accurately repeatedly doing good
agricultural practices GMP style for
plants that I made sure it was the same
time that it was water the same amount
of water the same type of water the same
nutrients all the same for each specific
cultivar so it's doable it's just a lot
of diligence and a lot of work but it's
doable so sure yeah one more lucky
question
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah our testing service you know offers
the labels as part of the testing for
sure
yep thank you thank je what a great talk
Applause
[Music]
oh