[Music]
I'm Sue sisily I'm a physici from
Scottdale Arizona I practice internal
medicine and I'm the site principal
investigator on uh randomiz control
trial looking at whole plant cannabis
for PTSD and I just wanted to convey our
appreciation to all the good folks here
who've been following our Saga trying to
get this study underway we're finally at
a point where we're um screening
veterans and hope to have our first
betet enrolled uh in the next few weeks
so I'll tell you a little bit more about
that during my talk thank
you so yeah my name is uh Dr Pon uh I'm
from Emerald Coast research director
we're out of Pac Florida okay cool
they're just doing for this
conference um we're primarily interested
in trying to uh study today's Canabis
products so the products that you're
actually picking up at your dispensaries
um and encouraging some of the larger
companies to and to research those pro
products in the ways that they can so
primarily survey and observational
research uh and the means that are you
know at their disposal at this
point uh my my name is David Ostro and
like most of you I'm from the Midwest
Chicago uh which is where I founded the
first gay community clinic in the world
uh back when I was in my mdphd training
at the University of Chicago we went on
to prove that Hepatitis B was a sexy
transmitted disease and from that we uh
were the first Community Clinic to get a
contract to study the natural history of
AIDS and its causes back in
1983 that became the largest AIDS study
in the history of the world the
multicenter AIDS cohort study and we're
still following thousands of men all
across the US um uh after 33 years and
we get semiannual physical mental
behavioral evaluations plus we put away
blood and lymphocytes and purified
viruses from those who become infected
so it's been a tremendous source of
information and it's a model for
observational research on in a subject
where we start basically at zero that
I've been proposing um in the form of
the North American uh community-based
clinical cannabis research and
evaluation Network for the last eight
years and I think it's a model for how
we can move forward now even pre-post
preib to work together at a community
and patient centered basis to really
understand through observational
research um what are the specific
strains and preparations that work best
and have the least side effects for uh
specif people suffering from specific
illnesses and I think everybody who you
know very properly wants to think about
post prohibition my I have I take a very
negative view about that because I think
post prohibition will will only happen
once the
pharmaceutical corporations have taken
over the whole field and driven the
community out of it so I hope we can get
going I think the time is now and the
opportunity is now to to do as much
science um in in the uh to help patients
and to help those of us who are
activists in this field really get the
best out of this uh wonderful
herb great thanks to all of our amazing
panelists I'm Rob Bon I serve in the
California State Assembly I was the lead
joint author of the medical cannabis
regulation and safety act from last year
and doing some follow-up work um this
year as well uh with a bill called ab1
1575 and obviously there will be a lot
of ongoing work in research and
development is a a critical issue and
we're uh just super excited to have such
a distinguished panel so thank you for
the introductions I'm excited to be here
and honored to be here with you so why
don't we just jump in outside of the
introductions into a little uh maybe
five minutes each on on where on on
where research and development is headed
um post prohibition um I I took a few
notes here so I'm going to use my um uh
first I want to say you know we got some
potentially great news from the DEA last
month right they announced that that
they're ending the Nida Monopoly and
which could possibly be a major step
forward for cannabis research and I
emphasize possibly because the fact is
that the announcement was not
accompanied by any timeline so um yeah
so as we all know the DEA are experts in
delay um as our study is proof positive
I mean it's taken us seven years to get
to this point where we're finally
allowed to you know where they finally
issued me a DEA schedule one license
that a lot of scientist call that the
golden ticket because it gives you the
privilege of buying cannabis from the
federal government and if any of you
have seen what that looks like I have
some pictures on my laptop we just got
our shipment in a couple weeks ago and
it was incredibly depressing after so
many years of struggle with the
government and everyone was celebrating
this so-called Victory and then the
study drug arrives by FedEx by the way
uh yeah it was arrived you think it's
like armored truck 4 kilos of cannabis
comes in a FedEx delivery man um so the
the good news so theoretically this
Federal monopo that has styed cannabis
research for four decades now I mean
they the federal government has enjoyed
you know they've assigned the University
of Mississippi this Monopoly for 48
years and it's very sad that there's so
many um investigators whose Studies have
have not been approved um to move
forward because naida simply didn't like
the nature of the study they only really
were greenlighting studies looking
safety studies we call looking at
harmful side effects and addiction
potential so if you dare said that you
wanted to study efficacy of marijuana
those were the studies that were you
know systematically impeded by our
government um so so we have a problem in
that the DEA doesn't have any timetable
to authorize other Growers um and in the
meantime we are stuck with this cannabis
um we we the the paperwork that came
with the Cannabis just you know does not
tell you anything about uh other than
the THC to CBD ratio so you just heard
all these you know experts on in the
last panel all these sophisticated
Growers talking about how complex this
plant is we don't know anything about
the other canabo in the plant the
tarpine profile flavonoids what
conditions it was grown under was it
grown with pesticides or not they told
me it was grown
organically so they don't Define that um
and it arrived Frozen and uh with a a
thawing procedure they said it had been
in their freezer for two years so um so
yeah that was uh it's frustrating um I I
did want to mention that um you know and
obviously we're still not able to get
the varieties of cannabis that we
request you know scientists who ask for
more than you know 10 to 12% THC that is
their high THC um available if you look
at the naida website they list the the
phenotypes that are available and 10 to
12% is the max so um uh I did want to
also give you one more bit of of good
news though from um to I don't I want to
instill some optimism here um many of
you saw that the American Legion which
is the largest veteran service
organization in our country 2.5 million
veteran members mostly very conservative
um they did announc that you we were
able to infiltrate that group and pass a
resolution there that um not just
ordered the ordered the DEA to
reschedule cannabis but also demanded
that the DEA license other Growers for
research and I thought that was very
powerful uh I want to give a shout out
to um my buddy Rob Berto Pickering is
with the battlefield foundation and this
gentleman was an integral part of making
that happen and we're going to continue
to see um efforts of good people real
expert Growers to finally be able to
apply for schedule one license and we're
going to pressure um you know pressure
them as much as we possibly can to to
get this um to get this going actually
tonight just my my final um word is that
tonight at the Garden Grove the the city
of Garden Grove the the mayor there who
was here yesterday um at this event
invited us to speak to their city
council about them hosting a federal
grow and helping them apply for a DEA
schedule one license to cultivate
cannabis for research so any of you want
to join us at that council meeting
tonight we're thrilled and I think it's
a really good uh opening so thank you
all very much appreciate
it
all right uh thanks so much to assembly
member bont uh for being here today
thanks so much to Susan for hosting uh
such a wonderful event and thanks to all
you for being here uh seeing all these
smiling faces that are part of the
movement or want to be part of the
movement or just want to be educated uh
it's a wonderful thing there's a lot of
good energy in this room and that's what
we need in this movement is a lot of
positivity and good energy
um I'd also like to thank my esteemed
colleagues up here on stage uh it's
actually an honor and a privilege uh to
be speaking with such an accomplished
group of cannabis
Scholars uh so that being said I'd like
to speak for just a moment about why I
enter this industry and some of the more
pressing issues that I believe are out
there today um so most folks realize
that the gold standard uh for uh
researching investigational new drug
applications um are blinded controlled
clinical trials and unfortunately we've
had far too few of those uh when it
comes to
cannabis and uh that being said I mean
we've got Pioneers like Dr sicy Who
spent the better part of a decade uh
trying to complete a clinical
trial um however the situation with
cannabis is really unique I mean this is
a drug that's been out there for
obviously a long time it's been smoked
for
Millennia um and
frankly uh it hasn't obviously followed
the traditional model of biomedical drug
Discovery uh usually we start out with a
Target usually uh G protein coupled
receptor a protein kise do a bunch of
fancy molecular modeling and high
throughput screening and to identify uh
candidate drugs and then eventually the
ideal candidate drug drug that will then
go through the clinical trial process
but obviously with cannabis we've taken
a completely different route
and what's unique about cannabis is you
couldn't ask for a better cannada drug
in some ways uh it has one of the best
safety profiles that you could ask for I
mean the ld50 which is defined as the
lethal dose that would kill 50% of the
people taking the drug is literally so
high with this drug that you could
consume pounds and pounds of it and not
die okay so and that is very unique most
of the drugs that are being investigated
out there today they would die to have
an ld50 in that range
so that being said um the real issue is
that the Cannabis industry is moving so
quickly right now and research is moving
rather
slowly and the products that we see
seeing in the dispensaries today and
especially these new products we just
got a wonderful presentation about the
evolution of cannabis and so we've got
all these new products on the market
that really haven't been adequately
studied I think most people would agree
that whole plant cannabis is relatively
safe and an ulous I mean it's it's
really not harming
folks um that being said these new
products that are in the dispensaries
which are frankly outselling flowers at
this point uh such as concentrates these
vape pens Edibles these new
preparations obviously haven't been
studied for any real meaningful length
of time because they've only been in the
dispensaries for a short period of time
so um I guess
where uh I came into this is I started
seeing uh some of the older generation
embracing these new products and and
some of the younger generation as well
well but primarily my parents and their
friends uh using these vape pens and the
truth is as a
scientist uh you know I started to look
on Pub Med the world's largest medical
database for Research into these pens
and they just really isn't any it's not
there uh the tobacco industry who
initially created these pens uh they
have the research but they sure haven't
published it so um I do believe that the
vast majority of the products that are
out there in these dispensaries are
probably safe you know I am not an
alarmist and I'm not here to scare
anyone uh in fact I am a supporter of
this industry and an
advocate uh that being said I also
believe that it is incumbent upon this
industry and upon the producers of these
new products to begin to do at
least you know at least what they can
research-wise and if that's just survey
research if it's just observational
research for now they could at least be
capturing all those data points so
that's what I've been doing is
encouraging these larger companies that
can actually afford to have research and
development program to go ahead and
begin that
research so I'll say that you know
nonetheless I do see a lot of signs and
a lot of improvement uh in both private
and academic cannabis uh research you
know the larger companies that I was
calling on privately a couple of years
ago and asking for a chief scientific
officer I mean they just laughed at me
they didn't have a chief scientific
officer head of research and development
no NOP not that either so we were just
talking with businessmen a few years ago
now those larger companies they have
those people in place so you're starting
to see scientists at these larger
companies and starting to see um more of
an emphasis on research and development
all those I would say personally that
it's really skewed toward
development um and although slowly
academic research as Dr Sicily talked
about is beginning to at least head in
the right direction uh because as long
as we can't do translational research
and as long as of the Cannabis that Dr
sic is being provided by naida uh is of
that poor quality um it's hard to
really uh call that translational
research when the vets that are going to
be taking that
product uh that's not the product that
they're going and buying in dispensaries
my my friends I mean and they're
probably like you said they're probably
going to laugh when they see what you're
going to ask them to inhale so uh we
really need uh these new Partnerships
and you know I like the model in
Pennsylvania that they've formed you
know Colorado wanted to be the
recreational Cannabis King uh in
Pennsylvania they want to be the medical
cannabis King and frankly um I believe
that these Partnerships between
universities and all these probably
private cannabis institutes in the same
way you saw stem cells have to go
private and stem cell institutes you're
going to see a lot of that in the future
so just to try and wrap up here quickly
all I know is this canos needs to be
studied thoroughly at all levels uh as
much as possible I believe there needs
to be frankly tons more academic
research uh do I believe that we need
more private research certainly uh do I
believe that there's a role for big
Pharma in this yes there's a lot of
talent in big Pharma and they're not
going to be cut out of the equation
anyway so we might as well move forward
with the incremental steps that we can
take right now and frankly as many
players as we can get involved in the
research is a good thing because we
need uh a broad spectrum of research not
just big Pharma not just Academia we
need everyone to be doing this research
and just to finish uh as a last Point
I've really actually never seen much
harm done by doing too much
research uh frankly the harm is done
when we do too little research so I'm
just here to advocate for more research
from all entities and thank you very
much thank you Dr Pon let's go to drra
yeah I wanted to follow that talk
because you gave me so many great
lead-ins and and one of that you know my
main talk is about yes we can talk about
the future in terms of what's going to
happen once prohibition uh is ended or
so forth but we all know that that is a
train a train that's hurtling down a
track that's almost worse than when we
invaded Iraq I mean that is a track
that's been laid by Farmer and the DEA
and FDA for decades and it's just been a
postponing act against the community so
they can you know have to total control
over this I mean one of the greatest
lies that you saw in the DEA statement
was that um we allow uh you know lower
scheduling for synthetic cannabinoids
that been made by the drug industry well
I want to tell you something none of
those compounds are synthetic mostly the
the the th is is extracted from that
same from the leftover crap from what
you've received from the University of
Mississippi which has been breaking
their contract with naida for decades
and then they have this other thing
called the midest touch and that is they
put it in a capsule they add sesame oil
and voila it's legal it's schedule three
so these rules only apply to the
community and they will apply to the
community and the ACT activist and so
forth as long as it takes for a farmer
to get complete control of this industry
so what do we have to do in the
meanwhile we have to do
observational scientifically developed
research on every single person we can
capture who's going on medical cannabis
in an area or a state or the system
where the with the concentration and the
composition of the cannabis is being
very carefully monitored and the amount
that they're using is being controlled
so I'm working with the groups that are
trying to set up the standards for that
and I'm working with the doctors through
the American Academy of canabo Medicine
and the society for cannabis clinicians
and all over the United States and
Canada who will agree to give us
objective feedback on their patients
every six month just like we
uh ran the Mac study and then to
interview those patients who agree to be
in it at least oneon-one on the phone
and then maybe thereafter through
surveys because as a long-term survey
researcher I know we can never assume
that we know what the questions are that
the patients want us to answer so we
must do mixed um method research
starting with qualitative and
ethnographic and so forth and I you know
kind of come to this place because I've
been doing this for 34 years in the area
of AIDS and HIV and have seen how
powerful Whoever thought we would have
not only the
treatment uh in Hand by now but be
reaching for the elimination of this
disease I certainly never thought of
this would happen and we would get to
this point so there's a lot we can do no
matter how much the drug company say oh
no observational research will never go
past the FDA it's not the state of the
art and all this kind of stuff well sure
they say that because they want the
system to stay the way it is we have to
do the same thing that a activists did
in the
1970s what and we have to stand up to
this we have to get the people uh out of
office have to vote vote vote at the
local and every other level but we have
to come together as a as a community
that wants to work together with
standardized Med methods and good
analysis and so forth and build that
database from which we can learn so so
much and we could do it right now thank
[Applause]
you um I you know cannabis is a a
controlled substance and yet its use has
proliferated uncontrolled for many Decor
decades so I'm not as freaked out about
big Pharma as my colleague Dr Astro is I
don't think you big farmer or any other
single entity can ever totally control
this plant it just won't
happen um but big Pharma is a serious
player and can have a serious influence
I wanted to start out my brief
introductory comments by giving a shout
out to of all people President Ronald
Reagan and we should all thank him
ironically because uh he did a lot
inadvertently to advance us to the place
where we are you know when Reagan took
over he relaunched the drug war with the
Vengeance he militarized it uh his
administration put a lot of money into
research because they were sure this
evil weed uh if the research was done uh
it could be shown how it damages the
brain this is in the 1980s they put a
lot of money into this but instead of
showing how harmful cannabis was they
ended up funding the research that
culminated in the discovery of the
endocannabinoid system uh which shows
why cannabis has a neuroprotective
effect not a neurotoxic effect so
there's a great irony there uh and when
we talk and and you know that's a hugely
important Discovery and and it's the
edifice for so much of of research that
has been done and will continue to do uh
be done as we transition into a post
prohibition era um you know when we when
I say it has a huge impact has really
opened up whole new vistas of
understanding human biology and
Physiology and it has an impact for many
different areas of Medical Science I was
say a significant impact for all areas
of Medical Science and it sheds a lot of
light on why cannabis is such a
versatile medicine and why it's the most
popular recreational substance on the
planet and yes it is medical and
recreational and yes low dose is very
significant value valuable and so is
high do we have to embrace it all when
we talk about research in the landscape
you know thus far I think one of the
misconceptions that have been promoted
uh by uh largely the media but policy
makers as well is that we're just
lacking the science to know really
what's up with cannabis we that's what
the DEA said that they didn't have the
science to to reschedule or deschedule
um there's a voluminous amount of
scientific data that have been
accumulated um uh most of it is not been
clinical oriented in fact very little
has been clinical oriented there's also
been observational research
observational studies uh so we have a
lot of data that explain how and why
cannabis works and we say we have a lot
of data people anecdotally or through
observational studies saying it works
for this that the other thing what we
what we are lacking by and large is the
clinical research to prove quote unquote
that it works to the extent that we need
it so what's the implications of this uh
as we are heading now into a new era
well you know for a long time the the
the rule of thumb has been cannabis is
so dangerous that they couldn't do human
studies right well so we have an animal
studies and we have a lot of research
and a lot of data for animal studies and
some of is very significant and
important but the problem is you can't
extrapolate from animal data to humans
necessarily always it provides leads uh
uh it it it show it can show the way for
or to develop uh drugs and so forth but
it can't always be easily uh uh
extrapolated in particularly when it
comes to dosage this is a problem that
we see uh at project CBD you know people
who want to make products are sometimes
times they are are are healing but
they're not necessarily medical
professionals they go read these science
papers and they look at how much CBD or
THC it's always single molecules
generally are given to a rat or a mouse
or a dog and and they and they take that
and then say okay well if the dog or the
mouse is getting 20 milligrams of
something per kilogram and they and they
weigh 10 lb well for a 200 lb person
they should be getting 20 times the
amount that is is ridiculous it it first
of all and and really this is how things
are calculated I've talked to people so
as a result this is sort of a Prejudice
for very high and when I say high dosing
I mean almost obscene dosing I'm not
talking about what Swami was talking
about and we're on the same page about
that you know um and and it's uh it you
start off on the wrong foot and you can
get very distorted results um uh so what
I think when we talk about research and
where we're going I think I would like
and it's going to happen on many
different levels and big farmer will be
involved and there will be observational
studies there'll be all sorts of things
going on uh what I think it's important
uh is that at least some of the research
be oriented very pragmatically uh to
enhance our ability to optimize this
plant for whether it's therapeutic use
or recreational use we have had since
before the written word humankind has
had a relationship with this plant a
very significant one that relationship
was broken uh last century because of
prohibition we have to relearn about how
to use this plant it's now that we have
uh uh oils and the concentrates where
you can measure very specifically and
know specifically what is in these
products if they're label properly uh it
gives us an opportunity uh to kind of
take it all onto a different level it's
not just smoking a joint anymore and I
have nothing against that I do it
practically every day uh but it now you
can uh know exactly what you're taking
you can repeat the dosage or you can
adjust the dosage um and you can get a
very clear indication of what you need
if you find something right so you can
repeat it uh so I think research and we
we talked before we heard about uh uh
this Quagmire around dosing on the panel
before this is an area that's really
significant you know dosing is all over
the map at project CBD we're hearing for
as little as 2 milligrams of CBD and
when I say CBD I always mean CBD rich
with other things never a CBD isolate is
what I'm talking about as little as that
can be very effective therapeutically
and as much as a grad day uh so where
are we all add in this we have to figure
this out luckily it's a very safe
substance uh but uh you know I think I
fear as we go forward last point I'll
make real quickly is that the
researchers and scientists they aren't
immune from the the cultural Prejudice
in which they're working you know there
was just as an example a study done was
published the results only last month
from the University of British Columbia
maybe you heard about this the press
release released from the University uh
described it as the first scientific
proof that cannabis makes uh marijuana
smoking causes one to be a slacker you
know what they did with this they
injected massive doses of THC into a
rat's brain and they found the rat
wasn't very interested in eating or
going for the sugar when they usually
are they Overlook the fact that you have
a by phasic effects so when you have
very high doses of THC it actually
dampens the appetite and dampens the
interest in Sugar so here they they
extrapolated from a single molecule of a
mouse and and projected onto that their
own prejudices and concluded this is
some uh that they had some serious data
they could say about uh slacker hood or
a motivation uh and we have to avoid
this you know in the future but but I
think that as we transition into this
new these prejudices aren't going to
just be let go uh and my final Point
here is I think uh I'm worried but I'm
also hopeful that as we move forward
that we don't sacrifice Medical on the
altar of recreational they're both
important uh and the medical shouldn't
be S shoved aside and and uh big farmers
shouldn't be allowed to dominate the
industry at least the above ground part
of it um you know there is a place for
big Pharma and there's a place for
isolates but to me it's a small place in
the overall research Universe in the
potential of cannabis it's a legitimate
place but the problem is it becomes
imperious and wants to take over
everything and shove everything else out
those are my
comments wonderful thank you to all of
our panelists again for your for your
opening remarks um I think we have some
questions that could uh if you have any
um you can uh we'll identify you and
we'll have a mic ph up here but let let
me just start with one there was some
reference to the the federal climate um
can any of the panelists share their
thoughts on specifically what is
necessary to change the federal climate
to be more supportive of research who
needs to do what and how can Advocates
and activists be involved in making that
happen sooner than later well it's um a
very interesting thing because you can
change the law you can change the
scheduling but until you change the
education of health professionals in the
United States and the and and the
stigmatization that's been driven into
everybody I mean I've gone before
Medical scho classes and talked about
the myths and the lies and everything
and I've had students stand up and say
how dare you say that our government
lies to
us and I look at them and I say wow I
mean don't they teach you anything about
medical ethics and and you know the uh
the the the projects that have been done
to uh infect people with with all kinds
of diseases and not even tell them you
know it's just you know our history of
our government and cover ups I mean from
the AIDS epidemic I could write a whole
book of having been the fly on the wall
when government people covered up and
lied and and and uh even they though
they knew that the government was
responsible for the spread of HIV among
Haitians when they released them from
the camps uh by by judge order they
didn't even warn the communities they
were going to and then they said okay
being Haitian is a risk factor okay all
right so you can change everything but
you have to change beliefs and you
change beliefs is the hardest thing to
do and then you change attitudes that
way and I even proposed that Nido once
that they should sponsor a program to
change the beliefs and attitudes of
their own staff around around
cannabis uh you could imagine that
didn't get a very you know warm
reception right now they say they've
changed they say they've heard the
message and everything but they still
are tool of the same FDA DEA big farmer
naida uh alcohol industry you name it
and who's fighting us the hardest now
now it's the opioid manufactors because
they see a tremendous threat if um uh
strong strains of of analgesic uh uh
types of cannabis get out there because
they're not going to be able to argue
anymore that they're incredibly
addicting and and accounting for more
and more deaths among Youth and so forth
the United States that their drugs
really are better than than cannabis if
we show them uh this is the fact and and
you know in defense of the University of
British uh Canadia there's another group
there that published a wonderful paper a
few months ago showing that a huge
proportion of the people in their survey
of 1500 people going on medical cannabis
a quarter at least did it to reduce or
stop the use of addictive opian for for
their treatment and I think that has to
be a cry you just like we used to say
you know uh ignorance kills and so forth
everything we have to go out there and
say that medical cannabis saves lives
okay and is harm
[Applause]
reduction I I wanted to mention that you
know the challenge with finding new
sources of study drug for any of these
controlled trials um is even more
problematic because of course the DEA
announcement said that if you're
breaking federal law now you're if
you're a state licensed grower you're
not eligible to apply and so this has
the potential to become you know an
academic oligopoly where only
universities can apply um to grow
Canabis for research and we really have
to fight that I saw an article in Vice
recently I'm not sure how many other
folks saw that the DEA director was
interviewed by this Vice reporter and
said you know was this just a publicity
stunt or is the DEA serious about
licensing other Growers and he said
absolutely not a publicity stun we are
you know this is a this is serious we
are going to um find other Growers but
we haven't received any applications yet
he said that there were no applications
in the pipeline because of course
everybody knew that there was a a
government enforced Monopoly and nobody
bothered to try so we are trying to work
with groups all over the country whoever
is willing to put their toe in and fill
out this application I want to emphasize
to you it's not as daunting as people
think because everybody assumes a DEA
application is going to be 200 pages and
ridiculously bureaucratic it is
literally a three-page application it
took us five minutes to fill out with
our group at the battlefield Foundation
that and I was really proud of people
like Steve D'Angelo you heard yesterday
who's offered to partner with us on also
on trying to apply for a federal growth
so I think I want to encourage you all
the more people who can get applications
into the Pipeline and pressure the DEA
to to license other real expert
cultivators it is going to be valuable
believe
the hello um my name is Dr Rosen and I
was the one who practiced Western
medicine treating benign and cancer pain
for 40 years and I retired 12 years ago
happy watching television and traveling
and all of a sudden medical marijuana
came to view and for the last 6 months
I've been obsessed with trying to
understand what it's all about and so I
resurrected my license and I'm going to
start a brand new clinic and a mobile
clinic to be able to get to those people
who need it uh I came from the last this
last month of this month this is my
fourth meeting on medical
cannabinoid and the last one before this
was in Israel which is the epicenter of
medical cannabinoid and my my husband
calls me the Godmother of pain
management because I did it before and
uh I met the Godfather of medical
cannabinoid my question is this how
could I treat my patients if there is
no um St standardized medication of
medical cannabinoid that I could use for
my patients and how could I study and I
plan to study all my patients because I
have a both an academic and private
practice um uh experience are they
standardized tests to C to know how
they're doing and I'm talking about when
you're in the clinic you have to give a
test that's practical that's paper and
pencil and can be put in a data the base
because I'd like to be able to say after
one year I treated 100 dementia patients
and 80% had better
cognition uh but I want to know what
kind am I going to use and where am I
going to get it thank you briefly there
are products out there a lot of products
uh it's a question of how they're
labeled if they're labeled well and
properly but there's there are products
out there you can mention a few that we
think highly of and and and there are
also product lines that have different
ratios of CBD and THC and you can think
of it really in terms of what we can
play with right now there's really two
axes the cannabinoid axis which is
really CBD and THC in terms of what's
practically out there what we can use um
and there's also the turpine access one
is ratio specific the other strain
specific um and at project CBD when we
we hear from a lot of doctors a lot of
patients and scientists we have
relations with the entire Community um
the best we can say at this point is the
goal is for a person to self-medicate
under the uh hopefully under the
guidance of a he health professional uh
starting out low
dose uh usually starting out higher THC
lower uh higher CBD lower THC and
increasing that ratio to the point where
it becomes balanced moving it in a
direction of balance so that a person uh
can use as much a can a cannabis remedy
with as much THC as they're comfortable
with and they shouldn't go beyond on
that and it doesn't have to be high
doses so it's not about figuring out the
perfect ratio for every condition but
what's right and comfortable for a
person and you don't necessarily know
what the right ratio is in terms of what
you're comfortable with in terms of the
psychoactivity or the Stony effect
unless you go beyond that and when
people go beyond that sometimes they
find in fact they actually like that for
for new new people in the scene they
they like getting a little high they
prefer that and that's also
therapeutic you touch on a lot of really
important questions uh it's one of the
reasons why we started up uh forming the
North American communitybased and
patient centered clinical cannabis
research and evaluation Network some
seven eight years ago and we've been
meeting regularly uh with all the
shareholders from every
level of the like you know putting the
the seeds in the ground the geneticist
all the way up to the scientists and and
people like myself who are
basically uh into Innovative research
methodology that gets around these
issues and we've come up with a whole
bunch of Baseline surveys um that have
been attributed from different groups
and things that have you know really
validated these surveys and then once
you get into particular um illness or
what I like to say set of cardinal
symptoms because it's very hard to do
illness change but if you can if you can
break that down to the Cardinal system
symptoms that the patient is suffering
and and and most stress them uh there's
always very simple uh measures of five
or six items at most that you can use
for that Sue knows that this there a
great um uh
PTSD index but you can also break it
down to looking at the actual symptoms
because some symptoms may very likely
respond to different canabo and that's
the ultimate question that we have to
ask you one other really quick comment
because symptoms I want to also always
play The Devil's atet and it's always
both are true uh uh Michael back has
referred to Cogen and medicinal genomics
earlier in the previous panel they're
doing Gene sequencing of uh cannabis
strains they were also involved in the
human genome product the problem with
just focusing on symptoms when you're
dealing with something like seizures for
example little kids with terrible
epilepsy um there are so many different
uh factors that can play into seizure
disorder there could be hundreds of
different mechanisms in the brain that
are wrong you know hundreds possible to
choose from and what medicinal genomics
done what I feel Is So Exciting in terms
of the future of cannabis research is
that they are matching uh uh a condition
where where they will Gene sequence the
uh tissue from from the patient and they
will locate uh the broken molecular
Channel let's say for the the EP
epilepsy D syndrome they're finding a
common theme Here is a problem with the
Sodium Channel they call it a broken
sodium Channel um and that happens to be
something that responds very well to CBD
but there are other severe cases of
epilepsy that that symptom that are a
result of a broken sodium channel that
don't respond well to CBD that respond
hardly at all or sometimes CBD can make
it worse even violently worse so so uh
it's very exciting that you have this
kind of Technology emerging that you can
match uh uh Gene sequencing data from a
plant to a person and I think that
there's a lot there and it's a uh for
the future and I think it's something
that the FDA can hardly keep up with
this is something beyond what the FDA is
really capable of regulating and and I
think it's a whole new universe opening
up my question is for Martin uh it was
about something that you said actually
two things that I wasn't quite sure how
to reconcile and I was wondering if you
could flesh it out you made a statement
that there is a role for isolates but uh
before that you said something about CBD
and when you referring to CBD you were
making it sound like you did not
encourage the use of that as an isolate
so could you flush that out a little bit
please real real quickly you know
there's been some limited research and
one thing about research you know has to
be done a lot over and over again until
you really have a consensus you know
just one or two studies doesn't really
prove anything but in terms of there's
been comparisons of CBD as an isolate to
a whole plant a CBD Rich oil extract and
what they found basically this is done
in Israel that you can get a therapeutic
effect from CBD as an isolate if very
high doses are used and very precise
doses they can get the readings they're
looking for for certain markers of
inflammation and so forth uh and if you
don't get the exact or very the problem
is it's a very narrow therapeutic window
if you're a little too low or a little
too high it doesn't do anything where
with the CBD Rich oil extract you give a
little it has a little effect you give
more it has more of effect so it's not
like the isolate can't do anything in
fact we're seeing from the studies now
with GW Pharmaceuticals with epids for
the D syndrome for the it's almost pure
CBD and they they are having positive
results uh but that's all well and good
we should recognize there's a reality
there but you know big farmer didn't
come to the aid of little Charlotte you
know it that came from marijuana growers
and and we have a lot of research and a
lot of information we're developing on
the ground uh that's also very important
the the point is not to reject what GW
is doing with epids it has its place I
think it's a very small place and and we
have much more potential using the
complex
plan I always want to add to that that
um a eons of research have shown that a
you cannot grow a cannabis plant that
does not have THC many people like to
talk about oh we're going have this
great law that only allows C pure CBD
you know that that's a fallacy first of
all you need a little bit of th there to
get the best effect uh um and who knows
what other compounds there and CBD is
despite the the uh you know the general
wisdom
is probably not the
specific real life um uh type two
receptor Agonist it's probably one of
its uh metabolites or a mixture of
compounds including what THC does at the
CB1 receptors so we have to think about
this you know the way Neuroscience has
been moving the brain is not a sponge
living in a in in a in aition dish tub
and then just absorbing these chemicals
and everything to think of what's going
on at the synapses and at the system
level and you see that it is complex and
involves a bunch of molecules doing
different things at different places um
in the brain and we shouldn't forget
that there's so much basic science
throughout neurochemistry and including
in canabo medicine uh to tell us not to
think this way
hi so um one of our patients called us
and said that one of our products
completely made him be able to stop
taking insulin for his diabetes and uh
Stanford University Hospital in Paulo
Alto wants to do a study on it and I was
just wondering what do you do with that
type of data once uh the study has been
completed I know you can do like get it
published in a scientific journal but
and then what do you do after that like
where can we take that to yeah the best
place uh for any scientific data
uh that's meaningful is in a
peer-reviewed scientific journal I mean
PubMed is the world's largest medical
database and frankly uh the attitudes
out here on the West Coast are a lot
more Progressive than the attitudes out
on the east coast in the I95 research
Corridor and until those Physicians out
there and the doctors out there that are
making a lot of the policy decisions uh
see uh a systematic and probably rather
lengthy
uh string of good peer-reviewed science
we're probably going to be sitting here
right at the same scheduling point we're
at right now would be my guess so peer
reviewed research is going to be the key
to moving this uh this industry forward
in a lot of
ways but it's not to the end all because
if that just gets into the journals it
doesn't do anything to change clinical
practice we have to change the attitude
of the scientists and particularly the
doctors and other primary healthc care
givers that this is not a
dangerous uh drug and that if they if
they prescribe it they're not going to
get their their license taken away a lot
of what we do at aacm is put out
practice standards so that people have a
way to defend themselves when they've
written that 50th recommendation and the
DEA comes down on them and seizes all
their records and and stops their
practice okay next question from the
audience yes good afternoon um I just
wanted to segue also from the uh limited
CBD question that was just asked to ago
um specifically in terms of industrial
hemp and cannabis I hope it's not sacr
sang to include that in the conversation
considering there hasn't been a whole
lot of research done across the board
but we see so much of this Industrial
Hemp coming from I I think southern
France is the largest European China and
it's you know it's invading our
Marketplace looking like uh Medical but
is I I would like to know your opinion
what you think about it okay Industrial
Hemp uh hemp is fantastic you know we
know 20,000 products and and one of I
think one very important aspect
incidentally we're not even touching on
uh in terms of the new research era is
Research into the plant forget about all
this clinical stuff there we're going to
have more opportunities to actually
research this plant and as you would any
other plant so I think this is a whole
vast area that we're we're moving into
that we're not touching touching upon it
would be nice for previous panel to
address that more but and and there will
be a lot of research in terms of
industrial hemp and I know there's a lot
going on now with respect to CBD to
create a plant that's very rich in CBD
let's say 20% like what we have here in
California with the ACDC in the non hemp
varieties because it's above 3% THC but
to create a plant that you know falls
under that marker for THC um but still
is very robust and rich in CBD uh that's
where a lot of and I think they're far
ahead in that effort in Europe but
that's an example of how a politicized a
needlessly politicized agenda kind of
truncates and misshapes research I mean
who cares if the plant has 3% THC or 7%
or
1% um in terms of what it actually is
going to do for a person if you're
talking about a drug or a therapy it
really makes no difference 3% or 0.5%
because we got the political situation
it gets all skewed you know it's a real
long answer that's required in terms of
industrial hemp uh because it's a matter
a lot of it it's a matter of definition
as we see it again we don't look at the
legal definition of 3% THC industrial
Hamp is low resin cannabis marijuana is
high resin cannabis if you're going to
extract from a plant to make a drug you
need the high resin cannabis not the low
resin cannabis in terms of low resin
cannabis to keep the answer as short as
possible there's really two kinds
there's the fiber hemp that's useless
for CBD and then there's the seed oil
that you can make nutritional products
varnish paint from a very useful
industrial product um those plants you
can get about 3% THC from the foliage as
compared to like our ACDC or some of the
other strains we have in California 20%
you can get a decent servical product
from that type of seed oil Foliage for
CB D but it means you grow have to grow
you know tons of it to get a little
amount of oil uh compared to what we
have here but from an economic
perspective if you're in Europe there's
no plant limits here 100 plants right
realistically you can't grow more than
99 so it's not econ you can't compete
economically with that source of CBD but
it's not as good quality but some you
can make products that help people and
if that's the case great I'm a physician
I've been working almost 2 years at a
medical marijuana clinic here in
Southern California and uh I want to
Echo your comment about uh physician
education in general uh being needed uh
I've seen hundreds of patients uh over
my almost two years working there and I
would say that at least 50% of the
patients I see the primary indication
they're coming in for medical marijuana
is for chronic pain uh and the vast
majority of those also give me the
comment I want to get off the opiates or
I don't want to get on the opiates and
here we have a government campaign
saying opiates are bad we have to stop I
get emails every day as a
physician with programs about helping
Physicians to get patients off of
opiates uh the DEA will not
deschedule right now they say they're
not worried about EIC uh safety they're
worried about efficacy it's I'm sure
it's not the first time the government's
been speaking out of both sides of their
mouth but it seems to me there must be a
way that we can leverage the
government's wish to get people off of
opiates with the knowledge that at least
anecdotally that uh medical marijuana
will go a long way to help this uh this
uh occur we have to do the studies to
prove that this is better
and less addictive and is an answer to
this every time there's an article that
appears that that talks about how to
keep your pain patients from getting
addicted to opiates I always write in a
letter to the editor why didn't you
mention uh canono why because the
article was written and paid for by a
drug company that produces high does uh
ones and they're leveraging their money
by funding all the anti you know
legalization campaigns because they see
this is a threat to their business so
vote at the voting booth find people who
are not bought and known hand inand and
work with your own medical groups and
societies and so forth to get them to
adopt these uh uh you know resolutions
in this in favor of using a medical can
cannabis it's it's a hard thing because
so many doctors get so much money from
the pharmaceutical companies but there
are others who who don't or you can
prove their conflict of interest very
easily follow the money is one of the
best things I always
say I would just say uh Physicians are
required to take continuing medical
education correct uh wouldn't it be nice
if cannabis was included in that that
would be wonderful I mean addtive yeah
exactly educ
not propaganda this is an area in term
this a tremendous organizing opportunity
uh to to this is a way to put pressure
on local government city government
state government I know in Maine um
there was a ADV an advac effort as a
result of Dr DUS slot's work there who's
been one of the leading physicians in
this whole field about um getting the
state of Maine to recognize as part of
its medical marijuana program that
cannabis is a therapy for opioid
addiction and didn't didn't get passed
because they got a weird government
there kind of a tea party government but
uh this is really a ripe area for
organizing and for political pressure
there's uh in every state now they have
a heroin task force you know opioid
epidemic task force um you know the
medical community needs to infiltrate
all of these um you know government
bodies and try to encourage them because
if you look at all these task force
reports none of them talk about opioid
as a potential substitution therapy I'm
Excuse cannabis as substitution therapy
for opioids none of them even in legal
medical cannabis States they fail to
address cannabis as a solution so we
have a duty as people who are
knowledgeable to get on these committees
and demand that that get attention on
these task force reports I mean I think
we all probably realize that task force
reports are generally worthless and they
sit on somebody's desk and never get
read but it is valuable to have that
documented in these various States and I
did want to bring up I know yesterday
somebody was talking about the the insys
um you know the pharmaceutical company
that dropped a half million dollars in
Arizona to to fight against the the
legalization effort I just want to point
out there's a quote from their SEC
filing so insus is the pharmaceutical
company that manufactures fentanyl um
and they also manufacture ironically
dronabinol which is the synthetic THC
product but um this was a quote from
their SC filing legalization of cannabis
or non-synthetic cannabinoids in the US
could significantly limit the Comm
commercial success of our dronabinol
product if marijuana or non-synthetic
canabo were legalized in the US the
market for ganabol product sales would
likely be significantly reduced and our
ability to generate revenue and our our
business prospects would be materially
adversely affected so this is what we're
up against in all of these uh yeah and
all of these states um these guys are
the ones getting on these heroin task
forces talking about you know defending
their position in the market so we have
to do the same thing we have to meet
them where they're at and fight this at
every turn every single specialty and
general medicine has a local and
Statewide
Association and they hold Grand rounds
and I have found that that's the best
place to confront these ridiculous
beliefs and attitudes uh about it I
spoke to gynecologists and they said
well you can't use uh cannabis and
pregnant women and I said where did you
get that oh it's all over the place it's
it's even in our Board Test well it
turns out that's total lie every single
study that is shown uh like Millie
Dryer's study of rosarians and those
women who did smoke constantly and those
didn't the kids were the same and
develop the same and I said and you know
we have a great opportunity is in
childbirth cuz a lot of women don't want
to take the opius they want to be a
participant in the process well give
them a canabo or a very canono along
with very low dose um opioid and they
can participate and not feel like they
were drugged out during that very
important uh event my question is does
is everyone familiar with talk to the
hand campaign referring to government
patent 6630507 it seems that if everyone
knew about 6630507 that the government
said that it is medicinal and non-toxic
that it could be a basis for um
different
conversation if everyone was educated
ated about that
patent one thing about that patent it's
it's been misconstrued by the industry I
think purposely as this legalizing CBD
or or patent for CBD not legalizing and
that's incorrect it was a based on
Research uh into CBD THC and other
cannaboids it's not just about CBD it
was saying a patent for cannabinoids
they're neuroprotective and antioxidant
properties which could have potentially
great benefit fits for neurological Ines
stroke Alzheimer's and so forth and yes
it it it underscores the glaring
contradiction but the way they get
around that contradiction is through
sophistry or they're not talking about
cannabis they're talking about
individual components of the plant
marijuana no medical value but THC it's
already recognized as a medicine CBD is
going to be recognized as single
molecule very soon so it's a game that's
played verbally that's what's going on
do
effect uh how are they going to cover
well it's not so much a cover up but
they just uh we'll see it's on its way
to approval we hope it should be a
medicine in there but you can already
get something exactly like cannabis uh
satx which is a one:1 CBD to THC
sublingual spray in most dispenseries in
this town you can probably get something
almost exactly the same except a little
better because it's not alcohol based it
will be coconut oil based but it's
produced from yes so is
Saturday so
thank you to all of our panelists I just
want to make a a few closing uh remarks
little bit of a perspective from the the
state legislature and a lot of comments
about the the important role that
government can play hasn't been playing
but could play if it if it were more
supportive of of uh medical cannabis and
research I think right now we're in a a
time of massive uh transformation and
change it's Dynamic um you know we had
the medical cannabis regulation and
safety act passed a year ago prop 64 is
Almost sure to pass in my view um the
California medical association did
endorse and support the prop 64 and I've
seen the attitudes and beliefs that have
been discussed up here changing in the
legislature in the short time that I've
been there there were folks who you know
fully adopted the the stigmatized view
of of medical cannabis but changed
during the the process uh when we were
carrying the legislation so I think that
California can continue to have a
leadership role in in changing those
beliefs those ideas uh those attitudes
and I think there's going to be more
embracing of it we had a bill this year
that would have provided for research
and development opportunities in the
state of California it got stuck because
the governor's office wasn't prepared uh
to to support that given that they
thought prop 64 was likely going to
going to pass and they wanted to make
sure that things were all all harmonized
but you know when in my view when prop
64 passes there will be an opportunity
to revisit that and um there'll be a lot
of other work to do too to to harmonize
uh and synchronize uh the mcrsa with
prop 64 but um there's folks who are
very interested in this we see the
medical benefits we see that medical
cannabis can be an alternative to
addictive opioids um and and all the
other positive benefits of it so I think
those attitudes are changing I think
you'll see more from the state legis so
just a a little bit of a of a window
into the mind of the collective
legislature but let's have one more
round of applause for our amazing
[Applause]
[Music]
panel