[Music]
we both are involved with the open
cannabis project and that's something
that I'm very passionate about it has to
do with cannabis and and patents and
intellectual property and you're an
attorney in that field so I'm sure we
have lots to talk about
yeah I think we do I got kind of pulled
into cannabis a few years ago I'd been
working with plant breeders for a long
time and someone who had started a
cannabis genetics analysis kind of
company wanted me to give him some
advice about open cannabis and I thought
it sounded interesting and it's evolved
into something that is a daily passion
for me
so that's alright I'm excited to talk
about it well you know thank you for
your interest and you know I think for a
lot of us folks that have been breeding
cannabis for a long time this is a
hot-button issue and you know I I don't
necessarily have all the answers but I
definitely have some opinions okay so
what do you think are the problems why
is it why are patents a hot-button issue
okay well here's the crux of it in in my
opinion that cannabis is unique in that
it's been under prohibition for you know
around 100 plus years well less than a
hundred years in some ways but it's been
you know it's it's been under
prohibition for almost 100 years
and that has made it so the common like
publishing of breeding data that happens
in an agricultural community
as not happened at all and so you know
if I created a new strain or cultivar
twenty years ago like I did I never in a
million years would have you know
written that down I mean shit like if we
kept records we made a practice of
burning them at the end of the season
like literally I remember doing that and
and you know thank God that we're not
doing that anymore but you know that has
made there there's now a vacuum of any
what's called I guess in the the patent
world like prior art evidence of prior
art and you know for folks that don't
know prior art just means like something
that people have done in and created
already and so it's not new and novel
and because there's this vacuum there is
the possibility that folks could come
and claim you know that they've created
something that they not didn't
necessarily create it may have been
something that I had or any breeder
might have had in their you know tool
chests for our tool box for years and so
why should someone be able to then go
and just snap that up and then come to
me with a cease and desist and say you
can no longer grow that variety that
you've been growing forever well that's
it I think you've exactly framed the
problem I've been doing patent law for
about 20 plus years and I've worked in
biotech and medical devices in a lot of
different areas and what happens when
someone applies for a patent as you kind
of correctly stated is that the patent
examiner looks to what's already in the
public domain and they look for
published documents such as academic
publications
patent patent documents as well as any
kind of commercial record and they use
that to identify alright here's a patent
application that claims to invented X Y
Z and I want to see what is the closest
thing to it that is already in the
public domain and then they use that to
figure out what really is new and what
should be allowed to be patentable
that's a hard job yeah but they do a
careful analysis when they're doing
their job right they do a careful
analysis of kind of drawing lines
between what someone claims to invented
and what is already known of the public
so okay we overlay that with the
cannabis
the cannabis market or the cannabis
industry yeah and we have a unique
problem of an industry that has
essentially no recorded history as the
opposite of recorded history a history
that was affirmative ly destroyed right
there is no academic record there is
essentially no patent record yeah any
commercial record was hidden
instead of published Brant Burnham I
would what stop exactly exactly and so a
patent examiner though has the same duty
the same mission they read a patent
claim that says I invented X Y Z and
then they go do a search and they look
for prior patents and academic
publications and some kind of record of
commercial activity and they find almost
nothing and then they're supposed to say
they're supposed to determine whether
someone who claims to have invented a
certain strain or a certain family of
strains with some properties and they
it's their job to assess whether that's
in the public domain or not and they're
working with their hands tied behind
their back and there and with a
blindfold on and all they can do is
follow the guidelines that they're given
and they issue a patent and then you and
I both know that we may not know for any
given patent whether it's valid or not
whether they mate whether it's wrong
that they found it to be patentable but
what we do know is that there's a hell
of a lot of reason to doubt that what
they found to be patentable actually is
because what we know is that the public
record is a complete vacuum that there
are things that happened that never got
recorded and you're a living witness of
that and so you see a patent that issues
and you say oh hell no I did that myself
or I know people who did that 20 years
ago and yet now someone is saying
they're the first ones to do it and so I
look at that patent I being you I look
at that patent and say I don't respect
it I don't think that it should be
enforceable I don't think that it should
throw off a whole industry I don't think
that people should change their
commercial activities and out of respect
for this patent and if I get a cease and
desist letter I'm gonna gather my
friends with their pitchforks and their
torches and we're gonna have an uprising
over this and it's understandable and
you can't blame the Patent Office
they're doing their job they don't have
the tools to issue a proper rejection
right you might blame the applicants if
their applicants that actually know the
industry and they're just taking
advantage of the lack of evidence
and they're they're basically doing some
kind of gold rush land grab because they
can because they've got the power and
the resources and they're just doing it
out of bad faith then they deserve the
mob with the pitchforks and and the
torches to come after them but maybe
they don't even know so we're in a
situation where there needs to be
some kind of other public forum to bring
to bring forward the knowledge that
exists in the in the memories and the
heads and perhaps some hidden records of
people like you so ok enough for me
what do you have to say about all that
enter the open cannabis project you know
I mean for most of my adult life I've
worked in the nonprofit sector as a
fisheries biologist and you know did
River restoration projects and so I feel
like if there's a a framework or a
structure for for an organization to
tackle this issue that the nonprofit
framework is kind of the best because
you know you've got somebody who is
essentially hopefully isn't putting any
bias into this isn't bringing you know
the ideas of of some big agenda agenda
exactly they're they're looking out for
it a you know supposedly the the good of
the of the whole and and I think in
particular you know folks that need some
protection are the kind of you know mom
and pop cannabis cultivator and sort of
the original pioneers of this industry I
mean now we're in Vegas this biggest
convention center there's thousands of
booths here obviously deep pockets
involved in this industry you know I I
do I worry about my community in
Humboldt and I worry about you know the
local like just for example my hometown
in Humboldt County the fire chief is a
cannabis grower he's a volunteer that's
he spends a lot of his time as a
volunteer firefighter and wildfire you
know kind of an issue lately we're in
California I was in California yes
turday and
and in the world's biggest wildfires are
happening so to get back to the point
you know Jessie is having a really hard
time financially and that's just signs
sign of the times but these are good
people you know these are the volunteer
the chief of the Volunteer Fire and
Rescue and the school teachers and you
know a lot of folks have somewhat
supplemented all the great things that
they've been doing with their farming of
cannabis and that's just not going to
happen anymore and and that kind of
stuff is changing maybe it can still
happen in some respect but the last
thing we need is a bunch of you know
cease and desist letters and patent
infringement lawsuits stopping people I
mean we've all seen what happened and
this is cliche but you know when
Monsanto had their fancy corn and the
pollen blew from their cornfield in Iowa
or wherever it was over to the Organic
farmer's cornfield and he said he he
kind of started the fight I think said I
don't want your pollen your GMO pollen
in my organic field you know I I want to
be organic and and that's actually my
market and I saved my own seed and they
said oh you're gonna screw with us well
we're gonna sue you for patent
infringement because you're now growing
our patented corn and you're not giving
us a royalty or or you're not paying us
our licensing fee so that could happen
it's it's not inconceivable that that
could happen in cannabis it's pretty
perverse isn't it it is it's you know
that's I mean I'm gonna get off topic
but that's capitalism and and greed I'm
not a fan of either of those things
especially not unbridled capitalism and
greed so well I think I guess my own
take on it is that if there's a solution
it is more transparency and more
communication about the actual history
yes
the essence of a good intellectual
property system is that it can't take
something out of the public domain once
it's actually in the public domain
yeah but we can't know whether something
is in the public domain unless we
document it that's right and the fact
that there isn't a good documentation
about what was in the public domain when
cannabis was kind of in the dark yeah
means that we need to take some steps to
document the public domain ex post facto
that's right away
I agree and that means that people need
to step forward and say especially in
the context of newly issued patents or
newly patents that are newly applied for
we need people to step up and say no no
this is this is already in the public
domain and here's my evidence of it
here's what I know was happening 10 20
years ago or whatever as long as it was
prior to the filing date and this is why
it's in the public domain and this is
why this patent is invalid and here is a
coalition of people who are willing to
stand together to to provide that
evidence and to essentially form a
resistance aren't we the militants and
really - you know it's not even in my
take you know you don't even have to be
anti-capitalist you just have to stand
in favor of the public domain
really if something's in the public
domain then damn it let's let's make
sure it stays there yeah there there
there is even if you're Pro capitalist
you can't have a meaningful IP system
that can grab things out of the public
domain and appropriate them to one owner
yeah it's just messed up that that
doesn't work yeah because as soon as you
can't rely on something being in the
public domain one day and possibly being
taken out another day then nobody has
any certainty about their rights also
whole world
where's civilization world coming to
dogs marrying cats so you know I totally
agree and
just to finish that point like I you
know I mentioned I you know I'm not
necessarily like like you know so
radical that I would I would never say
that you know I found it humbled seed
company I wouldn't tell you that I'll
never patent a cannabis strain I'll tell
you right now that I'm not gonna just go
and and grab something that is that
isn't yours that you didn't original
that's for sure or or that's like really
commonplace so I mean you know the
things that we could you know think
would would think about potentially
wanting to protect with a patent you
know like something like very unique
cannabinoids that have taken years and
years of of breeding effort to to grow
and develop and the you know that is
just something that that I haven't even
really I don't even know if we've had
enough time even using like traditional
breeding practices or even using genetic
markers you know to there there may be
some some groups that that have that
kind of IP and and maybe there's
definitely maybe there's some warranted
patents out there I don't think that I
want to make a blanket statement and and
I'm not just like blanket oppose to
patents in the cannabis space or patents
on plants unlike the whole patents on
living creatures a lot of people say you
know like I don't I'm opposed to that
altogether I mean there has to be
incentive for us as breeders and it has
to be somehow like a legal hammer to
protect that incentive and you know
we've used different techniques other
than patenting in the past and that's
been successful such as like licensing
you know like we'll have a license
agreement with several nurseries
throughout California currently
and you know that has worked wonderfully
and you know what I feel like is it
should be something that benefits both
of you anyway like if you're a nursery
and you want a license of varietal that
I've spent a long time developing I
license it to you you maybe give me a
royalty every time you take a clone from
it and then in turn I'm like dales
nursery calm everybody he does a great
job and and we worked hard on this
varietal and now he has it and the right
to propagate it and openly and you know
it's it's my opinion that if somebody
else comes in and gets it and starts
propagating it without my permission
you know that's not necessarily a great
thing but they also don't have the
benefit of me sitting there being like
Dale's nursery is the one that is the
the the right person to go to to get
what I had created and and so those
kinds of things I think are ways that
that we can proceed and have incentive
for breeders you know without big
overarching patents and at the same time
that you know there could be some really
unique things I mean there will be
incredible things that come out of
cannabis breeding and and different
techniques for cannabis growing and all
the stages of the game and those may
very well deserve patent protection and
so I don't think that but it's just this
very unique situation that we have where
we've had years of prohibition and so
there's a vacuum of data and I think
that's something that the open canvas
project is is tackling and doing a great
job and and providing being a leader in
that you know and there's a lot of work
left to be done so they need I'd say
support from the community as a whole
well a couple things on that
one of my favorite sayings is that when
you're a hammer everything looks like a
nail and I'm a patent attorney and so I
kind of like patents but I really hate
patents that aren't valid where someone
is basically being dishonest and taking
something that isn't theirs because that
wrecks the whole system rights and
especially when we're talking about
utility patents where someone says they
invented something that they just damn
well did not invent yeah that really
makes me AM because it messes up my
industry yes
on the other hand I've worked with some
plant breeders well I broke worked with
plant breeders my whole career and some
of them not as much in cannabis because
it's a it's a plant that you can
propagate quickly and you can select it
you can select a lot of them you can
plant a lot of plants in a relatively
small space but I've worked with
breeders of grapes and stone fruits
where they might spend literally eight
to ten years selecting a special variety
exactly and developing a variety that
has commercial value that might last for
twenty or thirty years right and if they
don't patent that someone can grab one
plant and ranch carry it off a branch a
small cutting and carry it off and
propagate acres and acres of that yeah
and misappropriate ten years of
somebody's work that's right
ten years you know and if there weren't
a patent system to protect that work
that investment these guys wouldn't have
a job yeah they wouldn't have an
employer their employers wouldn't have a
business yeah and all of us wouldn't
have those special varieties they spend
all that time developing yeah so you
know maybe the world would still turn if
we didn't have grapes that ripens two
weeks earlier or that tasted that much
better or whatever but there is a hell
of a lot of work that goes into that and
that's right that's what the plant
patent system exists to protect I do
have a friend who's a cannabis breeder
and he I absolutely believe that there
are a lot of things that aren't worth
patenting even though I'm a hammer and
everything looks like a nail there are
some things that you know you can
protect just with agreements either
handshake agreements
or written agreements and you can say
alright I'm not gonna bother to patent
this but when I send you my clones I'm
gonna ask you to only make only
propagate this many and to pay me this
much and to restrict anybody else from
propagating and to sell them for this
much and it is kind of respect the fact
that I originated it and give me some
credit yeah
that can work I do have this friend
though there's a cannabis breeder and he
actually did that and he sold his friend
500 clones
pretty soon he sees this strain showing
up in catalogs and he knows it's his
strain it's distinctive and I think his
friend might have even used the same
name and so he called his friend and
said hey dude where's my money what's
the deal you're selling us in catalogues
and he said oh you know sorry business
business is business
dude I you know yeah we had an agreement
but this is this is real life and that's
when he came to me and said I think
maybe I need a patent my strains because
some people you can't trust and that's
kind of what it comes down to at some
point things are valuable enough that
even if you wish you didn't have to it's
nice to have the recourse that's not the
case with everything but to this extent
that you invest a whole lot of work and
a whole lot of time and you make
something really special and a lot of
people are gonna want it sometimes it's
worth doing I not gonna say it always is
and perhaps with with a plant that is
easier to breed quicker to propagate
quicker to select and there are a lot of
a lot more strains and a lot more
variety it doesn't always make sense to
patent it but there is something about
that and I think there's a big
difference between plant patents and
utility patents and especially the
potential for abusing utility patents by
just pretending to invented something
that you damn well didn't invent and
taking it out of the public domain that
that does make me kind of crazy well I'd
say clearly this isn't necessarily just
a black and white issue I think one
thing to take home is the open cannabis
project
is a much needed resource for the US
Patent and Trademark Office and for our
community industry and that Dale you are
a very knowledgeable person I'm on this
subject and I think that it would be
great to have you come on board with the
cannabis project literally on the board
maybe it's a non-profit so you know
it'll be public records soon enough
thank you well we could geek out about
this for a long time but fortunately
we're out of time right now they're
probably trying to kick us out of this
hall so yeah that's probably all for now
I see that the guys in black coats I
don't know if if I'm just staying
overstaying my welcome or maybe I've
been infringing on some Manhattan I
don't know about it's tequila time
you
[Music]