and the problem with them is that they
they do phenomenal selection based off
of vigour and resistance and quality
experience but if your numerix are under
17% that shit doesn't move at a store
and that's the problem so what I do is I
look for very disproportionate ratios so
I look for three hundred four hundred
and one THC the CBD ratios with five to
seven percent in early veg and then I
take those males and I find it in
clusters then I take that cluster then I
subsequently flour it to see floral
formation turn profile resin development
overall vigor and then I throw it into
situations where I can test the
resistance once I have that now I have a
breeder male that I can use and then I
throw it on anything I can get the
numbers to skyrocket and so then I
provide those males to other breeders in
other parts of the country in Europe and
so this way what it does that lets me do
this hunt I can send it to them they can
use their facilities which has much
larger potential for multi thousand
plants ifs and then I can then get the
cultivar back that's been sifted from
these massive operations so then I get
these outlier cultivars that were bred
using the outlier males I find and so
it's easier for me to chase it in
juvenile and then I use sex casting
signify loss to sex test because what it
does is it used to take me twice the
vegetative space to do all this shit and
now as soon as I have my first coil lead
and I get my first true leaf I can then
take a sample stick it in a tube
I do these there's little 88 tube sets
usually punch cards now it's an 88 tube
sets I send it to Philo's three days
later I get the results back and it's
accurate and so we've never had an issue
that's been probably 150 to 200 thousand
seeds done like that we've never had a
problem that doesn't indicate intersex
situation though intersex is still going
to be based off of how much of the
female chromosome remains versus the
male and as soon as we can get that
haploid soon as we can get into a double
haploid where we're going only into the
female we can then remove that intersex
capability so stressful in the shit out
of it's only a big girl and because you
because you have them though in your
life as a cultivator you have
plants that you consider bulletproof but
the problem is a lot of them aren't
these Polly hybrids you're playing with
right now where we're mixing we're
taking skittle and purple punch and
forbidden fruit the wedding cake and
with swirling that shit up and we pull
out some sexy cut and the problem is you
have so much Jam material moving that
you have no idea what's really inside it
you just know that the quality of the
end product is desirable but it also has
pathogenic prone tendencies and anything
to do with cookie lines is what we find
from breeding them cookie lines and
skittle lines has an incredible intersex
situation so I have two different
skittle hybrids that it costs 40 grands
in in work in two years in testing but
they both won the Oregon concentrate Cup
two years in a row with zero issues so
they're absolute winners in terms of
competition quality plants but with a
high degree of resistance Heidi it was
the Oscar shot of out of third gen and
so I had the skittle I know that I know
where the skittle came from so I didn't
get the skittle from third gen I got the
skittle from the guys that third gen got
it from out of Visalia it comes out of
Visalia originally if it was out of the
bay and then I got moved to Visalia if I
sell you as where the cut came from they
grabbed it from them we grabbed it from
them and then I held it then I released
it later and so I have a sherbet cut
from share bin ski that uses the skittle
as them as one of the parents and so my
my sherbet cut is like they called the
Green Hulk because it has that rich
skittle like flavor if you blow it into
a concentrate it's phenomenal but it's a
stunning flower too and so the odds cush
though because you you have an addictive
response to all basically limonene
terpenes and so tobacco companies did
research on what's the most addictive
terpenes they find that it's lemon limes
oranges pink grapefruits that's the most
addictive response to determine that's
why you see people dab and heavy on the
fruits they come back they come back why
all of a sudden is there this incredible
resurgence in floral turps why because
the the OG chirps are popular cause
primarily it's a it's a mer seen as a
heavy and aesthetic so if you take near
scene and concentrated it's in an
aesthetic at a medical level and it
works as an opiate transferal so people
that use opiates can use
gee and get efficacy and treatment they
don't get from anything else because not
much else has enough near scene levels
in it but all of a sudden everybody gets
into fruits but why it's because
fundamentally that's your most addictive
response and so when you start to take
fuels which have the anesthetic and then
you mix them with florals and fruits to
get that that high monoterpenes
signature in Lyman Eames lemon Eames
mandarines and you put it on them they
come back so when you see what it was my
buddy call it tree basis that tree basis
because they can't stop based on that
shit it's just like it's for real tree
basin and but it drives a response and
so my partner nor I work with two other
guys that are friends of mine on a
private level where they're both I
consider them fantastic sisters so one
of them lives up in Oregon the other one
lives over in Willets about you know 80
miles from me and so the guy from
Willits has been in cannabis probably
maybe 55 years and a brilliant legend in
cannabis where no no this guy's name's
Ben but Ben's at a level far different
than all these guys been we've been was
a monster legend balla from the day who
can't get out of cannabis because he's
addicted to it so much and so all then
does its hunt genetics and because he's
tied into the world so heavily it lets
him access everything and because he has
such a calibrated market potential
he's un-fuckin'-believable accurate with
quality of product so old ben me and
this cat out of auto oregon hunt and so
if i can hunt and i get one new thing a
year and then hunts one new thing a year
and my boy in oregon hunts one new thing
a year we have three new things in a
year because basically people like I got
something incredible but it's it's if
it's not better than the parental it's
not better and so the odds cush is a
good example of where we had to go all
the way into the f3 on it to find non
intersects capability under stress and
then what I'll do is I'll send those
cuttings in to check the level of female
chromosome present because we know that
under no no circumstances does it
trigger where we had to go through a
full you know almost 18 months of
working about 40 grand
and blast them through this to find
where do we find the outlier potential
and so with marker assisted it just
allows you to move a lot faster and the
bottom line is that it's gonna have to
be product differentiation and what I
see with cannabis right now is primarily
technology that's borrowed from other
industries that comes into our industry
so if someone said I'm state-of-the-art
that means you're using technology from
other industries and it's
state-of-the-art in cannabis but that
doesn't mean its state-of-the-art
because it's being used somewhere else
it's dirty and and it's an application
yeah you're a guinea pig but with
genomics genomics is where the state of
the art is going to be because you're
gonna be able to go into stuff that's
never been manipulated never been sifted
never been driven and in that to me
that's where we really go because once
we have a genetic basics you can't get
around it and so I know what the human
genome that when you have superior
genetics you can't you can't you can't
do it if you're genetically programmed
to be an Elon Musk intellectually you
can read every book on earth until you
die you're still not gonna have this
capacity and so I know that that's
really where we're gonna go with
cannabis is that I saw this and I've
been hunting varietals for age and
decades chasing varietals but I realized
that what I'm doing is I'm chasing and
I'm hunting and was sifting and we're
using but we could compress that period
and get a more accurate situation and
then start to really develop unique
product lines for the respective farms
and then develop unique lines based off
a location so indoors is so we can
certify it anywhere we want I can do
computer chips in Taiwan I can do
computer chips in Silicon Valley
st. chip because we can control the
variables in the facility but that's not
the truth with glass house and that's
not the truth without door because
you're gonna have environmental inputs
they're going to change it but no matter
what you do you're gonna have
fluctuations and so if you're high
desert or if you're a valley you're
gonna have radically different
situations that occur with your
production methodologies and the only
way to get around this to me is through
genomics because what it'll do is it
allow you to be able to reduce
infrastructure costs where it's not so
imperative to have so much cooling I'm
not slurring off my terpene profile
if I'm having variabilities in my BPD
it's okay because the vigor the plants
still going to work if I'm having
pathogenic problems I should be able to
have higher resistance if I can breathe
plants that have a tougher epidural
layer because that's what we see now we
see certain plants just like when you
run in silicone and high levels we can
get the epidural layer to toughen up so
the probiscus can't make it through well
why can't we do that on a genetic level
and then I got contacted from doctors in
Florida that had said hey do you want to
work on a project with developing
medical varieties in Florida and a lot
of it was specific chemo type profile so
they could use it for sublingual and
topical patch and they wanted to do it
in conventional methodology because all
this genomic stuff is brand new and so
not everybody's aware of it they're
aware of it for the human element but
not for cannabis and the thing was we
were tying into a cilia Salinas
operation to go test through you know
hundreds of thousands of plants but I'm
like you're gonna miss them it's
impossible to pick the outlier when you
have that many plants and so what you
need to be able to do is use the genetic
testing procedures to start to locate
what you're seeking so then you can then
take that population and work with that
population if I can find the person
that's TB resistant and breed them I'll
get higher TV resistance if I can find
someone that has higher genetic levels
you see it in families where you see all
the athletes once there's a relative
somewhere who transferred some
phenomenal genetic material isolate that
person and reproduce that cap and that's
what we want to do with cannabis and
we're and we're about to it's happening
right now and so we started to work with
some crews out of Santa Cruz so we can
start to work with some of the lines out
of the cookie crew because we have
access through Parker Parker's partners
on the lemonade line with burner and
then it allows us to start to take some
of these highly branded varietals to
have exceptional velocity in the market
sift through them to find the true
production varietal and then you can
license them into into facilities that
can then sell this and so I have a large
manufacturing facility we're building
right now that's going to be designed
for Terps stripping
and so what you find is a lot of the
terpene profiles you've seen I've been
feeding these these companies Turk
sheets for years so it allows them to
take my data and put together
formulations to create plant-derived
tripping packages because it allows you
to have crude manufacturers help out and
what it does that lets me play with
other companies so I can understand what
you do so I I share my stuff I get data
back from you
it lets me keep myself moving
continuously or otherwise I would only
be me but if I can mess with enough
scientists and up other companies and we
keep our proprietary ship proprietorial
we work on joint projects it lets us do
better I don't give a shit what what
terpene profile you put together it is
not the same as a cannabis derived you
can't get the complexity straight and
you can't get the ratio straight and so
ultimately the the experience is
diminished so what we realized was that
if we put in commercial level
stripping operations I can then have
farmers who have locations that are
optimal for higher quality do my crude
production and then I can have farms
that have better situations to do my
Turk production and then I take your
cannabis I pull the Terps the rest of
the flower gets blown as crude so this
way you make crude money you make Turk
money the Terps now can get infused with
the crude from others because you're
you're having a radical amount of
product that can be created from serbian
infusion and so it starts to let me find
how do we stabilize markets and for me a
lot of it is that I've been in Humboldt
for almost thirty years and I don't have
any intention belief but what I see is a
tremendous number of people that were
phenomenal career cultivators but
they're not technologically aware
because they didn't have to be it isn't
that they're not smart enough they're
fucking brilliant
it's just that they've been very focused
on what they do so they're biologically
intelligent they're cultivar intelligent
and they understand how to produce using
their specifical location and that makes
them vulnerable and so for me what I've
been doing for a long time is I gather
these hot varietals I get access to a
number of number companies these
companies allow me to take the variety
sure so I got to hold it a cookie like
nine years ago and I was the first one
to put it in
broad-scale production and what it did
was in and it was allowed because
ultimately you can't build a true brand
a true market if you don't have a
million people using it if only ten of
us have it and only a thousand people
consume it that's not a real product
it's very niche and so for years I've
been receiving products from breeders
that said hey listen take this product
from us and move it because my nursery
focused primarily on black market
operations where it was legitimate so
you had to come in with a driver's
license in a 2:15 but I influenced up to
maybe the BOE figured that I was doing
anyway between one hundred fifty two
hundred seventy-five million a year in
influence in the system they stuff of
what was occurrence over the last five
years I might influence the billion
dollars a cannabis production through
the United States breeders recognize
that because they go everything you
touch blows up in other regions because
I do my research over the whole United
States to find out what's in demand and
then I take a look and then when you
would come in and speak to me I'd say
listen I'm not gonna rat you out so
people would give me the answer I'd say
what's your market and you'd be like
look I'm moving it to these coasts so we
would find cultivars that move in that
hot direction and then I would have
sifted out cultivars that work on the
production level for you and so what it
does it allows you is the the cultivator
to have a better level of success
because you can move your product and it
lets me have plenty of people to play
with to play the are indie game and it
lets me test my hypothesis am i accurate
with my market analysis and and you need
it you need to be able to figure out are
you on point and you can you can believe
you're on point but when you're moving
that much material you know you're on
point and so it allows you to reconfirm
your hypothesis because you have to
prove it twice in order to make it real
and so it lets me function in that level
and what I wanted to be able to see is
the development of varietals that work
in the microclimates of humble county in
these low-lying areas that have higher
humidity levels that have a longer
season up to where I am up in the
mountains where I have ungodly
production capacity and quality but with
a shorter season because the temperature
range is a little more aggressive and
then we started to mess around with some
of the new indoor facilities that were
popping up and it's the same thing I
feed into our people now but we want to
say hey
let's get varieties that work under your
lighting systems let's get them that
work under these environmental
conditions what works optimally in rock
wool what works optimally in cocoa and
we start to mark those varietals that
are that are outliers within it and we
start to take a look at it and say hey
these are the markers we see on those
plants and now you can start to go
through your breeding projects pull out
the outliers do the work
fill out the gradient and now you really
have a product distribution that
actually makes sense when you're talking
about the you know and I don't want to
knock any of these companies because
they I don't want it I don't thank
people on taper in either not shank yet
but it doesn't make any goddamn sense
it's arbitrary and so you're you're
having an opportunity to develop an
industry so we've been in this forever
so cannabis is going on in the US since
fuck the sixties but right now it's
actually changing into this very
accepted model so you're gonna have this
incredible increase in people coming in
and you're gonna bout to start having
global trading coming in so I'm getting
hit up from every country on earth to go
play so I know this stuff is is at a
level that's nothing like we've ever
seen and how do we start to develop
product lines that actually make sense
that you could own yourself licensed and
sell the other facilities around the
world as licensed product you want to
hold your product