[Music]
john has a new company let's hear about
your new co oh my goodness yeah
so I'm actually consultant so I'm a
seagull I fly in I shit all over you and
I fly away and so within that process
it's more of going through and looking
at where a manufacturing facility is
going so it doesn't matter what the
manufacturer of equipment is it's more
of taking an analysis along the way of
the material before it goes in the
extractor X Y Z I don't care if it's
propane butane tetrafluoroethylene co2
or I don't care what it is but what I do
is I see what's happening before test
that material then test the conditions
that it's going through and then testing
the material afterwards and so if
there's one thing that I'll harp on and
that is good is not a number I mean you
need to know the numbers to be able to
know what is your yields supposed to be
what was your yield and so therefore
you're able to find out where do you
have holes in the bucket of the
manufacturers so if you fill up a bucket
with water or how many holes are in
there I mean it's it leaking out
everywhere and you don't realize it
through your decarboxylation you're
losing 20% to didn't have to if you're
doing it through your extractor and you
find out that it's channeling so
channeling is like a river going through
an extractor and the co2 or propane will
find the path of least resistance if it
finds the side of that vessel it's it's
you know it's fast past time off you go
if it's sitting in the middle it'll just
continue to go like the Colorado River
and you're just gonna have erosion and
so but you're not gonna get to that
material so those are the sort of things
to be you quickly find out by testing
something in-house it's not that much
money to be able to go back through and
know what the numbers are so I say
that's what synergistic technology
associates does it's really looking at
process design you know where are you
losing money where can you maximize
money working you maximize productivity
it's not cheap but it'll save you a lot
more money than he charges you and and
if you take him out to lunch you get
good comic relief too so that's always a
bonus he's not funny you're not doing a
good job
[Music]