[Music]
uh yes good morning Robert suar with the
California Department of Justice I'm
happy to be here this morning uh in
front of these uh three committees I
think it'll be uh a really great panel
throughout the morning uh I'll keep my
portion brief uh and largely uh to the
role of the Attorney General as uh the
Constitutional chief law officer for the
State uh both the medical uh marijuana
legislation that was passed and prop 64
actually largely omits a direct role for
the Department of Justice uh aside from
our administrative Duty and in uh
disseminating criminal history
information uh that said uh as I go
through a basic overview of the bill
you'll see that as the uh lawyer for
virtually every uh government entity in
the state the Attorney General will be
continuing to to assess the impact that
prop 64 and the legislation proceeding
is going to have on our day-to-day
responsibilities through our various
legal divisions and sections uh we've
actually appointed a coordinator within
our government law section an attorney
whose sole uh purpose on this project is
going to be to assess the cumulative
impact of these new policies for
marijuana uh on the department to
understand whether or not we have
appropriate resources to handle all the
complex legal issues and Regulatory
Frameworks that are going to be
implemented as as a result of the law um
in addition to that we also are going to
be actively using our case management
system to track any litigation that
comes to the various sections that have
a core nucleus uh subject of cannabis or
marijuana legalization uh in order to
track the progression of those issues uh
as a quick overview I believe the
background paper does a fairly good uh
summary of the props 6or language but I
can just give a refresher it's that it
makes cannabis lawful under state and
local law for adults 21 and older uh
they can possess up to 1 ounce of
marijuana for personal use and cultivate
up to six plants for personal use in a
private locked residence it can only be
smoked and Vaped in places where tobacco
is allowed and it can't be ingested in a
public place uh from there it's prop 64
is largely based on the previous medical
legislation that was Champaign by
members of this committee and the
legislature uh in that it divides up a
number of very complicated uh and
necessary uh
regulatory uh framework pieces
across different areas of agency
expertise uh of course the one newly
created entity within the past few years
was the Bureau of medical cannabis
regulation uh which is going to be
handling uh The lure for uh the
transport distribution sale and I
believe will be testing um that is a a
new Bureau that as an entity of the
Department of Consumer Affairs will be a
client agency of our licensing section
and then meanwhile the food and
agriculture department is going to be
licensing the cultivation which which is
a client of our natural resources
section Department of Public Health
health will be licensing uh
manufacturing and that is a client of
our health education and Welfare section
uh from there uh those kind of key
implementers that are obviously working
on a tight timeline to implement
regulation uh there will be a number of
other impacted agencies or legal issues
that may come to Light Within the
Attorney General's office uh the State
Board of Equalization will obviously be
in charge of uh collecting the special
tax is implemented by prop 64 which is a
client of our business and tax section
another client of that section is the
treasurer who is of course working on a
number of issues related to uh dealing
with the profits uh related to uh
marijuana sales um the various
environmental uh regulations that are
going to be Set uh by uh food and
agriculture as well as state Water
Resources control board and the
department of pesticides it's a kind of
our natural resources section uh and
then on top of that you know we expect
that there will be a number of reduced
penalties as a result to prop 64 which
allows for marijuana felonies to be
reduced to misdemeanors with petitions
for reduced charges and so our appeals
rits and trial Section which handles
many of those cases will likely be
dealing with those issues as well as our
Correctional law section uh from there
as far as our employment administrative
mandate section uh prop 64 continues to
allow employers to discriminate against
users of marijuana and that may come up
as well as uh in settings of
professional licensure which is one of
the primary uh B&amp;P committee issues uh
both our Health Quality enforcement
section which deals with the Healing
Arts boards and our licensing section
which deals with many of the other
boards may end up uh seeing litigation
involving uh disciplinary or lure
revocation cases uh where one of the
factors uh behind the investigation was
use of marijuana uh to the extent that
local ordinances restrict uh cultivation
or use of marijuana in a zoning context
we have a land law section that would
deal with that prop 64 also envisions
the possibility of nonprofit lenses and
that would fall under our charitable
trust section it's it got to a point
when we were assessing this that as we
go through all of those issues which
unfold through uh the language of prop
64 uh nearly every legal section within
the Department of Justice is likely
going to have some case or some matter
that involves uh a new issue that has
been brought to light by the ass signing
of the initiative um as I mentioned
earlier we do also have a direct role in
that we are the state's criminal history
depository so to the extent that prop 64
and previous legislation continues to uh
uh lay out fitness criteria for lenses
with uh the idea that they cannot have
been convicted of a substantially
related crime or serious or violent
felony uh felonies inv involving uh
fraud and deceit or employment of a
minor in uh a drug drug business uh all
of that uh background check workload
will be coming to our arious division of
the California Justice Information
Services Division uh and then finally uh
I would also point out that as far as
the driving impaired issue uh there is
obviously going to be a lot of
discussion about what constitutes
driving impaired uh following the uh the
ingestion ingestion of marijuana uh
we're looking at all the new scientific
ways to be able to do roadside testing
and other types of testing uh by law
enforcement and that's something that
the various folks that work in
toxicology and our Bureau of forensic
Services is likely going to have to
handle from uh a it workload issue um
finally to the extent that uh law
enforcement training and standards
impact us as chief law enforcement
officer I'm sure we'll be working
closely with the various associations
and with post and CHP uh to make sure
that we are adequately preparing uh
folks that are doing local law
enforcement and Statewide law
enforcement uh for the new laws that
will be a large change in life for many
of them uh and then just to book end
with this if there is any case just
generally challenging the
constitutionality of either proposition
64 any of its Provisions any of the
regulations uh or any local ordinance uh
that will obviously fall upon the
Attorney General to defend as the chief
law officer for the state so uh while we
don't have a direct impact of result of
prop 64 uh you almost get uh a little
annotation next to every provision in
the the law where the Attorney General
will likely have to be present to lend
some legal guidance so uh in that
serving as kind of a basic and and
hopefully brief summary of the
provisions of the bill and how we see
them from our role at the AG's office uh
I'm I'm happy to answer any questions Mr
suner let me just ask you just something
real quick and I know Miss walren also
has a question but you know under under
the proposition it specifically names
you know Department of Consumer Affairs
Department of Public Health and the car
California Department of F and a to come
up with a regulatory scheme workor I'm
just wondering how is the Department of
Justice working with those three
agencies and what's the regulatory
framework that the Department of Justice
is doing is that independent is it
collaborative is it we're going to wait
and see what the feds do they've been
invited by the way they didn't show up
thank you for being here but can you
give us some sense of that
please uh sure uh we're not directly
involved with any of the the regulation
uh that is currently being developed by
the other departments um certainly we
have uh an open conversation and an open
dialogue with with the bureau with the
Departments uh with their uh parent
agencies uh largely as legal counsel uh
we have uh active client Liaisons that
are always available uh to work through
various uh legal issues but uh really
the the proposition sets out that the
stakeholders with the expertise should
be developing uh the specific policies
and regulations uh uh for what fits with
their own jurisdictions uh the
Department of Justice and there's you
know a portion in there uh you know kind
of clarifying and accelerating some work
that we've been doing uh to assess the
legality of hemp cultivation uh like I
said the the background check process is
something that we do already uh for
lenses of all kinds throughout the state
and we'll be continuing that workload uh
with what's in the proposition but
otherwise uh we really have been less an
indep dependent implementer of this uh
new initiative and more so uh legal
councel for those who are tasked with
doing the job so it's obviously it's a
it's a complicated issue and we're
always available to them for that so let
me ask you legally for the State of
California as we continue to move
forward and given the federal landscape
and the new Administration what are some
of the things we should be uh concerned
with right uh well I mean what's
important to keep in mind is that in
terms of federal versus state law not a
whole lot has changed at the federal
level what we've seen over uh the past
several years isn't a change in federal
law but the expression of different
enforcement priorities on behalf of the
US Department of Justice uh we don't
speak in terms of a federal statute or
or regulation we speak in terms of
memoranda issued by uh the Federal
Department of Justice we had uh you know
we'll talk about the Ogden memorandum
which was then replaced by the Cole
memorandum then there was a supplemental
Wilkinson memorandum all of these are of
course uh subject to uh the pleasure of
the United States Attorney General uh
but at this time uh there's you know
really nothing but speculation that can
be done for how the federal government
is going to choose to view its own
enforcement priorities obviously you
know we've been hearing a lot about uh
the issue uh from California as we look
to implement our own uh state laws that
would seem to conflict with fed law
that's why it's important to state that
it's not that marijuana is legal it's
that it is lawful under our laws uh but
while that is a new legal uh context the
the core issues of federalism and the
right of states to enact their own
policies that may or may not be
preempted uh by federal law is something
that is uh kind of at the core
Foundation corre of most government law
so uh you know we've been evaluating
that issue across a whole Spectrum
of areas uh of conflict between uh
Federal priorities and California's uh
policies and we'll be continuing to do
that as we get a little bit more meat to
what we're currently thinking we might
be seeing out of the Federal Department
of Justice yeah so as a Department
California Department of Justice are we
gearing up to have that argument of
state's rights and looking for
litigation not just in this area but
like you said there's a host of
areas um where this could potentially be
an issue
right well obviously you know we have a
new attorney general who uh knew from
his first day in the office that one of
his core functions was going to be
assessing when where how uh and uh how
most vigorously to defend the priorities
of the State uh it's a constitutional
mandate uh for the attorney general and
uh it's going to become a question in in
many court settings I don't want to get
too far out in front of but I think
certainly it is understood and uh the
analysis is already happening to
constantly look into issues of what
defenses was calfor would California
have in order to preserve its own
policies uh that its own uh citizens
have chosen to act on uh despite any
sort of uh Federal uh conflict got it
thank you Miss
wal thank you Mr chair um you know with
this implementation we can clearly see
it's a a balancing act um and with the
California Supreme Court affirming local
authority over medical Canabis um to
some extent and you know as was
mentioned the patchwork of local
ordinances trying to give clear
direction to law enforcement the
employment issues brought up um land use
planning as well as um just the state
being consistent Statewide as well um
having served over 14 years in local
government you know I'm I'm concerned
and I was just wonder wondering how
would your office and the other
stakeholder agencies that you're working
with how do you look to balance local
control with the Statewide concerns and
what would be you know how do you look
at defining the Statewide concerns that
would bring some consistency that is
needed while still preserving some of
the local control and I know it's a real
Balancing
Act uh and I mean obviously the the
issue of you know to what extent should
locals be able to govern for themselves
uh how marijuana should be lawful in
their communities is something that's
been present uh throughout uh a long
history on this subject and and I do
believe that uh both the uh the medical
legislation that was passed and also
what's mimicked in prop 64 does
recognize the importance of local voice
on many of these issues um I'll say that
having worked on this issue back in 2011
when we were evaluating if any
additional guidelines were needed in lie
of new uh statutory policies uh there
was almost nothing speaking to this
subject about what could or could not be
regulated at the local level so what
we're seeing now I think is a much more
memorialized commitment to understanding
that there should be a balance between
what standards the state thinks is
appropriate to set out through its
expertise through its departments and
also what is uniquely uh necessary for a
local community um and that's something
that I I know that all of the the key
Regulators uh have in mind and that
they're working actively with local
stakeholders and that's something that
the Attorney General General would
certainly encourage thank you thank you
let me ask if there are any more
questions all Mr wood has one and then
we'll go to Mr Brook super brief has
there been Outreach from our attorney
general's office to the federal attorney
general's office to get any sort of a
idea of what direction they're going or
is it premature uh it's premature but
more so for for me to say that there's
really any uh kind of uh direct
conversation happening with the federal
government now in terms of they're not
even really being a confirmed uh federal
attorney general at this time so uh
certainly you know state and federal
Partnerships are important but it's all
going to be handled uh In Due Time by
those that are going to be working on
any actual uh legal uh
forums but is it safe to say in the past
we had regular conversations with the
federal government on this issue or to
an extent yes uh I mean obviously uh the
US attorneys that uh represent the the
Federal Department of Justice when in
California have always had good
relationships uh both locally and with
the state law enforcement Liaisons that
work with them are are prosecutors uh
within the state AG's office uh
frequently engage with the federal uh
level and I don't expect that to change
substantially with the new federal
Administration uh that said when you do
talk about the potential for conflict it
becomes a slightly different posture uh
where uh obviously the the federal level
department of justice and the state
level department of justice are going to
be making sure that they're preserving
their own best interests if there is any
uh sort of Court setting for those
conversations thank you great Mr bro
please thank you Mr chairman the other
uh conflict between state and federal
government is the banking laws um is
your office involved with the
treasurers um working group or um you
know a lot of us in my view I think we
need to get out of the you know physical
commodity of cash needs to be something
uh electronic like Bitcoin or something
because we can't have um businesses
delivering hundreds of thousands of
dollars of cash to a Boe office and
having a a member of the staff there
count it and uh so please elaborate on
anything your Department's doing in in
regards to the banking of of marijuana
money yes of the many issues that have
been arising that is definitely one that
has been raised from a couple of
different uh perspectives uh within the
Department of Justice and our business
in tax section is client coun for the
treasurer's office and is working on the
work group that you mentioned uh as well
as Boe uh and so they are available and
continue to provide legal guidance as
that I agree very complicated issue is
currently being sused out well thank you
very much thank you
[Music]