[Music]
good morning we are here with the band
arrival lo kana and she is a presenter
or our April 2nd the path to cannabis
appellations event so Amanda if you
could start off just giving us a brief
introduction of yourself who you work
with and sort of how you got interested
in the cannabis industry how you got
engaged
in the first place sure well hi everyone
I hope everyone is enjoying their time
at home so I am currently the vice
president of community development for
flow kana flow kana is a cannabis
distribution company up in the Emerald
triangle that works with a network of
small sustainable Sun grown farmers and
does a distribution across the state
packaging and promotion for the Sun
grown in sustainable methods related to
cannabis cultivation I've been working
with the cannabis people for over 20
years my background is a social worker
and public health researcher and I
started doing work with the dispensaries
in San Francisco back in the early 2000s
and really starting to study how these
facilities were operating as health
service providers and what they were
doing in terms of being really good
community health partners which is so
interesting because the conversation now
in light of The Cove advice around
cannabis has really been patient access
and it's interesting to see the
discussion around cannabis kind of
returned to that more medical framework
which is what it was like when I first
started studying it you know it was
really all about how do we get access
for people who are sick to a product
that is currently illegal and so I
really studied how patients were
accessing cannabis but also their
behaviors around cannabis so
specifically looking at how the use of
cannabis impacted their use of other
substances most specifically opiates so
I really was interested in looking at
that framework because nobody was
studying it back in 2002 2003
there was very little known about who
patients were or why they were doing
what they did so I continued studying
that and looking at that from a public
health perspective through 2012 and
that's when I went to work for the drug
policy Alliance as their manager of
marijuana law and policy really starting
to get more involved on the policy end
as legalization started taking off as a
policy change around the country
starting with Colorado so then in 2016 I
worked on Prop 64 here in California to
legalize cannabis which was a very very
preliminary step to the shift of moving
cannabis out of the illicit market out
of the criminal justice system and
moving it more into the field of Public
Health alternative health and medicine
so legalization being that very very
initial step to start moving cannabis
away from criminal justice after we
passed prop 64 in California I decided
that what my role really should be next
is to be boots on the ground and trying
to ensure that the system that we were
going to create after legalization was a
system that was going to be supportive
of smaller entities and of methods that
were going to be environmentally
friendly I didn't see a reason to
unleash a whole new industry onto the
world that was going to rely on energy
intensive cultivation methods and that
was not going to look at this through
the lens of sustainability and climate
change so I came to work with Flo kana
and I moved from Oakland up to Mendocino
County in the Emerald triangle to really
focus on the promotion of sustainably
produced cannabis and to ensure that the
policies that followed after
legalization would help support those
smaller farmers so what I do now up in
Mendocino is a lot of non cannabis work
helping the greater community whether
that be farming communities nonprofits
healthcare communities better understand
how cannabis can be integrated into what
the work that they're doing to bring a
net benefit to the communities that they
serve that's great
a lot about
farming sustainably and sort of going
back to those smaller farmers can you
tell us how focus on the sustainability
and those small small farmers led you to
becoming engaged with Appalachia
and sort of what that means for these
small farmers in those communities you
also mentioned access for canvass
patients and so maybe if you can talk
about the dynamic between you know
maintaining those smaller markets
sustainability and then also on the
other side access is sort of what
happened industry as a whole
sure so you know one of the things that
we're looking to do in cannabis is to
differentiate right the consumer really
has no idea what quality means coming
out of an illicit marketplace in an
illicit marketplace you don't have a lot
of choice you basically have access to
what is available to you and at the same
time there isn't a lot of opportunity
for scientists and artisans and people
to have an open discussion about what
quality means so under prohibition you
know consumers started looking at
quality as orange hairs tight nugs you
know what does that really even mean in
the grander scheme of things the public
was also led to believe that a higher
THC percentage was indicative of quality
and that's really no surprise under
prohibition if I'm gonna take the risk
of going and buying a product on the
illicit market and engaging in a
criminal activity and I get that product
home and it doesn't give me the euphoric
effect that I was looking for because
it's not high in THC its higher and some
other cannabinoid I'm gonna feel ripped
off I'm gonna feel like I didn't get
what I paid for that the risk wasn't
worth it and because of that through
prohibition cannabis started to be bred
for what people wanted to buy on the
street which was a higher THC cannabis
so one of the benefits of legalization
is that we get a chance to step back and
really start thinking about what makes a
quality cannabis product and I think for
the farmers up in the Emerald triangle
where I work who for a long time have
worked to develop genetics that were in
line with the terroir and where they
were growing because if you're growing
outdoors and you're growing in a
clandestine
method if you lose a whole year's crop
because you didn't pick the right
cultivar to go with the environment in
which you're trying to cultivate that's
it I mean there really was no plan B so
we saw a whole generation multiple
generations of artisanal farmers up in
the Emerald triangle breeding to go with
the environment in which they were
producing cannabis and so now that
things are legal and we're looking to
establish an artisan marketplace it is
very important that we look to how other
products have been designated as
artisanal through four centuries and
that really brings us back to the
Appalachians program and looking at how
burgundy and Champaign and port were
protected by looking at the terroir and
the environment in which these products
were produced and making the designation
that certain products can only be deemed
with certain labels if they're part of
that terroir so it really fits it very
very well to cannabis given the
artisanal qualities that have been
developed through Prohibition you know
prohibition did give us something you
know it gave us this wide array of very
very specifically produced cultivars
that we may not have had if cannabis had
gone the way of conventional agriculture
from the very beginning so getting to
your question about access I think it's
less about access to an amount of
cannabis and more about access to a
certain type of cannabis so one of the
things that we see with this artisanal
cultivation are novel cannabinoids
cannabinoids that aren't being
mass-produced that are extremely
beneficial for certain therapeutic
reasons so an example I'll give is THC v
THC v is a novel cannabinoid that is not
found in many cultivars on the market it
is found in very high amounts in a
cultivar that is produced by emerald
spirit botanicals in Mendocino County
called pink boost goddess so that is a
very unique cultivar it is produced in a
small batch but it has a very high
therapeutic potential so you know
allowing these small arts
you know farmers to take advantage of
their terroir and to produce these
cultivars that may not have broad
commercial appeal but a very specific
therapeutic potential I think is really
going to help patients you'd better meet
their needs and they could with this
kind of broad stroke blue dream 21
percent THC approach that we're seeing
more in the mass market place absolutely
no consistency between the term blue
dream between different areas different
jurisdictions exactly exactly so we're
looking at less like just Merlot which
can taste very different depending on
where it comes from and burgundy which
could only be called that if it's
produced in the birdie region of France
from these very specific vines in a very
specific type of site yeah and while
it's important for something like the
wine industry the buzz that you might
get from a burgundy versus a general
Merlot may be similar but you have
different case and it sounds like for
the camp ministry you're talking about
really fundamentally different effects
and so potentially even a more important
concept in the cannabis industry because
you're talking about being able to
differentiate and consumer knowledge
around differentiated effects absolutely
and to that point you know when it comes
to how the product is produced I think
that we're talking more about that the
land and the terroir but when we're
talking about effect I think we're
talking about the difference between
like mezcal and Coors Light right and so
they're both alcohol but folks report
very different effects from hard liquor
her liquors with in hard liquors and so
that's something that I'm excited about
because I think that under Prohibition
the cannabis pain consuming community
had no way to take advantage of these
very specific differences between
cultivators absolutely use the word term
terroir a few times could you just let
us know in the audience can you let us
know what the definition of a terroir is
just I know it's a very sort of
complicated term that has
possibilities in there and then the sort
of the connection between the term
terroir and then sort of oh the overall
apple juice the term of Appalachians
sure so terroir basically refers to the
environment in which the product is
produced so we're talking about the soil
we're talking about the air we're
talking about the Sun the moon the water
basically the natural elements that come
into contact with that plant and the
belief is that the combination of those
elements in the place where that plant
is being produced can result in a very
different outcome for that plant than if
it was produced somewhere else and so
for example for talking about a cultivar
let's say like lemon tree if you grow
lemon tree on one side of the hill you
may get a very different effect that
outcome of the plant than if you grow it
on the other side of the hill just under
the Sun hits the soil the acidity of the
soil the wetness of the soil and so part
of the process of establishing is
determining where these terroir regions
are located and something that's really
interesting is that terroir doesn't
necessarily follow with political
boundaries of counties so you could have
an area of terroir that spans two or
three counties but still is considered
terroir and I think that's something
that's going to be really interesting as
we start this process of developing
Appalachians is to look and see how
terroir doesn't does not confer conform
to political county boundary lines and
so you know the land is really what
drives the terroir designation and
figuring out which Appalachians
encompass not just terroir but the
practices that come out of that terroir
for that community so if you have soil
that's extremely acidic then you may
have a community practice that involves
amending that soil through natural means
in order to establish a more hospitable
cultivation environment but everyone in
that terroir is engaging in that same
practice so it maintains the uniformity
of the plant
absolutely you mentioned sort of the
benefits to local communities into
farmers that are have spent you know the
last decades cultivating certain forms
of cultivars that maybe weren't as
attractive to the overall illicit market
because of this lack of knowledge for
the consumer could you tell us a little
bit about the potential effect that
Appalachians protection for certain
terms would have for those farmers for
those communities for the sustainability
of farming as a as an industry and as a
means of someone's livelihood especially
coming from a company like flow Cana
that many of us here down in the Bay
Area of you has kind of a conduit to
those small farmers you know
representative a sort of a
conglomeration of those farmers can you
tell us what it means for the industry
itself well I think it means a lot from
both ends and I think that that's a
really important part to remember you
know from the production end it means a
lot because it allows the farmers to
better categorize and describe what
they're doing and know that that
description is going to be uniformly
accepted so you know folks are talking
about dry farming for example which is
using no additional water at all but
basically tapping into the watershed
that's already underneath the ground in
it results in the most amazing tasting
cannabis similarly to dry farmed wine
you really have you know retain a lot of
those terpenoids and flavonoids you're
not adding water so folks that are able
to dry farm want to be able to talk
about that process and have it be
universally accepted and acknowledged of
what that means for the quality of their
product and that follows down the supply
chain so folks like flow Cana can market
that and use that in branding and then
the consumer at the other end
understands what that means because it's
a protected term that you could only use
if you're doing a very specific type of
farming and so they're able to go and
feel confident when they go into a
dispensary that if something says it's
dry farmed they're gonna get those
terpenes and flavonoids and though
impacts in the plant that they're
expecting given what we're telling them
dry farming does so it creates this kind
of reliability and validity all the way
through the supply chain so that allows
the artisanal farmers to more explicitly
and accurately talk about what they do
it allows us to more accurately an
explicitly market and brand what those
farmers have to offer and it allows the
consumer to more accurately and
explicitly get the product that they
want and to be able to make that choice
at the counter to say I'm gonna choose
the product that has had the least
impact on the environment from the
farmer that's taking the most care and
stewardship of their land and that's
producing this cultivar that I know is
not going to taste like this or look
like this
unless it was produced in that region
and that's the system that we're trying
to set up and look just like wine not
everybody's gonna be like I want the dry
farmed artisanal terroir cannabis
there's absolutely going to be room in
the marketplace for a more mass-produced
general product and that's ok and we
need it all right in order to have a
balanced market that has something for
everyone but establishing that artisanal
marketplace is what is gonna be very
important for the farmers that are
farming in 2,500 square feet of land or
5,000 square feet of land or who are
only doing sun-grown which means they're
getting one crop a year versus someone
that's growing in a large all season
greenhouse it is getting six crops a
year we have to develop a system for the
marketplace to hold up that small batch
crop as special unique and in demand
absolutely and so really we're talking
about to more easily differentiate the
market in some of those large producers
these greenhouses no matter whether
they're in Southern California in the
middle of a desert in Northern
California in the middle of Oakland
those products are generally coming out
fairly similar because they're able to
control all the environmental inputs and
you're you're basically saying that
those farmers that are toiling in the
soil
son that have these very specific inputs
that are very different from those large
greenhouses are those large warehouses
they're in or crows they should be be
able to have an easy way to
differentiate their product absolutely
and to talk about who they are as
farmers you know a lot of prohibition
the farmers were ignored right it was
like the cannabis just suddenly appeared
at the dispensary or appeared in the
dealer's hands or the sellers hands on
the street and I think that the
appellation program is going to be a
wonderful way too far for farmers to
finally get the recognition of the very
specific methods that they've been using
to limit their impact on the environment
and to produce a very unique high
quality product it's a very important
story it's something that lends itself
outside of cannabis farming into food
farming and we really hope that this
will help consumers start asking these
questions about their food and not just
their cannabis you know we don't see
this as being a silo of cannabis and
sustainability but rather a gateway to a
further discussion about sustainability
and artisanal II produced food products
the positives of the appellations
projects are there any aspects of this
that are sort of controversial we saw
the CDFA regs drops on February 20th I
believe have there been any points in
there or are they missing anything that
you think should be included in this
baseline well I think one of the big
discussions is going to be what is
terroir and I think within that
discussion one of the big points that
we're gonna have to have more discussion
on is the use of unamended natural soil
native soil you know there are folks who
have been growing in the ground but have
been amending those soils for decades
because of inhospitable growing
environments so now the question is does
that amendment preclude them from
claiming appellation designation does it
have to be the soils been untouched or
can we say there's a certain percentage
of native soil or if you've been
amending the soil but you've been using
amendments that come from your
environment over a certain amount of
time does that now cow
what about people that grow in smart
pots are they going to have to go into
the soil in order to be considered an
appellation even if they're producing
under full Sun so I think that's one
discussion that's going to have to
happen and then the other is going to
have to be the difference between a
geographic indicator in an Appalachian
because you can definitely have
Geographic indicators that we do for
wine and if you're growing in an
all-season greenhouse in Oakland you can
still have a geographic indicator that
tells people that this product was
produced in Oakland not the same as an
appellation so I think there's gonna
have to be some discussion including
legal discussion about how we really
operationalize appellation versus
geographic indicator yeah and that's a
really good point because right in terms
of the consumer I live here in Oakland
in terms of the consumer being produced
in Oakland within opens borders and
employing Oakland residents can be very
important to that consumer and you know
know exactly is there so last question
thank you so much for all those
information and last question is there
anything any sort of discussion any
person that you're really particularly
interested in hearing from at this April
2nd event that we're gonna hold online
any any sort of thing that you're
particularly excited about well all of
it
I have to say I'm so excited about the
lineup of speakers I've said a few times
I feel like it's getting the band back
together because you've really found a
lot of folks who've been doing this a
long time and I think that one of the
big pieces of value that all of us will
bring to the discussion is a recognition
and an observation of the evolution you
know none of us came into this yesterday
and I think on average the speakers have
probably been doing this for at least a
decade or more so I think that we've
really seen the evolution through
prohibition and legalization and can
really speak to that in the larger
context of the past 20 years rather than
just kind of since 2016 yeah no that's
we try to get that historical context
because especially in issues like this
they affect legacy markets small farmers
business you know that that
perspective and that perspective that
has some developments and evolution over
time so thank you so much for your time
this morning and we really look to see
you on April 2nd we can't wait to have
you and it's gonna be sort of a grand
experiment along with the rest of our
work from home last moment but we're
really excited to happen so thank you
again I look forward to it thanks