[Music]
you have enough to put out there on the
market yeah for sure and you're out
there shopping these guys getting them
and pick it up so how much do you do as
original brand to your own versus a
white label for laughing yeah well
that's a moving target as well you know
because just coming into the compliance
legal market and form a distribution
we're still kind of getting our feet wet
so as we're opening new accounts still
small business cash flows King
so I'm outsourcing and just bulking out
and white label and selling to
manufacturers as much as I can right now
to keep cash flow going and to still
open doors on stores and I'd say we
probably have a pretty extensive menu
compared to other brands on the market
and we have over 60 SKUs Co a shelf
ready and that's still probably again
probably bout 25% of my production yeah
so hopefully that will change and as we
get more market share
I will provide less material or
specialized on material because it's
great to have good relationships it's
great to thrive with a thriving brand
and so I'm happy to work with you know
people like poplin Barclays and be one
of their tried-and-true farmers and that
helps build my brand as well because
they have a good brand equity so we help
build each other up and I think there
will always be a balance where I won't
always just be like oh I'm gonna build
my brand in ya know find a new supplier
I always want to keep those
relationships and have a good place in
the brand for me and I'd also like to
look at limited release you know I mean
this is a seasonal product you know I'm
not I'm just trying to be something
that's on the Shelf with the same exact
product year round it's like get it
while it's hot there's something there
there's a hey there's a formula there
when you make a drop people know it's
coming and they're like oh it's not
gonna be around next month so I better
get all I can and we're seeing that in
other industries right it's funny you
point that out because the clothing
industry has moved towards that like
just limit it no matter if it's kicks
acres or if it's clothing lines and it's
interesting you point that after be area
yeah craft beers the same way and I'm
like it I'm mice self-proclaimed canis
or so every time a season ends I
actually pull out last year's crop like
I just from hidden Prairie farm I just
took out summer blue skittles which he
knows a bit trendy but there was
something about her blue skittles and
it's just like I bust that out this
season and was able to obviously
preserve it thanks to the seal on mason
jars and what we put our product that we
put out but there are enough canisters
to your point there like that is coveted
like that's that was the strain that
worked for me that worked for my
endocannabinoid system I don't know
about how I reacted to yours so I agree
with you I could see people like this is
a limited edition I got to pick it up
and I'm all about I mean I love
supporting the farmer but yeah I'll pay
20 30 40 percent more over what a
typical lathe goes for typical ounce
goes for if it means getting quality
fire you know just like that bottle of
wine from 2003 it's the same thing yeah
so very cool so yeah and that's another
part of my strategy is trying to get
ahead on the strain releases and
hopefully we'll have a hot new strain
and that season before everybody has it
and then get that out and go that was
that we're on to the next one you got to
get it while it's here so hopefully well
it'll all work out in that way
[Music]