[Music]
our local perspective we have Tim karti
legislative representative for the
league of California cities Cara
Martinson California State Association
of counties Chief Ron Lawrence chief of
police for Citrus Heights Police
Department Captain Jer alejandre san
waen county sheriff's office thank you
all for joining us this morning the
league as you know was very active in
helping craft and Shepherd the uh
medical cannabis regulation and safety
act and uh we have a set of priorities
with regard to the passage of
proposition 64 and the reconciliation
first we think it is essential to
establish a means of verifying local
compliance prior to the issuance of a
state license the medical Act was very
clear on this local approval was
absolutely required prior to applying
for a state license prop 64 on the other
hand expressly states that applicants
are not required to submit evidence of
local approval with the state
application there is however another
provision saying that state license
cannot be issued if it's in violation of
local ordinances so even uh with that
provision the way it's written uh state
agencies are going to be in the
unfortunate position of having to chase
after individual local jurisdictions to
get their licenses and then
unfortunately interpret them unless
there's a change in the law so we have
um helped develop language that we think
would uh meaningfully restore a means of
verifying local compliance to avoid
problems with licenses being issued uh
when they're not uh in in concert with
what the local regulatory structure
is second we would uh ask the
legislature to bear in mind the likely
Federal reaction and crafting various
parts of the regulatory structure
reconciling prop 64 with the medical act
we do know from uh the coal memo and
other uh sources from the Department of
Justice that two of the federal litmus
tests are diversion and
inversion inversion uh helping to
facilitate the mixing of illegal
unregulated product with legal regulated
product and uh export outside California
now the small growers association has
stated public that currently California
consumes only 30% of what it produces so
the other 70% is already going out of
state so there is an issue with respect
to likely Federal intervention just on
the amount of product that's being
generated in that regard we would urge
caution in approving type five licenses
which allow for unlimited cultivation in
5 years without some further uh
restrictions for example a certification
by the department of food and egg that
there is some supply side problem with
the current amount of cultivation
underway in California Colorado is being
sued on this basis Alone by neighboring
states right
now something to bear in mind we would
respectfully urge caution in deciding
upon how products will be distributed in
California distribution whether it is
vertical
integration uh or uh mandatory
thirdparty distribution should have
sufficient regulatory components and
controls in place to ensure compliance
both with state law
as well as to facilitate Federal
enforcement for any
violations one of the things that we
think would be helpful would be uniform
uh required electronic
manifests finally cities have no
interest in crafting local regulations
particularly in regard to uh cities that
have embraced this change in law and are
looking at it as a potential source of
Revenue to replace State subsidies such
as the loss of Redevelopment and
Enterprise zones they have no interest
in crafting local regulation
engaging in Planning and Zoning
activities to allow these facilities
affirmatively permitting them and
finally developing a local tax structure
only to have the federal government
sweep in and shut it all down so we
would urge caution in how this is all uh
arranged in the future in regard to any
reconciliation finally a note on the uh
the tax rate the tax rate is there's a
state excise tax of 15% the league
opposed similar legislation last year
Senate Bill 987 simply because we
thought it was too high 10% would be a
little more reasonable and we oppose
that for two reasons one we are
concerned about the stimulation of Black
Market activity and second we uh were
bearing in mind the cumulative tax rate
and the fact that local governments may
want to add on their own local taxes and
15% certainly seem to crowd that out the
possibility for those additional um
local tax measures now in educating our
members about this change in law we have
urged that they look at local existing
local tax measures to see if there are
any um Revenue structures excuse me
revenue streams that uh can be
established that are marijuana related
before they rush to enact some new form
of local tax having said that the 15%
tax rate uh in in the long term is
probably going to need to be lowered
that concludes my remarks thank
you thank you good please thank you good
morning Cara Martinson with the
California State Association of counties
thank you so much for um um having us
come speak to you today and provide some
feedback and I really do appreciate the
conversation and some of the comments
that were made by previous panels
because I think they highlight some of
the issues that the league and seesac
are continuing uh to focus on um we were
very involved in the development of the
mcrsa and were able to provide some
early and initial input into prop 64 and
that local control piece was extremely
important to local governments and while
we recognize uh that it's difficult to
manage 58 counties and 480 some cities
um different regulatory programs we
thought that that was necessary uh for
uh jurisdictions to be able to reflect
the will of their community so there is
a lot happening at the local level uh
and uh I think we can tell by where prop
64 passed about two-thirds of California
counties voted in favor of proposition
64 and we do think that will be somewhat
reflective of how cannabis is regulated
at the local level with that local
control piece uh in there uh as I
mentioned there's a lot of activity
happening right now uh within the city
and county level just as a snapshot uh I
believe there were 53 local City and
County ballot measures on the November
2016 ballot related to cannabis 39 of
those successful and out of those there
were seven County tax measures so in
addition to uh what the um prop 64
already sets into statute
so Folks at the local level are thinking
about this uh they're working with the
uh regulatory agencies that were up here
and I would like to thank them for their
Outreach um to us and being available to
answer our questions uh because that
coordination is going to be extremely
important uh in order for the state to
meet its statutory obligation of issuing
licenses January 1 2018 local
governments are going to have to have
their programs in place as well uh so we
have a vested interest in uh seeing the
state be successful and have them
achieve their goals so that we are able
to do that as well at the local level uh
but we do have a concern related to
timing because of of the urgency uh and
uh drafts still out there and that we
haven't seen yet and we would uh
encourage the agencies to continue to
outreach to us because there are a
number of counties out there that are
ahead of the curve that have been uh
working on medical marijuana have
developed their own track and Trace
programs that have um develop their own
licensing schemes uh so we feel that we
uh have a lot of expertise in this area
in some jurisdictions and can offer uh
comments and input into that regulatory
process um in addition as some of um the
other fellow panelists have made
comments uh and I won't reiterate but
there are are many differences between
the mcrsa and prop 64 in addition to the
local licensing piece um we've heard a
lot about the role of the ad
commissioner
and the role of environmental health
directors and we're very interested to
see what those draft regulations look
like and if they contemplate a role for
our department heads in any type of um
state regulatory scheme uh that will be
very important to coordinate with us
obviously uh we're also very concerned
about enforcement at the local level and
who takes care of that and what that
piece looks like and I'm sure um some of
my colleagues on the law enforcement
side will touch on that and then finally
I do think the revenue collect ction uh
and the banking component of this
conversation is extremely important and
probably one of our most challenging
issues uh if I do say so myself um
seesac and my boss Matt K sits on the
treasurers banking working group and we
are committed to working with all those
entities involved to develop an interim
solution uh I think it's fair to say
that there is an extreme amount of
uncertainty at the federal level uh and
as we wait uh for clarity and guidance
we will and we are also working on
implementing our program and so we need
to be thinking about um how we deal with
that cash situation it's my
understanding that there are only two
Boe districts that accept cash and
likewise at the county level with the
treasurers uh Tax Collectors at the
counter they're not equipped to deal
with the amount of cash uh that we'll be
collecting if there is also a local tax
measure in place so uh we're working
with Folks at the level talking to Folks
at the state level and trying to develop
some Creative Solutions uh to that
challenging and nuanced uh problem but
again thank you uh for having me here
today and happy to answer any questions
and look forward to the continued
partnership yeah thank you and thank you
for your testimony I'm glad to hear the
Departments are working well with both
entities but yeah I don't know captain
or chief if you whoever would like to
begin first Chief thank you sir good
morning chairman Salis and members of
this critically important joint
oversight hearing uh thank you for
including the perspective of local law
enforcement on this panel my name is Ron
Lawrence I'm the police chief of the
city of Citrus Heights I'm also the
third vice president for the California
police Chiefs Association of whom I'm
here talking on behalf of today as a
Statewide Association the California
police Chiefs find ourselves in the
interesting situation of supporting the
medical marijuana legislation signed by
Governor Brown in 2015 and we strongly
opposed proposition 64 for a wide
variety of reasons we now join many of
the stakeholders here today in working
together to B balance the often
conflicting interests behind the mcrsa
and the a AUM to develop one regulatory
structure for cannabis in doing so
California police Chiefs will continue
to advocate for absolute local control
dual state and local licensing limits on
vertical integration and cross Li chist
licensing and thorough background checks
for
lenses however in ushering in the
commercial structure of marijuana
through ballot initiative brings a new
set of problems as police Chiefs have
challenges and issues facing us and we
look forward to working with you and all
the stakeholders at getting them
addressed uh I'm going to stick with
five fundamental overarching concerns
that the police Chiefs have and I'm
going to keep them in very brief summary
first and foremost is for us to protect
local control each of our communities is
is vastly and wildly uh unique and
different with different sets of
expectations and our po policy makers at
the local level the city councils and
our Board of Supervisors must have the
the latitude and the agility to craft
policy and ordinances that best suit the
needs and expectation of their of our
local communities secondly the
commercial system is one based on
increased use and sales it is critical
that stakeholders work together to deter
identify and success successfully
prosecute marijuana impaired driving the
CHP spoke very eloquently about that so
I won't uh speak too much more on that
but it is important issue to California
police Chiefs number three advertising
and branding are sure to come with the
newly established for-profit industry we
urge all of us to prevent our history
with the tobacco industry and its impact
on our youth from repeating itself to
ensure that Joe cannabis or marijuana
man don't crop up and become common
fixtures in our society we are very
supportive of the regulations
surrounding proper packaging of Edibles
and the non-advertising to our
youth number four state and local law
enforcement entities in our Criminal
Justice System need to work across
jurisdictional boundaries
to ensure that our legal justice system
is not exploited to embolden the black
market number five and lastly we cannot
ignore the inflexible nature of a ballot
initiative as new challenges and needs
present themselves we will be
hardpressed to identify solutions that
do not conflict with the language in
proposition 64 this will require all of
us to have creative thinking uh all of
us leaders and stakeholders who cannot
be deterred from solving real problems
as a result of the initiative stringent
Amendment language Mr chair chairman on
behalf of the California police Chiefs
Association we look forward to working
with you and all the stakeholders moving
this forward thank you and thank you for
that perspective let's go to move to uh
Captain if you will please good morning
Captain J alandre sing County Sheriff's
Office also representing the Cal State
Sheriff's Association uh Mr Mr chair
Madam chair thank you subcommittee thank
you very much for this opportunity to
speak as Chief Lawrence just elely put
that we agree with what the Cal State
chair Chiefs of Police Association agree
with and sentiments on on their concerns
on there I'm kind of here as a more of a
boots on the ground I work a task force
that deals with narcotics and stuff and
so our our the goals are looking we're
developing policy and procedures now to
follow the new laws as written to
provide best service to community while
upholding the law of the state and the
public safety is number
one I was fortunate enough to go to
Colorado during July to meet with the
Colorado Chiefs of police and other
leagues leagues of supporting and
supportive that to understand what the
impact had occurred in there from what
we've learned from that and we believed
we anticipate increase in the marijuana
activity in several areas including that
L the black market it's still rampant
there um drug driving is a concern
obviously vehicle accidents the rise
that occurred from this marijuana use in
in and near schools and parks increas in
emergency room business due to toxicity
overdoses and psychotic episodes that
will come for
this you know it's we're kind of at
right now we've unknown as to where the
licensing regulation agencies are going
to be as we learned in col as they
learned in Colorado one key component
they did is law enforcement was tied
directly with the regulatory agency so
they created a task force as you would
to work with them because they are you
can be dealing with a
dangerous commodity in here so it's a
concern so we look forward to developing
relationship with regulatory board and
states and with local things um the
another concern will be they they talked
about us the pesticides found in there
currently going to as we do is we
eradicate marijuana cultivation sites
right now as we go to these sites we are
finding common house household
pesticides in there you can purchase at
Home Depot so that's obviously going to
be a concern for the Regulatory Agencies
and who while they'll deal with that
um as you know it's you cigarette
smoking is banned in C in different
areas just like the smoking of marijuana
is banned in areas well that is a hard
road to to enforce as you see because
with the new vaporizing cigarettes
you're really not sure what people are
smoking and so it's going to be an
interesting challenge as law enforcement
to work on
that just in general and just to give
you a rough ideaas my county is in The
Last 5 Years in the last 5 years we have
eradicated illegal cultivation grows
650,000
plants um that is involving 525 cases
just just say and that was in The Last
Five Years on there so the the hopeful
with this is that we move forward and
and the different areas work together
the other thing is with these regulatory
commissions with the Department of
Justice years back we had the Bureau of
Narcotics enforcement as a regulatory
arm with them that would probably be
very helpful in having a a creation of
that again to help work with these
bureaus in the uh dealing with these
issues thank
you ATF or something okay thank you
thank you for your testimony why don't
we uh just get the questions right where
we left off with Public Safety and you
know I'm just curious to see what you
guys are doing uh locally you you've
mentioned uh some of the things I know
you mentioned perhaps from the previous
panel we talked about the uh the
advisory committee and so I would
imagine you guys would want to play a
part in the advisory committee I know
when you said you went to Colorado was a
task force but here in California we
have that advisory committee so
hopefully we can uh see if we can
connect that I would imagine law
enforcement would want to be a part of
the advisory committee uh just given the
amount of questions I always get back
home I would imagine you get the same
questions as well throughout the entire
State and throughout your associations
question centers around for the local
land use and for our law enforcement
professionals um how we ensure that we
don't have a mild distribution of
marijuana related activities let me
speak specifically to what I'm concerned
about in the area of Los Angeles that I
represent known as South Los Angeles we
have too many liquor stores so much so
that we have a moratorium on New on and
offsite liquor licensing and we have
substantial
conditions as a part of getting a new
license or renewing a license or even
the transfer of a license that process
includes our local planning department
and the state Alcohol Beverage Control
Commission and there's effectively a
moratorium on the issuance of new
licenses despite that we still have
concentrations of liquor in South Los
Angeles that are disproportionately high
to the population it require eventually
that we change state law how do we
prevent marijuana businesses
particularly the retail customer facing
businesses that's the great concern that
I have for as an urban legislator from
being overc concentrated in certain
communities well let me if I don't mind
I'll go first on this in the visit to
Colorado that is a strong concern and
problem they actually do have with that
the concentration in the lower economic
areas and urban areas
of the city the cities is where the
highly concentrated areas of these s so
with local local bands the ability to
the local bands and the regulations on
that we can they can probably start
specifying specific areas of how many
per area to grow which was the
opportunity we will need to do okay I'll
just jump in really quick Cara Martinson
with um the California State Association
of counties I think that's an excellent
point and I think that was really sort
of the Genesis of our local control
argument
within specifically prop 64 it's
extremely important for local
jurisdictions to decide a do they want
to regulate or do they want to ban they
need to um make that decision uh from
the will of the community if you will uh
and then what that local land use and
and Zoning looks like and that is um a
process that a lot of folks are going
through now at the local level uh
identifying sensitive use areas
obviously we don't want these facilities
next to schools or children or other
areas so uh that is in some instances we
don't want these facilities honestly
near anybody and not in any substitute
in any substantial concentration so my
question would be is there a deficiency
in the adult medical use act prop 64
that might invite State legislation that
says per capita you don't have more than
x amount of dispensaries is it a
thousand people is it is it in relation
to a physical place that you're talking
about sensitive use because that's my
concern that Western Avenue crenchaw
Boulevard Pico and Olympic are going to
be concentrated by more and more
nuisance businesses if I could respond U
most of
these is on yeah there we go thank you
um most of the retail businesses are
going to be located within
municipalities and this is where local
control comes in uh it is critically
important and we tell
uh the league is going around doing
trainings to various cities for the prop
64 as we did for the medical act and we
tell them that if you are interested in
controlling this problem it is
absolutely critical and we very often
point to the city of Oakland because the
the problem you're absolutely right the
problem with liquor stores we don't want
uh repeated on uh with respect to
marijuana dispensaries uh there's been
criticism about the number of liquor
stores and over concentration there is
an over concentration statute uh in the
uh code governing the establishment of
liquor licenses which to the best of my
knowledge has rarely have ever been
enforced that uh basically it says a
license shall not be issued if there are
concerns about overc concentration that
statute has been copied into both the
medical act and prop 64 but the real
solution is for locals to be strategic
about uh how they allow these businesses
into their communities if they're going
to allow them and we urg cities to take
a page from City of Oakland what they
did they were very strategic about it
they adopted a per Capal formula for how
many dispensaries they would ultimately
have so if you do that one per 35,000
residents or what have you you will
never have an explosion of businesses
that outgrows your ability to regulate
it the other thing we caution cities is
whether it's a numerical cap or a per
capital formula it is important to set
some kind of a cap because you do not
want uh bearing in mind that this is
still an all cash business you you're
going to have to do audits for a couple
of reasons you're going to want to have
a a handle on the amount of traffic the
amount of product that's being moved the
amount of Revenue that's being generated
and if you have a local tax in place you
are also going to want to know if the
city is getting its fair share of the
revenue based on the total volume of
traffic you will know none of that
unless you have an audit protocol that
is set up to audit 100% of the
businesses
in your jurisdiction on a regular basis
one of the problems they had in Denver
Colorado is they were passing out
permits like hot cakes in the Denver
metropolitan area and the the scope of
the businesses and the traffic quickly
outgrew the ability to audit it and the
FEDS had to come in and do a sting
operation so we caution folks to be very
cautious be strategic if you want a tax
measure put it on the local ballot make
sure it's prop 218 compliant but have a
formula for the number of businesses you
will ultimately have in your
jurisdiction that's the answer to the
question it's a question of local
control but the see so I represent uh uh
three municipalities uh portion of the
city of Englewood the entirety of the
city of Culver City and uh about 200 or
almost 300,000 people in the city of Los
Angeles in the city of Los Angeles there
are five council districts that touch
the assembly district that I have the
privilege to represent each of those
council districts are driven by land use
uh decisions primarily connected to the
local representative and at the time and
place so if a local representative is
interested in seeing many of these
permits issued because of local control
and we seed that authority to them uh
and they leave office and like liquor
stores we end up with a overc
concentration if that statute was copied
into the adult medical use act that we
have uh fatal flaws with respect to uh
overc concentration issue
because in areas it is it is easy to see
it doesn't even take critical analysis
to see the concentration of liquor and
before our proposition D locally which
significantly
reduced um uh dispensaries in particular
we had an over concentration all
throughout South Los Angeles so for the
committee chairs and I know that the
local government committee chairs here
this is something that I will be working
on very closely with each of you to the
extent that you care to because I'm
afraid that my area and and areas
adjacent in South Los Angeles are going
to Bear the brunt of the retail
interaction with uh marijuana users and
dispensaries and they are nuisance
businesses and you cannot adequately
accommodate cleaning them up and it is
different in Los Angeles than anywhere
else the challenges and having cash
businesses is about the biggest nuisance
that anyone who lives in my area or has
been there for any period of time can
understand so that's the perspective of
this legisl who represents a quarter
roughly of South Los Angeles thank you
Mr chairman thank you Mr Ridley Thomas
and um you know I think we heard local
control is a big factor of it and from
our Public Safety also that local
control and I know uh from us was we're
working with the associations but also
with our locals as well making sure that
they have the proper ordinances in place
Miss cabier brought up a good point I
don't know if you want to State it so I
I have a question about who's going to
keep track of all all the local
jurisdictions and so that we know um
what it is that they're doing uh I I'm
with you on on this onec but the
regulatory structure for alcohol is
really different than what is in place
but we have to rely on our locals and
the only way we can do that is if we
know what it is that they've passed and
we know what it is that they're doing
and uh from my my perspective and my
jurisdiction one of the Mayors just
ended up being recalled because of the
vote of the council so the public is
paying a lot of attention
and they're getting very engaged and
they want to know they want to have some
control over this and they weren't happy
with their elected so is there somebody
that will be keeping track of all of the
different decisions that the locals make
and if there's change can change the um
the the um I'm I'm assuming it's going
to be a website or some kind of uh of of
page where you can get that information
there is uh and I I really appreciate
your comments because the police Chiefs
absolutely share your concern with
oversaturation I think there is a model
today uh the ABC for example the
regulatory agency that oversees liquor
licenses before a business can go to a
local community uh that local uh city
council uh and that police chief uh gets
that information from ABC and ABC and
the local have to agree on the the
number of licenses in their community
and and to ensure um that there's not
any oversaturation now they're
responsible to make sure that they deny
them if there is an over saturation but
there is that checks and balances with
liquor stores I hope that our regulatory
act going forward with marijuana will
include a similar model for those
communities that allow it well
unfortunately what happened is that
before that that uh process with the
locals was involved um ABC could could
uh award as many licenses as possible so
many of our communities are really
challenged because we already have over
concentration and it wasn't until the
public uh uh necessity um condition was
placed on local governments that it gave
local governments the opportunity to to
have that dialogue and to discuss it but
I'm I'm really looking globally at to as
to whether anybody is going to be
keeping data on what the different the
58 counties and the 400 and however many
cities that we have so that we can look
at it to see what it is that has been
done um within the state of California
just for our own purposes and that's an
excellent point um I think uh in
addition to our associations that are
working to do that uh there is a need
think for an entity uh at the state
level there is a advisory committee as
was stated that's required by uh 64 uh
but the the local licensing piece isn't
clear in 64 as it is in the mcrsa and so
we're waiting to see what those draft
regulations look like uh obviously the
state cannot issue a license that's in
conflict with the local ordinance uh but
how they find that out and who keeps
that information and what that looks
like is extremely important as we move
forward but I seesack and the league I
know are committed uh to working on this
issue and we do have ideas uh uh about
how we can fill that void yeah I think
what we're trying to do is make sure we
don't all collect this information and
keep it within our own Association when
obviously there's a a bigger uh need to
share that information with everyone and
perhaps uh Miss Ajax will help
coordinate some of that when she's
drafting the regulations see who's doing
what but that we'd have to ensure at the
state level that we're not in conflict
with the locals as well and so uh Mr
wood has a additional question well
actually just more of a a comment and
obviously as we see wait to see the how
how this plays out with the certainly
mcrsa was very very had a very different
Vision than prop 64 around local control
some of the some of those issues so
we'll see how this how this plays out
and so as someone who worked on that
I've I have a vested interest in in in
in that as well but I would just like to
comment too that you know and I
appreciate I appreciate my colleague and
the challenges they're obviously having
in Los Angeles and in some of his
neighborhoods however there are other
jurisdictions cities and counties who
have have taken a different approaches
who have seen that that while the the
businesses that some of the businesses
may be nuisances in in in your
neighborhoods they've actually been good
corporate citizens and Cooperative with
jurisdictions in other in other areas
and so uh it's not it's it's not all bad
it's it's actually there there are a lot
of folks that are actually good
corporate citizens and and and play well
with their communities are actually
embraced by their communities for for
what do so so how we marry that all
together and um and and make it work but
I would agree that I don't think anybody
wants to see an overc concentration of
anything and the liquor laws I mean I
represent a city uh that that has 25
tasting rooms downtown uh for wine and
and uh and while everybody talks about
overc concentration and and the ABC
regulations that's never come into play
it's never been an issue and you know
there there'll be another another one or
two that are probably approved this year
because because that's the nature of the
Beast so how we approach this this is is
uh is going to be very interesting going
forward so thank you thank you so I
think this issues was raised in the last
panel and this panel so obviously
there's a lot of interest from the
legislature and making sure how this is
all rode out but appreciate all of your
comments and thank you for answering
questions
[Music]