it would it made me realize the
vulnerability of what we do and as I was
going into the hospital I was just like
man who's gonna yeah who's gonna fuck
with my stock and it's yeah yeah and I
know the crew is gonna water but it was
what do they do with my genetics stop
fundamentally what do you do with all
the material you've worked with and what
do you do with the the the stuff that
you spend all these years on and that's
what maybe you realize whoa we need to
be able to start figuring out how to
Bank stuff and how to get people to work
with it and and how do you expand the
circle you're with and and for me it's
like a you career because if you're not
I don't want to even talk to you on this
level because you don't catch it you
don't really catch the amount of work
that went into it everybody's like I
want your shit I want your shit and so
that's not that's not what I'm looking
for is I'm not looking for anybody shit
I got plenty of my own shit I've been
moving stock for a long time I don't
have problem moving genetic material I
don't have a problem acquiring genetic
material and for the people that I
started out in breeding and all these
different companies that I fed them to I
didn't screw them when I gave it to him
I said listen I'm gonna give you some
killer shit it's gonna let you move
forward and it was basically based off I
thought you a good person so for me if I
play with you I just have to hang out
with you for a while I want to have
lunch with you I want to see how you
treat people I want to see how you treat
your workers I want to see how you treat
the fucking waiter because if you're a
dick there you're gonna be a dick to me
too straight up everybody's a superstar
now and everybody's got a scene and
everybody somebody and everybody's gonna
do the thing and it doesn't mean shit to
me man I've been around money my whole
life and we were all career criminal
black market guys so we made a lot of
fuckin money when money was to be made
and and in throwing it around and in big
long ziplock containers that you were
pulling out of the trucks that you had
hidden in the yard that that lets you
become immune to cash and so money is a
tool now and there's less disposable
money now but I'm not in any kind of
economic bad situation I own all my shit
and I'm a sole owner of all my
investments and then I partnered with
Parker and the guys that you met and
because they have a stunning facility
and they asked me to come in and said
hey would you be able to be our partner
on this operation and I just said hey it
would allow me to shut
my other facility turn it into another
form of entity and then we can combine
that as a combined aggregate so now I
cause I can hold multiple permits you
guys can hold more events I already have
all permits in play so let's adjust the
permits so that we can team up and not
have redundant shit I don't need to have
my own nursery and then operate your
nursery
I'll just operate your nursery and then
I'll go at it with this and so Parker is
successful from tech industry in terms
of putting together money packages in
tech he gets into cannabis but the kids
shark and he's a work demon and then my
other partner is aerospace engineer from
los alamos weapons labs so I have a
basically you on musk where he can't put
velcro shoes on but he can split an atom
with a butter knife in the backyard and
then we have a good staff that I brought
in that I've been existing Lee working
with we put the new dispensary together
at that new facility so we have a
beautiful facility right on the highway
and then we have a new mega lab going in
for distillate crude production so a
whole facility going in and then I have
another processing manufacturing
facility we're building on acreage we
already onto so we have all these pieces
in play and it's all happening and so it
lets me play different to where I have
14 these work with a lot of people and I
turn it down because I'm like you guys
are looking at short term money and what
am I gonna do next and yeah you're gonna
get paid but I'm already paid I'm not
broke now so what are you offering me
well you know I mean everybody's like
these people hold the money I had an
offer from the green house seat I knew
Franco right but they Franco flies in
and says hey my boss wants you to do
seed production for us because we're
gonna pay you $100,000 and I start
laughing and I'm like you know I got a
giant outdoor farm you realize 100
grands a single pull off a debt so
you're gonna make me commit to a year at
work for a fucking hundred K and he was
like no you don't understand it's a
hundred K and I says I don't think you
understand we got 100 K in a paint
bucket right here on the floor with
different guys you know I'm a little
different guys and so Franco laughed and
he ended up getting a bunch of genetics
from me and went back to Europe and then
Franco and I maintained a pretty good
friendship so he would send me a genetic
material from Europe and I'd send it
back to him
and then he dies the malaria but it let
me understand I asked him why don't you
do this in Africa where you can screw
them over and he said we tried but the
Africans nationalized our operation and
screwed us and so I said that's exactly
what you deserve you can't do that shit
and that's what I see right now is the
same abusive stuff and everybody's
waving money and so I go to a lot of
these lectures people have me come in
and they don't want me to talk about
cultivation they want me to talk about
state of mind and I tell people don't
mortgage your house right now don't look
at your house and then have an investor
take 52 points off your dollar to play
because that is your margin and all
you're gonna do is get wage and then as
soon as you don't achieve it they'll cut
you out and yes you'll be part owner of
a company that you will not get paid on
because they're gonna sink the goddamn
thing like a ship and so will it to me
I'm just like this is a disastrous
situation and because I've been here my
whole life I have an emotional problem
I'm actually connected to these people
these aren't cats I just hustle with
these are cats I lived with and rolled
with and did business with and all over
the state so we come up to LA to meet
individuals I go to some of these
monster operations and the cat walking
out the doors dudes I already know and
so I'm like holy fuck we really know
each other we traffic for years together
so we're cracking up because I didn't
know they had the new operation and then
they wanted to do the same thing they
said hey can you Bank genetics for us
can you take genetics from us and then
give them back to us in micro form in
Kelowna level so that we can shut down
our nursery operation and then we can
work in these capacity and so I'm like
listen we'll figure it out and that's
the main point of it is to find out can
you have a workable relationship with
other people that are in the same
situation you don't intend to go
anywhere everybody's trying to retire
and then retire and do what somebody
said when are you gonna move from home
boss and I'm like never
yeah and then the other question was
when are you going to get out of weed I
said when I'm dead when I'm dead oh yeah
no I'm no matter how many times I had a
fight a case I never gave up and no
matter how much crap I went through I
never gave up because fundamentally I
love what I do and I love the people
that do it at this kind of level you
your normal people that are abnormal in
your hunger and that's me I'm a regular
person who's abnormally
driven and I don't have any intention to
screw anybody so and I do business
people and look you can vet me and if
you want to do business we can be
friends but I it's all good I'm not
trying to forge a relationship I have I
have one with my kids in my old lady
relationship with me is over time if you
know me now check me out check me out in
the month I'm the same dude check me out
in five years I'm the same dude I still
got the same crew for 20 fucking years
that's how I know it works because the
same guys I'm rolling with now to send
guys I was wrong with then and you can
meet new people but everybody nowadays
is so transient this is very myopic I
only see this and it's gonna be this and
it's gonna be this and I'm like I didn't
want to work at you because it's not
real and it just makes it almost
impossible to have any success when
you're in those situations and no one's
looking at it as a long-term thing they
don't realize this is global situations
for me Humboldt County
I had an ability I got I got access to
the governor soryo office when all the
permitting came on so I had I had I had
a kind of neat situation when Gavin
Newsome came to my greenhouse to hang
out so he comes to LA comes to Oakland
he comes my greenhouse and they sealed
off my whole facility and the cops came
out guns and protected us while we had
lunch and all the county supervisors
were trying to get in but they weren't
invited and I wouldn't let him in the
gates so I pretend as it it's all right
we'll have discussion ourselves and what
it did is it allowed me to work on all
the permitting structures nursery
structures so else I had my hand and all
these permit pieces so I could try to
help create the levels and layers that
were needed for the people in my region
to still succeed because if you can't do
1,500 square foot a canopy which is what
you have available that means you're not
even allowed to be in the industry and
to me that doesn't make any sense and so
even though we're larger than that
that's that's only because we grew from
our lower levels