[Music]
let's go ahead and move on to public
comment if we could have everybody uh
line up that wishes to give public
comment please sir good morning Glenn
bis for drug policy Alliance uh rc4
partner drug policy action was part of
the drafting committee for prop 64 part
of the steering committee for 64 and the
second largest donor to 64 I would like
drug policy Alliance to be a resource to
the committee to the members to the
staff feel free to blow up my phone
thank you thank you appreciate that
please additional public comment yes my
name is Regina Wilson and I am the chair
and executive director of California
black media I would just like to Echo um
assembly member uh Thomas Ridley
Thomas's comments um I do believe that
there is a deep concern um I believe
earlier Mr join Sawyer also pointed to
the lack of Outreach um to the actual
community so I hear a lot of local
governments talking but the community is
not I represent over 22 African-American
own media
Outlets zero conversation zero
invitations to any of the to any of the
meetings to be able to talk about this
it's affected our community in a way
that I mean many of you know how the
drug the War on Drugs have affected our
community and I just believe that um I'm
hoping that I can work with the
committee in some kind of way to talk
about how notices Canen Within These
local communities so that they're a part
of the regul um process yeah no thank
you appreciate that it's going to take a
lot of Partnerships as we continue to
move forward let at this time let me ask
if there's additional public
comment uh hearing and seeing none let
me turn it back to uh members on the dis
for concluding
remarks just thank the chair for putting
this together and uh thank everybody for
their their comments and uh appreciate
really appreciate the update uh I want
to stress again um personal experience
working with everybody associated with
the regulatory process has been very
positive and I look forward to
continuing to work with them as we go
forward thank you Miss cavier again I'd
like to thank the chair as well and to
say that you know um it is interesting
to me to see um how smoothly this is
moving forward um I thought the 18
January 1st 18 day was crazy and people
have worked really hard at trying to uh
make it work um it the best way to do
regulations is not do the emergency
regulation process and so um that we
have that we had people here that um
that represent really important interest
in this industry saying that it's been a
good process so far I think is really
outstanding so there's a lot more work
to be done and they haven't seen the
regulations yet so um that's maybe pre
premature but I want to also recognize
and um and acknowledge the hard work
that's gone on by the um by not only um
the department um uh of Public Health um
the um food nag and also the bureau um
but everybody that's working on this
it's it's a miracle that it we've got
this far and that um people are nodding
their heads and it's going in the right
direction so thank you to
everybody okay thank you let me just say
say thank you as well to everyone that
not only participated but everybody that
uh came in to meet with us individually
as well all the different stakeholders
of groups I mean local police Chiefs
police offic people on the beat I mean
it was uh really everybody from every
Walk of Life and so we do appreciate the
impact that it's having but I do want to
thank uh my two co-chairs and all the
assembly members by my count I think we
had over 25 assembly members attend uh
this morning's hearing and so I want to
publicly acknowledge each of them which
was assembly member wood ciero steinorth
bro matthys W Waldren Grayson Quirk
Silva gray Lackey kie Bloom Eggman D
Holden Chu Gibson Burke Lon aramba Quirk
Joan Sawyer aguar Curry Baker Mr
Sebastian Ridley Thomas if I forgot
anybody I apologize but I think uh that
was a good it was a good showing so
there's a lot of interest here in the
legislature about not only how this is
unfolding and the framework we put
around it but the public safety aspects
as well whether it's around um Edibles
or the amount of dispensaries or where
they're located um also Transportation
you know there is definitely a a concern
here and something that we want to make
sure that one it's not in the hands of
children but also that we're making sure
that our communities are safe and that
this is done responsibly and we'll
continue to not only work on this in our
policy hearings but probably even um
have another informational hearing just
to see how things are going along the
way so with that I will conclude The
Joint informational hearing between the
assembly committee on business and
professions the assembly committee on
health and the assembly committee on
agriculture thank you all for being here
[Music]