[Music]
to started out I figure they all come
from different backgrounds of the
concentrate world so we'll just let them
each kind of give an intro and talk a
little bit about what they do and um
what they're focused on so we'll start
with you Frenchie
H so um all my knowledge of rine I learn
about it traveling the world and I spent
18 20 years of my life traveling and I
spend plenty time in the producing
country where I spend months living with
a
local making Ashish like really really
the the
world concept behind it it's really
picking up the wellness of the
plant and uh I'm trying to bring the
traditional art into into
America trying to find the science
behind what these people I've been doing
for for thousand of years and that takes
a big time of my life otherwise I'm
totally dedicated to to the Emerald
Triangle because as a resine
specialist I am nobody if I don't get
the best
resin and I also believe that in the
Emerald Triangle you have something that
is so unique that you can build up a
system like they exist in a wine
industry where you can literally protect
every small moment P grower because a 4
acre of land in champagne or in Bordeaux
it's a domain it's a chateau it's not
for sale it's Priceless and this you
have it in emal Triangle you have you
have the terar you have the land that is
incredibly Rich you have hundred of
microclimate you have genetic that has
been here in in the norn part of the of
the emerald for two or three generation
and you have an economy that has been
alive for three generation and that are
feeding basically the world northern
part of California the future of
California come from them if you can
protect their land they're going to be
the center of a multi-billion dollar
industry and we have the blueprint in
history book in the in the wine
industry thank you
Frankie very good
uh my name is Justin
pman with a PMP Laboratories uh PMP is
the acronym for purified metabolic
products and uh that is the goal when
you do purifications you know you want
to purify those metabolites using the
highest quality extraction equipment
along with the highest quality um
solvents and a lot of people that make
BHO they are not using high quality
solvents they're using very easily
accessible solvents like over the-
counter aerosol based butanes or lighter
fluid and uh in science that is a big no
no um due to the mere fact that there's
a lot of U dangerous components that are
in those solvents and
um let's
see when it comes to uh even the
equipment that's being used you know a
lot of people they uh they are DIY they
make this uh recapturing equipment uh
out of refrigeration equipment and that
within itself is very dangerous and so
I've tried to bring about knowledge in
the community and other friends of mine
on the importance of starting correctly
and starting with pure products and uh
the importance of that
thank
you hi my name is Mara Gordon I'm the
founder of ant zeldas um we have been
working with concentrates with our
patients for about 5 years now and um we
even at one point had a CO2 machine and
we were setting up the lab we were doing
it and we just didn't find the medicine
to be
as as aous as it could be for people
that were suffering with serious
illnesses we do in fact believe that
there's a place in the market for CO2 no
question about it butane I don't think
there's a place for in the market I I
have our patients I say go ahead and
take this amazingly healthy diet go
ahead and eat all these unbelievably
wonderful Natural Foods I don't then
tell them to spray Pam on their on their
plates before they make their eggs I
wouldn't want them to be put in butane I
don't care how many parts per million
garbage garbage out you don't want to
put poisons into your body when your
immune system is compromised your endoc
canabo system is not working efficiently
and you need to really ramp things up we
have made a commitment as an
organization to stick with ethanol the
190 ethanol the grain alcohol it works
incredible we have beautiful numbers our
medicines we we test each and every
single batch the results are
fantastic in the we have had incidents
where we've had patients where we've had
to go to CO2 because we had to go to an
outside Source outside source with the
most incredible reputation we even use
the same flowers they do the CO2 we do
the ethanol and our patient didn't do as
well so he's like you know what that's a
no-brainer this is all about the
patients this isn't about mass
production and though we are making a
heck of a lot of medicine and there's no
reason why we can't keep ramping up but
you don't have to go to costic
nonorganic nonnatural methods in order
to do that
we also have a commitment to not doing
um we use a whole planed extract and so
that we don't uh strip everything out
through our processes and then add back
in Turkey some people are doing that
there's a lot of call for that
especially in the Smoke Market but in
the uh serious Medical Market definitely
don't recommend
it thank you
Mara my name is hunter green uh
I'm the lab director for w Vapes uh we
are a high-end uh Artisan CO2 oil
company uh with uh Vapor
devices um I'm Jason Beck I'm founder
and director of Alternative urbal Health
Services um we're the oldest dispensary
South of San Francisco in the state
stilling operation I started originally
in 2001 in San Francisco and then the
city of West Hollywood in 2004 asked me
to come down an open up off of a
recommendation from the Board of
Supervisors um I currently have the
largest selection of quality
concentrates in the entire State maybe
even the world as far as I'm concerned
at this point in time um so that's
pretty much it thank you Jason when I
started this I used the phrase resin
specialist and as we were discussing
this panel Frenchie brought up the
importance of a common vocabulary so I
just wanted to ask him and the other
panelists if they'd like to chime in
what is the importance of using certain
vocabulary and what are some other words
that we should be using
Frenchie well to start with we don't
have a common word for unpressed resin
which is the material that every
everybody is using it's called it goes
under Min name from ke with a pretty
pejorative um
connotation to it to ice wax beach
sand and many other like this we really
need to be able to uh to Define every
aspect of what we do I do not extract
resin I collect it by saving it I'm not
an extractor they are and already this
is something big for us we really need
to to to use a common vocabulary to be
able to uh to teach people what we are
doing like we need to be able to have a
quality certification a way to uh to
show what is qu what is a quality in a
raisin to anybody who has no knowledge
of it by by looking at The annotation of
somebody you should be able to
understand what that plant or what that
type of medicine can bring to you it's
like when we don't have a common
knowledge and there is a World Market
opening to us it's a little
sad I would like to say something um
even when it comes to BHO um I think
people need to really understand the
importance of using uh a lighter fluid
based solvent vers um a
99.9% Purity solvent you know and that's
really big especially when it comes to
human
consumption you don't make a medicine by
starting with something that's used to
propel a motor down the
road nice I differentiate from from a
lot of that personally um I myself
suffer from cerebel paly myself just
first of all and and the reality of it
is that extractions need to be called
exactly what they are and they're called
Hy hydrocarbon extractions and that's
basically what it is it's used in pretty
much everything that you that you get
it's how coffee beans become
decaffeinated um it's how you extract
essential oils like lavender perfumes
things like that this is all the same
thing and all people really need to do
is stop open blasting and working with
quality Machinery that is actually made
to keep everything with
inside uh I mean Benzene is a
hydrocarbon but it's also a carcinogen
uh I don't think they fall in this same
category my my my my thing with CO2 is
this is that when you do CO2 you have to
add in artificial tpin into CO2 in order
to give it a tpine profile because when
you blast with CO2 the turpine molecule
separates from the THC molecule so
that's why they have all these different
flavors and different things like that
and that's one of the main reasons that
I don't sell CO2 products is because of
that like CO2 I feel is great for
Edibles and things like that but as far
as for baking I'm not convinced on that
yet you asked a question about common
vocabulary and I think the example here
is that and I think we're all not only
talking about different vocabulary we're
talking about different products and
different markets and different audience
completely so we call it
extracts and we are okay that we're but
we do extracts that's okay you know I I
was going to ask you because I actually
noticed on your website it said you
pulled the medicine from the plant and I
was wondering if you were trying not to
use extract you do me yeah yes no we
absolutely have no problem using the
word extract we do extractions and
infusions we Infuse into like olive oil
or NC oil we in some ways you know like
when you make a a thca for example
there's ways of creating a thca we even
Infuse that into an after it might start
out in an alcohol as aure but it's going
end up in an for proper dosing right I
so you do um it's organic organic grain
alcohol correct now and and you feel
that's the most efficient way to to pull
it out and my question is to pull the
medicine out my question is is that the
best way for to make extractions for all
uses um including like
smokeables do you believe I would say
that the reason that the profiles of the
plants we've got you know there's people
that do it at home in their in their
rice cookers or whatever it is they do
that's not the same operation that we're
talking about it's not the same scale
it's not the same equipment it's not
it's a very much of an art form in
addition to um just the flat out
extracting I me getting it decarbox
correctly to be to have your correct
number of you know the you know do you
want to leave some thca in for example
do you want it for a certain particular
uh designated use so for that the
profile that we end up with when we
extract using the Hy grain alcohol is
closest to the profile that what we see
native in the flowers that we start with
and if we wanting to achieve something
with the plant that we bought we have
this flower we want it to be just a
concentrated version of that basically
in the medicine itself as far as we
actually think that the smokeables I
mean I I do our medicine I smoke our
medicine you know same we into a syringe
I might put into a vape cartridge that
doesn't mean that it's necessarily
correct for everybody and for every
Market but we're doing with very very
seriously ill people and we're creating
profiles we want to be able to do that
using the the the Integrity of the plant
excellent um that leads me into a
question for Hunter so you have at w
Vapes a proprietary turine separation
process now I'm sure you're not going to
give us all the details but um can you
tell us a little bit about that and then
it'll probably open the door for other
people to talk about tpin and well uh
going back to what he was talking about
I do agree with him with most of the CO2
oils on the market uh he's correct in
saying that but now with some advances
in technology uh you can fractionalize
the turpins off to the side postprocess
your oil uh and then reintroduce those
turpins back into the oil giving it a
natural cannabis flavor that's really
really good and do you think that when
you're adding tpin back in what what if
they're not from Cannabis how's the
panel feel about that it's artificial
yeah it's artificial food coloring yeah
it's like adding artificial flavor to
your cereal so so everyone's in
agreement on that natural Canabis Tes
yeah so everybody out there starting a a
non-cannabis tpine company uh maybe not
do
that okay that's the kind of advice that
you'll get here quick question on that
though yes I mean it's aside from from
the Aesthetics and the marketing value
of having it be the same tpin from a
functional point of view are the Tarpin
from another plant different chemically
than the tpin you find in the marijuana
plant all tpin are the same in all plant
products it's the exact same turpine
profile that you'll get in a banana as
if you taste banana that taste flowers
like that it's the exact same turpine
profile I would have a little slightly
different take on that um we also make a
topical that contains 10 essential oils
and so I've done a lot of research on
and we're actually creating we're
starting some drug trials now on some
different things with our with this
particular topical it has in it
essential oils that come from various
other plants that also have the same
resonant tpin that are within the
cannabis plant so we specifically chose
these for that reason but then you start
getting into the chemo type of the
essential oils like we talked about with
our plants what elevation and was it
great was it grown at what was the light
it's going to change change everything
about the things with the plant well you
can look at for example Rosemary and if
Rosemary is grown in one place versus
another place it might have more uh alap
pining in it another place that might
have more of another essential uh
turpine in there and so you have to
actually it's so much more complex than
just whatever is in a banana is in a
banana because then it depends on banana
where did that banana get grown you know
I've had a lot of bananas and they hav't
all taste the same I think that's the
beauty of cannabis you know is that it
has the capability it Jean Pool is so
big to produce so many tpin and banana
flavored vanilla flavored skunk you know
the list goes on and
on it's just and those are other things
that occur in nature as well you know
like the skunk pherone or the smell that
it produces there are strains out there
that very similar you know and it's you
if you were to classify the molecule
they more than likely are the same
thing there is no scientific study that
have actually tried to make the
difference between terpen say lemon
coming from different
plant but at the same
times why would you lose the terpen in
the first place when you are an
extractor especially when you use CO2
and BHO machine that's machine that I
use in industry in the perfume industry
to pick up the most volatile
terpan so if from the beginning you lose
the terpen the game is over the plant is
all about terpen cannabinoid is a teren
compound cannabinoid are made by the
bounding of two molecule terpen and
phenol you lose terpen the game is over
I think you know like in the future I I
think if harvesting
tpin becomes something that be that
gains popularity I think there will be
other methods besides BHO and CO2
extractions you know these are voc's
these are compounds that naturally are
volatile at room temperature and just
under vacuum and you know having a cold
trap you can Harvest
them we have uh one of our extract
artist they have uh one in particular
line that's called uh Divine thorium it
means divine flower in Latin and that
whole line is all blast when it's
blasted it is blasted with actual like
lemon rind strawberries things like that
with the Cannabis and actually enhances
the turpine profile afterwards on your
after hit so then in the after after hit
you taste all strawberry or you taste
all that and because that's all a
natural tpping it can all be mixed like
that
interesting yeah so when we were
discussing this panel also uh Frenchie
brought up an important point about
relationships between cultivators and
and
concentrate manufacturers so I wanted to
see if uh you could talk a little about
that and then I'd like to expand on it
and say uh maybe for Jason how about the
relationship between the concentrate
makers and the dispensary and then to
Justin how about concentrate uh makers
and the manufacturers of the equipment
and basically how can we strengthen
those relationships and and anyone else
can chime in as
well so I work with a small Seed Company
in uh in mandino aish seed and the Ash
is actually a promoting tool for the
genetic you don't look hardly at resin
when you look at flower for me it's the
opposite I never looked at flower so
everything is about the resin so that
when you bring genetic to somebody and
you can show the flower and you show
actually the resin that is growing on
that flower it has a very very strong
impact you can use the ash to promote a
line of flower even before you bring it
on the market and also I'm a quality
control it's like any genetic who
doesn't pass the ash test it has to be
breeded longer or one who really show a
lot in a resin that should have been
stopped is brought back it's like I um
I'm the wine maker and I work with with
a a Vine grower so my relation with them
we share everything everything that
happened to me happened to them and I
receive the love and dedication of
months of art labor my tri everything
that come in my hand I've been treated
like uh the little beauty they are from
the moment they put the seed in the soil
to when it come in my hand
and I'm
only collecting the the expression of a
lot of work and dedication and because I
can create a relation like like this it
goes beyond buying Tri we work together
and we're trying to not only to show the
potential of the genetic because I work
with Elite heirloom genetic that have
been living in uh in the three state up
North for three or four generation it's
like I
can I'm the person between the plant and
and the patient that bring really the
full expression of that plant to the
people it's
like keeping the purity of it especially
when the plant are growing in two places
that it's all the terar she was talking
about plant giving different aspect of
herself growing in different place I can
tell you that up north they have a Tero
that is very unique as good as in the
Himalaya where when you change valy you
can really feel a difference between
between the genetic even if it's the
same genetic this is what I have working
in a close close relationship with
grower they give me they give me the
land they give me that all those months
and dedication and this is what I have
to uh to keep as pure as as possible
nice uh as a direct connection between
concentrate makers and Equipment
manufacturers uh they're one and the
same in a lot of ways uh you know the
the market for BHO if you rewind five
years ago it was very common to use a
aerosol base and PVC pipe and that
material was winning canvas cups left
and right and uh as time had gone on and
you know then people want shatter they
want honeycomb you know and there's
these trends that happen in the market
and then now nowadays you know if you're
if you're not using a Clos loop
extraction equipment and you know you're
still open blasting you're frowned upon
in the market which you should be
because that's very dangerous and uh now
dewaxing is come into play and it's it's
it's growing fast you know and it's it's
constantly changing and even like the
components you know people are realizing
that you shouldn't be using like pipe
thread or you know like and refrigerant
equipment like these are just frowned
upon things you know about there's a lot
of DIY people in the industry so and you
know if you're a farmer and you have
trim that's a viable product you want to
make it you you don't want to harvest
that for what it is but you don't see
people out there buying trim to roll
into joints or you know they're using it
to make extract so it's
like yeah I think both markets are
feeding each other you know and they are
are going to be you know well it would
seem that they're then really relying on
you to keep them up to date on the best
practices and the best equipment which I
think all patients uh we should be we
should be happy for that so so thank
you Jason were you going to as far as
from the from the store aspect um I'm
really big on only working with name
brand concentrate companies as far as
you have to be really branding yourself
and putting as much effort into selling
your product as much as I'm putting
effort into selling your product so and
with that said that helps a lot with the
quality control because anyone that's
creating a real brand and really trying
to be in this business is not going to
be in the in any interest of wanting to
harm people or creating a bad product in
the first place and so by working with
quality Brands and quality things like
that I Source numerous flowers for
numerous extract companies constantly
and it's it's basically it's all about
if you got good going in you're going to
get good coming out if you got trash
going in you're going to have trash
coming
out nice um did oh go ahead I I mean I
kind of wanted to comment on that I
think that there's a lot of people out
there making uh you know
butane uh related products that aren't
in the Limelight because you're
manufacturing a narcotic and they don't
tend to be in the Limelight you know
they don't want to Market themselves
they're not brand so they may they may
be selling their products to other
brands I I just I agree with you I
disagree they are Brands they're just
putting their energy somewhere other
than just selling a lot of stuff they're
putting it into R&amp;D they're putting it
into taking care of sick people they're
putting it into giving away free
medicines where necessary they're
putting it into paying out through the
NOS through lawyers and accountants to
be compliant and to be doing the right
thing branding is a is a business
strategy making good medicine is a
science I I agree with exactly the end
point of what you're saying the end
point making making quality meds is a
science 100% and that's why these Brands
make some of the best medicine and then
they turn it into a brand so then that
way it's notorized people know it people
know the name these Brands win cups you
know what I mean this it's just how the
market how market share works as you can
see there's no controversy in
concentrates by the way so we don't have
to worry about that um well so that
brings up another point we you know we
have these state regulations on the
horizon um concentrate manufacturing has
been and is basically illegal um in in
the state and so are there are there um
concentrate associations being formed
are there uh are there what is the
concentrate world doing as far as to get
involved with the legislation I'll let
anybody speak on
that I I can I can speak for thei and
we're trying to make a a guild
Association to be able to uh to know
what we're doing isia from the emerald
grower associ
assciation uh is the person in in charge
we have been talking about it for for a
year because as I was saying as a as a
ashin everything come from your Growers
that means that for us as a ash maker or
anybody touching the resin in any way
the only things we have to think about
it's protecting our grower and
protecting the the land literally Beyond
on that uh this is the beginning if we
don't have that there is
nothing I thought there was this
company
cersa uh I I may be murdering it but I
believe at one point reading about it I
wrote them um I didn't get a response
from the email they're an association I
believe so yeah I was looking it up yeah
s sersa that's a uh deor group nice yeah
cersa they the group up north that are
trying to lobby for
concentrates um other than that I work
with CIA I'm one of the executive
directors down here for Southern
California and so we work more on a
local level more than on a Statewide
level because at the end of the day you
need to get a local ordinance passed
especially in with how the new framework
of how this law works is you have to
have local sanctification for extraction
not just state approval stay licens I
work witha American Products
Association and we're treating Canabis
extracts just like any other herbal
extract but with a whole heck of a lot
of safeties put in there protections
because of you know the fears around
harm to given and taken the wrong way
you might not die for it but you sure
might feel like you wish you would for a
few hours and nobody should have to go
through that so we're working on all the
things around labeling and processing
and distribution and storage and Etc so
everything that you can think of Soup To
Nuts on this we're creating all the
guidelines so that we can then present
these to the various um you know
legislative groups and say here we've
already done this here this is how we're
self-regulating we want you to adopt
this because we were already we're being
harder on
ourselves great excellent that point
just pull up I've heard a lot of people
say there's been a huge farmal Lobby
going in place for when this becomes
more ferally legalized and the
restrictions that may come in especially
around exra because there arguments that
you're taking a plant you're taking
something out of that and you're doing
something similar to Farmer what what do
you think do you think that that's a
real risk in the cluster space I think
that it's a very big risk in the entire
industry and I think that the more that
we can do to collaborate and work
together and make sure that we self
self-regulate and that we have outside
independent you know adjudication just
make sure that we're doing it all
correctly and we can show that we're
putting all the efforts together to to
do that and test it and everything and
testing testing testing testing test
every batch test it again retest it get
the machines better get the the
technicians better but do you think
there will eventually be like a strong
hand in
the well as long as we we are doing
everything we can to keep this an herbal
product because if you're not dealing
with isol that you know standardized
pharmacology is about reductionism it's
about single molecule drugs that you can
dose you say you know you have 25
milligram and 25 Mig of X with what
we're dealing with is so much more
complex than that so we have to treat it
as an herbal product on the other hand
we're going to Spain now to start drug
trials with Guzman and Sanchez and we're
going to be taking using extracts full
plant extracts to be doing studies on
Cell lines or glol blastoma or to breast
cancer we're looking at the swamis and
the basal cell and we're using full
planned extracts so we want to show that
if you get it down and you know what
you're doing you don't have to get those
little single isolates and without
pharmaceutical companies don't have a
way to stand up well into that you work
with the American herbal products
Association and that's exactly what they
do and what they've been doing for a
decade or so is keeping herbal
supplements right out of the hands of
the FDA when they don't need to be so
that's why APPA is so important um I
actually have no idea how we're doing on
time but I think it's time to go to
questions so if anyone has questions out
there
Obie my understanding is that in Europe
smoking flowers is considered crude
that's not the end product the end
product is the hatch and in the United
States my understanding is that flowers
for many people is considered the endend
product Aaron you're the consumate
marketer comment on that okay so um I'm
on the panel now that's cool um no
that's good um yeah well we are a
company that specializes in high quality
flowers um I know it's kind of going
against the trend but that is something
that myself and my head cultivator Tyler
Wadley here uh really focus on so for a
lot of our Pati um it's about the flour
but we have plenty of concentrates and
like these concentrate manufacturers
have said um it all starts with the
plant
so definitely the trend is going to more
and more concentrates and like you said
hash is probably the finished product
but there's something to the flower for
me personally where I feel the full
effect um and it would be really similar
with with Frenchies hash um but when you
take that away from me um it's just not
the same whether it's BHO Co CO2 I I'm
looking for um more of an effect
personally so who knows I think people
will you know sometimes you take a dab
sometimes you smoke a joint it's more
more of a generational thing too now you
know what I mean like call me old yeah
this the the the younger the younger
generation is all like all about the
concentrates that's that's their whole
thing you're going to have a whole
generation of kids that have never
smoked flowers pretty much and that's
really what it is uh I mean
when I was in college I went to college
with Europeans who they smuggle hash
over here and they would roll their
little joints with the tobacco and you
know you turn them on into some
high-grade Sour Diesel and they're like
wow do you want my hash yeah I mean I I
I will say that uh trade trade trade
yeah I I would say that a lot of times
we get a lot of love from people who
usually don't smoke flowers um because
we produce a really clean smooth flour
and I think if there were more of that
um you would see more of these people
using it but so much of the Cannabis um
does hurt your throat and is not flush
properly so you know that is an
issue right there is anybody up there
noticing a trend where extractors are
moving away from using mainly just trim
and Sugar Leaf and extracting from Whole
flowers most of the people I know all do
Nug Run um trim is more of a economical
thing but but a majority of my concent
rates are all nugrun and and your
patients because your patients want that
correct yeah that's that that's what a
majority of them want and and I've I've
cuz I've had storees since 01 I've
always sold concentrates back when only
concentrates were only called ear wax
honeycomb amber glass Amber shards and
now the only thing that's different is
the marketing and the different
techniques and the different devices and
the different companies that have come
out to help help brand the market
share I uh I think that it's a marketing
thing um I think whether you're uh
purifying metabolites from uh trim or
from flow you know as long as those
glands are present and there is some
type of um cannaboids in there then it
doesn't really matter your yields will
be different and maybe the tpine
concentration will be slightly off but
it you know it is an economical thing
but if you know if you're in a contest
or something then I would suggest using
flowers but besides that I think it
could be a waste of
money we use we use flowers but
sometimes we'll get some popcorn but
it's still pretty good but even before
we'll use it though we'll always keep
that out we will not use it in its
present form we'll make sure that we
remove as much of the plant matter as we
can not that there's going to be much in
popcorn popcorn has to have some nugs in
there to some real nuts but we
definitely use uh flowers then the a lot
of what you see in the edible industry
is the trend that goes for that I don't
understand why anybody thinks that if it
goes through a different mechanism
through the body it doesn't matter if
it's as healthy uh to me it's it's all
going in it all needs to go in healthy
but um too many times I've seen the trim
that I've looked at and seen where it's
like after they do their they have their
trimmers there all day um not wearing
masks not wearing gloves not wearing
whatever they'll come in and they'll
just scoop upet off the floor sweep the
floor put that in big giant Hefty bags
and then sell that for 50 bucks or 100
bucks to some processor that's not
really what I want in my
medicine no it's like they they would TR
treat small birds the same it's it's not
really what you use of the plant because
the Trion on the sugar trim are as good
as a Trion on the
head but it's the way your Tri have your
material has been treated between the
Harvest and you that's why your relation
with the grower is so important because
my quality of Ash is the quality of
afishionado it's not my ash I represent
aish it's just made by me so so now it's
a question of for those grower they want
their reputation to stay high we have a
very small industry you cannot make any
mistake especially when you're a breeder
and they wouldn't give me anything but
the best when you have sugar trim left
in the plastic bag just by itself the
weight of the trim they're so sticky
that when I open it at home I can put a
coffee a full cup of coffee on it in
full confidence like not feeling afraid
at all and take picture of it this is
just sugar trim but this is the best of
the sugar trim that I've been treated
the same way that the flower have been
treated that's why you need that
relation of the grower because I know
that my medicine is organic I know where
it's grown I know it's been taken care
in between all my resin is cured or
fresh I know everything about what I do
because it's so concentrate thein at the
end that anything that is wrong is going
to show even more so here it's like if
you have any
pesticide uh and you don't have somebody
checking your plant to tell you that yes
now you at the end of the flower season
there is no more pesticide
about it if you don't have
that trust toward your grower you never
know the medicine you're giving
away um one other question oh are we
done now how about uh concentrate that
comes from sungrown cannabis versus
indoor cannabis is there a difference
and what is the difference all right
taste
taste yield quality price point color
all of these different things all all
will come into play with all of these
concentrates and when you are working
with outdoor and Greenhouse your numbers
are a lot larger so there's a fine
timeline from when you can process those
plants to when they will actually go bad
and you will actually produce bad
product because the the the turpenoid or
the excuse me the tricomes have already
amber colored so you're going to come
out with dark so the reality of it is
you better be able to pump it if you're
going to be able to grow
it we we prefer um
Greenhouse for uh in in what we do
because it still gets all of the natural
cycles we have to obviously you know
with light dep and you have to you know
increase the light certain times and
different times of year Etc but there's
we also like the idea that the plants
are being stressed to a certain extent
um
I I've really never understood the whole
indoor market I understand if you're
have if you're have to be stealth and
you're in an illegal place then that's a
whole entire different thing but they T
call it Bud porn that comes out because
they're they're pretty little nugs and
they're pretty and they trim them to
death and they're very but then people
are go oh wow isn't that great and
they're either going to then destroy
them in a concentrate or they're going
to put a match to it to light it up
anyway which just feels really
destructive to something that you just
cultivated to be pretty they're born to
die huh said they're born to
die I I I differ with that a little bit
just in the fact that that I believe
that by creating the perfect environment
for a plant to grow in you can pervert
per uh make the perfect medicine
basically that's really how I believe it
when you grow with Outdoors you have the
outside elements and so and so yeah yeah
so but even with Greenhouse but even
with Greenhouse it's still it still is
not the same as indoor it still it's not
going to come out with that same tpine
profile that same that same blood
structure that same same crystal content
all of that you are not going to get
that without doing it indoor yeah I I
would I would agree with Jason but we're
big indoor cultivators um on our Shelf
at Buds and Roses we have put some of
the best Greenhouse um on the shelf for
maybe half the price of our indoor but
our patients do prefer the indoor uh but
I think I'm biased Los Angeles is not
only the largest retail Market but the
Lar largest market for indoor
cultivation as well but I think indoor
cultivators need to um we started
cultivators Alliance actually in Los
Angeles to um build up the the ethics
and the responsibility um behind indoor
cultivators so I think there's a place
for it I I mean personally from uh doing
extractions with Greenhouse uh I've seen
some of the best extractions from all
organic greenhouse and you know I think
there is some importance to having it be
sungrown but yet in a controlled
environment of the greenhouse and um and
even when the farmer you know is taking
down that crop and what they do to
protect the uh tpin and the the
internals of that gland you know
immediately freezing it you know cuz
you're dealing with volatile organic
compounds that are immediately
vaporizing as soon as it's cut down you
know and and as a concentrate maker
you're trying to harvest that stuff and
you know you need to either do it
immediately or freeze it or you know
figure out a way yeah to uh to get after
it but yeah I have noticed definitely
organic Greenhouse weed makes the best
concentrate from any any of you have
ever been in a field of cannabis when
the plant are 15 to 20 ft High
yes it's like Ze plant a plant in full
power outside will
never be able to be compared for from
Anything Grows indoor doesn't matter how
good you are indoor the expression of a
plant outdoor fully grown in a soil you
cannot compare it when you when you walk
indoor at night do you think the plum
doesn't know that outdoor it it's it's
daytime that she should sleep or the
opposite you think that when you grow
indoors the plant doesn't know about the
Moon the Moon cycle like the plant is a
living organism that is aware and
intelligent and we don't
even pay attention to it it's like you
you're dealing with a living organism
that let you do a lot of thing because
you can bring a
a genetic further than any bees poll
pollin but there is a limit to what a
plant can give you indoor
without without uh like when you have
ventilation it's it's a fun it's nice a
fun it makes it makes the pl stronger
but it's not the win it will never be
the UV that you have in a grow room you
don't have the UV that the sun like
there is no there is no light that
duplicate the sun there is no room that
give a quarter of a moon to a full moon
it's like you have to realize the beauty
of that plant outdoor or she can give
the maximum indoor you're trying to take
the maximum of her pushing her to do
something that naturally it's against
her nature you know what I mean so you
do great R don't get me no no no I I
agree with you with what you're saying
but at the end of the day sales dictate
the market yep and the bottom line is
indoor sales a 100 times more than
outdoor or Greenhouse period you know
what I can just imagine somebody coming
to me with some disease and me saying
nah that's not financially viable that's
not even realistic that's not even a
realistic statement but it's far as that
if it's not going to
be if the Emerald Triangle wasn't
exporting all their flower on other
coast we will you will know what is Sun
grown flower it's just that you don't
find them in a market it's very simple
none of you have really know what is a
beautifully sunr flower coming from
mandino it's like Ze flower they indoor
cannot compete with that but it's not
known people have are not educated to
choose sunr to to word indoor because
sunr needs dirty bird shit on it it's
like how would you smoke that well no at
the same time too um from from from my
experience of running stores for so long
I've also noticed that outdoor
Greenhouse flowers decompose at a much
faster rate than indoor flowers decompos
also their color changes faster their
taste changes faster all of this changes
in a number of weeks as opposed to a
number of months well let me let me say
this
so bring Jason and I the best Su grown
we would be happy to carry it and get it
off to our patients and you know we're
all for it we're all for it so all right
um I I'll go to questions and then I
think we'll wrap it up go ahead I just
wanted to make a comment about this if I
may um I've been around marijuana for
decades uh my Collective just down the
street been there we're in our 10th
year I go to Amsterdam every year and I
buy all of the or
seeds I go to Spain to pick them up I
bring them
back give them to our Growers they grow
organically we have one indoor grower
all the rest are outdoor uh one
Greenhouse I will smoke nothing but
sunr the new stuff now the sunr from
from award-winning sves is the best
marijuana out there it's so pure when
you smoke it that you you just can't go
back to indoor that has been grown what
they say organically but I don't believe
that we have organic Growers but there's
always that taste
that weird uh chemical taste that's in
it that is never in a really really good
Sun grown from award-winning seeds
marijuana it's the best as far as I'm
concerned personally my
personal all right anyone else awesome
I I think um a lot of of new Edibles
Brands transdermal Brands even VAP pen
Brands look for extractors to provide
them with concentrate material to uh to
put into their products could you all
compare and contrast the uh the cost of
production of the different extraction
techniques and their suitability for for
these different applications the cost of
production is really going to depend on
the actual individual extractor how much
Machinery they actually have and are
able to process at one given time
because the more you can able to produce
the lower your price per gram cost to
produce so it's always going to depend
on the actual concentrate maker
depending on what the IND individual
price point will be and how fast he's
able to process
it uh I think you're asking like uh
Styles right CO2 and BHO and correct
yeah so I mean CO2 extraction is going
to be the most expensive to do uh
because the equipment needed to produce
that extraction it's very expensive uh
due upon the high operating pressures of
CO2 and so the thickness of the steel
has to be super thick it has to be bulky
whereas um a butane
extraction um it's a low it's a low
operating pressure solvent um
it it's like operates at like 50 psi at
like 100 you know which is not not high
at all when it comes to pressure so you
can produce this equipment relatively
cheap um alcohol is probably even less
expensive considering you just need like
I don't know a
giant say again sense to scale up
alcohol
say to scale up alcohol I would not want
to scale up a bad technique
of I think it's the best extraction
technique there is in the extraction
world but people don't put those okay
but you can't say that you can't say
that it's like this is the best way to
extract the most volatile in the
industry of the perfume it's V and so
you cannot say that it's bad technique
that's not really nice you can say
people say it's not a bad technique
because it has its uses absolutely but I
don't believe it belongs in a medicine
to use mutane extraction possibly
recreational or some Turin that you want
to add to your Frankenstein concentrate
but using
actual why not use I'd like to bring up
something that you mentioned earlier I
mean you said that you you give your
clients you know you you give them an
organic diet but you wouldn't tell them
to use Pam not would you tell your
clients to go get
drunk no I wouldn't but if but your
solvent of choice is ethanol correct
which is something we use to get drunk
well maybe you do I don't use to get
drunk I might use it to relax in the
evening a glass of wine really though
what's the difference really though it
comes down to the end product and how
well it was refined there's a lot of
really good solvents out there but at
the end of the day if it's refined out
properly it doesn't really matter how
you get very soon it's not about the
solvent it's about the quality of the
product going in in the first place it's
not about the solvent it's about the
quality of the product I'm making sure
the solvent's not there all right all
right all right are there are there any
more
questions yeah you've had your hand up
for a while go
ahead yes to um the state of which the
Cannabis is um in as far as you guys are
talking about the change in between
Greenhouse or or organic outdoor indoor
wouldn't that be based on um how like
the curing process lash the the
consistency and stability in which the
Cannabis is being through that period of
time so which would be burping the
whatever container in which the Cannabis
is kept in so that reflect how the the
longevity of freshness the cidis
has most likely but I I think what Jason
was saying is it just seems that the
basically it's it's kind of like this
and this is a really like weird analogy
and it might not even be politically
correct to say this but this is the best
analogy I can give you IM imagine in
indoor flowers as rich kids in Beverly
Hills and you imagine outdoor as poor
kids in the hood and all of the aders MS
that they have to go through in life and
to to be able to grow in that type of an
environment you're in Beverly Hills
you're in a perfect stable environment
that's a
maintained same same temperature same
everything outdoor you're subject to the
elements you're getting rained on you're
getting trampled on you're getting bugs
eating on you you're having all kinds of
problems but you
probably that's for sure that's for sure
that that's without a doubt but at the
end of the day it's about creating the
perfect environment to create the
perfect product all right so I think
that's oh uh Barrett go
ahead last question what are thei that
you guys are
finding you using how much of the AC
ingredients that's on the FL are is
being taken off when you're tra how much
is left off uh as a ash maker and I I
can look with a manif glass my trim to
be sure I don't forget any head I get
between 7 to
15% according to the strain the grower
and uh many many many things but as an
average and a good average it's 10% it's
already very nice 15% it's rare is some
special
genetic uh I found um if the cannabis
being tested has a
22% um uh THC or whatever usually my
yields are going to be very similar
[Music]