[Music]
it's been a long year and we're glad
that everyone was able to to um um make
it down A lot's gone on over the last
year A lot's about to happen over the
next um over the over the uh next year
as well in in this state the um very
first panel is going to feature some of
the I would say rock stars from from the
state capital this year who formed a
coalition and only half of these rock
stars are even here what you saw happen
in the capital was lawmakers come
together in a way they in a way you
don't see happen every day where you saw
four lawmakers testifying for one bill
one joint authored bill at the same time
you saw their staffs actively going out
in groups working with different every
stakeholder out there they made sure
everyone's voice were heard did everyone
get what they wanted no but everybody
got a chance to actually talk the first
problem you're going to have is um a
minute is not long enough uh my name
along alone assembly member Reginal
Byron Jones Sawyer senior takes a minute
so um but I want to I want to thank I
want to thank everyone here um for all
the work especially Nate Bradley because
he spended a a tremendous amount of
hours and work so that we could be where
we are here today waiting for the
governor of the state of California sign
AB
266 now how I kind of got into this um
when I was running for the assembly I
came in in
and my my father-in-law had cancer and
in 2011 is
um he needed you know to use some
cannabis to to so he be able to eat I
saw the ravages of that cancer what it
did to him how he couldn't eat and this
is a man that's from New Orleans and in
New Orleans they eat and they they fried
butter to eat I mean they love food he
had he had cancer to the throat so he
couldn't swallow it was just just
horrible um and eventually found
something at the medical marijuana place
that that helped with it and then one
day while I was campaigning no one could
take him around to the medical marijuana
place and they all looked at me and I
said look I'm running for
office I can't go over to that little
store that little place over there in
the corner with the little sign that
nobody knows what it is but everybody
knows what it
is and I remember taking him going in
and he said do you have any cash on you
I said this sounds like a drug operation
like you wouldn't believe oh my God but
when I went in I didn't see a lot of
students or a lot of people who were
faking it I saw a lot of sick people I
saw a lot of people who needed it and
and I saw how professional each of these
places were and and it just changed my
outlook on it and ways that I never
would have seen before if I had not gone
in so what started me is is my
father-in-law who who has since passed
on when I got to the assembly um someone
said that you know none of those places
are regulated I said yes it has and said
how long has it been they said like
1995 I said this is 2012 and what's the
problem and I work with Mr Amano um and
Senator kareah L kah to try to figure
out a way to make get the regulations
through I saw them suffer burn and and
die and not be able to get it done and
so I and then I saw measure D in La I'm
from Los Angeles South La 59th Assembly
District represents South La and I just
felt that for an industry a burgon
industry this big this large it should
have regulations and that um we the
legislator should take on that
responsibility espci you're talking
about Statewide and so um I decided to
put a bill through um I am blessed to
say that immediately after and soon
after um Mr B Mr kolie Mr wood all
started putting bills through that would
make legislation even better um the
other reason why I felt that we really
needed to do this that we're all
freshman well we're south for now and is
now freshman um there's been a lot of
infighting up and down when you talk
about the
legislature one of the things early on
that Mr Bon and my Mr Woods Mr coolie
said even though one person may have put
their bill across first if we all join
together we'll get our bill across
period and for the first time we wanted
to show the rest of the assembly I'm be
quite frankly Frank with you that if you
work together on a on major legislation
and you you don't understand this
legislation went through is Major and
and I'm not saying because I'm one of
the authors but I think it is the number
one piece of legislation that's gone
through in its entirety no disrespect to
the bill that the state sener has been
through but in its
entirety and hopefully when you look at
us because one of the goals that I
wanted to have accomplished when he when
we did this is what happens when you
collaborate how big bills can get done
how big Ideas can be done when the
legislature works together and that's
why I got involved in this
[Applause]
well greetings I'm actually going to say
some very similar things to Reggie um
I'm a member Ken kouy I'm from the
Sacramento County area and um all of the
authors involved in this issue I I think
it's important to flag our comparatively
new members of the
legislature uh number of members of of
Reggie in my class and then freshman
members uh Mr Mr Lackey Mr wood Mr
Maguire all newly elected just last fall
so I would say a key piece of this issue
was actually you suddenly had a group of
authors who have a little more time that
we can spend in the
legislature and are looking at this
phenomenon which I refer to as sort of
Groundhog Day
legislation where Year bye we we as a
state try to tackle Monumental issues
not not just medical marijuana
Monumental issues and you work hard all
year they become a black hole effort and
then the closing weeks the wheels come
off so that the next year you've got to
start all
over and uh while I am a freshman I
actually started in the state capital as
a young guy back in
1977 eight years Chief to a part of
leadership I've run policy committees in
both houses my law practice was such I
always did legislation so I'm sort of in
an odd place that I've actually done
legislative work continuously for 38
years in my career but as a legislator
I'm in my third year
so I'm a founder of the city of Ranch
Cordova in Sacramento County was mayor
there twice served 10 years in city
council although there's about 500
cities in California within a very short
time after my election to the city
council I started getting involved with
the league of cities and and between 06
and 09 or really 04 and 09 moved to the
number two position in the league of
cities I was about 5 months away from
becoming president of the league but in
2009 the Senate asked me to come in and
in a policy role and run a big policy
committee for them which I did promptly
resigning from my post with the league
uh so I would say I have a pretty strong
governmental skill set I think I'm
pretty
collaborative and when the league
approached me on this bill I had an
interest in it because uh Luke Kare I've
known him very well for a lot of years I
was very close to L understood his
effort in the prior session with Senate
Bill
1262 but I also have this conviction
that if my colleagues and I can be a
part of a a group of legislators
starting to become dominant in state
capital where some of these big issues
we actually start and finish in a
year and we start expanding that from
this beach head to other key issues that
at the end of our career actually people
will look at our time the legislature
and say the state of California and the
legislature in the assembly entered a
new era so that was actually a big part
of my interest I actually sat down at
the league of cities and says I actually
think I'll be a strong author but you
have to know that I can tell you that
there will come times in the
conversation where although I'm a strong
author on your behalf I'm going to do
things that you may not agree with
because ultimately I think the stake
here is not this issue but it's
institutional if we can be successful in
taking some big issues and bringing them
to a close and create some institutional
momentum we will touch the state in a
variety of ways which matter when you
have 12 years to serve uh I feel in a
particular way I kind of helped that
along I did start out with a bill AB 266
in the assembly policy process when it
went through the B&amp;P committee on the
day it was heard uh I know Rob's bill
got eight or nine votes that day in that
committee my vote got my bill got 13
same committee same
day but as soon as we got into probes we
merged the bills AB 266 which you hear
lot about actually for about half of the
year was the coolie
bill but I actually felt that
uh good work had been done trying to put
the ideas together I felt that we had a
pretty good working product in that
committee and I'm enough of a political
person to understand that actually if
you're Rob Bon from Alam
County this subject is more of a
district issue for Rob bana than it is
for me in Sacramento County so I
actually suggested that we should should
take the merged bills I would become the
lead on his bill we'd put the new
content in his old bill which stayed
with the committee and he would we'd put
the new content in 266 and we'd make him
the lead author and that was this
collaboration strategy it it could sound
funny that you menend the same stuff
into two bills one of which you leave
behind but the purpose of
that in Appropriations was to send the
signal that you could not put a a sheet
of paper between where Ken kulie was on
this and where Rob bonto was and that
became sort of our way to signal that we
are serious and Earnest about trying to
move something forward and then it did
become as as Reggie explained a great
collaboration of members Republican
Democrat staff and a lot of Staff
particularly on the Republican side in
their long careers had never been
brought into the table in a conversation
as we brought them in so I'm very
excited to be here I think it is a
milestone accomplishment uh long time in
coming and uh just an honor to be here
can
I I just want to quickly
say in the interest of
collaboration there were three bills one
was
mine but we didn't lose our minds about
it and we put our EOS to the side and at
the door
y well my name's Jim Wood I represent
represent the second Assembly District
which is the North Coast of California
so it's the northern half of Sona County
mesino humble Trinity and delnort
[Applause]
counties so we have a little we have a
little herb business in our
County and my interest my interest in
this um came from my time in campaigning
you know by training I'm a dentist uh
practice Dentistry for 27 years so I
have a healthcare background um over
those years I encountered a lot of
people who use medical cannabis and and
began to appreciate the value of that
especially uh my my receptionist her
husband was a patient uh and um we got
she worked for me for 25 years and which
is a pretty phenomenal in this day and
age to have anybody work for anybody for
that long but we developed a
relationship around that and my I began
to get an understanding for for the
industry and and for the value of
medical cannabis when I was campaigning
the things that uh con began to concern
me were some of the environmental things
that were happening there are folks that
are absolutely trying to do the right
thing and there are folks that are
absolutely raping and destroying our
environment and the the Legacy in the
history of the North Coast has been
about Environmental Conservation about
Environmental Protection we protect our
Coastline we protect our redwoods we
protect our salmon bearing streams and
to see what I saw firsthand that was
going on um in in my district broke my
heart quite frankly and when I went to
Sacramento in December um and sat down
with my new staff who knew nothing about
cannabis and I knew this much um I said
we are going to work on a bill that's
going to be very focused on the
environmental challenges we're facing on
the North Coast and um so we set as set
set in motion to do that um in the
process I got the opportunity to meet
these two fine gentlemen here Mr Lackey
who's also a freshman legislator like
myself and Mr bont and it became really
apparent for us to be successful we
needed to collaborate and so we
continued to collaborate um my challenge
um quite frankly was that people don't
think about the environmental impacts of
of largescale industrial cultivation and
and for me I was really stubborn and
Reggie and Ken know that really well now
um is is that I kept my bill very
separate for that very reason because I
really wanted to highlight that among my
colleagues and you know what was
interesting about this whole process as
we went through it was that we um we
took when you you mentioned marijuana or
cannabis to people who in the legisl
they kind of looked at you they of
Snicker you know and they kind of look
away but we have taken that to a point
where we freely talk about this in a
very very open way and that is a huge
step
forward so I mean to to the point where
you know we have had a party we had an
end of end of session party in my office
and we actually we made mock marijuana
brownies you know um
and mock mock
mock but we did have doubters you
know especially the speaker of the
assembly when I took hers to her office
she's I'm not sure if she ever ateed or
not but but um but but you know the
value the value of the collaboration you
know I maybe I was just you know new
enough I had I really had no legislative
background I com from from a local city
council okay practice Dentistry small
town 12,000 people that's where I live
small small town Northern California
town I had no knowledge of this and come
in except someone like like Mr Coy who
has tremendous knowledge of of of the
legislature and Mr Jon Ser who comes
from an area and has a background that
is that is um very different from my so
you put the five of us together as as
authors on these and we actually
Encompass the state of California and
that's the value of the collaboration
here and so so what has done for us and
me is that you know these are my go-to
guys on on not just this issue but a ton
of issues and so to be able to build
these relationships and friendships with
people moving forward and I will tell
you as I want I know there's a lot of
questions but I want to tell you this is
the beginning this is not the end of the
process okay keep that in
mind so nothing is ever perfect um and
you need to know that upfront we know
it's not perfect and we know why it's
not perfect and we want to make it get
perfect um but but this is the beginning
of the process and it's it has been
needed for a very very long time so so
I'm just excited to have been uh young
and dumb and you know enough to get
involved in this and and tackle a really
difficult issue that was in inherently
really really important to my district
so um so at the end of the day um if the
governor signs these bills I think we
all have a lot to a lot to be thankful
for and a lot to be proud
of all right the uh next the next
question is a two-part question there's
been a lot of talk OB see people have
had concerns about the bills can felons
get a license who can is there you know
what is the May versus shall mean type
of a situation so the the the question
is um what is the most important
elements of this legislation to you and
what parts do you think need
need to be fixed and you don't have to
give all of them just a
couple well well for me um I do a lot of
work um on recidivism um I'm the chair
of budget sub five over the prisons
incarceration and I know the war and
drugs especially the war in marijuana
has resulted in a lot of black and brown
Brothers ending up in jail um really for
lowlevel offenses um being able to work
on this um to kind of almost start the
discussion of trying to decriminalize
that so we're going have people come
back into society and H and work and get
back to their families is really
important to me um
even when the discussion about having
people who formerly had records or may
have been charged with something out of
state but never really was incarcerated
um to have them worked in this field
because when we bring people back we
want them to have working jobs that they
may actually be comfortable in working
in I don't mean that to be factious but
they may be good at it and they can work
in it um and we have to find a way I
know um because Mr coie worked on it a
lot a whole lot and because I know law
enforcement um is adamant about allowing
former felons and individuals to work in
this build in this business uh not not
to allow them at all um I I think
there's a happy medium where we can meet
um for me that might be the next steps
that we work through but it also becomes
part of us desensitizing as Mr wood said
you more you talk about it before before
you would say you talk about cannabis
and then they called us the Cannabis
Kings and making jokes like that to go
from that to you guys have some a
serious piece of legislation and and
start talking about ab66 266 and and
talking about in a serious way and so
for me right now um the the the number
one issue is to how to integrate people
who have been charged with this may have
serve a little time how to get them
involved in this business because
because quite frankly this is a
multi-billion doll business and we need
to ensure that everybody has an
opportunity to work in it especially
since we're talking about it may have
been a time where it was illegal like in
prohibition if you look at the
prohibition laws and
now hopefully in the future if it
becomes um legal that we can re
acclimate those people back in into this
business
[Applause]
well it's interesting question I think I
tend to
feel in the the broad brush areas where
IT addresses both public health or
public health Public Safety local
control those are very important
elements I think the use of existing
state agency expertise in food and EG
and in public health uh the testing
standards that will be introduced I
think all those are very important
Provisions uh an interesting part I
think when you look at it from sort of a
from a larger conversation standpoint
I'm not particularly a proponent of
legalization but I understand that there
will be a legalization
conversation and I from day one I've
sort of actually had the view that if
you if you're interested in
legalization you would probably be
advantaged by having the legislature
establish a a systematic framework for
the regulation of medical
cannabis uh with league with the league
of cities in support because I think
what you can anticipate is as you go
into January and February of next year
there will be cities up and down
California almost 500 talking about the
Breakthrough that this legislation
represents and consequently if you are
on the ballot in November of next year
on a related topic it will appear that
the jump between the new status quo and
California and that question is a
smaller jump so I just think I would
just kind of throw out that well I
actually am not a proponent of
legalization I'm not that just stated
the truth the political side of me the
tactician in me just says actually this
is a major stepping stone to the next
conversation and for a lot of folks
there uh the question that is coming
will seem a smaller question and I will
point out that um in I
and I think it is the Senate Bill there
are some general language that deals
with a study to be commissioned related
to motor
skills and I would actually say this
this study will address help address the
question of impaired
driving and I would just suggest that in
the in 2010 during the campaign on
proposition 19 a very big question a lot
of people's minds was actually that
impaired driving issue so even this
little study which was
uh proposed by Mr Lackey our colleague
who's not here I think even that study
will play a an outsized role in the year
ahead so I want to point that out to you
thanks well my my my bill's a little
different and and it's talks about we
talk about some of the environmental
issues that that come up with that with
with the cultivation so uh with with
cannabis um so kind of some of the
highlights of my bill first of all
funding for the new cannabis Bureau
comes from a funding mechanism in my
bill $10 million to start this up and
there will be I believe money that will
go um give us the opportunity directly
to to impact some of the cleanup efforts
that we need to do in my district so in
addition The Authority for all the
licensing entities to assess fees to
cover licensing and administrative costs
unfortunately with lure comes cost and
that is I know that's going to be
frustrating to you but hey I worked in a
very regulated industry I'm licensed I'm
licensed in 14,000 different ways it
seems like and there's unfortunately a
fee associated with that
um and it sometimes gets redundant it
gets frustrating but it is sort of the
cost of legitimacy and that's that's how
you're going to move forward here is to
you want to be a part which I know you
all do of of the mainstream business
Community out there this is there is a
cost to that and some of some of what
you're going to experience is is what I
consider the pathway to legitimacy has a
cost and I hope that I hope that you
understand that and accept that and it's
our job to try to make it reasonable and
and fair and that's I think as we go
forward that's that's fundamentally
we're going to continue to follow all of
this and and and and work on it because
the beginning is this is the beginning
the regulatory process as it plays out
over the next two or three years is
going to be absolutely critical so um
you you need to keep your you need to
keep your eye on the ball you need to
keep attention to that and you need to
keep us informed so we can so we can
help to Advocate um another thing comes
from my my bill uh is the creation of of
a fines and penalties account and that
money would be used to assess on on
non-compliant actors that are growing in
my areas that are not following the
rules
um to help pay for some environmental
cleanup to pay for some enforcement uh
for state and local law enforcement um
important to me and what I didn't expect
immediately when I introduced this bill
was to
um you know I was all about the
environmental part of this but you
cannot talk about the environmental
component unless you talk about
cultivation we knew that really early on
and we kind of kept that as a card um
and so what was important to me is that
as we went forward that we would
actually have cannabis actually
regulated under the California
Department of food and agriculture as an
Agricultural Product really really
critical from my perspective why if
you're not if you're not in the
cultivation business out there um and
certainly not an outdoor grower you may
or may not do understand that but the
The Growers who are growing um the
cultivators want to be a part of the
legitimate community and with that will
my intention My Hope Is that the access
to not only the regulatory scheme but
the programs that are available through
the department food and agriculture will
be valuable to the industry going
forward
um the the other thing for me is really
important for the requirement for
cannabis cultivators to follow all the
environmental laws one of the biggest
things I hear from my world is that
grape Growers get really irritated with
cannabis cultivators because grape
Growers or Farmers whether you're Dairy
Farmer whatever you have a lot of rules
to follow and there's a feeling that
cannabis cultivators follow none of them
and it's actually true for to for the
most part so so you have to be you have
to be willing to come on board and
follow those same environmental laws the
other thing which I think is really
important is going to play into 266
really really well and we these are this
is a package now we ought to we ought to
just recognize that this is this is a
package is is some sort of a unique
identifier program which is which is in
my bill we want to be able to track from
seed to sale U for a variety of
different reasons number one for me is
is going to be um Public Safety you know
I mean for kry out loud people out there
grow broccoli and lettuce and tomatoes
and things like that and if there's a
health problem something that gets into
a crop we've got ways now to to to
Target that small part of that crop and
take that off the market rather than
wiping out the entire system for for a
year so so those are some of kind of the
highlights of of what we're doing uh
with with my bill um and and but it once
again it's it's it's collaborating with
those and I'm G I'm going to do this now
because I I I want to forget I want to
give a shout out to folks that that work
closely with me who repres who with me
um Hezekiah Allen in the back California
Growers Association
formerly Emerald
Growers J Jamie Kerr um 530
[Applause]
edibles also CGA and Shan donaho with
CGA as well so it's okay Sean you can
look this way it's all right so anyway
um that's pass it back
Nate thank you uh we will move on to the
to the to the actual questions from the
from the crowd now
members thank you really appreciate you
guys here heading this project uh my
name is David Aro I'm elected council
member and St Gabriel Valley and my
first uh encounter with the industry was
back in 1989 when I attended home
state so as a freshman I moved forward I
served my country gradu
uh from Humble State and we helped push
the initiative back in 1996 so after
almost 20 years it's glad to see that it
has some you guys moving forward in the
right direction one one of my questions
was answered the first question was
answered and the thing was um the
Trailblazers back in the90s when they
were moving towards this Movement we had
we had people that got in trouble so I
appreciate that you guys are taking a
look at that because I think that those
individuals should deserve an
opportunity in this industry but my
other my my second question was um what
are we doing in regards to the medical
research part in the state being in in
conflicts with the federal government um
we have um a lot of um soldiers coming
back some of the statistics are with
PTSD they're dying at a rate of 22
people per day um so to me that's
touches my heart very passionate about
it and what is that the state
legislators is going to do thank you
question sounds like a medical question
to me yeah thanks thanks Rich well Dr
Jones s telling us about how you feel
about
that no I think it's absolutely critical
that we that we there there will be I
believe that that the the movement
forward you know California for one for
once again actually needs to lead the
way on this issue you know um we you
know we LED we led the way in 1996 with
with 215 and then we've kind of taken a
backseat it's time for California to
lead the way again and so medical
research I believe that there will be an
emphasis on medical research and and
public health and and I think it's going
to happen it's not specific to the bills
but um but it doesn't mean we can't we
can't move in that in that direction so
I think as the and I think part of
that's going to part of that should come
from the industry you know there should
be a way to do that I mean I know that
the testing now is becoming more and
more sophisticated um on and and there
is research out there how do we put it
all together and and how do we we
actually have reasonable uh symposiums
on the medical the medical research and
and and and promote medical research so
so it's something that um hasn't been
hasn't been brought up so I thank you
for your question I thank you for your
service on both as you know to our
country and also to your city um because
we need people like you uh with your
background so so but but it is important
it's certainly my background is
something that I that I I want to I want
to look at and I I appreciate the
question and and we will we will look
into it let me jump out on that if I may
too uh you know a bill like this is not
just a structure of law but it's it's
sort of a trigger to start releasing a
lot of energy uh every time we testify
in the bill Reggie was out there noting
that the US Department of Justice has
said they're going to take a more
relaxed attitude about marijuana
enforcement generally when a state has a
robust law in place that was a key
element of the strategy and so and the
bills actually include sort of this
Express authorizations if someone's
property licensed under this they they
can't be prosecuted under California law
and uh on the issue of research there's
research here we're setting up the
Department of Public Health to develop
Testing Laboratories so there's a lot of
very substantive work that's going to be
unfolding in the food and a area in
public health kind of developing
standards measurements and in general a
way to think about the whole impact of
the
bill this will sound sort of funny but I
I often invoke this even in some of our
conversations in the capital is every
California County every every
professional discipline may not be all
on board from day one but as you start
to make Beach heads where there's
Acceptance in counties and professions
within the structure of this bill as it
starts to release some energy in
research and Enterprise and other sorts
of things other folks who've been
negative or sitting on the sidelines
will start seeing it through a different
lens and the analogy I use and I just
would hearten you with this thought it's
sort of a crazy analogy it sounds sort
of
militaristic but in World War II we
fought the campaign in the Pacific and
the basic strategy was not every island
where there's resistance is is something
we need to tackle we will be targeted we
will advance we will make progress and
as we make that progress sort of moving
northward through the Pacific places
that initially might have been resistant
started to fall into line and that's a
more Dynamic way to think about how this
bill will affect the future of marijuana
in California but I think a lot fronts
that Dynamic model is probably what
you're going to see unfold and I
actually think it'll also be in the med
the research area so there you go and
and let me just quickly add because you
these forums a lot of times you think
you're coming and you're getting answers
and sometimes you give us answers um and
or even questions we need to ask I I'm I
represent South Los Angeles disadvantage
Community where will for defiance
they're kicking black and brown kids out
of school or or they're pres prescribing
Rin to take care of them we probably
need to do the research cuz these kids
are experiencing PTSD because they live
in communities where they see people
shot drug deals going on um some kids
are ad and they want to prescrib them
harsh drugs maybe this is the answer is
this industry the medical marijuana
industry might be a better alternative
than what has been prescribed in the
past
[Applause]
hi my name is Teresa Ryan I am the CEO
of a organization called kid we're
Collective here in Southern California
and we prly treat pediatric patients
with cancer epilepsy we have PTSD crom's
patients as well it's already very
expensive for us to grow extract and
provide this medicine to our patients
and the care that we also give them and
helping them with our dosing protocols
my major concern are the licenses that
my company and other companies are now
going to have to purchase in order to
still continue to do those growing
methodologies the extraction processes
providing of this medicine to these
patients having parents that we deal
with adop that have sick children
they're very very strapped financially
and they can barely AF afford the
medicine as it is now so can you tell me
do you guys have any idea or uh what the
pricing structure is going to be and how
is that going to affect the cost of the
medicine for these really sick people
who truly need
it I'll just I'll take we don't we don't
know what the fees and and and you have
to remember this this legislation number
one hasn't been signed yet so so if it
is signed by the governor that this it
will go through a regulatory process
totally understand where you're coming
from in the modern medical community we
have ways of dealing with with what
you're dealing with there are programs
that allow for sick people to get
medicine it's not the intent of what
we're doing what anyway to be punitive
in any way it was not meant it was not
meant to be that way but it it there are
I believe there are protocols and things
that need to be follow I mean I can't
tell you how many licenses and fees I
had to to do to provide care for
patients oftentimes care that I gave
away and and and and continued to do
that for the 27 years I practiced
because it was the right thing to do so
I personally subsidized a lot of care
out of my own pocket um and would do it
and would do it again in a heartbeat
um but there needs to be there need to
be mechanisms and there there there I
believe there will that will happen and
I and I would challenge the I would
challenge the industry to to create a
foundation to do something to help in
situations like this with critically old
children and people who have chronic
diseases that really need management so
I hear you and um I hope that you will
continue to correspond with us so that
we can get we can get that um get that
message out there and take care of the
people who really need it and then just
to jump in of course prop 215 had the
issue of access and affordable access
and every time the bill got amended I
was in my legisla coun my legislative
director's office making sure we have a
provision in the bills for a task force
that will be advising the imple the
Bureau of Med medical marijuana
regulation on its implementation and a
specific charge of the task force is
look at issues of accessibility as
affects uh patients and uh their
caregivers so what I would say is I
actually believing this issue of
affordable access is vitally important I
feel the work of putting together the
bill is a mammoth work a mammoth
undertaking tremendous but this issue
has been on sort of my personal radar
screen and I just made sure that at
every iteration that language stayed in
it's moved around a little bit exactly
how it's phrased but the ACC you know
the accessibility and for patients is an
element of the ongoing work of this
study thing so that's something you're
going to want to follow and when we're
done I can give you the site thank you
thank you so
[Applause]
much I'm uh Frank Marino from mgic
marijuana Investment Company we invest
across the sector and have investments
in
distribution manufacturing fused
products and dispensaries and I'm
curious to know just in summary what
this legislation will mean uh for those
uh those companies in terms of uh
compliance and keeping and
regulation Frank were you just to
clarify are you talking about the like
the uh the
uh restrictions on on vertical
integration like you can't own certain
types of licenses or what are you
talking about specifically what uh what
what sort of new compliance uh issues or
regulations are embedded in the bills uh
for those three categories distribution
manufactures and fused products and
dispensors Visa in particular Visa the
uh the federal guidelines in other words
to the extent that these companies are
in compliance with the new
legislation how do you see that fold in
and and Bing and strengthening the uh
the industry here in California I mean
some quick observation on the
manufacturer side some processes use
volatile solvent some don't there's a
different license depending upon what
style you have there is a licensing
requirement of Manufacturers on uh
Distributors and dispensing There Are
Rules There are rules concerning Safety
and Security of the business premises
with respect to
dispensaries um transportation rules
between dispensaries end up getting
regulated the Safe Harbor under
California law against prosecution
hinges upon being licensed so if you're
in that space you're going to want to
get licensed because that protect T you
from the law enforcement side there are
like 17 different licenses and they deal
with specialty cultivation small
cultivation moderate cultivation there
there's there's quite a structure but
it's not like you throw a switch on
January 1st and it's in place it's going
to take time to roll out but I would
just say uh you know any one of us can
get you a style of bill print out which
is uh as as it amends current law so you
can actually look at the bills as they
went through and see set out on italics
what's new and you you carve out two
hours of your time you kind of go
through it you'll have a heck of a
bird so so my my staff wrote something
out so to make it appear that I'm smart
so the bill language was designed to
create the Bill language was designed to
create a regulatory framework um that
fit in with existing models in in in
other Industries and did as little
disrupt businesses that have been
operating for decades in a manner that
is consistent with sound policy there
are some local jurisdiction such as city
of San Jose um that require vertical
integration which means that each
business must do cultivation
manufacturing dispensing at the same
time there's a concern from some
stakeholders that allowing unrestricted
vertical integration will be problematic
for enforcement and Public Safety thus
our bill does allow some grandfathering
under specific conditions including
cultivating manufacturing and dispensing
prior to July 1 2015 in addition there
is limited vertical integration allowed
under the confines of the bill we call
it the 314 model which allows an
individual who has no more than three
dispensaries to also hold one
manufacturing license and up to four
acres of cultivations other than these
exceptions the bill only allows for IND
individuals who carry up to two license
types depending on the licensing again
applicants for testing licenses may only
hold a license in that categories
Distributors may also only hold licenses
and only transport and distribution not
cultivation manufacturing testing or
dispensing this is to prevent diversion
as
well just just to add one one quick
thought on there there was actually some
some changes when the first
grandfathering Clause he was speaking
about um where do you he refer the city
of San Jose the word was basically you
could stay vertically integrated if the
ordinance required you uh we they
actually were able to change that and
they added uh they added the word
required or allowed so it actually
expanded it out to any or any basically
any any town where you've been given a
license if they allow you to be
vertically integrated and you're doing
it now you can maintain what you're
doing
now I I would just add that um you know
govern govern government in general is
not terribly Innovative so
um that probably feel like cap feel like
Capt him OB obvious here but you know um
yeah no it's we're not terribly
Innovative and so so you're going to see
as the regulatory process moves forward
especially around distribution
Transportation um and the licensing it's
going to rely on things that are working
well we also have a governor who doesn't
really like the idea of creating new
divisions and things like that so every
the emphasis on on this process has been
around on around using existing uh
programs that work well so so
distribution the the the the three tier
system is was was discussed at great
detail and that I know that puts people
who have vertical distribution uh in
conflict with that but but you're going
to see as we move forward a Reliance on
systems that work well and as you
remember too the regulatory system
process is going to take a couple of
years so it's not going to happen
overnight which once again gives you
that opportunity to to have input and
that's why the the language for these
bills was much more specific until we
got close to the end and when the
administration got involved with us
working with us online a lot of the
specificity was in language went away
because and and I get it I mean I get it
we kind of get wet to the language and
the issues we worked on and all the the
countless stakeholder meetings we had
with with everybody across the board um
it like a parade in our offices quite
frankly um um but but the governor the
governor's office his admin ation kind
of backed up and said okay we want
something more basic around regulatory
because we want to this to evolve we
want to be able to create a system
that's actually going to be able to work
so
so so my hope my hope is that it that it
will and and and and you know that's why
your input in the regulatory process is
going to be so
valuable Jame Shaw um I'm a dispensary
operator in Los Angeles property and I
also founded the union for medic
patients and aite corporated and it
sounds as though you're the the
intendant and thank you by the way for
your great effort this is a great piece
of work and my question is it seems as
though the intention is to license all
property organizations if that's
accurate um how to how do we rectify the
conflict with the the rules of property
in terms of Permitting and transporting
and if it's not then how do we um
interface with the
state being from Los
Angeles and making my first call to the
first bill or some of the first wording
eliminated La allog together and the
first calls were to the City attorney
Michael furer um to to let him know that
and he worked directly with the
governor's office to try to come up with
some solutions um I think they're still
working through that that um I know the
City attorney has specific ideas of what
he can and can't do uh I believe he
believes for example you may not be able
to license in the city of La we have to
work through that and and with measure d
uh with 134 there there now um we we
want to make sure that we ensure and I
think on both ends both the city
attorney's office and the state we want
to make sure that after a certain time
201617 it it doesn't become a major
problem where they they're not in
existence
anymore hi I'm Dr David Derman I'm the
Executive Vice President of the American
Academy of canid Medicine uh have some
uh concerns uh but I was uh delighted to
hear that this is the beginning and not
uh the end um I guess my concern is is
why this isn't being treated like any
other medicine uh why didn't you just
adopt the pharmacy regulations why
didn't you reschedule the sched to and
why didn't you put in $9 million like
John bason sales did in 1999 to do
research on on cancer I mean this is
real
[Music]
[Applause]
medicine and I I look forward to working
with a gentleman in the future I mean I
think you've done a good start and I but
it's only a start I think
um wow it took us 19 years to get to
where we are you know so it's going to
take a little while it's going to take a
little while longer so I I appreciate
the interest I mean I personally have a
concern as a as a current and past
medical provider so so you know this is
not this like you said this is the
beginning not or this is I said the
beginning this is the beginning not the
end um we need we need people like you
to help us um to move forward on this
it's not it's not an oversight the issue
is so large so large we couldn't capture
everything all at once there will be
cleanup legislation there will be
opportunities to make things better
going forward um I introduced a bill
11:00 on uh September 11th because we're
looking at uh at banking regulations
we're be working with a a uh Board of
Equalization member Fiona Ma on trying
to move forward Bank some banking
regulations so that this is not a cash
industry any longer um and which will be
hugely valuable for everybody uh moving
forward so so the these these kinds of
things we can't we couldn't think of
everything we couldn't get everything in
there but we'll you know who knows next
year there may be 10 10 or 15 Bills
moving forward on this subject
you know in a few minutes ago Jim
mentioned the word the movement towards
legitimacy which I think this
constitutes a great vating forward on
legitimacy uh one of the most remarkable
things on the subject was when our bills
reached the four the assembly in June uh
we got a 62 to8 vote in
support of ab 266 off the assembly floor
so that means we had 14 or 17
Republicans joining in support
so I think this the progress on
legitimacy you chip away on that and
other things will come it's sort of that
that island hopping argument you you
advance The Edge others will come along
I think you'll see more of that and I I
want to say one thing I'm a firm
believer in in incremental progress I
mean we could have gone to this huge
huge I mean this was this is a big deal
this is a big package but we could have
tried to Encompass everything and we
could have lost it we could have lost it
all and so the reality is we now I
believe have a strong foothold to be
able to move forward on something and we
will build upon that for the next
several years and so I would much rather
have something that we could start with
then lose it all and have to go back to
Ground Zero like it happened time and
time again in this legislature so so
while it's not perfect um we're not
done hello my name is Stephen MC I work
with medican and I'm also a former
professor of political science and the
one law that we all have to follow is
the law of unintended consequences and
so in reading this legislation there's
there's several things that I see that
are worrisome in terms of independent
consequences the first one is the
distribution model is that in requiring
all of the supply to go through a
distributor somehow the supply chain for
patients is going to be disrupted
because of all the unilinear
unidirectional distribution that's going
on now so that's number one concern
number two is that there's going to be
hundreds of millions of dollars people's
blood and treasure can be poured into
this regulatory process and if it's
delayed or if it doesn't work the
citizens who have decided to get into
this are the ones who are going to
suffer by having to sustain their
businesses while they don't have
permission to do that and then the third
thing is the taxation issue it's a
medicine yet we tax it at 8% that's
borderline pable the only way we're
going to be able to keep the medical
cannabis regime in place is if there's a
lower taxation rate for medical or no
taxation rate for medical ization has a
higher taxation rate and that will
sustain us in the medical model time so
my question to you is um what are you
going to do as far as oversight to make
sure that the regulatory system doesn't
damage us and the industry and can you
commit to us that you'll if if there's a
problem please defer to the current
status quo rather than to the regulatory
need to wrench it and make it right you
understand what I'm
saying well this was a key part of the
266 strategy from day one we have one
agency the medical marijuana regulatory
board in DCA which is actually in charge
early in the conversation people were
having agencies you know food nag is
going to do this but it's an equal with
public health that's going to do this
and equal with the third agency going to
do this we we opted for the idea that
there's one agency in charge that the
legislature could pursue oversight with
directly the other piece of this was
using food and AEG and Public Health we
didn't want to have some somebody in a
brand new agency purporting to come up
with the rules for ad because we felt
that would lead to who knows where the
rules came from and not necessarily well
founded in relation to how other a
interests get dealt with so I would say
the oversight issue is a vital one but
we've got one a one lead agency that the
legislature can bring before bring
before Force to talk about
implementation issues and the other ones
we we're bringing them in because of
their expert
we would expect to see consistency with
how they deal with similar issues in the
non-marijuana
setting I just I would just add that
there hasn't been a there probably isn't
a single piece of legislation never
passed in the state of California that
didn't have unintended consequences so
so I mean and We Know It And we know it
so um so yeah we're I'm committed to
make sure that it's right that it's
right in the end and that the interests
and concerns of patients are protected
um but it's going to be different it's
not going to be exactly the same as it
always happen has been and you need to
understand and if we're going to that
move towards acceptance and Broad
acceptance by the the entire State of
California is is there's a cost to that
I'll just quickly say they call it
clean they call it cleanup language for
a
reason my name is Mayon and I'm an
attorney and patient my question is
about the amendment to 11
368775 the
attorney that's a section that concerns
the collective uh it's what we refer to
as a collective or cooperative
cultivation defense it's the one that is
going to be is going to be rescinded one
year after licenses begin to be issued
um I assume that that uh that
that came about because um uh this
Collective or cooperative cultivation
defense has been used by big
dispensaries and that they were trying
to limit that something that's been
somewhat seen as an abuse and I was
wondering if that was a if that was the
effect of that and I was also wondering
if uh if be
um maybe an unintended consequence of
the law is
that
um there's going to be that vertical
integration requirement for everyone
except for anyone that had um a license
prior uh to
2016 and if in that case um if your
perhaps some ordinances local ordinances
even formalize vertical integration and
Collective Cooperative distribution into
their into their ordinances so in some
cases the big the bigger dispensaries
will actually have they will still be
operating as I see it they don't
necessarily need to get licenses um if
they were operating uh for like
cultivation licenses separate
from uh if they have to get licenses on
every step of the chain or if they're
not required to do that because they
didn't have to do that before
2016 I'll take the first part of that
this that language popped up in amano's
bill first last year it's not something
we were excited about um the thought
process behind it was though 2003 when
they originally wrote point that that
that entire section that was sort of a
compromise between law enforcement and
The Advocates because they didn't want
to actually create regulations that
would sort of legitimize dispensaries so
basically what law enforcement said was
fine they can exist but we're not going
to Define how they have to operate or
work or things like this just saying
these collectives can exist and that was
their kind of um that was their offer
and that's what got the B the bill
through in 2003 what these the problem
is is that is what's kind of created the
gray area which allows Harborside and
some mother with with three plants in
her backyard and her neighbors to they
all operate under that one section and
so they needed to be a to be able to fix
that and so they did what they wanted to
do you know back in 2003 is they're
going to actually create rules now so
the the thought process was we're going
to create this stack of rules rules and
regulations and take out the gray area
and and put in the actual rules and that
was the thought process it wasn't to
allow one group to be vertically
integrated or not it was they were going
to remove the gray area with with black
and white rules unless you guys want to
speak to no I think that's I think
that's I think that's exactly it
so only Pati only able to grow for
themselves and by themselves and not
other than the
there
was no there was case law before that
which clarified that people could could
collectively grow as a group and it's
not the Minch case it's a different case
before that but so people from 25 they
can grow in groups what what what 77
five did was put it in law and clarify
it so you still have the protections you
under have under 215 that doesn't get
changed but what there are changing is
sort of the gray area where it just says
you can't operate without any sort of
rules or regulations attached to it or
that that was the thought process and it
wasn't necessarily us but that was just
the conversations we we've had with with
the uh with law enforcement people who
are working on that issue and and first
of all I want to thank you for your
questions I don't mean I wasn't being
didn't mean to be flipping I often do
that I often say things I really regret
later but it's just who I am um
but um but like that one like that one
yeah like that one like that one
so we're in the same boat so you know
it's whatever whatever so um but but I
think you know to to part partly to
Nate's point which which may not come
out there is a there is a feeling among
law enforcement that that parts of the
collective model have been grossly
abused and so that's where part of this
conversation came from that's that's
that's what my folks that I talked to
law enforcement feel like has happened
whether whether and and when you're
trying to craft something like this
you're trying to work with lots of
different stakeholders to come to
Solutions and so there has there there
has was a feeling that that in some
areas um that it was grossly abused and
I do think that accessibility working
group will deal with will be looking at
that issue of are there people who
arguably under prop 25 clearly should
have ready access and are finding
barriers so I sort of think that is at
the end of the day sort of behind your
question and as I say we made clear that
never dropped out of the bill that is an
element we didn't solve every problem
but we kept a spotlight on certain ones
we want to keep paying attention
to and and finally you know it was never
nothing that we did on anywhere along
the way is meant to be perceived as
punitive towards patients it's not that
way at all quite the opposite quite the
opposite excellent that's it um I've
been told we were supposed to
stop SW me okay a third question thank
you thank you my name is
swam I'm from leville I'm a grower and
so far no one's been speaking for the
grower so I'm a member of the Menino
Canabis policy Council and we've been
working trying to get regulations from
The Growers point of view and as Ola
said recently without the grower you
don't have anything and we're all
concerned about prices for patients but
I'm really concern about maintaining
lifestyle for The Growers and I don't
know how many thousand Growers there are
in assembly M Woods District but very
many and my calculations are that
cannabis brings in between two and6
billion dollars into mesino County every
year and that's just meino County so far
so my question really is you're phasing
out cooperative and Collective
definitions but within the agriculture
there is such a thing as an agricultural
op and I think the only defense for
Growers is in fact going to be members
of an agricultural Co-op will that be
possible in this new legislation because
it's definitely under the agricultural
rules that we supposedly as cultivators
going under that is that is my intention
absolutely okay then the other thing is
are we going to be able to make a
profit there's nothing that stops you
now
and I would ask you I would ask you and
everybody else who's cultivating will
you do it with respect for environmental
laws will you use water that belongs to
you will you be careful with fertilizers
and pesticides will you respect the
environment mcpc and that's and that's
and that's that's my ask I am registered
as clean green with Chris hook good and
I have water I am trying at the most of
my ability to comply and the fact of the
matter is it's a lifestyle
and hum andd Tri we have a lifestyle we
have a culture it's been developing over
60 years and you all benefit from it and
we just want to make sure that we are
recognized we've supported Menino County
for the last 30 years when the L
industry went bankr so please give us
respect and let us grow and we will
comply if you don't make it to H us
[Applause]
[Music]
and on that note we