[Music]
my name is Andrea spiders wha I am the
science editor at cannabis Business
Times I'm joined today by the Whitney
who is the vice president and senior
economist at new frontier data in this
session on globalization consolidation
and segmentation we're going to be
discussing production shifts as global
markets open up how the US will play a
role in the expanding markets the cost
structures that will be needed to
compete moving forward in the next five
years and what sort of policy standards
will need to be put in place to help
that in to help steer the industry
towards sustainability though I'd like
to start a little with an introduction
into how you got became interested in
cannabis economics and how a new
frontier data has enabled you to further
your interests and have a voice in
market trajectory yeah thank you thank
you very much and it's just a pleasure
to be here so I really want to thank all
those involved for allowing me to have a
little bit of a venue today to talk
about the global cannabis marketplace
I've been in the cannabis industry for
about five years now I was teaching in
economics class and one of my students
started asking about how to set up
companies how to set up business
structures and like he let me know that
he was in the cannabis industry and this
is in Oregon and I asked him how large
the market was and he said I don't know
you're the economist you told me and so
I was very intellectually curious I
wasn't in the in the space I was
teaching economics working in high-tech
industry and so I just went for it and
realizing how large that market was in
Oregon I decided to do this full-time
and as a result I put together a
forecast for Oregon first and then
national
around that time new frontier data was
getting started they realized that there
wasn't a whole lot of data in the space
a lot of policy decisions were being
made in a vacuum or based upon headlines
somebody getting really high in Colorado
and not being able to leave their hotel
room for example and so so they realized
that there was an absence of data they
went about it on the East Coast I was
doing similar efforts on the west coast
and then about three years ago we
combined our intellect and and insights
and it's been amazing ever since the one
thing that's interesting is that five
years ago I was you know this dorky
economists in a sweater vest right and
over the course of that five years now
I've been to practically every continent
we talked about policy for hemp and
higher THC cannabis and Zimbabwe last
year heading to Berlin for the ICBC
conference in April the second time
we've been speaking there went down to
Panama and a lot of these conversations
were with Ministry level members
presidential advisors and alike so who
would have thought five years ago that
that would be the course of cannabis
five years later so it's been an amazing
journey where are we now in terms of US
production environments in terms of
indoor outdoor and greenhouse sort of
ratios so a lot of the a lot of the
cultivation right now is kind of forced
indoors due to the illegalities the
higher THC cannabis production however a
lot of the production in say on the west
coast is done outdoors and so you know
it's being the outdoor crops are being
exported to other places around the
country so you know I think 81 percent
of all of the cultivation is sold
through illicit channels so there's a
lot to that question but as things get
more mainstream I envision larger scale
commercial farming
and that would be more outdoor in nature
due to the cost structure doesn't mean
that a lot of those craft growers are
going to be out of a job or out of the
business it's just I think that there
will be fewer of the craft growers
relative to the larger commercial ones
what is influencing those sort of
projects other what other things are
influencing production shifts in the US
and do you think there'll be some there
will be production divergence between
cannabis and hemp cannabis markets yeah
the what's driving a lot of this is cost
consumers are very cost-conscious
there's high levels of elasticity and
the demand meaning that consumers are
price sensitive and so so in that sense
if you have inexpensive cannabis then
consumers will gravitate towards it
that's why policy is really important
because if you have high taxation like
they do say here in California then it
may price the legal growers out of the
market so price is a determinant but
quality is as well what we're seeing is
you know indoor remains competitive
because of its the the nature of its
quality and its consistency we're seeing
imports from I mean interdictions from
Mexico and like going way down
considerably like 80 90 percent fewer
interdictions over the last four or five
years and that's because the southern or
the the cannabis come in from Mexico and
and south of the border it can't compete
with quality so there's a quality aspect
and a pricing aspect which is driving
innovation into the marketplace you know
cannabis was an industry long before
prohibition Sears catalogs used to sell
it
one of the irony's of prohibition is
that it gave us a community as well a
movement how do you see large-scale
indoor production playing out against
the crafts market and will craft
cannabis continue to hold its place
within the industry and you know how can
those craft players strategize to retain
a substantial market share against big
businesses you know it's it's been
interesting because we study not only
the higher THC cannabis market but the
industrial side of the cannabis market
as well and we're seeing a little bit of
a divergence just in that aspect there's
that on the hemp side there is large
commercial operations generating tens of
millions of pounds per year in biomass
and the smaller farmers cannot compete
with that in terms of price so what they
are doing and this is kind of in its
nascent stages they're teaming up with
their fellow farmers and communities and
forming coops and so the coop model is
rather prevalent in the hemp industry
whereas I think on the higher THC side
it's going to take a while for that part
of the market to develop but what's
interesting is that there like I said
earlier there's going to be a place for
both sides of the of the business that
commercial and the craft growers it's
just going to I think shift more heavily
towards the commercial side as this
market matures and as the regulations go
more a national and international let's
move up north a little bit to Canada do
you think Canada will be a major
producer and is there a future for large
scale greenhouses in Ontario and and
alike well a lot of the licensed
producers or LPS
invested heavily in the Canadian markets
they got this war chest of money from
inflated stock prices and the like and
they've deployed that money to establish
these large commercial indoor grows
unfortunately they got a little bit too
far out over their skis
and there wasn't sufficient demand in
the Canadian market which is roughly the
size of the California market there
wasn't enough demand to satisfy all that
supply and in addition to that on the
you know in the Parliament and in Canada
they've set up some policies which have
limited the pace of the deployment of
the retail system so not only do you
have this large amount of supply or at
least supply capacity you don't have the
ability to get it into the consumers
hands and so that's exacerbated the
illicit market there was hope and I
think this was reflected in the stock
prices that the Canadians could
translate that large capacity into the
export market but that hasn't
materialized as much as people had
thought and as a result they're not
hitting their numbers the large license
producers are not hitting their numbers
like they thought they would there's
some barriers to entry say in the
European Union that which is the market
of choice for for those producers
there's been barriers to entry that were
unanticipated and it's influenced the
amount that could actually be exported
so are they going to be large players I
kind of doubt it
they had their run and it didn't go so
well but there's going to be other
countries that are going to supplant
them eventually there's still some time
in the Canadian market but I think their
time is running out
you mentioned stocks so let's kind of
touch over to that very quickly we've
seen a great deal of variability with
stock performance how has current market
volatility impacted the development
solid ation of the industry in north
america and what will it look like over
the next five years yeah the the access
to capital has been a major thorn in the
side of the development of the cannabis
industry in the United States not having
banking not having being heavily taxed
via 280e
it's really impacted the growth but what
it's also impacted is the ability to to
get financing to run your business and
so as a result there's been as the as a
market it has expanded in the u.s. in
Illinois and Michigan and elsewhere
there's been more players requiring more
money but there's just hasn't been as
much money available now it doesn't mean
that there's no money out there but it's
just tougher to get so as growers as
operators people really need to be
cognizant of how competitive the the
financing market is and they need to put
their best foot forward in terms of
making the pitch to acquire that money
and we you know in our phone just kind
of a we talked a little bit how this
stock market can also drive innovation
yeah you know as as more and more
players enter into the space there's
been and as investors toggle between
their risk tolerance you know sometimes
it's riskier they'll do more on the
plant touching side and other aspects
it's you know if there's a change in
attorney general for example there may
be shifts in the risk tolerance of those
investors and so they may invest in the
infrastructure or the picks and shovels
and so that's because there's been that
toggling between plant touching and and
non plant touching investment it's
driven innovation even in that sense and
then also as the cost is a major factor
and profitability comes into play then
that's driving innovation as well areas
to reduce cost energy consumption
lighting air movement especially on the
indoor side you know all of this comes
into play and is driving that that type
of innovation and it's also driving
innovation on the propagation side you
know four or five years ago I never even
thought about stem cell propagation very
very low cost and that's a innovation
that was outside of the industry but has
since been brought in biomass production
for plant extraction and minor
cannabinoid isolates including CBD is a
rapidly expanding and competitive
commodity market how will supply and
demand influence where and how this area
of the industry develops over the next
five years yeah you know on the
industrial side of things with the farm
bill that was passed in 2018 a lot of
people jumped into the market the number
of acres license for example increased
over 400% it went from roughly a hundred
thousand acres license to five hundred
thousand acres right and so a lot of
people got in thinking that they were
just going to get rich and everybody was
going to be doing CBD and all this stuff
yeah and that wasn't the case we
because there was a lot of
infrastructural and supply chain issues
that people didn't anticipate it
anticipate when they jumped in and so
the supply chain has really limited the
growth and development of the industrial
hemp market now that's starting to
change but it's gonna take a lot of time
it's going to take years and not months
for example and processing seems to be
the biggest bottleneck in the entire
supply chain there's a lot of demand out
there and so there's been talks of
oversupply
there's just oversupply relative to the
capacity for the processors to process
it it's not over necessarily in my
opinion it's not necessarily over supply
relative to the demand you've got large
cosmetic manufacturers you've got large
beverage providers that are just waiting
in the wings doing their product
development but they just don't trust
supply chain yet and so that's
inhibiting the growth the demands
they're just not enough supply making it
into the market where will it be in five
years I think certainly those supply
chain issues in terms of not only
processing but packaging transportation
storage drawing all of that on the
biomass side and the industrial side
will have a place in the market and
there's I think the the opportunity for
industrial hemp is far larger than the
higher THC side of cannabis because
there's more product offerings and
product capabilities fiber side
everybody talks about CBD because it's
sexy but there's bio plastics there's
food products there's you know
industrial applications that people
really aren't talking about but I think
that is the next wave of the industrial
side of cannabis especially how that
I think revitalize rural communities to
the idea that where you could have hemp
farming and industrial production and
manufacturing within the same town and
allow this those communities to grow
again I'm really excited about that yeah
you know that's where that whole coop
concept comes into play because large
consumers of isolate or dis lit on the
CPG side they're looking for consistency
in their product offerings and their
product inputs the raw material inputs
and so communities have the opportunity
to sync up plant the same strain
harmonized on their production capacity
and their capabilities and then cobble
together enough supply to satisfy these
large large actors in the space let's go
back to the sort of global idea in
equatorial regions outside of the US and
North America
well outdoor and greenhouse biomass
production be a competitive force
against indoor giants in cooler climates
and how the discussions so I think that
debate is still going to occur with
respect to producing cannabis in
tropical areas because of the moisture
content and humidity and so there's
issues associated with mold and and
other things that need to be addressed
and there's not a whole lot of seeds or
genomes let's say that are that thrive
in tropical regions and so there's large
opportunities for for those that can
supply into those areas however one
thing that was I mentioned earlier that
we were in Zimbabwe and we talked to the
government about deploying a hemp
program there and and kind of outlined
jobs and economic development and and
the benefits and they started a program
just recently
what they didn't realize is that because
of their proximity relative to the
equator
the plants grew faster and they matured
quicker and they had a greater faster
time-to-market and so there was a
competitive advantage that they didn't
even realize that they had as a result
of that they had to adjust their
propagation strategies and their
cultivation operations and like to
adjust for that but they were pleasantly
surprised and so I think that is one
thing that we'll see as more and more
global cannabis cultivation occurs and
there are players like in Thailand and
Laos that are looking at establishing a
foothold for to supply into Asia and so
and they have low inputs from a cost
perspective and so they may be able to
take a lot of the market share that the
the colder climate cultivators currently
have and you know once we start to see a
global market expanding global market
the idea that we could actually start to
cultivate chemo VARs in their land race
and fire
and being able to have that
specialization it's very exciting yeah I
mean that in that sense the
opportunities are really unlimited now
over 80 countries have some form of
cannabis legalization either for CBD for
medical for industrial hemp so yeah and
so the US market in that sense is
actually behind and they need to catch
up in order to remain competitive in the
global marketplace how the discussions
around climate change and industry
sustainability influence sourcing
outcomes you know I think on the on the
climate change side of things what it's
driving is the conversation and
education and that's a really good thing
to do the education about how you know
what the carbon footprint is what the
impact of water consumption use of
pesticides in the environment I think
all of that is good to analyze and study
and educate people what we're also
seeing is that it's changing the
behavior of investors and for those that
have a brand that highlight their lack
of environmental impact let's say and
their considerations for you know
climate change and like those are
differentiating factors that are good
for a brand that they can promote you
know in the future we're also seeing on
the investment side that and this is
similar for wine growers as well they're
competing for the same land and they're
chasing land opportunities north so for
example some of the Napa Valley growers
of grapes are moving into Southern
Oregon and competing for Southern Oregon
land and so it's increasing the property
valuations as a result so there's a lot
of movement and a lot of influence that
that climate change has had on the
industry as a whole
as a you know an industry in its infancy
the cannabis industry has the
opportunity to really take hold of
sustainability and innovation and and
present a model a standard of best
practices for other environments we have
people here today obviously that aren't
just in the cannabis industry how do you
think how do you see that playing out
over the next five years that sort of
interaction between the cannabis
industry and and and other agriculture
well um you know I think that in driving
of the innovation a lot of this has come
from within the industry and so that's
been a good thing and I think that over
time this will expand because for the
longest time the community was you know
very secretive and because of the
illicit nature of it so there wasn't as
much mine share that has occurred that
it didn't occur previously and it's
starting to occur now so now that people
are talking they're sharing best
practices and the like and as a result
you know there's a greater push towards
sustainability just because it's in the
conversations and then I'm not sure if
cannabis has gotten the respect that
it's due in terms of the maturity of the
market the generations of effort that
people have put into it and so there's
not as much of a push from the outside
on the sustainability side as there is
from the inside pushing out it's
unfortunate
if we do it right what are you seeing
now in terms of cannabis and hemp hemp
cannabis commodity product the product
prices fluctuation yeah so on the higher
THC side as markets mature and you get
more cultivation than prices just
naturally go down on the industrial side
it was a buyers market this last harvest
meaning that the processors had the
upper hand because there was limited
capacity and as such they were able to
drive the price down and I didn't
necessarily see a bottom I thought that
there might be but I saw some quotes out
there at at 40 cents or 60 cents per
percent of CBD for hemp biomass which is
just shocking considering just a year
ago as it was approaching $4 and so one
thing to consider though is that
although it's a highly competitive
market in the u.s. both for industrial
and for higher THC cannabis people need
to keep a watchful eye on the
international development because those
people that are looking at the Thailand
market they want to drive their
production costs down to less than a
penny a gram talking about competing
with you know talking about cannabis is
medicine you know if
10 cent per pill ibuprofen you know how
do we get to that point what what kind
of price what do we need to get to with
commodities with him commodities to be
able to actually compete against like
pharmaceuticals and over-the-counter
drugs yeah so as the prices go down on a
global basis then that will benefit
those folks that need it most the the
medicinal patients that don't have the
means in which to acquire their their
medicine and so I see that as a good
thing it just makes it challenging from
a business perspective in that interim
period oh and one other thing is that
not only is the cannabis cultivation you
know expanding globally and driving the
competitive nature and you know on the
global side other countries are an
existential threat but keep in mind that
the pharmaceutical companies aren't
necessarily standing idle and so they're
creating products and doing more
research and so they're just as much as
an existential threat then you know just
the global marketplace and here's an
example so in 2017 the CBD market was
roughly a seven eight hundred million
dollar market in the US and half of the
CBD was supplied by the marijuana side
half of it was supplied by the hem fast
forward just into 2019 now a full third
of the market is supplied from GW Pharma
and so you know so there's that
existential threat that's occurred that
people weren't necessarily anticipating
even two or three or four years ago that
being said you know I think we've seen a
shift away from people's trust in
pharmaceuticals especially after the
opioid crisis how well cultural paradigm
shifts like increased interest in local
and organic so we're seeing an
alternative medicine in the wake of the
opioid crisis influenced the future of
the cannabis and how cannabis market so
I think that that will play a large role
because we've done at new frontier data
we've done a lot of surveys not only in
the US but globally and we're about to
come out with some results on the EU CBD
studies and the u.s. CBD surveys and
what we're seeing not to steal any
headlines here but what we're seeing is
that people while they don't necessarily
want pharmaceutical you know drugs and
supply they trust it from a safety
perspective and so until the point comes
where the cannabis market can
demonstrate that there's you know safe
consistent supply dosage
you know that's consistent on a delivery
mechanism that people trust then there's
always going to be that that stigma
attached from a safety perspective but
once they can overcome that then it's
very very viable that they can steal a
lot of market share away from the
pharmaceutical on demand
possibility of any sort of you know
policy shift that would allow you know
pharmaceutical research and you know
craft and industry growers to to all
have a little piece of the pie there's a
lot of discussion on on these very
topics reform for veterans they allow
allowing for research and in fact we
just help prep some folks for some
congressional testimony for next week in
DC and they're really pushing for the
ability to do research the ability to do
to allow veterans access to you know in
order to move this along just recently I
spoke in Portland Oregon at the Oregon
Health Sciences University it was a the
topic was you know the benefits of
cannabis on the human body and there's
not a whole lot of research out there
except for some good work being done and
say Israel or Canada and like but a lot
of the doctors there that had done some
research showed that there was an impact
on the human body but it just needed
more research in order to fully vet it
out to see what's an appropriate dosage
what impact does it have on spasticity
on pain management and you know
childhood epilepsy and life so it's just
there's going to be more research done
and there's a push a lot of discussions
at the federal level it's just it's
unfortunately just taking some time the
last few minutes before we move to
I know you have been interested in
talking about intentionality and I'd
like to give you a little time to kind
of go into that yeah you know it's a lot
of the in the research that we've done
there's there's the concept of intent
that's coming up a lot farmers in France
for example growing industrial cannabis
with the intention of supplying a
specific market farmers in the Midwest
for example that are coming together to
grow a specific crop for fiber or for a
specific product that intentionality has
been just it's been coming up a lot but
in addition there's been people that
have jumped into this market that want
to do good things for good people and so
that intention also has been really
resonant with me personally as well as
with others because it just promotes
goodness in a world right now where that
can be considered a challenge is there
anything else that you'd like to add
that we haven't covered today no I think
that just a couple of closing thoughts
there's right now it's roughly a
thirteen billion dollar legal market and
it's growing for a higher THC just alone
and that's just in the United States but
it's really a seventy billion dollar
market if you look at the illicit
activity and the illicit distribution
channels so there's a tremendous
opportunity for those that get in here
still if they have a good value
proposition then they can get some money
right but there's this tremendous
opportunity still now based upon some
research that we did last year the
Global Markets a 350 billion dollar
market and 230 million consumers
globally I'm just a higher THC cannabis
so there's a market out there that is
relatively untapped and for those people
that have the vision
have the ability have the mindset you
know the sky is really the limit it's
very very exciting it's still in its
nascent stages and that's what really
gets me going in the morning and I don't
want to close my computer down at night
so the question was the GW Pharma number
we had forecasted that in 2019 they add
about a third of the the u.s. CBD market
share the other equally distributed
distributed between higher THC cannabis
and industrial cannabis they are the
only CBD pharmaceutical on the market
everything else is within the industry
so you know as far as the the ability of
doctors to prescribe any sort of
cannabis outside of a medical program
that really is the only option beyond
you know your drew Nabin all's and says
Mets and such that we're from like the
1980s where THC like compounds forgive
me if this came up already but have you
spoken about the size of the home grow
sector and how that would impact the
overall market and the future of home
grow in the canvas yeah so the question
is about regarding home grow and the
percentage of the market in our analysis
we've only seen maybe 2 or 3 percent of
the total production is based in home
grow so it doesn't really necessarily
move the needle as much as large-scale
commercial operations outdoor production
and like going forward it's it's really
tough to say in in my opinion though
when you can buy Tomatoes
at the grocery store versus growing them
that's kind of the analogy I make and so
people want to dabble into the home
cultivation side but I I'm not
anticipating that everybody will stick
to it in the long run I think that's an
excellent question I do think it is very
important moving forward that as new
states come online they allow people to
grow at home I mean it is it is not
going to be everybody's cup of tea not
everybody is going to have a garden full
in the backyard but for the people who
need large quantities who want to make
sure they know how it's sourced to find
a team of are that they really like and
want to keep it going who you know want
to have control over their own medicine
that has to be a priority and I don't
think it's you know just as my own
personal opinion and I'm not an
economist but I don't think it's going
to compete with the market as a whole
you know people still want something you
know that they can their grocery stores
still exist even though Gardens you know
people are growing gardens but I think
it's extremely important that that is in
place in every single state all right
thanks for the presentation my name is
Erica Matos and with the greenhouse
lighting consortium my question is
regarding market where the market is
going we got questions sometimes people
asking with the legalization here in
u.s. coming up on these states
eventually getting national legalization
where the cultivation going to go we
work with lighting so my question is has
this we're trying to see that the
lighting market so the the final
question is if it gets legalized
everywhere do you think the coat evasion
going to go to clean houses they're
going to go outdoors and would they move
to the southern states or you have a lot
of lighting or are they going to go up
north and going with the controlled
environmental agriculture set up so
those market trends is that possible to
do in estimative and gases well the the
longevity of the indoor market
we'll be determined by the federal
regulators because right now each state
has to set up their own closed system in
order to legalize and cultivate and
distribute cannabis and so that's great
for suppliers of the picks and shovels
into the market because you have to set
up a new market in every state that
legalizes now there are some there's a
push to allow for exports out of states
that have a competitive advantage such
as California Oregon Washington Colorado
and so if that push to allow for exports
occurs and comes to fruition then that
could be a threat to the size of the
opportunity for green house suppliers
for indoor lighting and HVAC and the
like so in the short run over the next
few years definitely a strong
opportunity for suppliers that support
the indoor and green house grow
operations well we talked to a lot of
craft artists and cultivators whether no
matter how they're growing and as in the
northern region they look to the
development of Appalachian as as
something that will really help them
survive what do you think that role will
be and other things like that that might
help support crop growers so one of the
negatives about large scale cultivation
is that it limits the amount of
different varietals in this space and so
that's why I appreciated your answer on
home grows is because you'll have that
different varietal that's that works
well with that individual person now as
I see it in the future
there'll be a VA or aviary zones where
growers will grow in specific regions of
the country
with specific soil composition and
humidity and climate and they'll be
known for those limited productions and
so I think that there's great
opportunity for small-scale production
of that nature it's it's similar to wine
right you grow a particular varietal of
of grape and then it's limited run
because you have limited space in which
to grow I think that is very very viable
in the future now with respect to the
Appalachia region I was in recently in
Tennessee and Kentucky
Oh appellees all right sorry
and so um no with so um no I just the I
think there'll be specific zones that
will be known there'll be destinations
you'll set up Kanna tourism you'll come
to that vineyard model and and I think
that's definitely viable for a lot of
the states that can grow appreciate you
mentioning a can of tourism and maybe
you could just talk a little bit more
about that as a cannabis policy
professional I recognize that we are
have have a huge lack of license types
that encourage the tourism side of the
business and it ends up being just yet
another piece of the underground market
for cannabis but maybe anything that
you've seen or what you might expect to
happen around cannabis tourism so on the
canna tourism side what we saw in our in
our numbers in the forecast is that
there is this can of tourism effect we
saw it heavily in Nevada because people
come into Nevada they go to Las Vegas
they have their fun over a weekend and
we predicted
you know what the surgeon demand would
be relative to the to the canna tourism
you
Nevada but we underestimated it because
what people do is they they buy way more
than they could possibly consume over
that weekend in Las Vegas and but there
is an effect of Kanna tourism from you
know into Oregon in a California and
like even in the Northeast with
Massachusetts and going up into the New
England area and there's a viable market
there the viability though will be
determined by the regulators in those
states because they can have a major
influence on setting up policies that
are favorable for Canada tourism or not
and then also social consumption is
another issue that is on the forefront
right now and so there's there are these
pushes in Colorado and Oregon and
elsewhere to allow for social
consumption but it's kind of lower on
the priority list than some of the other
things like export like supply and
demand and balancing licenses and like
so it's not quite it hasn't quite
percolated up yet to be one of those
issues that will coalesce with the
policymakers and and will succeed
through the legislative process but it's
a huge industry
it's just relatively untapped right now
I think that's it we're doing a great
job thank you very much thanks
[Applause]