I always just do you know wet paper
towel and wait a couple days and so what
what's your if you had for example these
are all from Pacific Northwest routes I
have other stuff but like if you had 20
seeds or 50 seeds for your home grow
what's kind of your starting point from
a you know hard seed to sprout in okay
okay so seed germination is really what
the main goal is to is to get liquid to
be imbibed into the actual embryo so
that we can activate it chemically right
we get the enzymes moving and the
problem is is that people sometimes
think old seed will will not open up
quickly and new seed will open up
quickly because all you see is the
exterior of the seed and so what your
tough to make the part that makes it
hard to crack seed knowingly is did the
person who made the seed or did the seed
that was collected in wild did it
actually go through its full cycle and
put on a full carbohydrate load within
the embryo so that it's stored in the
quarter lead as they come out and then
it starts to turn into a plant once we
start to get real photosynthetic
activity but the fact that you don't
know how much carbohydrate is stored in
the seed is the issue that I see most
people have seed cracking issues with
and so what happens is if you don't have
enough food in the seed when it opens
when it imbibes and the plant starts to
emerge there's not enough stored
carbohydrates for this plant to actually
open up and so when people go into soil
direct which is really how little farms
are run in all other AG they don't start
them and then transplant they go direct
seed well the thing is is they know that
the seed they're using is loaded and
ready to go and so for the cannabis seat
certain people do better jobs with their
seed production and some batches come
out better than others and some of them
that have been stored for time on is you
know viable so what i always recommend
with cannabis seed is not to direct seed
what I like to do
first is take the collection a seed that
I'm gonna work with by variety and I
just put it into a little baby food jar
or a shot glass and if if if I have
extremely rare seeds I think are
something from the past that I know are
old I go a little bit further than just
putting water in the container I'll use
something like a seed tea so you can
germinate beans and pull the liquid off
and use that liquid and that liquid is
loaded with all these hormones and
enzymes that came from that plant and
it's directly a stimulant for other
seeds sorry when you say germinate beans
do you mean light like dry it like white
beans and anything you want to germinate
because ultimately any being--you that
you can get your hands on that you soak
in water and pull off that liquid it's
enzymatically charged to assist in the
germination of something so you can go
really deep into seed tea technology but
the thing is is if you have stuff that's
old so in your hands right now you have
all this brand new stuff and KY isn't a
good reader so he knows what he's doing
he produces a really good product and
he's been doing it for a long time
consistently so with stock like his all
I need to do is open that container get
a container of regular water it doesn't
have to be distilled water I pull it
right off the tap we're lucky in the
country where our taps come in around
like six seven if you're in you know the
Bay Area and you had eight three you
don't really treat it water I'm not sure
what like la and stuff like that is the
same thing then you'd be better if you
pick up some distilled water because all
you're gonna use that water for is just
to moisten the seed and what I do is I
throw the seed into that container and I
usually add like a tiny drop of some
type of non ionic surfactant and that's
like a cocoa wet you know just something
and I stirred in the water and what it
does is it coats the seed with that
material which allows the water to bond
to it better and then I get better
penetration and I let the seeds sit in
that jar at least 24 30 hours and every
you know six seven hours all walk in
with the pen and I'll just stir the
container let him swirl around but so
these are fully submerged
mr. floating it floating because they
haven't imbibed the liquid and so that
that surfactant bonds to the the
pericarp the skin of the seed and allows
you to get water to actually you know
connect on like I'm on a molecular level
and then you just swirl them around a
couple times and I'll walk in once or
twice during that whole twenty four
thirty hour process and I'll give it a
little spin with a pencil and by the
time thirty I was of going by you should
see all of them at the bottom if they've
imbibed the liquid and if there's a
couple of floaters you can take a look
and realize that they are floaters where
they they're not gonna pick up any
liquor so they've been in there for
thirty hours and they're just still
floating on the surface
I can those but it's typically you're
gonna see you know 95% of the seed that
you put in the container will hit the
bottom I take those seeds out and I pour
it out onto a paper towel so that I can
then spread them out a little and I just
have a pair of really nice precision
tweezers and I just pick up each seed
and I place it into the media that I'm
going to use to do my actual true
germination and so what I've done in
that jar is I've been by liquid into the
embryo and I've got it moving now when I
go into the media that I'm going to use
I really like to use something that's
like a screen mix which means that this
it's really fine but it's gonna
composite a material so there's a mix of
cocoa mix of peat a little bit of some
kind of pumice so that it's very light
and highly aerated and what I like to do
is I don't put a hole in the dirt at all
i pre wet the tray so the tray has been
wet and then I just take the seed and I
literally put it right on top of that
soil right in the middle on each one of
those little cell flats and then once
everything set in place I have this
ultra fine mister I just run over the
top and it bends them right in in like
you know sixteenth to 1/32 inch covering
of the media because all we're trying to
do is get it to dark enough so that the
plant can can doesn't prematurely
desiccate before it opens and then the
plants crowd I don't I don't already in
take the seed I don't worry about
putting it down
line as a plant phototrophic and grab
atrophic which means the roots are gonna
go down whether you like it or not and
the shoots are going to go up so once we
lay it on that that tray and we give it
a light misting it begs them at this
perfect depth to where you're not
challenging the seed to have enough
stored energy to emerge from half inch
three I mean I've seen people berry
seeds deep and when you when you don't
get the germination what I used to do is
I stake the pot so I'm gonna cut them in
half and open them up and then you can
see that the seed had opened and had
extended 3/8 of an inch but did not have
any more energy to go any further and
subsequently died within that soil
chamber so if you lay the seed as a
delicate layer on top and just wet it in
and then sit it and ideally I would have
it with decent light and by the way the
taproot has not popped out yet correct
no no you're gonna see the emergence of
it you're gonna see the seeds swollen
and you'll start to see a crack and
you'll see the very beginning of that
tap and that's why I don't worry about
all the sitting bids when you're doing a
lot of seed trying to put each one in
the hold exactly as it is
when the water hits it it's going to
move a little bit the main point is if
that we crack it and open it so that it
doesn't have to fight to get out of the
shell and then we can bury it into the
media shallow and then get the bottom
end to be around 78 82 where the tray
itself is around 78 82 degrees those
things are going to jump and then as
soon as I get my first true leaf so
you'll according to lead will pop out
that was your embryo and then then you
get your first true leaves once those
first true leaves are there you're able
to start treating it with a stronger
nutrient solution but when we when we
typically put the plant into that pot we
don't really need any nutrients at that
moment because they should be stored
within the plant itself and so as soon
as we see the plant make its its
emergence we'll see to quarterly this
will see the first true leaf as soon as
those first realeased come in that's
when we fertilize and that would be your
sequence and then once we fertilize it
and soak them down now we start to be
able to have
everything present to build nutrient and
you don't want to go into heavily
fertilized soil as your base soil just
because it's a little aggressive for a
young seedling and so organically this
is you can do this organically
chemically it doesn't make a difference
how you deliver it it's just the fact
that the plant wants to be moisture then
it needs to have aeration and adequate
temperature and so you personally don't
use like cubes or anything like that you
just go straight to soil I would rather
go straight to swell and whisk let's
define soil of soil is so soil not dug
from the ground out of the earth but
something that we've manufactured right
and I most definitely would prefer to go
into that than cubes because the the
whole thing was if you're especially if
you're doing a lot of them the cost per
OSS or the cost per rock wall is so
disproportionately high compared to the
cost of regular media and so those are
excellent for propagation of clonal
because the the applicability of an
inert media lets you go anywhere with it
in terms of any direction any kind of
cultivation system but when I'm cracking
seed I'm looking for something that's a
cloning but when I'm cracking seed
because I used to do a lot of seed I
would I would always do it out of a
screen mix and so I could buy something
like what's a good mix right now that
you can buy commercially baby roots from
soil king right so soil king out of
cloverdale has a big roots mix oh he's
got a baby roots mix that kicks ass for
doing seeds it's already been
pre-screened and so you don't have to
screen it yourself through a screen to
make sure there's no clumpy shake and
then when you just lay the tray soak it
and you see that the cost per tray is is
you know nickels 20 cents it mean it's
cheap when you get right down to how
much it's costing you to fill the tray
versus ten eleven bucks for an oasis
sheet or you know depending on what what
quantity
where you're at but the course
differences is the difference and so
seedlings do wonderful in Rockwall and
seedlings do wonderful in Oasis and
they've been phenomenal in those cubes
right there but you know for the average
home individual I'm like buy bag a seed
mix and put it in your closet and shit
you'll have enough seed mix to grow seed
for the next five years if you're just
working small crops so now get into the
like be one and things like that do you
do you personally add anything to you
know the whole like root growth and
transplant shock and plant stress I
don't I don't and and the reason being
is that if you really you know a look in
California legal stuff you're not
allowed to use really any hormones
anymore for rooting so you can't really
use I don't think you can use in the
tear gas adorn a Placida Cassatt those
are those were plant acids that we
utilize to help drive rooting and
commercial agriculture we use them
cannabis only tonight leaves something
like clone acts or something like that
is that both of those so you're not
allowed to use that anymore in
California not for cannabis it's not
certified for cannabis production so
those are meant those are meant for like
ornamentals so you can buy it at the
store but it's not meant for food
production right and so cannabis is
regulated as a food production so you
use those to do coronal aids and what
you end up doing is you just end up
creating healthier plants and you strike
less viable ones you just call right out
of the mix and so California is going
into propagation you have a little
different strategy because you don't
have the tools to make things bite like
you once did but the seeds you don't
need that and if you take a look at any
of these like commercial rooting aids
they're basically a little bit of kelp
to make it look dark and then they're
adding some type of soy isolate protein
to it which is extremely efficient in
getting the plant to move aggressively
but the bottom line is you can buy soya
silly protein relatively cheap compared
to paying huge money for it mix it into
a can with a little bit of cow
to make it look like it's some kind of
special concoction so if you look at the
labels on those products they're really
they're they're micronutrients in a you
know organic matrix with some form of
soy isolate something that's going to
allow you to get high nitrogen
availability right now and the thing
with transplanting is that if you're
gonna go throwing like a water system
which gives you incredible routing right
so using water you get root water roots
if you go water roots into the water
systems they're unbelievable but if you
go water routes into soil list it takes
a minute for the plant to bite it in so
yeah they do bite in and yeah they have
great root balls on but there's a
there's a transition with plants having
to form the structure of the root and
the chemistry of the root to work with
the media that's on hand and so the the
fastest way to get any transplant would
be to utilize the system that you're
going to use in the end system so it's
gonna go soilless it can move through
all soil assistance if you're going to
go into the plug that you just showed
that composite rubber some kind of
organic material they wove into a matrix
that can go pretty much into anything
because it has movability
the root cubes they're good too because
ultimately the root is held inside it
really anything that's outside it's
gonna die off pretty much when you put
it into the pot some of you the new
roots that come out of it that make that
bug in connection and so if you're
trying to do you know it an easy routing
transition then what you're trying to
make sure is that you're looking
downstream of where is the end plant
gonna go and then you just match the
media so I use and doesn't be the exact
media but has to be similar so the
plants developing the system for the
transplant that's why usually your
transplant mixes are very simple and
light and fluffy and then it can go into
anything from there because you're not
having a large container of roots that
are gonna have to readapt and develop is
there anyone that you respect who you've
had conversations with about you know
this like popping
seeds to transplanting where they have a
totally they do something that like is
different than what you do and you're
like not what I do but that's actually
kind of interesting how you do it well
you know I mean I've been I've been in
prop for a really long time as a career
and so I I had krietor cut some you know
commercial education in it and then I
functionally did it for a long time so
it let me experiment with a lot of ways
and what I know is that I've met a river
of people who have little subtleties on
how they go about it I know people who
do this really they do a nice job where
they use one gallon ziplock bags as many
greenhouses and they lay a a rolled-up
paper towel in the bottom of it as the
routing matrix and they set the imbibe
seed in a line all the way across and
they hang it up where it gets in direct
light and the seedling grows straight up
and basically they when they when they
cut open the back
they just with a pair of scissor chop
the paper towel and they have a little
paper towel ball of roots and a stem and
coital leading into and true leaves and
I mean sometimes I laugh because the
seedlings have so damn good like that
it's funny but they've got a more pin to
a wall in a room and and each bag is
labeled but their success on that stuff
was just unreal and it's really about
what works for you and your personal
life mean and like for me because I did
commercial work and I had commercial
facilities then I'd be able to utilize
racks watering system and and assistance
but for a lot of people if you just
crack in the seat it has to be simple
for you so that it doesn't get away from
you because once you once you heat them
up you kill them once you dry them out
you kill them if you keep them too moist
and not enough light you'll you'll get
some kind of damping off if you're using
too much light they'll they'll scavenge
themselves too quickly because they
haven't formed a root system so like all
these little things of how you screw up
is really what you have to kind of you
know take a look at yourself and figure
out how do you get around and I mean
I've seen people you
heating pads that you would use on your
elbows to crack seeds where you go and
go in the seed room and there's a you
know a heating pad with a little
three-way piece on it and if it's
wintertime they hit high and if it's
summertime they'd hit low and they've
done unbelievable seed germination you
know so I don't think there's any one
method of doing it baskets just that the
one that I use is always work for me
well because it gives me a tray of
seedlings in a material that I can
utilize and the things that I go work
with next right so with with clones like
I've never been a fan of humidity domes
do you use humidity domes or are you I
feel like they make kind of wimpy plants
I do I well they they serve a purpose I
mean ideally like the best way I think
you can do propagation aside say let's
just we'll take micro prop out of this
race will take laboratory prop off
because that's out of the range of most
people to me the best system is is spray
tables and greenhouses because spray
tables allow you to be able to spray you
know in and you get if you can put a
fertigation solution in so that you get
in mild nutrients spraying on the plants
keeping your moisture levels high the
whole time it's using some type of
sensor to indicate how much moisture you
want present and if the climate changes
it changes how that frequency occurs so
that you're never going to over wet or
under way and you can utilize any type
of tray material you really want once
you once you dial in the amount of water
load so I like that system best for just
pure simplicity where you cut the tray
and stick it on a table and walk away
from it but humidity domes were always
for operations where you don't have the
ability to treat that water and so in
some systems you know you'll you'll miss
the whole room you'll increase the
moisture in a room but for me here in
Humboldt County the problem with
moisturize in a room is that when we get
the wet season in the in the half of the
year you can create mold factories that
are present in the rooms and so you have
to be able to control the environment so
in the summertime sprays are a lot
easier because you're gonna suck that
moisture up and into
into the air and then you can pull it
out but in the wintertime any kind of
excess water in the spaces that we did
drop with just didn't work and so I use
froth trays and domes for indoor
operations because it allows you to be
able to control the environment a lot
more simply and if they're not difficult
to utilize if you just go through the
hardening process but you're using them
to keep the moisture level constant so
you can strike a roof once you strike
the route then you can start to harden
them off and then you pull the lids in
that BAM now you're in it but they work
really well for controlled environments
where you don't have the ability to put
that much water down as a spray the
spray tables to me the best and then and
then micropropagation where you know
you're propagating at a density and a
rate of success that's just you have to
see it to believe it and the plants
coming off of that are the the
ever-lovin opposite of wimpy something
coming off a season you know what I mean
like that is a Herculean little plant
because they're completely hormonal II
charged and they have no obstructions on
them from any kind of pathogen