[Music]
we're going to cover some topics we're
going to cover history of genetics we're
going to talk about organic biology and
and how it how it impacts cannabis we're
going to talk about appellations
and we can weave all this together into
a into a big web but any point in time
man just make sure you stop somebody and
get access to a mic if you want us to
stop and cover topic or go into
something or anything like that because
that's the whole point of it is that
it's it's really
trying to share the information that
we've gathered over these years so that
as a group as a as a cultivation
culture we can actually do better
together so with that in mind i will
introduce mowgli
and jeff
and justin and i'm going to let them
just give a quick little little blast on
themselves because otherwise i won't
cover them correctly so mowgli
yeah
i'm the ceo of philos we're a cannabis
genomics company based out of portland
oregon we're working on
sequencing the dna of all the cannabis
in the world and figuring out what the
hell we're actually smoking at any given
time which is still to this day of
mystery to a lot of us
we have testing tools that are just
meant to help growers and we're working
on
helping people do really advanced plant
breeding
to bring this plant into the future make
it work better for growers
make it less susceptible to powdery
mildew and flower earlier and all those
things that every other crop has been
through all this science and they've
been incredibly advanced by it and
cannabis hasn't had access to that
and our whole our whole work really
you're going to hear about a lot of
things that intersect with this on this
panel
is to bring all that science
without fucking everything up in the way
that that science typically fucks
everything up you know so there's all
this diversity there's all this subtlety
there's all this stuff that's not
science there's all this stuff that has
to do with flavor and feeling and
history and culture
and it's like so how do we you know and
then there's a world of people out there
in canada mainly who just want the
biggest plant that yields the most oil
that they get the most single
cannabinoids out of
but that's you know and that will happen
right so how do we do all the science
that can drive that and and turn it in a
different direction so we're actually
bringing out the full richness of the
plant
that so that's our challenge
uh i'm kevin jodry founder of wonderland
nursery um i usually say career hustler
because that seems how i got here
but uh basically a lifetime of being
involved in cannabis i was a young guy
on the east coast i was involved in what
we called in criminal cannabis and i got
to see an unbelievable amount of
cannabis as a young guy coming into the
country through my neighborhood
and it it absolutely uh changed my life
in terms of i was just fascinated and
over the course of the last you know 40
years
that's been really the chase is to is to
better understand cannabis and
over the last couple years i say the
last 11 it was involved in legitimate
industry
regulated industry
and to trying to figure out how do you
maintain those cultural connections and
how do you keep the quality present and
at the same time how do you really share
the information with other people so
that you leave a legacy of people who
follow you and so
my direction has been that and it's been
a very interesting ride to say the least
my name is jeff lowenfels and in 1975 i
was in alaska and the supreme court
decided that you could do anything you
wanted in the privacy of your home
including smoking cannabis and so as an
assistant attorney general i helped
write the opinion
as to where you have a right to privacy
uh so that you could smoke cannabis in
your tent
or in your hotel room
uh we couldn't quite get a phone booth
that wasn't didn't work the
cars didn't work anyway but uh so so
i've been fooling around with cannabis
since 1975 and before
um and uh
somewhere along the line i started to
write a book on
uh organics
and resulted in teaming with microbes
and then one day i decided i needed to
figure out how plants eat and that
resulted in teeming with nutrients and
then one day i decided that not enough
people knew about mycorrhizal fungi and
how how it was so effective in growing
things and so i wrote a third book so i
have three books um whereas i used to
have two and i was america's dirtiest
lawyer i now have three books which
makes me
lord of the roots sorry um
and i'm very interested in organics i'm
very interested in making sure
that when the big guys come in the
little guys don't get pushed out
and i am very very interested in making
sure that we never again
let the government prohibit cannabis so
[Applause]
my name is justin calvino
i every time i i'm with kevin i realize
like
in 94 i started selling cannabis on a
fair street
in providence i grew up like three
blocks off at third street in rhode
island so we're like rhode island
cannabis
i probably sold i sold it to brown
campus so it was like brown and risd and
i worked at a skate shop and i moved out
to california in 96
where you know i was you know buying
cannabis from arcata from up on the
square or boulder creek in santa cruz
and selling it on haight ashbury and um
you know i spent two years as a homeless
teenager on the hate and uh kind of
trying to go pro at this thing and um
and i you know so
have some history in it uh
i you know moved up to mendocino county
i
um
you know did what everyone else did we
hid behind our locked gates we were
trying to raise a family small farms
work on you know
local systems of governance you know
sharing community fire departments you
you name it and um got arrested and
ended up in cannabis policy and ended up
saying you know enough is enough
let's you know sherry glazer said get
out of the cannabis closet
so
came out and drew a map
and i drew an appellations map i took my
design talents and uh you know in my
knowing of regional you know specific
strains and heritage and i was you know
put it down on paper started i was going
up to wonderland nursery and asking kev
what do you think about this what do you
think about that and uh
all the breeders and you know all the
regions and you know we we put together
quite a project and
since then i've done things like the
emerald exchange trying to get small
batch cannabis farmers
access to market so started bringing
farmers out of the hills setting up
tables for them getting them in mason
jars you know helping them brand and
market themselves
fully illegally um you know so
everybody's like what are we what are we
doing this for and i'm like because this
is this shit's coming and um you know so
we've been working hard for the small
guys um you know for quite a few years
now and uh i'm really i'm just you know
it's an honor to you know stay here with
kev and um
mowgli i'm really interested to learn
more about what it is that you're doing
and how you can help solidify some of
the some of the metabolomic research and
data collection that we're doing to
internationally recognize appellations
of origin um and jeff you know i'm a i'm
a lover of roots man 10 years in
regenerative design theory and
permaculture practice and so you know
that's that that's that's my geek so
this is going to be fun
right on i think we're going to get into
uh we go right into the history of
genetics where where we began and so
that way we could start the process
because it really ties into all the
stuff we're doing where the varietals
that came into the united states
initially what people call land race i
don't use that verbiage because land
race to me is open pollination and not
selected and so when you start to select
cultivars that you're going to work with
you also choose males from those open
populations that you're going to use to
pollinate with and as soon as you put
your hand in the in the pile that's a
cultivated variety me it's no longer
land race land race is basically plants
that have developed for survival that's
all that's all they're for they don't
they don't care about yield they're not
worrying about quality of smoke it's a
genomic form that wants to live
and once humans started from these from
these genetic piles they pulled things
out that they liked they started to pull
things they liked for whatever reason
they chose and when you take a look at
the world in terms of latitude you can
see stuff that was equatorial was chosen
primarily for cerebral nature we can
make generalizations but the more we go
up in latitude the more we start to see
cbd genetics come out as you start to
look through these this material on lab
analysis you can start to see these
connections where the individuals that
lived in you know latitudes 20 to 40 had
a much harder life than those from zero
to 20 in terms of uh climactic
situations abundance of food and just in
general living conditions
and so so much of the cannabis that
comes into the u.s from when i was a kid
was coming in off of ships
on the east coast primarily and so it
was coming over from mexico into
california we used to call that stuff
scentsy that would have been like late
70s but so much of the weed coming into
new england was coming in through
fishing boats and so just like in
humboldt county when when cannabis uh
took off in humboldt it wasn't the
hippies that really blew it up it was
the loggers because the logging industry
disappears all of a sudden you have this
massive industrial workforce that has no
job and they say you know what we're
going to get into growing weed the
hippies are making money we might as
well make money too and so the next
thing you know humble county is punching
out as much canvas as one could grow but
it was not the hippies that were
punching it out it was the industrial
loggers new england was the same thing
the fishing industry collapses
collapse my whole neighborhood's a
fishing fishing area
and all of a sudden the uh the fishermen
are grabbing all the weed from the
offshore boat so the boats are coming in
out to sea the fish and boats would go
in grab the weed bring it into the
neighborhood my family wasn't into
cannabis but my my family was into
organized crime and because they were
into organized crime
uh they were they were kind of
terrifying people it allowed me to
access the cannabis industry in a
different way where i could kind of do
what i wanted and hang out with who i
chose because my family had such a
reputation
and so
it allowed me to get involved with some
stuff as a young guy that wasn't normal
so i got to see this incredible
diversity cannabis and it would come
through
seasonally we would see we would see
varietals coming in and the people that
were bringing in in bulk would tell you
hey we got colombian coming in and then
we knew tai would come in basically when
school started so the end of august 1st
of september you'd see tai coming in
you'd see afghani come in through the
season you'd see cannabis move globally
into the east coast you would see hash
move into the east coast but it was
always on a really consistent basis
but what we noticed was
that it wasn't homogenized that all of
these varietals were very distinct
and that's i think where we we went
wrong with what we did in genetics where
illegalities forced us to make changes
in terms of how we perceive cannabis and
because there was a shortage of cannabis
in general meaning that the the open
population couldn't access it freely
whatever you could buy you would buy
and what occurred was i i call it a
dumbing down of the population and we
started to really truncate what was
shortened what was available
and what we used
and and how we went about it and
that's where like right now it's
fascinating to have you know mowgli on
stage because what he's doing he's going
back in and taking a look at these
varieties on on a genetic level saying
hey in the genome itself what do we see
where do these things come from what
traits do they have how do we start to
pull the directions apart and start to
take this homogenized mix and start to
re-separate it out
because fundamentally all the cannabis
that came in from these overseas
situations was justin's working on
appalachians but appalachians are just
designations of production zones but all
cannabis came from designated production
zones that's what made it unique and
like jeff is is uh because i've read his
books and and i enjoy the shit of him um
but it it it's about how cannabis was
produced then organically and so the
relationship between cannabis in terms
of genomic
how it was produced where it was
produced
all contributes to what we have today
and i think so much of this this
direction that we're trying to go is to
figure out how do we go back into this
pile
separate the pile and figure out how do
we put
what belongs where where
and how do you drive the greatest input
out of it
and i think that when you get into
organic methodologies versus chemical
methodologies a lot of it is a
function of for one i don't want to call
it ethics but desire
and
also simplicity because chemical systems
are the favored because it allows you to
do a lot of automation
but and so i don't try to knock salt
guys
but it's not what creates these hyper
complex varietals the relationship
between what's in the soil the
microbiology
and the indigenous microbes from the
regions combined with the unique soil
profiles
all create that
and i think that for us so many of us as
we start to go forward as smaller
operators craft operators niche
operators appellation operators organic
operators genomic hunters
you're that's the direction we start to
go because otherwise what it is is it's
homogenized cannabis and as moog said
you're talking about uh operations in
canada that are doing heavily funded
huge operations for extraction put
anything together and the problem with
that is that none of us can compete with
that on economic level so it
fundamentally wipes us out as operators
and the direction is to is to is to
differentiate yourself from that package
but it's a process and it's it's a it's
a difficult process because it revolves
many of us to work together in a
collaborative fashion i think the
cannabis
didn't require that same collaboration
we were all in a collusion we would all
work together to make the money we would
all work together to keep our mouth shut
we were pretty good about it but we
didn't have to work together in the same
combined level because we made enough
money none of us really were broke if
you were in the weed game if you were
you weren't growing very well
and and that's true
you shouldn't have been broke
it doesn't mean that you were a king or
a queen it just meant that you had
adequate income and for the first time
the the money is what's drive in this
unity and as you start to have the unity
come together it starts to become
cultural spiritual where you start to
realize hey wait a second what we liked
was that that relationship that worked
and i think that that's what's taking
place now is as we start getting into
this this situation of
what it is that we're creating why are
we creating it and how do we utilize
this the skill sets and the tools
and
so we you know we go back into this time
period where all this beautiful canvas
came into the united states in the 70s
we would say well you know back to land
movement 68 but back to land movement
and humboldt was in 68 but there was
also these other
situations where they call it chautauqua
you know this this resurgence relove for
the land
spiritual awakening renaissance but you
see it all over the the new england area
you saw it in tennessee kentucky
you have it in pockets of the midwest
colorado idaho you have it on the whole
pacific northwest so it wasn't just
isolated to one region it was all over
the place and all of these places
received this incredible genomic
packages they got material from these
countries that was pretty true breeding
in the sense that you could basically
see what was going to come out of it you
would have mixed packages in terms of
resistance because that's really what
broad spectrum cannabis is
but you would have somewhat of a
consistency and people started to take
those varietals
and then they would start to mix them
with other things to work for their
situation so you started to see some of
the first really good crosses coming out
of that time and to me
that late 70s early 80s is really the
zenith of american cannabis where you
had people who were able to work it
fully heavily and they were using
organic biology and they were using
sun-grown methodologies and so what it
did is it allowed you to use basically
the material that was from these other
countries in the same form that it was
grown there so you weren't having to
make a radical change in how we fed or
how we selected it
and then you get into 83 which was
really the beginning of the drug war in
full form and i always tell people i
remember 83 because i got dragged out of
high school in handcuffs for cultivation
and
that
that was a turning point for most
individuals because at that time all of
a sudden the enforcement became heavy
cannabis was driven indoor and that's
when you started to see these changes in
what was required and what was needed
and you also started to see changes in
what individuals wanted to consume
because prior to that time period we
would call it cannabis more ethereal
meaning more more uplifting more
spiritual what individuals want to call
sativa even though it's all sativa but
um mental ethereal
uplifting strains
the the world started to change you
started to see a desire for different
cannabis and as the advent of indoor
cannabis came along you needed to have
things that flowered on a quicker time
frame you needed stuff that was stockier
people started choosing things that
worked in those capacities and you
started to see a lot of these old
varieties get trimmed away so the first
real culling of the population was in
that early 80s where a lot of the old
beautiful land race or derived from land
race
taken through cultivated variety brought
over to here held in form
pollinated worked outside
they all got called out because that
stuff didn't work on the indoor
methodology so all of a sudden boom we
get into indoor methodologies that's
when you started seeing uh the the
shorter broader leaves stockier more
narcotic cannabis become more in vogue
and it's just basically run that that
that direction ever since
and i think that you know what what i'm
involved with right now is trying to go
backwards in time and find things from
those golden eras of cannabis when the
varieties had
a more diverse effect and you had a much
different amount of things to play with
and
i think that for so many individuals
right now
they're so used to homogenized cannabis
where if you take a look at it
genomically you see that there's these
clusters but so much of the cannabis on
the shelf today is really related so
basically it's you know you have 40
cousins you're messing with so you might
as well be in kentucky
and and there's a problem with that is
that it really really doesn't allow
individuals to have the full range of
experience and what it does it doesn't
allow you as cultivators to have a
diversity in your own libraries and it
doesn't allow you to have
differentiation so when everybody's
growing the same og it doesn't make a
difference it's all og so you might have
the best og but it's still og where's
the differentiation
and
that on that point of it is
you know how do we utilize these tools
that we have forward where how do we
take knowledge on organic methodologies
which allow plants to express themselves
in a more balanced form how do you
utilize
the locations of appellations which
means specific production regions and
optimize that and then you know how do
you get into genomic mapping and where
where is the future of that and so i'll
throw it to mold for a second and say
hey um what was the what was the reason
why you started mapping cannabis and
what was it that you saw initially and
then where are we going within that
direction
thanks kev welcome
i mean so when we started mapping it
we were trying to tell this
this historical story that you
in a way just told
off the top of your head because you
knew it but we're trying to go back a
lot further too
so we wanted to know where all the
varieties came from i mean the story
begins
like it you know it doesn't begin when
stuff shows up here right like it begins
in like 10 000 years ago in central asia
and then the plant
followed humans everywhere around the
globe it literally went everywhere
and
and we're starting
we hope we're starting to be able to
piece together the story of how it
migrated you know we think it came over
to south america with the conquistadors
and you know somehow it came up to the
united states and there were all these
introductions from china and there's
this whole long history of it
but throughout that time
these
these individual varieties were
preserved and at that like we call those
land races because they
so i mean the way that
plant evolution happens once humans
starts to starts to mess with it right
it's like humans get their hands on it
and then they they're not breeding but
they do this they do seed saving right
so for millennia humans are saving seeds
and they're growing this diverse
population in this defined geographical
region and they're saving the seeds they
like
and and that exerts a little bit it's
not
it's not real breeding but it exerts
some selection pressure on it
and you end up with these
what they call land races that
you know in a certain valley
in
somewhere in afghanistan or thailand
for maybe millennia people have been
saving seeds and the plan has evolved
along with the humans
and it's
it's a bit different from the wild
variety
but it's also not a cultivated variety
and we don't know if people started
making crosses before that stuff started
getting imported
to the united states we just don't know
like it may be that in the 50s
um
in thailand they were making crosses and
it was really a cultivative right it was
just a land race and it was still
growing
semi-wild and they were just saving
seeds we just have no idea
can we find out
yeah we
we could find out if we got enough
samples from a region
um
we can do a thing called molecular clock
analysis and figure out how fast it was
evolving and see if there's a signature
of human selection pressure on it we
don't have enough samples from each area
yet to do that but we could we could
find out
but then the thing is like all that
stuff comes here just like you're saying
it comes here
and bam it's just all mixed together
and so
all those genes are still in the gene
pool
they're all out there they're all
circulating
and when we look genetically at the map
all the cannabis out there
it still seems incredibly diverse i mean
there's thousands and thousands and
thousands of kinds
but
there's a sameness to it because
like
like imagine you put like
a bunch of different things in a pot
right and they're all different and you
just stir it and stir it like all that
stuff is in there
but there is a kind of homogeneity to it
the great thing about genetics is that
um
some genes
when you mix them together
they blend right so like if a tall
person and a short person have a kid
that kid is often of intermediate height
those genes are there's a lot of genes
that go into height
and
together you end up with something in
the middle but then there are lots of
genes like blue eyes and brown eyes they
don't blend
they're just discreet characters so they
they stay they keep their force and you
can stir the pot as long as you want but
in every generation that gene is just
like boom
but it's randomly distributed now
and so in canvas we see the same thing
like there are certain features that i
think get blended
um but there are other features that uh
they just pop out like they're still
there so that
the stuff you know before the
introduction of all the afghani stuff
and correct me if i'm wrong but like the
reason why everything became so sedating
uh like that was not a consumer
consumer-driven trend right i mean those
plants we had people just had to grow
those plants and so suddenly consumers
are like oh i like this but that's what
there was kinda kinda because it was it
was so
powerful at the time it was such a
radically different experience to smoke
these nasty at the time the first
afghanis i remember messing with where
they called missouri's and they were the
dark golf balls with the red hair they
just make you sweat
and you weren't really used to like
something that shook the shit out of you
when you smoked it like you get lifted
and forget what your name was from from
ethereal cannabis and you'd be like wow
the colors of the sky are incredible but
when you were smoking really devastating
afghani man you wanted to go home and
lay down and go hide in the bed and
you'd wake up and your mom be wiping
your forehead with a rag saying are you
sick and you'd be like no i'm just
really fucking like yes
but you know it but it evolved into
where people wanted narcotics where i
got we we were talking one time about
maybe uh 11 12 years ago we talked about
trends
and someone said uh oh geez a fad and i
said no it's not and because i i look at
i look at trends and fads with cannabis
and that's and i said no it's not and i
but i didn't understand why so i did a
random sample of a thousand people
because i had a dispensary that um i was
able to use as my my test period so i
could ask questions and i started
logging the answers and the answers on a
lot of the heavy mercine-based uh
carafeline-based stuff was
heavy sedative because the tremendous
number of people had opiate issues
and so what we started to see over time
was opiate driven
replacement where if you were on opiates
you could utilize things that were
based in specific terpene categories as
a replacement but other varieties
wouldn't work as well so i think at
first when the when those afghanis came
out they worked well for indoor and they
worked well for a shorter cycle but i
think also it was such a radical change
in the type of high that you received
that i think that really turned people
on where they were like wow this is some
really really powerful stuff
yeah
yeah so it's a combination of all those
drivers but those other traits right
those traits that um
that
that originated with the plants that
people tend to call sativa even though
i'm not going to call it that
um
like those are in there right they're
still circulating in the population
some aspect as far as we can tell some
aspects of those traits are blended
right they've hit some kind of like
you know they're just being averaged out
with the afghani stuff which is too bad
but some of them
they just pop out sometimes right
there are varieties that just have those
aspects but they
i think they don't have all of them
right so so there's all these different
genes that need to be recombined to
recreate those varieties and we can do
that now we can go back we can turn the
clock backwards
if we're really paying attention to what
genes we want to put together it's just
really hard complicated work
and so right now we have this soup
but
small farmers in california and oregon
have to differentiate themselves
and
the way they're going to do it is
they're going to take that
they're going to start to take that soup
apart
and they're really going to start to
re-differentiate the plant they're going
to start using real breeding to really
drive towards very specific things you
know right now breeders drive towards a
flavor
you know that that's that's a
overarching goal you know and they'll
get certain effects and
but they're still just stirring the pot
once people start to identify real goals
and they can really differentiate
cannabis into
back towards
specific kinds that we originally had or
towards towards kinds that are new new
combinations where you're really
combining a whole handful of traits to
make a plant that is outrageous in some
way and that if you mixed it into the
whole pool like it would all go away
that's the differentiation that's going
to make local growers in different
appalachians start to stand out and
people in different regions
they're going to focus on different
things like that and we can get there
where it's like wow in southern mendo
you know they're making plants that are
you know that remind us of what panama
red used to be like
and but it's going to take a lot of work
it's not this the way we've been
breeding now
it's not going to get us there
i don't think
no i don't think so either i think
i think too that like with what justin's
doing with the appalachian and i'm gonna
let justin and jeff kind of chew this
one up a little bit because really
the impact on the overall is based off
of the plant and its inputs and so much
is the direction of where it's located
and then what what's what's feeding it
what's driving it
and you're seeing this huge uh i say a
renaissance in organics i think cannabis
drove the renaissance and organics i
think that
for most individuals
they started to become very aware that
they were feeding their plants better
than they were feeding themselves
and because they had the disposal income
they could actually start to
create a market at stores where they
would say hey i want to go buy these
products and stores started to cater to
them and if you go to places like where
i'm from and humble there's a lot of
organic shops
and so you know and it's
disproportionate for the population how
much organic selection that you have
but i think so much of it wasn't that
the people were so aware it was they
became aware from the fact that they
were taking better care of their plants
it started to make them realize that the
products that they were purchasing were
of lower quality from supermarkets and
all of a sudden there was a demand to
feed this opportunity
and
you're starting to see this uh
incredible desire to hunt out microbes
um the the in
indigenous microorganisms where people
are starting to do their own mining and
i got involved in that maybe i say i'd
say 10 12 years ago where i saw these
filipino guys that had been culturing
stuff for like 100 years like sourdough
and they were passing it on and so i
started to mine my own microbes
and then tried to do the same thing but
it was i didn't have the skills to hold
it in that form i i'm i was learning and
then with fermentations and and how that
applies
to your appellations because these
appellations have a unique
input the terroir like french have you
seen french cannoli frenchies he almost
spits the word out
and
but the point is that i'm gonna let if a
possible let jeff and justin kind of get
into what is an appellation
and and from his definition of it
because it applies to us in cannabis and
it's been used in so many different
words and then and hopefully then then
uh jeff can kick in about you know what
what these inputs are and how they
affect because overall all of that
applies ultimately to the end quality of
the product
and for me more than just the end
quality the product also the
sustainability of the whole model
because to me i think that like i said i
try not to go off on salt driven systems
but
it's to me it's not sustainable because
you're you're you're creating too much
waste you're creating waste in the
creation of it and you're and you're
doing damage on the usage of it
and so
i'll turn it over
that's a lot
i wish i had a pen and paper because i
had
something on all of it um
one thing is for a shout out to frenchie
is uh
all of this is about proving tawa right
so it's like we have
a 20 50 100 year project ahead of us
this what we're talking about is
hypothetical and theoretical and and
everything that we're doing is
community-driven research
you know all of us together putting our
putting our knowledge in the pot and
coming up with what the best system is i
think that uh
prohibition didn't do us a service
um with plant cows i think that's
something we're getting into right now
with the appalachians you know project
is you know we're talking to a lot of
cultivators up in like palo verde and
places like that
and we're talking about you know
you know standard set to indigenize
inoculants engineer all soil on site and
you know and then we're getting farmers
saying well you know what about our
yields you know we can't go in ground
you know there's no way we're gonna
smart pots raised beds engineered soils
you know this is part of our new culture
and really that's part of a prohibition
culture that was when we had to maximize
the amount of of yield we were getting
off of a per plant basis because the
federal government was saying you know
99 plus plants
you know above 99 or 100 and above is a
federal crime so it was like so everyone
was like oh yeah 99 and below we'll you
know we'll we'll
you know state kind of frowns upon us
but uh so you know so if you realize how
do we get the biggest
freaking plant and how do we do that we
we put 800 gallons of soil we engineer
it all we pump it full of juice gas
whatever we're you know and then we get
a you know
a five a ten a fifteen someone in
southern oregon had a 22 pound plant you
know uh
do i what variety i think was a cookie
but it was on that it was on a magazine
it was in a big magazine it was like the
22 pounder and i was like i was like
that's got to be crap
but you know and so we were having this
conversation the other day on a on a sub
actually i think it was this morning on
a subcommittee call for appellations and
um we were talking about you know in the
fields of afghanistan where you know in
some of these cannabis heritage regions
where you see these you know um you know
valleys full of dry farmed in
afghanistan farmed waist-high cannabis
right that is it looks the opposite
there's always like afghani kisses the
opposite of these you know 10 12-pound
monsters you see in the magazines now
with all of us growers sitting there
with our like you know shirts saying yo
we did this and it's like but what are
you really doing right you know what are
you doing to the plant what are you
doing the genotype what are you doing
you know what is that phenotype you're
we're hunting something that's going to
get bigger higher yield but our quality
markers aren't set properly so we talk
about money now as it's getting on the
money thing we're all like unifying
around money and the fact of the matter
is is it's like now
we're going to be getting into this
place where genetics are going to be
bred where you're going to have this
like homogenized crop going out into the
open to grow 500 acres of cannabis and
it's our responsibility now to say how
is that cannabis grown where was it
grown in soil what was the marine layer
condition was the altitude what was it
you know what what did we do to not only
indigenize the inoculants but to
actually co-evolve that cultivar to the
soil and to the to the climactic
conditions over decades and how is it
going to express itself fully in that
region so we're looking at you know now
profile testing terpenes you know
terpene profiles like what's gonna
what's now everybody's talking about
like you know what's a terp count
you know so it's like the cannabinoids
are you know every day there's another
cannabinoid you know a compound that's
coming out in in reaction to another
terpene and now everyone's seeking that
medicine right well that medicine is
actually regionally specific
right the different heritage strains you
know we call heritage let's say 50 years
selected to breed that quality that
trichome development so it's like
appalachian's development right now is
going to be talking about quality
medicine development you know and we're
going to be seeking strains and we're
going to be seeking cultivars from these
regions because they were able to
express themselves fully in that region
and have full profile developments and
that's done i do believe in the mineral
content of the soil
with that with that marine layer
condition with with that altitude
and we see it i mean it's you know in
spy rock um i watched some of the the
world's best sour diesel being grown i
would never for the love of me grow that
sour diesel in navarro
like it it's like shitty and it's i
watch my friends and neighbors do it
every year and throw away half their
crop because it's market driven they
want something that's like high potency
they want something so we need to like
you know we need to start having this
qual you know this conversation about
quality and these quality markers and i
think that what you're doing mowgli is
really important because that you know
that cellular capture that data capture
you know to tell us like okay that's a
marker that's what that plan expressed
itself in that way that's the genotype
that we're seeking for that region and
then we need to
we need to match that with the region
and use that as i p protections and go
ahead and claim it so that's that's
that's kind of where we're going in the
appellation space with that but i think
the conversation needs to be about
unifying around markers of quality like
you know indoor
mixed light
appellation you know terpene
cannabinoid like what are what are you
know what are we looking for to come out
of the strain so that the consumer
market can start to differentiate
you know the the actual product that
we're consuming
well a couple of things first
it seems to me that we we need to
recognize what
why we're here and why we're really
talking about this stuff and i think if
i say coca-cola pepsi cola scott's
miracle grow
you know you get the idea what's going
to happen is this canadian situation
you're going to have a big company a
pepsi cola coca-cola they're going to
want one kind of cannabis because that's
what they want in their standardized
drink maybe they'll have three different
drinks but they won't have very many
more than that and and
you know if we're not careful
then we're going to be forced to grow
for them
what we want to do is grow for
individuals we want to stay in business
without having to merge with a gigantic
company we don't necessarily want to
merge with each other we want to
continue to do our thing individually
and and share our information and make
sure that we're not cut out of this
business by the industry that is clearly
forming no question about it
number two
we want to make sure that we don't
continue to allow the government to fuck
us over
as we do this and i mean this in a
couple of different ways
why
we allow
in alaska
you know they they say you don't have to
test your stuff for pesticides that's
bullshit of course you should
we're selling a product that people are
ingesting
you know whether you're organic or not
people need to know what's on their
product you know and so we got to make
sure that the government does what we
want them to do not what these new
regulators want to do so that they can
keep their jobs and those two things i
think are the backdrop
that you've got to keep in mind when you
ask the question which i think we're all
trying to ask
which is i put it in this way
can you grow
durbin poison in anchorage alaska
i want to grow durbin poison in
anchorage alaska can i really do it and
to me based upon the books that i've
written
and the stuff that i've you know read
from your company and others there are
three stool three legs to the stool
the first is genetics and if you don't
have the durban poison genetics you're
not going to have durbin poison so we
have to figure out what the durbin
poison genetics really are the second
are is the soil you know that's that's
in theory my expertise there is no
question that the soil has a direct
impact on all of the things that go on
inside the plant for the various reasons
that are in all three of my books but
not the least of which is that you've
got bacteria and fungi that are
responsible for feeding the plant now
they in turn are impacted by
microarthropods nematodes and protozoa
but all of those things together are
what help make up your appellation um
and and if you if you've got the durbin
poison genes then what you want to try
to do is make sure that you've got soil
that mimics the durbin
soil so you need to figure out and i'm
sure we're going to end up in a
situation where in addition to doing you
know the the genotypes and figuring out
i mean you know figuring out what what
what the dna is we're going to have
books that are going to be able to say
and this is what the soil is like this
is what the microbiology is like this is
what the this is what the uh you know
the the biomass of the soil is like in
that area if you talk to dr elaine
ingham she will tell you you need
slightly more fungal than bacterial she
will tell you you know that you need
certain kinds of protozoa over other
protozoa and all of this stuff is
important and we're not getting it
you should be getting it and i think
you're beginning to pick up a little bit
of it but we need to make sure that
we're all sharing this information and
figuring out what it really is we don't
know yet and then the third leg from my
perspective
is light sunlight and and uh
sin are you here yeah okay uh if we can
just for two seconds maybe while sin
sets this up
so you if you don't have the sunlight
from south africa
you can't really grow the durban poison
now we concentrate on soil because
that's what the grape growers do you
know but in cannabis
it's the light
that as much as anything that causes the
soil microbes act the way they act and
of course the plant to act the way it
acts so so we've got a situation where
we used to grow outdoors and we had
sunlight and then the prohibition came
and they pushed us indoors and so we've
got a lot of people are still going
indoors and the industry
seems to be
coming to the conclusion you know that
that if they grow indoors using sunlight
as well that they're gonna you know
they're gonna be
benefit i don't know where the little
grower fits in in that scenario but
we've got to learn
the differences between the lights that
scott's miracle grower wants you to buy
you know because they bought the company
and okay they're going to push it
they're going to advertise it they don't
give a shit if it doesn't do
a couple of the things that you really
needed to do because they bought the
company and they need to be making money
or we can we can develop our own product
projects which is what this fellow over
here has done now you may never have
heard of a plasma light but what sin is
about to show you
is the sun
in a little teeny light that he can pick
up with one hand
and he can change the gas that's inside
this lamp
and he can change that gas in many
different ways to create
the sun that you want so we went to nasa
to talk to them about the potential of
growing food using this light so if you
want to grow south african cannabis in
anchorage alaska you set the light to
the wavelengths which are all available
by the way
so that you can duplicate the same kind
of light that's in south africa that's
pretty amazing
now none of this stuff makes any sense
unless you know what the genetics are
and and so it always starts with the
genetics which is why you know the
phylos bioscience project is really so
key but i think you would agree that the
genetics are influenced
by
sunlight yeah mental conditions matter
but epigenetics matter like just as much
and maybe even more do they do i mean i
know they matter but do they matter as
much or more
where basically the expression is latent
in all of these watered-down strains
that we have and that we see but when
you give them the right environmental
conditions for them to express the best
version of those cells you see a
different version of that genetic
the period and the story whether it's
you know
the same
check check the same moms
right the same cuts from the same moms
you take them nationwide right
the the uh
expression of those is going to be based
on their environment not just the
energetics or the genetics that's right
but the question is
the question is the same and i agree
with you i think you're absolutely
correct but but if you are able to
control with better precision
the other the other
actions
then you then you have less of an
influence by the epigenetic stuff which
is not necessarily bad by the way but
jeff
i agree i understand yeah so let me ask
you a question
say you go down to
to humble you get a lot of soil from one
of the valleys there
and you bring it up to alaska right
and you and you plant
you plant an og
in it
and then you turn on the plasma light
and you dial it in so that it has the
same light at the latitude and longitude
where you took that soil
should that plant then be eligible for
the humbled appellation
that's that's the question i was going
to ask because i think it's a very good
question
no well i mean i said
no
no and and i and i think that's an
interesting question because it because
it's it's it's millions of years of
co-evolution of that soil's relationship
to the entire environment not just the
sun but you haven't but you haven't been
growing the cannabis for millions of
years here's the deal it's not about the
cannabis it's about protecting the earth
right we're also this ip protects the
earth in which we stand right this isn't
just about we are using cannabis
genetics to find out this metabolomic
capture but once we capture and and use
a sensational nature that we have this
stage that we have right now we can
protect genetics worldwide but not just
the genetics the humans that live in
co-crea and co-evolution with those
genetics indigenous tribes all over the
world need these protections as well do
their cultivars and so if we start
manipulating that and start shifting
that and then it's not just shifting the
genetics it's shifting the policies that
those genetics protect and we start
shifting the politics policies that
protect the people i mean capitalism won
i would i would agree that
way before you answered let me just
answer your question in a slightly
different way
if you take alaskan soil because that's
as i've done if you take alaskan soil
down to a hawaii
you can grow a giant cabbage
the giant cabbages that we grow in
alaska is soil based i live in anchorage
you can't grow those giant cabbages in
anchorage
wasilla
where they grow them palmer
is 40 minutes away
the difference is the soil if you bring
that soil from wasilla into anchorage
you can grow the giant cabbage
but you can't grow the giant cabbage
without that soil so in a way
it's the same genetics the same
conditions it's not the same expression
that's why we need that capture
that's why we need that capture i was
involved in led development probably a
decade ago with a company where helio
spectre came in and said we want to do
led development and at that time none of
the europeans could touch cannabis so
they used my facility to do all the r d
and then they would ship all these light
scientists in from all over the world to
do the tests and i would run
uh standardized testing where we would
hold one under what we knew so i knew
the cultivar i would put it under the
traditional hbs we would then run the
heliospectres and we couldn't get the
stuff to shine the way we wanted to
until i took them up the hill and we
started to measure the sun coming off of
my farm
and that started to let him get a better
baseline
of what was desired for that situation
but from what you're saying is yeah the
soil microbes from that and and and if
we move it does it does it create an uh
a sameness
but i think that justin's right in terms
of the overall picture is too big to
capture so you can't capture an
appellation by just microbials or just
sunlight because it has to be the entire
environment and even though we don't
have
cannabis appellation so to speak because
none of us have 60 years minimum of of
genetic manipulation where we've got
genomic forms that have been developed
for at least 60-year period which is
typically like a standard in
appalachians we don't have that
but the point is that
we always had that theory of if you
wanted to grow good colombian because i
knew that the hawaiian the same thing
was when i was in hawaii and i was
consuming some of this kill of high
mountain hawaiian which is really
southeast asian varietals
it was so nasty
but when we grew it in humboldt even if
we had the ability to protect it for the
longer season it didn't have the same
flavonoid profiles and the high was
different and so we knew that it was
soil biology that was driving it but we
didn't have the ability to replicate it
we weren't we weren't knowledgeable
enough at the time you lost it yeah no
you're right and and
all of these things make a difference
but the question the question is i live
in anchorage alaska
and i'm going to go down you know right
now i can't go down to california to buy
my
durvan poison from
you
so i got to grow in anchorage alaska now
if we end up with the wrong kind of
regulatory system i.e they're going to
let states make a determination in some
states you'll be able to do it and some
you won't
so that that that presents the sort of
the problem that a wine industry doesn't
have
you know you can ship anywhere but is it
responsible
now that's a whole other question that's
that's that's the question we have to
ask as consumers as you know it's like
is it responsible to put that love that
that that weight on the earth because we
want something
is it are you saying it is and if we
need something is it better for us to go
where that something is already
for appellations in in in norcal you're
going to see the incredibly diminished
amounts of cannabis that can be grown
based off of watershed availability so
they're going to they've already
controlled the water flow pretty good
but over the next couple years they're
going to go out all these watersheds
heavily and start to determine and it's
kind of arbitrary because no one really
knows consumptive how much waters are
actually in the ground to suck up
but they're going to start to change how
much you can actually cultivate in your
watershed so how much cannabis can be
created
which is terrifying for a lot of the
smaller people but they don't understand
that scarcity creates value just like
scarcity creates a value of an antiquity
sand is pretty old but it's not valuable
um you get something that has a scarcity
there's a value and i think that as we
go forward
yeah you can ship it as you go forward
but first even within these limited
markets
for the individuals that are able to
produce certain batch lots that are less
it'll be clearly defined from i mean i'm
looking at operations right now that are
talking about doing 200 000 pounds a
year
so i mean i'm talking i'm talking to
guys that are putting in that opposite
that are looking at you know that's
that's that's that's a credible amount
200 000 pounds off off of a single
operation is frightening
so you you and it doesn't sound like
scarcity no
and and so the thing is that with the
appalachian situations that he's talking
about it's not just geographical zones
but it will be it'll be compressed
because the state is going to compress
it through water usage
and so you're going to see
a lot less produced in general and in
these specific regions once we are able
to use genomics and understand
microbiology to a degree that lets us
tailor what we're really trying to do
i think then you'll have a
differentiation you don't really have it
now i think right now what you have is a
basket of cannabis everybody's just
grabbing it you don't really have this
upper shelf in this lower shelf it's all
kind of this what it is if everybody's
growing the same weed all over the state
and we're all saying we're doing some
unbelievable job with it
how can you really compare that you
can't
it has to be these unique forms
and so you know this this this situation
and look at this i'm sure there's people
here that are doing large operations and
it's not meant to exclude them at all
because those larger operations they'll
use the same information because they're
going to use microbiology to increase
resistance and they're going to use
genetic modeling sifting marking and
selection to be able to improve what
they do and then the appalachian regions
are where they produce these things if
they're within those regions and they
follow suit or they have an investment
in one of these it'll it'll diversify
their portfolio so no matter what size
you are the conversation still really
applies i think it's hilarious that in
humboldt county they're talking about
water rationing
and in in
in siskiyou county they're building
tunnels to ship water to the desert and
they're stealing water so it's like
so if you want to grow a bunch of
cannabis move to the desert i mean that
city like makes absolutely no sense
but humboldt county though your water
guys are going around to farms and to
producer to to large-scale industrial
facilities uh soil guys and getting them
to double their water count so they can
keep the water in humble because there's
people already shopping for your water
to ship it out well we gotta we got a
water mill i mean this this isn't about
cannabis but it kind is is that there's
a there's a lake called ruth lake and it
was it was designed to feed a mill so
this giant mill facility asked me if i
wanted to put a major nursery operation
in but when i toured the whole facility
it was a super fun site
and i just knew i said there's no way
you can get this thing clean enough to
really do any work and it's just not the
right location for agriculture
but the thing that made it attractive
was they have a couple million gallons a
day of water flowing from the dam into
this facility that's just flowing out to
the ocean and if they can't find a user
for the facility they're gonna have to
sell the water to someone else versus
just redivert it back into the river so
fundamentally you know when it comes to
these appellations and it comes to water
usage it's political because when you're
when you're when you're putting in you
know unbelievable operations in the high
desert high desert's defined by less
than 10 inches of rain a year so if
you're going to call it high desert then
that's really what it means so you know
we got we should be we should be popping
around 70 to 80 inches up in humboldt
which is a phenomenal amount of water
but they're going to limit us
tremendously i'm on a very protected
watershed but the watershed emanates
from my property so it gives me a chance
to work and what i'll do is i'll work a
canopy size that lets me get to a level
that's allowable because really you
can't you can't beat them right off the
bat
and that's why it's it's important for a
lot of the smaller operators to say
listen if i only have ten thousand
square foot of best five thousand square
foot then how do you work in conjunction
with other operators in your watersheds
in your directions to find out you know
what kind of kind of biology biology
systems do you utilize
and like what moly was saying which he's
been saying for a while is you guys got
to get together and team up and work on
these projects together so that you have
the resources to be able to actually
function because it's expensive
and with the course of of cannabis
production right now which is
unbelievable for the smaller operator to
actually function on
this this teamwork is essential
and so
as we go forward man it's it's it's
imperative that a lot of this stuff gets
brought out but the conversation of can
you grow durbin in alaska we had we had
the similar ideas of can you repeat
the experience of the cannabis because
what i knew was from me traveling all
over the world and smoking weed from all
these places
no matter how much we grew back at home
it wasn't the same product
and we knew that the light was different
but i didn't understand that light just
wasn't energy light was information once
i started to really mess with the light
scientists i started to find out that
it's information
and if we change the spectra we can make
a plant flower under full 24-hour
lighting we can make a plant not flower
we can make it elongate we can change
its shape we can change its profile we
can change soil uptake we can change
what micro microbial counts and how they
function
and so much of that is
is just knowledge that we're learning
and i think the problem is that what we
use is we use lab metrics to determine
quality and so that's one of the issues
is that you're using total terps total
potency this cannabinoid that
cannabinoid and the fact is that it's
all in a synthesis and
when you start to say if it isn't above
20 to 22 thc it's not top shelf it
instantly knocks out all these varieties
that are seven and eights and when i was
talking to a colombian that's a
colombian collector out of columbia so
he's able to collect all the south
american varieties so he and i have to
use google translate to talk
but
for real but the point is that he's a
collector he's an older guy in colombia
who collects in colombia
and
what he was saying is hey the only
reason why you guys aren't getting the
effect you want off of these varieties
is because you're you're muddied with
the the afghani cannabis that you're
smoking he said it basically muddied you
up and you need to cleanse your system
and then you'll get back to being able
to experience the effects you want off
these seven and eight percent strains
and and i always look at the total terps
as irrelevant because it's what terpenes
are present not the total concentration
of them that's why i don't like stuff i
always jam on terpinator because i call
it homogenator it makes everything taste
a goddamn same so yeah i'm glad it has
hot numbers but it's it's homogenized
cannabis
and and a lot of this is trying to get
the the market to understand it and i
just got jammed by someone on on plants
that i submitted to a competition of why
did i submit this plan i said because i
want the competitors to be able to sell
the product and if i give them something
like some laos that i'm messing around
with right now or some of some some
from laos or from nepal
for one it's going to have lower numbers
and it's not going to move on the shelf
because of it wait wait wait wait you're
saying the low you know the lower
numbers this industry in particular has
never said these words to people
whenever i say to them they go you're
right low number just take another hit
for god's sakes i mean you know i mean
but they see it as an economic concern
though like for someone who owns
dispensaries someone who actually owns
stores right for a long time
it is you have to gently
educate them and say listen just because
it says this number doesn't mean you're
going to get to smoke less because it
doesn't really
it isn't true
the the numbers don't dictate the
reality but they dictate an economic
reality just like terpene numbers doing
so i had a friend that had a you know
5.6 percent terps and i showed him a 2.2
terp strain and the 2.2 was volatile oh
we did we did we did it to ourselves but
the problem is we have to undo it
because what we've done is we created a
situation where the diversity is almost
impossible to put out if it isn't at
these atmos at
tremendous levels of numerics and i'm
somebody who breeds things to go into
heavy numerics where i chase these upper
30s i i put them in because it's
marketability and i tell people why i'm
doing it and it's not my entire project
it's just that when you want to make
money in modern cannabis and you need to
or you're going to go broke that shit
better have hot numbers
and it doesn't mean it's better and it
doesn't mean that it's going to get you
higher and it doesn't mean it's going to
be a better experience but the market is
obsessed with it and even the ranking
systems coming in through some of these
farmer federations are trying to
quantify the same thing that a top shelf
five star is you know over 22. and the
reality is
i think that we really have to have an
educational system come into play so
that the the users start to understand
that the metrics are something you look
at after the fact not first you look at
the numbers after and say hey that's
interesting this is the unique terpene
profile that made this happen perhaps
and these are these interesting
cannabinoids that i'm experiencing and
it starts to allow you to see patterns
and those patterns let you find other
varietals that are similar so that you
have a better range of choices because
in these limited production models you
won't be able to get it dispersed
throughout the whole state so this stuff
should have gone sorry man no i was just
gonna ask specifically do you still mess
with the 78 the six cut yeah yeah i
still messed up
like five five years ago that was like
we were like talking about like you they
had like recalibrate the machine for the
highest cbd dominant overall cannabinoid
strain ever found it was like yeah but
it was like 6963 and it was like it was
an og yeah and i mean it was great and
it i mean like i made great hash out of
it frenchy made great hash out of it
we all smoked it we all enjoyed it we
had a very cerebral experience kept on
going back for more like that was our
like little strain and i was like my it
was like my favorite thing and then you
know like the madrone picked it up and
those guys have been running with it so
it's like there is a market for it and
for for for that for that full profile
what's the rate what's the ratio on that
it was 16
nine six three was mine it was 16 nine
on the on the cbd and then six three on
the thc and it was an og it was a 78 and
it was the number six i think it was a
six or eight the six the eight phenol
then i have a ten female that uh the the
ten cut that comes out at around
nineteen 1908 and then like uh 10-2 yeah
and so when we did that i think i had a
combined canon later maybe like 33.5
which at the time had never been seen in
a cbd dominant cultivar but these are
outliers and because see the thing is i
got lucky
in that when when labs came out i was
one of the first people that was playing
around with them so i got access to labs
quick
and i understood how to use the tool
that let me see inside so i could steer
directions and those directions are
where we drove cbd in america so it was
the the my crew in arcata went through
the cantatonics and then and then ringo
went through ringo's line but that was
that was the basis of all cbd material
you have in america today came out of
those projects
but i wasn't caught up with that for me
with the cbd work once i found cultivars
and had a variety of them that had
certain ratios what i did is i just put
them into the market
i was i was more driven into
what i would call you know recreational
cannabis and and so i used my my
predicate of work to steer directions in
that so i could get these jammed numbers
because what it did was it let us move
let us move product and then it let me
put cuttings in the hands of farmers
that could then make money moving those
pieces and part of it was to explain to
the public at the same time these are
numbers that you used to sell but this
is an 11 that you want to enjoy
and so we would give the education but
man you got to sell the weed in order to
stay in business so let me make the
suggestion next time
because i have a dispensary in in oregon
that does this
so most of the weed in oregon has now
gotten really cheap
this stuff he sells for 25 bucks a gram
yeah it's got low numbers yeah it's
killer wheat but it's got low numbers
instead of putting the numbers down
it's the price people look at
and so he's charging 25 bucks a gram
for something that by numbers people
might pay six four oh yeah no it's just
it can't keep it on the shelf the
numbers are right on the product though
now like the the numbers are what you
can't see oregon's different than
california where oregon still allows you
to smell the wheat
oregon oregon still lets you open the
jar
we can't let the government in
california say you're not allowed to do
that anymore come on what are you
talking about this is our industry not
your industry let us do what we want to
do you know i mean it's not going to
kill anybody if you
yeah anyway sorry well
that's that's to i think to me that's
fundamentally uh tax base where it's
it's not so much they're afraid you're
gonna smell it but they're afraid that a
little nugget might fall out of that
open container into someone's hand for
free
and so you know when we saw this happen
and when we we used to do a lot of
giveaways i was involved in a tremendous
amount of uh free cbd where i've never
sold any cbd and i've been in in in the
industry fuck forever but i've been in
you know dispensary operations now for
probably almost 11 years and for the 11
years i've never sold any cbd material
if you if you came to me for cb material
you got it for free and you know it was
probably about 120 000 free clones that
went through on books another 30 000
that we kicked on the side so maybe you
know 150 000 clones i kicked out for
free and then probably another ungodly
amount of tinctures rso and all these
other components because
there was a there was a greater good
that was involved and
we knew that that was going to come to
an end and that's why we kind of went at
it so hard because we knew at some point
in time there's no way anybody was going
to allow us to do this much charity we
just knew it was coming and so that's
the problem is that
you know we you want to fight the
government on this crap but
fundamentally you need to have the
finances to survive long enough to do it
and they've done such a good job by
limiting what one can do and how one
does it but i think so many people right
now are just financially crippled and
it's really stopping any kind of battle
to where you you have to work with these
realities and i think part of the
reality is have varietals that you can
use as as attractions
and then create the the awareness of
what is an experience of cannabis how do
we quantify it does one just want to get
affected does one want a quality of
effect
and it's the new individuals that are
coming in that you'll be able to start
to give this this information to because
they don't have a back history
those in those individuals aren't coming
in
in the way they should be because of
this feedback loop between the money and
the high numbers right like
everybody's a little bit caught in this
trap that is a side effect of
prohibition
everyone's making moonshine
and they're just and moonshine is an
artifact of prohibition
you know you want that high potency
stuff for storage and transport
because shit is illegal
and when prohibition goes away
an industry is supposed to evolve into
variety they're supposed to evolve
they're supposed to start making pinot
grigio that civilians can appreciate
but
we have this existing market base that
will pay for stuff and there's all this
financial pressure and there's gluts on
the market and everybody just wants to
it's just this very short-term thinking
like i gotta hit 30 so i can move stuff
because otherwise i'm gonna die and
we're and we're still
it's like we're acting like we're still
in prohibition no one's willing to take
the leap to make
plants that smell outrageous and they're
incredibly low numbers
and you can bring them and you can smoke
them at thanksgiving with your whole
family and all the old people and it's
and like there's just
thousands of people that aren't coming
into shops
and i know dispensary owners who
who
want to start bringing in those people
but they can't because they're like i'm
not going to carry that stuff on my
shelf because it doesn't move and it
doesn't move because they won't carry it
on their shelves and they won't market
it
and so
everyone's in this financial jam
selling to these like
you know 200 000 consumers just smoke
all the cannabis
and only want numbers in the 30s
and it's like we're on this wheel it's
like we have to take a second and get
off the wheel and look at the fact that
everybody would like to smoke some pot
the floor you just
the flower market can learn a lot from
the low dose edible market right now
yeah the edibles have figured this out
way before people's figured it out i
can't tell you how many like you know 45
to 60 year old you know uh you know
women or you know or are gentlemen are
you know 2.5 or 3 milligrams 3 milligram
dose and you know and they love it
they're happening
we didn't get down to 2.5 to like last
year last year so it took until last
year for anyone to get under five
and also like one chocolate people were
like and it's so funny because you look
at these like ladies at like concerts
and stuff like that with their little
kiva tins and they pull the little kiva
tin and they take like one little bean
and they're like would you like one but
i'm like they're micro doses they're
sure yeah they're they're microsoft
you know what they'd really like to do
they'd like to take out a little
pre-roll that's like four percent and
just be like
well so i smoked 12 to 14. i smoked 12
to 14 and i and and i you know and so
like in founding the exchange and many
other markets i've always grown i i
worked with equilibrium growing um
african-based uh sativas
that's what i smoke and pineapple
because i'm from i'm from a pineapple
region right so it's like i like smoking
in the pies like good in the pines is
between like around 14
so if i smoke if i smoke that pie in the
pines you know or at least derek's cut i
smoke that i'm having a great time i
want to do my taxes if i smoke the
afghani i want to run from my taxes i'm
like fuck you know it's like hiding up
in my mom's bed with like sweating and
all that you know so i don't i don't
want to do that but so the idea that
there is that that market is emerging
but when i smoke at like an exchange
and somebody comes to me for a higher
dose you know and i smoke a pineapple or
i smoke a you know a malawi or something
they feel like almost they're having a
psychedelic they're actually having fun
they enjoy enjoying themselves on
cannabis they're like this is great what
did you put in there but that's exposure
see i i use my girl as the as the i call
it like my wheat guinea pig for for what
i call the lower octane strains because
everything that i was smoking was too
strong for her and so i went through a
couple years of sifting period where i
was able to get into some of mean jeans
lines and i was able to pull out this
beautiful cherry back cross and i i bred
into it and pulled out maybe you know
something comes around like 12 too
but it's beautiful and it's got a really
rich quality and the flavor's right and
for people who smoke it it's it's
unbelievably satisfying
but i'm telling you put that stuff on
the shelf
and you it sits there because of the
numbers there has to be some system that
that comes where you start to have the
ability to get people to come in
and actually experience cannabis and
then see the numbers afterwards it's
called marketing and we call it cannabis
light yeah we just don't have the but
the thing is you're competing you're
you're competing the marketing part's
hard because you're having to compete
with people that are that have the
ability like the emerald exchange and
events like you used to do no worries
brother was that it allowed you to have
people come and actually be present
and it lets you now have cultivators
that's where the problem with all the
cultivation where the farmers can't sell
direct the farmers can't have tastings
you know they you can do it illicitly
but the problem is that's not going to
allow you any kind of real penetration
and if you had that then what you could
do is you could have a real diversity in
your lines where you had a true gradient
and the gradients can be based off of
potency gradients and also how you feel
from the varietal and that's based off
the terpene relationships and so you'd
be able to have true gradients that
matched what you wanted to release from
your farm and it would have things that
would satisfy people who wanted more
broad-based stuff up to a you know to
peel the pillow topiad or if you're if
you skull
and some people like that too so i don't
i don't throw rocks at anybody what they
like some people like uh you know thc
isolate where they want that stuff at 99
percent and that's what they like
let's let's make that awesome yeah yeah
no it all has to it no it's full it all
has to be there
it's just that traditionally that's
that's been the problems and that's why
someone asked me they said why did you
chase such high thc varieties for so
long and develop males to throw those
numbers on other plants i said because
it sold and it allowed individuals to be
able to have sellable varieties which
kept them in business and so now we have
to redo just like back in the day i used
to go hunt varietals and had low scent
signatures and people say why would you
do that i said because i'm somebody who
was here before charcoal so before
charcoal technology came out you'd have
a full pair of balls to grow dope
illegally or otherwise you'll be about
to have a heart attack when you pulled
into your driveway and the whole
neighborhood wreaked and you were
looking at catching a felony case and
going to prison and so i would
yeah i would hunt
i would hunt varietals that had low
scent and it allowed us to cultivate and
move and so i mean by the time i'm done
with this we end up snuffing out a huge
portion of the population but that was a
function of illegality also mostly so
upsetting
i'm sorry oh no yeah you don't you think
i i'm digging it
it i had my own library of stuff i would
keep because i was somebody that was
basically a lunatic so i could handle
the risk i i was pretty ballsy but for
the clients that i built operations for
that wasn't the case for all of them and
so for these people that wanted to
cultivate cannabis in you know the early
90s
when you know the indoor was really
taken off it had to be and charcoal
wasn't present and and i was using a
high-tech ozone at the time to where i
could blow the ducks of a building clean
but regular people didn't have access to
this stuff and so it was really a
function of what could you cultivate and
grow and then we would have things that
were higher level and so all this stuff
that we that gets us here is all a
result of prohibition and that's why for
me i'm trying to go back in time and
mind the things that we've lost most of
the libraries that we held for so much
of us have got taken in raids so between
raids and armed robberies we've lost a
tremendous amount of genealogical
material yeah and but that was just
that's how it was i mean i could lament
the the story but it's just it is what
it what it is
and it's trying to you know move forward
from here and that's why i give people
the background on it and i explained to
them look this is why i chase the
numbers but this is why i'm trying to
expose you to an 11 varietal
my position let's do it yeah i had you
had to do it but but listen like
everybody's fighting for their lives now
right
but i don't think people are taking this
seriously
the the massive
the massive farms and the companies that
are
just
they're just after oil just after thc
they're just cannabinoid production
companies right
so
if we stay in this market where we're
chasing
numbers in the 30s for thc and we're
making oil in the 90s
it's like
i'm going to have a little farm and i'm
going to compete with big ag who's
growing fields of thc
we can't compete in the thc market the
thc market
the high thc market is now
kind of gone
if if we're gonna have appalachians if
we're gonna have small farms that
survive
a ton of thc
it's just not where they're going to
compete
they have to find other niches and it's
not just because i want to smoke that
stuff and because it'll bring in other
customers who are interested
it's just that
that
thing that was prohibited
prohibited in prohibition
big companies are taking that now and
that should not be our job anymore so
the question is how do we get there i
mean and i can see a couple of different
ways i mean one the work that you're
doing you know there's i don't know i
don't know how it's how it shows up on a
strain
so when i when i go and buy a durbin
poison then i know that's really durban
poisoning because you said the dnas
would you know what's is there a stamp
that's going to be developed yeah
there's a stamp and listen if i was in
alaska and i wanted to grow durbin
poison i would go to humboldt i would go
to south africa and i'd get the right
soil and i'd get the derby poison and
i'd go to alaska and i would grow it in
that local soil and i would put the
magic light over it and dial the light
in until it was like the right latitude
but but i wouldn't try to get the
appalachian durban poison right because
the reason for the appellation is like
you're not protecting the ip around the
plate the ip the soil is the ip
right there they're protecting their
locals
and you couldn't get it you couldn't you
couldn't get an appellation around it
and and what we're doing in appalachian
development is experience driven right
so it's like come experience the
cultural heritage of the region as well
so i mean it's like we're diversifying
you know a lot of us up there you know
we it's back to the landers we're
economic refugees we came up there for a
simpler way of life we like to build our
own shit like this is what we want to do
we want to share that with the world we
want to share our permaculture knowledge
we want to share our strained
development knowledge we want to share
the history heritage we want to we want
to feed you
right you know we want all of these
things and that's what we're doing so i
mean at the end of the day we're not in
the same market as these guys i'm not
i'm not worried about big agra coming in
and ruining our our region because at
the end of the day i mean we're capped
at 10 000 square feet we're and we're
geographically isolated to a point with
why would big ag and you're organic yeah
well
exactly beyond organic and it's why
would we why would big ag want to go two
and a half hours on the back side of
fucking iron peak you know what i'm
saying to get a 10 000 square foot grow
for a commodities market it doesn't even
make sense yeah but can you survive
selling your flour to your to your
neighbors i mean that is where yeah no
it's not to our neighbors
so you know in in initiatives and i
don't like self-you know self-promotion
or whatever but it's like initiatives of
micro branding your brand so like so we
are taking it's mic it's micro branding
so so we take small brands right we take
people out of the hills we incentivize
them
to start off in the branding space now
there's an evolution to that which is
cooperatives right so they start off
everyone wants to be king of the hill
everyone would be king of the castle i
did it the best i do it the best i am
the best and then all other sudden they
realize they're like hey can you sell my
weed you know and it's like they're
starting to depend on their neighbors
again like they always have and so the
cooperative forms now the cooperative
may be a series of micro brands acting
as molten we're seeing that with true
humble but still has little monikers on
or the little tags for each one of the
farms or arcana everyone wants their own
three sisters all these different things
you know now we've got uh emerald groans
coming out they're they're you know
they're going to be a ton of micro
brands you know but then you have
flocana which started out hey we're
going to be a bunch of microbrands and
they're like
maybe we're going to be one big brand
and so then you have a cooper an
agriculture cooperative that shows up
like flakkana so then you have this one
big brand of of weed called flocan that
goes out onto the shelves so you have
you know small micro brands micro brands
acting as a cooperative and you have
larger cooperatives of farmers acting as
a single brand it follows the coffee
model it follows the wine model i mean
but the appellation of origin and the
control and the governance behind the ip
protections for each one of these
regions actually gets to dictate the
standards of quality in which they are
allowed to grow in that region so they
they actually make their own rules the
state doesn't hand down a set of rules
i've been with cdfa now for
three weeks traveling around the state i
saw you up in humble you know it's like
we were just out in palm desert palm
desert said we're not going to be in
appalachian i said good because you're
doing it on stolen water you know it's
like they don't want it
it's like that's yeah yeah good luck you
know but the idea is they have they want
a geographical indication right grown in
the desert not of the desert because
they're not grown of the desert right
so these aocs that are forming these
collectives these cooperatives that set
their own rules to set their own
standards themselves get to government
this is an attractive you know this is a
proposition to a consumer that can only
get that product in one place only one
place right it can be distributed
to small you know dispensaries around
but the product can't be produced at a
scale that can feed the masses let them
have the central valley unfortunately
you know but let us have the small the
craft the artisanal let's take that
model let's take that market that's our
market and it and you know and i don't
think we're
worried at all i mean you don't think
you have to move stuff down to the city
i am a fuck dude you know okay so i surf
i surf right now 14 days out of 28 the
other 14 i'm up with my kids
the reason i i'm down here surfing
venice break water almost every single
morning and every single night is
because
i have to be down here selling weed like
this is where the market is this is
where i have to bring cannabis i i wish
to god i could just meet somebody at the
end of my driveway get a duffel bag of
cash and give them a freaking duffel bag
of turkey bags and and let that go it
only made the day
oh
yeah right right i'll meet you at the
third gate i'll leave the second one
open all right and i'm not giving you
the code and we need to count the cash
because
but i mean and you know so the idea is
like those days are over we're down here
down here with jars of fucking weed tons
all my friends and neighbors and it's
now we're becoming business people we're
becoming politicians we're becoming
consultants we're gonna be become
everything we never wanted to be just to
survive but the thing is is we are going
to survive
what are you growing high numbers are
you selling high numbers is are you
falling into that trap high numbers yeah
well i mean i say you scale you fail i
mean it's like so so so no we're not
selling high numbers we're trying to
sell at high margins no no i mean i
meant your your your tac numbers no i
mean i i'd say i'd say i would say i
would say there's a diverse there's a
diversity
right now that you know that that
dispensaries i just got a coa back from
big rock farms they're 22 percent
everyone's like oh my god i'm going to
take 50 of those you know i think you
know you know you know 100 of those all
right that's what i want the 22 i wanted
21 percent i'll take the 22
you know yeah numbers are still driving
driving the market we got we got some
questions coming in
well kevin you and i have talked about
this for hours so um and you guys kind
of touched on it i hate all sorry it's
lance mowgli
[Laughter]
um
you know you guys i hate comparing our
industry to alcohol but it's true micro
macro and justin and i just talked about
this on a boat in long beach the other
day um i think that's the only way it
has to go and justin's spot on with that
there's something that can't be emulated
on what's going on in the triangle
that's what's going to make it unique he
introduced me to hidden prairie farms by
far the best fire blue skittles i've
ever had it'll stay that way and i'll
pay all the money for we just talked
about used to getting free product but
there's some product you're willing to
pay for if you don't make it yourself
but what do you guys think about as far
as the evolution beyond the micro macro
you're talking about the race to the top
which is sad for the states that
everyone's to your point 34 35 38 who
knows if it's real on thc
when do you think that the 2.0 is going
to come in where it stops being a race
it stops me in the dumb question of
indica sativa or hybrid and it gets into
more of uh what's your terpene profile
is mercying for the win is lemony what
is it for you
and i kind of know your answer kevin but
i think everyone would like to hear some
on the same page i think yeah i think
that for the craft regions it's really
about getting it and it's beginning it's
it's it's to get the people see remember
most of these craft regions like
humboldt's a really good example because
humboldt is is unique in california in
terms of ownership of property so most
of california has a disproportionate
amount of state and federal land versus
private ownership humble has the most
private ownership of any any county in
california
which means that people really haven't
seen humboldt county so it's it's just
words it's coming from humboldt what
does that mean
and so what you're seeing right now
though is
the first time where we've been able to
work with the the the people who run
humble county in terms of tourism
and in humboldt made
and in the ability to get people to come
in and start to really be exposed to the
farms directly so we're working so
heavily on the tourism aspect to allow
individuals to come in
and start to experience what the farmer
has to offer because the farmer can have
a conversation now the the way we're
working it is the farmer can have the
conversation someone like me has to sell
the products i have the license but all
i'm doing is selling the product that
the farmer's convincing the people that
they want to try based off of what the
individual's asking for
and so when i when i when i look at
storefronts
the person who controls the destiny of
your farm is someone who's making under
fifteen dollars an hour right so under
fifteen dollars an hour they're
controlling the success of your farm
because they're a bud tender and that's
not meant in any disrespectful way about
money
or in skill it's just that it's it's
somebody who's at the counter is being
asked questions so few people actually
come in and ask for something
specifically
only a couple companies have that type
of market penetration
and it it comes down to the individuals
have to start to want to know
the product they're buying from who's
creating it
and based off of what these individuals
are trying to create and so i think that
the craft regions and as we go forward
the way you get around
this lack of understanding is to allow
the tourism to increase which it's
beginning and we can see it clearly now
and they're starting to come in
and you allow the farmers to to to
actually
converse with these people
so they can ask the farmer what are you
growing what are you doing what do you
recommend for me for what i'm seeking
because it isn't just about a single
terpene it's not about um i just want
this for maybe for opiate replacement it
kind of is and we can say that limonene
drives you drives you up and we can say
corophylline drives you down and so we
can make broad generalizations based off
of how we see terps but fundamentally
you want to be able to have the farmers
who are cultivating and working on their
own diverse varietal packages
things that make them unique in terms of
i don't grow the same thing justin does
and i might desire to send you a
different direction when the people come
in they're allowed to see these things
experience them
and then they do the word of mouth
they're the ones that drive that
direction forward they're the ones that
go back to their home of origin and say
man i said i got some killer weed this
was the company that i got it from
and what happens is
those companies only produce certain
amounts so say justin's farm does 500
pounds and we just talked about a farm
that's going to do 200 000
well what happens is why can't you do
pre-buys because we do that with other
products i'm in wine clubs i order wine
in and hold it and and there's other
things in life that we that we work with
i call it the ferrari model because the
ferrari model is you got 300 orders for
cars and you only made 200 of them and
the other 100 guys sorry you missed out
and it doesn't seem to hurt ferrari very
badly what it does is they've created a
demand for a thing that makes people
want a thing and it makes them commit to
this thing and it allows you then to
sell that thing at a higher price point
and have an ability to sell all your
product i think a lot of these craft
farms i don't think they should even be
putting them in eighths i think there
should be an ounce only so what you were
saying about bud tenders
so we have like three separate projects
now in oregon because we're realizing
the truth of what you said
we have like three separate projects now
in oregon to educate bud tenders
like these people are putting together
like reams of educational content and
doing blood tender certifications so
that because
we are super dependent on those guys
they're the gatekeepers
and and reaching out to them and getting
them to drive the market in a new way
that that's the easiest pressure point
right now
and we got to do that we should all be
pulling behind that like making sure
that the brand is carried into the shop
the bud tender understands the brand can
talk about it could talk about the
different varieties
and when someone comes in
they steer them towards something more
intelligent and then the market will
evolve it's tough for a lot of the
stores though because you got like i use
an example of some stores i go to they
got 400 flower choices
well jesus christ how does any bud tend
to know 400 goddamn choices well that's
like no no for real for real like the
why do they carry so much flour because
because ultimately they they believe
that that varietal is is needed in terms
of um who's coming and they want to
catch everybody because it's so
competitive and if you're really doing
legit business with your facilities
where you're permitted you know
basically you're if you're breaking even
you're doing pretty goddamn good now to
me this whole model is an assimilation
model where you're building something to
be sold in a couple years this isn't
about running a business like
traditional business where i make x
amount of money i have x amount of
profit we move forward most of these
places are being built on a for-sale
basis where you're building some kind of
vehicle that you can unload to a logic
conglomerate down the road
it favors that model if you take a look
at it to me it's walmart model it's it's
couple percentage points of profit and
if you can deal with it you're going to
do great but if you're not you're
screwed
and so they're trying to shotgun
approach who they're selling to and i
think what you have to have is you have
to have the ability for storefronts
in specific areas to say you know where
we're mendocino based where you have a
shop in venice that works off of
mendocino farmers specifically and what
it does it allows them to or the
appalachian farmers where these three
appalachians we believe have superior
product of these products and of those
appalachian farmers we believe these
three farmers have the right product of
this product
so what you hear about appalachian about
collectives trying to get retail right
yeah you have a you'll have some kind of
humble collective that has a shop in l.a
right and it's like an embassy
exactly that allows you
and then you bring a brand ambassador
down someone who's able to sit there and
educate the people on hey these are how
they produce it these are the different
directions and a lot of it is trying to
get people to experience some of it and
i think i think one of the one of the
the tricks of it is is you do steam
derived terps and you put it in a water
bottle because that's the only way
you're going to get anybody to taste
this shit legally and so we messed
around with it where we steam pulled
terps off the varietals put it into a
water bottle that's legal now you can
taste what that variety tastes like with
no legal issues and just just to let you
know also that you know what we're doing
right now what we've evolved from the
events not being able to happen this
year is we've made something called an
outpost right so we put all the brands
in like a kiosk and have the brand
ambassadors come down and actually like
do education pieces
but even that because the distributors
have just the distributor model too the
distributors are you know 200 500 skus
right they go into the shop and they're
looking at all these skus they've got
these price sheets got everything like
that and i went across the street across
the street is the e's headquarters i
guess heard of ease right right right
across the street that big giant castle
is is ease and um and i went in there
with a bunch of farm product little farm
box those super cute little stamps and
and all the humble magazine appellations
map you know like hi
you know you want to buy our weed and
they were like we're buying six dollar
eights
it's like well i was like oh shit that's
like 300 that's like 300 pounds unless
with taxes and and distro and all those
things so it's like so price
right is driving because these people
are trying to push it all out so it it's
like
we're we're up against
like this market is going the price per
per unit is going down right that's
driving a lot of the business inside the
retail the retailers are trying to push
this out you know so it's like it's
about education but it's about each and
every single one of you going in and
demanding higher quality products it's
about us
it's about us defining those quality
markers like we have to we have to like
you know friendships like with the hash
wheel
max mantra so give him a shout out you
know with the with the interpreting
guide you know it's like and you know
tim blake for the love of christ put
pressure on tim blake to release the cup
data you know of all the of all the of
all the of all the you know the the
judging cards
all of those markers we start speaking
that language and unification like every
single one of us we can demand bud
tenders
to actually give us a higher quality
product and brands to produce that
higher quality product
you just got to get the the problem with
that the is that you're if you really
want a good bud tender the best blood
tender is really the grower
because they're the ones that know the
product best and so it's trying to get
the the level of information to the end
user and you have to target it
geographically where you go for all the
years that i did you know illicit uh
sales for nursery work
um when people ask me uh that's where
that's where senator mcguire came in he
came and asked me he goes how do you
choose you for riles and i said you want
the answer i tell you you want the other
one the real answer and he goes i want
the real answer i said i take a look
regionally and i take a look through the
whole united states and i determine
what's moving in the u.s and i study the
us as a total market
and then when you come in to do business
with me i ask you privately where you
move in the weed and if you tell me
you're moving it to chicago i know what
to put you into if you're moving into
florida i know what to put you into i
know what to put you into because
regions have desires
and i think with cannabis what you're
doing is we're throwing and there's
something wrong with us people that have
lower income levels shouldn't be forced
to buy more expensive cannabis because
we want to get paid a fair price for it
because in every object in life you can
find a price price gradient and i think
that what we have to do is really steer
ourselves into people that are more
discerning and so that's why i believe
that when you work off of these craft
models
less is more
and you get a higher price because
you're trying to target a very different
user you're not trying to get everybody
in the country to smoke your weed you're
trying to get people that really have
enough income to smoke a higher quality
product and we don't have enough
price differentiation at all not right
now it's all in the same bucket like
there's like 1000x
range right
and with cannabis like we just haven't
figured out how to walk in
we haven't figured out how to walk into
a store and be like
this is a 200.8
because it's fucking worth it like
in every other
product it's like that we just haven't
we haven't the balls maybe yet to just
to just set up a store and to grow in a
supply chain and just be like this is so
much better
it's not the delivery funding to to
actually do it because at the end of the
day it's the education but at the end of
the day i did the math when you and i
used to work together i remember the
most money i ever made was when you the
ogsd right i felt greenhouse for the
ogsd it had worked in two different
markets i got to clear it out but when i
went with the diamonds with the diamond
og
i i got a third of what it was that i
was doing so i was like so i had to grow
that ogsd
because i could sell it
it would it would move it wasn't exactly
you know it wasn't a desired trade but
it would move as in the fuel market and
i could grow
three times as much of it so it was like
so it's like we we were we're economic
we're driven by economics as well it's
like what produces the most and and and
i know but it's the job of the small
grower to to its will be to grow the
stuff that doesn't produce the most but
is extraordinary and you can
you're getting that kind of price reward
right yeah back then of course the
prohibition model that's what it is
we're just not coming out of that fast
enough you know well it's going to it's
going to take time though wine people
had to drink it or they would have died
of uh toxic water so i mean fermented
drinks being christ was beer was a
breakfast drink
and so
it could still be a breakfast yeah still
is but the but the point of it is is
that you you you have to be able to take
the time and that's the problem is that
we don't have time or you don't feel
like we have time
but i know that as people start to
become exposed to cannabis and you start
to buy these cheaper products you're
going to say hey how come that wasn't
the stuff i used to smoke prior and
you're going to desire it you're going
to realize you know what i could smoke
an ounce of this shit and it wouldn't be
as satisfying as an eighth of the other
so therefore what's the difference in
price
it's like all things you you drink in
certain amount that's not a budweiser
you gotta you got some kind of little
micro ipa in front of you it's it's it's
a choice that was made a little devil
had on it this guy's interesting kevin
we got we got an audience we got
questions i'm sorry
hey guys thank you so much for coming
through you guys are all super
knowledgeable you know giving us all a
ton of stuff um i have a question on
consumers you guys are not you guys you
specifically kevin seem to be mixed on
consumer because um
you seem to say that the bud tender has
a ton of power but at the same time
you're saying that they go home and and
they decide so at the end of the day
don't you think that the consumer is
going to know what they want they might
be pushed something but just because
there's a hottie in a hornidos you know
cut off doesn't mean i'm going to order
hornitos tequila no it's not a hottie in
a horninos it's that when you're when
you're running a storefront it isn't
everybody that comes in is so cognizant
of what they want so most of the time
people ask what do you have can you
recommend me something and what they
recommend typically is something that
they have a connection to in some form
so if you're a good farmer in terms of
business skill you make a relationship
with the people who are selling your
product and that's where this
distributor model sucks in my opinion
because they're just sticking this shit
in a shelf the farmer has to actually go
to the bud tenders show them the
products that they cultivate tell them
why they they grow what they grow give
them the information about what makes it
different let them experience it in some
capacity because now what the blood
tender has is it is a memory of that
relationship when i walk into stores
that have hundreds of choices i go give
me something gassy give me something
fruity and give me something you like
and they go okay
this gassy one is what seems to be
moving most we seem to get the most
satisfaction on the on the repeat buy
and then this is the same for the fuel
so what we're doing is i'm asking them
and this is a game i'm playing i'm just
playing to see how are they choosing
these things and then the final one is
what do you like yourself what would you
choose yourself for your own opinion
your own piece
because then it lets me get an idea what
the individual likes
and so it's
it's this person who's selling the
product at the front of the counter
you have to be able to differentiate
yourself as a farmer grower whatever you
want to call yourself to that individual
because
otherwise you just fit into a jar like
all the others and that's the part that
matters is that in any single storefront
you walk into it's the person who's
being paid the least amount of money who
has the most amount of influence on the
sale of your product i mean in oregon
the consumers don't know what they want
people keep saying that but do you think
they'll learn is my question they'll
learn if the bud tenders teach them
through education the bud tenders can
teach them
yes the farmer has to teach the blood
tender though really about why the
product is different because it can't be
the distributor because the distributor
how the hell they're gonna know 700
products they don't even smoke half
these guys don't even smoke weed
so it it it's it's you're letting people
don't even smoke weed dictate your
success or your business but that's why
i tell the farmers listen you got to go
to every dispensary
don't go through the distributor in the
conventional sense go to the stores make
the connections as the farmer and then
find a distributor to sell to them so
the consumers who like pinot noir
or sold pinot noir at a certain point is
that what you're saying because i'm
asking they know they like pinot noir
from trying it from learning from
experimenting not because they walked in
and the hornitos chick gave them
hornidos and that's what they're about
but but a
partially both
some people know that they tried it and
liked it someplace they come in and ask
for it but a tremendous number of people
come in and ask to ask the person
selling it what do you recommend i have
20 choices in front of me what's your
opinion the bud tenders in oregon say
that it's like being a bartender in a
bar and every single person who comes in
says
what should i drink bars aren't like
that anymore
but for now though but for now i'm lucky
to have a difference
right because
we're looking we give out i think we
give out 50 to 100 dispensary comps
mostly to bud tenders to emerald
exchange events to come and meet the
farmers and then we're we're non-stop
giving samples we're like if we find out
you're a bud tender we're like
we're you know we're hanging out with
you i have a different experience with
bud tenders when i'm walking in you know
to to a space i'm usually with a brand
or or doing something different so it's
like it's education to me to see now in
the la market when i you know
watching how many products are coming
out how many products are available and
how important it is that we do
ask for what it is that we want like as
consumers so media
is becoming huge so the media outlets
partnerships with media telling people
the story of the strains that we want
and i know that that's one of the things
that you know i've noticed when being in
the la marketplace is like hey how is it
that we get what it is that we want
right what what how does it we ask these
questions and the bud tinder seem to be
to me
more educated than what you guys like
and i don't know i'm just coming from a
different place maybe it's coming from
the emerald exchange place but i think
that
i i don't know like
i just see a different
view vantage point i mean i think that
they're i think that we are starting to
find people that are like oh it's
beginning yeah yeah
it's beginning but it's it's not to the
point where
you have an ability for the customer to
know exactly what they like what you
what they what they can tell you though
is how they want to feel what kind of
effect do they want to achieve from the
product that they're buying so they can
tell you hey i want something that makes
me feel uplifted i would like something
to relax me i want to have some sleep
aid i'm hungry i'd like to be able to
have
a appetite stimulation either up or down
so they can tell you this information
but for so many individuals they used to
score and we just scoring weed and half
the stuff that they were buying was
mislabeled that's what philos lets you
find out half the stuff you were smoking
really wasn't what you thought you were
smoking and still isn't
and still isn't done
so when you go in and you talk to your
bud tender you're buying a blue dream
you don't have any idea whether that's
blue dream and your butt tender doesn't
either i mean and so so part of the but
if there was a really smart abundance
who had smoked that stuff right
thoughtfully and it was called blue
dream but he was like this is what you
want now i know that after talking to
you and it was called blue dream
right i mean i shouldn't say this but
if there was that connection that'd be
just fine you could have a contender who
could lead you i agree and one of the
ways they get there i think is because
they'll have a certification
by your company and they'll start to
know without having to smoke at some
point so there are seven or eight
different kinds of you know people
we know it but most people don't know
kush they don't know that afghan was was
was for you know making hash and so it
gives you a different kind of high most
people don't know that now i'm a member
of the garden writers of america we
represent we reach
85 million people a week
so
last year was the first time they ever
had a talk on cannabis they would never
let anybody talk about cannabis so there
are no newspaper articles by regular
garden writers and you know who would
reach normal people yeah you got the
oregonian has their you know their bud
tender page and everything else but you
know where they try to make it sound
like it's a wine and blah blah blah but
that's not the right kind of education
that we need right now we've got people
that are
they want to smoke the weed they really
don't even know what to ask other than
yeah i want to be uplifted or you know a
couch locked that's the two things they
know and and so all of this stuff has to
change and one of the ways i think we
change is by not wasting our time so for
example
we have this 420 day which gets more
publicity than you can possibly garner
for free
for the industry what do we do on 420 we
party you know we could use 420 day to
change the name from marijuana to
cannabis we could we could find three or
four different things you know
420 today everybody who who's thinking
about smoking cannabis or to read this
article or this week there's a way we
could unify
the way to reach people as an industry
jeff we talk to ourselves we don't
really get the people who are out of the
industry
did you say that the garden writers of
america reach 85 million people a week
really on tv radio that's awesome 85
million people a week
and so i go you're the new outlet for
the cannabis industry i'm gonna be
leaning on you heavily you're right
except we've got another problem there
so so so high times decides
dope magazine maybe we better buy that
we're going to see the same kind of
consolidation in the media industry
involving this you know we've got about
100 different cannabis magazines now
they're all the same you know but at
least we got 100 different ones they
could be different
and and you know now we're going to end
up with two or three and so but yeah
these are the things we have to do but i
want to go back to that 420 idea it is a
day that's there it is written about in
every newspaper it is on every
television station 4 20 oh my god what
an opportunity for us and we blow it
every year well we're just all really
excited
today well all right we should figure
out what to do ten more questions so
all right question
sorry
hi guys um sundaraj in here
i'm neutral it's really it's really dark
are you guys are you the guy with the
atomic light i'm actually very dark he's
the light i'm the only dark guy here
actually i thought that was just because
of the lighting no no it's okay
thank you mowgli i appreciate that
um
so i'm very new to the industry and and
first i want to say thank you guys for
sharing your wisdom with us
there seems to be for me
a different
pivot point
it's a plant
it's a living plant
it seems to me and when we talk about
numbers
high th
every plant it seems to me from what i'm
learning
every strain is different everybody that
smokes it takes it
because we're all individuals have
different effects with it
and so to have a discussion on one
particular one and how you like it don't
like it
is one thing the other and as good as a
question here
the other thing is that
the medicinal part of this
no matter whether you're a wreck whether
or not it's still a medicine in the
sense that whether it's a health
or whether it's a physical ailment
it's a medicine right and we know that
i'm from india and i know my ancestors
have been using it in fact my
grandfather as well for a long time
so what i see also from the outside is a
lot of camaraderie that happens
and a whole lot of
less amount of
collaboration not only in the
educational part of this
but also treating that plant
like it should be in the sense of
nature how nature is
well i guess what i'm trying to figure
out and from you guys is
you talk about pricing
you talk about keeping
that edge in the marketplace and mobley
i hear you very loud and clear
you've got to make that plant very
quality that people will come the
growers that have used i i'm not just
trying to plug the plasma lake but
they've kept their price up in oregon
because they can do and get the numbers
and get full entourage effect full
profile
so what i'm asking i guess is
when you go indoors like this
trying to do biomimicry trying to do
that
and get the full expression of those
specific land races you're trying to go
back to
what is the process that you're
currently using to do that and is
everybody doing it like in a vacuum and
then trying to figure it out so they can
get an edge or is there a group that's
literally working towards
getting more of the same kinds of
medicine out to everybody that really
need this medicine
not just i mean i smoke don't get me
wrong
i enjoy it too
but you know what i can just get it from
my grower the guys i know so i can
supply myself
but the medicinal kind of grow
the kind that really are helping
veterans out because of cancer patients
and all these
where's the group
that actually
does that as a collaboration and how do
you guys think that should be done
that's my question i think traditionally
that's been done
by a lot of us
behind the scenes because you're
when you're talking about medicine to
veterans and ill and stuff like that
they're broke
and so you know from my situation that's
why i've given out so much freaking
money because how do you how do you ask
somebody who's has nothing to give you
something
and so you're you're that's a that's a
charity situation which is very
difficult for for regular people to do
because it's you having to subsidize it
yeah but that's that's you kevin
but you know so so now there's companies
right that are trying to do that they're
trying to
make medicine you know they're trying to
have proprietary plants that have
unusual cannabinoids and they make oil
from it and they work with doctors and
they try to bring it to patients
and
and it's it's rough to watch them
because they they're they're trying to
help patients and they're also
simultaneously trying to build all this
ip
and they're conflicted in various ways
and they don't have any data on the
actual medicine they're giving patients
and it's not a collaborative thing
it's a handful of companies that are
very focused on the medical space
and
it's it's not like it should be that's
that's big business though the medical
end is the money yeah no but you know
that when you're talking about how do
you help you it wasn't about how do you
drive medical you said how do you help
specific groups
when you say the word help that doesn't
mean charge help is help is like come
over and help me if i pay you that's a
job
and so when you're talking about help
then then it has to be where
when we had ideas where you had these
regions like our regions where x amount
of the product that came off of your
farm was put into a a general fund
and it was allowed to be distributed so
that you only had x so you know if you
did 90 of the crop was for sales so that
you could keep your farm alive and then
10 of the farm was given to these type
of situations
then you'd have some ability it's just
that it's tough because you've got to
pay tax on these products you can't just
give anything away anymore so none of
this stuff is easily to give away you
got to pay all the taxes on it the
excise tax you got to pay production
costs so it's extremely expensive to do
what you're saying in the modern world
we went at this as aggressively as
possible while we had the chance but
i think that until you're able to create
these
uh larger operations that can get some
of the prices down on genomically sorted
medical varieties on how we want to
define medical say it's in a specific
direction i don't use the word medical
variety very often i think it's it's all
cannabis it's how you use it
and so the i think the problem is that
when it comes to these lower income
people i i don't think america really
gives a shit because i had a step over
three homeless to get in here so when i
see homeless laying in the street i
don't think people really weren't about
providing cannabis to people
and we were caught up in it because we
were
we were caught up in it because we were
just sensitized to it because these are
people that you're around you see your
neighbors that need help so all of a
sudden it starts to make you more aware
then you have strangers come to you for
help and it makes you more aware but
we're in corporate cannabis in
california this is this is a different
animal kevin i give i give weed to
everybody out here on the street you do
oh hell yeah all right that's why the
guy was lying on the ground
lying on the ground no i mean we've
actually had weed church which is really
cool we're like on sunday like we like
sat down and we're just sitting there we
smoked a joint and the next thing you
know we're drawing mandalas on the road
inside but but but i definitely like
it's uh that's a hundred that's so good
we don't know well my ex-wife used to
say like i was the only person that
could because dr courtney gave me an ac
dc strain and i got it through jew
tillman and then all of a sudden i got
their phone numbers and everybody was
giving me the phone numbers they or they
gave
their my number to everyone else and my
ex-wife was like dude you figured out
how to turn our square footage into a
non-profit and i was like you know
because at the end of the day how do you
charge it's not just veterans because if
you want to do veterans i mean the
compassion programs that we're you know
supporting through cga and wheat the
weed for warriors program that's
extremely important to support that at
any cost i mean that the compassion
programs to stay alive the way it was
written in the state we just got the new
regs dropped we're allowed now to to
have to sign it we're now allowed to
give our you know to be destroyed
cannabis to compassion programs which is
great but um
further things like the you know not
supporting cbd isolate and hemp drive
cbd full spectrum cbd products um
because you have brands moving into the
cbd space and they're saying oh fuck it
it's available in an isolate form at
pennies in the dollar so you have people
like myself or drew tillman who were
running compassion programs where we
were giving away tons of cbd medicine to
two patients to children with epilepsy
or people with cancer or
anti-inflammatory conditions we were
autoimmunes and you know now we can't
because it i mean at the cost of you
know of regulation and the square
footage we're given we can't afford to
grow it anymore and so it and you know
if we were to sell it which i've never
sold cbd in my life either one of those
i could i just couldn't do it i wish
that there was a way to you know
maximize square footage but at the end
of the day you just can't do that you
can't sell it to kids
but you know now we have to support
those programs those compassion programs
we have to support you know
you know i i would i have to say
at you know
asking your local dispensaries asking
your local politicians and everyone you
know getting involved
in compassion is the biggest thing that
we have right now
because these big hemp companies are
coming in and they're just driving the
full spectrum out of you know out of
business and
yeah i don't mix two messages there but
don't buy cbd isolate we have the we
have the first we have the first farm
in oregon
uh
it's a hem farm
full they make
full spectrum cbd tincture uh and it's
the first cannabis farm that's a b corp
yeah and they're fucking awesome
b corp's good way to go yeah you know
the other way sin is legalization we got
to get more states to legalize simple as
that i mean uh
uh you know i think the oregon
experiment experiment
in a way
has resulted in 50 ounces
which which is pretty compassionate when
you you get down to fifty dollar rounds
we've been accidentally compassionate
yeah accidentally we didn't mean to be
so compassionate right right right but
but i but i do think more legalization
and i did i hear today that the
that the federal government finally said
cbd is now not scheduled not scheduled
yeah that is a big deal that's a very
big deal and and again we just we got to
make sure that whatever it goes into
you know we're able to control how it's
how it's done and unfortunately that not
so easy all right next next question did
that answer your question
yes okay okay
also you know just to say
thanks kevin
we're going to hold my hand now
i just wanted an excuse to hold his hand
i know you do it i love you so i usually
i just usually just take that anyway we
got like five minutes just to say so uh
recently you guys been talking about
shrinking profits you've been talking
about uh general education of the
consumer and stuff like that and
educating um you know your bud tenders
and stuff but as a like let's say you're
a dispensary owner you've got you carry
20 30 brands you know and you've got
let's say five bud tenders you know
let's say that brands were able to
afford sales reps and they were bringing
sales reps to your dispensary would you
have the time and would you be
able to
educate all of your employees
on 30 different brands um would you have
the space in your uh dispensary to allow
like literature of a general education
about your brand or about other brands
you know i think that a big issue is not
that dispensary owners can't they just
can't afford it you know there's a lot
of things that i'm not expensive i don't
know so i feel like you guys have
way more experience you know we we were
just talking about i got approached by a
bunch of my uh
partners that are farmers that don't
have stores and they asked me if i could
um move their product since we've
changed the classifications on where you
can sell and so my thing was i wanted
the farmers i wanted to send a rep with
me and so what it does is i can have a
mobile storefront so i can set up a
storefront at these different locations
that are allowed through whatever county
we do but i wanted the farmers to be
present someone from the farm to be
present from that brand it's it's a
crucial because what i i'm not trying to
be the face of the of their brand i'm
just trying to be someone who sells
their brand i want the farmer to make
the relationship with the customer we
just happen to be a one of the sellers
and then what it does it allows the
individuals who are coming to buy
cannabis to meet the farmers themselves
the farmers can then
educate these people and if you were
doing your job as a store owner then you
you you take the people that are your
blood tenders and you you do put them
through a system where you you bring
them to farms you bring them to farmers
you let them get a good exposure you got
to put in the homework
and
i think that it's easier for us where we
are because we have a proliferation of
craft people around us
and so it allows it a lot easier for us
to go up and check out if i'm going to
ganja rebels farm tuesday so i can check
out all his products we're going to
carry some exclusive work of his right
so i mean i know dan forever but i'm
gonna bring a couple of guys with me so
they can see what he's working with and
they can see his new product line so
then this way they're educated on you
know why we think it's good and why we
think the public should enjoy some of it
and it would have you know gradients of
potency different profiles
so that you have a true um
uh
choice selection
but it's though it's the dispensary
owner's job
to educate the people who work in the
facility so they know enough and that
that's about your commitment to the
industry long term
i think that with a lot of stores it's
just if you're in a good geographic area
you get a lot of turnaround people
coming through i don't think that
emphasis is placed as much i think that
um jeremy's dispensary in oregon uh
pharma i think that he shines at this
every monday the whole staff sits down
and they bring a scientist in to talk to
them yeah you know he shines he's got a
really really good thing and oregon is
pretty unique in that way where i think
oregon has a more developed craft system
than california does by far
and
even though california is the monster of
the game oregon has a different level of
appreciation of the finite details of
the product and i think that when i go
and tour spots in in oregon i see a
higher level of knowledge from the
people but it's also they can be more
intimate because you can also touch and
play with the cannabis direct california
is different peter that's your sound by
right now california's different
california you don't get a chance to
touch this product and so that's where
you have to bring your workers that work
for you to the location so they can
actually see these products and get
exposed to it and the idea is to try to
find a cluster of farms that you can
work with that can provide you with
product right now it's brutal because
you only have so many farms that are
online and distribution controls a lot
of it and it makes it very difficult for
you to i used to focus on on local only
right so i i was a local only guy for
years
and we were known for that where we
worked so hard to develop all these
smaller brands where we would advertise
for you we would actually create your
brand
because we had the ability i had the
money and i had the resources and so
what it did is it allowed us to further
and people ask why and i said because
fundamentally i want to get their
product because it's a better product
and if i can keep them alive then i can
keep selling their product but that
means we have to have a relationship in
that form where the store owner and the
farmer believe they're connected now
no one gives a shit who you are it's i
just need product on the shelf
and so that's a a very transient type of
thought where it's anybody on the shelf
is fine and it can't be viewed in that
way and so if you're a smaller operator
and you have an ability to
choose farms that you work with based
off of the ethics that you believe that
they should grow with and you have
enough of them to give you a product
diversity and you have enough of them to
be able to give you sustainability over
the course of a fiscal year then you can
actually get a knowledge base on that
and then you have to hold that line
where you focus on those products and
those things
and that that requires
a different view of cannabis business
and i would say 85 percent of the
businesses in cannabis right now are
here just to grab the cash yeah so kevin
you know i don't fault it but i don't
think it's the right way to go we
identified that kink in the supply chain
with the exchange so we created that
emerald outpost so what we now
aggregated 25 plus brands we aggregate
all the brands in northern california if
you want what we've done is we've taken
ambassadors and and we've only linked
four to five farms like five being max
so that ambassador actually knows those
five brands in and out comes up to the
farm knows everyone visits the farm and
they can come down to the dispensary as
soon as we eclipse five brands per
ambassador we add another ambassador the
brands pay for the ambassador they pay
us a
referral fee similar to brokering like
we're brokers essentially we're not
distributors we saw that these these
products were just being dumped into
distributors we were visiting the
distributors because we were trying to
get the distributors into the exchange
we're visiting these distributors and
we're like holy crap you've got all this
shit sitting there what are you doing
with it our friends and neighbors aren't
getting paid no one's getting paid and
who the fuck is selling this and no one
from the distribution company they
couldn't they had two three guys out
there with you know two 400 skate skus
on the shelves so the idea is it's like
the brands
then pay the ambassadors the ambassadors
go to the dispensaries
exactly and then eventually what we're
going to be doing once we allow for
on-site consumption after 20 you know
after the january the 2020 passed that
we're going to start bringing all the
dispensary owners and everyone up there
for full experience driven tourism
models through the exchange and have
that like full you know the the full
gamut you know for the for the brands
themselves but yeah i mean it is it is a
thing it's like you right now it's just
another job that we've got we got to
keep on we got to keep on moving we
cannot sit and let weeds sit on the
shelves in northern california that is
our bread and butter that is that is our
mortgage payment that feeds our dog you
know what i'm saying like that is our
gas money is sitting on the shelves of
the distributor some somewhere in l.a
that sucks but you bring up a good point
though the dispensary has a much bigger
responsibility than they're taking on
yeah they want to make money exactly but
you know when you go in there and you're
waiting to get in
there should be some better reading
material and the crap that's sitting on
it there should be teaming with microbes
you know i mean
but but there should be better reading
material there should be the regulatory
agency should be helping with the
education when you leave dispensaries
you get the little card that says you
know if you're pregnant uh you know
there's all that kind of stuff that that
they force on us they could also force
on us a little education you need to
know terpenes you need to know the
numbers so just just you know
we're making a little science but
we're going to give it out to
dispensaries there you go it's going to
be like weed science for a civilian
right a little pamphlet we use your
galaxy at the nursery so at the nursery
i got i got a 40 inch flat screen on the
wall that just has the galaxy on it
right because we have a tremendous
number of strains mapped
and what it does it allows people to
come in and start to see these
relationships between varietals and they
can start to get their mind peaked on
hey these things are connected because
really that
you sometimes you can only find certain
things certain places but you want to
find something similar and so what we
want to be able to do is get you to
understand hey these things are related
they're close and that way when you're
in la you might be able to find
something that works for you like you
did in mendocino or in humboldt or in
siskiyou or wherever you're at because
what you're trying to do is you're
trying to get the individual who's
buying the product to enjoy the
experience of buying the product
and in that process they start to become
educated but if you make it miserable
and i'm telling you right now i'm
somebody who loves to read most people
don't like to read the damn thing
anymore so that's why i shoot so much
video because people really want it
delivered
and what you can do then is you can give
i give them all the strain info so all
the varieties i give you a full digital
breakdown of everything we're touching
so this way you can go home and look at
it and come back and say hey i want to
cultivate this i want to do that and i
think that has to be done with a lot of
the the strains themselves most of the
videos you see people smoking weed it
just doesn't give you the info you need
and that has to be done from from a
stability sense where it's easier as a
nursery because i control the the
material right so i i have this material
i can say look we're going to run it for
this many years we have it but with
purchasing products
it's constantly new turnover and that's
why i think that a lot of the stores you
have to kind of limit what you actually
carry i would rather see less choices at
a shop but better curated choices
so that you have a a better stability on
on how you sell it and what you know
about it yes and what you know about it
so that you can really give a
satisfaction to the user and then what
they do is they become educated and they
go to any shop and use that education so
not just us if you think about the way
wine works
like if you're a waiter in a restaurant
and then you have a good wine list
so that's that's how i got to be a weed
scientist right i was a waiter for a
long time
um
but you work in a restaurant that has a
decent wine list
like you have to go to the tables all
night long and you have to talk shit
about the wine
and you have to have some idea what
you're talking about and so a good
restaurant owner
every time there's a wine delivery
they sit down with their entire wade
staff or the or the person from the wine
company and you taste everything and you
talk about it and you learn about it and
then when you go to the tables
you're not an idiot and you can actually
steer people towards something they like
and if you don't steer them towards the
thing they like
you know then you don't make as much
money
but it's just like it should be like
that at dispensaries like you have to
educate yourself to sell something to
somebody it's hard with the weed though
because with wine you can spit that shit
out but with cannabis you're not
spitting that shit out you're high and
so that's where like me and the wine
industry have beef because
we're training the bartenders to go like
this
that's how elon musk smokes
and and the the thing is you know the
individuals that's why that's why i
believe that the farmer
i think that that's what we're trying to
do in our own world is and it's it's the
only way i can see this really taking
place is that you start to have the
farmers come into your facility more
frequently they're present you advertise
for them to be present it allows
individuals to start to meet the
individuals who produce the product
they're able they're actually able to
consume with you off the site because
they they have an ability to have an
ounce legally on i mean this all has to
work in legal shit everything we based
our whole world off of was illegal so i
mean i'm somebody who's trying to figure
out how do you not step in a legal bear
trap and lose your license
and so much of it is to let the farmers
come in they can have an ounce in their
hand that they're allowed to show you
outside that outside the room you can
have a separate area where people can
look at products it can't be through the
store you can't open that product that
product has to leave in a sealed bag all
the criteria in california make it very
very hard to have an intimate experience
change it with what we did then i and i
feel you change it sounds great now go
do that guy but you're doing it but
you're doing it i know but i'm not doing
it quick enough you're going to be able
to do on-site consumption some places
it's it's all about zoning and it's
about your county and so just like
someone says we're california's legal no
it's not go to go to uh calaveras and
tell me it's legal so
it it's a radically different situation
depending where you are geographically
and because of that you have to be able
to find the loopholes that allow you to
do it now or you won't be in business in
a year to do it when it does change
and that's why i think that you have to
be able to get your producers to come
into the place
and meet the meet the meet the buyers
themselves
and just make it casual to where it's a
frequent situation i mean i'm lucky in
the sense that the people that we have
at my shop are career so i pick career
people people that have been smoking for
a while and i bring in older people i
have 70 year old women that work for me
because i think that they're the most
knowledgeable about medical cannabis of
anybody i know they know how to do
holistic cannabis work better than
anybody
and so i i need that type of situation
to occur in my world so that when people
come in and are asking for how do you
use this you can actually get people who
have been helping people for 20 30 years
with with medical type needs
but with with the farmer coming in
the farmer is the only one that's going
to be able to get you to tie into this
and understand it or otherwise the blood
tenders they they have to be able to
serve as like a liaison but they don't
have to be hyper knowledgeable to the
degree where they know every single
product because not every one of them
wants to so you can get someone who's
phenomenal at customer service but they
don't they only smoke very very low
potency weed and if they do they smoke a
little bit of it at night when they go
to bed so how the hell are they going to
help you out selling any of these other
products they can't and it makes it look
like they're incompetent but they're not
they're phenomenal representatives of
your company and they're and they're
great with people it's just that you
need to be able to bring in other people
that can explain
why they chose this why did you choose
you know orange chewy berry because it
makes this happen for me and then these
people and this is my antidotal this
number of people worked when we looked
at the terp profiles and the potency we
found it had unique ratios and it had
unique cannabinoid
compounds that we didn't see in other
things that's the education that lets
the buyer realize hey that's what that's
what affected me now they know they can
find similarities in other things you're
trying to give them an education not
just to buy stuff from you or from the
farmers that you're selling for but
you're trying to give an education to
any store they walk in they have skills
and then any farmer they go to they have
an ability to work with
because that's industry building you
know it's not just you and one farmers
you're trying to build a new industry
but it's very difficult to do it the way
we did it where you could have an
intimate relationship with the flower
where you could open it up touch it
smell it look it christ we had a secret
smoke lounge for years people smoking
down i can't do that anymore i mean
they're going through my garbage they
dump out my trap i've had the bcc in my
my new shop three times since july
three times and we've nev we've never
had any problems but i'm talking they're
dumping the trash out combing the god
damn trash
so when they're going through your trash
and that's part of their that's part of
their they're allowed to it makes it
very hard to to do anything that's not
within a complete regulatory scheme
and so you have to get around it by
bringing in other people from the
outside that have an ability to be able
to start making these connections and i
think that's where together as a culture
we should do well because we've
historically been pretty cool even
though we may not have done a lot of
business you know intimately we did
business when we needed to to make the
make the pounds move
and we historically got along in a
pretty gentle
caring method and i think that's the
part that you have to bring forward to
the public that they realize well i got
you cannabis was always this kind of
situation and then that elevates him and
lets him realize i got you i have to
change the way i purchase i don't just
look at it to snap it up off the shelf i
actually take a second to get an
education on it so this way i know what
i'm looking for and then i can go and
find it at other places and if we all
had a
common you know
i'd say objective like that you'd see a
radically different change in how people
perceived what they bought and how much
they were willing to pay for what they
bought
that dog
hello so i actually don't grow cannabis
i uh grow bugs to kill bad bugs on your
cannabis farm
so
uh in conventional agriculture uh
one big thing that happens is a
globalization of pests uh asian citrus
psyllid on citrus right now we have
lanternflies eating up entire vineyards
over on the east coast
so
at what point is uh pest resistance
gonna become more than a novelty and uh
creating cultivars of uh cannabis and
also on top of that what's the most
susceptible strain that you've ever
grown like what's the drosophila that we
can test things on
so
go ahead
so so we're
so we're working on pm first right so
we've collected
a bunch of incredibly susceptible
varieties and a cup and a bunch of
varieties that have really high
resistance
we've sequenced the dna of pm varieties
from around the country
so that we know when we're looking at pm
which strain of pm it is because there's
a bunch of different ones
we built a detached leaf assay so
instead of running a breeding program
for pm in a in a building that you have
to saturate and mold
we can we can run it in a clean building
and pull off a leaf and take it into the
lab and inoculate it with a known
quantity a pm and then quantitatively
assess resistance
so we're on it
we're on it but it will take a little
while and then we've got to do botrytis
and then we've got to do fusarium so
like
we just didn't have a way to do this
stuff scientifically before
but um
now we can do it and then once you have
a genetic marker for pm resistance you
can put that on all the backgrounds you
want
so sorry
two parts one is i'll give you
i got a question for you
um
because we just had this crystal ortiz
and i just had this conversation she had
a uh she had a
root aphid no i think it was a it might
have been a russet might that they got
onto her plants so she she brought in
predatory mites she does dry farming all
organic beyond organic regenerative farm
beautiful beautiful garden
she introduces a predator she predatory
might right gets in works gets rid of
the you know
stabilizes the environment
next year she does it as prevention
right
she's working really well she's at what
point in time does the introduction of
this predatory might
be start to shift the natural
environment of of my of my entire garden
when does the predatory might start to
breed and then take over in in in the
area so i think it was like a question
for you is like have you done research
on how to stop because i know the pike
minnow when it was introduced into the
eel
right to kill to to kill mosquitoes
ended up eating all the salmon eggs and
so then they had this like huge like no
steelhead
because they had introduced the
pikeminnow to kill the to kill the um
you know to kill the mosquito so
question to you is what
how do you stop a predatory mite from
from breeding to
ravage a a you know a garden called
flora culture or when we're working on
the smaller scale like uh praying mantis
for example there are barely any pray
manta species that are actually native
to the united states everything that you
see is a chinese mantis but on the
smaller scale everything is incredibly
finicky so if there's no food there
the mites not going to exist same thing
with uh parasitic wasps and peristic
wasps are one of the greatest fire
controls out there because without the
pest there's no parasite so so they kill
the pest and then they die because their
food is gone yeah that's why you have to
re-inoculate every year like if you're
using oxidantalis you're using
persimilis like persimilis doesn't even
survive year to year half the time just
because at some point the uh
spider mites will go into diapause and
then once they're in diapolos they're in
the soil
and ones go into the soil the other
one's going right to the top of the
plant
so if you pre-inoculate that might not
even work because there if there's no
food there they'll just die right away
and they won't be there when the mites
do show up is that true
that is true and there are solutions to
this providing enough food for them you
can provide pollen for certain species
they'll feed off the pollen until
there's a better food source out there
or you can really just introduce a mite
that actually doesn't really do anything
to your crop it's just kind of there
generally so
official source yeah it's kind of like
really
you're giving a dog some food in a bowl
and the food isn't gonna get up and
crawl away and start eating all
everything around yeah yeah all right
the uh we gotta wrap it up on that uh
because there is a evidently a line of
people upstairs waiting to get down here
to listen to dj who
uh oh it's a whole band night um but
there'll be live music and i i think my
guests are free to stay if they're yeah
but there there's some reggae meets punk
meets
the guy from dub club boss harmony yeah
all right
so we call it
this is like the the like end of episode
one
and we'll to be continued on pest
management but i appreciate everybody
coming hope you learned a lot a round of
applause for
our panelist the marathon panel
you made it the whole time
all right thank you all very much
[Music]
you