I uh you know I want to say something
about legalization you know I'm it's a
big mess in California and a lot of
people are suffering but I'm really I'm
really proud to say that I've been
involved in the legalization and don't
use our full Terrell no in this mess it
is you know and I get and I do but
nonetheless a lot of less people are
going to jail yeah well there was our
priority now exactly a regulation or
legalization whatever you want to call
it exactly out there now yeah we are
I remember eight years ago and during
the high times cup I declared the war on
drugs that we want it yeah run the war
on drugs
uh-huh yeah a little-little event a
little ahead of your time when
Goldsberry and Steve DeAngelo started
all the dispensaries you know man yeah
yeah but you know we're still not fully
legal in America so no but I think 2020
it will happen don't terms gonna pull
the cards you think so yes and all the
democratic people on the east and west
coast and are not really big fan of him
are gonna vote for him no yes all of
them I'm a Democrat from New York that
ain't gonna happen
well five percent is gonna say oh yeah
you're maybe a cool guy because you're
gonna legalize marijuana now you getting
my vote because you know the Democrats
didn't do a lot of good things for us
huh no no politician isn't it that Bill
Clinton put more people in prison than
anybody else from marijuana yeah okay
yeah so yeah well what do we say about
that done we're gonna leave the DT name
out of this but let's not go to in
politics right right so you know on the
the global scale of legalization you
know you travel a lot more than I do
what so what can you tell us about the
global legalization seem well if you
look at Europe you know especially
Holland it was the leader for many many
years I think to take it from there
world's biggest economic disaster ever I
think a country threw away a whole
industry
that could have been leaders worldwide
which are now the Americans and Canadian
companies Holland could have could have
been that and we fucked it up so we
threw away a hundred billion dollar
prosperity in the next ten years so and
then the rest of Europe
slowly slowly coming well you know
you've been in my clubs in Spain sure
there is there's a little bit movement
there there's a little bit movement in
Italy with CVD shops there's a little
bit moving in Switzerland we're moving
to Africa now as you know we have a
license in the suit that we have a
license in Congo who slowly we're
opening up so who opening the boundaries
in Africa which is a really good thing
as a matter of fact South Africa
I'm from Zambia but South Africa just
two weeks ago
hi Supreme Court allowed personal use
which opens a lot of doors I did hear
something about that is very very good
thing
Portugal Europe also so South America
well South America you know now Chile
Colombia giving license
Argentina willing to change who I was
the first one I was one of the personal
advisers of president Mujica as I mean
all of and I could we were there three
times Paraguay Heiko just came from
Paraguay a month ago Brazil eight
license more license are in the Uruguay
no or ago I was the first one I realize
right now I'm talking about part of what
ones yes Paraguay to us and Brazil so
look the main thing is what we're
waiting for is America has to change on
a federal level yes
Canada did America is going to go yes we
will I think 2020 hope hopefully at
least that there will be a letter from
the from the government declaring all
states do whatever they want also on a
recreational level which means that
banks and other important assets for us
can come into the industry scheduling
these scheduling will happen and that
will make that will make the rest of the
world change a little bit faster that's
what we are waiting for I think I mean
that's what that's what it's all been
about for me is
the normalization and the legalization
of cannabis use I moved to California
about 17 years ago for the sole reason
of not being a criminal for the first
time in my life I remember the reason
why I moved to question 25 years ago why
don't you go there where it's easy you
remember you know I made it happen and
so California is a lovely place on those
on fire right now
I wish prayers to everybody that's vacu
ate their homes and such but that's why
we've been alban here and that's why i'm
i can say that i'm proud to be your
friend because we we've always
championed the legalization yeah and the
normalization of cannabis use we're not
criminals we're no different from
anybody else
in fact you people are all crazy if you
don't want to try a little cannabis well
you know my we've been very big
activists you know we've been i've been
15 years chairman of the cannabis retail
Association Holland I advise still
mayors you're him our partner you know
you're very well he's still advising the
government we change the law in Dutch
parliament last year together with one
political party it went through the
second Parliament which is really really
good I think it's our duty as a human
being and to be in the forefront with
all our knowledge and to be an activist
and to help legalize and for many many
reasons and for most important reason is
decriminalization and health I think
within 10 to 20 years we will all be
eating oil and it will prevent us
getting sick in 80% of the cases sure
you know we know now this oil is a great
product we know it stops in some cases
the dividing of aggressive cells that's
right of cancer cells
well yeah whatever so and it's a very
good kind of antioxidant for the body
and that's just the medicinal properties
of cannabis and then you get into the
the hemp seed itself go get into the
hemp seed itself which is a great
foodstuff yeah we're all we're all
lacking in DFAS
and so you know legalization and
spreading it around the world has been a
privilege and an honor for myself and
getting to know you as young bucks as we
were and now I look at you you're not
even great yet what's wrong with you I
smoked greenhouse sheets and marijuana
oh it's a new tagline you will never go
gray smoke greenhouse
[Laughter]
[Music]