[Music]
Tim Blake has several cannabis
businesses he's working on and he's
going to talk to us about manufacturing
today and then Amanda will talk about
flow Cana and distribution okay well
thank you and for the Emerald cup we
will have our license this year I feel
sorry for high times in some ways but
but as far as us we're working with the
state and we're working with Main Street
strategies and we're proactive and we're
way in front and they really love what
the cup has done and we will have a
license and be doing very well with the
cup this year so as far as manufacturing
you know you talked about the cup when
we first started it was flowers you know
later on we bunny did the concentrates
cold water and stuff and over the years
now you've seen that evolved to where
the flowers are really a small part of
the cup yeah like you know twenty other
contests going on and so what you're
looking at is the flowers becoming a
smaller smaller part of the whole
industry you know eventually it'll be
probably less than ten percent if you
look at people coming out with the
cartridges and now they're getting so
good all of a sudden you get the Terps
they burn right or vaporize right and
they work all the way down so people are
getting very accustomed to that and so
what you're seeing with manufacturing is
everything's going to be extracted you
know you talk about its oil fields now
it's not even flower fields anymore
they're called oil fields and that's a
new term that's coming out and so what
you've got is you get different forms of
extraction coming out you know back in
the day we're doing cold water
we were only solvent list we wouldn't do
anything at the cup with hydrocarbons or
because of the legal issues and people
blown themselves up and then using a you
know mystery gas in the cans
well that's changed now now you've got
systems that are like a million dollars
coming out that'll go to your field and
process like twenty five hundred pounds
in a day and just bring that out I mean
they're like million dollar hydrocarbon
machines and with the state going legal
with that you've got these different
forms of extraction coming out so you've
got the traditional
alcohol you've got co2 which people are
using a lot of and then you've got
hydrocarbon with XA in propane and
butane we have a new manufacturing plant
right outside of the Willis City Limits
and we're actually I was talking with
John McGowan the lead supervisor we're
going to apply for type seven and do
hydrocarbon I explained to John why it
first of all it's got the purge systems
get rid of it all you've got
pharmaceutical grade hydrocarbons and
then you've also got recirculating
systems where they're using almost none
of the material it's all being recycled
so we're gonna use all ways of
extraction to go into our products we're
still going to be based as much as we
can
solvent list but the industry is moving
very quickly in that direction and so
what what's happening with all these
manufacturing places let's look at the
whole world and we'll bring it back to
where we are really quickly in the world
you've got all these companies in the
countries going legal you've got Jamaica
you got Czechoslovakia again you got
Uruguay you know Colombia Colombia took
our flowers 40 years ago traditional
flowers they're gonna come after all of
our cannabis flowers right now you got
Jamaica you got other places what's the
big company the big boy in the box it's
Canada first g7 nation that's going to
distribute worldwide they've gone
recreational completely they're now in
talks to licence 150 products that can
go worldwide they just shipped Aurora
can imagine shipped to Italy they're
going to Germany you got the Israelis
taking over the medicinal market and
they're going to ship all over the world
medicinally they've been out in front of
us about 20 years and so if we look at
it while we're sitting here trying to
fight our way out of a box in this
county in California the rest of the
world is so quickly moving beyond us
it's gonna it's going to take forever to
catch up now there's good parts of that
we'll get back to but for right now
we're looking at the manufacturing of
these products throughout the world and
that's what they're doing they're
manufacturing oils they're not really
setting flowers so what do we do in this
country we send all of our manufacturing
off sure we don't have any manufacture
anymore the great thing is is that
cannabis really along with SpaceX with
musk what he's doing and Tesla we're
gonna actually bring manufacturing back
to this country and cannabis is going to
be the biggest growth industry
manufacturing wise and distribution wise
of any product of anything in the world
over the next 30 years so we're gonna
really lead the way it it's all going to
be manufactured products but we have to
find out where we fit in that rule
and right now we're losing a giant share
to Canada really and the Israelis and
their we're going to take that so then
you fall back to what we're doing in the
States
okay well what's in the state happening
is we're filing for a manufacturing
permit and cultivation permit in
Pennsylvania you got to have two hundred
fifty thousand dollars to apply you got
a million dollars in the bank and you
got to know somebody we're actually
working with a attorney who's a former
DEA agent and it's interesting about my
position being where I come my whole
life I'm talking about the DEA agent he
and he was funny he wanted to know if if
we were going to be legal enough and
follow the guidelines and I had
explained to it what we've done with the
the sheriff surveys with Tom Allman up
at area 101 and all the activism and
stuff and that we we're no problem with
that so check this out and so we have an
attorney DEA agent helping us get a
manufacturing license in Pennsylvania
because you have to be in West Coast and
East Coast the rest of the states are
gonna really chew this up very quickly
if we don't and I mean you look at
Washington Colorado all over the East
Coast and so we're not only losing our
black-market flowers we're gonna lose
our black market cotton well forget the
black market the other market cartridges
and the other forms of manufacturing if
we don't move very very quickly and so
we we really have an uphill battle in
many ways now you peel it back to the to
the local situation that we've got here
and you know it goes back to people are
saying I'm Floquet know we all want to
represent small farmers and I say that's
what the air moan cup is to but really
there should be a new phrase that comes
out we want to represent we want to rip
well we are representing the best of
small farmers because at the end of the
day that's all you can represent when
Mikey can't even from cloak Anna and
wanted to represent all the small
farmers I said we already did that with
with Mendocino farmers collective and I
had a collective up at area 101 and what
happened was we took 50 people's
cannabis flowers and realized that only
five retainer that would actually sell
and we had to give it all back and then
we had to realize we had to cherry pick
just like the black market is because
you just can't take it and nowadays
everybody knows you try to sell be great
black market people don't even want be
great oh geez not even if they're seven
or eight 600 hours a pound they don't
even want it they just want the finest
it move my be great OG to a high grade
flour
with you know perps or something any day
so it's the same at manufacturing if
you're going to go to manufacturing
system you have to have incredible
medicines that come out of there and so
even if it's going into an edible even
if it's going into a tincture of SAP
it's still product in product out and
you know this isolate this hemp you know
materials that they're doing for CVD
it's all garbage and they're already
talking about all over the country so
you've got you look at Fred from CVD
Mendo or Russell back there from CVD
healing medicines they're all growing
biodynamic they're growing high-grade
organic organic flowers and and medicine
and so whether it's flow canna is
manufacturing you're gonna have flow
Khanna's can imagine fashioning in rugby
valley we're gonna have three or four in
Willets here you're gonna one of your
chi you know about ten manufacturing
plants in Mendocino County alone how
many of those will make money probably
only a couple there's over a hundred and
something permits for manufacturing
almost all are type seven right now and
so we're going to be competing against
major manufacturers throughout the state
but it still comes down to their product
so for you guys what matters I mean I
guess on the manufacturing side is we're
gonna do a product and you want a white
label with somebody like us with low
canna
you're gonna have to have the finest
product or you don't even have a chance
I mean Amanda can tell you if you look
at the distribution companies I could go
into all that whole thing - you've got
River who's our distribution company
just merged with Canada royalty you've
got distribution merging left and right
and you're gonna do the same thing in
manufacturing and it's consolidate down
and the only people are going to really
be able to have a manufactured product
to go out are people that have something
phenomenal people that love doing social
media people that have deep pockets
people that are great marketing people
otherwise you're not going to
manufacture a product but if you make a
good product you could work with Floquet
know you could work with us you could
work with somebody else and do
co-branding you could do white label you
can end up selling the product to us and
we could do something together there's
ways to go about it but it's really
going to start with you know some type
of really fine product or you're gonna
drop down into being an oil producer for
you know concentrates and extracts now
they're you know what that's not a bad
living in there you started thinking
about it I mean I haven't done all the
numbers but we run them around and stuff
if you're really good you know get
depths and you bring it in 50
pounds a-year you look you're selling
for 300 bucks you know by time you pay
your taxes and everything else you got
all your workers in there
you can still make 75 to 125 grand a
year if you're good and you know what
you're only working six months of the
year people are coming to picking it up
you're not really trimming it caring at
dealing with all the issues and you get
the rest of the year off so you know
there is a world and life out there for
cultivators delivering just to
manufacturers because what you're going
to see is people going up these fields
with the their even got co2 machines
will go out there now too and going into
the fields and just basically harvesting
it right there and but you really need
to have the right strange to go with
that - I mean we go into a whole thing
about yeah when you're manufacturing
products you got to get quantity and you
got to get quality you got to get the
terpenes so you have to have the right
strains and nobody wants edgy you know
anymore you look at it they're looking
for turps and fine things so on a
manufacturing level this county is going
to do really good manufacturing there's
something else I want to say before I
lost my time we find the distributor's
that down in LA nobody cares about
general triangle or organic solvent list
they care about snap crackle and pop you
know who care about sauce and butane and
stuff and Shatter they were talking
about I think it's true we're gonna have
a better time with Emerald triangle
products and flowers once we get out of
this box and get out of this state and
get across the country and across the
world because they're the Emerald
triangle name has real value people will
want that so there's real hope for our
products and our flowers as we bust out
and we compete against the international
markets and it just comes down to not
only that flower being a degrade but
really having an incredible product that
goes with it so work with a great
manufacturer work with a great
distributor and you've got a chance and
make a great product and you'll be there
thank you very much I'm just gonna talk
a little bit about advocacy and
distribution as kind of a social justice
piece of the supply chain I did not mean
to say that they're mutually exclusive
so yes of course advocacy continues yes
and so I just wanted to talk a little
bit about how flokati evolved because a
lot of times when we look at what's
going on with agriculture and business
in general in the United States it's
very top-down right so it's the folk
have a lot of money making decisions
about how they can make more money by
infiltrating their power down to the
people who have very little control over
their situation how we grew up was
really kind of the opposite you know we
started as a delivery service in the Bay
Area and we were sourcing product from
farmers in the Emerald triangle our
founder Michael Steinmetz had come up
here and visited with farms and really
saw the magic you know having been here
from South America had a lot of
appreciation for small agriculture and
agricultural cooperatives and so the
idea was that we really what was
happening here was special and how do
you get that to the public and that's
really at the core of what a distributor
is supposed to do they're supposed to
find things that are special and figure
out how to get it to the public and I'll
talk a little bit more about what that
looks like in a scenario where you're
like a branded distribution company like
flow Cana
or if you're just providing things for
the shelves because they're two very
different models and I think that one
model serves this region a lot better
than the other but we were working with
small farmers and they were telling us
about some of their barriers in getting
to market and one of those barriers was
placed were places to safely store their
product where they had temperature and
humidity control it was a place to trim
their product where they felt like they
weren't in in risk of things getting
contaminated and it was a way to
actually get their product into
dispensaries without having to go to LA
and to San Diego in two different places
across the state and work with
dispensary owners one on one and so
hearing these barriers from working with
them as a delivery company as we started
to work more into wholesale we started
to think how do we address some of those
barriers how do we make it easier to get
these folks to market again what a
distributor is supposed to be thinking
about but this is before we were really
a distributor and so that was really the
idea for the campus in Redwood Valley
was the idea that if we built a facility
kind of like built go where the people
are philosophy if we went to where the
farmers were and we built a facility
that was licensed to do the
manufacturing the trimming the
processing the packaging the
testing and then we had a way to take
their product downstream and had people
on that end that could do the and brand
ambassador and go to the dispensaries
and do the social media and really push
the things that the farmers may have an
interested may not have an interest in
but are really busy being farmers and
going through the licensing process so
the idea to bring centralized processing
and bring this facility was really born
out of the needs we saw from the farmer
versus people saying you know what we
want to have a successful distribution
company we need to get source where do
we get source from and so I think that
that's why this type of distribution
model has the ability to actually
disrupt big agriculture and I think that
if distributors work together and really
focus on the types of brands and the
types of people that we want to see in
the marketplace and really advocating
for what quality truly is that quality
isn't necessarily THC level and quality
isn't necessarily orange hairs that it's
terpenoid and cannabinoid profile it's
how the product was grown it's the
amount of product that that person
produces a year if we have distributors
that understand this and advocate for
this that's going to make the whole
supply chain take the intent of the
farmer and translate it all the way
through to the market because when a
distributor is talking to a dispensary
owner about why sun-grown is better
about why Mendocino is special that's
going to translate into how that product
is marketed in the dispensary so I
absolutely think that distribution can
be a social advocacy if distributors
decide that they're going to stick to a
certain brand that their brand is small
producers for example so if you decide
that you're only going to distribute
people that produce under a certain
amount a year that's your brand and
anyone that knows that if they're
getting product from you that represents
something in the sphere of manufactured
products so I think it's important that
we use this these business structures
and these opportunities to continue to
try to create the landscape that we want
to see in the cannabis world and you
know playing off of something
Tim said about the global economy of
cannabis which is coming Canada wants to
own us all and they're all gonna be it's
beautiful I do but but but I'm telling
you they are really come that's where
big businesses right now and I feel like
we're fighting each other a lot in
California this is kind of my little
soapbox I feel like we're fighting each
other a lot in California and while
we're doing that like the Mounties are
coming and so we need to start banding
together and realize that in short order
cannabis is going to be a global
commodity when that happens the Emerald
triangle is going to be a teeny tiny
speck in that global landscape and if we
can establish now through a unified
voice that we are the quality that we
are the craft then we will have the
biggest share of the market for that
level of product the product Tim's
talking about you know the really world
premiere high-class product that we have
here in this region of the world so we
have to work together on that and we
have to work together through branding
we have to work together through
marketing I want to mention that I think
out on the table is forms to join the
Mendocino cannabis Industry Association
and risk let's say like a second about
that
so membership is $200 for a year and we
work with a lot of allied organizations
so we basically work on promotion and
branding of products that are produced
in Mendocino County so we work with the
county promotional alliances and tourism
boards we work with the Mendocino
Appalachians project and other groups
that are trying to work on specific
branding to this region we work on state
policies that enable things like event
licenses and farmers to do direct sales
so you know if you're really interested
in Mendocino industry and really
protecting the brand of Mendocino County
I think it's important that we really
have unity so I think the last thing I
wanted to say was about the idea of
challenging big AG so right now
agriculture in the United States as many
of you know is very monoculture
it's not using diversification it's
definitely not using regenerative
practices and we're all suffering for
that cannabis because a prohibition has
had the benefit of having grown up in a
place of ingenuity creativity
sustainability having to be hidden and
being off the grid which is a pain at
the ass but at the same time a model for
how we should all move forward and so I
think it's important that also through
our distributor work through our
processing work through all the work
that we do at every level in business
license we really have to remember that
we have an opportunity to challenge the
agricultural model so we're trying to do
that with the centralized processing in
campus the idea that farmers have the
ability to scale up by sharing these
costs by moving these costs off the farm
is very very different than what we see
in industrialized agriculture as is the
push for regenerative farming practices
so we're working on a regenerated
standard for farmers to help them move
towards closed-loop systems to help them
learn how to use beneficial insects and
compost teas and the things that we know
are good for the earth and that we want
to be part of the brand of what is
quality cannabis so it really all fits
together and it all fits in really well
with Mendocino County a place that
banned all GMOs a place where everyone's
a craft farmer because no one's allowed
to have more than ten thousand square
feet which we should totally use in our
branding and so we have a huge
opportunity and so I'm hopeful that
companies like Flo Cana can be helpful
in not only building the brand but
really allowing you know a thousand
farmers to flourish underneath the
support because at the end of the day in
every single market across agriculture
it's the small the craft the organic the
small batch the individually loved and
produced product that is the quality and
that's who we are
here in Mendocino County the market may
not be reflective of that yet people are
still learning and that's why it's
really important we remember that we're
still activists and advocates even when
we're talking about this
so I will leave it there alright great
well thank you so much Amanda Ryman Tim
you sounded like you had a comment when
she was talking about I'm with her on
the mound he's coming right at us
I have nothing against Canadians I have
a lot of friends or Canadians we might
even have been in a partnership with
some Canadians but you're looking at
kanima Doge with Aurora became a 1.2
billion dollar company you're seeing
Kronos you're seeing these companies
that are becoming gigantic I was hearing
somebody there to buying airports so
they can transport this stuff around the
world not have people in their way
and so it's it really is a global market
that's coming and it's when you step
back and look at us we're sitting here
at 10,000 square feet and you know Santa
Barbara's got 15 acre farms and stuff
it's absolutely absurd that our
supervisors haven't moved to the half
acre level or even one acre really it's
ridiculous and just open up this whole
thing now we're here in the heart of the
Emerald triangle and we're being
restricted so heavily well the rest of
the world is just coming right at us and
my hats off the case is they they knew
what it was and they took advantage of
it and they're going to be the ones that
are be remembered as the kings of
cannabis and queens I have a question
about processing this year I mean this
year seems to be such a transition year
and people will have their first light
up harvests coming in mid-july what's
going to happen to that product if
there's not enough processing farms that
are licensed to process their own that
can can process it all on their own
because of different restrictions with
with coating are there will flow Cana
have a processing center and do you
think there are enough around in
Mendocino both of you so we do have a
processing center in Redwood Valley that
opened officially about a week ago and
we're hiring so if anyone is interested
in being a processing a processor for
flow con you can go to our website and
fill out an application and we need
people because there's a lot of cannabis
to process the thing about processing is
that there are very strict standards
from Cal OSHA about worker environment
and so it's very different than
sitting at a table maybe even with a
little mask on you know it has to be a
completely clean room and people have to
be wearing gloves and hair nuts and
everything has to be sterile and so I
think that it's hard for a lot of
farmers to come up to that standard even
if the regulations allow them to trim on
their farm this season it's going to be
tough to do it in a way that's going to
satisfy some of the state requirements
so I think there should be more places
like flow Cana and I think it can be a
version of that so if there's a bunch of
farmers that you want to get together
and purchase a small building that's
kind of easy to build out into that type
of room and then share the expense that
may work better than trying to do make
each individual farm license to do that
so I think that there's ways that people
can try to work together but I think
that centralized processing is a really
good option for folks to lower the cost
and still build rooms to compliance
because it's partly one of the hardest I
mean more than distribution distribution
is putting it on a truck and driving it
from one place to another but the
processing you know that's actually
handling live plant material plant
material that's already been tested so
you know there's a there's a lot of
responsibility there that nothing
happens to it after the test has come
back clean and before it's been into the
consumers hands and a lot can happen in
that processing room so yeah it's it's a
lot there's a lot of machinery in there
Amanda you will you missed you all you
both missed I well no maybe you didn't
miss a very animated discussion before
lunch about distribution and how many
farmers are suffering because they've
got product they can't distribute it the
legal outlets are are in dispensaries
and retailing or not they are not being
able to get their product there so one
is how does a farmer get flow Cana to
distribute their craft cannabis and to I
wanted to ask if you are seeing the same
trend in manufacturing the Tim referred
to and are is flow can of getting into
oils and manufacturing and joining and
we
you're a plant Tim when you said you're
gonna emerald cup is gonna start a plant
a manufacturing plan and Willits yeah
well it's actually outside the city
limits it's the old Moser a garden
center it's one block behind the dump
out there waste management and it's
actually it doesn't feel like an
industrial park it's actually an eight
nap Baker you know three step up park
that you has a pond next to it and you
overlook the city so we're fortunate
it's gonna truly be an industrial park
so we're very excited about that and the
I'll let Amanda answer the questions you
asked her well first we need more places
like that so that's very very important
because we do need more outlets right
now I'll say flow kana is not taking on
any new farmers because we don't have
the capacity to process for any more
people than we're already processing for
that's how we're hiring more people so
we can hire more people we can bring on
more farmers we plan to be able to bring
on anyone that wants to work with us as
long as we do a farm on it and see their
practices and all of that but we also
have a responsibility of the farmers we
currently work with to be quality in our
processing and if we try to bring on too
much that quality goes down stuff starts
to slip through the cracks and that's
not fair so because the regulations are
so strict and you know we're just now
going through our permanent state
licensing process you know we just have
to be really careful about our growth
that we don't hurt the integrity of what
we've already built but that being said
we do have a farmer relations team that
will take your information and as soon
as we start taking on more farmers will
contact you and schedule a farm visit
and that's the next step we come and
visit the farm we see your practices we
talk to you about what your expectations
are and then the answer the question
about manufacturing we are going to
start manufacturing on the facility we
have a partner out of Colorado it's
going to be coming in and doing white
label manufacturing so if our farmers
want to take part of their product and
turn that into an oil they'll be able to
get that done there they'll be able to
co-brand with flow Cana with the oil and
then eventually what I see is edible
products I mean you know you really have
very little idea what flour is in your
edible product and so I'm looking for
all the way down the supply chain where
you're buying a cookie and you know that
it
made with oil from huckleberry hill
farms and so that I think is really
important or ladies sativa farms and so
I think that that's really what we're
pushing towards is we want folks to know
that when you buy a product that has
flow kana oil as an ingredient that it
represents the highest quality because
it's representing this very unique group
of prep farmers so white label means
that the manufacturer isn't putting
their brand on it if they're basically
making it as an ingredient for the
farmer and flow kana to co-brand so
Amanda its your would you say that model
that you're working with the farmers is
that you're contracting with a farmer
that you know what their quality is and
so you're testing and purchasing the
cannabis and then processing it at your
central processing plant or making it
into oil or edibles so all you've
already contracted to buy that cannabis
so that's one business model correct
right so I want to ask yes about that
and asked him if that's what his emerald
cup is doing as well so basically the
kind of the previous model was that the
farmer would sell their pound wholesale
and they would just walk away and then
whatever happened to that pound after
they sold it was whatever happened to it
it went into oils or it went into
something else or maybe it went into
nothing and so we work more with the
farmer on a contract basis now it's not
exclusive they don't have to sell
everything to us they can totally work
with other people but we give them up
and down payment in a negative
percentage of that product at retail so
if that product is turned into a twenty
dollar cookie instead of only getting
the worth of the flower that went into
that cookie they're getting a percentage
of that cookie and that's the white
label piece so you're basically
purchasing it at the retail level that
cookie is co branded so that farmer gets
part of that revenue and so it's and
again we have a whole menu of services
so what are the biggest things we offer
honestly is storage storage is a huge
issue our farmers are seasonal farmers
they're not producing all year round
they're pulling one or two harvests but
they
need that to last all year so having
safe secure temperature and
humidity-controlled storage was one of
the biggest barriers we saw and
thankfully at the property in Redwood
Valley because it used to store wine it
has a ton of storage that's built
exactly for that type of product so that
I think that in the end of the day right
now that's probably the best thing
service that we can offer farmers in
terms of their news issues so that's a
separate contract or separate
relationship than saying you're gonna
purchase that story cannabis so there's
different belongs to them so it's on the
Shelf in the storage facility still
belongs to the farmer still their
product they can come get it at any time
take it away ok and Tim what is your
business model there's a few things in
there one of them what you guys were
talking about earlier about the
situation and the cultivation and
distribution of stuff it's it's going to
be really even more of a mess because if
you look at it now it used to be if you
if you had a product and it dried up
during the summer at least during the
summer months you could move it out and
get a pretty good price for it and then
it became a shorter window because of
the depths coming in now it's basically
if you don't sell your product between
April 1st and May 1st there's gonna be
50 million pounds of Depot's coming from
Santa Barbara and from Salinas and all
those wholesaler and box buyers are
already down there waiting we've had
people turning down stuff for 700-pound
because they know it's gonna be 604 a
grades and those people down there have
now put the time into their filtration
systems and into their greenhouses and
into their above-ground soil mixtures
it's not in the ground they're not gonna
have the pesticide issues and so there's
gonna be a giant amount of Depot's
coming out that are so huge that you're
gonna watch whoever's got flowers right
now you're gonna be crushed if you don't
move that out in the next few weeks you
won't even bill it's gonna be 300 a
pound because there's so much coming and
we have that challenge because we can't
go out of this state we're the
breadbasket of this country we can grow
a ton cannabis flourishes we are going
to grow too much we've already done that
and no matter what Flo canna wants to do
in help they can only help so many
people if you've got 5000 farmers in
this county they're gonna you know if
they got a thousand farmers it
overwhelmed them okay the same with us
you know so you're really it's still dad
the Emerald cup you had 600 entries last
year it's just like it always was the
top
10 or 20% our fire the rest are B grade
and unfortunately most people in the
Triangle think they grow a grade but
they're growing B grade and until you
really get into those regenerative
farming practices and you get a high
grade soil system and you really know
how to how to grow a fine flower it's
gonna be a real challenge you know so
there's a whole thing coming in with the
depot's this year the markets that are
coming in what's gonna happen for us
like I said we're not trying to start
really large because we have four of our
own permitted farms our potential new
distributor has a million pounds of trim
under contract that's permitted right
now so we were talking about needing
30,000 pounds of shake to run our co2
machines for the year and he said oh by
the way I got a million pounds of
contract to trim that I can give you so
that's the size and scope that's going
to come at people and so just like
everything else we're gonna find the
finest products because when it's
powered by emerald-cut oils if somebody
uses an oil and does a white label we do
a product with them and it goes out it
says powered by miral cup oil we want to
make sure that that's really it's
noticeable even down to the edibles
because you really notice that high that
subtlety and that you know it used to be
already hit all the low-grade in to the
end of the edibles or into places they
wouldn't get it you know but whether
it's a tincture and edible whatever else
you're really gonna want really fine
material because people are gonna know
the subtleties in the high you know it's
gonna be there so all the way down the
board is going to be high-grade
materials and we're not looking to do
that much but we are looking for some
key people there's a few people around
that do some really incredible
cultivation and creation of flowers and
stuff and and products too so we're open
to that my business director director
business Bob John but the Kaling back
there he's the one who drugged me out
here we formed about 11 companies and he
runs most of that you can talk to him or
something and we're open there doing
partnerships and flow Canada hopefully
they can help you too they're a great
company
all right thank you so much Tim Blake
and Amanda Raymond happy fourth
[Music]