[Music]
the tournament when a plant is ready or
the indicators of harvest time so I'm
looking for both the pistols and the
trichomes will begin to change color as
the plant matures and gets closer to
harvest and the plant itself will start
to lose energy you'll notice change of
color and some of the leaves a lot of
the big families will start to wither
turn yellow as the plant kind of
withdraws and nutrients out of those and
basically sheds them in a way and then
the plant itself will just start to lose
energy and start to lose momentum when
you first go into flower you see it
build real quickly into that push and
then as it gets towards the end that
energy backs way off the pistols and
trichomes will will shift from the
trichomes are generally a clear early
then turn milky and then will start to
oxidize turn orange dark and tan on the
outside when you start to see a ratio of
about 8020 with the pistols which do the
same thing go from a light a white color
or I shouldn't say that they're not all
white but they'll go from a live healthy
moisture present to dry withered and
often in a darker color the moist is the
new growth and you'll start to see the
plant slow down the new pistols emerging
will slow down and slow down and slow
down the old ones will wither and
eventually what ends up happening is you
end up with different ratios early into
flower you should if the plant is
healthy you'll have close to 100 percent
of the pistols are a lighter color and
alive and actively emerging and then as
that slows down and the old ones started
to turn dark the new ones will
as well the new emergence will slow down
and eventually what you end up with is
the majority of them are dead or dry and
and withered and so the the to changing
color and kind of the ratios the
percentages that you find are what you
lead you into the question of you know
is it time to harvest so when it comes
time to harvest often the manner of the
harvest depends on the plant it's done
differently indoors the greenhouses and
outdoor scenarios depending on how big
that plant was usually for me is the
determining factor you know what method
you might consider you can go in and
take the whole planet down and just hang
the entire plant with some of the bigger
ones what you'll see is that the flowers
mature on the outside before they mature
on the inside so the things down on the
inside branches below the colas will be
sometimes a week behind week and a half
and if you take the tops off of big
plants first and then allow that inside
to mature a little bit in my experience
you end up with a higher yield you can
do two is obviously the starting point
if you're going more than one I've seen
it done as many as four and five times I
think when you start to get into five
cuts on the same plant that's not
necessarily viable commercially but I
think a first harvest on the outside of
some of the big plants is and and
increases your yield and can increase
the quality of the material down on the
inside if you allow that access to
sunlight before taking it so you take
the tops off and D leaf a little bit the
outside of the plant again and allow
that light to get in and penetrate down
into some of that stuff that hasn't
really seen light you'll notice that
they get more dense a lot of times
they'll put on mass they'll continue to
grow and a lot of times what you'll find
is that when the when the outside colas
specifically are ready
harvest if you look down inside that
stuff still has a ways to go all the
pistols will be the the pistols will
tend to be fresher younger continuing to
emerge or appearing to continue to
emerge very few dry withered compared to
the outsides and and the trichomes as
well and generally be behind the the
outside behind the colas the outside of
the plant generally aid the key I think
for the curing of it is is controlling
the temperature and humidity in the room
and trying to keep that as stable as
possible fluctuations in temperature and
humidity are what begins to turn the
plant colors and a lot of cases you'll
start to see things will tan off if they
were if they were taking on a little bit
too hard of a ride what you want to try
and do is is bring the temperature and
humidity of the plant material kind of
down down down up down and and kind of
slide it in rather than just all the
humidity out and then continue to drain
off what continues to come out of the
plant material for a few days the drying
of the material will take a little bit
too hard of a dip and a lot of times
what you'll do is you'll dip below the
threshold for the Cure which is if I
remember correctly is 50% and so if you
drop that plant material below 50%
humidity that curing process stops and
what you have is a dried material often
the difference between that drying it
versus kind of curing it versus slowly
withdrawing the the last bits of
moisture out the differences is often
found in the smoke the the young studs
of the flash dried is I tend to refer to
it the flash dried stuff you tend to get
a little bit harsher smoke and the THC
to kind of changes the experience as it
matures it softens it mellows the
experience a little bit especially with
some of the sativa stuff it can get you
really racy very uplifting but a lot of
times that can be a little bit
much with some of the strains that we
have now being so incredibly high and
THC
it'll-it'll softened that I guess
similar to the way that they aged
tobacco or wine with wines you know that
there's a sharper flavor in my
experience has been is kind of a sharper
tint to the to the young stuff and then
as you get older it gets kind of
smoother more refined and that seemed
type of thing happens with the THC which
with cannabis for the Cure the
temperature and humidity controlling the
temperature and humidity of the room
it's kind of the biggest priority for me
is watching that temperature and
humidity in the room not necessarily in
the plant material but in the room so as
you first load up a cure space or a dry
space and that fresh plant material will
be will be shedding moisture very very
quickly so your humidity will shoot up
and it will stay high for usually 2 3 4
days during that stage I take the
community out as fast as possible and
then as that starts to slow down I will
back off the speed at which I'm pulling
the humidity out of the room and that
kind of allows the plant material to
shed the moisture and a little bit more
drawn-out drawing out that that that
drying process was the process of
shedding the moisture and what I'm
trying to avoid is just kind of a crash
and in humidity sucking it out too fast
and a lot of times what you'll end up
doing is you'll dry it too fast it'll
become crispy you'll drop below the
threshold of 50% and once you once you
drop below that threshold my
understanding of the process is that
that's when the curing stops and once it
stops there's no restarting it so in
order the difference between drying it
and curing it is maintaining maintaining
a minimum of 55 50 % humidity in the
material
and drawing it out slowly along gating
that process a bit drawing out that
process ends up with a higher quality
product pure space temperature I tend to
keep it as low as most AC systems will
allow which seems to be in the mid to
high 50s and then as I'm drawing out the
humidity the only other real concern
that I have is airflow in the room
keeping the humidity within that room
consistent throughout the room not
having higher humidity down low hot dry
air up top you'll you'll end up with an
uneven uneven cure if I'm able to hold
the room for a few days at 55% humidity
that's kind of a I've had my best
results that way if I'm able to draw
that process out and finish by being
able to hold the temperature in humidity
in the room temperature low and
consistent from start to finish or as
close to consistence I can get from
start to finish and then the humidity
drawing that out quickly to beginning
slowing it way way way down and and then
that last few days of the process I
should be able to if I'm on top of
things and in a easily controlled
environment I should be able to take
that last few days and just hold the
room right where it is and allow the
last little bit of humidity to kind of
make its way from the inside of the
flower to the outside out into the air
and then if you're able to get that
whole space to hold that 55% humidity
for that extra day or two days what
you're doing is kind of evening
everything out so if there are parts
that dry it a little bit faster than
others that last little bit of humidity
is going to continue to work itself out
of the dense the the more dense material
and you'll end up with a more consistent
humidity throughout so the outside of
the flower will be roughly 55% 60%
humidity and inside will be the same
versus the outside being outside being
40% humidity or 35% humidity or or even
50% humidity and the inside is still in
the 60s or 70s
you know ten to ten ten to 20 points
higher on the inside for for that first
stage of the cure the cure can be broken
into stages you don't necessarily have
to keep the entire process in your
drying space or in your in your initial
in your kind of initial care space you
can if you can draw that process the
first step of the process out to 1012
days that seems to be a very easily
achievable target where if you draw it
out too long then you're just allowing
you know that stuff to kind of sit out
in the air a little bit longer than
needed
you then break it down break it down
into bins and you can kind of slow walk
the remainder of the process there by
just checking the bins on occasion
closing them up and allowing that
humidity in the bin to even out keeping
track obviously what that is and if
there's still a little bit more humidity
to escape you can burp the lids on
occasion there are a handful of ways to
to go into that second stage of cure
what's been I think very popular for a
very long time now on what's been more
of the hobbyist scale compared to you
know we're now expanding into full-scale
commercial production type facilities
but in the history of Canada the last 60
years the history of cannabis at least
it's been underground and on a small
scale which makes it to where large
mason jars or five-gallon buckets
sealable containers and that size work
well for the second stage of cure you
want I tend to go towards food grade
material you don't necessarily just want
to go grab a Home Depot bucket I think
that the the smells the off-gassing of
the manufacturing process and the
plastics can work its way into the flour
material but any sort of food grade
plastic or glass in anything mason jar
up to maybe a five-gallon as you scale
that up you start to start to look at
things like 55-gallon drums that can be
just rotated on a rack
a little bit at a time to kind of keep
that material moving if there is any
humidity left you don't want it all
sinking to the bottom you want
everything in there to kind of cure
evenly so you can turn that 55 gallon
bucket 55-gallon drum on a rack it's
similar to what you see with you know
whiskey the barrels yeah on its side it
seems like the key to longer-term
storage is in temperature and humidity
levels being maintained but also
removing the oxygen from the equation so
storing in vacuum sealed or nitrogen
sealed bags similar to the way they
store you know a lot of things in the
market in the supermarket more often
than not what I see is a rush to get
paid that causes people to skip that
last step and so assuming you've gotten
all the way to the finish line and you
have clean healthy material the the the
most common way people kind of lose that
quality level that I found is in the
drying process and then storage
transportation any sort of heat and
humidity fluctuations will cause that
material to start to turn the color
first and smell let's just say both will
go usually hand-in-hand depending on how
that material is treated if it's not
it's not treated well after harvest you
lose value so if you had something that
may sell for $1,000 a pound now the
smell is kind of diminished and the
appearance is starting to turn a little
bit there's there's a little bit more
color it's not a clean green dried
material or cured material it starts to
tan turn various shades of yellow orange
tint will start to come into the trail
and and then the smell will also start
to diminish or turn into something else
a lot of times you'll be able to
really tell from from the smell
specifically what's happening was it was
the material cured properly stored
properly or was it put away wet will
create a little bit a different scent
than if it was beaten up while it was
still alive and then properly cured
things like that so you'll start to see
the quality level diminish and and in a
lot of cases it seems the dot is due to
kind of a rush to get to market rush to
get paid and in that rush you end up
taking less on the material
[Music]