a fair portion of what shingle hill my
company does is work with large pools of
capital that are trying to figure out
how to play the cannabis industry and a
lot of them are looking at investments
they've already made that they believe
to be relatively safe in the industry
which for the most part you know the
last year or two has been the Canadian
companies and so as we've gotten the
point where those guys are building out
infrastructure and they're talking about
you know what Canada's can consume and
if you look at the Canadian market
versus the Californian market you think
you know thirty five million people in
Canada and 39 million people in
California you can roughly get a sense
of how big that market ultimately will
be you know call it a seven billion
eight billion dollar annual market in
Canada but you look at what they're
actually building out the way of
infrastructure and you're talking about
the canopies the aurorus they're free is
the the Cronos you know cobbling
together different groups green organic
Dutchman all these companies that are
all still building out because you know
demand is still outpacing supply but
ultimately you're gonna hit a point of
equilibrium but the plans these guys
have if you actually look at they're
blowing right past that equilibrium
point they're going to you know right to
a point they're saying we're gonna do
you know nine hundred thousand square
feet of greenhouse or we're gonna do you
know whatever how many hectares or how
many hundreds of thousands of square
feet and when you actually extrapolate
that back against what the size of the
market is you know they're they're
building out in a way that can't be
supported so when you talk to these CEOs
yeah well that's easy we're gonna export
you know we're able to export in Canada
and you know I go okay to who
yeah who's gonna buy it right now
they're talking about the European
market which you know for the near term
it's probably viable you know Germany
might viable Portugal might be viable
but ultimately Germany scam its own
market yeah Portugal's in its own market
every one of the European countries will
have their own markets it's a stopgap
it's a short-term proposition and then
you're talking about you know some of
the Latin countries that are coming on
you know that people are talking about
exporting to Colombia okay I'll explain
that to me because clearly positive it's
a perfect growing climate it's twelve
hours of sunshine every day it's twelve
hours of surface for you like it's the
perfect climate for flowering ants a
perfect temperature and they've got
mountainous areas if you had lower areas
you know there's so many different
appellations that you can actually work
from to say okay you know what do I want
to grow and where it's deciding like you
know do I want to coast layers my Pinot
Noir grapes versus you know do I want
you know open sort of warm weather
from our shard it's the same idea you
know down there you can produce stuff
for your labor cost is next to nothing
your your energy costs us next to
nothing your your access to perfect
sunny days is next nothing these
Canadian companies are saying oh we're
gonna be the the producer for the world
it doesn't make any sense what makes
sense is finding a great growing climate
producing an abundance there and then
shipping from there when a global market
emerges or even in the North American
market Canada's not supplying North
America okay that's not supplying
anything but maybe regionally in Canada
because they don't have the ability
nobody nobody's gonna be growing indoors
in four years it doesn't make any sense
you're producing two dollars a gram
instead of you know 30 cents a gram in a
super high-tech greenhouse that's fully
automated with the robotics attached to
it and that's where the industry is
moving that direction so all these guys
that like are you know building these
REITs to you know to support indoor
growers I keep telling them like ok
that's great for the first couple years
you're gonna have oversized returns on
your on your on your cap rate but
ultimately you know can that guys stay
in business and that's something right
now that I think people just aren't
thinking about is what's the cost of
production need to be to be competitive
in a global marketplace it's not gonna
be in Canada that's right yeah all went
to Columbia right in the end though the
entire thing went to Clemmy you look at
the tomato market that you know you want
to talk to someone understands has
talked to five Symington from copper
state farms in Arizona you know if I've
undercut every one of his competitors
and tomatoes that he's producing Cooley
con Mexico and then what I do came back
and bought those competitors the
greenhouses and now is producing
cannabis of you know snowflake Arizona
he's got 30 acre facility that used to
be one of those competitors and tomatoes
he crushed by going to Mexico so if that
doesn't show you you know kind of
migration of the market I mean Mexico
just announced that they're opening
their market I've been fielding calls
non-stop the last two weeks from the
Mexican market saying we really want to
do something down here now you know
granted you guys think about the the
graft and corruption that exists in that
country and the cartels and still the
stranglehold so it might be some time
before it goes in there but if you're
gonna say would you would you prefer to
be a cultivator of cannabis in Sinaloa
versus in Minnesota it's not even close
there's no comparison so that's really
what I think people need to realize that
as migration happens towards greater
legalization it's all gonna be about
highest quality lowest cost just like
any other commodity