[Music]
you know those couple things mentioned
transport track and trace and so will
bring up the folks from the state
perspective that are going to have to do
on the regulations for this so let's go
ahead and bring up at this time Lori
Ajax chief for the Bureau of medical
cannabis regulation Jim Houston the
undersecretary for the department of
food and agriculture and dr. Kevin Smith
director and state public health officer
for the Department of Public Health I'm
Lori Ajax on the bureau chief for the
Bureau of medical cannabis regulation
under the Department of Consumer Affairs
and today I'm going to focus my
presentation on brief presentation on
implementing the medical cannabis
regulation and Safety Act and
proposition 64 and then provide a status
of the regulations and our timelines
under these new laws the Bureau is
responsible for the licensing and
enforcement of the distributors the
transporters the dispensaries testing
labs and the micro businesses under
proposition 64 we're also the lead
agency to coordinate the efforts with
the other licensing authorities with
Department of Food nag and Department of
Public Health in addition to the many
other there's many other state agencies
involved that we're working with on a
quite a frequent basis our priorities
and implementing both statute is the
protection of the public the patient and
the environment it's important to know
that right from the start when we first
started the bureau I got stashed at the
bureau in February of last year and we
decided that the one of the most
important things we wanted to get out in
front of the public and listen to their
concern learn about the industry and so
we did informational tours across the
state from nine of them across the
street just to meet with the public and
a lot of the people that were there were
local government patients the public
local law enforcement and the industry
we went as far north as arcada and all
the way down to San Diego to these
informational session it was really
beneficial for us to learn about the
concerns of the industry of the public
and we got a lot of feedback we then
followed that up with our pre regulatory
meetings that we did it last year in
September of October we went to eight
locations across the state and that we
actually floated some regulatory
concepts and actually got involved with
we had small group discussions to
actually get feedback on what's the best
way to go forward with the developing of
the regulations so we did a lot of
listening we did a lot of asking of
questions and now we're at a point at
our pre regulatory stakeholders in total
we had over 2,000 people attend now
we're at a point with the other two
licensing authorities that we are
developing the medical regulations we
plan to notice those with the Office of
Administrative Law early spring all
three of us will be noticing our medical
regulations and then we'll kick off the
45-day comment period and we also be
holding hearings across the state to
take public comment we feel like a lot
of what we have developed in the medical
side is going to align very well with
the proposition 64 regulations that we
also have to develop at least where
there are similarities as you all know
there's some key differences between the
two statutes and so for those
differences we are going to see what
happens during the legislative process
and then we plan to use the emergency
regulation authority that we have under
both the medical and the adult use side
and and notice our regulations for the
adult use coming up approximately in
September we want to make sure that we
see what happens through legislation and
then go forward with developing those
regulations that is the status of our
timelines and happy to answer any
questions you have yeah I'm sure
there'll be plenty of questions thank
you Miss adex and thank you for taking
the time to meet with me appreciate the
sit down that mr. Houston please Thank
You mr. chair madam chair members my
name is Jim Houston I'm the
Undersecretary at the California
Department of Food and Agriculture it's
been echoed by my colleague both the
passage of Merkerson and prop 64 has
presented new challenges to the
Department of Food and Agriculture first
and foremost were responsible for the
licensing of the growth sites and
enforcement of medical and adult used
cannabis and throughout the state with
particular consideration given to
sequence so the California Environmental
Quality Act where the lead agency for
purposes of that licensing beyond that
we're also responsible for developing
the track and trade system that will be
used from seed to sale to track the
cannabis both through as flower state
and then whatever sort of masa nations
occur after that in terms of our
regulatory work you know we are sort of
lockstep with our other agencies we held
eight listening sessions throughout this
state all up and down both in the north
and the south and the central many of
those occurred with other agencies in
tow some did some not we likewise you
know have been proceeding as we did
expeditiously and plan to submit our
regulations in early spring to oal we've
already prepared our economic analysis
otherwise known as a Syria and then
that's with my cursor and sort of
parallel to that is the secret timeline
so we will be shortly releasing our
draft environmental impact report as it
will go early spring and then that will
sort of begin the process we've built in
a lot of public comment for both of
those and plan on submitting those late
fall around November for their final
disposition and then in August likewise
we plan on using our emergency
regulatory authority to implement prop
you know as extent expressed both on
legislature and here and in other
hearings and will be continued to be
discussed the harmonization between
recursive and prof 64 is dynamic and
occurring and so we want to be able to
adapt and put in any of those changes in
August so that we don't have to sort of
unwind the clock so August use the
emergency and then we will follow that
up with regular rulemaking as well and
that also presents a unique challenge
for us that is sequa for because we have
our mckersie sequined then we also have
to do prop 64 sequence but thankfully
you know we were able we believe will be
able to utilize the information that's
in Arma curse' sequel analysis apply
that to our prof 64 analysis and while
there are some differences believe that
that overlap will allow us to meet the
January one 2018 deadline there is
currently an RFP out to do the
consulting work for that so we
anticipate that should be wrapped up
shortly and then we will begin so you
know we I will say we've had I've been
very very impressed with the level of
coordination that we've had and the
level of dialogue that we've had with
both yourselves stakeholders and our
sister agencies and so look forward to
seeing this through to completion and
have to answer any questions you may
have thank you thank you i know the
questions as well especially around vas
cultivation and whatnot this that's
please dr. Spencer Thank You Keith good
afternoon cares good morning committee
members I'm dr. Karen Smith I'm the
state public health officer and the
director of the california department of
public health today I'm going to talk
briefly about the Department of Public
Health implementation of the medical
cannabis regulation Safety Act and prop
64 as you all know the medical cannabis
regulation Safety Act and 64 both
mandates the Department of Public Health
the license and oversee medical and
adult used cannabis product
manufacturers the department's approach
these regulations with the intent of
creating strong foundation for the
protection of public health and safety
what without making the regulatory
compliance so owners that manufacturers
of the cannabis products would choose to
remain in the
underground market we're drafting
regulations that are substantially
similar to the manufacturing practices
currently in place for food
manufacturers and the regs will include
things along the lines of licensing
requirements process control security
safety sanitation destruction labeling
packaging product standards and
compliance enforcement we developed the
regulations to include those
substantially similar both to food but
also to dietary supplements because
there are things about cannabis being
added to food products that are very
similar to that from microbial
contamination by employees to or the
environment to incorporation of foreign
elements like glass hair or insects to
contamination of a product with
unintended allergens the manufacturing
processes are provide numerous
opportunities for hazards to be
introduced the minimum facility
requirements and standard operating
procedures for sanitary manufacturing
established by the department's proposed
regulations are intended to reduce or
eliminate potential contamination the
regulations also limit the products that
are allowed to be infused with cannabis
because certain types of manufactured
products are more susceptible to
microbial contamination the department's
highest priority and implementing the
act and proposition 64 is the projection
of the public's health based on feedback
that we received from stakeholders the
department is contemplating additional
license types beyond those allowed for
in the current regulation one of which
is an additional license type for
businesses that only manufacture
products such as edibles that don't
conduct the extractions from the plant
and then a second license type for
businesses that do not manufacture the
actual product but package and label
them we have extensive experience in the
food manufacturing processing and safety
but the cannabis industry how is new to
us as well as others we estimate that
there will be approximately a thousand
applications for medical cannabis
manufacturing and potentially as much as
twice that for the adult use
manufacturing this required us to really
develop a quickly develop an
understanding of this entirely new
industry which is
evolving very rapidly us I think you're
all aware and because of the nature of
the industry there isn't a great deal of
data actually available to so it becomes
difficult to verify to educate ourselves
we met with numerous industry
representatives and associations and the
department staff visited manufacturing
sites of various types throughout the
state to learn more about extraction and
manufacturing processes the staff also
had numerous calls with other states who
have implemented similar programs during
the pre regulatory stakeholder meetings
we also heard from local health
jurisdictions and and others within the
local jurisdictions who represent they
are very clear about their desire to
both maintain some level of local
control and that they are important
partners in the regulatory process this
is consistent with the way we practice
in food manufacturing and other
activities in the department timely
completion of the regulatory packages is
also top priority for us and we've been
coordinating Alice has been said before
we also are on the same timeline we
anticipate releasing the medical
cannabis regulations for public comment
in early spring and full adoption by
January first because of the compressed
timeline we also anticipate using the
emergency regulatory process for the
adult youth regulations which will
substantially be the same as proposition
64 although there are some differences
that will need to be addressed to thank
you for the opportunity to share our
progress and plans in implementation and
I'm happy to answer any questions that
you may have thank you thank you for
your testimony so let's figure out we
will start with you dr. Smith and then
we'll work her questions all the way
through and first yeah I appreciate the
time as we were trying to grapple with
some of these issues some of the things
you touched upon the packaging the food
manufacturing because I believe you're
just looking at this is even from the
food manufacturing making sure that the
public is safe because that's your
charge so make sure that things are safe
for the public consumption but can you
talk a little bit more about how we're
trying to standardize that I thought we
had this discussion but I like to put it
on the record standardizing so if you go
to one dispensary as opposed to an
other that you're still receiving the
same product and how does that relate to
potency and what does that mean for an
individual so there's a broad variety of
regulations that touch on that some of
which of which are with us and
dispensaries themselves are within the
local control so we don't we don't
regulate that however sanitary practice
is part of it one overarching safety
measure that we are going to propose is
that we only will allow cannabis
infusion of shelf-stable food products
because of the possibility for foods
that require refrigeration or some other
level of maintenance at a particular
under particular characteristics at the
local level most dispensaries are not
prepared to do that and it becomes a
much more difficult thing for local
jurisdictions to actually regulate that
on a dispensary by dispensary basis and
so that's one of the things that we're
going to propose in the regulation the
other thing is we will be proposing
maximum THC levels in products that
edible products in particular as well as
topical products because we believe that
it's the most one of the most important
things for us is making sure that
children in particular who may
inadvertently consume a product that
looks like a food product that they're
familiar with that we maintain a package
so that it doesn't have so much THC in
it that the child ends up in emergency
room or the hospital there have been
examples in other states of well
pediatric poisonings actually increased
dramatically in Colorado after they
originally put using what we doing
obviously is a great deal of education
public education and about how to use
this product safely thank you yeah now I
know that's a concern of one of the
questions I also get back home is you
know some people know what they classify
is the good shops and right this one's
more potent than the other so I'm glad
that we're looking into it I know we
have a number of questions I have
additional questions as well but let me
go into that divert some of my my
colleague just really briefly and it may
not totally fall under your
fiction but folks under Section eight
housing and people who you know need to
apply to that or on the waiting list
it's actually illegal for them to use
marijuana because of the federal you
know saying that's an illegal narcotic
so that's an issue looming and it's
disenfranchising people as well and
folks may not even know that who are you
know needing section 8 so I just wanted
to kind of bring that up and I didn't
know if it was under the jurisdiction or
not mr Wood has questions public health
question first of all I want to say that
I appreciate the opportunity we met with
you and the work you're doing very
impressed with the work and the thought
has gone into where you are so far I
also appreciate the fact that you're not
trying to be overly onerous I think the
industry has is going to take a while
for people to get up and running there
and I think the worst things can do is
be overly onerous on a lot of these so
that give people an opportunity to
actually come into compliance reasonable
best practices so my idea have a
question which to questions and one is
how are we going to reconcile some of
the oversight issues because mtrs a was
pretty particular about at Department of
Public Health's role and now and then
prop 64 has changed that so do we is
there is that some there room for
reconciliation on that one because you
know we clearly after studying that six
months the governor's office had had a
very different vision of how things
should be done well be really the only
place where that comes up is in in the
oversight of the testing laboratories
and we are assisting the bureau with
development of the medical cannabis
regulations for the testing laboratories
we actually do believe that it will be
possible through legislation to align
the to the the drafters of prop 64
didn't intentionally our understanding
is put it back to the California
Department of Public Health they were
working from an early version of the
medical cannabis Act the reason for
moving the the testing laboratories
really was to facilitate the industry's
work distributors are the are the entity
within the process who actually take the
product
original product of the testing
laboratories right now distributors and
all other licenses except the very
specific agricultural license and
manufacturing licenses are with the
bureau so it was the the conclusion of
the group that the best alignment is to
have it with with the Bureau also DCA
has far more experience and licensing
complex types of entity that we do but
we would anticipate working very closely
with them over time it's likely that
given the science of testing is
developing that we're going to want to
be looking at the regulations over time
for the laboratories but I think that
that's a resolvable confident in my
final question from a public health
perspective become aware of the infusion
of cannabis in a variety of top of foods
and things but yesterday was brought up
to me and I'd this may be a question for
everybody I don't know who's going to
oversee the infusion of cannabis in
spirits and wine which is happening out
there and how's that going to play out
so our proposed regulations are not
going to allow the infusion of cannabis
and alcohol products into alcohol
products and that's based on science
that demonstrates that to depressive
effects which both marijuana and and
alcohol are both central nervous system
depressants actually can potentiate
there's also very early information that
there can be very real consequences of
that playing out particularly in the
realm of automobile accidents there's a
recent study done by law enforcement in
Colorado looking at fatal automobile
accidents from using autopsy data what
they found was that is that it was
incredibly rare for one of these for
someone who was had one of these
substances in their system for it to be
only marijuana in overwhelming number of
cases it was both alcohol and marijuana
and potentially other substance as well
and while people will always Co imbibe
we don't think that it's responsible to
allow to actually facilitate that by
allowing products that contain both okay
thank you Miss come here
thank you dr. Smith um I'm there is a
significant amount of concern around the
issue of infusion into products that
children would perceive as things they
eat yeah and well you have that the
ability to really and I'm thinking about
the situations where because with
medical marijuana right now it's infused
in anything and there's really no
regulatory oversight so stepping back
from that and changing what they can be
infused into has me concerned because I
I'm concerned that we won't have the
ability to be able to go into it to a
retail facility take out and test and be
able to determine whether they're living
up to their the requirements that are in
the regulations in particular for those
products they're cooked or where their
property has changed are you doing the
research to be able to know whether the
infusion if it's put into a product
changes over time and to be able to
really know whether the potency is such
that it's consistent on the product in
the product so we don't have the
resources to be engaged in that research
although it is an active area of
research there's actually a multi-state
meeting of public health officials from
the states with legalized cannabis
happening in California right now and
that was actually one of the
conversations we had yesterday and
Colorado's actively pursuing that as
well as others I think that's an area
that's really going to develop over time
but we are going to be proposing maximum
levels of THC in manufactured products
and that means we will be able to test
those products after manufacturing to
ensure that they don't exceed that we're
also addressing the issue of children
from several other ways the products
cannot look substantially like a food
product that children recognize the
packaging cannot cannot use bold colors
cartoons etc as well as it being opaque
so if it is a product that does roof
bolus of food product that that is
commonly in use the package has to be
opaque it has to be tamper child
resistant and in addition if it has more
than one serving in it has to be
resealable so we're building in some
pretty we hope strenuous regulations
without making it impossible to actually
make manufactured products and thank you
for that I appreciate that I know those
are some of the concerns to make sure
that we this doesn't get in the hands of
children right on so we need to make
that sure that that's paramount but let
me just ask that they were quick before
we moved about this that relates so
earlier you mentioned some of the
science and the research what is that
science what does that research can just
elaborate a little bit more on that on
that specific issue of how how potency
changes I think that essentially what
they're doing is in laboratory research
laboratories they're actually taking
various manufactured products currently
for sale and there are there's
everything from really basic science
research looking at the molecular
changes in in the molecular
concentrations and the flavor profiles
all the way through to you why testing
the product on humans if you is not
truly human testing that volunteers who
imbibe the product who can provide
subjective information to inform it as
well and so it's not the same because
earlier you said up to this research
about allow scientific research for the
infusion and alcohol and spirits great
so so I was speaking to one as a overall
we know that when you take to central
nervous system depressants and you add
them together and that would be the true
of opioid products for example and
alcohol and many other types of drugs
and dietary supplements that you can get
a potentiating effect in other words
that's stronger and synergistic rather
than just additive and as I think
there's emerging evidence to demonstrate
that that may in fact be true that is in
true is also true for marijuana okay
thank you for the clarification mr.
Mathis please
dr. Smith is you're talking and you're
talking about the science and all that I
know we get into discussing CV oil and
when we percentages of THC within and a
lot of that from some of the science
that I've been going through and folks
I've been talking to talks about I mean
you literally get into like a molecular
level of how the plants grown what it's
grown with and trace amounts of
different things being into that so what
was your department looking into those
things as part of the standards and also
as far as moving product and from other
states ensuring that the products that
are coming in as well meet the same
standards that we're putting on the
products here in California and this
gets more too awful like with the
medical side I mean if you're saying you
know three ounces of THC oil is going to
be this much is it really and it kind of
gets into the purification standards and
issues of that and I'm just interested
in where you got to write with that so
the the science is really limited it's
rapidly evolving and there's a
distinction between THC which is the
psychoactive part and other cannabinoids
in particular CBD those are the ones
that most people believe have the
medicinal properties so you can get
profiles and people do this actually of
every single there are many enter Keynes
which provide flavor and apparently some
level of the kind of high that's the
language that people use you can tell
this isn't terribly scientific at this
point we are not in we are we are taking
a of that based on safety as opposed to
efficacy as if it were a drug that we
could that we knew about potency so what
we're saying is that there can only be
this much a maximum concentration of phc
because that's the more psychoactive
substance the one that creates the
impairment that is a safety issue in in
a serving essentially and that so that's
fairly that's very simple it's easy to
verify we can test for that I think that
over time as the science develops there
will be
more information but for what we know
now that's the way that we have landed
on is being the safest way to regulate
how much of the psychoactive substance
people are going to be in Justin thank
you thank you mr. Dalli real quick I
don't know this is for the Department of
Agriculture or for your office but so
I'm a farmer regulated heavenly by the
Department of Food nag on I'm a seed
farmer so I racy but the chemicals i use
in the process of my seed is all
reported to the Department of Ag and so
the consumer knows what's been applied
to the products that I sell and when
it's ingested for human use to so who's
going to take who's going to know what
the growers out there putting on the
plants and who wears that regulation
commitment okay we'll segue into mr.
Houston yeah thinking mr. jolly I think
you know that's a good question and tore
my pesticide regulation will retain
their authority they've issued
guidelines you know it's a little bit
tricky because there's no federally
registered pesticides for cannabis but
they've done a lot of work on issuing
guidelines for cannabis growers as to
what substances can be used and those
will continue to be reported to the
county commissioner and utilize that
process to keep track of what pesticides
and then the testing protocol as well so
all the distributors have to drop it off
at a lab you know statistically
significant sample size like like we do
in our produce testing so I'll produce
is tested for pesticide residue to make
sure this in compliance with laws and
all cannabis and product will be
likewise tested to make sure it's in
compliance with the laws so so the
agriculturists out there Asian that is a
crop is going to be permitted and then
has to is going to be required to also
let the County High Commissioners know
when they're what they're applying and
when they're applying it yes okay
could I just ask just to clarify for the
record though what is current practice
in terms of cultivation sites for
acreage and you mean what is that like
you know I when I go back home I talk to
the city managers and supervisors as
they're all worried about mass
cultivation okay yeah so the limit right
now is 22,000 square feet which is about
half acre so that's going to be the the
maximum size and that is a level 5 all
right well which comes into effect in
2022 so there's going to be large scale
grows that will come into effect then
but the there's two things they're
supposed to the statutory sort of
licensing restrictions but also our
sequel analysis will shed some light on
that so you can foresee that there will
be you know as you get bigger and bigger
and you utilize more and more resources
the mitigation burden on that entity you
know grows it lengthwise and so that's
going to factor in to how large the
grows do get but it isn't something
we're also likewise very concerned about
to make sure that I think that's why the
drafters of prof 64 put in the five-year
delay my understanding is the intent was
to allow for small growers to get a
foothold in the market and as we've seen
you know both in the agricultural field
but we'll see it in cannabis and it's
going to be hard for small growers to
and so what is a CDF a doing to help
bring people into compliance because you
know we keep hearing of yeah illegal
growers yes well as I said before at you
know sort of my mantra you know we
really need to focus on having a
reasonable and as simple as possible
regulatory system so very mindful of the
small grower you know as I talked about
in the Senate hearing and mr. wood when
i went up to read way you know it's very
illuminating to see the the diversity of
farmers that are participating and and
the one thing that I really worry about
I mean you know the larger folks the
green
house folks the well-heeled you know
capitalists for lack of a better term
are going to probably be okay but it's
the you know small fruit and veg grower
who's got a half acre a cannabis or an
acre cannabis you know what are they
going to do now and and you know however
simple we can make our registration
process and the the cost associated with
that license you know we're all on
borrowed money right now and the
expectation is it's going to be paid
back through the cannabis program but
we're very mindful of that and so trying
to limit costs trying to limit
registration fees and education and
outreach to those growers utilizing both
you know the sort of NGO community
legislators such as yourselves in your
outreach but also you know doing our own
outreach I'm as much as possible
utilizing ad commissioners to get the
information out there to assist folks
with their compliance obligations and
like I said keep the fees down and so
the more people we can have in there the
easier it's going to be on the flip side
but the flip side is you know both going
to be complaint driven primarily but I
mean it's not something we can do on our
on our own you know the California
Highway Patrol federal drug enforcement
agencies local law enforcement all need
to be involved when we're talking about
illegal grows and and that's all going
to depend on the skies the size and
sophistication of those operations ok
thank you I believe mr. wood at mr.
Dalli traditional costume mr. would
please yeah thank you thank you also for
your availability and willing to reach
out and work with us I think someone's
worked on this issue just in general
this way Ajax everybody has been has
been very accessible we really really
appreciate that done a lot to help us
along the way my question goes back to
you talked about 20-22 and the potential
for these type five licenses is it a
fair characteristics that if they can
meet someone could meet sequa and there
was plenty of resources that we could
have conceivably an unlimited growth
size I mean really really large growth
after their son to your kitchen that
will prove that their one little number
of actual limit to their but um I mean
theoretically yes and I think that's one
of the things that we want to be mindful
of but it's not it's not a conversation
that we're just having with ourselves
I'm its conversation that we're having
with sister agencies with yourselves
with stakeholders I mean I think
everybody the one nice thing about this
for the for the most part is everybody's
rowing in the same direction we all want
a successful regulatory program come
January one 2018 we want those we want
to participate to be able to and we want
those who don't want to participate to
be able to stay out and and you know
having a marketplace that allows for
growers to have access to not have
imbalances of power between the
different entities between distributors
and growers manufacturers and
distributors I mean we've you know we've
seen a rich history in this country of
how these things play out and how these
imbalances ultimately almost always
impact the consumer the person on the
low end the farmer the tumor so we're
trying to have a conversation to get
ahead of that to make sure that the
fairness I guess sort of rules the day
that that do you have an equal
marketplace when the folks are allowed
to compete I mean that's what I think
you know we need them to do is to
compete and then so that's a
conversation will continue to have so
yes theoretically that could happen but
I don't think it's likely mr. golly
Thank You chairman so I represent nine
counties I'm in the same boat as a
member of a wood were my counties are
it's the Wild West all right and so
counties are looking at it as a revenue
source there so and then some have tried
some things they didn't like and change
those rules so I got all my County's
doing something different so very
difficult for the growers for the
processors for locals who have been
there abiding by rules and rules are
changing so what is your role
coordinating with the county I guess
because I'm just giving an example
shasta county had and pretty much do
what you want for a while until they
realized there was a lot of prop
conflicts with neighbors in with
dispensaries so they didn't that they
ban they said we're no more outdoor
grill so the county i live in last and
had really restricted it and then they
decided to open it up a little bit so
basically what happened was last year
around my farm all right where we live
people are buying up land like crazy and
putting in all these groves and its
really the Wild West I mean my wife is
afraid to even drive to our farm it's
that crazy so what is your role with you
you is there some some something that's
going to be put out so this may take
Connie this is going to be the process
that this is how this is up the chain
abri it from grower to processor to
consumer this is going to be the
statewide this is how we're going to do
it so to some extent yes and I think
that's one of the reasons why we've been
coordinating with our sister agencies to
make sure that the regulations unfold
sort of commensurate with one another so
that oaks are able to get a complete
picture however we are restricted to
some degree at the local level because
you know it's up to those locals so our
challenge is how do we stay coordinated
set so you know one of the probably the
most important thing that we want to
accomplish is to bring order to that
chaos you know I think that's all of us
that's why this was all done so you know
we certainly want to accomplish that and
I think as this gets going that is going
to be you know one of the things that is
successful as folks are going to see the
regulatory environment they're going to
be able to participate in it they're
going to be able to have feedback etc
there will be a you know a period of
adaptation you know I'm sure things are
going to be anticipated and there's
going to need to be some changes but but
as long as folks are participating and
feel confident about it you know that is
good with respect to what's happening
sort of you know at the local level with
speculation and whatnot there's going to
be a settling out I mean there are going
to be people who bet wrong and that's
not something we can really control but
you know
we have to work closely with the
counties and our primary you know
contact resolve ously the county AG
commissioner they have a lot of
advantages you know both their their
responsibilities and understanding of
their County Board of Supervisors but
also their connection to the growing
community so they know more than anybody
else what's happening at the county
level and and what the wishes of the
county board of supervisors are and that
is sort of where we are being
deferential to so so you know in your
case where you've got a county that
doesn't want to do anything you know
their hands off we we we step it so you
know there are there may be cities that
in with in that county they want to
participate that's certainly what you
see in Southern California so if the
county AG commission if the County Board
of Supervisors tells the county AG
Commissioner hey don't touch this at all
then we will step in and we will do the
licensing and enforcement at the local
level to the extent that the county AG
commissioner is allowed to you know
regulate the the local municipalities or
whether it be the county of the city
reform cooperative agreements much like
we do in our c program and others where
they'll carry out the work so that's
sort of how we're trying to attack that
and to bring some certainty but but
feedback and communication is really
important thank you sis man just one
word on manufactured products while the
local jurisdiction would decide whether
or not they want to have a manufacturing
plant of some sort in their jurisdiction
the regulation rests entirely with the
department so they don't set local
manufacturing regulations it's different
what allowed to be sell a fold in a
dispensary what's allowed to be made
falls under the department's produces it
is similar to food in that way so there
isn't there there's no wild wild west as
far as manufactured products or edibles
that's where the thing or at least not
though if we do this right and we can
move people out of the black market
there will be single regulatory
structure for the state as far as
manufactured products ya Yin extra
clarifier regulations as well set the
floor for
level so so the locals can can go sort
of below what our regulatory our license
requirements are they can exceed them
they can further restrict but they can't
say oh hey you can have a thirty
thousand-square-foot license you can't
go just an observation from more i come
from it i was with county government for
16 years I totally understand I'm and
I'm regulated by the Department food
nagging my own business you know the
agriculture community that has been
growing crops to feed the world
understands the process what we've had
is those those who are coming and don't
understand the process of how we get I
totally understand where you're trying
to go and how you're trying to do it you
know that something you're right at some
point we'll have mega-farms out there
and will destroy all these little guys
that are trying to I mean that's what we
do we put each other out of business all
day long in the agricultural community
we over produce it will eventually level
out and then the price will come down
and it won't be the Wild West it will
level out but we need to try to figure
out a way that we can capture that
revenue for the state there are a lot of
consequences that come with you know
bringing this into the regulated market
that we don't even know yet talking
about driving impaired than all those
things there needs to be a revenue that
comes with that when we when we came out
prohibition we've made it was set up a
little better right we basically said
hey you're going to go buy it from this
store and they have a license so if you
want to do alcohol you had to your
license yet to be controlled and if you
weren't at that license you you got a
penalty right now with the way that as
you all know when that way it came
through with the propositions is there's
no place to really we're trying to force
ourselves into that because it's been
set up wrong so I think all or what
you're doing and I think most of the
members here are trying to get to that
point where we actually capture that
revenue and we actually get it in the
control bar so the consumer at the end
knows exactly what when they buy my seed
they know what's in the bag and that's
what we need to know when they when we
sell this stuff that the consumer the
other end goes okay this is what I'm
getting this the potency this it has it
what's it been sprayed with what those
tape cards in there so I appreciate what
you're doing I thank you for taking the
time to come down today appreciate it
thank Jack I know there's several
questions are for you but let's just ask
the first
told question is will we be ready in
January yes all right I like that we
could just make that clear what to
further expand I'm sorry thank you I the
level of coordination January 2018 Yeah
right right there it has been the level
of coordination between the other two
departments and all the state agencies
we are committed to making sure that
this is off the ground and we're
accepting applications on january first
2018 and where we can issue some
licenses on january one 2018 we've made
it very clear not everything we can't
issue everybody a license obviously on
january first 2018 and we we recognize
there's going to be some transitional
periods that we're going to have to make
some decisions like once we license a
dispensary what do we do is the product
that's currently in the dispensaries
because it won't be it won't be tested
and whatnot it won't be in track and
trace so those are some transitional
issues that i think will work through
over the first year and then probably be
working with you to make some tweaks or
making tweak to our regulations as that
occurs yeah absolutely i know we got a
couple spot builds and a lot of members
that are interested but can you talk a
little bit cuz you talked about it is
your testimony the emergency regulations
how that's going to work out how long
you anticipate those to be as we consist
start transitioning into the whole full
regulatory body work alright so at least
for the medical side we're going to go
through the full rulemaking process we
are we are going to like we say we're
going to notice them early spring and
it's going to kick off our 45-day
comment period we're going to have our
hearings across the state get feedback
and then respond to that feedback and
maybe even have to go out for another
comment period then those that we think
a lot of what's in the medical that is a
lot of it's similar to what's in
proposition 64 that is the feedback we
get from that that's going to help us
with those emergency regulations for
prop 64 and then also any legislative
changes we will then do that through the
emergency regulations so we
plein de I think you know we're all
looking at august/september once we have
a clear what the legislature is going to
do and then we're going to work on
probably noticing those and I believe
the statute gives us like 180 days we're
still going to go through the comment
period it'll just be after the fact that
the emergency regulations will take
place an effective immediately or
there's a there's a time period there
got it but you have a game plan in place
and you're ready to go yes we have a
game plan and we have to change that
game plan frequently we're always
reassessing our timeline constantly ok I
have additional questions that I know
members are anxious to ask you to plenty
of questions but let's start with mr.
Cooley and then we'll move to mr.
Johnson really two questions for all the
attendees I thank you very much for
being here this is very much the basic
idea behind 266 was to have a lead
agency apartment with other agencies to
make sure we cover the whole waterfront
but take advantage of expertise so I'm
delighted to just kind of see how it's
unfolding and I mentioned the
characterization just generally not
warranting the level of this but how are
you staffed up at this stage for what
you think you're going to end up being
and I sort of feel like ms Ajax you have
a different challenge than the
established agencies that were sort of
tackling in there is this danger but I'd
be incident getting a quick
characterization from folks on that and
then I'd like to hear a little bit about
the advisory committee I always felt the
advisory committee was a very important
transitional body because the original
prop from 1996 dealt with affordable
access we're going into a different
market and that was a place where issues
of access we're going to be able to be
discussed and it became a way to let low
and moderate income Californians people
dependent upon the old system to have
their voice in the system but so a
characterization of staffing levels just
gently across the 38 season in the
Advisory Committee I'll start with a for
the bureau we were we have a 15 position
that we were through the bcp
that were authorized we currently have
six vacancies but we've also utilized a
lot of temporary help we've have some
limited term attorneys on board we also
have to do a sequel initial study so
we're partnering up with water resources
with MoU with them to help us with that
we also have an MoU with Department of
Public Health to assist us with the
testing lab regulations and we have a
couple of retired annuitant and a couple
student assistants so where we wear our
vacancies are we've we've helped staff
up with some temporary help we also have
the Department of Consumer Affairs that
helps us with a lot of our
administrative tasks with budgets and
helping us with human resources issues
and contracts and so they've been
supplementing us and helping us through
for for our staffing great overview
thank you very much for the Parma Sweden
agriculture we have a hard 22 people so
far and but I mean in terms of how that
relates to the scale budget proposal
proposals to hire 60 people next year
and anticipation because you know the
gamer ones in the budget year and then
but we're full scale we're going to be
you know in excess of 150 employees for
the bid for the division and so I can't
provide you with exact numbers but we're
staffed for the development of the
regulations and what we've done is also
submit for additional positions in the
bcp in order to help us establish
training for people to who want to do
manufacturing I want to become a
licensee's but then also to establish
five at this point we're thinking five
offices throughout the state of
California so there's ready access in
all the different areas and that's going
to require additional staff as well
thank you and for the advisory committee
question so under the medical cameras
regulation and Safety Act there was a it
was a there wasn't required it was a May
and so we are approached with to really
do a robust public outreach for the
first because you know a lot of our
staff including myself there was a lot
of learning we had to do to learn about
the industry how they
operate here about all the concerns so
we use that approach under the medical
instead of the advisory committee but
under proposition 64 is required and we
are working on putting out the process
for selecting those committee members
because we really think that going to be
very helpful when we do the adult use
regulations going forward and where we
really want that input like you said we
need that input let me just ask wouldn't
you anticipate that first advisory
committee coming together for a meeting
well first where we're going to have an
application process and then make the
selection I would wear that's a priority
right now for the for the bureau and so
I expect that to happen very soon okay
so selection process will conclude when
they have anticipated date now or not
yeah we expect to have the application
process of be able to announce that
probably within the next week or so with
like a 30-day period for people to apply
and then make selection so I would
anticipate a first meeting being at
least several months down the road okay
thank you i think mr. Cooley had a
follow-up question i was more going to
make a fall just on session my
recollection is through most life of
this discussion the advisory 20 was was
a shall at the end it probably was
switched to a may but i think the issues
had covered and the and the foot hole
that gave certain people to kind of be
inside the conversation and my statute
sort of affirmed that their viewpoint on
those issues was important is probably
an important piece of kind of how it
moves forward so I do understand as the
Lord of this we shall in May but I think
for the chemistry of how we sort of
advanced a conversation I definitely
think that protected on the issue of
access that's a very important body to
constitute in it and it gives you a way
to give some people and see that the
table that might otherwise feel sort of
not included and I think it becomes it
may be an a but it may be a very useful
management tool for the conversation so
observation on it thank you very much I
need right Thank you Thank You mr. rules
chair looks good i move to mr. reginald
Byron Jones Sawyer senior very good
Thank You mr. chair you know part of and
it might be for all maybe just miss age
actually because you've been singled out
more than anything else part of the
reason why a B 266 was successful after
years and years of people trying to
basically get regulations in I think it
because we had several joint authors
between Mr Bond circle allegiance or
Lackey and mr. wood which we
affectionately call ourselves the
fabulous five we were able to get
something done that nobody else had been
able to do and I think because we were
inclusive we were a broad spectrum of
mod aggressive a broad spectrum of
different geographic areas and I think
most important we also were bipartisan
and I think that really really helped
and us moving to where we are now if you
if you think about if we hadn't put into
regulations now prophet64 passes we
would be starting from scratch scratch
scratch and and so it was the input of
everyone and so from a predominantly
Latino African American community or I'm
very concerned that we may or may not
have an opportunity to be at the table
may not have an opportunity to to have
input I would not I mean I am concerned
that we look up one day we get all this
done and the mobility of people who are
in business are white males with a lot
of money or corporations as my colleague
talked about and we don't afford the
opportunity of people of color to
participate in this in any substance of
ways and i'm not talking about selling
to us because we are great consumers but
do we have an opportunity to participate
the second part of that is the impacts
that it can have on our community I know
when we went down this road of having
liquor stores for example probably more
affluent areas that probably became
liquor store boutiques where they're so
fine wines they were unbelievable
detriment to disadvantaged communities
and I think at the onset nobody ever
really could perceived that it would be
a problem and I think part of that is
because no one included people from
disadvantaged communities Latino African
American in the process in my district
I'm not certain if you reached out or
had any hearing in my district the 50
nights Assembly District which is south
los angeles as you can show me that that
would be fine it would be great to know
but more important if the outreach has
not been a successful because i don't
know is there ways that we can make it
even more successful in the future going
from a positive point of view if it's a
whatever we can do to ensure that you
get full full of input from from these
disadvantaged communities we need to do
that especially as we move from medical
marijuana to to full class adult use
again it's my responsibility Valerie's
an assemblyman but to to look out for
the impact that will have on
disadvantaged communities and try to see
it see ahead of it instead of waiting
for it to drop on us disadvantaged our
communities and then we have to be back
here trying to figure out how to clean
it up this is a great opportunity now to
have those discussions and not wait
until later and so I and I I'm hearing
about hiring I'm hearing about a an
advisory committee hopefully we're
looking at making sure it's inclusive of
everyone
that you don't become advisory board as
I like to say it the white is white
board you ever seen but you do include
people of color in these discussions and
and make sure i guess most important
that they're heard any comic or also
heard crickets again no I completely
agree with you and I we the bureau and I
think all of us are committed to making
sure we hear from everybody and I think
from day one that's what we want we want
to get input from everybody not just
certain folks but to be inclusive and I
think there's always room for
improvement I look forward to working
with your office we were in the LA area
and but downtown where people could
hopefully get to easily but I think the
more outreach we do the better our
regulations are going to be and the
better informed we are also working with
the locals we've worked a lot with the
local cities and counties because there
is local control they do they've been
dealing with this a lot longer than the
state and so learning from them on their
affected communities what you know there
are some really good robust cities and
counties out there that have cannabis
regulations and learning from them and
moving forward with that so I am
committed to work i think the other
thing is is our application process
making people understand the application
process once we notice our regulation
doing that outreach and telling people
about the opportunity and what they need
to have in hand on day one when they
want to apply with the bureau or one of
the other departments and explaining
that process and getting out to the
communities so that they are empowered
to go seek a license and not have to
hire a lawyer or consultant to do it for
them so i think that also comes into
play with our regulations and making
them simple and comprehensive and so
that's what we're committed to going
forward and i look forward to working
with your office so it sounds like the
message has been received and it's a
good segue into our next panel to
to see how that's actually working on
the local level but I just have to quick
follow-up questions for you but say Jax
and then we're going to move on unless
members have additional questions but
you know you touched upon you know us
making sure we're how long the licenses
ready for 2018 is there a priority like
how are we prioritizing that how are we
going to work through that I don't know
if you expand on that just a little bit
and then going to have one more question
so there is priority licensing in both
medical and the adult use statutes and
so we're going to be looking at you know
most of it is people who are currently
in operation or good standing so we're
going to be looking at that when we
prioritize who we licensed fun on
starting in january of 2018 and there is
also authority in the adult use for us
to a temporary licenses okay thank you
and then maybe I should ask this is all
three of you as mature women caballero
sherman mr. wood and myself there's a
lot of bills being talked about and
proposed and spot bills are currently
before us are going to come before us
but do you anticipate anything that we
should be focusing on I know we touched
off a little bit earlier or we need to
do the entire fix but something we
should be looking at specifically as the
chairs of these three committees yeah I
mean I think we're having discussions
but both internally and those folks are
having conversations with legislative
representatives about sort of what those
areas are I mean certainly at the
department food nag there's a difference
between the two licensed types other
requirements under Merkerson and if
acquirements that our prop 64 are
different so reconciling those something
that you know that's our sort of part of
the conversation is that I think other
entities have sort of similar
discrepancies but I know that there's
sort of a working group of folks that
are hammering those out so maybe I
should ask a question a little bit
differently because I know we're going
to have the reconciliation bill later on
but are there any specific legislative
needs to specifically for
department that are dated at this time
or we're just kind of work through it
will figure it out yeah I think it's
matter