[Music]
there's a fight on this one
in terms of interpretation of what is
microbial progress and so microbial is a
living organisms of fungus it bacteria
that live on the surface of basically
everything now some of these things are
deadly like e.coli so things like e.coli
which we test for on cannabis we want to
see none but what we're having problems
with is having East issues and East is
something that is present in it's really
present if you're using enzymatic scuzz
enzymatic SAR using yeast to do the work
and so for a lot of people who used
enzymatic sit invalidated the cannabis
for a lot of people like me who use
compost tea it has ability didn't
validate your cannabis and so what we're
trying to understand is how does one
take a look at other agricultural
industries that use organic
methodologies and find safe working
levels for these things and so the state
of California standards are actually
pretty good and they're pretty
reasonable and what you have is you had
new standards get brought in they call
them the Berkeley standards and those
standards are based more on a conceptual
purity and what it does is it basically
renders probably 95% of the Sun grown
market red out of existence and there's
this belief that these this yeast must
be it must be terrible for you but it's
on every single piece of organic fruit
vegetable herb that you buy so you've
been consuming tons of it your entire
existence with never any issues
and so what you're having is you're
having companies that are looking to
generate more testing requirements to
benefit the companies versus individuals
trying to create standards that makes
sense for production models and I think
the California will actually do a pretty
good job with this I think they're gonna
take a look at this and realize that you
can't put a zero living tissue count
where there's nothing on the plant from
an outside plant growing the Sun and it
favors an organic model or favors an
indoor model heavily because we can
completely control everything but the
problem is does that mean that that's
really real does one need to have
sterility on a product as any of my
other agricultural products sterile no
so the only thing we're talking about
sterility on is cannabis and so it
doesn't really hold suit I hold suit
that somebody's gonna make money on a
standard and I think that that's really
how you have to look at this it's such
an issue that when we did the golden
tarp this year we change the microbials
to where it reflects the California not
the Berkeley standards and we said
listen these are the things that we're
gonna work with we're numbers that make
sense
it's a toxic component like you call I
know it's not allowed but on some of
these yeasts and molds that are
prohibiting organic cultivators from
getting their products and it's only
it's impossible to can see that that's
not healthy product so at the golden
time what we did is we change the
requirements so that we're able to
really focus on that sun-grown sector
and once we start to have some
individuals who can interpret organic
methodologies correctly and explain it
to the people who are regulating
cannabis correctly when we'll have this
Saturday but in the meantime it's pretty
difficult so what we've done you know
here at the nursery was I went through a
tremendous number of plants that are
really tough they'll let me grow them
dry which means no fungal sprays and no
composting spreads and I really love
using compost teas on plants because it
just really boosts up the helping plant
overall but because of some of these
standards I dropped it way back I pulled
out a certain cultivars out of the
library that I know just come up hotter
and it's because if the Berkeley
standard is used it Bakley hit almost it
wipes out the you know the entire crop
and so these things just don't make any
sense because they're they don't reflect
reality
and that has to be addressed and I think
that the California regulators will and
I think that they'll do a pretty good
job I don't see the situation like other
states in the same way where they want a
favor a buffered into a model because
California has electrical problems that
are just out of control meaning no grid
capacity and who anywhere in the world
if you didn't grow it outside California
I mean if you can't grow it here were
you gonna grow so you have this
incredible opportunity to grow
efficiently effectively agriculturally
soundly once we start to rain in the
requirements for testing do you think do
you think that
it would be a good idea for some of
these people who are using compost
sprays and such to wash their cannabis
would that improve their ability to pass
some of these testing standards and then
of course keep super-clean trim
environments yeah you know I mean a lot
of year a lot of year a lot of your
yeast and mold is coming out of the dirt
so basically if we keep the dust down at
your property that helps a lot and the O
in terms of washing washing washing
possibility of Washington not with water
with with the hydrogen peroxide solution
we can use an h2o to solution that and
it's basically going to be like a it's
going to peel some of that surface
fungal off and it can take plants that
wouldn't have passed the make and pass
but the idea that your and wetting
cannabis before you harvest it isn't
terrible it's it's good to clean it off
a lot of times but to have to harvest an
entire entire crop and wash every flower
if it's maybe about a washing you're
doing here is ungodly and I'm like wait
a minute wait a minute and so it's it's
for people the strategy that we explain
this year a lot of people was let's get
into cultivars that don't require the
buffer let's get into cultivars that
don't require a lot of the microbial
assisters meaning things that you had
had to help you work with pathogenic
pressure and so it limited the number of
choices in the library to be used for
the cultivators that understood it they
were doing they found stuff that didn't
need any assistance and I did the same
thing now I had one plant that I ran as
a test and it came up too hot for
Berkeley so it would be able to move
under the California but not the
Berkeley standards and so that's one
that depending on if you're trying to
push it to a store that uses the
Berkeley then it would invalidate it so
I have to be able to kind of cattle
does what when and where and then it
lets me know can you use the tool
appropriately and so once we get this
reigned in reasonable legal open up a
tremendous number of cultivars again for
usage and it will allow us to really get
these biologically driven systems up to
spec to where they belong because you
have to have the biology on the surface
effort early in in the root zone and if
you can do this it works in concert to a
degree that's unbelievable and that just
has to be seen as non-harmful an
organically driven apple is pretty
healthy I don't see why I'm so afraid of
it and then with cannabis it should be
the same but because it's cannabis it's
looked at as something very different
and so cannabis being the single most
agriculturally regulated product in
human history who knows but what we know
is that I think California is going to
really look at these standards and rein
them into reality because if they don't
make any sense right so you think that
the not just the Berkeley standards but
the California standards need to be
adjusted California is actually not too
bad
Calif lung is not too bad where they're
saying in chloroform's on coal lies all
these things that you do not want to
have in your products zero but then on
euston moles it's an allowable and I
want to say it comes up to like maybe
four to five percent of the total weight
by volume you know total weight of the
product can exceed this so much of an
encounter and these are standards use
from other organic
I say certification industries agencies
for food production because you're
taking data from where see that's the
problem with a lot of canvases and
there's never been any Studies on it in
a way that lets us use any kind of
pesticide so the FDA epa none of these
people will certify anything so nothing
could ever be tested or used and
determined hey this is something that
used here this way is a safe for human
consumption we don't really have any of
that assistance and so the problem a lot
of us is trying to take information from
one industry interpret it and apply it
to another and depending on who is
teaching you this information are they
trying to teach you were they trying to
push an agenda and I just think that the
State of California's numbers really not
too bad and that with a little bit of
adjustment into reality that it'll it'll
be an accurate system and a safer so if
a farmer has cannabis it does test
positive for mold or mildew or yeast
what are their options concentrate yeah
you know concentrate in the Croods
distillates things that you're gonna do
an extract on or you can peel a lot of
that out I mean if it's too covered in
mold no but if it's if it's just east of
mold and stuff yeah you can blow it and
that those will come out in the
extraction process
[Music]