[Music]
focused on compliance ish sending things
one of my bigger concerns has been the
way people are paying their employees
and documenting that so waging our
compliance our people classify his
employees versus independent contractors
correctly
oftentimes in this industry people are
labeled as independent contractors or
even volunteers when they're really
employees so it's been a big hot button
issue categorizing employees accurately
so can you talk about what you're seeing
in the cannabis industry yeah I think it
is well I don't think I know it is
largely driven by the banking problem
and historically these companies not
being able to run a traditional payroll
because they didn't have a banking
relationship and a misunderstanding that
you can't pay employees and cash what
you can it's just not done in a
traditional business because it's just
complicated messy and cumbersome but as
a result of that there was sort of a
default to callin people all sorts of
things as I mentioned volunteers or paid
interns or independent contractors when
really the individual was an employee
and California law had been a little bit
more complicated in years past but more
recently there was a decision that came
down that simplified it and if you're
controlling the means and manner in
which people are doing your work if
they're working on the core business
that you're in
you're a grower of throwing if you're a
manufacturer if they're on the floor
making products if you're a dispensary
if they're selling products if they're
doing your core business and if they
don't have a job outside of yours by and
large they are your employees so they
should be treated like employees and
really to the point of why labor and
employment lawyers would ever get
involved they need to be paid like
employees because if you don't pay an
employee like an employee all sorts of
really bad things start to happen you
may not be tracking their hours
correctly or you may not be at least
documenting them you may not be paying
them for overtime either eight in a day
or 40 in a week you're just paying them
some sort of a lump sum per week as an
independent contractor that could create
liability for not paying all hours or
not paying overtime you may not be
giving them meal periods or rest breaks
or if you are you may not be documenting
that they're doing that again this opens
you up to liability and I hate to be the
bearer of bad news but people actually
don't tell the truth sometimes and they
will stretch the truth when they want to
get money out of the business and
they'll say I'm not getting my new
period or I'm working off the clock or
I'm not being paid off my overtime and
if you dream them like an independent
contract or you don't have all these
documents that you know they would have
for an employee you're sort of left
there saying well yeah but and then of
course going to look at you and say well
prove
imitation so those are some of the
things that grow a lot of not treating
employees like employees and if you have
unpaid time or unpaid or underpaid time
or overtime or people are not getting
their meal periods of the rest breaks
and you're not giving them an itemized
wage statement that sort of lists all of
the things that are supposed to be out
there these pencil the penalties start
mounting under the California Labor Code
they get really expensive and it's not
unusual for me to speak to somebody and
say oh we do all this a person $800 in
overtime and $6,000 in penalties plus
their attorneys fees and people are sort
of shocked to learn that an $800 wage
claim can turn into a $15,000 wage claim
downtown at that the labor board but it
happens so these are really these can be
business killers and you've seen this
play out in cannabis businesses yes okay
yep yep without naming companies can't
can you give me an exploit you just
mentioned was that an actual case like
it was 800 it turned into 15,000 not in
the cannabis space but we've seen
something along those lines we've also
seen people that were classified as
independent contractors going to the
labor board and saying hey I wasn't paid
correctly and then go into other state
agencies in making claims of
discrimination or harassment and the
first threshold for those agencies are
going to be well are you employed or not
because if you're an independent
contractor you're not given some of the
same rights that you are if you're an
employee and the first thing that those
individuals need to do is pierce through
that sort of definition or
classification and convince the
administrative law judge or a judge that
hey I'm not an independent contractor
I'm an employee and because of that I'm
protected from discrimination or I'm
overtime wages and they also have a very
difficult
job for the candidates employer to
overcome so as an example it's expected
that I show up at nine and stay till
5:00 p.m. Monday through Friday
which is sort of a baseline definition
of independent contractors have choice
of one and how and where they get the
work done employees are expected to you
know on a set schedule be there and do
the work yeah so that's a tradition a
traditional sort of consideration and
there used to be a long list of things
that courts would look at and really
grows out of the IRS is definitions of
independent contractors versus employees
and a number of cases I sort of adopted
them but as I mentioned that the
California courts really simplified
things maybe six months ago beginning
part of 2018 and made it much more
difficult to treat somebody as an
independent contractor whereas before
you would look at hours of work and
equipment used and all of these other
things it's not three factors they call
it the ABC test this is that individual
are you controlling the means in the
manner in which the individual is doing
their job are they performing your core
business and do they have an independent
business outside of what they do for you
and if those things aren't being met
they're unemployed it's just that simple
so what you were describing where nine
to five you're telling them when to show
up where to go to work I do their job
that's all you know that that's a
quacking duck that that duck is employed
on anything contract workers comp is
something that we're increasingly seeing
questions come on I'm not a worker's
comp expert but I will I will tell
people in the industry that are confused
that there are workers comp policies
that they over for their employees it's
mandated that any employer in California
have those they need to have them in
place if they don't the penalties are
pretty onerous and again this goes to
training your managers or the people
that are sort of at the front line
dealing with the data
alignment issues if somebody comes
forward and reports an injury at work
you have to take some steps immediately
to preserve certain rights and it's also
the right thing to do but there's
there's a form you need to give to the
individual to allow them to make a claim
to identify what the injury is and get
them into that process if somebody's not
carrying workers comp whether or not to
buy that notice of rights and they're
allowing injured workers to continue to
work there's some serious liability that
can that can flow from that and then
sort of anecdotally we sort of are
interested to watch around the country
how certain judges nobody in California
have actually ordered workers comp
carriers to pay for marijuana as a
treatment for certain injuries so that's
something many of our carrier clients
are watching very closely to see if
that's going to explain how to price the
risk and what's going to be available
for employees but then also how to
administer it because if you're a
worker's comp carrier if you can imagine
you getting premium dollars in you're
paying benefits out and somebody says I
want you to pay for some sort of a
cannabis derived product for pain
medication or something else like what's
the logistics for actually pay for that
medicine or are insurance companies
gonna start handing dollars directly to
dispensaries or should they get them to
the individuals and the concern there
becomes are we effectively engaging in
something that's unlawful by providing
money to a claimant knowing that they're
going to go use it to buy something
that's vitally illegal so it's a bit of
a there's a maturation that's happening
very quickly tonight I don't know
precisely what it's borne up but I do
know that there are people coming from
other industries into cannabis that sort
of encounter it outside of the lawyers
on on the ground inside of a
manufacturing warehouse I'm saying like
what is this we can't do business like
that which is great there's been
insurance so insurance products come in
and they underwrite and they're
identifying some of these things and
saying we can't write insurance unless
you
improve certain things and then folks
like myself have become more active and
interfacing with the industry and
educating them and teaching them all of
these sort of things are quickly moving
and pushing the industry along to the
point where you are getting more formal
processes for hiring people people being
reclassified and put into their right
classifications people being able to
sort of identify a phony termination and
pick up the phone and call somebody like
myself before they pull the trigger on
it so it's gotten better but but overall
I would say it is no different than
anything else it's not because it's the
cannabis industry entirely it's just
because it's a new industry a lot of the
operators tend to be younger or less
experienced or at least they were when
they started first time operators
exactly exactly that they just need to
have a focus to those and I the other
part of it they that I didn't mention a
minute ago is for the last three years
the focus has been on regulatory reform
having licensing regulations in place
doing what's required to get the license
in place and now in a state like
California there's probably a lifecycle
like this in every state now that more
and more businesses are sort of over the
hump on getting that license and they're
turning to running their business these
things are now getting more attention
because they just can't so I would
encourage those businesses that are
either taking in some private equity
money or doing fundraising or just
coming out of the licensing phase and
going back to doing their business if
you want to be successful in the long
haul and you want to be attractive to
investors who are going to be able to
make investments in your company so that
you can grow be able to demonstrate that
you have solid onboarding processes that
you've got some policies and procedures
in place and that you train to them you
take
serious it's not just a handbook that
Dean Rocco gives you and you throw it in
a file somewhere and as you go forward
and you manage your employees you do so
in a wise way and if you sort of
identify that there's some thorny issues
you know work with an HR consultant that
you can trust or an employment lawyer
like myself and figure out sort of what
the risk management would be as you go
through those then you don't have to
look over your shoulder too much as you
[Music]