and speaking about other you know
cannabis solutions is his Big Pharma and
dr. Ethan Russo is here to talk on the
three echelons of cannabis commerce
pharmaceutical development standardized
cannabis supplements and artisanal
production you know Ethan you talk about
a peaceful coexistence can you explain
that to us and what that would mean to
us as a collective first by way of
introduction yes I'm a neurologist but
I've been an organic farmer since 1974
when I was a grad student at UC Davis
additionally while I was in practice in
Montana I ran a thing called boffo the
Blackford organic fruit and flower
operation and sold the most expensive
organic vegetables you can imagine at
the farmers market and Missoula but
there are three echelons of activity in
terms of how cannabis is produced the
model that you probably will not be
emulating is the pharmaceutical model in
that I like to say that there four
pillars of true medicine and got a
graphic here I find now you've probably
all read the hundred page PDF that I
sent but anyway this is just a little
analog demonstration so the four pillars
of a true medicine are efficacy does it
work safety self-explanatory
standardization that might require a
little more explanation can you show
absolute chemical consistency over time
and this is a prerequisite of a
pharmaceutical and then the one that's
often ignored is the fourth one called
accessibility and that's a combination
is it available number one but number
two is it affordable because if it's not
if we're talking about biological
medicine the things they advertised on
TV and they hope you're not listening
when there are two paragraphs of
rapid-fire side-effects that they
scribe most of those medicines are in
the 50 to 60 K per year range and cost
now you're dealing in a much more
reasonable level so beyond the
pharmaceutical model which is generally
a 10 to 12 year proposition and
somewhere between 800 and one-point
million and 1.2 billion expenditure it
is the case that you can make a
botanical medicine that's a
pharmaceutical approvable by the FDA
this has been done with epi dialects 98%
pure CBD I would have been a lot happier
if that had been an extract with full
flavor and capabilities in the medicine
but I don't work at that company anymore
but you're not likely going to be going
for that if anybody's interested in
genuine pharmaceutical production we can
talk more later the second echelon of
activity would be material that's still
pretty standardized but would say be
sold on the supplement market and so
this could be any number of products
that are derived from cannabis probably
not so much straight flower but any kind
of extraction and it could be a topical
it could be oral could be some of the
products that we've seen people bring
today but this isn't a growth area
clearly a lot of you might know people
like horizon herbs and things like that
some of those people especially in
Southern Oregon had big enough
operations that they were able to put
out their own tinctures commercially and
this kind of thing this is again
requires a lot of bureaucratic rigmarole
to do properly but it's below the
pharmaceutical effort and finally is the
the artisanal for lack of a better term
now it's not the case that everyone has
an expert herbalist in their
neighborhood and can vouch for you know
this batch material is really strong so
you want to be very careful with it as
opposed to it's good for this condition
and not so much for that condition but
for you that have been doing this a long
time I'm sure you have good ideas about
what you have and what it's good for and
that hopefully can also succeed in the
current difficult market but you do have
to distinguish yourself in some way and
I'll be talking a lot more about how to
do that later particularly with regards
to different components of cannabis on
how what their therapeutic benefits are
and how they can be leveraged in a
patient population