[Music]
I've talked to Lori Jenks before and I
was like okay well let's talk about
advertising love to help with the
regulations love to help what you're
doing I said some of these don't make
sense they're based on the old school
Nielsen's radio absolutely and that
doesn't really work anymore and I think
you and I have discussed previously like
Nielsen rating is literally like you get
a phone call hey Roger right did you
watch that Seinfeld last night how long
did you watch it for yeah frequently to
watch it for and that's it just doesn't
exist now in a world we're like digital
media and digital everything is the way
people market how do you enforce that
right well that's actually a really
interesting way to get on what you guys
are doing right so traffic routes well
why don't you get the good people at
home a little information about about
what you guys are doing at traffic
routes yeah so traffic routes we are a
digital ad network so as you may or may
not know advertising in cannabis is a
challenge yeah simply because it's still
federally legal 1/2 and there's a lot of
unknowns so the traditional outlets such
as Facebook Google Instagram technically
you can't do it they're their guidelines
and regulations are very specific to
Facebook they just change some of that
though right they changed their search
criteria right but not their advertisers
right here so there is a misconception
there and I can touch on that as well
but simply because it's federally legal
now Facebook won't touch it obviously
Google won't touch it either right and
the one question I'll just answer it now
that I get the most is like well what
happens when it does go legal what
happens if it goes federally you know
right
so there are well double-click all of a
sudden me and the answer nothing's gonna
change simply because those guys are too
interconnected with some of these bigger
ad networks like double-click like
Google yeah and they're not gonna risk
losing one of the bigger accounts like
Ford or Chevy or tired or whatever
because they show a cannabis ad next to
something like that right but more
importantly to take out of this is
cannabis isn't the only sector that
Google and Facebook won't touch there's
actually other areas that are federally
legal that Google and Facebook will not
touch like tobacco alcohol Firearms
Pharma nutriceuticals adult crypto so
kind of those polarizing topics where
yes you don't want to be seen - you
don't wanna be associated want to be
associated so in every single one of
those as a single siloed industry is
much bigger economy wise in cannabis
right so for those people that think
that once cannabis goes federally legal
that Facebook and Google gonna open up
their arms right I'm not sure if that's
gonna be that easy well so what makes
traffic routes different in that you're
able to publish advertisement on non
cannabis sites valid question yeah so
what we do is we work directly with the
sites and believe it or not at the site
level they're very open to it
we've been able to connect with some of
the you know pretty significant big
sites that are pushing a ridiculous
amount of users about 150 some of them
150 million unique users a month okay
and they're very open to it they're open
to the CBD they're open to a lot of
these cannabis products because it is
the the the new thing right and it's to
an extent it's there if they're open to
other things they're open to cannabis
right so how about from so it's from an
advertising perspective how about from a
Content perspective right like so are
these are these bigger sites opening up
to cannabis content yes okay yes so the
other question I get asked a lot is well
you know what about the age wall if I'm
advertising on a on a CNN or I'm
advertising on a Newsweek or I would you
know do they have to have an age wall
and I think that's another misconception
that people have the age wall isn't
really on the content sites the CNN
writes about right and of us all the
time yep Newsweek as well and some of
these other bigger publications also but
there is no age wall because it is
content the age wall comes into effect
once you click on that ad right and you
go to the product page right that's
where the age wall needs to live and
that's what needs to be in for
because that's where you're really
entering the product phase right not at
the content line you know it's no
different than alcohol tobacco right
these sort of things same thing I
remember years ago I worked for Sky
vodka and Campari and putting up those
age walls and those guys definitely even
though there are limitations on where
they can advertise you do see
advertisements for for liquor companies
for alcohol companies and then once you
get to the site that's where you had to
make sure you're collecting the the age
wall which I mean let's be honest right
like January 1st 1969 or something like
that right everyone puts in if it's the
bogus it's like it's just this
requirement that you have to have and no
one pays any attention it's like yeah
sure I'm over 21 but that's a liability
situation right that's what it is
content site does not have to have age
wall but a product side once you click
from the site to the product is where
the content page and the age one needs
to live we touch on the topic that you
and I know talked about quite a bit
which is education right it is and it's
not so much that there are so many
things you can and can't do I think it's
really more the problem really more so
as people aren't educated and have
clearly defined guidelines I'm sure
because every time I have a conversation
with somebody you know like you you and
I spent a lot of time together we talk
about this I think we're both pretty
well-informed about what the issues are
and aren't but I have so many
conversations with other people were
like well you can't do this and you're
like well actually I can you just have
to be very careful about it right and I
mean what's what's the solution there
like how do we you know I know we spend
a lot of time educating our clients you
know for us we we were one of the first
companies to focus on being TCPA
compliant so that we make sure that
anyone who's receiving our messaging has
opted into it and all that and make sure
they can opt out of it whenever they
want I know a lot of other companies who
came before us weren't so focused and
that's you know kind of the nature of
this industry and that so many people
would rather ask your forgiveness and
permission true right and now it's
catching up with a lot of folks it is
right it does come to education and I
think I think you're at the panel you
know last week when we talked on
education and what gluten-free was right
and I gave that example yep and I think
that's a pretty I think that falls in
line with kind of what we're talking
about
if we take that as an example again and
we say well who's following a
gluten-free diet now and who was
following a gluten-free diet
5 years ago 10 years ago 5 10 years ago
nobody knew what the hell was gluten
free yeah but because of education and
the marketing behind the education now
it's becoming a standard of like oh I'm
gluten free or I am this and I think
that's that's kind of where we are now
we have to set a standard only within
the marketing guidelines but really
explain to people how that affects their
brand and how can they affect their
their overall performance as a brand
right in such a gray industry especially
in the digital side yeah
on the digital side it's even more
complex simply because obviously we both
have internet at home yeah I don't know
if the Internet's registered under your
you know your fiancee your daughter your
aunt your mom I don't know yep and who
that internet it's registered to under
means nothing to who's behind that
screen agreed yeah and when you register
for your internet provider they don't
ask you for age they don't ask you how
many people on your household they don't
ask you who's gonna be using it there's
social name and address that's it so
from an advertising perspective it's
really hard to be able to track age
demographic on who behind who's behind
that screen right you can do data
overlays it gives you similar audiences
but a one-to-one relation on who that is
it's nearly impossible yeah now unless
something changes you touched on on you
know branding and marketing and unite we
spend a lot of time talking about this
and I think it's really really
interesting what's happening right now
and the emerging the emerging market
right so the newly acquired customers
right I mean you spend a lot of time
talking to advertisers and publishers I
know you know we do the same and for us
I think number one a demographic that
we're looking at right now is maybe the
Chardonnay mom you know we spend a lot
of time talking about the senior
community right and like these are
segments that need very different kinds
of of advertising of marketing they're
not comfortable you know they don't
understand strains they don't understand
straight names we talked about effect
based marketing like how is all this
impacting the work that you're doing
right now
how doesn't I think that creative we
talked in a creative life the last
penalty right yeah so we've taken a very
different approach and the way we the
way I see our ad network is kind of like
an investment portfolio we have to have
a very diverse portfolio of sites
whether it's cannabis sites mainstream
sites in mainstream I mean like
soccer-mom sites culture sites for men
sports sites tennis golf extreme sports
as well snowboarding skateboarding video
gaming believe it or not one of the most
interesting group of sites that we
started working with that reached out to
us was this group of publishers that
have about 50 sites I was like okay
let's talk you know see what you guys
have and they own crochet sites knitting
sites cooking sites nice scrapbooking
sites
Chardonnay mom Sharda mom Chardonnay
moms that's what you want everyone in
those in those sites are doing very well
not surprised
very well because that's like the mom
that it's kind of in the closet yeah
they want to kick that bottle of wine
yeah that went from one glass to two
glasses to a 750 milliliter bottle and
they're like well I'm gonna drink a
bottle now but it's not gonna be 750
it's gonna be 1.7 right let's do a
bottle a night absolutely and then
they're they're kind of dragging the
next day so I think that the modern
consumer is not the the stigma that they
were involved in seen in the past yeah
it's different I think a lot of the you
know a lot of people want to believe
that you need to market to this donor
culture in this space and quite frankly
let me don't get me wrong there is a
strong stoner component and then what
we've seen out there what is an ever
dwindling segment of the market right
it's a growing that's all it is it's in
addition to right which is why you know
we talked we touched a little bit on
effect based marketing right which i
think is really really interesting it's
a trend that's happening right now
you know the Chardonnay mom doesn't care
what strain she doesn't care of his
banana cut she doesn't care if it's og
cush she wants to know is this gonna
make me relax
yes is this gonna make me sleep is this
gonna make me focus what is this gonna
do for me and I feel like you know again
going back to the fact that you work
with non cannabis
I feel like from that angle that really
opens up a lot more opportunity it does
right because you're not talking about
this you know you're not talking to an
echo full of you know a room full of
echoes yeah they're talking to a new
audience you're dressing and it's even
today I think the stigma of cannabis
consumers are still there I mean if you
and I both walked out of our houses
tomorrow morning and we talked and we
knocked it you know three nor three
three doors to the right and three doors
to the left every single what I was
going to deny it the third cab is
consumers yeah but behind closed doors
it might be a different story
oh great and in that different story is
simply because of that stigma but
they're afraid they're gonna be
categorized that and and I think through
education through more normalization of
products that stigma is slowly being
ground
absolutely now you see this now I mean
you walk into just as an example am
Edmund right and they very carefully
curate their brands that they have on on
display you're not seeing you know I we
refer to it the bongs and thongs era of
cannabis right you're not seeing
everything in green and pot leaves on
everything and bright Rasta this and you
know that's that's all out the window
and now you know you have brands again
you know not to pick any one out for any
reason but like select for example comes
to mind Kiva comes to mind right these
are brands dosis comes to mind right
right these are brands that you look at
you go that's intriguing that's that's
not an intimidating package it doesn't
say anything about a specific strain it
says very clearly on the front it says
column you know they can destin does
this as well just calm says connect it
says sleep and you know as someone who I
mean I've been consuming since I was
eighteen there's twenty some years now
so for me none of that stuff matters but
if I'm talking to my mom you know they
have nowhere to run like they don't know
they have no idea I have no idea right
and so I think and for in that situation
my mom would be like I need you to come
to the store with me like if I'm gonna
do this I need you to come to serve with
me and point stuff out and be I get
people asked this to me all the time but
do you think your mom would go to the
store and order go for flour now from
the top no god I go vape go babe
edible actually sure I go edible right
which with so many people make a mistake
of doing that is their first product in
that they try because they think it's
safe it's a form factor they're familiar
with
yeah you're really oh man you're you're
walking a fine line there you overdue an
edible and you're you're never coming
back right which I mean is that an
opportunity is that an opportunity for
education that tell people I know this
seems like the way to go because it's
something that is familiar and it's a
brownie or it's a candy true but in
reality if you overdo it you know you're
gonna have a bad expedite you know what
Iran actually at the CBD Expo not too
long ago I ran to a gentleman that has
CBD wine and teach the infused wine very
nice I was like okay there you go you
know it's funny you said that
who was it Sarah McLachlan she did she
has a line I believe and it's one of the
few that I've seen that is both alcohol
and THC because so many the ones that
I've seen are Jets I thought it was
illegal to do THC and I'll call together
and I don't I don't know if this was
something that happened before all the
do regulations went into place but ya
know what from what I seen for the most
part it's a non-alcoholic beverages that
have THC or CBD added and you know
beverages we were at yeah we were at new
s last week right it was a I think BDS
scale talked about trends in the
marketplace in the beverage segment is
actually it's growing like crazy right
now
and that's I personally I love an
infused beverage I had I feel like I'm
dropping plugs but I honestly I'm not
getting paid for any of this but is it
sprig
I think sprig right yeah it's great CBD
infused sparkling waters I mean it's I
think they're doing great stuff there I
know and in Colorado Keith's Cola but
again
those guys are around longer and there
you go like Keith Cola I think it's very
almost stoner right I mean you know what
Keef is I know what Keef is but the
Chardonnay mom doesn't know what Keef is
right and so I think that a lot of that
is changing now yeah I'd be really
interested to see especially with what
you guys are doing I'm assuming you've
got analytics around everything that
you've done we have so much data yeah I
think yes probably while we get along
yeah exactly as we need nerd out about
that all day long you have any sort of
trends that you're seeing a you want to
talk about anything
I think CBD right now is doing really
well there's hands down especially
online because it's a product that you
can advertise you can sell they can
monetize you can see a return immediate
right
it I'm here I'm curious I'll stop you
there for a second Horace again just to
maybe have a polarizing conversation
about this
we spent Rico and I we spent a lot of
time talking about who's an opportunist
in a space right now right like who's a
good actor who's an opportunist who's
just trying to make a quick buck of all
the CBD companies that you're seeing
what percentage do you think are
actually selling what they say they're
selling or how much of it is a placebo
effect it's hard to say yeah it's hard
to say because there's so many of those
that are being white-label
yeah that's hard to see and track like
who is the who's at the top yeah who's
at the table and whose product is it
really it's just been relabeled right
absolutely doing a little bit of
research actually smart thing to do yeah
well don't get me wrong I think there's
a lot of CVD companies that are doing
the right thing more than there's more
good actors and bad actors let's say
that yeah but just in general I think
education once again you have to get you
have to do it yeah do it and it's not a
kid it can be overwhelming because
there's so many damn products out there
absolutely but it's nothing that can't
be done right it's just a matter of time
it's testing just like anything yeah
getting some samples trying the products
yeah that work for you and every person
is different yeah I know I mean for me
I'm one of those people that I can
consume all the CBT in the world and I
barely feel any affect off of it my
fiancee any other hand she loves it
she has a bit of anxiety little CVD goes
a long way for her helps her take the
edge off so I think I think it's a great
you know not to use a overplayed term
it's a great gateway drug you know to
get people involved in the cannabis
world because I've seen so many people
who even have some difficulty they have
to give them a little bit of pause to
even try the CBD through and and it's
really it's difficult to overstate how
non psychoactive it is right now like
you truly don't get any nothing nothing
I mean it's
but people still very hesitant but it
works it does yeah work yeah absolutely
so my dad has had all kinds of surgeries
knees shoulders like literally open back
surgery significant stuff not a drinker
obviously never consumed anything so one
of the trade shows I got some CBD
patches okay yeah the one to one and
then the TG that are one to one as well
and I gave a CBD you want it's it I'm
gonna get you ha just give it a try for
your back I give to him in a Thursday by
Saturday morning who's asking me for
more really it's like I don't know what
it is but it works I love that yeah and
it's like I'm like here try to teach g1
he's like this one even works better
right and it's a topical situation where
that's that's a good way to get you
anyway
as long as you're not ingesting it I
feel like people are more open to it
open it Ryan it's what they think it's
that perception if I smoke right I'm
gonna get a high even if it's CBD yeah
if I take something it's gonna go
systemic and it's gonna affect me yeah
but if it's topical it's topical right
exactly what's funny is how many people
how many of those people who are
hesitating but we're willing to go try a
topical solution do you think they've
ever looked at the ingredient list on
any other topical they've ever put on
themselves oh never know don't know the
first thing that goes into one of those
topics and there's probably worse oh my
god worse ingredients in there than CBD
so we were talking about trends so yours
we talked about CVD that's a big one
everyone's talking about it right again
I think it's because it's the one that's
safer yeah it's it's like you said it's
a very easy entry point
yeah industry and it's it's a non
aggressive non like you don't need to
know too much of the different strains
or different products or different types
to be able to understand it it's it's a
very simple product to understand when
it's a pill or just a swab or a teacher
whatever it is it's a lot easier one of
the trend side the CVS are doing really
well beverages as we talked about I'm
seeing more and more but sticking with
the trends I think it comes down to
the brands that are doing well are not
packaging it as yet as high as you can
get on it and that's that's important to
understand because that in itself will
attract that soccer-mom yeah that
professional woman that professional man
and that's that's the audience that has
the money absolutely to spend it yeah
and I remember this when we first
started Baker about four and a half
years ago I remember being in Colorado
and I had one of our guys come home with
his roommate who had just come home from
a cannabis store and he was excited
because he had this headband oh gee
and he's like 35% THC is like whoa count
me out like I I want no part of that
right and back then it really was a you
know and I've since dubbed this in
conversations I've had this prohibition
mentality right you want the biggest
bang for your buck if I'm gonna go out
and spend 50 bucks on an eighth it
better be strong yeah but that's that's
only in cannabis yeah it is because it
doesn't I don't think it applies to like
tobacco or alcohol but but think about
alcohol during alcohol prohibition you
weren't going out and buying beers right
you're going out you were buying whiskey
you're like gin you were getting your
biggest bang for but there wasn't there
wasn't that impro Bishan yeah inhibition
yes which were just kind of coming out
of right that's true serious and then
what we've seen is we've seen a
migration of all of a sudden you know
for me if I see something that's 15
percent THC I'm like that's real nice
I'm gonna be able to actually consume
this for a little bit right socially
with other people function and move on
with my with my day and I and well I
mean that brings us back to branding
where we started and I think that that's
a topic that I love talking about right
now as the industry is progressing
I think product differentiation is so so
difficult right cuz it used to be right
well I mean the old school was lows mids
highs right and I that's that's I think
on the way the dodo you still have shops
that sell that way but for the most part
you know again you don't find really you
don't find brick wheat anymore right
you're not no one's selling brick weed
anymore a weed from the 70s when it had
seeds in it right exactly that's gone so
product differentiation based purely on
quality is very very difficult
so what's taking its place is brand
differentiation right identifying are
you selling to the Chardonnay mom are
you selling to the senior citizen
community are you selling to athletes
are you know Marvin Washington we spent
a lot of time with him he's selling ice
ice ice it out hostile sport export and
those guys are very focused on the
athletes community I mean I saw we we
were Deven recently with five former NBA
players where they're pitching the value
of CBD al Harrington just launched viola
extracts and I mean all this time you're
wrong I think they're all great products
but if you were to remove all the
branding from all those products and put
them side by side it'd be very difficult
to figure out to know which ones which
because the products are all high
quality and and and so similar so brand
differentiation is really in my mind
where things are going forward you know
we're starting to see more marketing
professionals enter this space we're
starting to see fewer people trying to
go for mass market appeal more people go
for that very focused second touch of
the market and I'm sure you're seeing a
lot of that as well and yeah you're
right on the niche marketing it's it's
true and don't get me wrong I love my
cannabis sites that they're working with
us and I appreciate what they're doing
put a lot of these brands like we talked
earlier don't want to advertise on
cannabis sites because they do want to
go after that very particular niche
audience that is not a cannabis consumer
currently right oh yeah everyone wants
that newly-acquired consumers and then
to retain them a retainer be like I want
you to be loyal to my brand I hooked you
on to my brand and now I'm gonna do
everything I can do to make sure you
don't leave my brand and that's all
marketing yeah that's all branding
that's all packaging that's all image
and I think there's room for everybody
whether it's the supports whether it's a
soccer mom whether it's a professional
businessman
it doesn't matter there is a product to
be able to tailor to each individual and
I think that market segment is growing
significantly from different aspects
just recently had a consulting call with
like this vaporizer company that was
working with us and they solely wanted
to advertise on cannabis sites
and the vaporizers like I don't know
$250 all right beautiful thing that
looks great comes the beautiful
definitely high-end market high-end
market and he's like it's not working
it's not working I'm like okay well
let's let's jump on a call let's figure
out what's going on and be more happy to
help you and I said well why are you
only targeting cannabis sites and he's
like well that's our that's our consumer
right I'm like no it's not I said that
was your consumer rights now you need to
be like oh there was broader yeah and
then start cutting the fat on the
marketing so once you start getting some
analytics back on what's actually
converting I said hey you know what
I'll give you I'll give some credit on
your account but we're gonna we're gonna
do this we're gonna target investment
sites smart and he's like why yep trust
me on this absolutely enough we went for
investment we went for mainstream like
news and media kind of hire and websites
we're more professional people at 10:00
right sure enough within ten days we
increased his ROI by about 200 percent
yeah not surprised I mean that brand
marketing focus focusing on a specific
segment is working so well for people
right now and so I mean I think you know
if there's anything I've been seeing as
far as from a career-wise trend what's
hot right now because I mean a lot of
people ask me how they can get involved
in the cannabis industry and the first
thing I tell them is you don't have to
cultivate you're not gonna you're not a
cultivator you don't know nearly as much
as these guys who've been doing it for
30 years you don't have to get a license
you don't have to be a dispensary just
like what do you do
true and do it in the cannabis space
exactly and so I think the biggest
influx right now that I'm seeing is
marketers I think marketers are
realizing that the time has finally come
to where the maturity in the cannabis
industry is where it has to be to where
you can go in and help people understand
why spending ten fifty a hundred
thousand dollars if you're med men
millions of dollars on marketing makes
sense makes sense because that's where
you're gonna get that newly acquired
customer and we are actually getting a
lot of the mainstream marketing
companies reach out to us connect with
us and say hey I know what you're doing
yep absolutely we got clients and these
guys and that's kind of in the same line
where some of these bigger cannabis
brands are going for the bigger
mainstream advertising agencies instead
of going with the cannabis agencies on
some reason so now the mainstream
agencies media buying and marketing
agencies are coming directly to us so
then those agencies that are mainstream
are like well we don't know where to buy
cannabis traffic or where we source it
right and eventually end up on our desk
and they're like oh yeah great let's
let's work together so you guys can be
our cannabis arm yep to the digital
advertising space which is great and the
question always comes up wow you know we
can't do through Google we can't do
through this but and in that sense
sometimes Google and us share the same
sites yeah I mean that's fine yeah
there's room for everybody think just
just being able to access non cannabis
sites to your platform is a huge value
add right and it's also something that's
really easy to demonstrate to people how
that is a value add it's like you can
advertise on BuzzFeed you can advertise
on this side on this side whatever it is
and people just again tell lack of
education they didn't know they could do
that a good example was a music site
that we started working with and I have
to jump on a call I got in the phone
with their operations
I got it all the way up to their CEO and
it's a wrap site pretty big wrap site
and they're like well we're not sure
about advertising cannabis on our site I
said you know what why he said well
we're down to the lyrics of the music
you're pushing on your site so that was
kind of like that was it's exactly what
I did I'm like you know what I'm on your
site right now I'm on your video page
I'm literally gonna do just round-robin
I'm a click of video thank you almost
guarantee you that you were already
promoting cannabis consumption through
the videos you're showing yep and he's
like
yeah yeah yeah okay you know what's
funny about that it's a it's like that
scene and a half-baked came you know it
came to life right Samson and exactly
eggs now that's actually happening right
you guys true you have people dropping
jungle boys and songs yeah right
dropping brass knuckles in song 100%
it's it's this weird situation I never
thought I'd see that happen in my
lifetime so it's a brave new world ya
know a lot of exciting stuff happening I
think so too I think we're we're in for
a pretty exciting next few years
as things kind of settle and progress
and settle down in a good way absolutely
awesome man well good talking to you
always always a pleasure
yeah so next time till next time
[Music]