[Music]
all
right so
we tripled the size of the shade house
the footprint we went out that way we
knocked that side wall out well not
sidew wall but we flipped it up and we
put the whatever kind of netting this is
up top so now we have
about 160 Square ft on this side to work
with and then we also upgraded from the
rain barrels we have two
275g
totes running out uh each will
eventually be running out to one to this
room you can see
we're getting to be about
8T about 8T now where this one is
and
then we extended this
way and this is iteration
one of the throw
Improvement clean come back and start
cleaning this up a little bit
but see 160 sare feet on this side ning
happy
plants and so yeah drip system for that
room and then a separate one for out
here so we have
19 different strains right now a lot of
different CBD
varietal bunch of different types of
OG so
and then one thing we eventually want to
do is put two drippers in each pot for
redundancy so these things get clogged
up although they're all working right
now so