[Music]
good morning today we're here with my
friend Omar Figueroa
Omar is the principal at the Law Offices
of Omar Figueroa he has been in the
cannabis industry for probably the last
25 or so years he's got a huge amount of
fascinating stories to tell so I please
do hope that everybody that's listening
to us today looks come up off line
if I was gonna ask him about his
background in the industry we'd go on
for 40 minutes just than that so I
really just wanted to jump straight into
the topics that we're really interested
in today Omar how did you get interested
in this appellations project and sort of
what brought you to us into this point
here today yes so I'm interested in the
Appalachians because I see that as a way
for craft cannabis cultivators to
survive by producing ultra-premium
products the same as wine Appalachians
the same as cheese Appalachians and it's
really a way to honor the specific
geographical characteristics of a region
so it's also a way to honor the heritage
of craft cannabis and so when you're
talking about that heritage of craft
cannabis what would a system of
Appalachians mean to some of those
legacy producers that that have been in
this industry for decades that maybe
have been on the wrong side of the law
at certain points now we're struggling
to make a living
what Appalachians do something for that
legacy culture those legacy communities
up in Northern California yes many I
think it would incentivize the more to
transition into the license part of the
cannabis industry and that is because
you know the only licensed cultivators
can apply can submit a petition to
establish a new appellation under the
proposed regulations in California and
so this new world of Appalachians is of
course going to be limited to regulated
cannabis and
the cachet of many cannabis producing
regions is which is worldwide if once
there's an opportunity to put an
appellation on it and an identifier some
sort of designation or seal I think
that's super exciting for people who you
know used to be persecuted and that's
why they went to the Emerald triangle
which is composed of Mendocino Humboldt
and Trinity counties and now they're
celebrated and so this celebration of
their heritage I think will be
incentivize people to come out of the
legacy duty-free market some call it the
black market and go into the regulated
cannabis world and you mentioned that
sort of dynamic between the historic
illicit markets and those legacy markets
and the current regulated cannabis
markets could you just explain a little
bit more how having an appellation and
sort of what that means for consumers
how that would help those farmers
compete more effectively against those
illicit markets definitely by having
like officially recognized Appalachians
which will you know be a shorthand for a
particular type of product standards
practices or varietal you know and
basically a symbol of quality I think
that will give an edge to the struggling
farmers in the regulated cannabis world
who have been competing against growers
who don't have to pay taxes don't have
to pay licensing fees don't have to
worry about regulations and don't have
to worry about testing their product and
they can use every type of pesticide
fungicide and herbicide that they wish
without restriction and so I think you
know once consumers realize like that
cannabis with from an appellation
denotes not just geographical origin but
also particular standards practices and
cultivars I think that consumers will
naturally be
attracted to products bearing an
appellation of origin designation that's
great and you mentioned that it's not
just a geographical indicator that there
are other aspects of how a plant is
cultivated of what types of different
substances are used on the plant can you
give us an idea of sort of the range of
different inputs that we could have in a
set of definitions of appellation so
whether that does apply to you know the
chemicals the pesticides that you're
using how that would define sort of what
those practices are that we want to
communicate to ultimate consumers about
how their farmers are are cultivating
their products yes there's a lot of
flexibility in the proposed regulations
which require the petitioner who is
proposing the establishment of a new
appellation to identify not simply a
geographical area but particular
practices or you know and then the
practice this could be like a practice
like not using pesticides not using
herbicides it could also be practices
such as plant by the light of the moon
plant in the new moon harvest in the
full moon you know those could be like
practices as well as well as standards
and standards are interpreted more to
mean something like green clean green
certification or biodynamic Demeter
certification or other standards that
the petitioners of a new appellation can
propose and then finally varietals and
so you know that's kind of like
chardonnay or champagne which are
particularly for idols of grapes you
know there's the idea of having a
geographical region with a particular a
particular varietal of cannabis you know
an example would be like Blue Dream and
say Tom CAI you know Tom CAI region in
Mendocino County is near Redwood Valley
and so an example of that would be Tom
CAI blue
which would just simply specify a
varietal another option would be Tom Chi
biodynamic Dimitar certified which would
be specifying geographical region as
well as a standard or it could be Tom
Chi you know hand cultivated and
everything had to be done by hand you
know and that would be specifying
particular practices and so when you're
applying for an appellation you said
that the petitioners would have to apply
to a certain body under the CDA
regulations whose the application made
to is that a County based application a
city based application is that a
statewide you to apply in CDFA yes the
application is submitted to CDFI and
then to help make its decision the CDA
FA can appoint a petition review panel
and the petition review panel is
supposed to be composed of people with
particular expertise in you know the
area of Appalachians one criticism of
the proposed regulations is that there's
no time frame for decision and there's
no reconsideration of a decision or
appeal from a decision and so you know
technically a petition could be
submitted and then it could take 50
years for them to the side on it because
there's really nothing that incentivizes
prompt review and so what we are
proposing as members of the incb a will
be procedural protections so that we can
have review and so that the process you
know is also more predictable to those
who are submitting applications or
petitions sure so you mentioned that as
one aspect of sort of controversy within
the the set of proposed regulations
coming out of the CDF a are there other
aspects of the regulations either
procedural aspects like the lack of a
timed review in which you can expect to
answer in an X number of days are there
other either procedural issues that you
have with the CDFA regulations or or
perhaps there are substantive issues
where a term or a set of terms hasn't
been adequately
to find are there other pieces of it was
sort of we see troubles with sure I
think we want a longer public notice
period so that the public has a greater
opportunity to comment and there they
don't we don't have to be constantly
checking to see if a new petition has
been submitted because it's gonna be
long enough comment period that you know
you can check every month you don't have
to check every single week because if
you don't check every single week you
know then things could get yeah somebody
could submit a petition for the
establishment of an appellation that is
really wholly objectionable and so I
think that's one thing with regard to
you know ways to improve the process the
incb a appellation subcommittee has
identified ways to make this whole
process more accessible currently the
way they are proposing to fund the whole
cannabis appellations program is with a
one-time fee of approximately $20,000 to
file a petition to establish a new
appellation of origin and this $20,000
is supposed to fund the cannabis
appellation program in perpetuity that's
why it's so high so what we're proposing
instead would be a more reasonable
filing fee like say half of that $10,000
and then every ten years there could be
like a renewal fee and that would
accomplish the objective of funding the
cannabis appellation program in
perpetuity but it would not establish
such high barriers to entry that
struggling farmers who are now competing
with unregulated unregulated unlicensed
and untaxed cultivators it would allow
them you know the financial flexibility
to submit an application and so we've
had really constructive discussions with
incb a appellation subcommittee and
there are many brilliant lawyers who are
really like donating a lot of their
expertise and their time and so we have
been formulating some pretty um
well-thought-out comments that are need
to
on certain policy positions that are
controversial and that you know we're
just noticing the policy differences but
there's certain procedural
recommendations that I think everybody
would agree within you know we're going
to be making those recommendations and
hopefully the board can consider them
and you know perhaps this will be
something that's incb a will take you
know establishing the first Appalachians
for cannabis in history is a momentous
occasion and we're lucky that so many
members are really an integral part of
that process yeah we're we're really
excited to be a part of this and of
course thankful to you who Omar you
stood on our board we have countless
attorneys that have contributed so much
time to this project and we're really
excited about that
you had mentioned that sorry let me just
catch up to my thought on it you had
mentioned that the fee structure seems
both over burdensome and inadequate
right and so it's sort of on both sides
it's lacking a little bit under the
proposed fee structure it seems like the
burden to establish an appellation would
fall on the farmers that need it the
most
so maybe the ones that are under the
most financial duress at times certainly
like this one that we're in right now at
the same time my understanding is that
anyone could then take advantage of that
appellation as long as they adhere to
the standards that the appellation sets
forth and so could you tell us a little
bit about the dynamics of maybe having a
group of ten farmers from the eel River
apply for an appellation around the eel
River and then having sort of a
different set of people come in and take
advantage of that appellation is that a
concern that we should have here that
perhaps the people that are funding the
appellations Oversight Committee aren't
necessarily the ones that are able to
take advantage of this in the long term
that's a good point that you bring in
because you know they would have to be
within the same geographical region and
then also adhere to the same standards
practices or cultivars that are
specified for the appellation
but there's going to be a piggybacking
problem right like if you say only those
who submitted the petition can use the
appellation that also seems unfair and
short-sighted because as with wine
Appalachians many of these wine
Appalachians were established decades
ago you know and a lot of the companies
and the individuals who initially
proposed those wine Appalachians they
are no longer in the wine business you
know they've sold their businesses or
you know they passed on and so I think
we we do have a free rider problem with
people piggybacking and you know that is
a problem that many growers are facing
which which is you know growers thinking
like why should I be the one to invest
all this time and money in establishing
a new appellation when others the Free
Riders behind me will come along and try
to cash in on my appellation and then
the better question is like how do you
enforce the standards or the practices
or the cultivars for the appellation how
do you keep other licensed growers from
claiming the appellation but not really
a d-ring to the standards practices or
cultivars and therefore diluting the
goodwill associated with that particular
appellation those are really good
questions and questions I'm sure that
we'll get into in depth on April 2nd
right yes something I'm very excited
about is that you know while we were
brainstorming we came up with the idea
of having a CEO that identifies official
cannabis appellations in California and
initially I proposed having two seals
one official seal that said official
California cannabis appellation it would
have the fancy you know like what's it
called the Outer Ring
yeah like the Apple yeah like the
European seals and then there will be a
second seal that would be proposed and
it would have a uniform design element
on the outside and then on the inside
the proponent or the petitioner would
have their own design that they would
propose and so I like that idea and
unfortunately you know
it seems like real estate when it comes
to packaging and labeling in such short
supply that it's not practical to really
have two seals and so Mary Shapiro has
suggested just having the one seal which
would be the outer ring would have a
uniform design element which would
probably say official California
cannabis appellation and then on the
inside it would be like blank and so
there the proponent could you know
propose their own design and they would
have their own creativity and then there
will be a small modest fee to use that
official seal and that would also help
you know fund the cannabis appellations
program because the way that the
regulations are structured currently is
they basically want to fund that the
cannabis appellations program in
perpetuity by having really high fees at
the beginning and then no fees ever ever
after and that to me sounds like a
recipe for establishing a program that
will end up weathering a way for lack of
funding and just kind of dying into
irrelevance and so we are making several
proposals for establishing different
sources of funding you know such as
having like you know renewals for
Appalachians every ten years so they had
to pay a little bit more money to keep
that Appalachian current but really like
having an official seal would
incentivize official enforcement against
misuse because now anybody who is
counterfeiting that seal is misusing an
official seal and then there would also
be a value to the producers they'll be
happy to pay some money to use the seal
because they know that the state of
California now has an interest and is
willing to allocate its resources
towards enforcement so I'm really
excited about this idea that we all
collectively came up with of having an
official seal for cannabis appellations
that can be put on cannabis products and
can help identify cannabis products
yeah I mean I that sounds like a great
idea from a couple different
perspectives obviously from the official
steel use and sort of having an inner
walking an interlocking type of seal
that had that that you know that idea
that this was sanctioned by the state
and then had the more specific sort of
logo in there and then of course you
mentioned the problem with funding
enforcement of this going forward you
know and if enforcement does fall to the
CBF a you know we here and and for those
of us that have seen the development of
Appalachians you know we're aware that
the wine and the cheese industries have
spent tens of millions of dollars
enforcing these very specific marks that
become very valuable over time and
without that enforcement mechanism and
without adequately funding that
enforcement mechanism the Appalachian
who really doesn't mean much so I love
that idea it's the first time that I've
heard of it and it's the you know that
this idea of sort of an interlocking
seal which would certainly go towards
both of those points you know current
recognition of the Appalachian and
potential future funding of enforcement
and continuing the program into
perpetuity because that's the idea is
that we're gonna set this up in twenty
thousand dollars today
isn't gonna do much for enforcement and
you know twenty years down the road so
that's right the money she's gonna be
sitting in like some you know state fund
it's not gonna be like you know sitting
there yeah go towards the government
bailout the cruise ship industry Omar
okay Omar thank you so much for for
chatting with us this morning we're
really excited about this event thank
you for for continuing to come even
though we're doing it online instead of
in person we're trying to recreate some
of those wonderful things that we get to
do in person while we're going through
this difficult time so we really
appreciate your continued support and
we're really excited to speaking to your
April 2nd so am i likewise thank you for
doing this