[Music]
my name's AJ I'm a second-generation
farmer my parents got into it and I
naturally took to doing stuff I think 12
13 we get paid a little money to dig
holes and stuff like that and her kids
and grew my first crop but at 13 got a
few plants so me and my buddy got a
little spot on a on a ridge and that's
when it started with me so I've been
growing ever since things used to be a
lot different we used to grow up in the
tops of trees I was kind of a technique
that I I pioneered at least in my area
and was somewhat legendary for and we've
been building the farm been in the same
spot for the last 30 actually 32 years
and we've been slowly but surely
evolving our farm into what it is now
now we have a couple acres of permitted
cannabis in the center of 280 acre piece
of property in Humboldt County right
pretty much close to the center of the
Emerald triangle so southern southern
Humboldt right we were started with a
smaller property and we were able to
acquire property next to it to make it
larger so was it we didn't start off on
a 280 acre parcel we started off on a
40-acre parcel got to buy the property
next next to us and
and then some more lands came up for
sale and so we got to expand a bit like
that but it's been the 288 for about 20
years that's been well we're like 1200
feet elevation so we get we get some
cool River fog that comes in not
consistently all year but certain times
the cool river fog comes in afternoon
winds come up so it's definitely I mean
there's so many microclimates up here
that we're kind of on a southern gentle
slope so the air is kind of sliding down
the hill
when it gets cool and it's pushing up up
the hill through the plants when it's
warm getting hotter in the day we've
been working mostly with the SF vog and
it loves it too dense of a of a strain
has trouble with its chicken through
situs as a challenge with rot at certain
times because of the cooler nights but
the oh geez Sour Diesel really really do
well we primarily grow in soil we have a
few pots around but but we mostly grow
in beds and we've used the per most of
our soil is about we brought in soil
mixed it in with the native soil that's
seven years ago now so we amend it test
it see what it needs and yeah it's
pretty awesome we earth worms and
beetles and and lots of you know the
good beneficial stuff growing in there
one part of the gardens we've got some
four hundred gallon smart pots the rest
are holes we have for our long-term we
have holes they're about the same size
they're about a three feet deep by five
six by six
and that's in the ground and we have
primarily beds that are tilled into the
ground with with potting soil mixed in
and then in an annual amendments to
amend that and those are eight-foot-wide
beds and if you look at pictures of our
pharmacy the terrorists they're kind of
terrorists on a gentle slope so so those
yeah that's that's how we primarily grow
I'd say 80% is in the beds we do 8 foot
by by 98 by 90 its amended in native mix
so so we didn't put a barrier underneath
it or anything we did we got I mean the
the soil you know the spring when it's
like a dark rich brown you know it's
it's a pretty nice nice soil we till
them back in because we get started
pretty early as soon as the weather is
permitting for depth so so they get yeah
they get tilled in a few of the later
ones kind of got a chance to completely
finish out and we just knocked them down
with the weed weed eater and tell them
in and they're they're you know lush and
a little less mature you can just take
the tiller right right to and chop them
up because they're all crisp and green
and yeah when we still do but you have
to amend a lot less and so so you do
that and then we get it tested and and
our nitrogen in that case it's usually
pretty good we do light depths mostly
light depths what we do do some
long-term the farm that the the bottom
two-thirds are our light depth and then
the top third is we have some long-term
on well we don't have it right now but
we grew a golden strawberry that was
that was pretty awesome and and
definitely like to get a hold of that
again yeah that's one of my favorites
yeah Sour Diesel is great on a on a a
good year on the really the traditional
Indian summers that we get it seemed
like it was a nine out of ten loosely
get get eight out of ten you know you
can count on a pretty good Indian summer
but if you don't they're gonna be
regretting it which was last year last
year wasn't fun for the Sour Diesel
during the offseason I'm a big fan of of
fava beans but I can't always find
enough fava beans to do so so last time
I found it
nakai at the demand o AG store they had
an organic organic veg cover crop that
we did last year and that works pretty
good I was pretty nice it had it had
follow beans bush beans I think some
barley handful of different different
grasses nitrogen producing we plan also
around not in the beds but all around
the beds on the outside
clover nitrogen-fixing clover so that's
that's really it takes a while but if
you have you know freshly grated places
and and things like that it really
rebuilds the soil and takes nitrogen out
of the atmosphere out of the air and
puts it into the soil and it keeps
growing year after year nurse it along
and keep it expanding so that's and it's
nice it's kind of like working walking
on a carpet in the spring so it's pretty
cool a big fan of white clover in the
rows in between everything and in the
walkways in any of the open area within
the the fence
I get bags with it throw that seed
everywhere it keeps you know honeybees
love it it keeps the dust down it's it
doesn't shoot up and you know like a
tall grass and then unleash a barrage of
thorns or this you know foxtails or you
know things that become a real pain in
the ass and sticking your socks and
stuff but below the soil
yeah it's pulling it's pulling nitrogen
and releasing it into the soil so it
will take ground like the ground freshly
grated ground like ground behind me and
it takes you know it takes some years to
do it but it'll rebuild that soil
and and bring it back up to a good soil
that has you know a top soil so it's
yeah it's a pretty awesome plant for
that
I've done some teas but I was doing it
wrong so I kind of gave up on the tea
and now this year we're just starting
use them use the instruments to measure
to know what I'm actually working with
know if I'm doing it right if I've
actually got a live proper amount of
microbes ready to ready to go or if I'm
just dumping a dead liquid out on my
Vice stuff that's you know not knowing
that that makes it pretty tough and you
can't really afford to have to be
pouring out a dud you know material and
then and then some pasture or microbe is
taking over while you're while you're
sleeping at the wheel
[Music]