[Music]
how does that affect reaching the result
of a harvest most common tripping points
that everybody seems to be experiencing
come from the same root cause I think
everybody's trying to get to the end
result fast without establishing the
proper infrastructure or knowledge base
or mechanisms for analyzing the process
and we have investors that are near the
industry that want widgets and they want
them now
and so growers are altering their style
they're watering multiple times through
the day to try and feed the plants push
them and coupled with a bad greenhouse
environment that leads to pests and
disease pressure and so there's
different ways is that manifest but
that's like the main thing we got a
whole bunch of carts in front of horses
and we just need to like look at the
horses for ten minutes we need a little
bit more open dialogue between the
people that actually have growing
experience and the people paying for the
building it's remarkable how many people
buy a greenhouse with an investor and
another guy and nobody that cultivates
is involved in that conversation which
is mind blowing and so a bunch of
facility configurations are chosen and
those do not lead to plant health and
vigorous harvest it leads to resorting
to chemicals and failing tests and
having crop loss so what is the cost to
the operation of you know trying to cram
this thing into the hole before
everybody loses their opportunity to
find gold and how that manifests with
the customers that I work with and
living soils is we have a lot of people
that are moving from old technologies
hydroponics the nutrient quantity
mindset and they go they you have to use
a certain quantity of nutrients to get a
certain plant result and that's the only
way we need to know how to
get a harvest and so we're just pushing
on that same thing so when we move from
that old nutrient quantity techniques to
a living soil which is a nutrient
availability system and we're relying on
nutrients to be produced and available
when we increase the quantity we slow
that system down and becomes problematic
so pushing water pushing feed all leads
to crop loss question essentially is how
does the different techniques processes
and practices we're doing negatively
affect us at the regulated scale
techniques that we used to do on a small
scale we're manageable and when we're
inside of a smaller space we can manage
the pests and disease that's manifested
from the techniques and processes we're
doing and when we move up into these
larger just like Jonathan said I mean
we're talking acre properties now life
you cannot have highly-trained hands-on
skill looking at all those plants and
dealing with things in the way that we
did before the techniques and processes
and things that we've created an
emotional attachment to it the smaller
scale when we move to the higher
regulated process those techniques are
actually the source of our problem and
that's the biggest most difficult thing
to communicate to these growers is that
this three-day tea brew that they're
making and high-altitude is literally
and mathematically the cause for the
rest of mites and when you suggest that
to people they take it as a personal
attack against internet heroes and
personalities and their religion and it
gets really deep but like this is just
math here and we can open up a
first-year freshman biology textbook and
we can identify these organisms and we
can we can do this ourselves you don't
have to take my word for it you can
learn to use a microscope and you can
see what this is happening but the
techniques that we use that the smaller
scale are literally the cause for
failure at the regulated scale because
now we have somebody that is using
scientific methods for analyzing your
process and they are finding Listeria
and they're finding e.coli and they are
finding these disease-causing organisms
that fail a test and and if we can
understand that conditions create
biological organism proliferation and we
can understand that the condition
these are creating the those organisms
to grow we can avoid that test failure
and most common problem is somebody
doing a tea brew that's actually brewing
disease-causing organisms you spread
that throughout your facility and you
have pest and disease pressure and the
problem is a communities we don't have
much reference for this and we're just
barely getting a reference for it
the information has been around for
decades but it's now starting to pick up
in the cannabis industry with the
growers that are trying to find more
responsible ways to farm and so we're
just barely in the last year or two
starting to get like a community
reference for these measurements on an
actual scale actually
[Music]