[Music]
yeah I I got introduced HR not not too
long ago or we it's been brought to
everyone's attention on on the benefits
of it and clay I I'm fortunate enough to
try his live soil as well as he makes
biochar and he approached me wanting me
to give his biochar run so of course we
jumped on it we do a lot of R&amp;D we were
happy to and we're really excited with
the results and what we're seeing and
I'm not the expert in biochar but clay
tell me a little bit about my
understanding is you can you can use the
source different kind of wood to make
biochar and there there's different
grades and and well the outcome will be
different on what kind of woods you're
choosing tell me a little bit about you
know what you're doing and why you do
that you know what would you select we
start with hardened soft woods one step
up that we offer in our biochar product
is we also use coastal driftwoods the
sea is amazing for plants so anything
that those those those logs that could
saturate in the biochars
burnt to a specific degree every creator
of biochar has their own degrees the
Amazonian started at first so obviously
they didn't have thermometers they burn
it to the point where my grandpa taught
me it's time to snuff it out so we kind
of did that year after year after year I
mean before I bring it to any of you
guys I definitely had to run it in our
medical grows and so we use hardwood
softwood and the the driftwood that kind
of makes it a little bit different
there's a lot of different biochars you
can make biochar from straw that's right
and it's just it's not the same I'm a
molecular level
the straw isn't the same as the
hardwoods like madronas and stuff like
that it's its mother nature's perfect
store perfect hotel for the microbes for
your soil and you know my understanding
is you you you've moved on using some of
mammoth products and tell me some of the
goodies that you're putting in to your
biochar in your process you know your
teas and your mix and and how why that's
so much better
why your product has become so good well
a lot of R&amp;D thousands of plants it
biochars whole process is to collect
nitrogen and phosphorous from the soils
after a fire because there's no more
foliage there's no more roots to be able
to hold that stuff in the soil so Mother
Nature doesn't want the year of rain to
come along and wash all those minerals
away so they create she created biochar
it actually collects it so what we do is
we brew 26 organic ingredients
amendments everything from green sand
crustacean meal alfalfa we have a few
secret ingredients that once you isn't
it you get you get told what those are
but I can't give all all the goodies
away now that goes and we actually brew
three it's a timing thing you brew three
different teas and then towards the end
we actually add mammoths at the end for
the microbes can't put him into earlier
they'll eat everything before your plans
yes and I was fortunate enough to you
brought me you're making live soil now
and you he reached out to me and wanted
me to try a run of his live soil so we
have it's very new to us but you want to
tell us a little bit about that project
and and what you're doing with your live
soil line and how how its special well
it's it's special my one of my best
friends
besides Casey is he's he's a Marley worm
growers he is has
sends one castings all over well a lot
of doing organic amendments that you can
buy out here have one type of worm
castings we actually have five different
types of worm castings in ours and the
he also makes soil so then Casey and a
few other growers that use our biochar
we're like well why don't you work on a
soil so actually the last year we ran
different tests the SEM the other you
know I've been building soils for twenty
years so it wasn't new to me but to put
a super soil out there for this
gentleman to risk fifty thousand dollars
worth of his product on that's something
big to ask and and I think it's pretty
dialed in
it's stoked to harvest soil know
nutrients added needed to be added
unless you're gonna run a long outdoor
it's about you know four four months is
a good run if you're gonna run along
outdoor you want to top this yeah clay
could you tell us a little bit about the
your soil making process you're making a
live soil with biochar you know part of
your expertise and background with the
biochar tell us that process and how
you're selecting ingredients for your
live soil how that how that comes to be
well as a grower you try everything
Coco's amazing peat moss peat moss is
amazing our living soil actually
probably has more peat moss in it per
bag than any other super soil out there
I prefer peat moss it is it is organic
and created to also help the microbe
growth Coco is a really good product
also but I just prefer the peat as a
grower and everybody's got their own
their own their own choices we use only
percent organic and naturally collected
amendments we start with micro and macro
nutrients EO do three different teas
that we brew and there's a certain order
that we add stuff to it and that's been
a test because then we test the soils
and see what the runoff is see what's
not staying what is staying for
different stages of your plant one our
first brew we start with the fish
emulsion that fish emulsion is what
speeds up that year-long process that
the mother nature needs to go through
after after a fire because I needed to
speed that process up obviously we
harvest every week you got to have a new
soya ready to go and that the the
microbes and the beneficial bacteria
that grow in the fish emulsion is the
first T that we start and we slowly add
the macronutrients after that all the
way from crustacean mel alfalfa meal
glacier still green sand we also use
brown and black compost from olie
mountain very very reputable company
it's time it's it's if you think about
it you watch your compost go from color
to brown to black finally when it's
ready to go and that that's that's all
that is you can because we want you to
be able to only water your whole cycle
so you get out food in the beginning and
you get out food available at the end
what I'm hearing you say is brown and
black compost what one's a little more
hotter than the other great one will
affect your plan a little more the most
of the black compost is now broken down
and ready for your plant ready for the
microbes to eat as your microbes are
feeding on that compost in our soil your
brown compost is breaking down by the
time you're switching into flour it's
breaking down that high phosphorous
bagua know which is what the cannabis
plant needs and for extra extra
flowering extra flower power I like to
say the timing was important timing is
important and and it takes time to learn
when to do your compost and stuff but
you kind of took that out of the thought
process by using both compost I said
we're really excited to run it thank you
for that by the way what you running
it's been adjust not even two weeks now
since we transplanted them so we're
following taking data and we'll get you
the results and we're excited to see
what what we can do I'm glad you guys
I'm glad you trusted me and absolutely
keep I'll be at your door every day yeah
make sure we make sure we get it
those are crossed all the t's those are
definitely crossed all the t's the
microbes we add towards the end because
they'll eat everything I also we're
coming up when you have living soil you
don't want to flush it's a big you hear
people talk about flushing because there
is no flushing you want to ground your
microbes I mean I'm just saying you
don't want to wash those microbe job
because they're doing the last of their
life trying to get that phosphorous out
trying to get the nitrogen out because
you don't want your cannabis to Sparkle
and crackle when you light it and then
so you want those microbes to eat up
everything that's left in that soil so
we're gonna actually make we've we use
in our own farm sugar finishes is what I
call and they're their organic extracts
I make three different extracts
depending on the strains and we crushed
the biochar into a powder add this with
three different natural sugars so as you
water your last two weeks of the of the
flowering cycle that powder does what
Mother Nature wanted it to works its way
through your soil and takes out all that
nitrogen grabs out all ups not available
to your your microbes or your plan
anymore
so what's left the sugar and the natural
extracts that we use the organic
extracts blueberry huckleberry I mean it
just depends on the strain but then all
those microbes have to feed on is that
sugar honey and there's a few other few
other items that we use that I don't
want to say but you know if they are
listed on the product of course but that
just leaves nothing else in the soil but
natural sugars there's no natural sugars
you know how sticky honey is will feed
your plant honey tell me how sticky your
buds are just saying so clay what else
outside of what you've mentioned already
are you putting in your super soil your
live soil
well obviously mammoth microbes is the
last we also use
we're doing soils for other other other
cannabis growers and hemp growers they
want to use there's all kinds of
microbes out there to use and there's
different cultivators of those microbes
so you're actually adjusting per farm if
they ask so it does kind of change a
little bit but as far as you know the
compost the there is a little bit of
that brown and black compost and the
teas but very little of it we actually
add most of that to the super soil at
the end 1/2 the earthworm castings
there's five different North's worm
castings that we use two of them go in
the t's three of them are added to the
super soil by themselves everything from
high phosphorus bat guano low fuss cow
calcium kalmec we use ground up moisture
shells in it obviously helps the pH a
little bit but Mother Nature the biochar
actually pH is for every plant
I mean think how many plants start up
after a forest fire at a just a pine
tree you know it isn't just a weed it
has to be all the way across so even we
have some non organic growers that are
using a chemical based nutrients that
use our biochar because it does work but
they add these teas in between them to
help replace the microbes so just stay
organic yeah then you don't have to do
that so for some of your customers that
you're providing a biochar your soil to
if they're in different areas regions or
go growing differently say outdoors or
if it's in a greenhouse or indoors what
are some of the changes that you're
having to make or that your that they're
wanting maybe even for certain strains
that they're running and what are those
changes that you would do for your live
soil for the life so the first change
that I try and do I don't play with the
ingredients so much a play with the
amount of biochar the amount of perlite
the amount of peat moss well we'll play
with that a little bit but as far as the
grow if they're on a drip system most of
my grows are watering once a week in a
professional go that's a lot of labour
not being you know being used on better
things and holding the watering wand we
will change it basically when it comes
down to them to the gardeners already
using it it will change on just the
amount of biochar that's added some
soils heavy clay soils 20-30 percent
biochar I have a whole group of farmers
that grow indoor fruit trees they're
running their mixes they're using it
about 30 percent which is even more than
most cannabis growers so we kind of
adjust it per what their soil medium
whether they're gonna use a soilless or
they're using our live soil that's
pretty much I don't adjust the recipe
only because I think as being a chef for
15 years for the Hilton I've got the mix
down I've got the alfredo sauce pretty
knocked out and I'm not gonna have my
buddy over for dinner to try my alfredo
sauce if I haven't already fed it to my
own family and we use our biochar and
our vegetables my mother's house plans
amend everything have you made a change
purse drain or maybe if a customer has
asked you or do you know of say a strain
yeah if it's you know blue dream or
blueberry that by tweaking your formula
a little bit now this is for the strain
you know strain specific that you get a
different result or get that strain to
reach its full potential or and what
would those changes be a pretty wet
strain that everybody knows same way
with like say blue dream had a blue
dream cut for about seven years it's
amazing everybody loves their blue dream
but we have a grower Gorilla Glue Number
Four actually use it as one of my
father's or not gorilla glue number four
and we change it we have changed it a
bit
because there are certain strains
there's landrace strains that have not
been adult altered that come from other
countries there's different minerals on
every part of this rock so we have had
to adjust depending on a cup we got a
couple growers that grow gorilla glue
number four strictly for edibles and we
have backed off we backed off about half
of our biochar and ingredients in our
last tea for that particular strain
because anybody can grow it you can put
it in a mud puddle and it would probably
grow so yeah we do adjust them because
why am I gonna have you pay for a full
product when I'm not putting all that in
there I mean I'm just not you don't need
it for certain strains another one God's
gift
very very very easily grown very low
nutrients blue dream now then on the
other side we got some land races
Afghani number one that you know that
that that can be a 13-week strain well
it's gonna need phosphorus a little bit
longer than everybody else especially if
you don't want a smoke leaf if you
actually want some density to your
flower you got a kick up that low Foss
in the beginning of flowering to make
sure you actually get a but instead of
just
Thank You clay welcome so after
presentation today what what are some of
the the key aspects you'd like to cover
again what struck your fancy you know
the the main takeaways from from where I
spoke yeah and very important it varies
per state every state is different but
the main takeaway is you have to plan
for change there's going to be change
change change and you have to plan plan
plan and phasing your built out or your
planning is important because the future
is unknown and uncertain and so most
people that are building out to a to a
large capacity want to phase that build
and there's unforeseen and and you want
to plan for that and if that's using
mobile structures maybe you know - or
not knowing if you're gonna if your
county or zoning or a lie to do
extraction and arable put a moratorium
on that area or limit your extraction to
the market itself changing and suddenly
you know flour might be extremely
competitive and I want to you want to
build a kitchen you know you want to
launch the edible line or a topical line
so so much is unforeseen so the main
takeaway is is plan for change there'll
be a lot of change and and you have to
kind of forecast for that and always
keep that in mind
I think another big one from the the
mice my conference behind presentation
is all the different government agencies
and their their regulations and how you
have to abide by them all and they're
all different they all have their own
requirements and it makes it challenging
and those can change as well and trying
to when you're looking for a site - - or
starting your business you know you have
to take into consideration your local
authority and the state the city the
county you know clean air Health
Department Department of Ecology the
Planning Department fire marshal the
troopers yep your neighbors yeah and
those are all gonna vary depending on
where you are you know different County
will have different requirements and
even one of the things I wanted to talk
more on and we
didn't was the hoop houses and how in my
County that's considered a temporary
structure but they didn't have a
definition for what a hoop house was a
year ago or and in some other counties
they don't consider a hoop house
structure and now the clean air agency
has come in and they're trying to
regulate us being able to grow in a hoop
house this temporary structure and
they're wanting to police you know if
you don't have a hoop house or you're
not growing you know this was this month
March last month of this year you're not
able to now grow in one this is a the
clean air agency which is in Spokane
County you know it's kind of their kind
of their own Authority and they're not a
planning department it's something that
you think the county would be policing
and telling you what you can do in a
structure and you have this other
government agency coming in and we had
to file an exemption to be able to grow
in these temporary structures and we're
not exempt of anything and that's a
yearly now fee I have to pay and they
want us to give them our my harvest
schedules you know which is putting my
team at risk and there's proprietary
information there and in another County
it's completely different you know they
might not even have a clean air agency
in that County hoop houses aren't even
considered a temporary structure or a
structure at all so all of that is gonna
play a huge role in where you're gonna
build and what your plan is and you know
get yourself up the to success you know
basically so doing all your homework is
basically a large one adaptation another
to be open another main takeaway is you
know yeah and I feel that this
drastically is your budget you know
whatever my budget was I I feel that
that and you know Matt now for me it's
just double it you know there's gonna be
so many unforeseen costs that you cannot
plan on or you wouldn't imagine and so
you have to it's just really hard to get
your budget down for what you're working
with so you know that was a huge one for
me is just whatever you think your
budget is double that budget there's
gonna be unforeseen things and things
are gonna be required to do and new
licenses and per
it's and government agencies coming in
trying to get a piece of the pie you
know like the clean air agency or and so
yeah those are the those are the
takeaways mostly you know plan plan plan
do your homework your budget whatever
you think you need you're gonna need
more and also contracts when you're
dealing with your contractors you know
roofers electricians a lot of these guys
this is new to us right the cannabis
industry commercial at this scale
especially to the government agencies so
we're all on this vertical learning
curve and they're not they're not gonna
know how to decide a grove they're not
gonna know where you need power and why
and how much you know your architects
not going to know that your head grower
and the way he envisions that his system
his method he has to work with this
architect with the the electrician and
so there's just everybody's really on a
large vertical learning scale which is
exciting everybody's learning and that's
another reason for all the change as
they learn and figure out what's going
on there'll be changes that will be for
the positive and for the negative to to
a business owner or to a grower to to
the county to the city but I think those
were those are the main takeaways oh
yeah it's been it's been a Zam indoor
and outdoor I hope with a lot of
different grows and the Clean Air Act
that they put together and it's gonna
happen in every state there's gonna be
some states that don't care and there's
gonna be some they're three or four
different agencies pop up and they go
you know I mean really a hoop house I
mean there's cattle farms that are
putting off more co2 on the air than we
could ever think of doing and are they
getting charged by the acre or are they
even getting charged for clean air I
mean you know it's just kind of it
really hit it really hit a lot of farms
we're struggling and so I can understand
them needing wanting to get their piece
of the pie but they could have
you know give give your state five years
give your give your investors five years
as people are putting out their entire
life savings into these places and
there's more and more things keep
popping up really you have to be like
Casey said have two times the amount in
your investment book than what you're
planning on action spending because it
changes it'll change next week it's
going to change again in the next month
yep month to month
it changes packaging rules labeling
rules security rules you can set your
main game plan up but definitely leave
some quotations for adaptation on it
because it changes you're right you know
one of the panels that I enjoyed and it
was it was today and it was the breeding
panel you know a lot of what we do at
contender gardens is the the Rd in the
strain selection and and running these
strains in different environments that
scene scene where we can get the best of
the best and what we're looking for
right the bag appeal the vigorous growth
the resistance to pathogens and insects
and we're really big on that research
and I enjoyed the panel today on the
breeding when it was really good to hear
them talk about Auto flowers feminized
Auto flower seeds we do see that
becoming more and more of a big deal
because in the past it wasn't yeah yeah
in in the world but in the US and the
gentleman that spoke mr. loud did say
how you know how he wouldn't even
consider a look at feminized Auto
flowers you know not not too long ago
couple years ago but how he's looking at
and seeing things a little differently
now from from going to a greenhouse from
talking to another breeder and that's
that's been the truth for me as well
where you know Auto flowers weren't
really interesting and now we're seeing
the breeding and the auto flower what we
have now to work with the stock has
changed and you know when you can get
two or three times your canopy in the
season when before it wasn't really an
option or you wouldn't consider it I
mean that's that's huge you know that's
that's really doubling
doubling up your your yield and doubling
up your sales and we're gonna do them at
two locations this season the auto
flowers we very sprouted them and we
have more going in so I'm really excited
to run them and and I have interest in
in perhaps providing some of the seed
stock these auto flowers to some of our
other fellow farmers and in a Washington
State because you see more and more of
them running them and wanting to get
that second third crop in the year a lot
of potential there and I'm glad they
touched on the art feminized Auto flower
seeds because it is it is up and coming
I I was at first not so happy with them
either I don't have time my cologne
breeder myself but I had fortunate
enough the last couple years to be able
to run some some pretty decent strains
of Auto flowers and I'll tell you what
they'll be a part of my grill from now
on no never always go because I love the
propagation process of the plant but
definitely for that third run you got
space and you need canopy space to fill
out I definitely know 27 years ago and I
would say you know fill it in with your
Auto flowers you've gotten a lot better
too
you know first seeds I had and I wasn't
so impressed but now the breeders that
are that are working with those you're
getting a lot more reputable a lot more
time under their belt and their luck I
think there will be a game-changer and
you'll see a huge push and evolution
with feminized Auto flower seeds farmers
in my state are now using them to fill
their canopy or their rows or their
cells
they'll just plant them in between their
full season plants or where they they
have their plants laid out and then
you'll just see those come in and just
sprout their entire field earlier to get
that extra crop and you'll see that the
higher potency Otto flowers the bigger
yields and the denser the denser bud as
as the breeders and and we have moved
forward on this on this project but the
demand form is is you as a parent I know
I would say that I think
we have all known just from from
breeders in the past and readers today
that you know readers are you know are
have bottlenecked a lot of strains um
and so all these varieties and types
have gone away because we have you know
found things we liked and use those to
breed and and kind of took the best of
the best to breed with and so we have
less of a selection today than we did
you know 10 20 years ago and so and in
you know and breeders will acknowledge
this and understand that that's true
this has happened and so there's some
pros and cons to that you know obviously
we get some really good hybrids and the
best of the best with today's today's uh
breeding and stock that comes from it
but at the same time we've left behind a
lot of types that that we might not have
anymore don't have access to that are no
you know we're forgotten about or not
used and
I'm popping a couple seeds out of my
seed bank this year the can't wait to
get home and see them I got a I was
gifted a 1970s humble or 1970s Amsterdam
haze it was smuggled out of Amsterdam I
don't know how but I'm popping the beans
pretty excited to try something that
comes to mind for me and these aren't
really strange that are our land racer
or you know ancient or stuff you can't
find but I remember a Mazar was
something that I was really into that we
got our hands on early early on in the
2000s and there was a G blue that we
really liked that I haven't seen around
and it's not an old ancient strain this
was in early 2000s as well now Trinity
was another one and but yeah that G blue
was something that we would love to get
our hands on again
g13 across G 13 is one of my first
trains back in the day orange peeking
out the window watching for your local
mailman
has he got a bad yeah you know I think
our parents maybe would be the you know
somebody to to ask on that you know
someone who substantially maybe older
than me that was into the end of the
scene and and now you know doesn't here
has not found that strain again you know
just inexistent yeah because I think I'm
still on the on the younger generation
you know as for when I started
cultivating and up till this point
there's you know I didn't grow up
consuming in the 80s you know or you
know I was a kid 70s you know wasn't
even alive so there's a lot of strains
that I wouldn't even have any idea that
don't exist anymore
[Music]