[Music]
what I'm hearing it sounds like too is
that maybe there's it's probably a lot
more complex than this but three General
Uses or purposes for your te's one would
be to break down what is already there
creating nutrition for the plant uh two
would be to grow the plant and produce
some type of growth hormone there and
three would be some type of resistance
um and or preventative measure in that
uh you'd be fighting off the bad guys if
you will so let's say that we started
with a new clone right what would be
your tea of choice for a new transplant
into a sterile medium um I I tend to
lean more towards the fungal dominant
first why is that um so a lot of if
you're looking at
the roots of a plant underneath a
microscope you have the the main you
know in a lot of ways it mimics what
you'd see above ground so you have you
know kind of that main branch coming off
and then they'll be uh the root hairs um
and if you look at closer what you see
is it actually is kind of deceptive like
in a lot of ways your your skin so we
have hair coming off of our skin but we
also have holes in our skin in the form
of pores where um there are spaces that
are actually going inside side as well
so Roots have those and what ends up
happening with a lot of the um a lot of
the the the the fungus that we
introduced this is that they have a um
that they have a very close relationship
with the plant and that they will
actually plug into those pores and then
they themselves will snake out spiderweb
out into the
soil and actually extend the surface
area or multiply the surface area of um
that that plant is able to cover so a
plant route in of itself or just like me
standing here I can only Reach Out And
Touch what's immediately around me if I
am you know Spider-Man with a web
Slinger sh throwing out something while
I can grab something from across the
room and that's how the fungal hypi act
when they're in a direct relationship
with the plant so for early growth um
for for establishing that root system
and and getting it as strong as as
strong as possible as fast as as
possible and giving it immediate
immediate access to as much of that
surface area as possible I tend to to
want to lean towards fungal dominant
early so as the plant starts to get
established and is able to kind of
absorb what's immediately available in
whatever soil mix that you're using then
it starts to lean towards the breakdown
of the soil which although the the uh
the fungal growth definitely has a big
role to play in that as well but a lot
of the the I guess a little more diverse
side of that is really in in the biology
is is in the the the
bacterias um so the the bacterias are a
lot of the ones that create different
hormones create amino acids um the the
the lacto basilis and basilis will have
a little bit more um active or faster
role in in breaking things down
especially when you combine them all um
but they can also occupy a lot of that
same space that fungus would like to be
occupying so the fungal growth tends to
happen a little bit slower the bacterial
growth can happen relatively quickly um
and so that's the reason for kind of
establishing the the get getting the
fungal colonies established first and
then starting to transition into the
into the bacterial more bacterial
dominant and then as you get into late
flower there are all kinds of specific
um species that are um
producing a lot of those growth
hormones and uh or there you know some
of them that will specifically break
down certain things in the soil faster
so early on we're more interested in in
nitrogen uh later on you know goes from
basically goes from n from from n to P
to K in terms of our focus of uh and the
plant's lifecycle so you can kind of you
can kind of tailor that a little bit
with the biology as well right on so I
know that for me you know it the the
similar mind frame and that you know the
fungal colonies get them developed first
and then the bacterias can break down
those things like You're mentioning
green sand and montr malite clay and
these very mineral Rich Trace element
Rich compounds that are not readily
available to the plant so the bacterias
that produce amino acids and enzymes
help the plant to make that bioavailable
and then I know for me that towards the
end of the life cycle especially in
flower and cannabis plant
um you run into a lot of the problems
towards the end and being an organic
cultivator um and a conscious cultivator
doesn't allow me to put any sprays on my
plants or do any of that topical
preventative measures um so what would
you utilize like what are some strands
you'd utilize say towards the end to
fight off a fusarium or pythium or
Bettis you know uh um there
are 50 different species
that you'll find in a lot of the
hydrocor mixes if you actually take any
of those names written on the back of
them and look them up online you'll see
what kind of effects they have and and a
lot of them are kind of on both sides
but they they're participating in in or
assisting with the breakdown of the soil
but they're also um they're also
antagonistic to any sort of pathogens in
the soil but then there are some that
are more aggressive than others um so
streptomyces actin actinovate yeah
streptomyces sold is actinovate is one
that that a lot of people use and it can
be also used as a foler although I think
it's soil born naturally comes from the
soil uh can also be sprayed as a foler
um something like that is a is a good
one to start adding into the te's as you
get a little bit later later on down the
road yeah um um I have a question for
you on that on the strepto my I've heard
that um you know one of the reasons why
you wouldn't want to use the
streptomyces early on as say a
preventative like why wouldn't you get
strept is in there right off the bat so
that that stuff can't come
in there are other species better suited
to that that are not going to actually
attack the fungal growth in the soil
that you do want and streptomyces and
again I'm not a biologist but my
understanding of streptomyces is that it
is a pretty
aggressive um pretty aggressive organism
when it comes to
attacking uh different funguses and
things like that and it doesn't
necessarily differentiate you know
there's going to be some different
some some of their preferred Foods
versus things that they wouldn't
necessarily prefer or wouldn't
necessarily want to bother with but um
that they are aggressive enough that
they can uh that they can have a little
bit of an effect on the the fungal
growth in the soil that we do want and I
don't necessarily know that to be true
that's more of an intuitive um you know
something that I think was more
intuitive for me in terms of my practice
but uh I didn't necessarily want to use
those things um right off the bat just
because you don't necessarily have to
but then as you get later on down the
road and you you know and the plants
start especially as the plants start to
reach the end of their life cycle and
they start to get weaker um they are
then subject to any of these things a
lot of them are systemic exist in nature
anyway you know like hero we are I think
they say that there's 20% of 20% of the
dust in the air is actually active mold
spores and things like that so these
things all exist in the environment
anyway it's not necessarily that you
need to have a plant that's contaminated
and then comb combine that with the fact
that a lot of the issues that we have
are systemic and they actually came from
you know they they've been with the
plant for a very long time uh that's the
stage of life where those things will
start to uh start to gain a little bit
more of a foothold now that the plant's
weaker and they they have kind of an
Avenue of attack um so as it gets later
on then I'll start transitioning from
start transitioning more into those
things that are really going to be
uh antagonistic to the pathogens U and
that's to to where by the end of the
life cycle that's really all you're
trying to put in there because the the
plant is it's got It's you know it's got
the majority of its nut the nutrients
that it's going to be using either in
the stored form of Bri you know
measuring bricks levels things like that
it's part of building up the bricks and
so the middle stage of using a lot of
those type of bacterias um uh will will
help to increase the bricks levels and
then that's a lot of the stored energy
for the plant and as you get down to the
last bit of the life cycle and you know
a lot of that stuff is is kind of
already set in motion you're not
necessarily as dependent especially if
you're supplementing Foods soluble foods
like we do a lot of times in laid flour
um you know you're supplementing like I
said from end to PK depending on where
you are in the life cycle and as you
transition from P to K and you get into
the end of the life cycle um you know
we're we're using Bloom boosters and
we're we're feeding them stuff that's
soluble which is also going to disrupt
the biology in the soil um prior to I
guess my personal approach early on for
a lot of this stuff is that you don't
want to feed them heavily ever really I
I don't lean towards that ever to you
know just pump full of steroids cuz it's
just it's not not how I would want to do
everything in
moderation um and and then as they get
to the later part of their life cycle it
just it to me it seems much more
um uh much more uh realistic or or My
intuition I guess then says to okay now
we've gotten pretty close to the end of
the road let's make sure we don't have
any problems and concentrate really on
um on the things that that are either
going to help the plant finish assuming
that it already has access to everything
else that it wants um either by
supplemental feeding CU you know end of
flour were always supplemental feeding
on some level uh uh so then then the
te's become more targeted towards pess
suppression disease disease suppression
things like that and then you can shift
that at any point in time too if you're
having um you if you're having specific
issues that you want to Target you know
so you have you have fungus gats or you
have uh roote aphids or you know things
like you then I wouldn't necessarily add
like the very basana is one that I use
for some of that stuff I wouldn't
necessarily add that to any te unless I
was interested in making sure that I'm
not going to end up with a fungus knot
explosion or rud aphids taking off or
anything like that then I would so later
on in the process I start to add things
like that more to the tea so I'll add
more of the streptomyces I'll add more
of the very vasana um subtilus is really
a good one for the whole process that
one also is is is an antagonist of a lot
of pathogens so those would be kind of
the three General t's for me would be
first fungal dominant and then
transitioning into something that's a
little bit more bacterial focused where
you have some of those um and anything
that's producing like a like a plant
growth hormone um and then towards the
end it's just making sure that we cross
the finish line uh you know in a strong
way and not not get all the way to the
finish line and then oh oh I can't move
yeah totally so one one peanut gallery
question uh I'm glad you mentioned
fungus uh do you think a lot of people
who GRE SE just sort of solely focus on
bacteria um and sort of forget about or
don't think about the importance of
fungus my experience with the majority
of people that are using te's or a lot
of people that I speak to using te's is
the the understanding of the difference
between a fungal dominant tea and a
bacterial dominant tea and what it takes
to achieve those two things is not
necessarily common knowledge and what it
requires a little more
investigation um and
uh
so I guess in a lot of cases it just
seems like a lack of a lack of
understanding of you know okay this is
what I'm trying to do this is why and
this is how I achieve it versus I've
heard I've heard compost te's work
really well and so I'm going to buy
these products and I'm going to combine
them in this rate that I found online
and I'm going to create a compost te and
I'm going to feed it to my plants but
the number of people that are doing it
and not able to actually
determine anything about their tea other
than the fact that it's brown and smells
the way they say it's supposed to smell
if you don't have a microscope to look
at it and actually see those life forms
and have I produced a bunch of fungal Hy
or have I produced a bunch of bacteria
and um it's like is that yeah so I I
think that in in my discussions with a
lot of people and a lot of lot of the
questions that I F is um that it it
takes a bit more sophistication and an
expensive microscope that you utilize to
look at your te's and see where your
te's are and if the balance is where it
needs to be and most people don't have
access to that and don't have the
knowledge of that but there are plenty
of good recipes out there for General
te's like you were saying basilla
subtilus is a good overall it kind of
works for everything and it's pretty
easy to find in bagged mixes and then to
multiply into 5 gon with an AirStone so
um in general a lot of the tea recipes
come out as a general overall tea um but
when you get into production as large
and specific as we do here then you need
to know exactly what's going into your
tea and what's coming out of your tea um
so you know when to use it and if your
tea is ripe or not
[Music]