[Music]
we're gonna dig into our panel now are
you ready are you ready for this yeah
all right I'm gonna go ahead and
introduce our panel we have james eikner
here from sauna packaging he's going to
talk about hep based solutions for
packaging which is quite important we
have our star Cristina Dempsey of the
manufacturing cannabis safety branch
this is the regulatory body from the
Department of Health here in California
that regulates packaging Andrew Hopkins
of the workshop and Julie Crockett of M
MLG consultancy here in Santa Monica so
let's start with you James can you talk
to us a little bit about hemp based
plastic and why it's a great alternative
or could be for petroleum-based plastics
so I'm with sauna packaging and we
design and develop hemp plastic
packaging solutions for the cannabis
industry simply put you can make plastic
out of a variety of bio-based materials
hemp being one of them
most bio plastic in the United States is
made out of corn and when we first
started working on this we were
basically frustrated consumers looking
at the amount of petroleum plastic
packaging waste that we were creating
and as we started to look into
sustainable alternatives corn plastic
was the first thing we looked at but
seeing the evolution of the hemp
industry that's kind of been happening
in tandem with that at the cannabis
industry we thought it would be a good
idea to look into hemp based plastics
and that's kind of how we stumbled upon
it a few years ago basically the the
plastic that we use to make our
packaging which is right here is a fiber
reinforced biocomposite so we're using a
corn plastic resin which is a PLA as our
base material and then we're infusing
that with
my critized tempered which is the
innards of the stock which is currently
very underutilized part of the plant and
it's a hundred percent plant-based and
chemical free however I hope some of
what we'll get into this evening is
talking a little bit about waste
recovery which is a large challenge for
all packaging for instance I believe
that only 40% of packaging is actually
recovered where 60% is landfilled
so recovery is a challenge for all
packaging materials but it's
additionally complicated in the cannabis
industry due to a number of factors the
largest of which is it'll be interesting
to see how it plays out in California
but for instance in Colorado even if the
plastic that your cannabis packaging is
made out of is recyclable recycling
facilities there do not accept cannabis
packaging so either a change needs to
happen where facilities can accept it or
there's a missing piece of the puzzle
which would be you know a company that
sterilizes or cleans the packaging
before it goes to the facility so waste
recovery is a big challenge and you know
regardless of how cool the materials are
that we continue to develop that's
something that needs to be addressed
before we can really solve the problem
of waste within cannabis packaging and
within sustainable packaging in general
can you speak to us about poison
prevention and what the what the testing
is that's required to be considered
child resistant packaging because my
understanding is it does require quite a
bit of testing and from my my research I
believe that you can do your own testing
if you like but it's it's it's a
difficult endeavor and there are
entities or agencies that will do that
for you I'd like to know a little bit
more about that yeah so ASTM
the organization that kind of monitors
all of this however the testing can be
done by a number of third-party testers
the poison Prevention Act I believe was
in 1970 I forget exactly what spawned it
but basically child resistant packaging
was developed at that point and to stop
children under a certain age from be
able to access certain substances so it
was pioneered in the pharmaceutical
industry and now it affects cannabis and
as you would imagine
rather it's kind of exactly what you
would imagine when you do the physical
testing whereas you actually get a room
full of you know 200 kids and under I
believe it's 48 months or something and
they have the way the testing actually
goes is they're giving they're given the
packaging samples they're given five
minutes to try and open it and then
after those five minutes they're
explained how to open it and then they
have five additional minutes and you're
supposed to hit a threshold I believe of
over eighty percent so if more than 20%
of the samples are open then you fail
the testing and that's kind of as as
simply as I can put it but it is kind of
funny being there and watching all these
kids try and open packaging there are
allowances for elderly packaging in
other industries and unfortunately
that's not something that's been made
available to us potentially you can talk
to us about why that is that the the
elderly rosalie allowance was not part
of our regulatory basis sure so again my
name is Kristy and I'm the outreach
manager for the California Department of
Public Health's manufactured cannabis
safety branch was which is a whole lot
of words before I answer your question
I'll just tell you my area of specialty
is cannabis manufacturing and
manufactured products so if there's a
question that is asked in the audience
or by Courtney
that is falls under another state office
I'll tell you which state office it is
but I can't answer those questions so
I'll try to be as clear as I can for
answers that fall under our office and
I'll tell you where they fall if they
don't so to answer your question about
the elderly packaging allowances the
medicinal and adult use cannabis
regulation and Safety Act or mal curse'
which created the whole cannabis
regulatory structure for both adult use
and medicinal cannabis specifically
states child resistant packaging it
doesn't refer to the poison prevention
packaging act that's what our office did
in talking about what would qualify as
child resistant packaging but because
the act itself refers to all cannabis
and cannabis products being in child
resistant packaging we didn't have any
req regulatory authority to allow for
something like that it's worth noting
that with the elderly allowance you
would be able to say on the package this
is for households with no children in
which instance you would not need the
child resistant packaging so that would
be pretty nice for us it would also
reduce them out of plastic because in
many of the solutions some of the
solutions I passed around here today
you'll see that plastic is providing a
solution with the child-resistant cap
for example so potentially we can get
around that another issue that I see is
that with pharmaceutical industry for
example they can do shipments of bulk
products so the pharmacy isn't getting
tiny bottles of child resistant
packaging they're getting a bulk
shipment and then they are packaging at
the retail level and in our industry
unfortunately we're not packaging at the
retail level and there's no bulk
packaging available to us is that
something that we can also ask you about
Christina about what may be the
reasoning was for that or okay we're
gonna talk to the bureau later
all right let's let's turn to you guys
Andrew and Julie I know that you have
different specialties but can we ask you
about some of the issues you've seen
with your clients that we didn't talk
about and potentially individuals in our
audience have had similar issues my name
is Julie Crockett I'm a director of
compliance for M MLG I was recruited to
help launch a brand called W vapes a
vaporizer brand in 2015 I very I mean I
had no experience in the cannabis
industry my previous job I was a
marketing director for an adult toy
company so that was my background with
dealing in fringe industries and I you
know walked into as a civilian in Los
Angeles I thought in knowing nothing
about cannabis law I was like there's
dispensaries everywhere it's been
illegal for years it's no big deal and
then I realized I walked into an empty
warehouse an empty office building in an
extraction laboratory and was like
what's up guys what are you doing and
and and realized that I was put in
charge of an unlicensed business in Los
Angeles and very quickly made myself
their chief compliance officer and
helped guide that company towards
compliance and did that for three years
and then ended up doing a flip where I
went to work with our compliance
attorney at MLG and and now my my old
job became a client and now I get to
help a bunch more people go through this
process so as a person what I do with
them MLG is I am the do ongoing
compliance with all kinds of different
operators so I work with cultivators and
manufacturers and retailers pretty much
every license type and and go in and
help them to figure out how to navigate
and meet the requirements of these
regulations which is brutal enough like
the experience the real-world experience
of operators trying to adjust their
businesses and continually pivot to the
demands of these regulations
is heartbreaking and crucifying to watch
the the costs of compliance the costs of
lawyers and consultants and redesigning
your packaging and and the impossibility
of competing with an illicit market at
this moment is crushing the most
compliant companies that I work with are
doing the worst our suffering are losing
money their sales are down 60 to 90
percent they cannot sustain and compete
in this environment that said you know I
help them try to find a way so so some
of it is understanding like that this
you know this is an evolving system the
one thing that gives me hope as we go
through this process is one cannabis
folks are wily and creative and they
will find a way so that's a good part
and to that this is a living evolving
process that is still happening that
there is like the the political
activation that has happened for me as
an individual by going through this
process by working at the state level
with organizations like CCI a and the
trade organizations with local
organizations like glocca like go seeing
human beings inform policy and watch
laws change I saw a law change sitting
in a meeting with the Department of
Public Health because what it was
written is not what they meant and when
somebody from the industry explained to
them do you realize what the impact of
this law is gonna do to businesses they
went oh no that's not what we meant
let's change that so we're actually in
this incredible moment of time where the
agencies the state agencies know that
they don't know everything and are
listening and willing to receive input
and they have to hear a voice that's
loud enough and clear enough and can
tell a concise enough story because
attention spans and time is short to
communicate
like the real needs of this industry
because it's a very short window that we
have right now really short window and
when this period comes up of the the
full regulatory language being
introduced in operators have 45 days to
make a comment on it which the agencies
have to respond to every single comment
that is submitted during that time there
has never been a better time to tell
your story and state your experience and
talk about what needs to be done and
what's not working and and not receive
this is something that's just happening
to you but it's something that's
actually being participated in because
for years I've been saying in these next
like you know few months we're either
going to see the cannabis industry wake
up come together and become one of the
biggest like political forces the world
has ever seen to defend what has been
built or see it get ripped out of our
hands and become an industry like every
other industry and Amazon will be like
delivering vapes it'll be it'll suck so
basically that's what I do I want to add
to that I worked with a global cannabis
manufacturer and I worked so hard
through the winter holidays to bring
medicine to patients and then in January
discovered that there was 800 dollar fee
per unit for for the testing so when
we're larger companies and we're going
to market and we're bringing large
volumes of product it can make sense you
kind of work it out in terms of the
volume but if you have smaller volumes
of product and you didn't know it's a
huge it's a huge expense especially if
you have multiple SCU's because of the
testing is per stew that means you have
a different size product it's each size
so that's something worth noting
first of all tough act to follow
my name is Andrew Hopkins I work for the
workshop we are a laboratory front
pioneering some terpene development and
flavors in addition we do compliance
consulting up and down the entire
cannabis supply chain myself personally
I work a lot with the manufacturing side
of things so to answer the original
question what are some of the challenges
the workshop has observed with brands
and specific to packaging the biggest
challenge we're facing right now is with
the idea of preprinting potency as
Courtney mentioned before the only
requirements to list on your label are
THC and CBD that's it you have a plus or
minus 10% variance on that those listed
cannabinoids
now there's two caveats I want to
mention to this as Courtney mentioned if
you start to list other cannabinoids THC
a CBD a any of the others the same rules
apply 10% plus or minus and generally
speaking those cannabinoids are found at
much lower levels in your packaging the
same it applied to CBD traditional vape
cartridges let's just assume it's 700
milligrams it might that gives you
basically 70 milligrams plus or minus of
your variance on your testing so you
have some wiggle room based on the BCC
regulations however CBD if you only have
one milligram in your product you have
10% that gives you almost no wiggle room
in the BCC state testing laboratory
requirements so what we recommend and
although brands generally do not like it
we recommend do not drink your potency
on your permanent packaging
apply some sort of sticker that you do
at the time of production because that
way you do your final potency testing
and you'll know that hey it's going to
be within that 10% threshold
unfortunately if you go off and do a
5,000 print run and preprint your
potency due to manufacturing
complications we know that that potency
can change and now you're in a position
where they're stuck with packaging you
can't use or you're going to have to
either label over it or sticker over it
in some way shape or form to make it
compliant and so although it's not
aesthetically pleasing keep this in mind
as you go to your manufacturers that if
you want to pre print your potency you
better be darn sure you can not get
block down that number
because if you can't your boxes are
gonna look even worse with markers all
over and stickers the Henry's package
that I passed around has what is called
the variable data label and you'll see
on there that that's a solution for this
problem that you're printing a variable
label instead of printing the boxes
themselves so that you don't have issues
when you're trying to meet this variance
of five milligrams which is quite
difficult when you work out the ratio
and the numbers so can we talk to you
Christina about some of the issues
facing the department Public Health I
think I want to just piggyback on
Julie's statement that the regulatory
bodies do care about what we have to say
as an industry that's another reason
we're here today we are here yes exactly
as I was getting into that yes they are
very responsive we reached out to them
and said would you please send a member
of your organization and she really
rallied for us to make sure that she
could be here so thank you for that
again maybe you can talk to us about
what are the issues for Public Health
that are at the top of your list that we
need to to discuss I know that brass
knuckles for example not to call them
out but we're gonna start to see some
more litigation and pertaining to
pesticides pesticides are a dire a dire
issue for our planet they're much more
prevalent now than they were 20 years
ago and if you are an organic cultivator
for example I'm using organic in the
sense that you are cultivating without
pesticides if you are cultivating
organically you can be subject to what
we call pesticide drift so other farms
are using pesticides and now it
compromises your cultivation so it's
something that's pretty serious and we
want to we want to we want to keep an
eye on that because it affects our
children we're finding that there are
residues of pesticides in the umbilical
cord it's causing brain damage this is a
real issue and it's here today so just
for example though I'll let you take it
from here okay that was a lot of
different things but I'll give you some
public health issues that we're
are looking at because testing happens
in the final stage right before product
goes to retail which is different from
some of the other states I think a lot
of the contaminated product issues that
other states have seen will not happen
in the same volume in California so as
many headaches as the testing system
does create I think there's some public
health benefit to the way that it's set
up from one of the things that we've
been looking at is how manufacturing
facilities are set up so we have quite a
number of extractors among our
manufacturer population and one of the
things that our inspectors are looking
at is do you know how to operate the
equipment that you have which shouldn't
be a tough question but it is with
people coming into this market we've
seen people who order equipment and they
read the instructions and they think oh
I know how to operate this and the
reality is extraction is a chemical
process in a lot of instances and you
have to understand chemistry or at least
basic science so one of the things our
inspectors have been asking when they go
into facilities is tell me how this
equipment works how do you disassemble
it to clean it some basic questions
about it
so we've been looking at is it being
operated safely as it's set up safely
are there any risks to the workforce and
the surrounding communities
so that's products that's manufacturing
I don't know any other public health
issues that are on your mind I think it
might it might do some justice to share
the fact that much of the regulatory
outline is based on historical context
so for example I don't know if you all
remember the tylenol murders of 1982 but
this is where this tamper-evident
packaging stems from individuals went to
the store they purchased tylenol
they took it for a headache and then
unfortunately that was their demise
because it was poisoned and in that day
I think you know as a as a populace we
were much more trusting so there wasn't
a concern about whether or not someone
had tampered with your product of course
now I think we've we've come to a point
where maybe it's a little excessive
however there are solutions we spoke
about whether or not you can use a paper
strip around your package to indicate
whether it's been tampered with and the
answer was yes also if you would like to
go a little bit step another step
further you can put your logo and print
that on the packaging so it's not just
an Avery label that anybody can pick up
and put on top of a package it's a
little bit more unique and descriptive
it's another branding component so
that's something that you can leverage
you can also put on your packaging a
little note to indicate that hey by the
way there was a tamper-evident strip
here if it's not here now then you
should be cautious and in taking this
product I'll add one thing to the public
health side because I like that you
brought up packaging and labeling our
labeling requirements are fairly
extensive and there's a reason for that
we really want consumers to be informed
about the products that they're
consuming so it comes from a real place
the tamper evident that's part of MRSA
but I think there's real value to
knowing when these products have been
opened before and then the
child-resistant piece is comes from mal
Karsa because mal cursus says that one
of the cornerstones of all of our
regulations that we develop but the law
in general is protection of Public
Health and use in particular
so the child-resistant packaging
requirements while they can feel like a
lot to grapple with as a business the
legislature was really keeping the
residents of the state of California in
mind for that I visited Oregon a few
years ago and I took the opportunity to
go to a retail out a dispensary and when
I went in they had
a exit package so when you go there you
can purchase an exit package II I don't
say if that's the case now but at the
time okay thank you when you go in you
can purchase an exit package it's child
resistant and it creates a solution for
all of your packaging needs so we don't
have an instance where we're trying to
package a pre-roll for example to be
child resistant sana James brought a
very nice example of a solution here
it's similar to a Tylenol bottle when
you turn the cap and you align the notch
and then you can open it so we're
creating these solutions to to meet the
demands but there there are solutions
that other markets have presented Oregon
being one if you don't if you don't
purchase this exit package that's child
resistant you can bring your own so
similar to what we have here in
California the ten cent bag requirement
if you bring your own package we're
reducing waste where we're using and
that's something that we could be doing
here in California as well we could be a
model for the entire nation of course
Oregon's already done it
so here's a question if if I may is it
possible for you to elaborate on
potentially why we didn't choose that as
a solution for California it's the way
that Marisa was worded and I don't know
if it was intentionally or not but the
way mousekersize worded is is that that
child resistant packaging piece must be
done before retail sale so our
interpretation or the bureau's
interpretation is that that means before
the time of sale so you're talking about
on the product quite a few other states
have used exit packaging that is child
resistant to do that same function to
protect consumers I I think it's a
possibility here but our position is
that it would require a legislative
change to be able to allow us to change
that in regulations I just want to add
to that I think one of the issues with
the exit bag conundrum is that it causes
redundant packaging and if you have a
legislative environment where you're
trying to
everyone comply to certain regulations
to have the wiggle room of being able to
use an exit bag just causes people to
not necessarily meet the regulations
because they can fall back on a retail
outlet having to use an exit bag and
that costs retail outlet and it also
these exit bags are typically made out
of mylar which are very terrible for the
environment and then even if you do have
someone for instance in Oregon it's
about 50/50 there whether the actual
package that the product and is child
resistant and even if it is child
resistant the dispensaries they're just
trying to cover their asses so they'll
still throw it in a mylar exit bag and
so then you have a child resistant
packaging package and I just think it
opens kind of a Pandora's box for
inefficiency which leads me to my lower
packaging so in case you all are not
aware mylar is a metallus eyes plastic
and there are only three recycling
facilities in the entire country it's
also one of the most prevalent used
prevalent used packaging for cannabis
that we see so be aware that those
facilities are here in California
potentially we should be leveraging them
but if I may I would ask you to consider
glass or some other renewable resource
in your solutions
I spoke to James and I said hey are you
guys gonna do a hemp hemp based solution
for a CRP cap similar to what we talked
about earlier and they said it's on
their agenda you know they've done a
great service and in trying to bring
these products to market and these
solutions given that there is this
excessive testing that has to happen for
example there's a cost associated and
I'd like to maybe can we talk a little
bit more on about the the hemp solution
and how it affects the the landfills in
terms of the way that methane gas is
released etc yeah absolutely so
I'm plastic similar to corn plastic is
biodegradable however that is not to be
confused with compostable so
biodegradable just means that something
will break down in a reasonable amount
of time and it's literally defined as a
reasonable amount of time so that's up
for debate what reasonable is with
exposure to light water and oxygen
similarly compostable products are
defined that way but the reasonable
amount of time is 180 days within
certain conditions and where am I going
with this
methane gas exactly so what are the
benefits of hemp plastic is if your
product does end up in a landfill the
hemp will act as a carbon trap and it'll
trap that carbon so it won't release gas
however if it does go to an appropriate
composting facility it can also be
appropriately composted so it kind of
offers a dual solution and in the short
term we're gonna be looking at most hemp
plastic going to landfills simply
because waste recovery is a huge issue
and it's not just with hemp plastic even
with you know your to go Starbucks cups
that are made out of corn plastic about
5% of composting facilities nationwide
even accept that so it you know green
washing is the wrong term for it it's
more just an issue of consumer education
and consumer engagement and you know
goes back to the point I was saying
earlier about how we can keep innovating
materials and make materials more and
more sustainable but we're really not
going to solve you know this like
circular puzzle until we really address
that recovery part and so what I think
makes them interesting is that in the
short term while products go to the
landfill it'll act as a carbon trap and
then once we do have
the infrastructure required for all
sustainable packaging not just hemp it
can then go to a composting facility
thank you I want to just point out that
part of the reason we're here today is
to identify solutions so we're not just
talking about it we're not complaining
and we're actually looking at how we can
create solutions and and address some of
these issues Starbucks I want to point
out their lids are of a specific type of
plastic that extra can be toxic it's not
recyclable and they've created a
challenge they're offering 10 million
dollars for companies to come together
and make suggestions for alternatives so
that's something to be aware of also I
know that Julie is part of the CCI a
legislative committee pretend
potentially you can also speak Andrew to
how we can we can work to change
regulations how we can move through the
legislature legislature and what those
steps are what can we do information
have a child resistant packaging all of
this so I'm wondering from the agency's
perspective from the Department of
Public Health what are the plans if any
that the Department of Public Health has
for public education about why somebody
shouldn't buy that $10 gram and what's
wrong with it and why consumers right
now where they're just coming to you
know licensed operators and going why is
this so expensive and why do you use so
much packaging and you're ruining the
earth and what's wrong with you like how
the departments and agencies can help
the licensed operators with the
education of the public of why they
should care that they're using you know
really expensive but you know laboratory
tested and well packaged products
I think this the fact that licensed
products are laboratory tested has to be
a huge selling point for people so III
do think it's an area where there needs
to be more education the bureau so
there's three state offices for cannabis
we're one of them and then the Bureau of
cannabis control which most people are
familiar with is the lead agency for
cannabis so the bureau put in their
budget request for this year money for a
public education campaign on that very
issue so both consumer education and for
educating people about how to come into
the licensed market we're still all so
this is part of the state process we're
still all going through our budgeting
processes but I think something like
that would go a long way towards helping
people understand how these products
that come from licensed companies are
different not only for the product
itself but because you know that that
manufacturer located down the street
from this place that you go to all the
time is not a safety risk for your
community I think even things like that
are important for people to know how do
we make these changes what can we do as
individuals to make those changes
there's a Los Angeles City Council
meeting tomorrow morning at 8:30 a.m.
everybody gonna be there all of you I'll
be looking for you I mean those things I
mean that's the thing that those things
actually work the people who show up who
make the public comments you know some
of the things being discussed tomorrow
that the state has introduced the s-type
license for shared facilities which is
huge for small businesses and smaller
operators Los Angeles needs to introduce
this license type as a local option
because we don't have that license type
there's many many facilities ready to go
that could do it if they could get a
shared license authorization there at
the local level you know Los Angeles I'm
just speaking specifically Los Angeles
Los Angeles doesn't have any testing
labs we got a test July 1st everything's
gotta be tested we don't have a
the lab in los angeles it's gonna be a
problem i think there's what what like
eight 18 13 how many lab there's like 20
or so we're up to 20 or so great so you
know 20 labs let's do it every product
has to be tested so los angeles is
looking to mainline an emergency you
know licensing process for testing
laboratories in los angeles because we
need them there are there were 55 i
think we're down to 37 bills currently
going through at the state level that
have to do with cannabis issues some of
these would impact operators like you
couldn't believe like there's a bill
right now that's trying to define a
mature plant as anything that's 18
inches that doesn't work for a lot of
people that's arguable so so knowing
that those things are happening at the
local level at the state level you have
to show up you have to say your opinion
you have to not be crazy when you show
up and say your opinion i'm just gonna
say that too like don't don't go up at
the city council meeting and be like we
want an unregulated market ship is
sailed
we want a regulated market i got a kid i
want good schools i want roads you know
i want things i want this money to be
distributed well i want an equity
program i want social justice that's why
I voted for it yes many people are
having you know voters remorse about
prop 64 we didn't know exactly how it
was gonna shake down but it was time and
the main thing is that it is a moving
evolutionary process that is not over
that is never even when the full
language comes out it's not over you can
do like bills you can do like politics
everything we saw in School House Rock
is real like you can do it you can make
a petition you know whatever it sounds
ridiculous but the world is you know
crazy and anything's possible at this
point so the main thing is being engaged
and the one thing that I will say again
my feeling is you
the big thing right now is you know
pathways to compliance how do we get
more people participating in this
industry
nobody genuinely who wants to
participate in the cannabis industry is
your enemy like the days of small groups
battling with other small groups is over
the Giants at the gate are just hovering
you know you look at what I now call the
Canadian Menace the Canadian like most
major companies in Canada trace it back
who owns them this industry is changing
in front of our eyes there's huge
multinational corporations itching to
come by your companies you know some of
that's great someone maybe that's what
you want to do that's great but if you
want to preserve the dream of the
industry that has kind of existed the
time for action is now it is gonna be
over soon
and as I've always said the main
beautiful potential of this industry is
that the world has always been filled
with like healers and shamans and cool
people but they've never been sitting on
top of a multi-billion dollar industry
that they need to like own and get
politically active and like donate to
politicians you want to change some
stuff donate to some politicians they
will listen to you it's crazy doesn't
one thing I've learned at the state
level it's pay to play it's like the
Sunset Strip out there man but but when
you have the seat at the table have a
good story
don't be crazy okay so I just wanted to
tell you all before the panel Julie told
me that she has to be out of here at 8
o'clock because she's going to theater
and I feel like she's a show woman I
want to piggyback off of that a little
bit because I think especially because
this is sort of Co marketed or whatever
the relationship is with cc MA it's
important to talk about industry
associations so
see CMAC CIA there's a number of local
ones any sort of outlet like that where
you come together and you make your
voice a little bit louder is really
valuable I think for us as regulators
sometimes we look to industry groups and
we say hey what are all of your
membership saying about this are all of
your membership confused about this is
there some issue that this collective
group that you represent is having
trouble with and that really helps us
just to piggyback on Courtney's question
on how to influence legislation and
regulation change I think first of all
you're doing it right now you're here
you're attending you're learning that's
that's the first step here yeah that's
really the first step in addition I know
Julie spoke to this earlier but you know
regulations changed again you know a few
weeks ago and by law not just with
cannabis other regulations as well
there's a public comment period not very
long especially this last one but yeah
you know that's your time that's your
time to talk and that's your time to get
your answers out there your questions
and your feedback and by law the state
has to listen doesn't mean they have to
act but they have to listen so that's
the first thing you can do and that's
the public forum the next suggestion I
would have for every single one of you
out there is based on my experience so
far in the last few months all three
government agencies regulating cannabis
wants people to be and companies to be
in the system I know it's a challenge
know what's gonna cost money it's a
burden to entry but if all that being
said they want us to get out of the gray
market in the black market they want us
to be legit want us to be legal so all
that being said submit your questions
online there go to the BCC go to CD pH
go to CDFA there's website that just
says email for questions they will
answer you do not even have to be some
huge corporation answers ask a question
is an individual why not what's the
worst that can do not answer and again
from my experience so far answers have
been excellent they've been timely
they've been promptly and it's
effectively again everyone wants this to
happen in the right way so if you ask
the right questions in the right way
based on my experience so far
the you know government agencies are
gonna respond in the right way thank you
I asked Christina if it's possible for
individuals or companies to send their
actual packaging and ask for input and
unfortunately I think that time has
passed I personally did send several
emails asking for guidance and I did
receive prompt responses that were quite
hopeful and there's one more thing I
want to talk about and then I think we
should probably open up to questions so
start thinking about what you want to
ask while you still listen to us lab
testing so for a lab testing its pass or
fail and when you said you're talking
about your child and it just reminded me
that you know cannabis as medicine and
cannabis is medicine for adults and for
children so when we have a pass or a
fail if we have some of this critical
illness there is a concern that those
trace amounts of pesticides can be
harmful so not all of us have healthy
immune systems I'm son of us are looking
at what that what that can do to
compromise our health and it's something
worth noting so I just like to turn to
love you and ask if you've had any
instances where this is something that's
come to your forefront or perhaps maybe
there's other ways that we should be
approaching lab testing besides a pass
or fail anyone you know just to be
honest the latest regulations that pass
by the BCC changes change some of the
tolerance levels for for some of the
testing and it's a challenge it is it's
a capital expense to buy that kind of
machinery to perform these tests I don't
really have a good answer unfortunately
but you know again as the laws of law
and these are the these are the path
that's been been directed so you know
you can either try to influence
legislation and hope it goes back or I
hate to say it grin and bear it because
it's probably going to be a reality you
know I think that almost everything that
gets passed that has to do with safety
generally doesn't get taken back so when
we talk about these pesticides solvents
and these tests aside levels being you
know very very stringent I just hate to
admit it guys start finding clean
material I
should put it I want to piggyback on
that a little bit and say that one of
the most effective things you can do is
vote for your dog vote with your dollar
and something you can do while you're
shopping is look for certain
certifications I'm sure you're all aware
of the fact that you know not being a
federally regulated substance cannabis
is not subject to USDA certification so
kind of in the absence of those a number
of third-party certifications to the
rose and something I always do when I'm
shopping for cannabis products is look
for either clean green certified or
certified kind or diem pure which is a
really cool one because it's for
regenerative cannabis and that's I think
a great way of kind of you know weeding
out a lot of the shit that you otherwise
get Demeter is a 40-year organization
biodynamic cultivation it's a bit
esoteric but in the very basic it's a
more stringent requirement than the FDA
would require if organic cultivation so
that's another avenue that you can
pursue with that let's open up our panel
to questions how are we doing on time
Julie okay we have like ten minutes guys
Jodi Kristina is there any kind of
certification that you foresee coming
down to give us more information about
the microbes or other issues pertaining
into tests pesticides so her question is
really about labeling and and you know a
past past lab requirements kind of label
I don't see that coming because the
truth is if it doesn't pass lab testing
it will not be able to be sold there is
some allowance for certain products if
they do not pass lab testing they can be
remediated which you mentioned that word
so I wanted to talk about it a little
bit so if a product fails lab testing
for any issue other than labeling THC
concentration something like that so it
passes because there are pesticides in
it or there's some mold and flowers a
common
then it can be remediated if a plan is
sent to the Department of Public Health
and approved it'll go back to a
manufacturer the manufacturer usually
it's like an extraction process that
they put it through to try and clear out
whatever contaminant is in there it
still has to go back through lab testing
to confirm that it works so at the end
of the day the products that you have on
the shelf are still products that have
passed lab testing
I asked Christina what happens if the
packaging is not compliant and it's past
the July first deadline and she notified
me that that's a question for the PCC so
I want you all to be aware of that I
think at this point the BCC is intending
to provide education and guidance as
opposed to just laying down a hammer so
we can be a little flexible but we
should all really strive for this this
deadline of July 1st questions on that
really quickly I will say the Bureau has
a transition period and like a July 1st
fact sheet up on their website that
talks a little bit about I don't think
they're going to just look the other way
for packaging again this is a question
that asks them about how exactly they're
gonna approach it what I can tell you
that I've seen is that we've had six
months of a transition period and that's
a relatively short time for a business
to get up to date on regulations to
order new packaging to in many ways
raise the bar for compliance but so my
team reviews every email that comes in
to our office we got almost no questions
about packaging and labeling maybe like
a handful over the last the first five
months of the transition period in the
past two or three weeks we have been
inundated with questions about packaging
and labeling can you review my label no
we cannot is this correct what about
this requirement and what that says to
me is that as far as packaging and
labeling goes I think it was one of the
last people and one of the last things
on people's minds so I in some ways I'm
not sure if it's sort of
six month of a transition period that
opportunity was squandered a little bit
or it was an overwhelming everything
else was on the mind first but at some
point we have to have an end to the
transition period and the date is July
1st that's what we announced in November
so again I would talk to the bureau
about how they're going to enforce this
at a retail standpoint but at some point
it has to change over to compliant
packaging so we can start saying that
message about the products on the Shelf
here are different from the products on
that unlicensed shelf there and I think
many of us know that retailers have
already stopped accepting packaging that
is not compliant a gentleman in the back
can we still use stickers to adjust the
packaging this has been an interesting
question because in our transition
period language in the CDP H emergency
regulations we talked about you can use
a sticker to satisfy patent to satisfy
labeling requirements during the
transition period and people some people
read that as you can only use a sticker
during the transition period but that's
not the case you can use a sticker at
any time as long as it's actually
adhered to your package and not one of
those peel away stickers great question
blue hat backwards
yes they they rip open so that's your
tamper evidence and the mylar packaging
when it's heat sealed is that considered
tamper evident yes that's a good
indication that someone has been in your
bud so the only products that have to be
an opaque packaging are edibles flour
does not non-edible manufactured
products do not we get that question a
lot too
how about a ziplock if it's Ziploc if
it's well it would have to be child
resistant reusable like this yes like
this
so it says that you can't use an exit
package so the product packaging itself
is what has to be a child resistant we
have distinguished we use the term
secondary package because you could use
a bag like that to meet the child
resistant packaging requirements as long
as it has all of your labeling
requirements on it your package is
already packaged into that exit
packaging is what a retailer puts your
whole purchase in before you walk out
the door so that's different from
secondary packaging so what we're
looking at is is your product each
individual product sold in some sort of
child resistant packaging it could be a
bag it could be something else
so for pre-rolls for example let's IVA
pre-roll package if it's not if it's not
child resistant that solution to bring
it to market by July first can be a
child resistant package it would be an
additional expense but it will it will
bring you compliant so that's that's
something worth noting see the CBD and
THC will be kept separate or
but are you working with the TTP at all
in on packaging with alcoholic beverages
that are including CBDs and not nice
like non psychoactive effects with like
turkey so it's a it's a you repeat the
question so his question is about
alcoholic beverages being infused with
THC and/or CBD either way so that would
be a manufactured product if you're
talking about CBD from cannabis and we
specifically prohibit alcoholic
beverages from being sold as cannabis
products it doesn't matter if it's THC
or CBD
there's also CBD from industrial hemp
which Marisa specifically excludes from
the definition of cannabis so it doesn't
fall under our office
but from what I understand with the
offices that it does fall under it's
still prohibited it's a good question
because we are seeing a number of beers
that are including cannabis across the
nation young lady here with the blonde
hair please a physician endorsed formula
how would we add it to the label and who
would we speak to so obviously I could
be corrected here but one of the
requirements for all manufactured labels
is that the product that every claim
must be truthful and factual on the
label so if you have a clinical study
from a physician that you could actually
document in sight as backup if some
regulatory agency came knocking on your
door I think that you would be okay to
include that and as already previous men
should previously discussed there is no
quote-unquote label approval that has to
go through the state with California now
that all being said I strongly
discourage this practice because what
you're doing is the moment we start
making we as the industry start making
drug and health claims on our products
you open the door for the FDA to come in
and now look at you so you know we are
legal within the state of California and
we followed the rules within the state
of California but you start saying pain
relief cures cancer you know all this
kind of stuff
you better have some sort of
documentation behind it to back it or
else you're just opening the door for
legislation you can say things like
there's a relaxing physical effect but
you have to be pretty cautious I'm sorry
good yeah so there is a provision that
talks about health related statements so
if you're talking about one specific
physician said this one specific thing
and again backed up by a study maybe you
could get away with it I have to second
him I wouldn't do it the there the
provision about health related
statements so you're talking about
treats this disease cures insomnia
something like that those are only
permitted if there is a consensus of
science I can't remember the exact
wording but it is a significant
scientific agreement and peer-reviewed
studies and at this point there is not
that there is a provision that allows
you to include statements about what we
call characteristic anticipated effects
so that's like something that informs
the consumer about what they might feel
if they take the product so might make
you drowsy might have a relaxing effect
something like that but yeah the second
you start to get into anything disease
related you are really inviting a level
of scrutiny that I don't think you want
this gentleman over here with the rosin
hat on so his question is about
characters cartoons it's essentially
there's a provision that one of the
labeling prohibitions is anything that
is intended to be or is attractive to
children and it lists a couple of
examples cartoons are one the word candy
or candies is one there's a couple of
things so we've gotten a lot of
questions about this since the rules
originally came out and it was
essentially the question that we usually
get is something like can you tell me
exactly what this means
and that's a really hard question for us
to answer because every time we've tried
to put really concrete regulatory terms
around it you either end up looping in
things that are not attractive to
children or not including things that
really are so the way it's worded is you
cannot include labeling or images that
are attractive to children as determined
by the department on a case-by-case
basis if you have a question about
something on your label like that you
can send it to us and we'll look at it
but it's really challenging so I'll tell
you what we sort of look for in general
the thing that I usually say is we look
at the totality of the package just
because you include like a graphic on it
if it is an adult-themed package and it
just happens to have a drawing on it
that's not necessarily attractive to
children there are some things that we
look at in the market that are so
attractive to children and we're like
there's no question about it and then
there's some things that are clearly
marketed to adults it's the gray area
that's a little bit harder so if you
want me to look at it you can bring it
up afterwards or you can email us that's
very kind thank you I have cards here if
anyone wants them
great I think with that we need to
conclude our evening I feel like I hear
a cue here I want to ask you all to
visit future cannabis project and if
you'd like to know more about these
types of events you can visit white
buffalo cannabis calm forward-slash
events and I hope to see you all very
soon thank you again to our panel thanks
Julie please stick around and enjoy some
drinks and some food from solidarity
you
[Music]