[Music]
everything's getting flushed out with
licensing and so yeah we're gonna see
another flush out once the temporary
licenses go away so yeah that's going to
be an interesting landscape come early
next year
yeah and that's I think it's another
thing that's talking to a few growers
this morning one of them sitting on
about 325 acres up in Santa Barbara
County near Lompoc and then the other
guy has Humboldt has Humboldt ranch up
right outside of Eureka clearly right
next to a airport and it's interesting
the two different conversations because
what's going on in Humboldt just a crazy
crazy will just say that I won't you
saying customers you know versus how
quick and efficient their their being
with licensing any and permits to in a
place like Santa Barbara County versus
LA where it's just been crazy these guys
are do you know this because you're one
you're the one saving the day from the
growers that can't grow yeah you know
even in Humble we have I'm in three
different jurisdictions I have
unincorporated area Humboldt County city
of Arcadia so if you have a building in
Arcata that's different
and then there's Eureka so now all three
municipalities are on Eureka was the
last one to come on board but they're
moving the fastest their processing
permit after permit and so I've heard
that it's really interesting to see how
the local municipalities either
roadblock or propel economy I mean at
this point it's it's real estate jobs
you know disposable income from humble
your your boutique shops their business
is down but it's getting harder find
vacant real estate housing markets doing
really well
grocery stores are doing really well
yeah employment is definitely on the
store because you go through you drive
by one of these cannabis facilities and
there are people there there are bars in
the parking lot because especially when
you come to packaging and processing
material I mean it takes a workforce so
no it's nice to see people don't get
that Eureka for several years has not
been a thriving
topless I mean when when all the timber
kind of pulled out of Northern
California by Northern California we
mean essentially north of San Francisco
or Santa Rosa more specifically you know
Trinity humble Eureka County Lake County
even you know into Nevada County north
of Sacramento that kind of saw this
constant decline of populous of jobs of
opportunity and this really is and
that's where again a played-out turn but
that's where I think like the Green Rush
replies like this is injecting the
monies and the people and everything
back into societies that are kind of
forgotten about yeah I bet people don't
realize that's a big portion of this
state
everything's it's just from San
Francisco to San Diego it's like there's
a whole other side of the state from San
Francisco to Medford you know so but I
mean I think I'm in a further like a
Eureka is pretty damn impressive there's
a lot of drug I mean yeah the industry's
gonna help clean up the city but would
be even better than if we can use the
cannabis to help get people off the
opiates get wonderful the meth and all
that stuff and so hopefully besides just
the economic base value of it that we
can do a social economic improvement in
terms of let's get people on more
cannabis and less opiates and less meth
and all the nasty drugs that kind of
make it an exit drug right we hate to
call the drug I think a lot of us Pierce
but honestly that's what really never
mind Daryl gates and the whole dare
movement from 1983 which again both of
us grew up with put that to bed and say
no if anything if we're going to call
the drug this is an exit drug because to
your point the opioid issue is an
epidemic in every every corner of this
country I mean just coming from that
show in Utah I mentioned they're having
problems there and they're seeing this
as a solution not just a solution for
cancer survivors like myself or for
children with Grandma epileptic seizure
issues I mean this really does it's a
miracle plan I call it that and I don't
know you know I'm totally serious about
it yeah you talked to like Aussies I
know max stone this great guy from the
hemp embassy down in Australia they
always preach about freeing the plant
and again at first I was like I'm free
the plant really I'm like that's true
they do need to free the plants
so much opportunities it makes sense
what you're saying all the Rastas caught
the healing of the nation's
yeah yeah yeah yeah they're on to
something that was
[Music]