really California trip I mentioned
earlier California has always been at
the forefront of marijuana reform past
proposition 215 almost 20 years ago and
have had a very those activists in the
room I've been doing this for 10 years
there's activists in the room of been
doing it much longer than that and now
we're standing here in a world that is
completely different than - 10 20 years
ago not only do we have medical cannabis
in 23 states but in the District of
Columbia we also have adult use markets
emerging Colorado Washington Oregon soon
Alaska and DC soon enough here in
California it's ours to lose 2016 but
these markets are also different every
every regulation every regulatory
framework and structure is different
than the one before it and sometimes
especially on the East Coast like the
the regulation seemed crazier than the
one before that came before it so and
there's also a little micro economies
within each state especially a huge
state like California where Los Angeles
is vastly different than in San
Francisco and so we have a assembled a
great panel from states across the
country and also national players to
kind of give a look from their
perspective at the different markets and
the economic opportunities because even
in these these heavily regulated markets
like New York Illinois there are
opportunities I'm so I'm going to start
with Jill actually always introduce the
whole panel to lamoureux
an advisor with bo tech and several
other other hats and then we have James
Slavik with Bank Corporation and Midwest
Matt Carnes with green wave advisors
Erin justice of buds and roses here in
LA
and you just told me your name and I
made you give me your card John KJ with
new fronts here so we'll start with Jill
since you're here to my right
so my name is Jill Amaro I am a former
operator in Colorado starting about 2008
i have worn several hats but most of
them focus on regulatory analysis and i
kind of wanted to talk a little bit
about how regulation actually drives all
of these different markets we're going
to be talking about so when we look at
new states one of the things i hope
people do is apply in the onboarding
states and come up with pro formas and
financials and the first thing that i do
when making projections first state is
go to the regulations and say what do
they say about the potential market size
and so I just kind of wanted to talk
about a couple of the major inputs and
and you guys in California have the
opportunity I've had a lot of people ask
me oh if you read the regulations and
I'm like you don't have regulations yet
this is legislation we have about
another five six hundred pages coming
and hopefully there'll be the
opportunity to provide a lot of input
into that process for those of you who
are here on the ground and advocates and
looking to make sure that this market
evolves the way that you can capitalize
on it so some of the major drivers the
one of the first things we look at you
know the economics start with the
patients one of the first things we look
at is what's the condition list and
that's not going to change here in
California probably has the best
condition listed in the country other
than maybe Massachusetts in Maryland and
a few states where they let doctors
prescribe for pretty much anything they
want but chronic pain and PTSD are the
two indicators we look at first 90% of
patients report chronic pain is why they
are using medical cannabis so it is
crucial in a good market for that to be
there the other thing with patients is
how hard is it to obtain a card are
there very few doctors because there's a
lot of pressure on them
there are a lot of doctors is it
expensive in Illinois you have to be
fingerprinted as a patient so that
drives our estimate of patient basis way
way down because not many people want to
subject themselves to that and I talked
a little bit about the environment for
the doctors so then the next thing is
what is it going to cost operators to
grow so what regulations really impact
operators plant limits canopy limits
really dictate how a market is if they
restrict the size of an operation you're
cutting down on economies of scale in
Washington for example where they have
plant canopies you have operators going
well can i stack
can I go vertical can I have three tiers
so there's always going to be that how
limited is my actual potential growth
and the other thing cannabinoid limits
so we see in Florida where you have to
be under point eight percent THC we see
in New York you can only have five
brands and they must be within one
hundred and five percent of this ratio
that drives up costs significantly when
you have to you know fraction eight and
separate Cambo noids and make sure that
your formulations are really on par with
what the legislation says and then
limited licenses that I mean for sure
dictates the size of a market is there
going to be competition or they're only
going to be 15 operators if there's only
Connecticut for example there's four if
one of those operators fails great for
the other operators but are they scaled
properly can they pick up the slack can
they you know can four people with all
that capex on them the amount of
investment they had to put into these
grows it was huge and so if they're not
prepared for that or they're not ready
for the market to come out way slower
than they anticipated it can really
impact the market if nobody is supplying
or producing or marketing to create a
patient base it can be really really
terrible what are the excise or VAT tax
and you know in Washington it was a
three-tiered system where it was 25
percent on top of 25 percent on top of
25 percent and they've already looked at
reworking that because if the taxes are
too high you obviously can't compete
with the black market what are the
Quality Assurance requirement
what are the testing requirements what
are the compliance requirements in
Colorado it started out that there was
zero quality assurance items at all and
as we have evolved now you have to have
an industrial hygienist you have to
touch a test every batch are there batch
limits does a lot size have to be five
pounds am I going to be testing every
five pounds or every twenty pounds and
what is the you know what is the number
of tests I have to do is this a twenty
five dollar potency test or is this a
thousand dollar full slate of tests on
every five pounds accounting and
record-keeping requirements you know you
wouldn't even think about this but if
they tell you you have to store camera
data for 90 days your you know server
and your computer costs go way way up
and so even the simplest thing like that
and how long are we gonna store these
videos for is critical so when you're
going through this mind-numbing
regulatory process you gotta look at
those little things and be like is this
gonna cost me money and those are the
ones to fight for or against and then
the demand factors are their purchase or
possession requirements or their limited
amounts that a patient can buy that
really really drives your budget as well
and then you know most recently
Minnesota just had an article about how
everybody's still on the black market
because the cost is just too high there
so when talking with regulators those
are the kind of things that you want to
pay attention to and be like if we drive
the cost way way we have an established
market here in California you have a set
price if the regulations drive that up
too much they're gonna force people back
into the black market so my talk will be
entirely different than Jill's because
I'm gonna take a step back because this
is the economics of cannabis so I'm
involved I started in 2009 on the
packaging side I started a company
called pop bottles calm and then kind of
morphed into the medicine side and now I
think arguably were when the largest
companies were in multiple states and so
I've seen the evolution of this industry
and now it's sort of at another croc
strip if you were here for the last
session trip was hitting on this and we
say you know the next great American in
stree and so when we talk about the the
economics of that there's you know the
challenges and the opportunities Aaron
is involved and and also I I must
preface this by saying there's always
the activism side because we're still
putting people in jail for possession of
this plant and that's kind of what got
me involved in the activism side a a
very quick story I was delivering I met
a elderly couple and they were getting a
cookie because this woman had
osteoarthritis and she was in pain in
the city of San Diego where we lived
they decided to shut down all the
collectives including that one where
this this elderly couple lived in an old
folks home and they came down they
didn't know about delivery service or
weed maps or Swede Maps they just knew
that this helped her more than the
vicodin they said the vicodin made her a
vegetable and you know all the other
side effects which I know about now -
I'm having that but they should the city
of San Diego and your government thought
better than them being able to have
access to that so they shut down that
collective and I was like you know what
that's just not right so I was like they
can't fight their eighty and infirm and
and I have a little bit of money and a
lot of gray hair so I'm gonna fight for
them I got on the activism side and I'm
on boards you know with MPP and I think
was one of the first people to get
involved with Aaron and the National
cannabis Industry Association so please
if you're not if you're just here for
the economic side of cannabis please
leave immediately because we're still
putting people in jail for this plant
and in harm reduction and what it's
doing to families and so forth and if we
don't address that we're really building
a house on a foundation of sand so
that's that's the the preface of speech
and Susan Susan knows that very well
so then back to the back to the business
opportunity so we've heard the the first
inning of the doubleheader or seven game
series or so forth there's no doubt it's
at the beginning so the what would I see
from from my level from going around the
the business interests and art view and
and the investors that at the very
beginning in 2009 10 and 11 no one would
invest so of course we have a hard time
getting banking of course we have a hard
time with the you know the IRS and 280e
and a number of things and we're doing
everything we can to resolve that but
there was just really no mechanism to do
a real business in California have to be
nonprofit other states you can be
for-profit so you know we're still
dealing that our corporate structure is
is convoluted because you know you're
not allowed to make a profit in
California from the sale of cannabis so
half the time you're dealing with
regulatory banks I've had ten banks in
six years and we are a there's a
multi-million dollar company and you
know we have a 401 K we have health
insurance we have corporate matching and
then they go oh yeah you have no bank
account I'm actually getting my
statements and then putting cash in an
envelope and we paid the tax payment
payments for the employees so very hard
to navigate that so you have a great
business model you've gone out and
you've raised your friends and family
capital and you're walking it out to the
marketplace well make sure that you
budget you know 30% for your of your
time for issues that you would never
deal with in any other business so if
you don't do that you're you're gonna be
in big trouble because when you get that
letter from Wells Fargo saying yes
you're dirty cannabis money is not
welcome here and we don't have to give
you a reason why and and and they won't
I've also been evicted twice we wanted a
buying a building in in San Diego
because we've been evicted twice and it
very costly to move so that impacts the
you know the business and its future so
going back to investment the future
we're seeing a very very very big
morphing now of the level of
sophistication of investors at the
beginning of art view we had 13 people
sit around a conference table and and we
were gonna put our own money in and
people came and pitched us a PowerPoint
and then he said who's interested in
that would raise our hand now ArcView
has over 450 maybe 500 accredited
investors people are now coming from
from Europe seeing the opportunity here
and in investing in this industry
originally they wouldn't touch the plant
still a lot of them are like that they
will invest in software and security and
and you know business services or
containers or any one of a myriad of
things that don't actually touch the
plant but are involved and generally in
the issue in this space that is now
changing more and more I'd say easily
50% of the investment companies firms
and individuals are now willing to
invest in grows processing you know we
see a lot of action and a space that
we're in the vape pen and concentrate
space and so we expect that to continue
so the risk profile originally no and
very few investors were willing to touch
over you touch a plant well no I much
rather invest in a software program that
helps people you know attract patients
so for a long time the largest company
in the space was weed maps because they
had what we call the first mover
advantage and they had a model that drew
a lot of traffic to dispensaries and you
know I'm gonna take a wild guess and say
there about a twenty five million dollar
company so in any multi billion-dollar
industry if the biggest company in the
space is twenty five million dollars in
revenue
it shows how how fractionated it it's
just use a cannabis term we it's so
segmented so small so nobody is
is a bent there's no you know Kleenex or
band-aid in in cannabis as yet as much
as brands like bang or Dixie would like
to think you know Oh everybody knows
knows us well you know we're in the
industry so people in the industry you
go to somebody in the general public and
say you know what's Dixie or what's bang
and they're like I have no frickin idea
so we're seeing this with media there's
a lot of media ideas we saw a new media
venture that Snoop Dogg was launching
this week and so where is that target
what are people going after what they're
going after is the Millennials that's
you know the biggest spender and the
biggest growth area in cannabis and
we've all been fighting over this this
core group of stoners the the ones that
love it and we got in the arms race of
the higher and higher dosages because
you know it was like an arms race if you
sold you know our bar we went for the
chocolate we went from you know 60 to
120 to 180 in the milligram strength and
every time we did that the sales doubled
of the higher milligram so you know like
how high was up when we started seeing
things in the thousand milligrams now
regulations are coming in with those
specific type situations and I believe
personally that that's where the growth
is and the so-called low dose 5 10 15
milligram products and that's going to
appeal because we've all heard the
horror stories of IOD Don edibles and
I've od'd on edibles so I I have
personal experience there and then a lot
of times people once they OD and it
almost like fuck that I'm never gonna
eat that it yeah I'm not I'm that don't
give me that cookie like forget it
because you know if you had a bad
experience then you're kind of out of
the market so you know the education
side the low dosing side that's gonna
bring in about another core group of
about 30 million so we estimate that the
the hardcore stoner market is about 10
million people and that the Millennials
that know cannabis maybe tried it
really know where to go where to get the
information we think that is about 30
million so it's three times bigger so
you got like 25 companies all fighting
over that hardcore $10,000,000 stoner
market
I'd much rather target that 30 million
market that likes it thinks that it
could be cool but don't know where to go
what to get what's the cool thing and
that's that's the next frontier I feel
in the economic growth of cannabis so
that's my five minutes thanks James all
right well I'm a I'm a numbers guy I've
never actually touched the plant well
that's not actually true but I have
never worked touching the plant I should
say that and I'm a numbers guy I worked
I started my career as an auditor with
Price Waterhouse and I then went to Wall
Street and so to me I really find this
industry of great intrigue from a
numbers perspective because you know we
all know that this is an industry that's
really thriving and is going to continue
to do so but I really felt it was
necessary to get an understanding of you
know the industry dynamics what is
unfolding to help investors understand
the different dynamics that we're seeing
in each state so what I've done the last
year I started Green Wave advisors and
I'm leveraging my prior work experience
to really get an understanding of what's
going on state by state I've gone
through the arduous tasks
single-handedly of going to each state
compiling data and analyzing that data
and trying to make sense of the industry
so that investors are better informed so
when the day comes they'll they'll have
something for them to you know really
give a better understanding of what's
going on the industry and so what we've
done is we've went state-by-state we've
defined like what the addressable market
is on the medical marijuana side
determining how many people have cancer
how many people have glaucoma etc etc
and then we determine what the potential
market sizes so and these are all
broad-based assumptions
you know in certain categories and then
we looked at Colorado we looked at the
penetration rates and we apply this
exercise state-by-state and you know we
drilled out and we of course focused in
also on California and as we did that we
then also determine what the
recreational market would look like now
that's a little bit more difficult to
assess because we don't have the data in
every state either the data is provided
by the state or if you're proactive you
could approach the state in in most
cases under the Freedom of Information
Act and get the information that you
need and so we compiled all this data
and now you know May it's the medical
mark it's a lot easier to assess because
then you could kind of determine what
average revenues are per patient and so
forth and we're developing all these
metrics the recreational side was still
continuing to evaluate so we sized the
market and we put our estimates you know
in a model and we have full transparency
as to how we get to our our numbers and
we estimate by 2020 under the normal
trajectory of when we think states are
going to legalize we expect a market of
about 22 billion and if you if you then
say okay in that first year remaining
states are legalized we easily get to 35
billion but then we kind of Auto report
last year we did what we expected that
when that the the medical market would
be disrupted by the recreational market
in Colorado it's the first state where
we have both a medical and a
recreational market that's commercially
available and so we're seeing will
continue to see a decline in
fundamentals and we expect that same
trend to happen in other states that
implement a recreational program where
there's a medical program so if you're
going to open a business in a medical
facility of a dispensary just be
cognizant and be mindful and and hope
that there would be state protections
that would enable you to have first dibs
on a recreational license like they did
in Colorado and they think they're doing
that in some other states as well so
then what we looked at from that we
really also have an industry thesis and
what we think is going to happen
is that the way the markets are right
now the the medical and the recreational
market will combine into one
substantially larger market and then the
medical market will recalibrate and that
will be defined they'll be more precise
dosage and so forth and Big Pharma will
probably come in and it will be
regulated by the FDA and really what
underscores that when I flew out here
yesterday it was a flight from hell I
miss my first flight and the silver
lining was that I was in a mil seat and
I was next to a physician and a
pharmaceutical rep and I was like wow
this is gonna be a really good
conversation this isn't gonna be a
horrible flight but I'm gonna get a lot
of good information and and the doctor
really kind of underscored what we
believe is that the Met community the
met the medical marijuana market is only
as good as the doctors are willing to
recommend the product and it's right now
the patients are having to push the
product rather than the doctor I'm sorry
pull the prior to rather than the
doctors push the product to their
patients and the the doctor the
physician from Michigan said basically
you know we have a lot of concerns about
you know prescribing marijuana because
we don't know what's gonna happen we
don't know if then you know we tell one
guy that it's good and then he brings
five other people and they don't really
need it and so forth so there's a lot of
concern so then when I was talking to
the pharmaceutical rep and she said you
know some of my colleagues are really
concerned about the pharmaceutical
market that they're gonna lose their
jobs in a few years because marijuana is
gonna replace a lot of these
pharmaceuticals so I said well what what
do you sell what drug you sell she said
I sell for fertility drugs
I said well you don't have to worry
about your drug because as far as I know
there's no cannabinoid that is going to
address that right now you never know
and so what we're really striving to do
is to continue to evaluate all the
information that's coming out of these
states and it's like really
Lucy and Ethel and the Chocolate Factory
and there's there's just more and more
information coming out and what we are
really focused in on is to collect this
data and really analyze it and make
sense of it so when the time comes you
know you'll all be better informed
and I on a personal note my mother I
mean a lot of this is really driven for
in memory of my mother she had Crohn's
disease and she was miserable and there
was nothing that was working and she got
sicker and sicker and sicker and she
just got more and more bitter among
about the medical profession finally we
got something for her up in Vermont that
you know alleviated a lot of the pain
well guess what then about I know six
months later she got diagnosed with lung
cancer and she went to chemotherapy so
it was early stage she had surgery and
you know it was four years and we just
watched her kind of you know we knew
that time is gonna come but during that
time we go the doctor you think any of
them said hey once try some marijuana
because every time they offered her
something for nausea it was making her
more sick so I wanted to do the my
brother's a lawyer he's like no no no my
sister likes to bake I'm like I live in
Manhattan I could get marijuana quicker
than I can get a pizza delivered so
there was really nothing we could do and
then to add salt to injury for months
before she passed checked kidney stones
so if nothing else I needed the
marijuana so anyway that's my story
so my name is Aaron justice as Aaron
said I am the president of buds and
roses here in Los Angeles I also serve
on the board of directors for the
National cannabis Industry Association
with Aaron as our director I am on the
steering committee of glocca the Greater
Los Angeles collective Alliance where
our president is sitting right there
Yami bolaños say hi and glocca has been
trying to regulate cannabis dispensaries
in Los Angeles for almost 10 years
Yami's been at the forefront of that and
and I serve on other various committees
the patient provider network for
Americans for safe access do work with
American Herbal Products Association and
so on so for those of you who don't know
Los Angeles is by far the largest
cannabis marketplace city in the country
we currently have maybe 12 to 1800
dispensaries in the city of La the the
the big thing is that all of those
dispensaries are basically illegal about
100 of us have limited immunity from
prosecution where one of those
dispensaries and I pulled some numbers
from the office of Finance and last year
there was 100 million reported in sales
in the city of LA this is with all
illegal dispensaries as I said besides
some that have limited immunity and that
seems like a high number it's higher
than some states but the truth is I
believe it is grossly under reported
almost 1,000 dispensaries reported to
the office of Finance and paid taxes but
if you do the math that's only 100,000
per dispensary which is not the average
it's much less than the average some
people looked into this some tax
authorities and found that a the
minority of these dispensaries paid the
majority of taxes and that makes perfect
sense
Los Angeles is similar to Washington DC
if you know they always scream about
taxation with
about representation and that's kind of
the thing in Los Angeles so we pay a 6%
gross sales tax but we're illegal and so
what I think is that the only way to
really get this under control is to
regulate it to a certain amount of
dispensaries we've been trying to do
that for years and to really audit these
dispensaries and to license them so that
we can build a real system here that
brings in instead of five million
dollars for the city which is nothing in
Los Angeles absolutely nothing that it
brings in forty to sixty million dollars
in taxes and that's you know a number
that our officials will listen to beyond
that there is the sales tax I believe
that if we were doing those numbers a
billion dollars a years what I believe
the Los Angeles marketplace is today if
we were doing those kind of numbers we
would bring in 100 million dollars in
sales tax for the BOE
our Board of Equalization last I talked
to the BOE they were expecting to bring
in 100 million in the entire state I
believe that they have grossly
underestimated that and so what we're
doing is what we've always been trying
to do we just passed state well the
governor is almost signed state state
legislation here and what we are trying
to do is make the dispensaries in LA
that are under limited immunity we're
not authorized to operate which means
that this whole marketplace could
disappear or be completely black market
if the city doesn't act to regulate it
so again we are back in the trenches
glocca with asa most likely the union we
are trying to figure out for the city
how to make a path to state licensure
and and and bring in the revenues that
the city should bring in and the state
should bring in and and basically
finally have a regulated system so what
we have now in the largest city the
largest retail market for cannabis in
the country is a really poor regulatory
system and hopefully our
vermin will act to reconcile this
because the excuse was always we have to
wait for the state let the state figure
out and then we'll go from there
so hopefully we can turn this into a
real marketplace that's regulated thank
you everyone and good afternoon my name
is John Katya and I am the director of
industry analytics with new frontier I
should preface this by saying I'm
sitting in for Giada Dakar sera new
frontier CEO who unfortunately got
detained in Washington and so even
though I'm nowhere near as attractive I
will try and present our points here as
well as she did as well she would have
so for those of you who don't know us
new frontiers a big data company focused
exclusively in the cannabis industry we
founded the company because we realized
that there was a dearth of good
intelligence about what's happening in
the industry how it was growing how it
was evolving and what market forces were
shrimping it's evolution so we brought
together a team of market strategists
economists strata statisticians
technologists and industry analysts and
have done nothing but pour through data
from every state that has an active
market for the past year to really get
our hands into richer insight into some
of the factors that are shaping this
markets growth in evolution so to try
and help contextualize just some of the
things that we have found in our
research I'm gonna speak about five
different markets and just pick a point
about each market that I think is
illustrative of some of the issues that
are shaping this industry and I think
that we should consider as we look
forward to the markets growth so
starting first with a national market we
have spent a lot of time trying to get
our hands around how big this national
market is and as everyone here has
mentioned already this data is very very
difficult to come by but we have a team
of econometricians who applied a
patented very very sophisticated model
to all of the data that we have and we
project that this year the US market
will be slightly over five billion
dollars and that will grow to over seven
and a half seventeen and a half billion
dollars by 2020 one of the things that
were particularly focused on in the
national market as we have this
discussion about the US market overall
is what's going to happen in 2016 so we
have a major election going to happen in
2016 with three actually four candidates
representing states that will have
initiatives on the ballot John Kasich
from Ohio bush and Rubio from Florida
and Bernie Sanders from Vermont this is
gonna make the discussion about
marijuana more prominent and prevalent
in a way that we haven't had in a
generation and I can assure you by the
time you get to 2016 the idea of
marijuana legalization - effects on
society marijuana is the effect of the
Prohibition regime is going to be part
of the public discourse in a way that we
have not seen yet and one of the
potentially interesting things about
that is that I think that could be
proved to be a catalyst in reshaping the
way we are approaching our federal
policy you may have seen yesterday this
article that came out that the DEA
spending $60 per plant to approve plants
in Oregon and people in are gonna sing
but it's legal why are we spending that
much money to address illegal grows the
national debate that's going to happen
during the presidential election will be
bringing these sorts of points about how
federal policy into lighting away that
it hasn't done before and I think that
could be one of the major catalysts for
change as we look at the years post 2016
and as you heard Tripp has bet MPPs
as he $1,000 that there's going to be a
federal pivot in 2017 some say 2019 but
it is coming and and that's going to
help really transform this industry
a second market Ohio and political
circles does a statement that says as
goes Ohio so goes the nation well as you
may know Ohio has a ballot initiative on
the books for this November
somewhat controversial quite
controversial for some in that one of
the stipulations in it is that it limits
the number of licenses to ten producers
however despite the controversy
surrounding the the way they have
drafted the ballot initiative and we
think it has a very good likelihood of
passing there's a couple of things about
Ohio that make it unique it's going to
be the first state that has legalized
medical and recreational marijuana
simultaneously now we forecast that by
2020 the Ohio market is going to be
generating 1.8 billion dollars in sales
that's slightly lower than responsible
house projection of 2.2 billion but
either way that's some very very serious
money and I think one of the outcomes of
Ohio is that we expect to see other
states that have a similar marijuana use
profile as Ohio to adopt similar
approaches to legalization so here we're
looking at states like Kentucky like
Tennessee and the two Carolinas where
they don't have medical marijuana or if
they do it as a th a low THC high CBD
only program they're much more likely to
adopt the type of regime where it was a
group of investors who were designing a
ballot initiative that works to their
advantage rather than the more
egalitarian models that we have seen in
the marijuana programs adopted to date
third California the powerhouse stage I
think is an beautifully said la is the
biggest market and country in California
is far and away the biggest state in the
country by our modeling we estimate the
California's market this year alone the
medical market alone will generate two
and a half billion dollars in revenue
which is half of the national total and
by 2020 that will have grown to over
five and a half billion
with expected legalization in 2016 and
the market coming online in 2020 now I
know we'll have in 2018 I know we're
gonna be discussing California in a
little more detail here so don't want to
belabor the point but there's one aspect
as I was reading the proposed
legislation that really caught my eye
and that was on the creation of
standards for organic marijuana
certification California's going to be
the first state that's attempted this
and I think it will be a signal because
if the program is effective here other
states are gonna follow suit and as I
was thinking about what models we can
look at as analogies for what might
happen with Agana organic marijuana
standards I looked at American spirit
the tobacco company that's not owned by
r.j. Reynolds that offers natural and
organic cigarettes now the only
cigarette consumption has fallen fairly
dramatically over the past fifteen to
twenty years and that there's a
consistent in fairly strong trend
however American spirit sales have gone
from 260 million in 2009 to over 650
million last year
they're doing very very well then I have
2% of a market and this for a company
which one was founded people thought was
absolutely ridiculous that because who
is going to smoke organic cigarettes
this huge demand for this and I think
it's it's illustrative of the sort of
demand that we might expect to see for
organic cannabis and I think in
California the organic cannabis market
could it could be a small but
potentially very very lucrative segment
of the market forth Oregon organs a
particularly exciting market for a
couple of reasons one right now it's set
the lowest tax rate in the country and
there's a lot of states which are going
to be watching this quite closely our
analysis has shown that marijuana is
very price elastic which means that even
small changes in price will dramatically
reduce demand now it's not that the
demand
goes away it just means that the man
stays in the black market I mean that's
the reality of it legal cannabis is
competing with the black market and so
when states set their taxes very high as
Washington did the ostensibly almost
guaranteeing that consumers who may want
to be active participating in the legal
market are being priced out of it
they're not going to be spending twice
the product what they have been spending
in the black markets by the Mart buy the
product from the legal market and this
is why Oregon's model is so interesting
at 17% it's the lowest tax rate in the
country and both Washington and
California are going to be watching very
closely how the market does from outset
because and we expect that demand is
going to be very very strong we will
start to see states gradually lower
their tax rates because in one of the
paradoxical aspects of this industry the
lower tax rates the more tax rate tax
revenue you will generate because more
consumers will come into your stores to
buy legally as opposed to continuing to
buy from the black market and then v
Washington DC we actually based in DC so
we have a unique view into that market
and Washington is unique in a couple of
respects one it's it's the only
jurisdiction I believe in the world
where marijuana is completely legal for
adults to use and to cultivate but there
is no regulatory model by which you can
buy it and so earlier this year they had
a seed giveaway and apparently was the
largest seed giveaway that has ever been
held in the country and now all of the
product that folks went home and plant
into the basements is actually now
coming into the market when we're seeing
a graph of this product being sold
people are selling it even though
technically it's not legal but that's
unfortunately one of the byproducts of
congressional oversight we're not
allowed legally to set up a regulatory
framework and our council members have
been threatened will with Jane with jail
time if they spend any time even having
meetings discussing the possibility of a
regulatory frame
but Washington is important in another
respect as the nation's capital as a top
domestic tourist destination it's one of
the first places Americans are coming to
to end it's the first time they're in a
legal marijuana environment and you know
I spend a lot of time in the tourist
destinations in Washington and so it's
interesting to hear people sound
completely gobsmacked that marijuana is
legal in the nation's capital Washington
is also the epicenter of public global
public diplomacy we have virtually all
of the country's embassies all of the
international embassies based there a
huge intimate international contingency
based in the city and you have
representatives from other countries who
are saying the United States has pegged
aid money cooperation and the
development of our strategic
partnerships on how strictly we enforce
marijuana prohibition in our country
whereas you u.s. continues to expand
marijuana legalization in fact I
speaking to someone in South America who
is complaining about this quite visibly
I think the fact that Washington is
legal means that it is going to be part
of this conversation that is going to
lead to a broader discussion globally
about marijuana public policy and I
think it's going to help begin this
discussion about whether to dismantle
our Convention on narcotics or whether
to exclude marijuana from that given the
size of the markets that we are seeing
and as Amanda raman had said earlier in
this market when California goes legal
and be fully expect that it will
countries like Mexico and and a lot of
other countries which have long
histories with marijuana but have made
it illegal due to the rules that were
imposed upon them by this narcotics
regime will begin to push back against
that which could catalyze a global
market unlike anything we have seen
before so a pause they're happy to
discuss further thanks John Thanks
I'm told we need to wrap up but I wanna
but before doing that one I compose a
question too to any of you and really
you know as this market has evolved out
of a from first a criminal marketed into
kind of a gray market in this Wild West
that we're still in in California and
have been in in Colorado and other
states so the unregulated markets one
benefit of that is we've created these
quintessential American success stories
in the cannabis industry where you have
world-class business is now operating
that started with a couple pounds of
product and a few thousand dollars and
with the you know the current regime the
current regime now that seems like those
days are over
and sometimes I know a lot of us are
concerned that the opportunities for
small entrepreneurs and mom and pops and
middle-class folks to get involved and
get become successful in this industry
are dwindling and I just want to ask
those who have been around in all of the
around the country what do you think
that there are still opportunities Aaron
well yeah I would say that you know one
thing about Los Angeles and I said there
was limited immunity that was about what
happened was and it will probably never
happen again but in 2007 in activists on
Duncan from Americans for safe access he
floated a resolution and got a city
council member to basically say anyone
who comes forward can be registered with
the city of La and 185 people came
forward and they said okay no more no
more and so I think those days are over
but with the state legislation that was
just or almost signed by the governor
and probably will be this leaves a lot
of opportunity in California still for
smaller players because it is a you have
to get your license locally you have to
convince your locality for it and it's
an it's not like you're just applying at
the state so California when it comes to
wineries when it comes to craft beer you
have a very similar model and we believe
maybe there's 50,000 growers in
California and
I'm also a member of the California
Growers Association hopefully soon to be
a board member and we are pushing to
license tens of thousands of growers in
the state so California is going to keep
that tradition alive opposite of Ohio
that wants to give the license to ten
people I would say coming from Colorado
that I work nationally and I'm in Denver
now anytime I go to the East Coast I get
off the plane and I have to remind
myself I'm not in Kansas anymore I think
the opportunity you know west of the
Mississippi California Oregon Washington
Colorado where we had very entrenched
cannabis cultures that opportunity to
still exist but when you go to the East
Coast and there's only five people in
New York who can get a license yeah I
mean it's over so hold on hold on tight
build what you can build now because
this is one of the last few places where
that mom-and-pop spirit can survive you
know the ancillary entrepreneurship and
finding a good product and a new idea
that will always work but when you talk
about you know micro wineries or micro
breweries those cost millions of dollars
to start I mean you can't start a
microbrew with a six-pack and $1000 so I
mean it's it's it has evolved and it is
kind of unfortunate but that is just
yeah that's the way it's going I know in
Connecticut where I'm from there's more
and more there's added expansion in
other counties there's probably you know
I don't know how many more licenses are
on the table right now
and you know I think the what will
happen to is they'll be looking for
different types of products to stock on
their shelves in these dispensaries so
there's the innovative opportunity that
will transpire in Connecticut further
and you know New York is you know very a
unique animal I think it will its baby
steps right now and eventually the
products will become more widely
available and
more abundant in terms of selection
Thanks well I'm told we are out of time
but the panelists will be around