[Music]
encountered and a lot of handshake
agreements folks that sort of put to put
companies together on the ground level
and sort of trusted each other that they
would do the right thing so we've had a
lot more partnership disputes where
somebody would show up to a dispensary
or a manufacturing plant and literally
the locks are changed and people pretend
not to know each other and so you gave
to these disputes about who owns what
whether its revenue of the company
intellectual property that sort of stuff
so there's that going on at an
increasing rate and then I think another
thing that the industry is starting to
figure out as it comes away from
licensing and a focus on compliance
there they're starting to look at
branding and the importance of branding
really I think in the context of I want
to get investment in my company or I
want to build this and sell it so I have
to have brand recognition and brand
protection and IP protection but there's
not really an understanding or a focus
on the fact that that has to start with
your employees because we've seen cases
where individuals have worked for a
company that company has been building
client base it's been building a product
it's got intellectual property and how
it does things and then we see employees
slipping out under the cover of darkness
and either going to work for a
competitor or setting up their their
business on their own and companies are
sort of left
flat-footed saying what do we do now I'm
not realizing what the landscape is and
again not realizing that there are some
things you can do on the front end to
put yourself in a position where
notwithstanding California's sort of
employee favoring laws you can still get
some some recourse from the courts in
terms of injunctive relief or damages
when employees do that and interact
competing is if you were to sort of give
best practices around the upfront things
one could do to protect yourself legally
from somebody jumping ship with all your
trade secrets your customer rolodex or
know-how
your idea and basically setting up you
know it's almost like you go to China
you set up a factory and then the head
of the factory goes across the street
yeah and creates the exact same product
that's the beauty of doing business in
the United States which for a canvas
company you don't have any choice but to
do all your business here in California
but it really runs the same sort of
themes as we've discussed with the
industry as it relates to discrimination
or harassment prevention and sort of
setting up some things there so that if
there is a dispute as to why somebody's
let go you've got some documentation
around it so if you are trying to
protect your brand trying to protect
your trade secrets and your intellectual
property do those same things on the
front end identify what you treat as
trade secrets identify what you think is
intellectual property put agreements
between yourself and the employees that
say look you're going to work here
you're gainfully employed we want you
here but if you leave you can't take all
these things with you so that there's no
expectation that these are sort of out
and open to the public and beyond sort
of setting some of those parameters with
employees with written policies or
agreements treating that intellectual
property like it is intellectual
property so if it's client or customer
data or formulas or products put them
under lock and key treat them like the
the kernels
spices mix and coca-cola max exactly put
it under lock and key and let people
know that that's something that you hold
as intellectual property that you feel
is special to the company it shouldn't
be used outside of the company beyond
the employee theft which really relates
to having agreements and understandings
with him with the employee about what's
protected and what's not and treating
those things as protected I would say
that this business needs to get away
from the handshake agreements as between
partners and business owners it's it's
not that costly it's not that
complicated to get businesses into the
correct form have operating agreements
have partnership agreements or joint
venture agreement so that it lays out
who's a party - what who has equity who
owns what and so that that's something
that every one of these businesses
should have quite frankly for getting a
license that stuff should formalize in
that process
you mentioned operating agreements some
of the concrete blocking and tackling
steps one can do around that topic of
protecting your business when people
leave or when their disputes yeah so
when you're thinking about your partners
and the people that have an equity stake
in the business you want to have written
agreements in place that outline sort of
what that our rights are in that context
probably the biggest one to talk about
is non-competes
in California typically speaking you
can't prevent someone from leaving you
or leaving your company and competing
against you it's a restraint on trade
and California doesn't like it if
somebody has a ownership in the business
I won't go too deep into it a material
ownership in the business and there's
some sort of an event where they are
liquidated they sell that to back to you
or you all sell to a third party because
they have that ownership there's an
exception to the non-compete law so
those sort of non-compete should exist
in those sort of agreements moving away
from sort of the partners and more
talking about the employees I would on
the front end when you're giving
somebody all those those forms that we
were talking about the application maybe
an offer letter with some of the terms
and conditions of their employment the
state-mandated notices copy of your
handbook with an acknowledgement
well there's in the handbook or not
there's there should be some sort of
standalone document that says maybe it's
in the offer letter or somewhere in that
process a documentation that this is
what our intellectual property procedure
is this is what we consider in the our
trade secrets and you can't go outside
of this company with them if you work on
a formula for an extraction method and
we come up with something amazing you
don't take that invention with you down
the road those are the big goes on the
front end and then on the back end just
be smart about it if you do see that
there's an issue you find out that
someone has done something unsavory
we'll call it act quickly jump out do a
cease and desist letter engage counsel
if you need to and if there's are
appropriate avenue to do it
file for a temporary restraining order
and tighten to stop from using your good
traits
[Music]