I mentioned to you we have a few friends
out here from Denmark couple friends
down from Canada more and more it seems
the world is recognizing thankfully the
California really is the epicenter of
many respects at least with respect to
the craft as well as a culture and I
definitely would say the genetics how do
you see that playing out as far as as
far as tourism as far as people come in
here and this essentially being you know
the holy land for lack of a better term
when it comes to industry there's
cannabis oh man I think it has an
unbelievable potential because
California is already clocking over a
billion interest money so it's already a
global tourist destination and all over
California it's not just one spot San
Francisco as an ungodly amount of people
that want to come and see the beauty of
San Francisco the culture of San
Francisco you have people that are going
to Southern California to do the
Hollywood experience and that that is
unbelievably populated with people from
every part of the earth coming into it
so you have these global attractions you
get into Napa area the wine County same
thing global attraction up where I'm
from Humboldt County
redwoods global attraction and then all
sudden you put cannabis in there and it
doesn't mean that the people all have to
come here to get high it just means that
they get a window into a world that they
heard about but never could see and it
starts to allow people to tourists to be
able to come to regions where you had
people living and like where we are
noble these that specifically some of
the most beautiful region in the world
I tell people being from the Bay Area
the most beautiful part of California
near Point is north of San Francisco yes
all the way up to Crescent I'm almost
stunning and what you find is you find
all these individuals that form this
really interesting relationship with the
property so that was highlighted all the
all the grows that were contaminated you
know facilities but in every in every
population you're gonna have outliers
that are that are dirty the majority of
people with really pretty good land
stewards and built a really nice
relationship with the land they lived on
and in the region
and and what that does it allows people
to come up and and see what's it like to
live in the country where you have an
industry that was hidden that can now be
seen and what are the people like and
because cannabis people are eclectic and
interesting generator it allows the
tourists to really have a different type
of connection with the people and the
people for the first time have to be
open about what they do and they know
that they need to be open so they can
get their products out in the world and
they're also no longer afraid to get
arrested so they can actually laugh and
feel good about what they've done with
the public because really the opposite
of a lot of the corporate because the
whole thing with cannabis was that you
are basically an independent producer
that could function in all aspects on
your own with very little oversight very
little accountability to others and as
long as you made enough money you had
time so you live this unbelievable life
that only the mega-wealthy really live
because they don't have no one else has
time and so if all the cultivators had
time which gave them time to develop
personalities and neglected hobbies and
things and it makes it interesting
because it's like going to a circus and
there's so many little facets that are
unique to me that's the growing
community where everybody is really a
unique character in a play they didn't
have to homogenize because they didn't
have to fit in and when the tourists
meet the people they really enjoy the
company so I watch it I go when farmers
meet customers it is a really real solid
cool thing very true and then you'll
have all these facilities that people
get to check out product assortment so
we'll be there people will be able to
come in and experience cannabis and in
in bath bombs so you you take your wife
and go hike in and she's like I'd love
to take a can of his bath bomb you know
so she feels wonderful she goes wow
that's that's that's how I consume
cannabis through the skin your
grandmother uses it on her feet your
your your brother only likes to take a
candy
you're smoking flour you're able to use
cannabis in all these ways that are
readily available accessible tourists
enroll oh the world want to experience
it and if you make it Pleasant and you
give them all the different choices and
you allow them to make the choices then
they get to experience cannabis and some
of the most beautiful regions in the
world and it allows them to be able to
relax and and what I see with most
literacies that they're they're
overworked in their technical stuff you
mean like most people are doing data
entry tech very computer driven work and
they they they're they're frozen in a
thing and you get them out in the
country and you get them into cannabis
growing regions and you got yourself an
incredible experience different than
wine because wine even though the
facilities a gorgeous and wine is an
incredible substance you have a
different impact from wine in terms of
it's a depressant it is natural it's
drug as a drug and so I mean I don't
knock the wine or the industry never
mind that the grapes do to the to the
soil but that's a whole other chemicals
can be used but yep ultimately the grape
industry does some unbelievable work on
visual beauty experiment and satisfying
the individuals experience visiting that
place and that's really where we model
cannabis and in a sense is that we
realize that people want good escapism
and cannabis provides it and it doesn't
have to be necessarily in a psychoactive
way and the people that that produced it
provide escapism to them because they're
very unique individuals it would be like
going back into Appalachia and talking
to the moonshine runners and saying hey
let me hop in your car and go drift
around because we know moonshine turned
into NASCAR oh yeah hundred percent so
but I think this you're right it is I
think of some of the growers I'm a huge
fan of you guys but even the family over
hidden prairie Oreo or whatever I mean
there's to your point everyone is so
unique it is eclectic you've done some
world travels you can attest just like
I've been Australia I've been to South
America I've been across Europe the
culture it's uniform it's so interesting
because the the religious beliefs might
shift or the language might shift or
certain elements of the ideology but
overall it's it is good vibes it's crazy
because that's kind of like it almost an
unofficial mantra of our industry right
is as long as it's good vibes but
speaking specifically about use I don't
know if people
I mean you really remind me Kevin and
this is going back to being a California
guy almost like the Huell Howser of this
industry and this guy cool house
originally from Tennessee he'd come out
into a series called California Gold
nobody embraced I mean this guy really
he doe California better than most
native Californians that's what I love
about you again coming from the East
Coast come an interesting story that's a
whole other whole other show but your
background coming here
you have so embraced not just California
not just this industry but the whole
aspect some of the things you're doing
with Humboldt specifically on cheer
point the Chamber of Commerce and and
the stuff to get the tourism and breeze
some much-needed life into that into
that area right you tie it all together
because we feel private prior cannabis
stigmatized a lot of illegitimate
industries even though they've benefited
from it but publicly it causing problems
and now with that stigma removed you're
able to really start to be honest with
you each other as business owners and
you can all start to figure out how do
you benefit each other in a way that
benefits the region so that you have a
longevity because we all live there so
it's not it's not colonialism it's not
extraction it's not resources leave
money leaves it's hopefully resources of
rebuilt improved and capital remains so
that you end up having better better
quality community and I'm just dumb
about it man the new billboards that are
going up the Laura from the southern
Humble Visitors Bureau they put together
this incredible campaign with some of
the other business owners elevate the
magic and they have some phenomenal
billboards that are going up that are
that are going to talk about America's
cannabis heartlands and you had you have
publications like the North Coast
Journal that putting out the dispensary
guides and they're there helping with
the the picture of the visual that
helping shape the tone but in a way that
really reflects the region not because
they're trying to be your distributor
they're trying to highlight it so it's
this beautiful internal development
versus an external force to drive a
result it's about really getting the
people to be able to see what's to
happen in and
and help them with the things they need
which are things that the opposite of
what they've done
everybody's really good at hiding oh
yeah it's sort of shadows that's easy
but it's hard just like it's hard to be
well-known and to have the community say
okay we'll all agree that we don't need
to be shamed we can advertise it we can
have quality advertising and then we can
have cannabis people that are coming to
see cannabis how do we steer them into
the hotels how do we scare them into
vacation packages that are gonna be fun
for them that are going to reflect
Humboldt County's lifestyle which is
unbelievably diverse from heavy Coast
pounding surf beautiful rivers stunning
planes gorgeous mountains it's
everything you want is there everything
is so nobody on the beach
many people petrolia no people yeah and
so it's a privilege to walk on the beach
with nobody on the damn Beach except you
and your friends you like what is unreal
well ñ even when you guys do a partying
and again this is in your backyard but
but talking about northern nights or
reggae on the river right you're tapping
into the Gen Y there's that generation
but I love how even when they come up
you guys like hey we're on the river no
class we're all about eco we have the
water station it's like everything that
goes on in Humboldt is still respecting
what Humboldt was always about all the
way back to which we've discussed before
it was it wasn't the hippie movement as
much as it was the forestry right I mean
you've talked about that yes I mean I
love the history lesson that you give
when people come up there and say you
guys got it all wrong like this is what
really happened this was the evolution
of of how cannabis came to be in this
this area of the country and people are
passionate about it and I think the kids
are today are too though like the
problem is that you know what happens is
you get educated how to behave by the
world around you correct and when it's
in a disposable world and very transient
fast-paced no need to make connections
that's what you learn but when you come
up to a smaller town you go out on the
coast you go into the into a smaller
neighborhood all of a sudden people are
more watchful of each other because you
learn to rely on each other and it
starts to humanize people and that's why
you know small-town Americana is in your
small town anywhere in the world
is always so rich because you get to see
people at their at their finest because
their desire to be good as that it's her
desire to be good there's no ulterior
motive they want to be able to do that
and so when you can get people into the
country and you can you can let them
enjoy being in a clean environment and
they realize that that that's part of it
that we don't throw trash on the ground
they don't know and people start to
really you know slow down and they put
the phone down they might actually talk
to you in person instead of text you
while they're standing next to you and
that's important because it starts to
get you back on a more grounded level so
that you can then return to your busy
hectic life living in the city that
looks like someone's dumped the trash
can over the top of the fire hydrant
yeah and and you deal with it and then
you know you can go to the country go to
the ocean and and find some kind of
balance but when you go there you don't
bring the bad habits of the city bring
the good habits which is understanding
that things move but also understanding
that you don't have to move in tune with
it the same way yeah we talked about
just now touched on but maybe getting a
little bit more into one log I mean this
is something where people that aren't
from California aren't familiar or those
that haven't been here for decades it's
kind of special when you come up 101 a
lot of people don't notice you ask
someone that's from San Diego LA San
Francisco Sacramento if you ever knew
there to be a stop sign or a single lane
on 101 and they go what are you crazy
this this is the biggest freeway it runs
through our state this can't you go to a
little town called Garberville and you
will find that stop sign you will find
that cross walk across 101 and that's
what amazed me again growing up in Marin
County being a kid from the bay that
people don't know just how sacred and
special it is when you're coming up into
the proper triangle and you guys are
right there you've got one log I mean
that that's the first thing I see when I
come into town never mind the huge tree
that it was named after right so tell me
a little bit about what you guys are
doing there if what you have in the
works I know you have some plans as far
as expanding on the space you have in
2019 as well you know that we're really
fortunate though the
one log site right on the 101 is
historic tourist destination with coffee
shop tourist things
what redwood carvings a lot of cool
old-school big redwood carvings and it
used to have a lot of salmon that was
sold out of there back in the day when
the salmon was really hot and in the
river before we had the droughts and
some of the offshore issues so the
salmon business was hot at the spot and
people from all over it would be driving
down one on one they'd pull in there's a
beautiful Grove stunning redwoods and
the one log itself was is a giant one
log redwood tree that they used to drive
around the country on the back of a
truck in the 50s and it took six months
to carve out with chisels and they built
a house inside it and you can actually
walk around inside the log like it's a
house that's a crazy story you know my
partners grab this facility and we put a
dispensary in it the nursery there's a
new extraction of a giant extraction
facility but that all these things are
tucked away you can't see them so you
can see the store when you roll up
because of the signage but everything
else is completely woven into this these
groves so that it you never really think
you're in an industrial area at all
no you walk in I walked in and I was
like well you have no idea yeah the
whole building is a nursery the holes
the whole basement is a nursery all
blown out yeah then you're on five acres
creates a mile of riverfront and you got
the Northern Lights is my partner's so
they're then the northern Knights crew
two great guys and then High Times is
next door which is the old reggae site
yep so we catch some of that stuff and
what we're doing right now is we're
putting in the development of some form
of visitor center so that what we have
an ability to do is start to really get
the tourists to come into the facility
and then help them understand where to
go because you need what do you do when
you're out in the middle of nowhere
there's no directories and there's
pamphlets and stuff but what you need is
more comprehensive and Heritage's and
and River guides and hikes
and the eco-tourism component of
humboldt just has to be really
highlighted because it's kind of hard to
know what to do without having some form
of help yeah and then we will be able to
put in all the farmers gear so we'll be
able to sell farmers clothes and all
their branding labels and let the flip
the people come in and pick this stuff
up and we can have music events in the
back we can have farmer events I'll be
able to put the golden tarp event back
out on it which is that Cup and I didn't
do it this year because we didn't have
an ability legally to do it without it
being in a State Fairgrounds the gut and
we'll do it again in the back of the
facility next year so we have this
ability to hold all these really killer
events and it allows people to come off
the highway and pull in the parking lot
then we have 88 bathrooms which is
crucial because it allows you to catch a
population of everybody yes and there's
a food there's a small restaurant
there's a really a gift shop and that's
all Humboldt County centric so unless
people come in and feel like they're in
Humboldt and then when we built the
dispensary or the partners Jonah was a
master bricklayer glued like 14,000
glutton shot 14,000 hand-cut redwood
blocks to the wall to make it look like
you're inside all we'll have to hope
it's visually the guys can dub in I'm
coming up on Monday I'll send him a
picture but that you you can't
understand this until you actually go
there so you know you're in the redwoods
but it has modern amenities so what it
does is it lets people that want to
escape their digital life and be green
could be green but they can still use
the phone and they can still have normal
things that they need to function in the
way they've built their worlds but they
can get out of that world and go enjoy
the river and enjoy the the grandfather
tree next door to us is me max is
nominal we're Richardson grow of which
is you know some of them some of the
most central region in the area and it's
it's just it's really nice to be able to
be so
yeah you know I mean I didn't mind being
private I'll be honest well yeah on the
hill you've been prime for a while but I
love the new rena side call it a
renaissance all the time because it's an
it's an awakening which is what a
renaissance sure for sure and for the
first time you know the mainstream can
touch cultivators businesses can benefit
from the the new tourists that'll come
in and they will it so there's a
transition how much going through some
are times yeah
but the the fact that you were able to
start having a California that's that's
so big that there's not that many places
left that aren't that crowded and
homeless one of them and it's just a
trip up the 101 Greg foster did an
incredible job bringing in airline so we
have direct flights to LA direct flights
to Denver yeah and they have one in San
Francisco you have the Frisco one
everyday but now there's a Frisco LA in
Denver everyday so you can go from
Humboldt so the two Colorado the East
Coast in a single hop you don't got to
go to another hub airport and jump out
you can go to LA and so it's
hour-and-a-half to LA 3540 minutes of
Frisco and all of a sudden man people
are coming in to visit or hangout and I
just I hope I live long enough to be
able to see where how this will change
because it'll be like Napa and the wine
region where at one time it was like
this and then it became oh yeah so
develop Napa was I got my mom moved up
there you know parents divorce I was
young or long story short my mom moved
up there off Silverado try remember when
Napa wasn't cool
you're one same thing people don't know
downtown Napa was it was pretty ratchet
as the kids saying yes it was kind of
tired then all of a sudden to your point
Napa it's about bill and I mean there's
that Sonoma County to him but it's come
a long way and I agree I'd love to see
that in Humboldt
I love to see it in Garber build up I
mean all the way up the corridor do you
recall all the way yeah and the bottom
line is you have these beautiful
northern regions
underpopulated and they'll never be
overpopulated because they're not built
for the flat ground sprawl for the big
city but they're definitely designed for
people to escape the sprawl and to go
enjoy themselves and meet nice people
smoke some really good grass and see
some visual beauty that's just you know
you can't just can't film it I know no I
can't wait to come back well I stopped
by supposed to be a half an hour we
ended up together I want to say it was
about four hours yeah you know it's
really like there's better signal and
reception up there than there is here
and it's the one place where I really
didn't need it I was like dude this is
I've been wanted you know me like I
travel at this my 28th show this year to
met between domestic international and I
mean like that's a weird thing dude like
hanging out talking to you and just
humbled feels like home like it's just
this is a place I'd love to come home to
kind of to Matt's way and here's why I
work so hard he's part gun i lucky that
i was so fortunate to move there in the
early 90s and I just never want to leave
so you know you work really hard to
force
whatever you possibly can positive
forward so that you're able to enjoy
that that's a gift man what's up boys
all right
[Music]