[Music]
my name is Maureen Smith in Boston
Massachusetts and embarked on a travel
nursing career in 2018 I decided that I
was going to change my life and I became
a cannabis nurse educator I don't have
one-on-one consults with patients I
advocate for the plant I advocate for
cannabis education and I advocate for
people to understand that cannabis
medicine is a viable alternative to
Western medical pharmaceuticals for
chronic and lifestyle disease management
my name is Judy Tillman and I'm a
medicinal cannabis educator based on a
graduate degree in public in education
but more based on my activism in support
of health care as a right and in
understanding traditional medicine I
don't think that cannabis as an herb and
as an herbal remedy is an alternative
the pharmaceutical industry's the
alternative and we need to be fighting
for the traditional return to
traditional medicine which worked for
various various diseases and conditions
for 5000 years but we didn't understand
the reason why it worked until the
latter part of the 20th century I'm very
happy to work with healthcare providers
in the allopathic tradition as well as
patients public and the industry itself
my background is international
solidarity movements piece of social
justice working in South Africa and
Nicaragua and the old Soviet Union to
bring human rights and health care
rights to people around the world so
this is my passion and we have a
dispensary a holistic wellness center
that's been alive for eight years now
and before that for nine years I was a
cultivator and that's me so you want to
know what's the biggest thing on our
minds today with and you said with
medical cannabis well person
my biggest concern is that people don't
understand that all cannabis is medical
I don't think that when people go home
at the end of a stressful day and have a
martini or two they're doing anything
beyond self-medicating for stress and
it's the same with what's called
recreational because the history of
cannabis in Western culture particularly
but Eastern culture as well has been one
that was us care using cannabis as a
source of inspiration for jazz music and
art and all of that we've associated it
so much with the pleasures of the
creativity that you get from getting
high that we forgot that there's a
medical motivation in the plant behind
that so my but being more direct about
your question about what's on my mind is
begin to continue to fill the gap of
knowledge both within our farmers who
are growing the medicine our medicine
makers who are trying to craft these
great medicines out of them those
medicines try to begin to bridge the gap
between them and the researchers such as
the you know cannabis clinicians and
many many researchers around the world
who are figuring out how cannabis heals
and treats certain conditions so there's
a big gap between those two the
knowledge gap continues throughout the
entire Western medical healthcare system
I had been speaking to you that there
about sixty percent of American adults
live with a chronic medical condition
and that forty-two percent of those
sixty percent have something that we
rn's called multiple comorbidities
multiple comorbidities there are 30 of
them associated with poor dietary
choices especially when coupled with
weight gain and sedentary lifestyle this
includes insulin resistance type-2
diabetes high blood pressure high
cholesterol heart disease stroke sleep
apnea gallbladder disease GERD pain and
some cancers and insomnia these chronic
health problems have a negative impact
on quality of life and they lead to
depression and social stigma and
discrimination it is a result of toxic
and work-life stress
as many to use excess food and alcohol
as a coping mechanism
these poor choices are made under duress
because quick energy is needed to fuel
these hectic lifestyles
none of these are hypothetical scenarios
I have taken care of people from all
walks of life in every condition known
to man
every three nights for 12 hours a night
for 14 years and I know they are on
several different classes of
pharmaceuticals and that each particular
drug has the potential to cause another
disease state this is a national
healthcare crisis that we can actually
fix let's see what cannabis has to do
with us this is great this is the
tremendous opportunity and this is
probably the first interview that I've
done in in joint work with another
cannabis educator medical practitioner
like Maureen this is the perfect
marriage of two different knowledge
bases and we're both on the same page
about the value of cannabis and the
terror I'll use the word terror of
pharmaceuticals so everything that I
agree a thousand percent with everything
Maureen just said first this time um I'm
I hate to be a pessimist but I've done
presentations to doctors and nurses all
over the place I was at st. Jude's
Hospital down near San Clemente I was
presenting to a group of doctors and
nurses and there are about 25 doctors
and nurses in the room and about 3/4
through my presentation about the
wonders and the science and the richness
of what we understand about how cannabis
works a nurse raised her hand and she
says this is such good information we
were never taught this in nursing school
she says when do you think we'll be able
to integrate this into our clinical
practice as Western practitioners and
she was like really earnest about it I
took a really deep breath trying to
figure out how to answer her question
and a gentleman in the back of the room
an MD raised his hand and said we'll
never be able to do it and I'm like whoa
I wasn't gonna be that pass
why do you say that and he says because
the insurance industry will not allow us
to spend more than 15 minutes with each
patient and write a prescription that's
what we're supposed to do that's the way
the system is structured I as a patient
counselor when I sit down with a new
patient at DraganFlyer anywhere in
California or on the phone from
Australia to a group of artistic
children in on the East Coast
whenever I spend time with new patients
it's a minimum of 45 minutes and you can
see his point then I'm like wow how is
the system going to allow this change to
take place you answer the question Maury
please
I was thinking very similarly when I
woke up this morning that when you go to
a doctor Oh
traditional conventional doctor with a
serious problem on serious concerns and
you're looking for solutions they the
last two visits I've been at for my
personal you know to go to my doctor I
believe that I wasn't hurt at all that I
wasn't even listened to I think they
have in their mind which prescription
they're going to write for you to walk
out the door and I am no longer walking
out the door with a piece of paper the
prescription it's within us and it is
the endocannabinoid system and it is
through natural healing and it is
through time and it is through lifestyle
changes the sparks are being made there
are a lot of people in the medical
community who are catching on it Western
conventional medicine will always be an
option for some they just have to go
that route that's okay we just need to
get the message out to the people who
are willing to change and are who are
willing to nurture this type of medicine
for life to thrive for the community for
the people you know I
couldn't agree more and going back to
what you were saying in your previous
comment about how it also depends on how
you manage stress about nutrition
exercise all of those things when we
started dragonfly in 2011 it was a group
of women there was a Tai Chi instructor
a yoga instructor an herbalist Lib
manual lymphatic drainage instructor
they were like all of us and then
somebody everybody said I want to do my
practices my holistic natural healing
practices but I don't want to run a
dispensary so I got voted in to be the
admin person and which was thanks a lot
but but the point was we could have
carved out a tiny piece of real estate
much cheaper and become a pot shop just
like many dispensaries are in this but
we decided we would have space for a
classroom for yoga classes we would have
a practitioners individual room where
you could have massage or acupuncture we
decided we would go the extra effort to
make sure that cannabis was integrated
into a holistic lifestyle and we're
still struggling we're not there yet
we're still struggling to offer all of
the things that patients need to by way
of information because it doesn't do any
good to come in and just say oh I've got
cancer
give me some cannabis for it know if
there's a million other if you're not
doing all these other things for
yourself and you're living an unhealthy
lifestyle
you can eat all eat or smoke or drink
all the cannabis in the world and it
won't do any good so I'm really an
agreement with the framework that
Maureen is suggesting about holistic
healing veterans are a powerful group
and they are moving this message forward
in a very strong way a lot of them are
healing from cannabis through cannabis
they're healing their PTSD but sorry
they're healing from PTSD through
cannabis and are becoming like you know
very vocal advocates the VA is actually
following suit they are looking for I
forget what they call it but they're
it's um they're looking at different
modalities and they're actually funding
different modalities so I think and
there's lots of veterans bills up in and
wherever bills go up sorry I'm not a
political person in Congress in the
national-level you're right there are
some bills proposed that are very met
with very positive attitudes on both
sides the aisle Republicans and
Democrats yeah and what I'm finding that
in practices that state-by-state the VA
heads of the VA will do kind of a Don't
Ask Don't Tell look the other way with
some of them and then some of them are
absolutely ideologically opposed to
cannabis in any way shape or form so
it's gonna be the VA is a kind of a
little bit like the state's it's gonna
be you know chipping away at it to get
it to open up but Maureen's absolutely
right the V the vets are powerful voice
and and we work with vets as well it's
great well I'm a member of the American
cannabis Nurses Association and we just
had to write an essay for a scholarship
to their first conference in New Orleans
and the nurse there was one for a
student nurse somebody who hadn't become
a practitioner yet and there was one for
an advanced practitioner and the
advanced practitioners essay was just so
heartfelt about the first time that she
had treated a patient with medical
cannabis it was a hospice patient but
that patient found relief and you know
was able to transform you know from
being alive to passing on in a much more
spiritual and comfortable way and this
nurse was moved so much that she decided
to devote her life to this type of
medical sorry I'm losing words but also
in Michigan I know that there's a format
in a long term nursing care facility
where they are allowed to treat with
cannabis I gave a lecture in Ukiah and a
woman came up to me and said that she
was interested
using CBD and somehow she is able to use
CBD with her mother who has dementia and
I have heard from her and her mother is
sleeping through the night and you know
and they're hoping like in six months
time to get her off some of her
antipsychotic meds because she's doing
so well so I think that the answer lies
deep within our cellular matrices that
has a profound ability to use beneficial
molecules without fretting about
political or religious or cultural
ideologies and once people get those
molecules and find the change and start
benefiting from chronic conditions that
they've had their entire life that was
only exacerbated by pharmaceuticals
these people are the people start
advocating so when I tell when I talk to
people I say if you get it if it works
for you if it changes your life in the
most profound way please grab somebody
else's hand and teach them what you know
that is so true it the most inspiration
that we've seen in all the state
legislatures were about up to 31 states
that have now legalized medical cannabis
but the patient's the parents of
children with epilepsy the patients who
come forward and speak those moving
stories just as Maureen is saying but I
would just add one little extra thing
aside from telling everybody you know
your family and friends about how it's
worked for you the orgonite organization
I'm a political activist a political
organizer for 30 years and when we work
with the hospice groups I've presented
to the American the Mendocino cannabis
Nurses Association the the Parkinson's
support groups
the vets groups for 20 we have six six
target populations and they each have
groups that represent and lobby for the
patients so whether it's hospice seniors
anyone over 65 that have particular
needs parents of children with autism
epilepsy athletes use this no pain no
gain either
get out get back in the game kind of
thing and I said that went wrong get rid
of the pain get back in the game that
kind of pets are another big big big and
and then that's I did I get all six
anyway they each have organized
grassroots organizations that are
lobbying on the state level and on the
national level and people need to plug
into those because they it's with unity
that they add heft to their individual
patient voices also on a positive note
in that direction the National Council
for the State Boards of Nursing
regulations did come out with their 2018
guidelines for medical marijuana so key
to those guidelines are that nurses
nurse student nurses and advanced
practice and nurses must learn the
endocannabinoid system cannabis
pharmacology that cannabinoids and the
AMA has not come out with such a
statement the American you know so in
Canada nurses are leading the way and I
think that that's going to be the case
in America too in fact I asked a leading
researcher dr. Ethan Rousseau how are we
going to bring the medical cannabis to
the dispensaries and he said a good
doctor always listens to his nurse in
that moment I decided it was gonna have
to be me the nurses really do lead the
way in elip a fee in Western medicine
they really do and that it's an Ethan's
a great a great advocate as well well
we've been focusing on the medical
because that's what we're about right at
the moment but I have three hats and one
of them has to do with policy and we
were talking about this earlier farmers
are the best farmers and the best
medicine makers of second and third
generation are being suppressed and
stopped by over-regulation and
ridiculous taxes people can't
this very high-quality craft cannabis
flour that we need for good medicine as
we have in the Emerald triangle unlike
anything else in the rest of the world
they can't create it they can't get in
the game and become regulated and legal
because the it's too onerous it's too
difficult it's too much money to get
involved too many taxes too much
infrastructure that's the state or the
counties requiring them to build so on
the cultivation level and then I know of
at least six medicine makers who for the
last eight years I've used their
medicines very effectively with patients
very good high CBD tinctures and SABS
and cancer THC oils they can't produce
their medicines under the current
regulations so we're losing very
important medicine makers for our
patients because of ridiculous
ridiculous regulations now ironically
both on the county level in throughout
the state of California and on the state
level we're starting to see the pendulum
swing back to a little bit more
reasonableness in the regulations
because not because they get it that
they're hurting patients but because
they get it that they're not getting the
tax revenue that they want because so
many people are staying in the
underground market because why should
they get legal and compliant when they
have to deal with all of this nonsense
you know so I think they're finally
beginning to get it and that's what we
have to advocate for to protect there
are not many places in the world where
you can get pure and potent cannabis
medicine other than the Emerald triangle
for reasons that you know I could go
into but we won't right now but
elsewhere Salinas Valley Tennessee
wherever they're they're growing things
in soil they're growing cannabis in soil
that has had previously treated
agricultural crops chemical nutrients
chemical pesticides and all kinds of
other toxins that we don't want as the
root cause of our medicine so we have
the unique possibility here in the
Emerald triangle to support and sustain
the most pure and potent in the best raw
materials for cannabis medicine in the
world bar no other place in the world
where it's a reputation that we have
around the world and if everybody
doesn't protect that and cry out to
protect it we're gonna lose it to Big
Pharma and other forces so
I came up in the time of dare and I
raised my children in the time of dare
and then I became a nurse and I had to
put veils on to sort of be able to exist
in in a culture that I didn't really
believe in I wish I had known more about
the plant and so that's the next journey
for me is to integrate the plant one
thing I do know about the plant is that
in Israel the strains are a little more
controlled and they're a little more
medicinal I don't know if controlling
the strains are making them more
medicinal rather than more marketable
through like high THC strains you know
is possible or viable or even a solution
I think if we create a market for
medicinal marijuana then the farmers
will grow the more medicinal varieties I
don't know if that's true because I'm
not a plant person unfortunately not yet
I want to get my hands in the ground I
want to get my hands on that plant but I
just haven't had the opportunities yet
but I I do believe that there are
cannabinoids we don't know about Israel
has been studying these cannabinoids for
the 80 years that we have been
prohibiting it so they know which
cannabinoids actually cure which
prostate cancers through the biomarkers
and they're growing to that yeah and and
absolutely right Mirena is absolutely
right and not just Israel but University
of Bonn and potency in Madrid and Oxford
and Brazil is doing a lot of really good
work as well everywhere in the world
where they didn't have this silly war on
drugs that also included marijuana you
know it's just just it's a crazy Alice
in Wonderland world in the United States
right now it'll end with time that will
change but it does take time to change
people's attitudes the one thing I would
say is that this I think there's a false
notion that the dispensaries have
recreational marijuana and we're trying
to get medicine in there I again will
say that I think all cannabis is
medicinal the question of which is the
best to live
system which are the best ratios which
is the best dosing all of that can be
done within the products that are being
created now and we just need to educate
our staff in these various dispensaries
so they can give honest good information
to the patients there's a huge gap there
23 licensed types of the state of
California but there's not one of those
licenses that has the state of
California has has directed any
resources toward public and patient
education zero zip so we're on our own
out here and having said that there's
still a big gap between the research
that's being done in places like Israel
and what our farmers are cultivating and
are what our medicine makers are making
we need to close that gap so that we
begin to see it's not just a question of
the markers and figuring out because
even with that study on pancreatic
cancer in Israel they ran into a problem
halfway through the study because the
cultivator hired on contract by the
Israeli government switched one nutrient
in that very controlled indoor grow and
all of a sudden they had completely
different results and they couldn't
figure it out but fortunately they were
able to trace it back I was on an
international webinar that where they
talked to the person who was doing that
study and he says we spent we were going
crazy 24/7 trying to figure out what did
we do wrong it was one little variable
so there's a lot of science that still
needs to be applied to our cultivation
and to our medicine making and we're not
that those structures aren't set up yet
system is under genetic control so it's
it's gonna be personalized and different
for every single patient which is a good
at a bad thing because what we know
about herbal medicine that's
fundamentally different from
pharmaceuticals is it's individuated
from a suitable treat patients like
we're cookie cutters take two aspirin
every four hours no matter what's wrong
with you how big you are how small you
are male female child and whatever
that's crazy medicine it doesn't it's
not the way our bodies work so that's
there's a good in a bad part to that
yeah for sure
well I have a lot of fantasies but
they're not fantasies that are mine
alone because there are groups that are
organizing around some key aspects of
where do we go next in cannabis
regulation and such as if you look
through the state of California those
counties or those sectors of different
counties who have had strong trade
associations have achieved the most
traction in Sacramento and in their
local county seats so here we have the
coming together of a couple of
grassroots organizations in something
called MCA the Mendocino cannabis
alliance now what we need to focus on is
menace as MCA and becoming a very strong
voice on behalf of our farmers our
cultivators our medicine makers our
distributors our dispensaries all of us
in not just Mendocino but our entire
Emerald Triangle area a region is we
need to focus on lifting these onerous
regulations treating it as a regular
agricultural crop get the helicopters
out of our backyards lift the tax burden
that welcomes invites people to become
compliant and legal make it easier for
them to do that support an Appalachian
system that would create a protective
envelope around the craft cannabis that
exists in the Emerald triangle that's
unique and different from anything
they've when they throw seeds into the
dirt in Salinas Valley or Kentucky or
wherever they're throwing seeds into the
dirt these days it will distinguish the
the high quality and the purity and the
potency that becomes the basis of our of
our medicine we don't have to create a
market the market is out there just
since January 1st 2018 with the
legalization in California people are
coming out of the woodwork because they
have there's patient needs patients are
coming out of the woodwork and saying I
want to try cannabis instead of being
dependent on all these pharmaceuticals
that have all these side-effects so we
need to organize ourselves as an
industry and have a strong voice at the
table to create a supportive at a
supportive fiscal of tax and regulatory
environment for our
people in the industry to keep making
those hi craft hi heritage value pure
and potent materials by biological
materials I'll just be brought about it
biomass flowers everything that we need
to create these medicines so we need we
need that kind of organization my
personal belief is that everybody has a
right to thrive up to their level of
their ability
I believe the Western medical model does
not believe have the same belief many
are caught in a trap of working in a
toxic work environment coming home
stressed taking their stress out on
their families you know and the cycle
just continues and you know people are
turning to opioids alcohol food even
hectic lifestyle as an addiction many
are depressed many are anxious we have
the highest level of stress in ten years
cannabis medicine can bring the change
that we need to our culture to our
society we've just gone mad we have gone
mad with collective madness with all
this trying to keep up with the Joneses
trying to buy the best couch like
constantly watching TV our kids are
feeling it our kids are stressed
overweight and pre-diabetic
there needs to be a cultural shift
cannabis will