[Music]
I'm David Bennett suck apparently a
professional stoner
I'd like to think of myself a bit more
as a journalist I've been covering
cannabis I am a STONER
I've been covering cannabis for 15 years
that's a big period of time for cannabis
a lot of change I now write a lot for
Leafly and I have a podcast called great
moments in weed history with Abdullah
and beam spoiler alert I'm being another
guy as Abdullah I'm very excited for the
panel I'm going to introduce everybody
in a second and then they can of course
educate and entertain us all the panel
as promised is called from
counterculture to Main Street but I'm
actually gonna rename it because I don't
think that's what we're facing I think
what we're facing is from counterculture
to corporate capitalism when I look at
what's going on with cannabis
I see the counterculture and Main Street
on one side we share a lot of the same
values and I see corporate cannabis as
this new entity and where things are
actually moving and I think that we all
have to be realistic about what that
means I like to say everything bad
that's been happening to small
businesses and small farmers in this
country over the last 50 years is
happening to cannabis all at once right
now is there anybody who doesn't know
what I mean by that
okay that's pretty powerful we all know
that that's what's happening I don't
even need to explain to you the market
forces that are at work but this is our
community and our movement and it
doesn't have to go that way
so I think that idea of that we're
moving to Main Street is not really
where we're moving we're moving to
corporate capitalism so let's be honest
about that and let's be honest about
Wall Street
and what their values are you know there
was a lot of talk as we approach
legalization tell me hands up if you've
heard this one Wall Street and big
business are going to legitimize
cannabis bullshit right anybody disagree
cannabis incredibly legitimate Wall
Street in big business not such a good
record so what we have to ask ourselves
as these two forces meet cannabis and
free-market capitalism as its practiced
in the United States at least is it
going to add to our culture is it going
to add to the values of this plant or is
it going to be an extraction industry I
was just up in Humboldt County who knows
Humboldt County okay that's the heart
and soul the whole Emerald triangle
everybody but really the heart and soul
what are the industries that have been
there before timber and fishing their
extraction industries well guess what
they're not there anymore because they
took all the trees and they took all the
fish and what they left behind was poor
people poor people who turn to this
plant turn to cannabis and found a new
way of life well now we're facing
another extraction industry ok cannabis
is renewable you have to keep growing it
but what they're extracting is market
share what they're extracting is the
value of this plant only in terms of
money and we have to place that value
differently so my first let me introduce
the panel and I'll just say my first
question to them is going to be how do
we balance these things how do we make
sure that the roots culture of cannabis
that we all love and that sauce through
this prohibition survives and how do we
make sure that the communities that have
been targeted by this prohibition
disproportionately put in prison have
their families torn apart how do we open
a door for them and not just let all the
market share and all the capital flow to
people who frankly already
way too much money and way too much
power and not a good track record of
using it so that's gonna be my first
question but let me introduce everybody
and then they can weigh in
Justin Calvino is the founder of the
Mendocino Appalachians project and the
co-founder of the emerald exchange he
sits on the board of directors of the
California Growers Association as well
as the Mendocino County Industry
Association Justin also founded Green go
cooperative in Mendocino County thanks
for coming
Matt Stang started working at High Times
Magazine in 2003 as an intern and is
currently the company's chief revenue
officer
so that's he moved up for almost 20
years he has met and interacted with
nearly everyone in the cannabis
community and his expertise includes
marketing branding business development
event production and product viability
and and what I love about this panel is
it shows everyone coming from different
directions all have a place in this
community
Bret Leonard has been at the forefront
of the digital media revolution for over
25 years whether it be the director
writer of the groundbreaking cult
classic film lawnmower man yes whoo
which introduced the concept of virtual
reality of popular culture or being the
first to pioneer modern stereoscopic
techniques and photo risk realistic CGI
and his IMAX film t-rex Nicole West has
over 10 years of experience in the
cannabis industry and has had success in
forty five-plus cannabis business
applications open 20 retail locations in
four states overseeing over 200 million
dollars in sales and has helped scale
over a hundred and fifty thousand square
feet of cultivation and yeah that's a
lot and I'm sorry Rebecca is it Gascon
mm-hmm I should have just gone for it
Rebecca Gasca is a cannabis business and
government affairs strategist who's drug
policy experience began in 2008 as the
first in-house
lobbyists for the ACLU of Nevada and she
is the founder of pistol and stigma
which works to bridge the gap between
policymakers and the emerging cannabis
industry which is definitely something
we're going to get into but why don't we
start closest to me and we'll move down
the line a little bit just general
thoughts on as I say you know this
intersection between cannabis capitalism
what's to be gained what are the dangers
and how do we as a community respond to
what can be an existential threat and as
we're seeing in the marketplace a huge
number of businesses not able to compete
on what's you know not really a fair or
playing field in many ways so yeah I
mean I've been connected to all this
ever since my film was rated as one of
the top ten stoner films of all time by
premier magazine a long time ago so I've
got some Leben connected to being a
STONER professional like you are in the
context of being a filmmaker and someone
who also is a cannabis enthusiast I will
tell you that the more weed I smoked on
the films I made the more successful
that film was and that literally is a
true statement
beyond that in context of your question
I feel there's a Platonic responsibility
for those of us that are global
storytellers to tell stories to shift
the narrative around cannabis culture to
make it much more inclusive and more
expanded outside of the ghettoization
that it has been given by most of how
they would content and most content in
general now there's nothing wrong with
stoner comedies there's actually a few
very funny ones and good ones but that
is not the entire story as a matter of
fact it's the tiniest sliver of the
story so at my company studio lightship
we are very much embedding in many of
our IP our creative projects which by
the way in encompass what we call VX
story worlds virtual experience that's
what I call VX it's VR AR em are at
their core but are also feature films
digital content television content and
you know Arg and finally at the core
virtual story worlds in that as a
storyteller or now as I call myself
story world or we are embedding positive
truthful mythology around what this is
as a culture and that needs to lead the
way storytelling has always led the way
in terms of the steering of the
zeitgeist and right now there is as we
all know there has been a disinformation
narrative going on around cannabis
culture for a very long time and it's
been stepped up with the increasing
success of the new business models but
of course that's one of the things
that's creating the corporatization
because there's this this feeling like
you can't actually address the core soul
of what this is about which is health
healing and actually a mind medicine for
the planet that is unprecedented in
human history and that narrative in that
story is something I'm committed to
telling and I believe that that is one
of the first steps that has to happen
for popular adoption of really
understanding what is at the core of
cannabis thanks thank you so I I think
it's important to note that this isn't a
binary like it's not an us-versus-them
and I think that the longer that that
sort of framework is extended the more
of a disservice we're doing to ourselves
as advocates as people who care about
cannabis as business owners as you know
parents as scientists because you can't
look at this through my kata mist lens
as a lobbyist somebody who comes from
drug policy and criminal justice reform
who's a civil libertarian at heart like
I know that the only way that I was ever
able to move the ball down the court was
because I reached across aisles talking
to people even when they thought they
weren't going to agree with me right
that is how you change this story
right that is how you touch minds and
hearts and it takes everybody to do that
what's most interesting to me is since I
left and I started pistol and Sigma I
worked with people who have been
longtime growers right who were arguably
incredibly successful but they don't
know how to create rules to the game
right and that's what you can do when
you are proactive advocate and lobbyists
you rewrite the rules and that's what
we're doing in this industry thankfully
I had a very fortunate opportunity as a
lobbyist for the ACLU where I got
entrenched into the actual like
institutional side of rule writing right
policymaking where I got to see how easy
it actually was to be able to shift the
narrative once you were there and you
were applying yourself
I've been lucky that I've been able to
take that same experience and apply it
from state to state with clients now
across the United States and to be able
to take what has otherwise been you know
institutional capital and teach my
clients like okay you come from this
banking world you come from this
business world right that is very very
different than how the cannabis industry
has worked thus far but I can take your
capital and I can apply it in meaningful
ways to write some of those wrongs of
the you know of the criminalized aspects
of the industry and teach people how to
otherwise you know participate on a
level that four on a social justice
level that they've never had the
opportunity before because they've been
working through this you know blinded
set of their own business functions but
now I get to pull them into the cannabis
industry and be like oh guess what you
get to work with people who care it's
awesome right but but it does take
reaching across the aisle it does take
saying okay you might have a different
history than I do but let's talk about
how we can co-create this now moving
forward and does it take a lot of money
yeah you know of course it's not easy to
build a business I learned that like you
know I'm a little guy still right like I
you know my firm has learned the hard
way like how to do business I come from
a nonprofit background right but
gracefully I am learning from my own
clients and I'm learning from the
engagements that I have you know from
state to state and it's but again I just
want to stress that this is not us
versus them we're all a part of this now
I want to just make a quick point I
think there's a big distinction to be
made between ending the war on cannabis
ending the arrests ending this
incredibly oppressive system that's
winning the war and now what we're
talking about is winning the peace which
is the economic aspect of it how many
people out here are small cannabis
business owners or small growers and how
many of you feel that the rules of the
game are fair I don't see anybody you
know that speaks kind of volumes to me
and I think that that's what we the
mentality we have to pat ourselves on
the back really hard for ending this
incredibly oppressive system but we have
to be realistic about what we're up
against and what I'm hearing is an
extinction-level event for these small
business owners and for these small
farmers and it doesn't mean bad
intentions it means we're taking a
system that existed outside of
mainstream capitalism and pushing it
into that system and we have to you know
be honest about what's what's going on
and I kind of wanted to parlay off of
both of them in my opinions and it's
because I have two different places that
I come from in this space ten years ago
I was one of the first lottery winners
in the city of Long Beach in this
beautiful city that we're all in
currently I am NOT a license holder in
the city of Long Beach I invested a
little over a quarter of a million
dollars we played two leases for almost
two years to go through the process I
got a location for those of you who are
familiar with the city of Long Beach I
was over off the Studebaker in spring
right across from the El Dorado disc
golf course
this upset some council members within
the city at the time they were able to
overturn the ordinance after they took
all of my money made me relocate and add
parks to the ordinance after the fact
thus zoning me out in the process of me
losing my entire life at the youngest
business owner in my family I felt
vindicated to fight right my first were
warriors in this fight
the answer is we I have to fight and
stand up against this so I fought I
fought for almost a year I had all my
friends and family that worked for me I
was receiving $1,000 a day fine to
myself and $1,000 fine day to my
landlord my landlord was pretty cool he
said keep paying the bills and I'll let
you stay as long as you want but at a
certain point when the police are
harassing your customers you decide to
shut down your business my customers
were getting tickets my employees were
getting their cars towed I mean it
became a full-on harassment from the
Long Beach PD I eventually decided I'm
gonna shut down but I had fought for too
long that process of fighting for so
long in in this new ordinance when the
city of Long Beach got all those people
that were able to get priority points
because I fought for what we stood up
for I lost my ability to apply for a
priority license when Long Beach did
their licensing process last year so I
was required to go into the priority 3
section even though they had taken my
entire life from me and I when I say my
entire life I literally mean my entire
life from all of the money I had to my
car fast forward 10 years that I've I
moved to Colorado because obviously
California wasn't ready at the time I
worked for a bunch of companies Mike I'm
now back I just started a marketing and
branding company but I do also I do
advisement for investment firms and my
main piece of that is from the cannabis
industry I try to claim myself as a
fairy godmother of cannabis because I
want the people who are coming into this
looking for money to know what the heck
they're asking for to know what they're
signing up for and so for me and for any
of you out there who have that bit of
knowledge who have the ability to impart
this information to your friends you owe
it to them you owe it to them so that
they can make wise money decisions
because so many of us have been living
in shoeboxes of cash having no interest
didn't even be able to talk to a bank so
the people who are most experienced in
this business
I have no financial understanding of
what it even means to look at a banker
and say here's my money they don't even
they get nervous when they walk into the
bank to cash or personal check I mean
and that's the truth and and a lot of
these people are still coming out of
their ptsds
so if you're one of those people who is
coming from the other side some of my
best mentors right now are people that
have no and your interaction with
cannabis outside of the fact that they
believe in it and they're coming in from
banking they're coming in from finance
and I'm connecting with these people
that understand that this is a movement
and that people whose lives are being
changed by this and so for me I say if
you have the ability to impart knowledge
to one of your farmer friends or or
extract your friends who's been crushing
it what they're doing but maybe have not
been able to use a bank or ever ask for
money I mean if you've been in the
industry for more than five years you've
never even considered going to a bank to
be like hey can I have a million dollars
get out of here and so that reality
we've never even read a book most of the
people to understand what what most of
these terms mean I was at the Boston
freedom rally I told people there's a
book called investment terms for dummies
and I know it seems silly but read it
before you go talk to some money people
and something as simple as that we need
to educate ourselves and for those of us
who are already educated who are making
the way it's your duty to help those
people that you know deserve to have a
space in this industry to fight for that
and to educate your people yeah
absolutely let's just just for anybody
who's not aware of due to cannabis being
federally illegal that prevents not just
banking but getting a bank loan so
you've had a successful business for ten
years your books are great to the extent
that you know you could show them but
you're denied the money to grow your
business to compete and yet somebody
with private equity can come in with a
hundred times your money they can make
fifteen fuck-ups and still win where you
get one chance and then all too often
they turn around and say well these
stoners just don't know how to run a
business and you know I think what
you're saying is there are people of
good intention coming in with the values
of the plant and we
want them but the question is are you
gonna add something or are you just
going to extract you know how many
people had any trouble getting cannabis
in California ten years ago we know how
to grow and distribute cannabis
we don't need private equity to do it so
let's take that off so what are you
gonna add Justin I want to thank you for
this topic anybody who knows me knows
this is pretty much all I talk about all
day long like everyday this is it as you
know I won't drop an expletive there but
capitalism before that fuck is the word
he's thank you very much fuck capitalism
no last year I said I write is relative
in you know capitalism is messed up at
best and I dealt with hezekiah said like
oh my god I can't believe you said that
on stage and now we're having a full-on
discussion so this is the evolution of
the conversation we're finally tired of
it it's not an us-versus-them it's an it
capitalism is an it it is a disease it
is it creates disease like we I don't
feel easy I don't go to bed easy I don't
wake up easy I have to tell my children
they can and can't do things that we
could and couldn't do before and like
you know and why you know it's like you
know I moved into a beautiful region to
raise my family the right way and I'm
watching people who've never touched
cannabis before taking market share
dropping us down 2/3 making things it's
the REE criminalization of cannabis it's
not decriminalization is not
legalization we got recriminate
into a separate category and now you
know they're like thank you we'll take
it from here
good capitalist this is this is our
chance while we're still having this
conversation hopefully this conversation
continues to actually take the main
stage that we have and speak out against
what we're doing to the rest of the
world we are shipping capitalism around
the whole planet and we're getting to
see it now we're actually getting to
experience at a small
scale producers they can tell this story
we can tell the story of how you know
yesterday I could buy groceries next
week I'm probably gonna be on food
stamps week afterward I'm probably gonna
be working for someone and that and and
then keep on and keep on and keep on
losing farms my friends my neighbors
everyone that I turned to has a
different story I've become a grief
counselor on my Ridge I'm not even an
activist anymore the idea that we as you
know we as small-scale producers have a
chance is is like sort of like a it's
like a myth and a hero's journey right
like it's like it's the only thing now
that we can do the show the world that
like there's a breath left and humanity
I mean the idea that we are actually
seeing people like come in well funded
with 20 million dollars to buy a shelf
space to push small producers off the
market like and we're what and we're
applauding these people we're cooking
them dinners we're throwing events for
them we're letting them sponsor it's
it's it's it's beyond ridiculous it's
like and then now we're funding water
infrastructure being stolen from
Northern California shipped down to the
desert to build billions of dollars of
infrastructure to build a new
agricultural industry where there was
none that's capitalism I mean so like I
don't like I could talk for like days
and days and days it's probably like two
zero point and no end because I think at
the end of the day like as depressed as
I get it's like I'm also just as hopeful
and happy that we're having this
conversation I'm hopeful and happy that
we can decentralize agriculture I'm so
happy we're having a collective and
cooperative conversation about how to
distribute resources I think that if I
was to say something about the Segway is
it like work together don't sell out you
know every single one of us like band
together sign jayvees you know create
cooperatives
you know don't sell to Canadian
companies just because they're offering
you hella money you know what I'm saying
like you know give that IP to your
neighbor you know and your neighbors
neighbor and continue that pattern
forward so I'm just gonna keep on
talking about it again one more quick
show of hands who here in their hearts
loves coal more than they love cannabis
again nobody but and this is with full
respect to people who work in that
industry when we hear oh my god we're
gonna lose coal jobs even though we know
that industry is polluting the planet
potentially into a catastrophe we
collectively act like it's the biggest
emergency that ever fucking happened on
planet earth is we have to save these
coal jobs well we have 60,000 small
cannabis farmers in this state alone and
they're facing that and we need to react
I would say even more robustly and you
know chuckle all right good man yeah
fuck coal totally no but it is kind of a
terrible polluting so here's what I
would say I love the Joseph Campbell
hero's journey reference I think that's
fantastic I think everyone here is here
because they're on their own hero's
journey and I think part of this whole
thing part of this legalization thing
that's happening is we're bringing
together the people who thought we were
15 years ago when I was at high times
and I told people I was at high times
they would be like that is fucking
disgusting you dirty stoner and now
they're like hey can I pick your brain
about CBD do you know anything about
this weed business what about these
Canadian stocks is there anything going
on that I should know about like is this
the craziest thing that's ever happened
and while there is a lot of negativity
around it there's also a lot of
positivity because we have a moment now
and mean I love you but I don't think
the war is over
I don't think we're fighting for the
peace yet I still think we're
fighting the war and I am very very
strongly that we have not won that
there's still large compartes of this
country that are not the people are
still going to jail like I went to jail
and people are going to jail and I sat
in jail for five days with the federal
government and it fucking sucks
and if any of you have done that it's
the worst thing in the entire fucking
world so anything that you can do to get
yourself out of that situation to stop
the people from arresting us for
cannabis I am supportive of I don't like
John Boehner
I think he was a fucking asshole but the
fact that he's on Kevin's board now is a
huge movement the fact that Mitch
McConnell signed off on the farm bill
because a couple people I know went in
and lobbied the fuck out of him for
their farms and Kentucky that's huge
like all of this aside people should not
be going to jail for a fucking plant
everybody in here I hope everybody in
here agrees with that so like we gotta
win the war
first before we win the peace and that
really does involve money because this
country it's a fucked up system but it's
our system and that's yes everyone here
should be agitating to change the system
but we also have to change the fact that
we're going to fucking jail for weed and
that there's eight great states that
have legalized it but there's still
people going to jail there's people
getting hit in NorCal I know someone who
went to jail three weeks ago they might
have been shipping weed summer I don't
know okay maybe they're okay sure sure
okay yeah
but fuck that like they're still going
to jail here in California what is it
require it requires all of these
wonderful people in Congress who you
maybe would never want to share a
fucking joint with but you definitely
want them to vote on our side we need
the states bill to pay we need all of
these fucking bills to pass so that
people stop going to jail and that's my
position the same one that we hadn't man
being worked together for many years we
had this conversation
many times smoking joints playing
ping-pong and you have to you have to
win the war first like I idealism is
amazing and it's great but I don't want
anyone to ever go to jail again for weed
and that requires some money and some
people with their power to be like hey
guy who works with me on these projects
vote differently because I gave you X
dollars for your last campaign and
that's the shitty system that we're in
but if the system are in and we need to
fucking win this war we can fight about
how to make it better but right now it
is still there is still hundreds of
thousands of people going to jail
every year for smoking cannabis for
distributing cannabis for for bringing
cannabis somewhere for for whatever the
whatever the plant does they're like you
are now in jail you are stripped of your
freedom your rights your voting rights
you're no longer a human being and
that's fucking horrible and if we don't
stop that if we don't first of all stop
that and then get into the yes we need
to change the rest of the system yes you
shouldn't be killing small farms to go
and build a fucking private equity thing
in the desert that shit is I'm sorry to
any of you who are running a giant
facility in the desert so no no insult
ment but like what the fuck like 400,000
square feet in the desert with no water
and you're like I'm gonna grow tons of
weed why why are you not going up to a
place where it's wet all the time and
perfect and just just work with the
people who have their setups there and
help them get licensed and give them
some money and then make money off of
that rather than some absurd gleaming
desert dream anyway I'm sorry I grabbed
the mic I'm I just feel very
passionately that if we don't fight for
the end of the war on drugs we can't
fight for the peace and it's not done
people are like people like oh it's done
don't worry I'm like he can with a
stroke of the pen Donald Trump could
fucking arrest all of us every one of us
just like that and it's still not done
so like we need to finish that off and
then we can all deal with the remnants
but like first don't
go to jail okay I think I just
absolutely don't go to jail and don't
get caught the first responsibility of
any revolutionary is not to get caught
they can't arrest you if you don't get
caught I I think I hope it's pretty
obvious that you know I've dedicated my
professional career to that idea that we
need to end this war on people
ultimately on marginalized people
specifically I just don't think that the
two ideas are mutually exclusive the
idea that we work to end this oppressive
system but that we don't give over our
values in our community to these moneyed
interests along the way I don't think
there's ever a right time to do that and
I don't think there's ever a wrong time
to stand up for what you value and what
you believe in and it's like to me
that's a false choice we don't have to
put all these farmers out of business
and we don't have to put all these
mom-and-pop true believer people who put
their asses on the line and many of whom
went to prison we don't have to push
them out into the street and push them
back into the black market in order to
win neither political party backed us
and we still won we took on the criminal
justice system we took on the medical
establishment we took on both political
parties we took on the public and
propaganda and we won and we did it and
the politicians came along for the ride
once we proved that this was a winning
issue they didn't lead and it wasn't a
bribe it was us that changed and ended
this and it's like if we give over to
the idea that it was some outside
benevolent force that did it we lose our
agency and we lose our sense of
community and we become sharecroppers to
corporate America and that's not my
vision and
I think there's no wrong time to start
pushing back against that which gets to
my next question for the panel if we
really can't look at big business to
change outside of its own best interests
the economic fight is on very difficult
terrain but the culture fight is one
that we can win so how do we and Bret
this is a great question to start with
you how do we educate consumers who will
ultimately vote with their dollars to
support the kind of businesses and the
kind of business practices that make
this such an amazing and valuable
community well you've got to entertain
people in our culture you can't just
call it education it can't just be set
in this sort of dry situation it has to
be something that is done in a way that
moves emotion on a mass scale and that
is that's what's in coming upon
storytellers to tell better more
powerful stories and I believe as
Rebecca said the the core thing here is
to not polarize the bit the greater
narrative that this all fits into is the
greater narrative we're all experiencing
in American culture and many ways global
culture right now writ large this is a
time of separation and dividing and and
pitting things against each other as
long as we push against that with our
stories and push against it in a way
that creates the war and it is a war I
totally agree we haven't won the war
as long as we as push against that that
way we're going to get that same
resistance back sometimes even more
powerful and so we have to find a clever
way of shifting the overall mass
perception and that is not playing to
our own room it's not ghettoizing it to
be something that is just for this you
know those of us that know and there's
the smart stoners I mean there's so many
ways that elitism creeps into every
group into every fight into every
revolution and that can't happen here
because the truth is the core and soul
of this plant is for everyone it's
something that
creates so many ways of making your life
better you know and that's not just
about getting stone that's one tiny
little aspect of it so that larger story
and the the ability to shift it from the
polarization that's the challenge I
think that's where the answer lies to
start moving the body politic and the
group you know zeitgeist in the right
direction I would agree that this is
this is a global phenomena right this
stupid war on drugs has really divided
us in ways that are so beyond
unfortunate but it's not just California
right I mean obviously look at things
from the state state level but look at
things from a country to country level
right the US has been throwing its
weight around for far too long
in criminalizing consumption on a global
scale of one of the most powerfully
medicinal plants that again that we know
of and I mean that's just one upright
coca then you can go on to other
psychedelics plants are powerful and
that was realized that was a you know
the the core of this more on drugs
heaven forbid you know people get along
shit you know cuz then the
military-industrial complex yeah I could
I could go on on that forever and ever
to but but really I really think this
comes down to popularizing some stories
right I mean that this is what happened
this is what we saw with Charlotte's Web
right Sanjay Gupta weeds all of that
like you move emotions you move people
you get people to start seeing like oh
you know this is like a like gay
marriage right gay marriage oh my gosh I
actually have a cousin who's gay so all
of a sudden it's not that terrible oh
you know my mom's her like retirement
community ladies are like we want to
know what this CBD is right we heard
this could help so you take those
opportunities and
you start educating people where they're
at and that's been the problem I think
for so long in this work that we've done
it's been disparate disparate messaging
right because we're not starting where
other people are coming from you know
some people excuse me did some assholes
don't care that black and brown people
have been going to jail they still don't
and you know what we might never
convince them otherwise that that is
actually a real fucking problem
so we start to educate them where
they're at with Grandma right with their
grandchildren who have autism you know
you start looking at it from different
angles because this cannabis plant is
actually a dodecahedron right it is
immensely powerful and it can touch
everybody and I truly believe either
Knossos theory of the endocannabinoid
deficiency I think that we have been
living for way too long with not enough
cannabis to treat our endocannabinoids
system so you know I know that's like a
heady idea for most people but it's
natural food let my food be thy medicine
you know there are a lot of different
ways essentially to story-tell this and
and we're all responsible in different
ways for and to make it more successful
commercially in this form because we are
in this system we're in we are in a
capitalist society we can't but deny
that that's real I mean every business
that gets to this point of you know
these inflection points suddenly the
giant money comes in and that those
players come in on every single vertical
you can imagine so this is not a new
story that's why it's really a much
larger thing that I think this is
perfectly emblematic of and we can make
it the emblem of smaller is better think
I mean it literally will connect
directly to better healing better
lifestyle better wellness better joy
when we can tell that story and make
people understand it then this thing
moves Nicole so yet again my answers
kind of a combination of both of them
the entertainment factor is huge my
example on that as my grandmother I told
my grandma was a day trader for the
first five years of being in this
business I told her I sold commodities
which to this day I still believe is
pretty much the truth but in the process
my grandma found out it was the end of
the world I was a drug dealer
I was destroying my grandfather's life
because he was dying and I was sneaking
him edibles so that he could live the
end of his life in a good way I was
gonna destroy my grandfather's life who
was in a wheelchair and he was gonna
wheel himself out on the Long Beach
Boulevard looking for some crack or
something I mean I was I was the devil
and and since the education factor you
know I could have done the most I tried
to tell my grandma I had booklets and I
had information but the entertainment
piece got my grandma she watched a few
of those it really changed her in a big
way and then the next piece of getting
to people where they are I agree and yes
like my educating my grandma was huge
she's that she's person that shows up in
votes every single time but local
government people forget how easy it is
to become a city council member I know
that not to say like it's the easiest
thing in the world but it's it's not
like becoming president like you can
make a difference in your local
community and even if you're not going
to become a city council member to get
to those people where they are because
most people who go into politics want to
continue in politics right like nobody
starts as a mayor and it's like yeah
this is it I'm done
most mayor's want to go on in the
Congress or something higher and so we
start on a level where they're actually
listening to us and they kind of still
have to listen to us that's just a
person that shows up to City Council and
waits for your three minutes you get to
speak to them where they are and if we
can start at an early stage in their
political development and help educate
people politically early on before they
become your president
sidenote on that but no but before they
become you know a governor or a
congressman or somebody who has
political experience that before that
happens if we could get to them where
they are as a city council member or as
a mayor I mean Mayor Robert Garcia was
here this morning like if you had it you
had a chance to speak with him when I
was going through the city of Long Beach
drama he was a council member I've been
in his office he's heard my issues we've
had one-on-one meetings and not to say
that I changed his mind but all of us
helped him understand where now you have
a mayor who supports this that and
that's huge we all got to somebody where
he was and was able to really help
educate
a council member who then went on to be
mayor who's now much more powerful and
is allowing for things to happen that I
don't know would have happened without
Mayor Robert Garcia and so it's kind of
combination the entertainment gets the
voters to listen the voting age is in a
big way and talking to people where they
are we can bring people into politics
knowing about how amazing cannabis is
rather than trying to convince somebody
who's been doing their job for 30 years
and has already kind of put the cloak
over their eyes that this is a you know
a drug and you know a lot of these
people still really do believe that
there's a war on cannabis out there and
they need a fight against us because
yeah the worst not over this is still
very real but I would say entertain and
talk to your local teams your local
governments I mean especially when we
talked about the equity that's locally
being done because local governments did
realize that this is a problem that the
people have been going to jail for this
by being racially profiled that's a huge
issue and local government the state
understands that it's a thing but local
governments are choosing to enact their
equity programs and that's because
somebody talked to their local
governments this has to happen and they
want to make change I am really excited
to hear Kath speak by the way because
that's somebody that is really
interesting right now if you guys aren't
familiar with Kath Packer but following
the the equity movement in LA has been
really really interesting and I'm proud
of what's happening right now thanks
Justin I think that the Appalachian
program that you could speak on is one
of the great things to come out of prop
64 to help us educate these consumers
right this is rapidly becoming my
favorite panel ever we've got a
moderator it allows us to drop f-bombs
we have a capitalist bashing session and
one of your panelists just dropped
dodecahedron on the stage all right so
yeah so basically I'm kind of cheating
here because I live in a region that is
steeped in heritage we are a legacy of
small farmers every day is a story
everything that we do is a story
everything is a story that replicates
what's been going on for almost five
decades in that region so you know the
edutainment or however
you know we want to call it where we're
actually like educating people while
having fun is what we're about because
in Northern California that's what we
want to do is we we came up there to
basically become small farmers raise our
families a certain way and have fun in
2015 in developing the Mendocino
Appalachians project realizing that you
know sort of resource mapping community
resource mapping economic development
seeing that no one in their right mind
would stick a commodities grow
two-and-a-half hours on the back side of
a mountain down a windy road where two
cars going down at the same time passing
each other almost created off of a cliff
makes absolutely no sense to a
commodities distributor all we have in
that region is tourism and all we have
is our story and all we have is our
quality and to tell the story of the
breeding to tell the story of the
communities to tell the story of the
heritage in that region is is not only
our right is not only our saving grace
but it's also our gift to the rest of
the world because now we are creating a
system is everyone here familiar with
appellations of origin okay so similar
to wine in France essentially like
Bordeaux champagne in Northern
California in Mendocino we developed a
map that's very similar to these regions
so we've broken our county up into
multiple regions and each one of those
regions has its own unique heritage its
own unique strains its own unique
communities and will eventually create
its own unique brand around that story
so being able to do this and being able
to split these regions up into these
cultural hubs will allow us to
distribute our cannabis at a higher
price remain small cooperate know your
neighbor know your distributor know your
market come down to Los Angeles like
we're doing right now and actually
telling that story through the Emerald
exchange I'm not trying to selflessly
name drop it just like where I work
like but I mean basically we have these
entertainment events we come down we
tell the story we bring the products we
talk about the small batch and the
lifestyle so it's the idea is that like
I said I feel like I'm cheating because
this is though I just live this life and
it just and I feel so optimistic like
what I said was are kind of depressed
I'm also just as hopeful because no one
can ever take away our place there's no
one that's ever gonna be able to grow a
calm sea cush there's no one ever gonna
be able to grow a spy Rock Sour Diesel
all of these all of these epigenetic
expressions are happening in those
regions specifically you can't recreate
it so I really believe that through that
story of cultural heritage that you know
I mean I believe we're gonna be alright
in that region I don't believe all of us
are I think we have like 30,000 plus
farmers but 80 percent of us if not more
well way more than 80 percent are not
legal at all and we're talking about I
think we have 200 legal cultivation
licenses in Mendocino County right now
going into the market and every single
gate on my Ridge is locked because
there's cannabis behind it so and that's
one Ridge I can count over 200 people so
I mean by no means is this you know
gonna win it for everyone but it's
definitely a good shot moving forward
Thanks yep I kind of forgot what the
question was honestly so how do we
educate consumers to support the real
grassroots movement of cannabis that
kept this movement going through
prohibition thank you and I didn't even
get stoned today so I guess here here's
what I would say I think there's in here
there's probably 10 media companies
filming right now I think there's
wonderful events Tampa sitting back
there from the Eroica
Sampath exchange here I think there's
places that that educate both
experientially and in written print
digital form that are putting out
stories in a great way that they kind of
bring that feeling that the cannabis is
normal that marijuana is safer than
alcohol as our friend Mason put it out
there many years ago and helped change
the world and I think that's the biggest
thing that anyone here can do is tell
that story because humans are
storytelling people like that's we all
want to gather around the fire and
listen and I think back to his Joseph
Campbell reference thank you for that
was that wasn't made this my favorite
panel but you know I think if you look
at it as a way for people to go and
normalize and and make cannabis not
something that's scary or dirty or makes
your grandfather smoke crack I think
there's there's a lot of things that you
can do just all the people sitting here
all the the media companies all of the
event companies all these people who are
who are out there telling the story you
know this event right here is
normalizing cannabis we're on the Queen
Mary we're on a beautiful historic ship
in the middle of Long Beach and having a
kind of his event with a bunch of
tourists walking around and I think
people seeing that it's not scary that
it's not dirty that it's not something
that's gonna lead to some terrible other
thing which what it's leading to is not
is was never that in the first place but
just convincing people that all of it
was propaganda that it's all bullshit
that that utilizing cannabis is a right
is a natural plant-based medicine as
there are many other plant-based
medicines that are currently outlawed by
the system because they create people
who question they create people who who
want to understand more who want to seek
and search and that's not good for a
controlled system and so it really comes
down to people messaging that and
creating great content great events
great other things that you can interact
with and take
and tell that story to your friends and
your family and their friends and their
family and you wind up that's the most
powerful thing in the world you know the
the most powerful thing is not something
someone tells you to do it's what you
feel internally and want to tell
everyone else and you want to give that
so I think that's probably the most
powerful thing that people can do here
and and I think they're doing it right
now I think it's it's happening here
it's happening in other places you know
there's there's events all over the
country now where cannabis is normal
aware it's it feels like something
that's just integrated into normal life
and that's the probably the best way we
can really win this war in a final way
when people are like I don't believe you
I don't believe that cannabis is a drug
I just don't believe that this is a bad
substance is gonna hurt people we went
it's over they can't keep fighting this
anymore Thanks I think how many people
just to kind of wrap up on the idea of
the media and how we portray ourselves
to the people outside this room whether
they're with us against us or curious
how many people remember like when
Colorado legalized shows like pop barons
of Colorado and Marijuana ink and making
a shitload of money off weed and the the
cash kings of cannabis and all that well
well what that was was the corporate
media coming into our world and deciding
for us what stories were gonna tell
about ourselves and they wanted to tell
those stories because it lets them off
the hook for being the propaganda wing
of prohibition for convincing for a
hundred years everyone in this country
that they were right and we were wrong
that we were people of low value that we
XY and Z deserve to go to jail basically
the stories that they didn't want to
tell were about our real community about
our farmers about our small
businesspeople
about people who'd been trampled by this
war I didn't see a lot of shows like
that and there's a reason the New York
Times
endorse legalization until 2014 that's
fucking ridiculous you're supposed to be
the paper of record you're supposed to
be intelligent people you couldn't
figure that out until 2014 the Denver
Post told everybody in an editorial to
vote against legalization guess what
they did like three months later they
started the cannabis t' so that they
could cash in i know good people who
worked at the cannabis i think they put
out a great product I'm not knocking
them but what I'm saying is that's how
this corporate media works that's how
they see a same fuckin way and guess
what happened to the cannabis it got
shut down because a bunch of hedge funds
assholes bought the newspaper and that's
what's happening to the media okay how
many farmers remember when it was four
or five grand for a pound yeah fuck yeah
what is it now yeah I I don't remember
I'm not as old but two bucks a word used
to be a good rate for a writer
it ain't anymore let me fuck to tell you
the same things the two things that I've
worked in my whole life are the media
and cannabis I see the influence of
corporate America on both of them so
when you look at your news stories and
you look at your storytellers and you
decide what are the stories we're gonna
tell about ourselves and to each other
and to the rest of the world that really
matters support the kind of media that
you believe in support the kind of media
that reflects the values of not just
this community but this plant thank you
and thank you to our entire panel it was
really one cool it was a diverse group
of people please come up and ask
questions please come up and hang out
with us I'm sorry we didn't have a Q&amp;A
what
start here we go the food doesn't start
until 5:40 so I liked the direction that
this panel headed and I think when we're
talking about small and craft we can
also talk about small craft events and
there's a big sort of yeah it's funny I
look at sort of who puts on events and
you know the event later this week in
downtown LA it's big its corporate it's
an event production company that just
looks at industries and says you know
the banking industry there's money to be
made throwing events there the
healthcare industry let's launch the
healthcare event series Oh cannabis we
can make money there and then you have
people who are doing sort of the small
craft events and I just wanted to say
it's appreciated that you all come to
events like this definitely go to the
downtown event but it's important to
come show up to events like this as well
which locally produced event by a local
resident slash activist yeah so anyone
else have a question it was mentioned
about you know people are still getting
arrested for marijuana and um we have
three strikes law that's still here
which means that if you get arrested for
a drug more than three times it's a
felony and if you get arrested for three
felonies that's life and I think that
that's pretty horror horrific but for
the individuals that are incarcerated
right now for past marijuana laws I
it was just on my mind like is there
like thoughts and anybody's minds about
you know like counteracting that because
I know that it's a lot of color people
that are facing that and those are
families that are ripped apart so I mean
for us now like we all want to stay out
but what about those people that you
know have been locked up for years and
years and years over a couple joints
been prop 64 there are provisions for
expungement of records and for people to
petition the government it's not it
should be a blanket thing to just let
peep
well no it passed I'm saying it the law
that passed has includes some of those
provisions and some local communities
have chosen to expunge people's records
even automatically San Francisco like
like five hundred there was a number I
saw a paper recently San Francisco let
out some several hundred people that all
had previous marijuana convictions I
know for a fact they've done it Colorado
did it in a big way 2015 it was some
like billions of dollars in savings from
letting these people out of jail that
they were you know keeping in so again
I'm gonna go back to making sure that we
pay attention to local communities
because local communities are going to
be able to push on this like the city of
San Francisco was able to so I mean
people need to start leaning on Los
Angeles and and you know Sacramento and
these other cities in a way if you have
some involvement in your local
communities I feel like that's probably
one of the best ways that we can right
now because I'm 64 did allow for it
again similar to the way social equity
is working the communities are going to
have to stand up and do this the state
as a whole as it stands right now is not
but if you know San Francisco can do it
anybody can we're talking about a lot
about how we can as citizens at this low
level interact with our government
officials both from a city level and
state level but there's I feel like
another opportunity that we have to be
able to act as private citizens and I
wanted to get the the panel's thoughts
on using concepts such as during during
nullification to help prevent the
conviction of of again like you
mentioned people of color who have been
uh neck without the drug war do you feel
that that's something that we could
educate not just here where we have
legal markets medicinally and
recreationally but nationwide
to help prevent further damage being
done to to the equity of those of those
unfortunately targeted people I probably
don't have a really great answer for you
there are several criminal justice
reform groups who who theorize and
strategize around a question like that
I'm not sure that the cannabis industry
is equipped for something as technical
but it's certainly a good idea it's
certainly juries we do understand are
not representative they're not peers you
know who are convicting people
historically speaking
that's why Sheree selection is such a
complicated thing and that's why people
hire expensive attorneys especially when
they are looking at the you know threat
of going to jail for life if you can't
afford that
otherwise if you're stuck with a
criminal public defender right who has a
caseload of 400 you know the the options
are much more limited I think that's
creative I think you know stories or
ideas like that are certainly ways in
which the cannabis industry could
contribute by you know in some sort of
reparations obviously what we've seen
mostly or have been these equity you
know reform projects but I think that's
why organizations like the ACLU are so
important in arenas like this because
they span their their intersectional
right it's not just cannabis its its
criminal justice reform as well sorry
that's probably not a good answer but
yeah I just think to when you know add
to what you said I think the role for
the industry and criminal justice reform
is to support criminal justice reform
financially and the people who've
dedicated their lives to doing that
don't need anything except resources you
know there's specifically to jury
nullification that's you know gets a
little into the weeds bad pun is my
stock and trade but but on the grander
scale if you're making a lot of money
off of this plant or off of this
community or in a better way if you're
making a lot of money with this plant
and with this community and you think to
yourself well what good can I do with
that money
start with criminal justice reform start
with undoing the damage that we're doing
right now and the damage we've done in
the past and there are
plenty of organizations that are worthy
and willing and ready and already
engaged in that fight and you can
support them with your resources we're
good okay that's a great note to wrap it
up one more time thanks to an incredible
panel
[Music]