one of the things we talked about
briefly the other day was going from
some of the smaller greenhouses you've
been consulting with to kind of you're
now doing a project down in Salinas
which is a much larger project so can
you talk about kind of some of the
nuanced differences of scaling out yeah
sure yeah it's an interesting project
for sure I mean I've been you know
involved in dealing with a lot of these
bigger greenhouses when I was doing
procurement and doing the designing and
equipment but now we came to a whole new
level where you know I'm involved in the
production side of things the actual
operations of the greenhouse and and
there's just a lot of moving parts I was
really surprised to see or I'm
fascinated by how many moving parts
there really are with these big
greenhouses and on the corporate side of
things whether it's a single best or a
big corporate group or whatever this
corporate really really slow there's
nothing that's fast about corporate
cannabis you know like on the smaller
scale we want something done we get it
done that you're the things that we talk
about in order to you know get stuff
done basically somebody that like I when
I purchased a greenhouse and it's no no
disrespect to the company but I actually
purchased the house because I was
purchased in Erik as part of the company
because what I wanted was I wanted the
troubleshooting support and I wanted
someone who was a conscientious about
trying to cut costs and keep
profitability high and not make
tremendous problems for the operator and
I think that that's the component that's
taken place when you make these
transitions from small to big is that
you're I always used to say the same
thing most people learn how to grow in a
closet and when they built a big
operation they just made that closet
module bigger and when you're talking
about these large operations the the
investor groups
to sink and say some of these ops you
know forty fifty million dollars so when
you when you've got forty million
dollars of someone else's money that
you're responsible for they they always
move slowly because they can't make
mistakes and come back for maybe damages
their reputations but it creates a
situation where they have to get people
that are competent at running operations
that are acre of level and above under
undercover and that's extremely rare for
the old cannabis industry there was
nobody running operations that big
period and so that's where these
problems are is that when I get brought
into jobs a lot of times it's just take
a look at the project and we realize
that the people that they brought in
were competent for you know five
thousand square feet but they're most
definitely not competent for three
hundred thousand square feet and that's
that's that's it that's a real problem
in the industry and that's why you're
seeing so many of these big ops fail it
isn't because anybody stupid it's that
the the the approach to it isn't
appropriate where the individuals who
are running the facility have to have a
cur level operational experience and
then the individuals that integrate how
you grow cannabis in terms of what the
market wants and how do we position it
price-wise and how do we position it in
its sale points there's this disconnect
between the three groups the commercial
operator who's used to run in tomato who
knows how to run a facility knows how to
run injections knows how to maintain
your your diff so that you're not having
environmental fluctuations the person
who knows herb and the cat that as the
money that process is not quick like it
used to be for us when we were in self
you know more self control and so when I
go into these operations to I trip out
because you think it's going to be a
quick decision but it's a long laborious
dragged-out process and there's only so
many guys like you know we use arrogance
and example cuz I respect shut up
there's only so many of them in the
industry where they have commercial
level knowledge but they understand
cannabis as a product yeah Kevin's
exactly right and that that's exactly
what I'm seeing a lot
is that yeah there's people that know
the shit out of cannabis but moving it
big scale and keeping it efficient
yeah the cost of production really goes
up as people start to try to bring in
original nutrients or programs that they
had before because now you're working it
a lot bigger commercial AG level and you
need basically what's happening is is
there's only a fraction of big
greenhouse guys that want to get into
cannabis and a lot of them that have
gotten into cannabis aren't really
interested in hanging out with the
cannabis people if that makes sense and
so we had a big disconnect where big AG
tried to come in that didn't know
cannabis lost their ass because they
didn't know the cannabis aspect and then
you have the cannabis people that didn't
have the big guys to help them along and
there's only a small fraction of big AG
guys that even want to be involved in
cannabis and make friends I guess with
the cannabis people so to speak and so
it's really a culture thing it's always
been a culture thing but now on this big
level there's also the culture of
cannabis people getting together with
the big AG people and everybody getting
along and having the same goals and you
know this this go-for-it approach we're
gonna win type a thing it really turns
into an ego battle of these guys know
this these guys know that nobody really
actually vibes together on these jobs
and so when you finally get the vibes
right and you have these big AG guys
that really love cannabis and really
love what they're doing and are really
interested in what you have to say a lot
of times whether you're right or wrong
they're open to the conversation you get
so many more things done and those are
the ones that are gonna make it
unfortunately like Kevin was saying
there's not a lot of those I can't
believe it I'm starting to really pay
attention to this more and I'm kind of
shocked at how many people are running
big stuff but aren't doing it from the
experience gag and running big
greenhouses it's it's it's it's kind of
surprising but at the same time if you
look at all the pot stocks and the way
Canada was going and these big you know
massive greenhouses how popular
extractions are and things like that a
lot of these people are getting
i but I mean the there bleeding out
pretty good and so you know we're
starting to see a lot of you know
especially up in Canada the bankruptcies
and different things moving to outdoor
you know it's like all of a sudden
everybody's gonna be a big outdoor
grower it it's like fact that's what we
started with you know and it's kind of
coming full circle now so I mean it's
really important to get these things
dialed in and work with the right people
and knowing who the right people are
that's the other thing it's just like
the consumers they don't all know what
good quality is and a lot of the people
that are involved in this don't know who
the good people are either because
there's so many people on LinkedIn and
all over the place that come off like
professionals but it's really hard to
vet people these days I mean I've been
lucky enough to been around the
community and knowing Kevin and Scott
and all these different people so we
actually do pull from each other from
time to time you know a lot of us will
reach out to each other and say you know
I got this situation who's the best
person to talk to about this and it
could be irrigation it could be genetics
it could be you know pinpointing one or
two things but we try to source and deal
with the best of the best in those
particular categories in order to make a
lot of these big things work totally I
don't I don't do consulting as as a
business so to speak because I have my
own businesses what what I do those I
get brought in by people have asked and
say hey can you come in and take a look
at this and then I try to figure out
where I see the the evident problems and
then I try to get the people together to
see where this friction and then I can
try to figure out from my you know pool
of professionals that I know in the
industry who might be someone that we
could bring in who might be looking for
a new career opportunity and it's it's
to create a success and the thing is
that when you're building an industry
everyone at first was so hyper
competitive that each person was going
to be the top of the food chain and but
he went huge they were gonna take over
the industry you know that the shit
kicked out of them which just makes me
fucking over
because what it does is it allows there
to be a pace of development that lets
stratification for all operators to fit
in where these mega operations they need
to succeed they need to satisfy the low
cross markets they need to satisfy
globalism and then it creates the
awareness of what small scale is because
you have a comparison and a lot of it is
just trying to you know source through
the industry that we know from being in
the industry and just saying hey this is
the right person for the job I know my
limitations and I'm not afraid to admit
them because that's not where I'm trying
to make my my win in the things that I'm
good at I try to be very good at them
and what I've seen so much is that
everyone lied through their fucking
teeth and no one told the truth about
their limitations and so these investors
are coming in to do business and they
get lied to by operators and you go into
these places and you're like who the
hell design this shit and you realize
that the direction was steered from the
initial wrong and what it does is it
makes all of us look stupid and that's
the problem is that it diminishes us as
cannabis operators because we all look
like we're charlatans so instead of
telling somebody that you know you're a
fucking virologist when really you know
how to use a pump sprayer it would it
would help because then you can actually
hire a virologist then you can guide the
investment and you can guide the project
and in the success of it you develop
your reputation you develop your success
but that's not what happened
men like this is a train wreck and it'll
clear itself up but some of the stuff
I've seen it's just crazy and it's the
teething of a new industry you know
whatever we did prior is irrelevant to a
couple years ago it really is this point
forward and it requires all of us to be
a little bit more honest about what
we're good at what we're not good at and
don't be ashamed to reach out for
assistance and and don't be afraid to
say look I know what I'm talking about
and that's just what it is can each of
you just give a couple that's the worst
so just quickly earth can each of you
give a couple kind of like bad news
bears uh things witnesses that you've
seen fairly frequently oh yeah yeah
actually Kevin who's designing these
things and that's one of my you know
starting points for the war stories is
like who thought this who designed it
and who said okay to all these things
because nine times out of ten when you
get in there with the cultivator or
somebody that knows what's up
the greenhouse facility isn't designed
for work and smarter not harder
basically and what it is is a lot of the
greenhouse companies design um the
builders that build them sell them and
design them and what I found is is
sometimes these guys will sprinkle in a
little bit of everything that they've
done it one of these jobs to make this
one masterpiece it's got a little a
little bell and whistle of all these
different little tricks and at the end
of the day we didn't need all those
bells and whistles or little tricks or
maybe we needed the whole trick and not
part of the trick you know and then and
we get into these situations where the
workflow isn't right you go who the fuck
thought of this and then that's like
well we went with this you know company
that's been designing greenhouses for 40
years but they've never grown anything
one time and all their knowledge for
growing comes from the people that have
grown in them before you know the other
vegetable growers and things like that
it's not the cannabis growers and
specific regions and states that you
know have these certain climates that
everybody's only grown primarily in the
summertime you know it's just a whole
different deal and that's where I kind
of get up you know a lot of calls or
situations in is like the designing and
the the the spending of the money it's
like that's the easy part and then they
gotta have somebody actually go grow it
and none of these guys in these big
scalable facilities were designed by
who's running it
like I haven't ran into one yet that is
designed by the guy that's running it
that guys usually gone before the
fucking shovels even you know the the
start the job and and how many times is
a cultivator asked to operate something
or use nutrients that they weren't
involved in
any of those decisions like Scott here
by the way I just got in sorry but a lot
of times we get brought into a facility
and a bunch of board room members
decided facility layout nutrient
considerations whether they're doing
Coco buckets what-have-you and then they
throw a cultivator in there and say all
right here's what we got for you go yeah
that that's the worst that's that's
probably more scent of cultivator though
the cultivators are going to say listen
you're you're putting me over a barrel
and I'm going to look like I'm an idiot
if I do this and you have to be able to
have faith in yourself to say I need to
leave the job and the problem is is that
you see the potential so greatly at
least from my experiences with when I
talk to the operators that are running
these projects that were created by five
or six people before them like the chain
of failure isn't just one person made a
mistake and everyone else pays you're
talking multiple CEOs that got canned
because they couldn't the investors can
the management group everyone that the
management group brought into canned and
a lot of times they can the guys that
was smart because they were
argumentative because they disagreed
with the approach and so the people that
had intelligence got weeded out people
that were basically able to tell a good
story remains they design assistants
don't lock up and then the cultivator
that's supposed to be that or run it
gets screwed but that's in life when
you're in a situation that doesn't pay
off for you it's best if you leave and
find another operation or what happens
is you struggle you fail you mostly get
wiped out because you want to succeed
and then you're attached to that
operation and that's part of it too like
my thing with cultivators is you need in
fact the owners the operators the
designers as much as you do the you that
you it's it's both you actually look at
each other or otherwise there's no way
you can do these projects it's not it's
not so simple but it's it's the way that
it's been laid out and I think that for
cultivators that I get hit a constant
saying hey I'm in this position and I
think it sucks and he said what do you
think I should do and I tell them tome
fuck off go get another job because if
they're gonna if they're gonna break
your balls over every detail that they
want you to execute that doesn't make
any sense because it's the motion that
they said in play that's ego and you
can't can't win they're so cultivators
with egos that won't listen can't win
CEOs investment groups with egos can't
win so think that's the pockets getting
cleaned out right now to where
eventually as we go forward you'll have
cannabis operators that have success in
operation being involved with the design
just like a good builder is involved
with the architect the architect creates
a project with the Builder who builds it
is part of the integration so we can say
look I see problems and that's the thing
is I see people making changes
constantly I don't see anything built
and then ran as built it gets completely
modified over and over and over by the
time you come in you just like you don't
understand what anybody's through and
salespeople a good man they're going off
on you go to LinkedIn anything you post
god help you but anything you post every
reply is someone trying to sell you a
product to go along with that thing
you're doing so the thing is you getting
bombarded non-stop with stuff how do you
even know what anyone's used and how do
you know where this success we don't
have a database you don't have a black
list you know it's it's tough so by the
way just quickly Scott the the guy who
ran the Carpinteria facility into the
ground is now the CEO of said company I
just found that that's amazing how are
they still in business that's what's
remarkable that gives me hope but to go
back to business go ahead yeah
but to go back to a point that Kevin
made that I think was really spot-on is
you know a lot of times we come into a
facility under you know unfortunate
circumstances trying to make them better
and a really common
we see is there's an investment group
that built what they believe to be a
state-of-the-art facility that's
actually maybe you know some range of a
pile of shit to moderately successful
and they don't want to admit that they
built a bad facility or they don't want
to admit that they made a wrong decision
or maybe they don't want to admit that
one of these sales people lied to them
so there's a lot of that ego factor that
really leads to prolonged failure and a
lot of times these facilities like Kevin
said they might you know they might have
a cultivator that ran a for lighter and
a lighter and they try and put a the
common patterns are you have investment
groups that maybe don't want to admit
that they made bad decisions along the
way that's leading to their failure or
they don't want to admit that they have
the wrong cultivator in position and
they just get really really married to
those things and just ride them off into
the ground and I would say you know
probably the top three reasons for
failure of a facility that we see our
investment group that doesn't want to
admit that they built the wrong building
admit they've got the wrong cultivator
or a cultivator that doesn't want to
admit that he doesn't have the skills
and doesn't seek the help needed to be
successful just write a couple of
specificity questions between the three
of you what percentage of the
greenhouses you're going into our
retrofit versus new state-of-the-art and
then when you're talking about the new
buildings that they build the wrong way
what are some common things that they do
that like examples of things they did
wrong even though it's a brand new
building you know earlier on when I
wasn't how I was listening to what you
guys were saying and you know at the
infancy of the market to be fair there
was a you know there's 50% snakes and
50% we just don't know like Kevin was
saying earlier we haven't gone this big
before and so there's a lot of guessing
or hoping or you know somebody
convincing you this is the path and it
turns out not to be appropriate at scale
and it doesn't work properly and yeah
well for me I end up in a lot of new
greenhouses but it's almost 50/50
sometimes because there's a lot of
retrofits that do go on but at the end
of the day a lot of the new stuff is
even basic hoops new PVC you know I mean
it's not always big massive fancy
greenhouses because people are scaling
up to ten thousand square feet or more
with PVC hoops and trying to do AG
exempt stuff and they're getting all new
plastics and new you know way of doing
things and so scaling up isn't always a
fancy you know state-of-the-art new
greenhouse these days it's it's a mixed
bag so to speak and so while there's a
lot of new there's still a lot of
retrofits going on and some of the
common mistakes are just things that for
workflow for contamination purposes you
know one of the things that we deal with
a lot and I don't want to speak for both
Kevin and Scott but I know we all deal
with it is the cross-contamination and
setting up a workflow so the people
aren't going backwards and it's really
easy to have a facility that causes
people to go from clone rooms the
flowering rooms are passed by the same
doors or the same areas sometimes and
they don't realize that some of that
stuff needs to be separated and some of
these massive facilities you know we try
to create people that only work in the
veg downes they don't go over to
flowering the propagation people stay in
the propagation when you you know tours
don't necessarily start out on the
flowering rooms and then end up in the
cloning rooms I mean which is most
common they're very common because I get
a lot I get toured around a lot and it's
you know people are starting to get the
hang of it a little bit but when it
comes to the design you know it makes
sense on paper if I was somebody that
just was looking at something cool on
paper I would say yeah that's beautiful
but if you don't take into the
considerations that we're thinking about
or the fallout that we've seen for some
of these reasons then you'd look at
these drawings and go this is crazy this
is like no way and so you know I don't
know what do you think Kevin I don't I
don't think I think
for me I see new facilities both small
AG exempt oops going in and they I think
they have less problems with those in
terms of integrating how you use it
because they they're more comfortable
with it
the newer facilities that I get to tour
they're you know state-of-the-art that
word gets thrown around but I mean these
things are impressive it's just that
they're way too sophisticated for an
average operator to understand and when
they laid it out they didn't lay out the
understanding that it's not normal
agriculture so you can't use chemical
spray models so if I chemically treat I
can I can control most all pathogen
problems but cannabis is so regulated
that it creates the situation where you
have to be hyper clean to the degree
that like when I show up in jobs and I'm
like you know you got to dress me and
they go no no we know who you are I'm
like I'm a fucking vector it doesn't
matter who I am like where's my
contamination shit the thing that I
noticed is that you know every
Investment Group has some attorneys on
the team so lawsuits aren't hard to file
when you're business partners a lawyer
and it really starts to create issues
where the the nurseries and even if it's
in-house nurseries it's your in-house
nursery you have to treat it like you're
going to get sued because you're going
to end up killing your own business but
for it you know while shooting er cereza
provide to the public the diligence they
have to put together to make sure
they're protected because there'll be no
forgiveness for the mistake because the
margins are so small that you can't make
it up and years past we could we could
make mistakes because we were all in the
learning curve and we all had a
different level of the ability to what
we could do because lack of legalization
changed our ability to actually put
together stable infrastructure but now
that all that's in play man it puts you
in a hell of honorable situation and I
think that's where the rise of the labs
are coming in where the the technology
to get around these issues with orchid
to get around it with banana to get
around it with strawberry
they had to go that route because they
couldn't control it any other way
they're going to transfer in our direct
and I just think that that's important
for nursery operators to understand that
the technology that's coming out to deal
with these issues is expensive and it's
not simple to do and you have to make
sure you're clear that that's going to
be the future that's coming so if you
make the decision to be a nursery
operator and you develop partnerships
with these groups or you become your own
laboratory based system but I think a
lot of the conventional agricultural
practices we had and how we function
prior are gonna change dramatically just
like socially with the coronavirus I
mean this shit just changed the world
and a it's really hard to convince these
facilities to make the decisions that
will help them ultimately that's that's
one of our biggest obstacles is you know
a lot of times so many other bad things
have happened that now when it's time to
make a call that will really really help
you it's hard to pull the trigger
well they've run the runways gun runways
that they've to fuck around already is
is is excessive and so by the time we
get called in the shit's hit the fan
more than once and that's part of the
problem that we run into is that you
know we're not always called in at the
design phase we're not always called in
when things are you know about to kick
off there's a few of them and you know
here and there but they're few and far
between and so what ends up happening is
that the shit hits the fan so many times
the runway of money's gone if they don't
make it this next six months or whatever
it's over with and so can they afford or
make the changes that are necessary at
this point and do they trust us because
they got PTSD right well the thing too
is it you know you don't you know you
don't want to spend any money if I have
to hear one more motherfucker tell me
they want to pick my mind I want to pick
your breath on to spend any money on the
initial but they will beg you to come in
and pull this shit out of a trench yeah
and I'm just like it's so much cheaper
did not make
the mistake but there's an arrogance and
I like I said I kind of like it I like
that the arrogance gets beat back
because it it let's there be a more
normality of the operators that are
coming in if everyone was so smart from
the onset there would be no rooms with a
small operator exactly that's how I see
myself still is a small operator and
that's where I want to be as a farmer I
never want to do large canopy for my own
production because it's not in line with
what I do but it doesn't change the fact
that I know that we have a need for the
larger operators it's just that there's
a humility period that's taking place
and you know and now you'll you'll be
able to come into these operations as
they move them and say hey look this is
a strategy let's work let's figure out
you know how do we move forward
correctly without putting ourselves into
a fucking graveyard and that's really
when I get brought in a lot is like you
guys are ready to die this I don't think
you're gonna recover the money and then
and and then the no one has any faith I
like I said I always look for the guy
that's got the huge bags under his eyes
and fucking retreat in the airline
because he's the guy with the money they
just want to be told the truth by
someone and everyone who's involved in
these big operations doesn't want to
lose their jobs nobody wants to miss out
on the big payday when it sells everyone
thinks it's gonna get sold for a fucking
billion dollars and everyone's gonna
dance in the money bucket you know and
it's it's a job you know you
it's farming and it's just so weird and
it's surreal to see it in person