[Music]
with the passage of AV 2020 raise your
hand if you've read a B 2020 from front
to back
oh my god we have Pam Epstein in the
house who's gonna be doing a legal deep
dive into temporary licenses cannabis
events something that captain happened
fairly often in 2017-2018 a lot of the
consumption events you all know and love
came to a screeching halt pans here to
explain why but to explain why things
are about to change and on our panel we
have a whole bunch of cannabis event
operators in the state of California so
I'm gonna turn it over to Pam she's
gonna do a little legal deep pot dive
with everyone and then I'm gonna do the
business side of running events with the
panel so Pam welcome everyone I think
it's interesting to set up the
conversations you're gonna hear from the
operators up here who have lived through
the challenges who have learned
throughout the implementation period of
what is now the Mau CRS a and have
persevered through that and are going to
kind of take us through that journey
through what living this ever-changing
legal landscape was with a lens on what
we have to look forward to in 2019 and
why it may seem like a small victory it
is going to be a watershed moment to get
us back to the events culture that
California was known for under prop 215
I'm so to set us up for that California
was one of the was the first date to
take decriminalize action in 1996 with
The Compassionate Use Act that then
became the medical marijuana program
with SB 420
that gave you the cooperative collective
model in the 2008 attorney general
guidelines and we lived under that
system for quite a long period of time
until late 2015
when there was a trio of bills
interesting to note there were over I
think 80 legislative bills this past
session so we've come a long way and
that gave us mersa
which then gave birth to what statutory
structure we currently have and under
that structure predating that structure
under the 215 model you would simply
have an event and you would check
recommendations patient recommendations
and you would have brands that showed up
because they were properly forms
collectives and people would join the
collectives and they were able to have
this robust interaction with cannabis
and the operators and the manufacturers
that were truly engaged in this process
what happened when we had infrastructure
come into play is you had the creation
by one of the three regulatory agencies
the Bureau of cannabis control developed
an event organiser licensee and special
event licenses and when the ma us and
when the ma UC RSA came into effect it
said a very specific precedent about
where these events were allowed to be
located they were allowed to be located
on agriculture agricultural associations
in County Fairgrounds district
agricultural associations there are 58
throughout the state and they are state
agencies however the state agency these
are like little state agencies are
housed within other jurisdictions and
because when we had Mandy ma you see RSA
come into effect you had to have local
authorization local authorization was
given to you by a local jurisdiction
that was defined as a city county or
city and county and that did not include
a district agricultural Association so
as these event organizers went to go get
their license and
and engage in a compliant activity they
went to where you naturally think that
you would go as you are a state agency
and we'll hear I'm sure about the trials
and tribulations with chalice I in fact
worked with the 28 CAA
because they believed that they had the
jurisdictional control over their
borders to regulate what events took
place there that's an important
distinction right you would think that
they don't pay city tax they get all of
their permits from the state that now
all of the sudden where you are located
where this district agricultural
Association is located and it's in the
name they serve a larger district they
serve everybody in the state of
California to the means of granting them
access to agricultural activity we are
in fact in cannabis and agricultural
product right so this is in the
wheelhouse of what these district
agricultural associations are used to
doing they put on events they have
liquor licenses they don't go to the
jurisdiction at any other point to ask
for permission and why is this so
critical because you may have a
favorable DAA who has had positive
experiences with cannabis operators that
then have to go and ask a city for
permission and that city may be
unfavorable to cannabis and that then
creates a conflict that was unresolvable
until we got to a be a year 2020 so an
event organizer goes they go through the
disclosure process they get their
license and then they have to go and get
that event license that temporary event
allowance that's when we run in to the
problems at the fairgrounds and moving
forward as we talked about 2020 gives
you the right gives these operators the
right to be able to hold events not on
das or County Fairgrounds but anywhere
where they can get local authority in
local authorization at first that seems
like you're going to be able to have an
event anywhere
what this does is it allows for events
to take place not at those two specific
locations by you have to gain permission
to do so and once you give the right to
regulate you will see cities and
counties stepping up and wanting to
regulate so what does that mean are you
going to have to get some sort of permit
we hope so what I always advise and what
I know that these operators will likely
do is to go to those cities with a
request know what kind of event you want
to have know where you want to have that
event know whether or not there is
alcohol that's going to be served at
that event because that is a critical
component of the events culture that is
going to continue to experience pain
points is how do you have an event where
you have two substances that are heavily
controlled and we've seen the state and
the governor take a very specific
position a that you cannot infuse
cannabis to the with any alcohol more to
the point than that the regulations
flushed out that you cannot even have
the alkalized beer or wine or anything
that we confuse the consumer so you can
see that we're gonna have strategic pain
points to learn how to navigate between
having a premise and what that premise
means and whether or not you're at a
facility that serves alcohol and whether
or not that facility could potentially
be jeopardizing their liquor license or
their insurance policies or any other
business license that they currently
have so what is the difference you may
be thinking between a consumption event
and a event that you can consume out
where you can also purchase cannabis
does that sort of also what we're
talking about where we've seen in the
last year to two years these pop up
events that occur where you see vendors
that are there that are exchanging
products if that product has not gone
through a retailer if that event
is taking place in a non private
residence even then with track and trace
coming online you're not going to be
able to hold those events those are
non-compliant events California says
there is no or the city of Los Angeles
says there is no consumption right they
do not have time yet to regulate this so
there are no consumption lounges that
are regulated there are no consumption
on site with a dispensary these are
things that need to be flushed out in
Southern California the only people that
are the only city jurisdiction is moving
in that direction is the City of West
Hollywood and they are issuing specific
consumption licenses and dispensaries
that are allowed to consume on-site and
sell so you can see the more they they
have the bandwidth to regulate these
jurisdictions will start to do so and
they will regulate events in the same
manner and practice these West Hollywood
is looking at the events issue now that
they want to get ahead of it because
they are a progressive city other cities
you're gonna see in Southern California
move much faster unfortunately than the
city of Los Angeles will be out in the
desert where you're gonna see Coachella
Palm Springs Desert Hot Springs they're
all gonna issue events up north you're
gonna see this play out much quicker as
Oakland and Sacramento already have said
we're just gonna process events in the
same in similar fashion I know Davis the
city of Davis is also very much looking
into that so if you want to support
these event organizers I say please be
responsible when you're at the events
these is you know we're learning to walk
crawl run it out here in California and
as we want to develop the ability to
curate events where you're gonna be able
to see demonstrations of cannabis
products being made and then ingest them
without having to have final form
product through the Quality Assurance
and quality control mechanisms that we
have the best way to do that is to
be a compliant attendee at these events
so it would ask you to do that and
really listen and support these
operators as they tell you how they
Traverse these very Tremmel tourist
waters over the last two years
[Music]