today we're going to expand on the
concept of cultural control that we
briefly covered in our first webinar on
the 10 cardinal parameters of plant
health and vitality
and take a deep dive on ipm and imm
cultural control is environmental
control and it's the foundation of any
comprehensive ipm plan to manage the
pests and microbes present in your
cultivation space
it is also the oldest ipm method but was
largely abandoned with the advent of
chemical pesticides
the bioecology of the indoor garden was
not well understood
creating inconsistent results chemical
pesticides offered a more reliable
and less knowledge and skill dependent
solution
but as consumers desires for clean
pesticide-free cannabis increase
and the toxicity of pesticides becomes
further scrutinized by regulators and a
scourge on the environment
there is renewed interest in cultural
control
only recently has the pathogen host
environment relationship been understood
well enough to harness the power of
cultural control
to boost secondary metabolite and
biomass production
it also serves as a potent risk
reduction technique to prevent pests and
pathogens and allows cultivators to
produce consistent clean cannabis
cycle after cycle without the use of
harmful chemicals
just a quick note from the legal
department due to the federal illegality
of cannabis and the variability in
by state laws we cannot make specific
product
recommendations for your ipm plan
i'll pass it over to jesse to kick us
off
right on thanks brian
appreciate it and thanks everyone for
tuning in on this topic
i'll be honest it's one of the main
reasons i'm so passionate about
cultivating cannabis when my mom was
diagnosed with cancer
it was about trying to find her the best
and strongest possible medicine we could
we went everywhere we hit every
dispensary every medical outlet
and we purchased products that had mold
and mildew we purchased products that
didn't burn right
purchase products that were clearly
sprayed with pesticides
i remember one one time i was smoking
with my mom in the backyard and she
turned to me and she said oh
this one's a sparkler snap crackle
pop the bud was doing things it
shouldn't have
indicating that it had been sprayed with
something heavy metals
sulfur something along those lines for
me i immediately realized
the importance of integrated pest
management
and it's a controversial topic there's
personal choices
business choices and legal parameters
but when i had my hydro shop
oakland garden supply we encouraged
people to bring in leaves and media in a
bag
we put things under the scope and we'd
look at them we learned a lot
and the two questions i got more than
anything else were
what is this and how do i kill it
and my answer was usually are you sure
you want to kill it
and what are we doing to prevent it
as a result we became amateur
entomologists
microbiologists and chemists all in a
trial by fire
people would come in and want a solution
directly given to them within 10 minutes
and then we would have to look them in
the eye the next day
and talk about how effective it was so
the idea behind this webinar
was really to present the
tools and share some of the experiences
that i think will further the discussion
on ipm
and imm for cannabis so what is
integrated pest management
it's about dealing with and living with
and managing pest
same with imm integrated microbe
management
treat them the same way and i think it
probably seems like an
oversimplification
but the truth is i've used this triangle
and this
book to develop hundreds of successful
ipm and imm
plans for gardens the triangle on the
left
illustrates the progression from
prevention to intervention
it starts with cultural control that's
the foundation of ipm
cultural control is about creating an
environment where plants thrive
and bag bugs don't and it's the only
non-invasive option
then we move to physical control which
is about
traps barriers and the physical removal
of pests
then on to biological control which is
about deploying beneficial insects and
good microbes to work on your behalf to
eradicate pests
and then finally to chemical control the
application of items
toxic to pests that don't kill the plant
the reason i love this book hemp
diseases and pests
management and biological control is
because it allows you to look up a pest
and understand the progression that you
need to take in order to eradicate it
but it's important to know the tools of
the trade
when we really think about fighting
pests and pathogens
it's important to start with good
genetics i mean i think this is one of
the reasons why so many people
grew blue dream initially it's a great
yielder
it's hard to kill even when it's covered
with mites
but that's really not enough we need to
understand that
growing healthy plants is a science and
these tools are going to help you refine
the process
it starts with some sort of lighting
meter something to determine the energy
that's coming into the space
lighting infrared uv they're all
important
then you need to think about the
temperature and humidity of the ambient
space
you need to think about some sort of
tool to measure
leaf temperature whether it's a camera
or an ir gun
so you can manage vpd your vapor
pressure deficit
then you should think about measuring
the gases in the space specifically co2
you'll need some sort of microscope to
take a close look at bugs
eggs and leaves sometimes you can even
get away with a camera
a microscope app then you need some sort
of water activity meter
to determine whether or not your product
is safe for final packaging
and lastly one tool that i like to use
is a refractometer
which essentially measures bricks in the
plant and this is a trick i learned from
commercial gardens
that grow grapes in northern california
which is if you can get your brix level
above 12
it's going to be really hard for bugs to
eat your plants
so the healthier plants we grow the less
susceptible they are
to pests and pathogens
but it's also about creating the right
culture in this case
creating a clean environment it's
important to clean the garden space in
between runs
something like hydrogen peroxide or
gases like
ozone that really get into the nooks and
crannies will help you eliminate the
pest vectors
it's also important to remember to do
this when the plants
aren't in the room because some of these
products can have a detrimental effect
on the secondary metabolites
also you need to clean filters fans
fertigation lines and those
wild condensate lines who knows what's
in there you need to clean them
clean the plant debris from the space
from defoliation
dispose of that properly and also i
think a lot of people know this but
quarantine your plants but also
quarantine your media
as it enters the facility i like to
treat every plant
and every media that comes into my
facility as if it were infected
and deal with it appropriately then
i think something that we've all gotten
a lot more used to recently
is that people carry pests we have ten
thousand microbes on each hand
and we shell forty thousand micro
or forty thousand skin cells every
single minute so sops are important
wear gloves wear hair nets also
think about cleaning the ancillary
spaces like the bathroom
employees use the bathroom they go in
they play with their phone
then they wash their hands but when they
leave the bathroom what's on their feet
what's on their pants are they bringing
pathogens into the space
think about the hallways the mop sink
these are all
vectors and they either need to be
cleaned with technology
or with elbow grease also
think about cleaning the water the water
that comes into the facility is usually
not the biggest obstacle it's the
recycled water
it's about standing water and making
sure that standing water is
treated appropriately aerated because if
it's not
it's going to develop water molds that
are systemic and you'll feed them
directly to your plants
so another way to remember it is start
clean
stay clean finish strong
so now that we have a culture of clean
let's talk about a culture of success
and that starts with scouting with a
microscope
getting positive identification taking
appropriate action
and evaluating it's a continuous cycle
keep a log of the pests keep a log of
the conditions
the fertigation the water into the space
all these things are important when you
think about
historical trends and how you're gonna
eradicate pests for the long haul
speaking more about positive
identification this is
so important to winning the war against
the pests to threaten you
there's an entomologist that i love her
work and i love what she has to say
suzanne wainwright evans
she's when she decides to publish
her photo book on positive
identification
i would spend whatever it costs to get
that book because
positive identification is critical like
i said to a lot of people looking at
this slide they might think man look at
all those bad bugs
but they're not all bad bugs sure the
majority of them are
but a cautious story i worked at a
facility in oakland that was an outdoor
facility and i came into work one day
and there was a petri dish filled with
larva and a note that said
jesse please kill these bugs as fast as
possible
and i sighed i picked up the petri dish
i
opened it up i walked outside and i
sprinkled the ladybug larva
all over the plants it was a
inappropriate identification of a pest
so it's critical that you know good bugs
and bad bugs
otherwise you'll be trying to kill all
the guys that are trying to help you
fight the war
positive identification of microbes is
also important this is a chance to bring
in a microbiologist to talk about
which microbes are good and which
microbes are bad which microbes you have
in your compost tea which microbes you
have in your space
they can take samples and they can give
you a really good idea of what you're
working with
but furthermore get to know your shapes
and structures
once you start to know this you can
really do an amateur
evaluation and identification under a
microscope
another story of caution here when it
comes to positive identification is i
had a friend who had a 500 light
facility
and he said hey jesse one of my rooms we
had catastrophic loss in week four
everything just died because of rude
aphids please come
assess the situation and tell me how to
kill the rude aphids
i went to the facility i looked through
the media i dug through the root zone
i looked at every plant i possibly could
i couldn't find larvae i couldn't find
eggs
maybe i found some fungus gnats but i
sure didn't find root aphids
and then it hit me you have pythium i
could see it on the stalks of the plant
so i said let's go look at your water
source so we immediately went to his
water source which is a 250 gallon tank
outside of the room
that wasn't aerated wasn't treated with
uv wasn't treated with anything
and i could see the black mold growing
on top of the water surface
and what i said was all right you're
feeding your plants pythium and they're
gonna die
you're feeding them a systemic water
mold that's going to kill them
that's the problem not root aphids so
all the effort
all the time and all the money you spent
trying to kill root aphids that weren't
there
were just simply not effective positive
identification
is critical
so when it comes to positive id let's
assume for a second that we've made one
we have mites and we have powdery mildew
but witch mites
are they carmine mites are they russet
mites are they broad mites
in this case we have a picture of two
spotted mites
and powdery mildew so now that we know
who our enemy is let's learn everything
we can about them
do every bit of research you can consult
the hemp disease book
look at everything you can possibly read
to understand
how these things grow and live so a
little bit on powdery mildew we know
that it thrives in low light conditions
with poor air circulation and excess
nitrogen we know it's spread
by the air and we know that it's spread
faster in high humidity environments
and we also know that it's all around us
spider mites right we know they feed on
these particular two spotted spider
mites feed on chlorophyll-rich plants
the females lay 200 eggs every eight
days
they prefer hot and dry conditions cold
temperatures cause hibernation
and the light cycle is going to impact
their action so this gives us the things
that we need to know
what are the pests susceptible to how do
they feed
how do they breed how do they move where
they hide
and how do we pierce their armor
well the first step is understanding how
we prevent this infestation in the first
place
so we need to understand cultural
control again
for any pest it's about creating an
environment where they can't thrive
so how do we do that well
at inspire we model every room so we
know where the air flows so we can
create the right pressures
we remove oscillating fans and pocket
dehumidifiers so they don't create
microclimates or become the source of
pests then it's about air cycling
every three minutes we try to cycle
through multi-stage
filtration first through a merv 13
capture filter
which gets everything down to about one
micron then through a photocatalytic
oxidation process
which is essentially uv light shining on
titanium dioxide which creates hydroxyl
radicals
that function like a molecular shredder
then
in-rack airflow will continue the
airflow cycle by delivering the co2 rich
conditioned air
without radical oxidative species
directly to the plant stomata
to break up the canopy which further
eliminates microclimates
and lastly it's about control control of
the temperature
control of the humidity when the lights
are on
when the lights are off and during the
transitions
swings in temperature and humidity
create an environment for powdery mildew
to take hold
and precision control will allow you to
manage your vpd
your vapor pressure deficit at every
stage of the plant growth
which will help mitigate the risk of
powdery mildew
it's also important to note
understanding light penetration
temperature humidity air flow nutrient
dilution
watering rate they all play a big role
in the formation and spread of powdering
mildew
so get control of your culture
and powdering mildew won't affect the
bottom line
don't get control and you'll need to
prepare for a war
every single flower run
so what's the next type of control it's
physical control
what could we have done physically to
prevent the spread of this
well first let's check the air pressures
and make sure that we have a positively
pressured space
let's check the sops and make sure that
everyone is wearing gloves when they
handle the plants
we want to make sure that your master
gardener isn't playing with their
pitbull before they come into the shop
and we want to make sure that house
flies aren't entering either
who knows where your pit bull was last
night and spider mites can
hit your ride on the back of house flies
and get into your facility
so it's not the flies that are the
problem but they are the vector
so what's the solution amputate
and remove leaves at the initiation of
outbreak
we had mentioned two spotted spider
mites lay 200 eggs
every 8 days so by removing those leaves
we can remove a significant amount of
eggs sometimes a lot more than 200
but again be careful because if we
remove too many leaves that's going to
affect the plant's vitality
the next stage of control is biological
control which really deals with the
three p's
predators parasites and pathogens
this is another opportunity to bring an
entomologist to the party
but the resources are out there it makes
me think of my friend
charlie mckenzie and the cropwalk team
who does an ipm audit
they'll walk your facility tell you what
bio biologicals would help you
win the war and in this case we have two
spotted spider mites so we might choose
californicus
and persimilis they both work a little
bit differently they're a little bit
different
different sizes but they're both going
to eat mites and eggs
and it's important to know because if we
think we're going to bring
rove beetles in here then they're going
to live in the media
and not on the leaf tissue and not be
quite as effective for what we need
and then we can think about biological
control with microbes
it's a chance for you to bring a
microbiologist to the party to talk
about
which microbes are going to thrive in
our space how we're going to get these
microbes is it teas
is it ferments is it purchasing
individual microbes
and if you take a close look at this
slide you can see
we might choose bacillus pamilis which
is a fungicide bacillus subtilis which
eats powdery mildew streptomyces
trichoderma there's a lot of choices
here
that we can apply apply from a
biological standpoint
to eradicate the threats of powdery
mildew there are also
beneficial bacteria that consume eggs
and
ward off bugs so it's it's a real option
for you but it takes an understanding
of microbiology to deploy
then the next step is chemical control
so
this is the chance for you to bring
another is to the party
a chemist and this chemist is going to
tell us what's in every bottle
and how it works and how it affects the
plant
there's a lot of tough decisions to make
here are we going to go with
biorational insecticides are we going to
go with
synthetic insecticides there
essentially are two main camps when you
really break it down the long-term
prevention and eradication of pests fall
into
the oils and soaps category or the
sulfur category
and one of the major reasons we
differentiate the two
is because we can't apply them both at
the same time
it's not a matter of just going into the
ipm cupboard
grabbing a bottle and applying it we
need to know how these things work
as a synergy if we apply oils then we
really can't apply
sulfur within the next 14 days or we'll
burn
our plants so it's an important
consideration the chemistry the makeup
and how they impact the plant
alright so which path do we choose
this is where it becomes a personal and
business decision and it gets really
tricky
this is really about understanding the
interaction between
technology the farmer the market
and enforcement there are a lot of
things at play when determining the
appropriate ipm strategy for your
cultivation facility
it's a delicate balance of risk and
reward but it's also a personal choice
that will affect the business bottom
line
so legality and this is something that
brian mentioned earlier
federally illegal it becomes a gray area
when deciding which
which pesticides and which biological
control methodologies to deploy
federally there are no guidelines state
by state
there are varying guidelines so it's
important to know in your state
what you can and can't use and that's
important because
testing is the enforcement arm
so we need to know what's going to show
up on a test
how it's going to show up and what's the
cost of that
so if you use a substance you shouldn't
or you use a substance that's allowed
but you use it at the wrong
time it will show up as a fail
for residual pesticides and that will be
a compromise to the end product
and it will be a compromise to the brand
it's
often very hard to recover from
something like this
and next in making this decision it's
about understanding the factors of
influence
and i think a lot of times when we think
about factors of influence we think
about doing a cost benefit analysis
how does this system make sense for us
where is the risk where is the reward
what are the costs so it's about taking
the historic ipm triangle
and incorporating it into your business
plan for long-term success
understanding the modes of action how
things work
understanding the environmental
considerations how do they work in your
space and how do they affect the spaces
outside of yours what are the
application guidelines
what's the dilution rate how much does
it cost to use it what are the timelines
for
efficacy what are the timelines for your
needs what are the stages of development
that you're encountering with your
particular pest
what's the systemic acquired response
how are the plants going to respond to
this
can we prep them for a threat and what
are the synergies
how do these things work together and
i'll try and go through them really
quickly
so modes of action there are a lot of
different modes of action and there are
good resources out there that break them
down in even more detail
but essentially we're talking about how
are we going to physically kill the bugs
are we going to dehydrate them
are we going to suffocate them are we
going to get them to eat something
that kills them from the inside are we
going to affect their nervous system
by either over activating them or
slowing their development
are we going to prevent them from
molting are we going to prevent them
from developing into the next stage
and also i think there's a great picture
here in the lower right corner
that if you've read jeff lowenfeld's
book teaming with microbes or
studied with dr elaine ingham you'll
know that this is a fungal hyphy
that is strangling a root-feeding
nematode
pretty cool mode of action in my book
then you have the environmental
considerations just like i mentioned
all the ipm and imm decisions you make
will either
impact the environment or will be
impacted by the environment
your brand might be more well received
if you choose the least toxic path
but the application environment like
temperature humidity and airflow can
have a dramatic
impact on management efficacy if you're
playing the microbe and biological angle
think about creating environmental
conditions for them to thrive
beneficials need habitat they need a
food source they need appropriate
temperatures in day and night
so that they can breed and they can
establish for the long haul
also think about environmental
considerations for chemists
the chemistry you might use for example
sulfur
is going to be much more effective in a
high humidity environment
when the temperatures are below 80
degrees in a dry and hot environment
you apply sulfur you will burn the
plants
then you have to think about application
guidelines
how do i apply this product is it a dust
do i spray it on the leaves do i dose it
in line
where do i deploy the sachets of insects
what's the personal protective equipment
i need for this application
what's the dilution rate per acre per
canopy
per plant the math can get confusing
when do i apply it
where do i apply it in the root zone the
undersides of the leaves the tops of the
leaves
well for mites we know we need to focus
on the undersides of the leaves and for
pm it's going to be
all over the plant but important
considerations
timelines timelines are of utmost
importance as well
for reapplication for toxicity toxicity
to the bug toxicity to the plant
we need to understand the time that it
takes the fungal hyphae to develop so it
can strangle that root feeding nematode
we need to understand how long it takes
resistance to occur
in the bug we need to understand that so
we know when to rotate
the modes of action we need to
understand
how long it takes the plant to build up
defenses
so we're building up the defenses to the
utmost capability
before these threats come we need to
understand
how long it takes these applications to
be effective
how long does it take them to work how
long before we judge whether that
application was or wasn't effective
what's the half-life how long does it
work for
and what's the re-entry period for
worker safety
how long do we have to wait before we
can go back into the space and start
growing
another factor of influence is thinking
about the stages of development
first the stage of development of the
plant then the stage of development of
the pest
we want to kill all stages of the pest
development
while considering all stages of the
growth
so for something like our two spotted
mites we're going to want an
obicide a larvicide a pupicide
and an adulticide we want to kill them
at every stage
for the powdery mildew we want to think
about something that's going to deal
with the pustules
the spores and the fruiting bodies
important to consider
all of those factors and deploy
different mode of actions
varied at different timelines to be most
effective
something to think about sulfur is going
to kill powdery mildew and mites
really well but when you get into late
stage flour
if you spray your skittles with sulfur
they're gonna turn into rotten eggs
so it's important to understand the
stage of development
the application and its impact on the
final product
then we get to systemic acquired
response and this is essentially getting
the plant to fight back
for you it has natural defenses and with
hormones
acids enzymes and microbes we can
trigger the plant's natural responses
i love salicylic acid it's a product
that you can apply to your plant
to get it more tertiare to get it more
rigid to have the plant be
very strong and very hard to eat from a
leaf tissue and a root zone perspective
also i love to apply seaweed or kelp
and one of the main reasons for that
outside of the fact that i love to eat
seaweed
is it's filled with beneficial hormones
in a very balanced application
cytokinins auxins and jaberlins will all
help the plant
trigger its natural defense mechanism
and
fight off this plant so in reality or
fight off this pest in reality what
we're trying to do
is uh uh prepare the plant for war
at all times and allow the plant to
defend itself naturally
and then that brings us to synergies and
this is about
how the choices that you make interact
with each other
how do they inner fat interact with the
microbes the beneficials how do the
chemicals
kill beneficials how do they kill the
bad guy how do they affect the plant
and again synergies sulfurs and oils
right we can't spray them at the same
time
otherwise we will burn their plant how
do your choices
interact with your personal
consciousness and how do they
impact the bottom line efficacy
price point branding and the final
product
at the end of the day what i usually say
is your ipm
and imm strategy will have a tremendous
impact on how your plant grows
every ipm and imm choice you make has an
impact on the pest the plant and the
environment
the more that you can prevent the less
you'll have to intervene
and accept the negative impacts physical
biological and chemical control can have
on plant vitality
yield and quality of your finished
flowers and extracts
i like to say control your culture or it
will control you
and what i mean by that is that a lack
of control
will necessitate consistent intervention
and leads to inconsistent results
physical biological and chemical
control require training and
misapplications do happen
sometimes with disastrous results
whereas proper cultural control has no
negative
impacts on the plant it will never burn
your plant and it synergizes with every
aspect of your cultivation operation
cultural control is environmental
control
it's the foundation of any ipm and imm
strategy
and the key to consistent high quality
harvest
if you don't have good environmental
control you will always be battling
pests
and you will never know how many grams
per square foot
or hundreds of dollars per pound it is
costing you
and with that i'd love to sort of jump
into some q a i tried to go through that
pretty quick so we could tackle some
real world questions which
we saw a lot of come in before the
webinar as well uh
first question here from ben uh you
didn't answer how i kill
pm and mites uh
yeah that's a great question ben and i
appreciate that and it's something that
um i think definitely takes a
conversation with the individual
gardener
on making the appropriate approach but
let me put it this way
it starts with cultural control you need
to have a clean space
and then the progression goes something
like this right
we need to get cultural control so we
can prevent this from happening in the
future we need to get cultural control
so the applications that we take
are most effective for me i like to
start with
if there's an outbreak immediately go to
physical control remove the leaves
that you see being hot spots for
possible
vectors contamination and spread and
then it's about building this castle
cell wall with microbiology
i had mentioned a handful of beneficial
fungi and bacteria that work against
powder and mildew and may work against
mites in the space
but my feeling is it's all about
diversity let's throw
every beneficial microbe we can at this
plant and see how she responds
let's give her every tool in the toolbox
we don't know enough about microbiology
and plants for me to say
this is the answer instead i say think
about teas
ferments read some good books that are
challenging
challenging what we know and allowing us
to really dive into
different microbiological answers then
it comes to to an actual deployment of
beneficial insects right
so in this particular case like
let's bring insects to the party but
what if we're indoors
maybe that's not an option like i don't
want to burn a bunch of ladybugs and i
don't want to clean up a bunch of dead
carcasses so
same time i'm thinking give me diversity
give me as many beneficials as i can
let's get them in the root zone maybe
they're not a direct
impact on that spider mite but they're
going to help us
you know uh soil mites or rove beetles
beneficial nematodes get them all to the
party
so they can try and work for you 24
hours a day the entire time before we
have to get to chemical
and then when it comes to chemical i
sort of
tend to find myself in the oils and
soaps category a lot so
i think about some sort of extract that
might affect
the mites as a nerve toxin something
like pyrethrin
derived from chrysanthemum i would mix
that with an oil
that would suffocate maybe another oil
or an extract that would prevent
breeding
prevent feeding and and prevent the
larval development
so something like neem then we need
something that's going to mix those
things together and make them more
effective as an application so a
surfactant like soap
and then i like a penetrant i love
penetrants to kill eggs whether it's
citric acid
or alcohol or something of that nature
now when we think about what we just
went over
oils soaps and alcohols those are also
really effective against powdery mildew
so that's a pretty good synergistic
first pass of hey
that's an application that's going to
kill both of these things
it needs to be done appropriately with
the appropriate dilutions
at the appropriate timelines with the
appropriate environmental conditions
but they are absolutely effective and
for me
it's really about understanding what the
ultimate goal is to get great flower
so if we can get environmental control
we can do
preventative applications during the
vegetative process build the castle cell
wall
and then in the first two weeks of
flower
take action if we need to from a
chemical perspective
and then kick back and let those plants
develop without additional foliar
applications that degrade our product
and compromise our quality in the end so
sort of my approach there yeah thanks
jesse that makes a lot of sense it seems
like um
that ipm triangle has been sort of
flipped on its head
uh over the last few decades or
so and people start with chemical
control but
it should be really reversed and started
with chemical control first as a
preventer
excuse me cultural control first as a
prevention method and i think we're
we're still
discovering right when i had my hydro
shop everyone just wanted to come in and
buy a poison
and i would say like hey think about
talking to the beneficial insectary
and seeing what they have available talk
to dragonfly earth
talk to mammoth p they make microbes
research dr elaine ingham
look at the soil food web take a look at
korean natural farming and one straw
revolution
look into these other methodologies that
are historically viable and have worked
for hundreds of years in other locations
understand what's working for them and
incorporate that because it's so much
more cost effective
with so much less degradation to your
product if you can take that
that approach of prevention before the
intervention
yeah yeah sort of a line of last resort
with uh with the chemicals um
an interesting question sort of
parlaying on the on the concept of
of microbes and microbiology and pests
uh from anders
um he's saying some growers seem to be
taking a sterile cleanroom approach to
ipm
whereas others are utilizing natural
defenses like biologics and beneficials
do you think a hybrid approach of the
two methodologies is achievable while
being practical in day-to-day workflow
and cost-effective in terms of
production costs
or do you think this approach will
lessen the efficacies of both schools of
thought
that's a great question that's a great
question
and what i usually say is that every
facility i've ever been into has pests
and there are cultivators out there that
will attest to me walking to their
facility and them saying hey man
this room's really clean me flipping
over a bug
and or flipping over a plant and saying
but what about these eggs
what are these guys so in short what i
would say is it's really really hard to
have a perfectly sterile environment
um and then on the flip side of that
there's there's a benefit to sterility
you know and i'm a big fan of trying to
be as clean as possible
i think what happens is you get these
two schools of thought and they think
that they're diametrically opposed
and the reality is is that yes so many
chemical applications whether it's
hydrogen peroxide
and acetic acid with xeritol or some
sort of
other spray like sulfur which is going
to kill our beneficials
are not going to work with the
microbiology
and that's true and i used to say this
all the time too encouraging people
that were using synthetic nutrients in
their feeding schedule
to incorporate compost teas look those
synthetic nutrients
some of these chemical poisons and
toxins will kill
microbes but the strong will survive so
if we kill
60 percent of the microbes with our
sterile approach we still have 40
of the microbes that don't care about
what you're throwing at them
so for me yeah i mean there's there is a
marriage in there somewhere that allows
for
realistic application of you know
a sterile environment and what it takes
to do that while at the same time
embracing microbiology and beneficials
so there's a cost and benefit there but
yes i think it's viable to blend the two
of them
um i think the more momentum you can
build
with microbiology and beneficials
the better that momentum is what's going
to carry you through those last four
weeks of flower
and if you need to you can apply some of
these chemicals sterile
approaches but don't be afraid to mix
the two see see who survives and who the
strongest ones are
you know if pathogen pressures are
cumulative does it make sense to
do as much as you can all the way
through the cycle
right you know we we go into rooms where
they've got the pads full of alcohol
or whatever some other paralyzing
media that you step in before you walk
in we see people gown up
i've seen that on smaller room grows
it can be a real hassle in terms of
workflow if you're going from one room
to another
and the the movement is uh the duration
in a room is short
then it is really gonna hamper your
workflow but
when we go to large greenhouses for
example they're gonna be in this
bay for two hours or three hours at a
time
um you know what's that break-even point
is do we do is there a breaking point
we've noticed
in the facilities we've been in or
should we just be doing it all over the
place
well i think again it's sort of going
back and referencing that triangle right
it's about starting with a culture of
clean and what does it take to get that
culture of clean and make decisions that
are appropriate for that
but then when it comes to plant health
it's important to think about
the stages of physical biological and
then
chemical so just because you're trying
to create a clean
environment doesn't necessarily mean you
have to
exclude beneficials we are trying to
create an environment that doesn't have
bad pests and pathogens no pythium no
botrytis
no powdery mildew no asparalis but those
are not the beneficials we're bringing
in
so for me it's like let's bring in some
beneficials that work on our behalf
let's try and keep the room as sterile
and clean as possible in between the
rums
gas the room to make sure that we don't
have that vector
but at the same time if you think that
you're going to
skip those first three steps of cultural
physical and biological control
it will be very expensive to continue to
apply
the right chemicals and the right
processes to make sure that you have a
sterile environment
and in the end you're probably not going
to achieve it
it's so rare that i've walked into a
facility and i thought man it's going to
be hard for me to find a pest here
it's usually i just walk walk in and go
to the mop sink or go to the bathroom
or go to the doorknob and just like hey
let's do a swab send this off to the lab
see what comes back and people are
shocked
yeah i mean pests are one thing
maybe there's a way to keep them all out
but you
talk about microscopic microbes and the
fact that
we're shedding microbes off of our skin
at such a high rate
i don't i don't have a scary thought
right it's crazy it's crazy to think
about i just i don't see how there'd be
any way
to really create an entirely sterile
environment
so to me it makes a lot of sense to
foster the good microbes
and the beneficial pests potentially
because
i just it just seems like an impossible
thing to achieve
and i'll say this though i've seen a lot
of automation developments in automation
where we're trying to get more people
out of that space
more items out of that space more
vectors out of that space so instead of
having someone come in that's wearing
gloves and a tyvek suit that's four
inches too short on the arm
and every time they brush against the
leaf they bring on whatever's on their
arm
you know now we're trying to get to the
point where it's like should we automate
this completely should we have
sensors and cameras in the room telling
us what
pests are there or where we have an
issue in the canopy that looks different
than the rest of the
the canopy right and we have you know
basically a
running set of you know mechanical
scissors that come and trim
up the cannabis appropriately i've seen
these things explored and
one of the reasons is because it's so
hard to keep a room clean
and people coming in you know they they
bring in their pests with them a lot of
times
yeah gosh darn it's uh
yeah i mean you gotta do tissue culture
to make sure your genetics are clean
make sure
the media that you're planting the the
plantlets into
are clean that you know there's zero
interference from from humans
and then i mean i guess i wonder also um
if it's a sterile in fact a sterile
environment what are you missing
if you don't have beneficial microbes
within within your ecosystem is
are you growing good the best plants
that you can are you getting the terpene
and the cannabinoid content and
the biomass that is potential in the in
the genetics
yeah i think there's a whole another
webinar of me
blabbing on my soapbox about how great
microbes are but
the research is out there and more is
coming the benefits
the yield benefits i mean a company that
i look at
is is mammoth p you know they work with
a lot of people
they show you how much more you can
yield with the benefit of microbes they
show you how you can
unlock uh nutrients in a different way
um but then it's really embracing it
from a synergistic you know
position where it's like if you're just
gonna feed nutrient salts do you have
the appropriate cation exchange do you
have amino acids do you have b1 vitamins
it's about thinking about plant health
from a holistic perspective
and microbes play a role whether you
like it or not there are going to be
microbes on your plant
even in a sterile environment rob and i
have talked about this it's like
well maybe we bring hydrogen peroxide
gas or
radical oxidative species to the plant
in order to make sure that the plant's
sterile
right but the reality is that's probably
going to wipe out the beneficial microbe
cell wall that we have on the plant or
in the root zone
that's allowing those those nutrients to
be
more available or creating nutrients
cycling
so the plant can eat hundreds and
hundreds of times a day
rather than just the one to five times
you feed it
it's again it's about synergy and it's
about understanding the risk reward and
costs and cost benefit analysis there
too
yeah yeah that's great and just really
quick uh
question from from pat jacker just
really asking for a little elaboration
here
um about uh just your linkedin post
about the health of the cuticle
and um the the plant waxes deterring
powdery mildew
and uh so i think it's a little bit
different than the
systemic acquired response and the plant
is essentially it has these waxes on it
that allow it to
photosynthesize and transpire and deal
with the external environment
and what i've seen is that you know one
of the biggest
pest vectors is when leaves die now
that i believe sends off pheromones from
the plant that attracts these negative
insects that say oh
this plant's weak let's come eat it
right
and at the same time those dead leaves
are a potential habitat
for powdery mildew or botrytis so
for me and this is probably a
conversation that might set rob off
it's about accurately controlling
the vpd it's about making sure that the
moisture content
in the air relative to the leaf tissue
temperature
is appropriate so we're not drying out
those cuticular waxes we want them to
remain as long as possible because
they're the best defense especially in
late stages against these infestations
so again it comes back to the tools of
the trade know how to measure what's in
your space
know how to measure the plant and know
how to control
so you don't have too much wind or too
much heat
that are destroying those waxes and
making the plant more vulnerable
mm-hmm jesse you hit the hot button
no i just want to disagree with you look
the particular membrane is a
very important part of plant physiology
um
whether it's receptive to vpd or just
relative humidity of the air
and air velocity i don't know right you
know i don't know enough about the
particular membrane and what it's
sensitive to um
that particular article i yeah i get it
there is
very good data in that article that
pat's talking about but um
you know i'm always very sensitive to
leaf canopy temperature right i
i didn't see that um i didn't see that
touched on heavily enough for my own
liking because whenever we talk about
vpd
around the office or with anybody it's
how are you measuring
vpd is it that we saw that we saw a
chart in that article
that is the one that's very popular
online um
that's a static chart vpd changes
constantly and it's
different in your entire canopy at
different heights of your canopy
uh you just have to make a best guess
with it sometimes using the best tools
you have we use the cameras
you know other people have different
tools but that's the only thing i would
say you know
vpd is absolutely vital for plant health
the plant has
got lots of vigor it will be able to
fight off all sorts of pests and
pathogens
if the relative humidities go off you
know you look at that chart on one of
the slides
it's the relative humidity where you get
into the danger zones of pathogen
proliferation so yeah i would say i
you know we've talked about this and we
will continue to talk about this but
i also think bpd is really important for
bricks
and if you really want to accumulate
more sugars and vitamins and minerals
inside your plant tissue
it's important to control transpiration
the right way
and if you want to get to a 12 on the
brick scale
you really need to make sure that you're
appropriately controlling
vapor pressure deficit so the plant can
take up the mobile and immobile
nutrients that it needs
and redistribute them appropriately so
that you get
you know a healthy plant from tip to
stem to root
so when you do that test you know it's
reflecting plant health
and vpd is one of the ways to get your
bricks higher
and also i would say that this is one
thing i think we totally agree on rob
whether it's vpd or relative humidity or
airflow or whatnot
those particular waxes are important and
it's just something that we should think
about and consider
and talk about how to protect and that
was one of the main things i wanted to
um put out there by sharing todd's
article was like
hey let's think about these cuticular
waxes
let's think about vpd let's think about
humidity
and and how it plays a role in
integrated pest management the analog is
skin health right if
you don't have um you know supple enough
skin
if the you know the cholesterol and your
skin goes away which is you know a
problem with some people
it cracks and this is an infection uh
zone for your skin right that is true
for plants it's true for people
we have to be very sensitive to it so i
get that 100 agree
we don't argue about that right got it
so
plant defenses as an ipm strategy built
really building the the vigor of the
plant as a
as a an ability to to defend itself
against attacks
yeah cool yeah makes makes good sense
um another one here from francis is
is there an ipm strategy for curing
yeah i mean i think that it's i think a
lot of people don't think about
what happens when you cure or the
potential for
pests and a really quick aside story is
i have a friend
uh who whose dad is sick and was
had grown grown wheat a long time ago
and he had
put it away when it was far too wet and
it developed all kinds of problems
it had all kinds of molds growing on it
and when he would smoke that cannabis
he would literally pass out he would
black out and wake back
up and it was it was hey does weed go
bad
or you know or is there something in
these rolling papers that's hurting me
and
it wasn't until we really realized like
you know there's probably a lot
of things in this product that you could
have
dealt with before you put it in the jar
and if you just would have had an
appropriate curing strategy you wouldn't
have the botrytis the pythium and the
powdery mildew
that are all over this cannabis and it
would be safe to smoke
um so for me it's also a thing with my
mom it's like when trying to find
safe cannabis early on in the
deregulated market people would sell
anything because there was no testing
now we have testing it's not just about
testing for residual pesticides
it's testing for e coli it's testing for
salmonella it's testing for
asparalis and these are things that can
occur
in the curing process so for me it's
really important to make sure that we
migrate the moisture from the interior
of the bud
to the exterior of the bud in a s in a
linear fashion we don't want the
moisture to migrate back in
because then that will trap water inside
that will become anaerobic
and bring up anaerobic pathogens in
addition to that we need to make sure
that the water activity
inside of the buds when we go to finally
package them is below 20
everyone's got a different signature
some people in some
counties are even testing for this which
i think is really cool
but the idea is is that if you put
cannabis
in an airtight environment with water
activity
over 20 it's going to sporulate things
are going to grow
in there and if you can get the water
activity below
20 then there's not going to be activity
there's not going to be migration inside
the bud that leads to sporulation of
these
these pathogens and pests
and then a lot of people don't filter
the air in their curing space i mean for
years i would just hang it in my garage
and blast it with air
and then throw away 20 because i'm like
ooh you know you get in there you start
trimming away to roll yourself a joint
you're like oh that one's moldy let's
heave-ho on that one and move on to the
next one knowing that those spores were
probably just circulated in the space
without appropriate biological
filtration or just passing them from one
bud to another
well i think i think to that end moving
a lot of air through the room gets that
homogeneity
of the environment which gives you some
reassurance that every bud
in the drying and curing area is getting
a consistent temperature and humidity
around it to keep the moisture moving in
the right direction
so if you move a lot of air and if you
have the opportunity to move air
you should be cleaning it as you move it
there's no excuse so
you know we use a strategy um you know
trapping with high efficiency filtration
and then
uh photocatalytic oxidation downstream
to clean the coil but also clean the air
with the molecular shredders and also
seal that room right i mean that's one
of the physical barriers you can do to
create
pests and pathogens coming in i mean i
know people too that have had
a handful of spider mites on their plant
and they're like no it's pretty good
it's not affecting my bottom line and
then they go to cure
and then you know eight days later we've
had
thousands and thousands of eggs hatch
and those mites are like man i gotta eat
this really quickly before it dries out
and all of a sudden you're coming in
with a vacuum cleaner trying to suck
webbing off of buds that you think are
going to be sellable
not going to happen yikes
uh well jeff had a question here that i
think
was just addressed um about how
important particulate control
is in ipm and how it's best controlled
in cannabis cultivation
if you guys have anything else to add
there please please do so
i think um ahead rob no i was just going
to say i think it's
it has a lot to do for me about
third-party testing data
like if someone says i'm going to do
this i need to see the proof in the
pudding so many times
i've been misled by people selling a
product that
hasn't been tested that hasn't been
tried especially in the emerging
cannabis industry when i had my shop
every day someone would try and come in
and sell me something that didn't work
that didn't work and it was up to me to
do the research
and find out how it worked how it would
be effective in my facility would it
synergize
with my team and how i go about ipm
what are the costs to deploy it and you
know
so often people aren't thinking about
the facility and the cultivation space
as a whole
and all of a sudden people are like oh
ozone works great just pump it into your
room and it'll kill everything and it's
like well
man i've worked in rooms that are filled
with ozone
i've left dizzy with nose nosebleeds
and thought man i didn't have to do much
in there today because everything was
dead
but am i dying too you know
yeah yeah that's uh yeah man it's a
scary thought
and uh that's balance between risk and
reward right i mean
some radical oxidative species some
stress to the plant is good
persistent stress is bad um
use it to clean the room between plants
sure but do everything else you can to
prevent
those oxidative species from oxidizing
the
terpenes that you're trying to preserve
or oxidizing the thc you're trying to
preserve so
uh and the cell wall cell membranes
things like that so some of those things
might be
totally deployable in a cloning and
vegetative
and mother room space you know but not
deployable in a flowering space
but at the same time understand how
that's going to affect your other
approaches is that going to kill the
microbiology
is that going to destroy the rhizophagus
irregularis that's getting you bigger
roots faster
is that going to kill the glomus mosaic
that needs six months or six weeks to
develop in order to keep heavy metals in
the root zone and prevent them from
going up into the plant
these are compromises you might make by
bringing in
some other sort of advanced filtration
technique
got it okay
good one guys um
shift gears real quick uh question from
uh chris uh can one unit be utilized to
control both vegetative and flower stage
one hvac d unit yeah i believe so
yes the answer is yes it's okay yes and
no
the difference there's there's the
distinct calculation
that goes along with a vegetative state
room
and another one for a flower room and
typically flower has got a
higher pound per hour moisture removal
requirement
the same amount of airflow if the room's
the same size we'd probably see the same
airflow every two to three minutes we'd
be changing the air in the room
um you've got to make sure that if
you're going to use one unit
it can handle the highest load in flower
and the lowest load in veg so many times
you get into a veg room
and the minimum stage on the hvac d unit
is pulling too much water out of the
room and we need humidifiers i mean it's
crazy but
you've got all these room full of
humidifiers plants then you have to add
humidification
so our units don't seem to suffer from
this problem we turn down everything
fans to compressors to the energy
recovery system
um so we can get down to very very small
zero moisture removal just complete
sensible
and then all the way up to the high
latent removal
we can do both but you've just got to
make sure when you're sizing the unit it
can handle both sides of the spectrum
i think to piggyback off of that too
thanks rob that was great and
what i usually say is you know if you
size the system for your flower
room then and it's the same space in the
same plant count it should be able to
handle the bedroom
this question also might be bringing up
the fact that people want to run
one hvac unit for both their flour and
veg
and that's where it gets really tricky
right because those can
those conditional set points are so
different the
the vpd is different for those spaces
you know for the
the stage of growth so you might have to
compromise both spaces if you think
you're going to run
one unit for flour and veg
but absolutely the same unit if sized
appropriately could do
veg or flour the other keyboard being
there
turn down so you have to have the turn
down ability to handle
the veg the lower load and veg all the
way up to the higher lord and flower
yep great all right thanks for
clarifying that guys
um on on a similar line of thinking
um anders is asking can some of these
pesticides some of the essential oils
and pet
and other pesticides being sprayed
indoors damage hvac equipment
good question i think the answer is yes
radical oxidative species will tear up
plastics like nobody's business
if you've got a persistent one of them
usually
what we find is they are i think they
are
oxidative to you know copper aluminum of
some sort so
vaporized hydrogen peroxide as an
example
is vaporized as long as it stays in the
vapor gas phase we're okay as soon as it
starts condensing and
landing on the coils you may run into
problems so if your coils are running
and cooling and pulling out
turning vaporized hydrogen peroxide into
liquid hydrogen peroxide
at high enough concentrations on the
coil you'll go over through aluminum
real quick as
my understanding of it we recommend coil
coatings if that
is your cleaning the room ipm strategy
so we've seen this come up in a number
of different projects but
usually the answer is just don't run
your cooling coils while you're doing
the room cleaning the temperatures rise
up
and allow more of that vaporized
hydrogen peroxide to get into the air
because you're just vaporizing so
got it yeah there's another thing about
that you know anytime you're using uv
light so
uv lights can be used as a surface
cleaner we use them
as part of the pco mechanism to create
the oxidative radicals with the titanium
titanium dioxide mesh
uv light will tear apart plastics again
you need to have hardened surfaces uv
hardened surfaces or
conduit metal conduit for all your
plastic wiring
uh plastic sheath wiring inside your air
handling units and you know you can get
a
mile of air of wiring inside an air
handling unit pretty easily
um it's one of those things you don't
want to overlook because you will start
shorting out sensors and
start shorting out electrical circuits
and then
you know pop those in and to add to that
too
this is actually off topic but it just
got me thinking about
what these applications do to the
machines in your space but also to the
final product and
you know i've been a big proponent of
neem for a long time and
different oils just because they mesh
with my strategy and they have low
impact on
the environment and the beneficials and
what i started to learn was that
you know i might have a product that's
considered fantastic
top-tier high-grade flour and then when
i put it through the extraction process
there have been extractors that pointed
out to me it's like man i'm getting
incredible yields out of your product
like
to the point that i don't understand
what's going on
and then we dig a little bit deeper and
we realize oh
stylet oil and neem oil are now produ
part of my
extract so just another reason to
seriously consider
what's going to attach itself to the
trichomes what's going to attach itself
to the secondary metabolites
bond with that and carry through and the
casual smoker
in low doses might say man i love it it
gives it a whole new flavor
or they might say hey i don't you know
this isn't as great a product or it
might cause
more oxidation in long-term storage or
what triggered it for me was
knowing that so many extracts
concentrate
these applications and all of a sudden
you have heavy metals you have oils in
the concentrate
even though you did very minimal
application during the growth stages
wild yeah
jesse i want to congratulate you for
saying trichomes the right way
hey i get one right every once in a
while man hey get one right
next no i mean you know don't make me
say
pillow or windmill man
like you just did
yeah with regard to anders anders
question as well
it makes me think about the quality of
your condensate
capture as well right if you're if
you're pulling in all sorts of
weird oils and pesticides through your
hvac
cd system what kind of stuff are you
capturing when you're condensing that
water from the air
and you know what impact does it have on
the ability to recycle that water back
into your
plants that's a great point man even if
you're not doing foliar sprays let me
just throw this out there
you've got a tube with no light in it so
you know you're not going to use your uv
cleaners in the air handler
um in any configuration to clean inside
the condensate drain
condensate running off of the coil will
pick up all this
micro particle stuff that's not
pathogens necessarily but it's dirt and
then these dirt
become these dirt balls and these dirt
balls become nucleation sites for
bacteria and it's hard to get rid of all
the bacteria
uh you know anywhere in an air handling
unit or in a room like we're talking
about
um whether you're doing sprays or not
condensate drain
water needs to be analyzed and treated
um and probably purified in some way
shape or form before you try and put it
back into the room
um but just like you said if
your if any of this oil makes it through
the particulate capture system
and makes it onto the coil the
condensate coming off is a
stream of water that's going to clean
off that coil and it's going to end up
in the condensate
no sensor no i i like what you're saying
and as a guy who loves to
recycle 100 of my water it's one of the
reasons why i sort of
steer in that oils and soaps world
because
the bacteria and the fungi that
accumulate in the condensate drains
i'm okay dealing with remediation
through compost tea
through fermentation through breeding of
billions of good microbes that consume
the bad microbes and outperform them in
a space
and an environment in the tea brewer
where they're guaranteed to win
the biggest problems for me is like what
else is coming out of that room
how much sulfur is coming into that
space
what other acids and chemicals are
coming into the space that are
compromising my ability
to recycle the water and messing up with
my tea
or becoming consumed by the microbiology
in my tea and then redelivered to the
root zone
in a super available way that now is
absorbed into the plant
is you know there's a lot of unhealthy
things to think about when it comes to
that perspective
geez that's that's amazing lots of
interesting stuff to consider
um another one from andy here um
have you had success getting rid of
fusarium into cannabis grow
yeah i mean i think a lot of times
people see it and they're like oh man
i'm going to spray hydrogen peroxide
that's my only option and man when it
comes to
systemic fungal colonies coming through
the root zone and coming through the
water
you need to go back and get cultural
control it's really the only option you
have to
treat that water so maybe it's about
getting a water test
and understanding what's in your water
as it comes in just like rob said as you
recycle it let's learn about the
microbes that are in there let's
let's make sure that we you know
remediate with uv
filtration or some sort of treatment
ozone treatment or something in the
water
and then have a secondary process to
make sure that we're not putting ozone
and uv
into the root zone but absolutely
there's some
some spot fixes that people do i think a
lot of people like to run
systemic microbes you know get as many
fungal and bacterial colonies on and in
the plant as possible so they can
prevent the uptake of that
so they can filter that horrid water as
it comes into the root zone
but in the end it's a water mold and you
need to deal with
standing water in the space possible
drips from condensate lines
filters leaks anaerobic water pools
water if you clean the room and you push
everything into the hallway and you
don't clean the hallway
bam there you go water molds in the
hallway mop sink
water molds like any place where water
is going to stagnate
needs to be addressed and it comes down
to that culture of clean
in addition to dealing with the water
and there's almost no point
in going in and fighting pythium or
fusarium
in the space on the plant until you get
control
of the water system otherwise it's just
a it's a battle you're not gonna win
right yeah it makes sense it's uh attack
the source not not
don't don't put a band-aid try and put a
band-aid on it and once you get control
of the culture
then your applications to take that
fruserium and pythium
rhizo rhizoctonia anything like that out
of the picture will be that much more
effective
because instead of battling the incoming
of new stuff you've stopped that
and now you can let good microbes take
hold or good chemistry
ward off the effects but in the end you
know a lot of times i see people go to
tissue culture after that experience and
they think oh man
i need to remove the epigenetic material
i need to get back to a stasis
i need to start from a genetic beginning
again so i'm not battling this with the
cuttings that i
maybe got from my mom because if you fed
your mother plant that same water
now you should think about getting rid
of all your mother plants or treating it
with systemic bacteria and fungus
yeah jim is asking how do i determine if
something is a nutrient deficiency or a
pest sure
i think a lot of times it comes back
down to scouting so for me when i walk
into a facility
i like to take a look at the canopy as a
whole i like to find
plants or spaces that look a little bit
differently than the rest of the canopy
and then i immediately go there and
address it with my microscope i look on
the leaf surface i look on the back side
of the leaf i look on the stem
i look in the media i'm looking for
larva i'm looking for eggs
i'm looking for bugs that's always my
first spot you know like
let's find the pest that's killing this
if i can't find any pests
if i can't find pustules if i don't see
the black dots the initial formation of
powdery mildew
then i think of fertigation as the
remediation
and i think okay what's going on is this
emitter on these group of plants working
right
are we delivering the appropriate amount
of nutrition do we have
a nutrient lock up but for me if you go
through those steps
and you you can't identify a pest
on the plant or in the space then it's
probably nutrient or environmental
related
so go back change your fertigation
schedule
think about what that might be what
might have caused that
try and link that up with some pictures
you see
and get a balanced delivery of
fertigation back to the
back to the plant or what i would do is
say come heavy with seaweed because
it'll trigger systemic acquired response
and it'll be a bunch of micronutrients
to help your plant recover as quick as
possible
you know if you're losing if you're
losing emitters you know
a good control system is going to tell
you that right if you're tracking like
we do
uh moisture removal across the course of
a day
and we're stacking it on day on day and
day we know if we're getting to the end
of the cycle
and the water transpiration rate starts
to fall off that
it's probably an emitter problem or some
sort of watering problem that'll be the
first place to look and you know we
alarm off that on
our control system so um i think there's
ways to just kind of
get that one in the bud uh if you've got
a good control system i'm not sure about
the other ones though
yeah and a lot of times like you know it
just ends up being
depending on your fertigation it's a
salt buildup or a buildup in the lines
or
glomulin or something preventing that
that plant from getting the appropriate
dose of nutrition on the large scale
that tends to be
with a with a professional fertigation
approach that tends to be like the
number one problem
and then then we can go ahead and take a
look at changing the dose but if the
rest of the canopy looks good
isolate that space isolate that plant
think about what's specifically wrong
with the controls
the physical and cultural space for that
plant
yeah and pat makes a good point uh about
identifying the the
damage to the to the plant tissue as
being a good way to tell uh if
it's a pest that's a great one like in a
lot of ways i can spot a pest from a few
feet away
if it's speckling on the top side of the
leaves depending on the size of the
speckling i'm like oh you have mite
issues
you see the lines in the in the plant
you've got um
you know some sort of leaf miner if
you've got a big juicy bud
outside in one little brown spot you've
got caterpillars
go quickly spray some bacillus
thuringieneses spray it in the morning
so it has time to work and
not be affected by the sun release some
trichogama wasps you know think about
the local hatch rate
there's a lot of stuff you can do to
sort of you know
take a look at the damage and get a
really good idea of what's going on due
to the damage because you might not
always find a pest
pat's actually absolutely right but if
you do see the damage that's just
another sign an indicator of what's
going on in the space
yeah perfect perfect all right final
final question here and we can we can
call it a wrap uh what are the
advantages of pco
over uv uh also hepa versus merv 13
versus merv 8.
man please so
as i mentioned before we use uv in pco
um it is activating the titanium dioxide
catalytic reaction to disassociate water
molecules in the air
create these oh negative hydroxyl
radicals
and for that eight inch window we are
creating a very highly oxidative
airstream
eight inches just downstream of our
cooling coil that anything running
through it
in that eight inches it's enough um
it's enough exposure to the oxidation to
basically
shred the liquid well the
casing on a virus or spore you know even
tear apart vocs and odors and things
like that
so um that's different than uv
so uv light requires a dose over a long
period of time
it's a uv is a good surface cleaner but
if i'm going to try and get a particle
of air that's traveling
at 500 feet per minute through my air
handler and 1100 feet per minute through
my duct
i need 40 feet 60 feet of
uv light at a high intensity throughout
that entire
now again uv light great surface cleaner
not so great particulate killer um or
particular
you know disabler because you just need
so much of it
we know those systems are out there if
that's your preference
fine but i just i don't understand what
you know the maintenance costs
associated with having
such a high intensity uv light changing
the bulbs all the time
having access into that ductwork i just
see it being problematic
um that's the difference between uv and
pcm
so i hope that made sense in terms of
filter you know particulate filtration
hepa merv 13 merv 8 the lower you go
so hepa is our merv 16 or yeah it
happens over 16 plus
um merv 13 and then merv 8 the lower the
number
the more of the smaller particles are
going to get through
a mirror 13 is not perfect at capturing
all of the particulate
that we want to stop you know one micron
and above
but it does a very good job of it hepa's
you know there's a balance point here
you're going to spend
a lot more energy moving air
through a hepa filter which has just got
smaller holes which is why it's doing so
much more particulate capture
than you are in a mirror 13 filter
and also you know mir-13 equivalence or
hepa equivalents
have the lower pressure drop and we
prefer to use those instead
um it's a balancing point they never
been moved they just they're a sieve to
the things that we think are a problem
murph 13s do a really good job with the
pco downstream
doing the coil cleaning and the
airstream cleaning i think we've got a
pretty good one too
it's good balance between energy
consumption
and air cleaning for sure so uh
i know that was supposed to be the last
question but you know when we announced
this webinar i got a handful
of questions from legacy growers from my
friends in the industry
from people that asked me if i was going
to sort of tackle the
conversation about micro dosing and i
think it's an important thing to talk
about right
when i first heard the term micro dosing
it was you know
i immediately thought yeah sure do some
mushrooms and go to work man you might
be more creative
sounds like a great idea to me but then
i realized that
my friends were talking about you know
micro dosing you know
eagle 20 and tetrasan and forbid and
merit wp and these banned substances
and i came from an industry where we had
to use what was
available there was a lack of regulation
there was a lack of study and there was
a lack of knowledge so
we grabbed for the things that were
commercially viable in
in commercial agriculture and we utilize
them and if you utilize them
inappropriately there are
huge consequences yeah you'll fail a
test you'll have to destroy
product it'll be a brand black eye
it's you might pass a test when it comes
to buds but then you're going to fail a
test when it comes to concentrates
but here's my real cautious tale here
i've been growing cannabis for a really
long time
and before i knew any better i used
banned substances
and then i decided that i was going to
have a family i've been with my wife for
over 20 years
and it was really really hard and i
couldn't figure out why it was so hard
we were trying so much but we weren't
having kids and what i realized was
maybe it has something to do
with this stuff getting absorbed into my
skin
into my body what are these systemic
pesticides doing to me as a person
so i completely stopped i got away from
every pesticide that i did not
understand everything that i thought
may or may not be banned and six months
later
my wife and i had our first kid miles
what so to me
yeah you do whatever it's a personal
choice it's a business choice but in
reality
there are consequences that you might
not be thinking about
and that's just my personal story so it
doesn't resonate with everybody
but the reality is i think that is the
reason
why we were unable to have children for
so many years
wow wow thanks thanks for sharing that
jesse i hadn't heard that before what a
that's pretty wild um it makes you
wonder
what what the the impact it has when you
smoke it yeah
right a flower with banned substances
talking about oxidation like you turn
these chemicals into
you know awful carcinogens and uh
yeah yeah well i hate to hate to end it
on on that note
you guys want to tell a joke before we
sign off
[Laughter]
ipm's not a joke brian nothing nothing
happening in youtube for the rest of
that history
yup got it all right fair enough
well uh hey great great job guys
thank you very much for your time