our keynote panel which focuses on the
proposed cannabis appellation program
itself and leading that discussion
tonight will be Jeannine Coleman
Jeannine Coleman is the founder and
executive director of origins Council a
non-profit education research and policy
advocacy organization so I'm going to go
ahead and get started and just offer a
brief overview of the proposed
regulations and then we'll open up into
more specific topics for discussion so
essentially the regulatory package
describes a system to establish an
appellation of origin and that process
is that farmers come together to
research and develop a petition to
propose an appellation and the
regulations propose a minimum of three
license cultivators come together to do
so and then the petition describes the
geographic boundaries of their proposed
appellation evidence of established name
use and geographic factors that
contribute to the inequalities of the
cannabis and the cannabis cultivation
and then any region specific standards
practices and cultivars then the
petition submitted to CDFI with a fee of
$20,000 880 and CFA proposes in the
regulations to appoint a volunteer
review panel consisting of seven members
with two alternates to review the
petition and provide recommendations to
see DFA and once the petition is
determined to be a complete CDFA will
notice a 30-day public comment period
and CDFA has the sole authority to
approve the appellation of origin
appellation petitions once established
can be amended and the proposed fee for
that is ten thousand four hundred and
forty dollars a couple of other
considerations in the regulations we
it's a little bit unclear whether or not
the appellation can be used on
manufactured products so that's a point
of clarification we're going to be
looking for
there's no labeling guidelines that are
provided
so that's another pretty significant
scope of clarification that we need the
regulations proposed allowing for
partially overlapping Appalachians as
well as nested Appalachians and Richard
spoke a little bit to the potential
friction between trademarks and
appellation of origin and the
regulations proposed a three year sunset
period for Geographic trademarks that
would be in conflict with an appellation
of origin with that timeline beginning
once the appellation of origin has been
established on the verification and
enforcement side of things the proposal
is to essentially handle those
requirements solely through
record-keeping and then the defines for
misuse are very minor and ranged from
$100 to $500 so that's just a general
picture of the regulatory package and I
think to start us off what I would like
to do is ask Richard if you wouldn't
mind walking us through the specific
petition requirements and explain how
that is important with respect to the
causal link okay so these proposed
regulations they're in the California
Code of regulations title 3 division 8
chapter 1 and specifically the
requirements for a petition are in
sections 9 102 9 1 0 7 and it's pretty
self-explanatory I'll just review that
briefly first of all the general
information is set forth in 9 102 and
you have to describe who you are your
license number contact information you
have to give a general description of
the area which would be the total
acreage the acreage under canopy and the
acreage of the of that total the amount
which would qualify for use of the
appellation so give them the the sense
of proportion at the outset and then we
get into the specifics that are going to
look a lot like what I showed you for an
ABA with one notable exception named
boundary distinctive geographical
feature
which looks like a navy a style
requirements and then your standards
practices and cultivars so let's run
through those specifically the regs give
some guidance into the types of
information that would be acceptable and
of course all this is subject to review
by CDFA and they will tell you just as
ttv tells you with a navy a petition
whether you are quote-unquote perfected
whether you've met the original of an
injury burden in order to get yourself
into rulemaking so the name in nine 104
is is pretty straightforward the name
has to relate to the boundary it doesn't
say in the regs whether the name can be
under inclusive or over inclusive it
just says that you can use among
numerous information sources to justify
the name so the name doesn't have to be
a name that's been known in the world of
cannabis or for cannabis the name can be
a governmental name it can be a school
district it can be a road it can be a
mountain name it can be the names of
businesses it can be in the media can be
used in tourism so what the petitioners
will have to do is to bring all of those
sources of information together in their
petition to justify that the name
applies to the given boundary obviously
even though it's not stated in the
regulations if the name is misleading if
I were sitting here in Napa and calling
myself Berkeley well I consumer is not
going to understand that but no matter
what information I adduce so the name
has to be understandable to the
consumers then you go to 9 105 which is
the boundary you have to have a
narrative description again it looks
like a lot light with TTB rules for ABA
su you describe it in a clockwise manner
you know starting at the beginning point
going clockwise and ending at the same
point and you can use any features that
appear on a map and they give you
examples of that that might be human
features human construction features
like a bridge it could be natural
features like an elevation or a mountain
peak or a road or a river
it does not say but I presume it means
the regulations mean that you're not
doing this by parcel lines it's not my
property but not my neighborhood's
property as to finding meets and bounds
so again I think it looks pretty much
like the same kind of information that
you would do for a for an ABA petition
in nine 106 we get to the most
interesting part of the regulations and
where the causal link comes in Jeanine
and that is the issue of what they call
distinctive geographical features in the
regs and geographical features it stated
in the initial statement of reasons
include cultural factors and
reputational factors it's not just the
natural to bringing in what they call
anthropogenic features cultivation
practices and the why so it's a
geographical features in the broadest
sense of the word
and they they ask for those features
that affect cannabis cultivation I
personally have a problem with that
because it it should be that affects
cannabis not it affects cannabis
cultivation the test of any GDI or
appellation of origin is the final
product how you grow it is essential
that's a standard practice in cultivar
but ultimately the geographical features
have to relate and this is your causal
linked to the final product whether it's
a natural feature as they call out here
climate physical features elevations
geology no mention of soil which should
be in there and then and then how it
relates to the final product and then
they also include reputation history of
the area
Automation practices so what that means
is that you have to show not just that
the region is distinctive compared to
what's outside um you have to show that
what makes it distinctive affects the
final product when you add up the sum
total of the of the geography the
geographical features and the standards
practices and cultivars that that
equation will lead to those special
distinctive characteristics and
qualities of the final product that's
the burden of the petitioners to do
that's why the petitioners three or more
are going to get together and
collaborate you know how do we prove
this that our cannabis really is
distinctive in this area and then of
course they want you to enumerate what
those standards practices and cultivars
are interestingly the practice can be a
prohibited practice as well as a
prescriptive practice the cultivar can
be a prohibited cultivar as well as a an
allowable cultivar and it says this
directly in the recs practices of course
are they don't say it but maybe they
would be the same either those you can
do or those you can't do but
interestingly it works both ways so you
could for example if you're not ready to
specify a cultivar or cultivars you
could say it won't be these cultivars
and you won't be farming in this manner
so it can be negative as well as
positive in terms of those standards
practices in the light and of course you
have to have the record-keeping them to
show them so the main thing I think the
main burden names and boundaries are
straightforward
the main burden is is going to be the
causal link between the geographical
features writ large and the final
cannabis product and all the standards
practices and cultivar prescriptions
that go along with it
great thank you Richard I really
appreciate that
I think this is a good segue to discuss
terroir it's it's been a topic that the
farming community has been talking about
for reviewers and Heather I know this is
something that you've been working on as
well would you speak to the issue of
terroir and how it relates to the
program and the causal link yeah sure
and here are is really an important
concept it's a French term and it's been
translated as the taste of place and and
I think it's a lot more complex than
just the taste of place it's this whole
concept of you know the environmental
factors that affect the product what my
friends as Sciences Holly Hall called
the biophysical factor so the climate
the soil and you know the way the fog
rolls in and how that affects the
product but additionally also the human
factors so what are the ways that humans
have interacted with that you know
terroirs generally through an
agricultural lens and so how that the
humans have worked with the environment
in that agricultural practice or in that
agricultural point I trying to say in
that area of agriculture and so for
cannabis for instance the way that we
have interacted with the plant has been
under a cloud of prohibition for so long
and so you know we have this opportunity
through the statute to codify
essentially it's the codification in
regulation anyways the standards that we
have used under this cloud of
prohibition for so long to cultivate the
plant in our Northern California and our
legacy producing health and that the the
practices that we've employed what are
the traditional practices and what are
the cultivars that grow in certain ways
and those human interactions with just a
regular cultivation of the plant
together that allows in California
cannabis to an active program that is
terroir based
is linked to the the the product is
linked to the plate and so the link
between products in place those are
generally governed in law by
appellations of origin the appellation
of origins well like I said codify those
links into the regulation and that's the
causal link there that's how come why
the product expresses the plate it's
because of the causation there and so
it's really exciting in California
cannabis law because we have this
opportunity to do so to link the
products to the place using the using
these causal links through standards
practices varietals our geographical
features and it's a really exciting
opportunity that we have and the
regulations I think set us up to to be
able to do that except for they do
include this reputational evidence as
well which Richard talked about earlier
that we have two different ways that we
can codify or two different sort of
applications of law that we could use to
to to codify the causal link and one
comes from the Lisbon Agreement and that
is an exclusive or essential the product
is exclusively or essentially linked to
its geographical source and that's a
much higher standard
whereas we could have one where the
reputation is linked to the place and
that's a lower standard and so I'm kind
of excited to see what we can do here
through our draft regulations with CDFA
to see if we can push towards a more
terroir based application that includes
the the human and the geographical
factors and the reason that that's so
important is because terroir base
Appalachians
have a higher value in the marketplace
and
tomber understand that when something
went up programs like an Operations
program when that can ensure to the
consumer that not only does it come from
a particular place but that the
standards that are used or the practices
that are used or the particular
cultivars that are used are also set
forth in that theme or controlled under
that same program the consumers can have
a heightened trust and when we trust the
product more we're more willing to buy
or pay a premium price for that and
that's shown in all sorts of consumer
studies so the higher price that we can
fetch when we have greater control over
the appellation and by using a terroir
based a geographic and human controlled
type of program and that money then goes
back to the farmer and that farmer then
spends the money locally and we have
then increased economic ability for our
farms and for the communities that have
a terroir based appellation program and
there's a ton of other reasons why the
terroir based Appalachians program you
know when it has a heightened control is
good for our communities and one of the
other reasons in addition to consumer
confidence and therefore higher brand
value higher economic opportunity for
the farmer and for the community is also
that the codification in regulation of
our practices and what we've been doing
in the hill for so long that allows us
to protect it in a way that if someone
from big AG wants to come in and say
this is hand trimmed or this is you know
this cannabis is produced in a certain
way but there is at least some reference
to what that means and it's going to be
harder for somebody to take that type of
practice and to co-opt it into big act
the other exciting thing about that is
by keeping all this stuff local and we
can work together to have a more
regenerative business
model and that can work to reduce the
global supply chain right now that is
causing so many farmers and other
agricultural industries and to just be
squeezed out so many of that contract
farmers you know it's like essentially
in some ways a new form of indentured
servitude and so you know the fact that
we can keep our value we can tell our
story our own way we can manage how our
story is told out into in other ways I
mean in other industries and so that
it's not co-opted it's a really exciting
opportunity and we have that right now
in a way that wine doesn't have wine ABA
is that American viticulture
associations cannot regulate in a really
strong meaningful way standards
practices or cultivars but cannabis says
we do have this opportunity so to to
lose it and not use it right now when
we're set up and teed up in such a great
way is would be it I think a
disappointment to to the the work that's
been done so far to get us to this point
where we are teed up in that way so I'm
really excited by these good for the
farmers I think it's good for
communities and I'm really hoping and
praying that we do have a terroir based
program that's enacted here in
California well thanks Heather I really
appreciate that and I want to key in on
something that you really brought to the
fore which is the consumer trust and
consumer loyalty because that is
effectively how we can leverage this
tool in the market right and bring bring
those deliverables back to our producing
communities you know as we've been
researching and meeting and discussing
this and thinking about the program
we're going to try and look through the
eye of the consumer and ask ourselves
how we can reach them you know what are
the tools that we have and I think one
of the most powerful tools
that's not spoken to in the regulations
and and I think certainly there's going
to be a lot of comment coming forward is
the concept of an official seal an
authenticating seal a logo that lives on
the product and really rare
this program and so a standardized seal
and Omar I know you've done a lot of
research and thinking and looking into
this and so I'd love to hear your
thoughts about you know what what you
would like to see happen along those
lines yeah thank you
I would like to see an official seal
that the state of California adopts and
the official seal will be an emblem of
authenticity
it will provide consumers with helpful
information about the origin of the
cannabis and the requirements associated
with California cannabis appellations
which are requirements for practices
standards or cultivars we want it to be
something that's consistent and easy to
identify so in the European Union
there's something like this and this is
denim miniature Nate the original
prototype and this is for like cheese
and other types of products but it's
like a nice identifiable seal that
consumers can you know without knowing
anything about the particular product
they can see the identifying seal and
see that it's you know a designation of
origin that is protected and that is you
know basically like a proxy for quality
for consumers it will assist consumers
in differentiating among products in a
very crowded marketplace and so what we
have in mind would be something kind of
like the you know here's like the the do
C steal and there would be like a
uniform design element the ring on the
outside would state official California
cannabis appellation and then the area
on the inside would have the name of the
appellation as well as Union as a unique
design that would give petitioners
artistic leeway so it would be like a
cool seal whatever the you know proposal
the petitioners come up with and the
main benefit you know to having an
official seal is that individual
appellation you know the licensees where
are the ones who benefit from the
appellations they will be relieved of
being solely responsive
for enforcement and monitoring costs the
state would be incentivized to make sure
that the official seals are not misused
and so basically it would give the state
of California some skin in the game in
protecting appellations the system that
has been currently proposed it's not
really and partly because it can't but
the regulators can't impose criminal
penalties on those who are not subject
to their regulations they cannot like
forbid you know the use of these seals
but I think this would be something that
would really like number one help
consumers identify official California
Academy South Asians and thereby make
appellations more valuable and more
recognizable more uniform and so that's
something that we had identified and
looking at you know the examples of
other parts of the world we don't really
need to reinvent the wheel because you
know people have really you know this is
what works in the marketplace in Europe
and I think it's something that would
work here in California and that would
probably spread out throughout the world
yeah I think I really support that and I
want to mention you know we've been
talking about applying that concept also
to count origin right so we've got the
two tools for geographic indications for
canvass we've got the county of origin
and the appellation of origin and I
think in polls cases particularly you
know the opportunity for conjunctive
labeling where you're identifying that
County area and then perhaps an
appellation within that County area I
think that would be really helpful yeah
it's a great one of these could say you
know could identify a county yeah and
the other one could be like the
appellation yeah and I think you know
you spoke a little bit too you know that
could be another opportunity to look at
funding and fee structures and how we
tackle the cost of the program and the
cost of petitioners you know one of the
first reactions and strongest reactions
we've gotten from farmers taking a look
at the regulations is concerned over the
proposed
so $20,000 biola petition $10,000 to
amend and so you know it's our
understanding that part of part of why
it's structured that way is the agency
really needs the the fees to fund the
program and so we've all been discussing
various ideas about how to spread those
costs out and lower the barriers to
entry for farmers and so I just want to
open it up to the group to discuss this
and bring forward some of the ideas that
I've been hearing about how to how to
really tackle that issue
well like I could take the lead I guess
you know the barriers to entry extremely
high like $20,000 for a petition to
establish and $10,000 for a renewal and
I think this is predicated on the idea
that they're gonna get these fees one
time up front and this will fund the
appellations program forever
indefinitely in perpetuity which is an
insane way to fund a program because it
doesn't really account for enforcement
and it doesn't account for maintaining a
viable thriving program and so what
we're thinking is instead of creating
such a high initial barrier to entry by
happening at one time feed to establish
an Appalachian and no other revenue
sources why don't we think of new ways
to bring in revenue to lower the barrier
barrier to entry so what I've heard from
some struggling farmers in the Thom Kai
region of Mendocino County they're
thinking why should we have to pay
anything why should it the state be
paying for all you know for the cannabis
appellation program which is an
excellent question
why should this be a burden that those
who are proposing appellations you know
have to bear but if we're gonna assume
for the sake of argument that this must
be a revenue neutral endeavor then
there's ways to like lower the barriers
to entry significantly and that's by
requiring renewal fees every ten years
once an Appalachian is established and
instead of charging twenty thousand
dollars upfront forever and never charge
ten thousand dollars up front and every
ten years charge another ten thousand
dollars and that will maintain a viable
appellations program we're also thinking
that use of the proposed sealer seals
would be subject to a modest royalty and
that would incentivize official
enforcement against misuse because now
the state doesn't want anybody stealing
their tax money with these fake seals
and I think there's other other
proposals that are lead to my
co-panelists sure a couple of points I
agree with with
everything you said Omar and Heather
just first of all the fee for for filing
an ABA is zero okay just so we know by
comparison the federal government does
not charge a fee for for filing a
petition nor does it require as these
regs do the users of the appellation to
file a notice abuse
well the notice of use of who's using an
appellation is another funding potential
funding mechanism because particularly
if the cannabis is is used by not just
cultivators but manufactured products or
other manufacturers there were others
they would contribute to the funding and
the enforcement of the program as well
the the part of it $20,000 a lot of
money because you have to pay experts as
well I think they calculated in the
financial section which wasn't
distributed online but is available
cost-benefit analysis that high between
hiring experts and paying this fee that
you know you're gonna be close to 70 80
hundred thousand dollars but by the time
you get done with an appellation of
origin that's a lot of money um and I
find it particularly troublesome that
there's a fee of ten thousand thousand
whatever and change to make an amendment
because in fact amendments will probably
be routine and I'm not thinking of
amendments of the boundary or the name
I'm thinking of the amendments of the
standards practices and cultivars once
the group the petitioning group and all
the people inside the area start working
with one another and they come up with
new ideas and they gain consensus on new
practices and new standards there should
be numerous amendments and there those
should not be prohibited those would be
free or very minimal cost yeah thank you
Richard I I think you know such a
salient point because the amendment
process is going to allow innovation to
move forward and you spoke to that
tension between innovation and tradition
and I think you know also it helps
inform the development of the program
you
through that amendment process that
we're going to learn and grow and really
develop on a community side on the
Appalachian side and on the in the
program itself hi Blake I see you've
joined us yes I reappeared I wanted to
jump in because we've received some very
excellent OnPoint questions but I wanted
to subject you guys to and on the note
that we were just talking about the
first question I wanted to ask that
comes from Matthew Allen who's asking if
wine took hundreds of years to create
Appalachians is there a risk that
creating Appalachians for cannabis that
it's too early and in the legal process
you know the process of cannabis coming
to legalization I mean are we we
building this like grand edifice it's
not gonna actually do anything
I mean is it actually going to amending
these things is that going to help what
do you see in terms of the efficacy here
well if I may I'll just start this I
don't think it's too early I think
anytime you have a product that's
already well known you'd better be your
Appalachian program sooner rather than
later or you'll have so many knockoffs
out there that your Appalachians will
never be meaningful by the same token
Blake well I think the Appalachian
should start now I think you know having
any three petitioners decide on an
Appalachian may be too few and lead to a
rush to market you know I want mine and
not another three people want theirs
particularly if they allow partially
overlapping Appalachians thank you Chris
for those of you who are trying to
receive CLE credit there is the code
sorry continue Richard no the last point
is I think having a requiring more
consensus before people come in to file
would be good I mean there should be a
whole consensus building process notes
the people inside in Appalachian before
they file rather than everybody wanting
to get their names quickly so I think
CDFA estimated there would be ten new
Apple
a year I think that was in their
cost-benefit analysis I mean you know
let's take the time let's do them well
the first ones are really important to
establish some precedent here about the
causal link and let's go slow but let's
start now whereas my just adds about I
really agree with what Richards saying
and one of the things that we're hoping
is to see federal and international
walls fall and so if we do hold up not
only will there be so many knockoffs and
copycats biking's Northern California
and our legacy cannabis producing
regions will lose a significant
opportunity to define what the program
could look like that could then be
emulated around the globe as these walls
do hopefully fall and I think that
they're expected to do so in the coming
year and that actually leads to another
good question that we received from one
of our viewers from Massachusetts it's
bit of a longer question but the the
gist of it is how do you see the
California Appalachian program meshing
with with other states and potentially a
federal program is this sort of like you
know a test case is a little incubator
where we test out the system and then
maybe you know put it forth the out of
the federal level are we looking to see
how other states use it as well or how
do you see this program maybe as an
exemplar for others or something to that
effect sure I would say of course
California so goes the nation and you
know this is one of the biggest
laboratories of democracy so what the
experiments in California tend to
propagate across the whole United States
and you know if somebody said in
Massachusetts it's already thinking like
how are they doing Appalachians in
California I think that portends well
yeah I would agree I you know we have
been our organization has been so laser
focused on the policy because we are
setting a precedent here and we do have
other states watching this very closely
I know
at Oregon Washington are looking at this
Jamaica is looking at this you know
there are legacy cannabis producing
regions all over the world that are in
in a very kind of you know pressing it
moment right now in terms of
legalization unfolding internationally
and and this is such a tremendous
mechanism to protect you know
traditional producing communities and
their genetic property their
intellectual property their traditional
knowledge and so you know I absolutely
think that you know this is a very
pivotal moment and getting this policy
right means sort of everything for those
communities worldwide just because of
the precedent sure and I think we should
cut off in a moment but I do have one
more question that has come up a bit and
some of the questions that have arisen
here in the petition process they gets 9
102 the petitioner is supposed to
specify the license types for the
cultivation license types that the
appellation would apply to and that
particular section allows for all types
so you could you could list mixed indoor
outdoor cultivation as part of the
appellation however it's unclear how
some of the other requirements would
allow for indoor cultivators to be a
part of an appellation I was wondering
if any of you had thought about that or
how you think that indoor cultivators or
people who are using bagged soils how
that would play into this new system
well or no soil at all you know my view
about that you're right and thank you
for pointing it out whoever asked that
question I should have made that clear
at the outset you're part of a petition
is to say which license types are
allowed to use the appellation
personally if we're talking about a
terroir based population system it would
be in a causal link between a natural
environment the natural environment not
an indoor created environment it would
be a mockery to have an indoor
appellation I guess one could claim the
rep
station has been developed in a certain
region but if we're talking about
terroir then then it's not possible and
the fewer interferences between the
natural environment or manipulations or
whatever you want to call them and the
final product is a more true and
integral and comprehensive and
understandable system that's what we're
working for right now absolutely all
right
and I guess since Chris isn't stopping
me I think I get to to pick another
question here so one of the other
questions I thought was interesting this
comes from Amy King does the terroir
based system set too high of a standard
for for people who want to establish an
appellation or sort of take advantage of
the protections and the opportunities
that come with an appellation so is it
is it too prohibitive does does it
create too much tension going back to
Richard's presentation too much tension
between the standards and traditions of
old and then innovation I want to is
just make you quick comments on that and
I'll pass it off to somebody else to say
it more eloquently than I can but one I
think that it's not too strict consumers
respond to those strict control controls
and will pay a higher price for them so
I think the stricter that controls the
better and I often think that the
terroir base program is going to be more
defensible if challenged so if you can't
prove your causal link because you don't
have one because you're not terroir
based then how are you going to defend
it a punch challenge that was very
elegantly stated agreed there now if
it's too elegant I can't go ahead if you
want to think one final note Janine and
then we need to we need to shift off
well I just wanted to point out again
that we've got to two tools we've got
county of origin which is all inclusive
there's no additional standards on it
it's open to all operators and then
we've got appellation of origin and
there's a balance there between
inclusivity and exclusivity and I think
that's often kind of set to the side
and not really a part of the
conversation so I think that's really an
important piece to address that concern
excellent all right
thank you all it was pleasure hearing
all of you talk about this the new
system because it's just it's so
interesting it's it's got elements of
the the AOC where we've got standards
practice and cultivars but then also
leaving a little bit of room because it
is so new for the innovation our keynote
panel which focuses on the proposed
cannabis appellation program itself and
leading that discussion tonight will be
Jeannine Coleman Jeannine Coleman is the
founder and executive director of
origins Council a non-profit education
research and policy advocacy
organization origins Council is
dedicated to sustainable rural economic
development within legacy cannabis
producing region regular producing
regions and establishing nationally and
internationally recognized legally
defensible standards-based geographic
indication systems for cannabis Jeanine
lives in Mendocino County and has over
20 years of cannabis cultivation
experience in 2012 she stopped
cultivating cannabis to take up cannabis
patient and policy advocacy she is the
co-founder of the Mendocino Appalachians
project which is now a regionally
sponsored project of origins Council and
serves on the board of directors for the
4/20 archive which is devoted to
collecting preserving and sharing the
history of cannabis culture and
prohibition in the United States Janine
is also a founding board member for the
Mendocino cannabis Alliance formed in
2019 from 2017 to 2022 served on the
board of directors for the can of
California Growers Association I'm Omar
if you're if you're able I'd love for
you to introduce yourself and tell us
tell us a little bit about yourself sure
my name is Omar Figueroa I am currently
in Sevastopol in Sonoma County I've been
a lawyer doing cannabis law for 21 years
when I started out the only type of
cannabis law
available with freedom defense
liberating cultivators to have been
charged with felony cultivation back
before 2016 the cultivation of a single
plant for any purpose was deemed a
felony and it was a pretty serious
offense and so like with you know other
lawyers like with Heather we did a lot
of Academy's defense over the years and
then and I developed a passion for
representing cannabis growers because
they were like the nicest of all the
defendants they were responsible they
were peaceful they did all their
homework they did community service you
know they were like just really you know
the kind of people that I looked up to
and so I'm you know in my pursuit of the
world's finest cannabis because I had no
skills as a grower I focused on the
pending growers because they had you
know certainly like the highest quality
and you know that it was like there's
like a saying back in the day you know
solve the rest and smoke the best or
whatever and usually the lawyers we get
something called a head stash which was
like the very finest part of the
cannabis so I guess if I were a wine
aficionado you know I would have said
that I pursued you know my journey you
know for cannabis is I was like seeking
the world's best cannabis and since I
didn't have the skills to produce it I
focused on representing those who did so
I wasn't a cannabis community myself as
a young person and saw my friends
getting arrested and wanted to do
something about it so we went to law
school and became a lawyer and I'm
really lucky that I was good at it and I
enjoyed it and and at some point you
know write out a lot so actually went to
work for Omar he was my first mentor out
of law school and I worked for him for
about two years which was awesome
because we got to learn really fun
exciting and all sorts of crazy emotions
and we got to work I got to working
primarily for cannabis farmers and for
people who are like my friends at family
and it was really exciting intro to the
law to practice Omar style like most
have a really fun new novel ideas that
we litigated in one all the time because
this you know cannabis law and where
we're at right now it has been such like
it's a watershed moment and so a lot of
these laws were right for winning and it
was really exciting time as a new lawyer
now going to oh you're ten years and the
entire time has been practice been
supporting cannabis farmers so people
say like what kind of lawyer are you am
I or what are gamba farmers in need of
right now that's the kind of law I
practice and so a lot of times when we
see these big shifts in the laughs I'll
just get really deep into those areas of
law and the policies and learn that area
of law and I've done that now probably
do every time and I'm really excited for
the Appalachian program because in my
mind you know the Appalachian program if
we can get it right this could be the
program that we have been working for
for so long I mean just had the
opportunity the potential here to really
like support candid farmers and not just
any cannabis farmers but like our legacy
heritage producing canvas farmers and
our legacy producing regions and that's
me is so excited exciting so I've kind
of shifted my practice towards
Appalachians in a big way and right now
it's mostly you know pro bono work
policy work and really just what I like
to do on my free time because it's so
important but in any event I represent
canvass farmers I live in Nevada City
I've been here for five or six years and
Sonoma County before that I went to
Humboldt State and just in a couple
months my son is going to college and
humble and I will be moving back there
so I'm really excited to be where I
think we were going to have the greatest
concentration of cannabis farmers doing
appellations work and to see how that
you know unfolds over the next few years
to me and to be an observer and a
supporter and that is just the highest
honor that I think that I'll probably
ever get in my career I'm really
grateful I'm grateful to be here I'm
grateful to work with all of you guys so
thank you
thanks Heather I really appreciate your
work and welcome Richard thank you for
your presentation I caught most of it
and that's always learned so much when I
listen to you so thank you so much for
joining us