[Music]
you know I've been in it for a handful
of years you've been it for some time
but I think the the common ground we
have is both coming up in the Bay Area
you know myself in Marin County and kind
of being apart and seeing the scene as
it evolved the Waldos were around before
my time but talking about strains and
specific so it seems like things have
changed a lot right
I mean well let's roll it back a little
bit right because there was a time when
there weren't strains right and true did
come up in California over the last 15
years but before that I was on the East
Coast yeah and the first long stretch a
period of time right we didn't have
strains of cannabis we had source
countries so you would talk about
Jamaica and you would talk about
Columbia and you would talk about
Nepalese tempo balls you would talk
about redneck Lebanese hash we would
talk about cherry oil you would talk
about you talk about Thai sticks and
this is all what came off the ships
right this is yeah so well if you were
lucky it came off an airplane because
airplanes tend to preserve the preserve
the quality of terpenes terpenes get
very degraded by salt air right so so in
the days of Columbian weed when we were
getting like massive amounts of
Columbian coming in there was there was
weed that was flown in there was
airplane weed right and that was really
beautiful super Turkey really sticky not
super compressed and very expensive like
twice as expensive as what we called the
boat weed and the boat weed would be
pressed into bales and it would just be
trucked up in these freighters and and
it was you know they were in bilges they
were exposed to to salt air and so they
got oxidized lost a lot of their terpene
content and because they were bricked up
in order to get more into the boat so
you know could be could be more
reasonably priced they were also they
kind of fell apart they had a lot of
shaken up right so there was there was
plain weed and and there was boat weed
back in the days before there was even
strains right so that it's so
interesting to hear that Ike's myself
you know so I'm a
born in the 70s but came up in the 80s
and being in Northern California even
though we had a lot going on and in our
back yard proverbial back yard as you
know we would always talk about brick
weed or ditch weed the stuff that was
coming in bricks over the border from
Mexico and then the the top shelf for us
in this was just to identify my my
generation was Northern Lights that was
really like at that point you know that
this was after our Co poco gold but this
is before the Kushans got crazy and some
of these other you know long before
cookies and skittles and all these other
crazy genetics but to your point
auditioning because we had the same
thing there was kind of like there was
the okay and then there is a great and
we just classified him as its breaker it
must be Northern Lights so so do you
know do you know who who would we
consider the Johnny Appleseed of of
cannabis who is the guy most responsible
for the fact that we actually have
strains of cannabis that we're working
with today that's an excellent question
I'll tell you who I think the candidate
is a guy named Neville shoemaker Neville
shoemaker started Neville's original
seed bank
I believe in 1984 Neville very very
interesting cat dual Australian and and
Dutch citizenship lived in Australia
developed a passion for cannabis he was
the first guy that went all over the
world collecting landrace strains of
cannabis indigenous strains of cannabis
and so forth right and he was the first
guy he was the first guy that bred a lot
of what we called the first generation
of cannabis hybrids now from those
landrace strains right so Neville was
like like a lot of us then he was struck
by what I call divine madness right we
were just so fucking sick of cannabis
prohibition of being closed into this
box of being denied something that was
our right that it made us kind of crazy
and we were just determined we weren't
going to take it anywhere right
so Neville went out on a limb and he
started sending thousands and thousands
and thousands of cannabis seeds to the
United States right via mail order right
it was Neville's original
seedbank and he was the first guy that
sent seeds to the United States this is
in the middle of the 1980s when Ronald
Reagan and his crazy wife Nancy are on
the warpath right sterile hates for dare
program of 1983 in LA it all started
right here where we are that's what's
crazy yeah so Nevel is living in the
Netherlands where he's doing this
completely legal for him to be sending
cannabis seeds all over the world
including to the United States under
Dutch law not legal under US law well
not according to the DEA because what
they did and this was a you know one of
the darkest chapters in the war on
cannabis is that Neville went to
Australia to visit his daughter to visit
his daughter and the and because they
could not arrest him in the Netherlands
the US authorities the DEA arrested him
in Australia on a conspiracy warrant in
the United States and had they been
successful in that prosecution my friend
Neville would be in prison in the United
States to this day today that was how
many charges they had stacked up on him
okay for sending cannabis seeds to
people who needed them he was going to
get life in prison
okay Neville fortunately you know we had
to kind of be wily in those days to
survive and he was being helped each
other out somehow on Neville managed to
escape from the Australian jail that he
was being held in managed to get a
passport in somebody else's name that
got him out of the country and into the
Netherlands and and ever since then and
this is decades ago Neville has been a
prisoner in the Netherlands it's a big
jail but he hasn't been able to leave
the country because he's afraid that if
he does he's going to be arrested by US
authorities so even in this day and age
the last time I talked to him he did not
want to come to you he wanted to come to
the United States he wanted to see this
because he's one of the guys most
responsible for this amazing thing this
whole cannabis Renaissance that's
happening now
so it that was the beginning however of
a long and difficult saga for him that
basically wrecked his personal and
financial life and separated him from
his family and he endured years and
years and years of persecution had a lot
of his work appropriated by by other
people and it's one of the most tragic
chapters in the war on cannabis but
Neville right Neville should always be
remembered as the guy who first saw over
the horizon who understood that there
was going to be such a thing as modern
cannabis genetics went out and got those
landrace strains preserved them combined
them a true visionary Thank You Neville
yeah in such a great story I mean now
that segues into a question I have for
you because you've built such a great
brand it offers such a phenomenal
product and you've supported the small
boutique hoop growers over the years up
in Northern California and a lot of
those strains it's they've kind of got a
little diluted right I mean are there do
you ever feel like there's a point where
I mean I know myself me a little bit of
a seed hunter I wanted true Acapulco
gold and supposedly ecstasy out in
Amsterdam has it I want to stop and see
if they do but a true non back bred
crossbred Northern Lights I'd like to
find that do you think there's some
potential in finding those original true
pure strains in this day of crazy
cookies and and pushes and every other
thing that's going on in the trendy
space of industries well it's a race
against time right there's people like
Neville and people who have come after
Neville who have made it their business
to to go into the farthest valleys and
the highest mountains on this planet and
find indigenous land race strains of
cannabis hopefully you know folks are
doing a very good job with preserving
those those original genetics you know I
I think that what we've seen since the
seed bank is a is a one really great
thing right which is that the overall
quality of cannabis around the world is
much much much higher than it ever was
before right over the course of the last
three decades the can
this consumer has been exposed to much
higher quality of cannabis steadily
increasing quality of cannabis and
that's a great thing but what's also
happened along the way is is that
there's just been a huge amount of
genetic crossbreeding and hybridization
until there's an awful lot of strains
out there that are awfully much like
everything else that's out there that
don't have a lot of distinctive
character do so nowadays I always tell
people if they're gonna bring me flour
and I have to ration myself smoking
flour because I've smoked so much flour
in my life my lungs are bearing the load
right laughter it's got to be really
special right so I always tell people
bring me the ugly but don't bring me the
perfect round dense lovely right I don't
want to see that I want to see something
ugly right because if it's ugly most
likely it's gonna have some kind of
distinctive character in there right and
that's and I want to see distinctiveness
so I think that we're also seeing a real
shift in what people are breeding for
right people are becoming more and more
sophisticated so in the early days
breeders didn't have any access to
analytics so the only way that you could
test your product was by seeing how
potent it was by trying it and smoking
it right well that was good for building
your THC content but not very good for
any of the other 400 cannabinoids or
hundreds of different terpenes that are
out there right definitely
so a story that illustrates that when I
was a co-founder steep hill laboratory
the first cannabis analytics laboratory
and when we ran our first 2,000 samples
of cannabis from California's medical
cannabis market all came from Harborside
only ten of them had measurable
quantities of CBD really ten right why
because every grower was trying to
maximize their revenue and the way that
you maximize your revenue is by
maximizing your potency and in the
process of maximizing potency without
even knowing what they were doing people
selected out CBD from the genetic pool
so the Harlequins the Suzie Q's
the Charlotte's Web I mean the ac/dc s
I'm a medical advocate and having for
your cancer survivor so I do look at it
from a medicinal standpoint I've always
been a fan of either high CBD s or at
least a one to one right to get a bit of
that body of mine so those just weren't
weren't the thing because they had been
weaned out so much to your point through
the 80s the 90s this whole we had we had
we had to build CBD back into the
cannabis genetics pool right it wasn't
there everybody had been selecting for
high potency and had just inadvertently
without even knowing it without trying
to had eliminated basically eliminated
CBD and that was that was disturbing to
me because like you I understood the
therapeutic implications of that right
and that there that there would be
millions of people who would not get the
profound therapeutic benefits of CBD and
particularly people like children with
intractable epilepsy right so we
actually had to do it things that we
didn't ever do in any other program in
order to get CBD back into the genetics
right so when I first went to growers
like after we got these results I was
like oh my god I got to get more flowers
to grow CBD rich cannabis right so I go
to them and I would say hey I want you
to grow this cannabis that's rich in CBD
and they would be like dude what are you
you want me to grow with it doesn't get
you high what happens if you get raided
this is back in George Bush days what
happens if you get raided and you're not
here and I'm gonna sell the weeds it
doesn't get people high so we did
something we never did right which is we
paid growers in advance for weed that
had not been grown yet so that they
would grow CBD rich cannabis that's what
we had to do in the beginning right
[Music]