[Music]
so um the amount the the temperature and
the amount of dissolved oxygen are two
big factors that dictate the rate of
multiplication of life in the tea right
yeah depend temperature um yeah those
are the two biggest factors that and
what you started off with um so it's uh
having kind of a clean slate for them
usually when I'm starting te's I'll be
measuring three things I'll be I'll be
measuring the PPM the total dissolved um
particulate that's in that and uh I'll
be measuring ideally dissolved oxygen
and temperature of the water and um the
the
temperature you know has has a huge role
to play in that it's uh it's you know
biology in 80° water is going to
explode uh you know 50° water it's going
to
just just like a person you're not going
to be moving very far very fast if it's
3et of snow and 20° outside but if
you're you know in the tropics and hot
and humid well you probably wouldn't be
moving as fast as but you know if you
have a nice comfortable day where it's
you know 60 something and and a light
Breeze then you know you're going to be
able to run a marathon totally and that
brings up a good point too in that the
temperature and the ppms both have a
direct correlation effect to dissolved
oxygen so if temperature is too high
your dissolved oxygen potential of what
you can actually reach hits a ceiling at
80° you can't reach the same dissolved
oxygen level that you can at 65° and the
same thing with ppms you said to start
off a clean slate so a clean slate means
there's plenty of room for dissolved
oxygen and there's plenty of room for
biology to grow but as you add food
sources in there and you add your ppms
of say a fish Emulsion as a food source
for your biology if you had too much of
it then there's no room for the life to
grow and there's no the dissolved oxygen
levels come down as the ppms go up also
so you want to make sure there's a
balance there of the right temperature
and the right ppms or your dissolved
oxygen level won't be able to get high
enough that's so a lot of the best te's
that I personally have created over the
years are based on kind of that less is
more type mentality too um and really
kind of one of the one of the resources
for me in getting started in all this
was was Dr Lingham was the soyo food web
and you can find that online and um I I
absolutely um love everything that she
has you know she to me is one of the um
kind of founders of this whole practice
one of one of the originals and and the
the stuff that she has
done um was was really what got me kind
of interested in it and then pursuing
you know was kind of the mentality that
I had as I started to you know Branch
out and try and learn a little bit more
because she she does tend to lean on you
know she almost takes a don't to
anything type of approach um you know
very very light hands when it comes to
uh manipulating soil ecosystems from
from her line from uh from from her
mentality whereas for us with cannabis
you know we we can hit the throttle a
little bit harder and it does have a
direct effect on yield and this stuff is
all about you know
medicine absolutely but you know yield
is is everything for us and uh yield and
product quality so we we can manipulate
a lot of that stuff a little bit safely
but generally speaking less is more um I
have created better I have created More
explosively Alive te's using really
minimal
input
um far more than using you know some of
some of the products you might buy where
you use them at at their full
recommended dose and what you end up
what you end up with is a solution that
has some bacteria in it but it also has
a whole lot of fish and a whole lot of
kelp and a whole lot of humic that isn't
necessarily being utilized just yet
whereas the purpose of the compost te is
not necessarily to you can use this as a
mixing tank for fertilizer if you want
to but really the purpose of the the tea
practice or Brewing compost teas is uh
for me more about the biology like that
other stuff is a separate practice so
the biology is one part of it and then
the foods that you might introduce to
this last minute right before you put it
out okay then then we're to start you
know then we're walking in different you
we're talking a little bit different
game we're talking about a feeding
regiment not biology whereas the the
term compost te in a lot of cases in our
industry you know I mean our industry
does have a lot of kind of misused terms
you know like
um you know Master grower is actually a
certification it's not something that
you just say oh I've been growing canab
I'm a master grower no that's actually a
certification that people go through and
you'll find that people that um are
taking care of very complicated uh
botanical gardens with thousands of
species that's generally a master grower
um so it's just kind of that that term
compos T tends to kind of be this
all-encompassing thing where you know
anybody that's using this kind of
mentality well it's all considered comp
te and for me compos te is more about
the biology specifically and then you
can combine that with fertilizers with
nutrition with Plant Nutrition and
obviously they're not only compatible
but they're in a direct relationship so
they kind of get tossed in the same boat
a lot but uh yeah I tend to take the
less more it's almost like the t is
creating the army of helpers to help the
The Roots break down what the part two
is which is the nutrients you would then
introduce into the yeah environment and
so if you're using Nutri that are easily
broken down by the biology in my
experience it's a little more beneficial
to divide them up do one that's all
biology or almost entirely biology and
then you can I mean you can even use the
Brewing you know you can even use the
tea tank to do it but then you brew up
your nutrients or you know mix up your
nutrients and put those on um you know
and then obviously there's a timing
factor with there too and that well do
you want to lay down the food and then
introduce the biology to it or do you
want to introduce the biology and then
put the food in a lot of that comes down
to what kind of rates are you using how
fast are you trying to do it um because
the idea behind a lot of this is to keep
that soil ecosystem as stable as
possible because that to me is where a
lot of when things get thrown out of
balance in the ecosystem that's what
leaves the door open for things like
pathogens to come in whereas if you have
a like like you we kind of talk a little
bit about that jungle mentality if
you've got a a jungle where you know the
hunters come through and they pick off a
bunch of the Predators then you have an
explosion of you know versus a healthy
jungle that has never been touched and
everything is kind of in Balance well
anytime you throw
in anything from the outside you're
throwing that out of balance a little
bit so as little as you can throw those
things out of balance and that includes
like your your feeding rates you know I
mean for me nutrition specifically they
a lot a lot of the nutrient companies
will tell you you know feed this stuff
at full strength but then every every
other watering you have to use
water why because there's an excess of
stuff in there and you have to rinse it
out in order to introduce new stuff to
it when hold on a second I just put it
in there on purpose and now I'm rinsing
it out so I can add more uh a lot of
that mentality is coming from they want
to sell you nutrients whereas if you
introduce that stuff in a very light
amount all the time what you're
mimicking is rain coming down through a
healthy compost layer washing down a
relatively consistent amount of these
things down into the soil to where the
soil is never really thrown way out of
whack um different parts of the Year
obviously you go through the winter it's
going to affect the biology and you're
going to end up with it in the spring
you're going to end up with like kind of
that new flush of of uh of nutrients
down to the soil and they get used up at
different rates but really for me
keeping it balanced is about using
minimal input and in using minimal input
you can do it consistently you can do it
all the time and if you're doing it all
the time you can actually have a little
bit more direct relationship with what
effect that's having on the plant um
because with a lot of this stuff mean if
you hit if you hit these plants with you
know
1600 full dose of something yeah you're
going to see a a bang of a result but
then if you try and do that repeatedly
you're not going to see the same result
whereas if you feed things a little bit
at a time slowly over time what you'll
see is a much more natural kind of cycle
whereas those other Cycles will Spike U
you know when when you're spiking the
nutrients and a lot of that stuff is
either a insoluble which means not
readily available to the plant which is
why you have to rinse it out or uh you
know the plant's not able to take up the
the the even the soluble stuff there's
so much of it in a lot of what we tend
to feel from the kind of common
fertilizer regiments there's so much of
it in there the plant can't use it which
is again why you get back to that meing
to flush it out of the
system um so I tend to lean towards
having everything available on a light
scale and then if I want to bump that up
during certain periods you know if you
want to bump up nitrogen a little bit
here and then you want to you know bring
the nitrogen down a little bit while
you're increasing you know again NPK
through that cycle so you know
NPK or n and then p and then K I would
tend to lean more towards this rather
than
this and that's a lot easier to do if
you're um just feeding things light and
you're kind of dividing up those two you
know the food and the tea are definitely
separate entities although they
generally are thrown into the same term
compos so what what would be the
frequency of T feeding like we we talked
about about those three scenarios right
like one cocktail that would be more
conducive to uh you know new clone put
into the sterile grow media uh are you
doing that just once like on initial
transplant it really depends on your
media so if you have a sterile media
that's not necessarily going to support
these things you introduce this whole
ecosystem into a
desert um it's not going to last very
long and it's going to end there's going
to be certain species that will become
dominant very fast and a lot of the
other ones won't be able to compete or
will not have their preferred uh Foods
or ecosystem that and they'll start to
die off um with something like an
organic an organic base blend that's
been commercially bashed and it's just
not very broken down generally you don't
have to do it that that often I tend to
hit it pretty
hard you know at first just to get
everything established but then if you
just kind of let everything reach a
natural equilibrium you taper off a
little bit if you're using a sterile
media um obviously that's not going to
support that that life and so um you
know you're going to introduce it and
it's not really going to have much to
feed on except in a lot of cases
synthetic nutrients unless you're doing
something you know really organic again
is another term that you know there's
all kinds of different what is true
organic versus what is Omri certified or
different things and so if you're
introducing you know nutrients that will
keep biology alive on a regular basis
and and trying to keep that biology
stable um doesn't always work out and
and uh um so for me it kind of depends
on what media you're using if you're
using if you're using a rich like
backyard compost then you're not using
this to do anything at all what you're
doing is taking that stuff and rinsing
it in here to use it somewhere
else so on that level the ecosystem is
there it's established it's healthy and
you don't really need to do much to it
at all whereas if you're using something
that's like pure cocoa well you've got
these these materials the nutrients that
you're putting into the soil and
building up um it's a good idea in my my
experience I believe I've seen results
you know again not a biologist and how
do you test this stuff in these type of
environments you know I'm not in a
laboratory
so um in those type of in those type of
situations it's something where you
would follow up almost every te almost
every feeding with at least a light te
um because it it that's that's what's
going to speed up the breakdown of what
you just introduced that a lot of which
is not necessarily immediately available
for the plants and the biology is what
make what makes it available so it's
almost like introducing nutrients into a
healthy compost that's alive that soil
will Auto will will immediately start to
break that stuff down and it'll happen
relatively quickly um whereas a sterile
media you introduce the nutrients and
it's going to take them longer to break
down because the biological activity
going on in that soil is to is a much
lesser scale
[Music]