[Music]
best practice is having personnel files
disciplinary files handbooks policies
procedures those sort of things in place
so that when an environment which right
now is very collegial and everybody sort
of knows each other and is growing
together goes through some sort of a
cyclical nature and people need to be
let go or someone has a performance
issue and they claim discrimination and
or or something along those lines the
company has something to go back to to
say well these were our policies and
procedures for example here's the
discipline we gave you these are the
warnings we gave you here's our open
door policy for example if you really
had all these concerns which are now
voicing and you didn't voice way back
when why not those sort of things so
that's that's been a big issue
compliance front on the discrimination
and harassment front I think a lot of
what we've seen is a nascent industry
sort of growing up very quickly and in
the early days of the industry you would
have everybody sort of being friends
they everybody sort of knows each other
or they're referred in from somebody
they know it's a very comfortable
situation because not a lot of
boundaries or rules or policies or
procedures in place to sort of lay some
of the expectations out there and things
were pretty loose that's a bad
environment to be in from an employer
standpoint because people will right or
wrong
get the understand that they can get
away with certain things that certain
behavior might be okay and this industry
whereas if you went to work for a law
firm and you wore a suit and tie just by
operation
you're addressed in the environment
really you might think oh well this
doesn't really fly the cannabis industry
is no different than any other other
industry you you are employers these are
your employees you have to take steps to
create a professional environment so
that individuals understand we don't
want you doing certain things and if
you're an employee that is subjected to
some behavior that they don't like we
want you to tell us about it so that we
can take steps and we have policies and
procedures out there that tell anybody
in the universe if you tell us about
stuff we will do something about that's
the sort of environment that you want to
create in a business to put yourself at
least in a good starting spot if
something that happens people are going
to do stupid things it's just human
nature but from a company standpoint if
you can show that you have a policy you
have a procedure you have an open door
and over time you've got a track record
for doing stuff when people complain
that pushing that that seemed possible
if somebody does something stupid and
another employee harasses another
employee my analogy or my example of
what like would be appropriate somewhere
is like in the NBA on the basketball
team they Pat each others butts yeah
what would happen if you were walking
back to the hall and one of your
colleagues like pat you on the button
man like you rocked it in court
yesterday yeah you'd be like that was
weird
yeah they're theirs without going too
deep into the definition of sexual
harassment there is a context to some of
these things and and there's some famous
cases out there one involving a bunch of
writers for the show friends whether
developing topics for the show and the
nature of the business is talking about
relationships and sex and who's sleeping
with who or which relationship in that
context there's going to be a discussion
about sex but if you're a you know line
worker at McDonald's and you're making
hamburgers there's no reason for you to
be discussing sex with your coworkers
similarly in this in the cannabis space
there's a conversation probably that
would take place about legalization of
drugs
or legalization of cannabis or that's
what the stuff but outside of that
there's really no you know why would you
be discussing sex for example or race or
maybe the the topic would be social
equity and there's a discussion about
social equity what that means in that
context okay but to discuss somebody
else's race and oh I heard you're a
particular race and does that mean that
you are blind there we're outside the
bounds of what the context of that
discussion should be given the industry
so yeah it just needs to become more
professional I think is the overarching
theme that we're trying to tell people
and what we're sort of encountering is
the very loose very relaxed environment
some of which business owners are
telling us well this is what I want and
we're telling them look no good deed
goes unpunished if you have this very
lacks environment that's okay people are
jeans and t-shirts to work but you also
need to have a conversation with your
employees about what sort of behavior is
appropriate and what's expected of them
so that they don't mistake the fact that
you can wear shorts and a t-shirt to
work to mean you can wear certain
outfits to work that are going to be
inappropriate or because a female
employees wearing a particular outfit
and mail-away can start commenting on
her body it's just they don't so some of
the things that if you were to grow up
as a business you what like employee
handbooks and training programs and can
you just give me some examples of like
some easy low-hanging fruit that a
business that has no procedures or
protocols or best practices could yep
started on in terms of blocking and
tackling some of the basics of nmv
there's there's sort of things that you
have to have by law in terms of your
payroll records if you have a commission
agreement with an employee has to be in
writing you have to keep certain you
have to provide certain notices to
individuals when they're hired these
sort of things just have to be there and
you should be documenting that you're
giving these sort of things and keeping
those in a personnel file
beyond some of those mandatory things
the employee handbook would be the first
thing that I would probably mention and
there are different levels of
sophistication there's sort of a magic
number around twenty five and fifty
employees where different laws start to
kick in and so I would tell them if an
individual if you've got less than 50
employees you can have a pretty simple
handbook that sort of covers the basics
and lets you communicate your employees
what's expected of them provides
required notices and and get you going
once you get past 50 employees some
additional statutes kitchen kick in
order you have to add some things to it
but again it's not some mountainous task
a lot of the stuff that sort of in the
can and a good lawyer or a good HR
consultant couldn't give it to you
pretty quickly the other thing that is
somewhat required somewhat recommended
would be training so if you're in
California you've got employees you
should be training your managers on
sexual harassment there's a requirement
under the law beyond that in terms of
educating managers it's not required by
the law but like a handbook I would
encourage employees or employer or its
excuse me cannabis businesses to be
doing it teach them what disability and
lead management looks like a lot of
times people don't understand what an
individual's rights are in terms of if
they're sick or they're disabled or
they're injured on the job what they
should be doing that's a giant area of
liability right now for employers across
all industries and cannabis will be no
exception teach managers about that
hours and wage and hour issues teacher
managers about that if you have an
expectation that people are working a
particular schedule help them understand
that help them understand what the
requirements for meal periods and rest
breaks are educate them on the fact that
they can't be changing employees work
hours or or adjusting clocks without
legitimate reasons and some
documentation on those try to stave off
some of the stuff that will get you soon
if something happens again from an
employer standpoint you want to be able
to say this is outside the no one this
is not what we expected whether it's
discrimination or a manager manipulating
somebody's timecard you want to be able
to show from the company standpoint
that's not the expectation that's not
what you want and you had some effort
out there to try to prevent it from
happening again people will do silly
things and they will make mistakes but
the more you can do from a company
standpoint to show but that's not what
was expected this is not a company-wide
practice or procedure the better you
will do it stay tuned off you know big
damage claims punitive damages certain
penalty provisions
[Music]