okay we are live on the book of faces
California operators data geeks who look
at retail and brand data and can drop
knowledge and insights we have
regulation gurus so I'm Peter Suvari and
that is me and we're gonna kick it off
with Tamar from BDS who's gonna give us
a quick quick snapshot in time knowledge
data dump of what she's seen in the
cannabis market mostly in California so
tomorrow take it away we will be
covering some high-level market insights
and Kovach 19 update and then
specifically focusing a little bit at
the end on upcoming trends but as I'm
hearing on the street I'm not
necessarily anything that will be
showing via the data but just to kick
off the discussion in terms of what we
can expect oh well we can all hope to
see with the development of cannabis
post these crazy - Kovach 19 days let's
start off with a little bit of a higher
view a little bit of a macro perspective
just again understanding of you know the
significance the US markets specifically
in California so looking out and then of
course 2020 through 2020 or 2025 details
we can see that currently not
surprisingly the US and Canada make up
the majority of global sales that's
expected to continue to be the case
through 20 to 25 however I do want to
just call out that current you know
obviously you have more activity from
other countries currently us in Canada
represent about 90 percent of all global
cannabis spending and so really they are
the dominant players in global cannabis
at the moment and looking specifically
within the u.s. at the
legal markets right medical and adult
use in this case for 2019 and 2025 we
can see the California obviously has
been and is going to continue to be one
of the primary drivers of growth for the
US market and of course as we look to
other states coming online specifically
Florida New York with adult use with
adult use sales we can expect a
significant market when those come
online by 2025
obviously that's driving a lot of that
the u.s. volume that we expect to see by
them now of course all of this is
accounting for the covered 19 impact
however of course it's important to call
out that we are going to have a you know
regulatory and legislative impacts due
to due to Co bid obviously slowing
things down and not just the federal
level but this the local level as well
now looking specifically at Co very 19's
impact on cannabis so zooming in a
little bit into the legal cannabis
markets we can see that almost all
markets posed growth in March over
previous months Nevada's a little bit of
an exception obviously there were a lot
of significant restrictions in the
Nevada market around delivery only for
adult youth sales now a market that's
also highly dependent on tourism when
tourism is essential as a stem cell is
going to be even further impacted by
that lack of foot traffic and so so not
surprising to see Nevada take a little
bit of a hit however we did see medical
sales in Nevada
take a little bit of a spike you can see
that broken out here but at least
medical sales were up in that it I'm now
looking at sort of ranking of maturity
by markets and
we can see that the more mature cannabis
mark it's actually are the ones that
fared better with the Cova 19 in fact
not surprising right that the older
markets the more mature markets rather
obviously california's younger than
organ in colorado but it's in in in
legality but it's more mature and and
how long it's it's been operating and so
it's not surprising obviously to see
that the younger states with the newer
ordinances were more severely impacted
right and we've seen this before but in
case we have an i'm just going to focus
on a few key points first of all we're
looking right now across all states not
just California all legal states in the
US we can see this you know surges that
we've all seen already on of course the
Friday the 13th March 13th when the
pandemic was announced we see the 316
Monday surge right where the
shelter-in-place was announced and then
and then of course continuing into that
following Friday we see a typical Friday
surge and then however you she had
dropped following those that initial
stock up right so so you can see
obviously a slight decline right after
that initial stock up where daily sales
are following falling below average but
that's start as you can see it picks
back up coming in to 420 and actually
looking specifically at California we
can see that the dip below average is
Nestle slight dip in those days between
the surge and coming back into 420 but
not as much as as all states combined so
we're definitely seeing California as we
mentioned before right a more mature
market that's capable of handling a lot
of these supply chain disruptions in
this case it was a demand disruption
right you know
and followed by erratic mainly alow and
but but but what we did see in
California more specifically and that's
actually across all states but we saw a
slight decline in the early transactions
but an increase in the average
transaction value which is further now
promoting the notion that the consumers
were stocking up right in advance of the
uncertainty right but you saw them
making fewer purchases but larger
transactions and now one of the big
questions right that you know I am um
proposing to myself and you know bookie
than I out in our research is is it is
this indicative of consumers consuming
more right obviously I mean the purchase
purchasing less frequently income but
they're producing at a significantly
higher act are they going to blow
through that there now that everyone's
at home right I know I for I for a fact
from a flower consumer and I'm
definitely concerned making more than
more than or coal so see if that's
something that that continues I have a
quick question about this um any
indication if the stimulus payments have
played a role in now in sales yes and so
actually I'm glad you brought that up I
have a note here not until so coming
into 420 we were actually pretty
concerned I don't know
we as an industry also PBS on Linux but
everybody was keeping an eye out to see
how 4/20 was there and as you may or may
not be aware that you do have instead of
one major assertive day on 4/20 you've
got some certain states leading up to
420 right and you can definitely see
that when the government stimulus tip
started with them in fortunately for
everyone just in time for 4/20 as well
as for the consumer but also what's
great about it is you know the way
California at least there was a
flattened delete button the 4/20 / but
incentive going around that flooding
into the shops on 4/20 right and
obviously defines social distancing
requirements so so yeah that's good to
see that and he actually managed to find
the fourth 23rd checks coming in
certainly aided with for 2014
nonetheless 4/20 wasn't bigger than the
surge day of March the biggest surge day
of March March 13th in fact March 13th
was the third biggest day in California
across all of history so March 13
through 16
yeah mic restriction was the biggest day
across all history so sorry excuse me
March 16 in dollar sales legal tract
market history let's just be clear
doctor yes legal legal legal California
history yes and and that's third to I
think 420 of 2017 and 2018 so obvious
sorry excuse me 2018 and 20 no 2759 2019
correction so 2018 obviously was still
getting its feet off the ground with a
new adult new sales and then 2020 as we
can see here they actually managed
flatten we did not want to see a surge
on 4/20 and we did it well we did but
not as big as it should have been had we
not flattened before 23rd um all right
so now with in price point bands right
so we see that not surprising right in
addition to consumers you know making
fewer transactions right obviously with
limitations on I'm going into shops and
and such and with a higher transaction
values we're also seeing that the
majority of the volume behind
transactions is actually driven with the
lower price point products wares are
buying they're trading down so they're
buying more cheaper products overall
right now of course a lot of this is
driven by flour and I didn't I don't
have any slides pulled up to reflect
that I intended to but enough time so we
can you can do another time but but I
can tell you that a lot of lower priced
volume is driven by the flour category
which did see a bit of a surge on these
or did see a bit of a peak on these peak
days along with edibles and things
actually and interestingly looking right
now just at California and shop and have
store pickup and delivery right we can
see when I say pick up and curbside
picked up we can see that you know
following the immediate days of the
announcements and with state with the
state allowing for curbside right for
justin regulations to offer curbside
delivery we see curbside beginning to
take share i'm in terms of consumer
fulfillment type or purchasing
fulfillment and incidentally that trend
seems that now also delivery took share
right well delivery maintain share we're
actually seeing that as as sheltering in
place restrictions start to ease and
consumers start to to get back out
actually in-store is beginning to take
share back away from curbside pickup but
delivery is maintaining all right so now
focusing on the california
humor a little bit I mean we're just
like a quick over you kind of question
um would you say that the market is up
down or roughly where it was in relation
so if if you see if you look here and
actually let's just kind of stay on
California so you can see California for
the most part is is where it was we are
however though okay look this is looking
through the first few days of May if you
kind of look for you know similar view
is just daily conductions and average
average transaction value but daily
transactions we are certain we are
starting to see and I count these few
data points is at the beginning of May
but even further I mean the you know
until we're mid May now so the last week
or so we have been seeing a slight
return to normal in increase in sales
also we're starting to see more regular
cyclical you know weekly trending you
know we see the general peaks on the
Fridays right before people go into the
weekend so post paycheck and and before
they go into the weekend right we're
starting to see that come back to normal
right so we saw our last you know Friday
last real Friday on March 20th right and
then that's when you know you started to
have you know abnormal blow slightly
below average transactions are taking
place right daily transactions taking
place and now coming into the first
Friday of me and and and second Friday
of May which I don't have displayed here
but I can tell you that we're starting
to see normal weekly cyclical activity
taking place at them so hopefully
hopefully that means that that means
that we can expect things to be you know
going somewhat back to normal right I of
this depends on on when people get their
jobs back right I changes regionally
speaking specifically to California I
know there's still a lot of question
marks around the timeline
but but the biggest question really is
around the uncertainty around consumer
spending right I mean how tight are
there pockets going to be and will they
continue spending on cannabis will they
trade down either to lower to your or
price products that like we saw over
here or will they leave the legal market
altogether right all of that remains to
be seen
I'm also wondering does your data tell
you about new people coming into the
cannabis market locked up people who are
like new to it I you know what asking me
shall receive two seconds so so actually
looking let's look specifically
California but yes one one of the
questions I've been posing right and now
are jumps of consumer research right we
do semi-annually we do quantitative
surveys asking you know the consumers as
well as the acceptors and rejecters
we'll get into that in a second about
the cannabis preferences activities
consumption habits etc now we are
currently in the field with our sixth
wave okay so we will be collecting
information on changes in consumer you
know among the acceptors is what we call
them but but you know as a result of
this Cove in 1910 endemic now I before I
jump into discussing the acceptor or
what I like to call the new consumer or
the consumer coming in let's just talk
about the existing consumer in
California so you know benchmarking to
other states we can see that when when
I'm looking here the you know poor older
older than California adult you say it's
right you can see that California still
got a ways to go right an opportunity to
capture or increase its consumer base
especially comparing it to say a
Washington or an Oregon right
well actually in Oregon Washington
actually is a little bit of a funny
state but but California you did
we did see a 60% in percent of the
California consumers from 2017 to 2019
if you benchmark that to Colorado
Colorado saw 75% in consumers over that
same time period and so we definitely do
have a nice growth potential still in
terms of capturing additional consumers
if we actually look at at this breakup
in California of the consumer acceptor
rejector now the consumer is these are
folks that don't currently consume what
are open to it I'm sorry the consumer is
sorry these are folks that consume right
you can see that purple segment in
California as we saw before slowly
increasing over time the acceptor these
are the folks that don't currently
consume but are open to it that's you
know call it your low-hanging fruit call
it your untapped target market whatever
that may be but that's a significant
portion of the population this is adults
over 21 in California that doesn't
currently consume but is waiting for
somebody to tell them what to buy and
where to buy it essentially now I've
been talking about this segment for
years years I mean you can probably I'm
sure Peter remembers me talking about
these acceptors from three four years
ago i I've been long waiting for them to
come in and I am now well we cannot
speak to this in the data just yet as
like I said we're still in the field
with the next wave of this survey I can
tell you that I have been seeing and
hearing seeing and hearing from
dispensaries right as well as
anecdotally reported from my friends my
cohort that a lot of these consumers are
now turning to cannabis right to just
solve a lot of their kovat 19 problems
if you will you know they're stuck at
home with two kids you know drinking
half a bottle of Chardonnay and I
looking to make healthier choices for
them and their family and our Chinese
and actually see Peters sharing the
photo I shared with him and now who told
this person what to buy so so so this is
my friend never she actually I've
watched over the last four years
involved from a rejecter to an acceptor
and then an exec and accepted to a
consumer and and actually that that last
evolution just took place in the last
few weeks
she called me you know you're she's your
typical I will refrain from using her
name but she's your typical Chardonnay
soccer mom you know thirty mid thirty
year old mother of to Southern
California disposable income I'm looking
to you know substitute her Chardonnay
with healthier choices and so I'm here
let me reassure my screaming again but
but this so this my you know my friend
called me a couple weeks ago and said
tell me what to buy right and I gave her
a list of a bunch of different products
to try as you can see you know mostly I
stuck to low dose wrap it on set right a
couple free rolls but you know wanted to
give her the experience of a different
ingestion or intake methods but she as
you can tell she had no problem dropping
180-190 dollars right I mean she that
was in one in one visit and so actually
as we look at you know previous slides
with in you know increased consumer
spend or average transaction size
increasing we could pose the question is
it existing cannabis consumer is buying
more low-priced products that at higher
volume right stocking off or is it
potentially some new consumer is also
coming in and spending a larger amounts
right like like this unnamed friend of
mine so that remains to be seen but I'm
actually gonna move quickly through this
because I realized I've taken way more
time than I wanted to what's important
to note here is that we're seeing the
total consumer plus acceptor base
increasing right so the total
addressable market
whether being existing humors or
prospective consumers is increasing in
California and that's always good news
and zooming through this really fast
it's a summary of the 2019 California
consumer with this fun little visual we
can see that consumer predominantly
skewed men not surprising made up of a
combo of Gen X and Gen Z Millennials
right that's mainly in that 25 to 55
demographic about 20 percent of
consumers though are in that humor 55
plus year old demographic consumers of
per month spend about 135 dollars on
average about two and a half product
really use use cannabis to relieve pain
minutes audience sleep their purchasing
is predominantly influenced by taste and
flavor which is actually something that
I noticed sort of move up and down in
terms of being number one purchase
driver our purchase influencer that has
gone up in recent waves meaning
consumers really care about taste and
flavor which I will I will touch on in a
bit obviously price but but it's always
surprising to me to see taste and for
ever have such animal looking now and
within you know we're seeing obviously
trends within a cannabinoid specific
mostly CBD products especially in the
sublingual the sublingual subcategory
distillates within the vape category
accounted for almost two thirds of sales
not surprising top-selling edible flavor
was watermelon just throwing out so
quick highlights here that I know I'm
running through and not having a lot of
color but um I do just want to wrap this
up again give me this tender to chat
we saw constitutes an hour each doing
about a billion dollars in sales in 2019
edibles almost half a million and the
top three strains of 2019 or blue dream
poison and salary so a quick question
any idea on how frequently the average
person shops goes into a place once a
week but once it
it depends I have we have insights on
that I think that I think that about
I think it's like 10 to 20 percent of
consumers shop the most frequent is once
a month and I think about 10 to 20
percent of consumers purchase about once
a month and the rest you know bell
curves from there into you know weekly
daily and you know less than once a
month but I'd have to pull those exact
numbers I don't know if they talk Amman
and so so now look you know at 2019 an
aggregate we can see that a lot of the
growth was you saw 18% growth overall
over 2018 and a lot of that growth was
driven by not surprising the
concentrates which is predominantly
driven by Bay right category still
closing 22 percent growth year over year
for a massive category which is very
impressive but we're also singing
impressive growth with smaller more
adult use oriented categories right
which isn't surprising as you look at
the image that Peter shared what my you
know my friend my anecdotal Chardonnay
soccer mom purchased we saw her
purchasing right even though yes I told
her to buy it
we saw her purchasing you know easy to
use low dose products right so pre-rolls
I put that in the easy to use not
necessarily low dose but but edibles
right sub sublinguals I mean I don't
know that you would call the nanos
sublinguals but I say the fast onset is
what I'm getting at
right she wants something that's
accurate easy to dose and and has an
onset so now obviously as this new
consumer enters right and has been
entering and we have seen an evolution
in in you know the category mix and in
general obviously you know faith has
been or had historically been grabbing
insane amounts of market share as
very easy to use discrete rapid onset
form of consumption however in aftermath
of a stay in the second half of 2019 we
definitely saw if they take a little bit
of a hit giving an opportunity obviously
for other categories to continue to
capture share such as edibles and
sublinguals as we see here but also and
improve oles excuse me sorry but also
giving an opportunity for flower to make
them a bit of a comeback and so just
kind of wrapping up what we what we just
went through you know we're going to see
bright new markets continue to come
online you know now in fact I'm hearing
specifically in California for major
markets that makeup up to about a
million and actually Dooley will
probably speak better to this hey Julie
say your pop in there but but I think
Anaheim Concord Fresno and another major
California city seem to be discussing
putting ordinances in place those four
cities together make up about a million
people in population so obviously having
these additional cities and additional
access come online will be a huge boon
to California cannabis we're gonna
continue to see this new consumer come
in right and thus the consumer evolve
the question is you know is now you know
we've seen this slow entrance of the new
consumer but is now going to be the time
right is now going to be there real in
flux is it finally as cannabis has been
deemed in a central business right
nationwide in most markets is that you
know really the stamp of approval for
the you know that final D stigmatization
right that final okay to everyone this
is a safe and healthy alternative and
and finally with that you know we're
going to see continued product
development right so to address these
new consumers who expect you know a
certain level of delivery in their
product whether it be inaccurate
accuracy with extra dosing or onset and
offset
right or even just packaging and
delivery of you know the consumer
aesthetics you know is this gonna be the
year right you know we've seen obviously
this evolution across a lot of party
categories I know we've been talking
about beverages for four years now
everyone's been expecting you know that
beverage boom that we haven't seen well
along with that new consumer starting to
or continuing to come in perhaps that a
more accelerated rate is 2020 gonna
finally be beverages this year right
with with advancements in you know on
set offset technology and emulsification
right and and and then and as well taste
and flavor which we saw I was very
important to the consumer you know
especially in recent years so I I'm
curious to see where we evolved and
that's just you know posing some
questions for the group to discuss
hopefully that was useful and yeah all
right so let's get to it