[Music]
testing changed dramatically the skill
level of the operator prior to testing
there was really no way to ascertain
what was on the cannabis and many of the
varieties in cannabis today if one wants
to chemically drive them nutritionally
speaking into a very high level of
production they become very hyper
sensitive to environmental issues such
as molds and funguses and pathogens such
as pests and so what you find is that
the amount of cannabis that was
chemically treated might have been maybe
88 90 percent of the total and so when
we started to really get into testing
you started to realize that the
predominant amount of cannabis grown not
just in Humboldt but in the industry in
general was actually contaminated with
products that were meant for
horticultural purposes not edible
purposes so ornamentals things you would
use to control the shape of a mom pack
of betrayal' growth regulators things
that are designed to create appearance
and a flower but never meant for human
ingestion mica butanol which is an equal
20 which is designed that to keep
powdery mildew off of roses unbelievably
concentrated in cannabis and so these
pesticides and fungicides and growth
regulators they all started to reveal
that we had an educational deficiency
and I think that what you really got to
see was that the growers in Humboldt
County a lot of them were able to start
to realize that they would not have an
ability to exist in the future if they
didn't start to change their practices
in terms of how does one work with this
on a regulated level and it was tough
because we don't know what to use as a
regulated level so what we did was we
took Oregon Standards because Oregon
pretty much had a pretty comprehensive
coverage and it was pretty restrictive
so probably three four years ago we
started looking at Oregon's levels of
what they were trying to put into play
and Oregon helped us really start to
understand better like what was the new
allowances of what could be used what
was legally allowed to be used and you
started to see cultivators start to
really get into best practices the
integrated pest management concepts took
off the beneficial insects to go off
people made a huge change into organic
methodologies of cultivation because
organically driven plants typically have
less problems and so it's interesting
but the testing change the production
methodologies not just that customers
get cleaner pot now but there's also a
cleaner production methodology in it so
the whole knowledge level increased
dramatically that's why I always give
Samantha Miller such a shout because
Samantha Miller went on a one-woman show
driving the importance of testing why
you use this how you use these testing
methods to improve your production and
now to keep us alive in an industry
that's highly regulated meaning that if
your product doesn't pass the lab test
you can't sell it and so for so many
people who didn't really take that
initiative early they're gonna have to
make the changes now but for a lot of
people in Humboldt
they really made the changes and they
made the changes because they would get
the lab results back and they would see
that they were dirty and it started to
make an awareness that people don't
understand residual so they don't really
understand half-life of nuclear products
and they don't understand residual
contamination from pesticides and
fungicides and exactly how long it takes
for that material that was sprayed on
your cannabis plants to dissipate to a
level that's considered safe and non
detectable and all of a sudden it was an
incredible education and people started
to realize that they not only was
selling cannabis that was saturated in
toxic they were living in saturated in
toxic production zones because they were
the ones applying it they're the ones
using it and so all of a sudden the
awareness started to increase
dramatically and you started to see
people may
better common sense decisions just based
off of this is in good period and so the
testing allowed people to really start
to make educated choices on what we used
in production because prior there really
was no real information and everyone
would say I think it's all gone there's
no residual left and with testing you
found out that you were really running
almost toxic levels of it and so it
started to really key in all these
producers that used it and because I own
a dispensary live two of them but their
drop-offs for labs which means that
people bring me their products and we
send it off to the lab for for
examination so for the nine years that
I've been running dispensaries I've seen
between ungodly number lab reports and I
know from the lab reports that we've
seen an incredible change in what the
contaminants are and what kind of drove
a lot of it was was concentrates see
concentrates became you know almost 48
percent of California's market as of
right now
and because concentrates concentrate all
things present concentrates started to
reveal residuals in a way that flour
testing never did so flour testing let
us understand was it clean as flour but
concentrate testing let us understand is
it clean as genetic source material
meaning where your mom's clean you had
to go all the way back to the material
used to create the material you use to
create your product because the
the extraction process concentrates to
such a degree that it pulled non
detectable amounts from the flower and
made it clearly detectable and clearly
non allowable for consumption and so the
concentrated industry is what really
started to force people to fix the
problems in the in the back end of the
business because the flower production
they they have clean but the mothers had
been historically so dirty so for us at
the shop we had by didn't organic
cultivator for a while but I would love
to use the tools that other people get
to use but we realized that at some
point when regulation is kicked in
everyone would be under such a
microscope that if we didn't really
practice completely and understand fully
how do you actually control these
problems to a workable degree because
you're not gonna get a sterile system in
organics right it's gonna be a
population of beneficial and predator
and so both of them prey and they're
gonna work on each other and so
ultimately it's trying to learn what is
the allowable balances and to get
customers to understand this to get
people in the real world to understand
it no chemical pesticide fungicide
growth regulator issue had really
created an artificial world of an
unattainable appearance an unattainable
production amount an unattainable
ability to have certain cultivars of
certain climactic situations so it
allowed people to get around a
tremendous amount of true agricultural
skill and practice and I think that a
lot of humble guys really really
practice they went up so all in all
testing changed this area dramatically
[Music]