[Music]
all right
this is the connoisseur kit
here it is this is the silver dragon
connoisseur kit this is a half
ounce i'm also going to have ounce
kits available in the future but this is
the half ounce kit size
but what you want to do if you want to
reuse this package
is you want to take a razor blade and
or an exacto knife you can actually peel
these off if you wanted to
actually save this or you can cut it
and then it's permanently opened and cut
inside your kit you will find your cola
jar
and you will see your
14 grams your half ounce of
bud in there on the stick this is how
a grower and all
the highest quality producers of
cannabis
of all time have really kept their weed
most
growers will keep their herb on the
stick
and with all the with many of the leaves
intact
because those leaves are going to uh
provide protection for the trichomes and
and hairs pistols and they're also going
to
provide a little bit of the moisture
reservoir in the environment around the
bud so that the bud itself doesn't dry
out too much
this little bit of extra water retention
is like having a boveda pack
or a boost pack inside of your jar
it will release that moisture over time
and make your bud stay fresher for much
longer
your bud can stay fresh on a stick like
this with the leaves
in a cool dark place for up to a year so
you'll see our lab tests here and you'll
see our
identifying functions on here
and we'll open this jar up
here child resistant child proof so you
have to push
and turn to open it and as you do so
you will then be opening the seal
uh sometimes the seal doesn't open by
taking the lid off you just peel the
seal off as you would with the vitamin
jar
this is the airtight seal keeping your
bud 100 percent airtight fresh in here
um for as long as it's on the shelf so
you know your product your if you buy
your
cannabis from us it'll be fresh
and you get to pull out your nice cola
inside here
it's gorgeous check it out see what it
really is
so you can trim them off the stick as
you need them
and leave them where they'll stay moist
and fresh
longer for longer if you choose to
and you can observe just the beauty the
raw natural beauty of the plant
itself this here is a calyx it's a
swollen
gland swollen sac
of the flower that contains
cannabinoids and terpenes
the bulk of the flowers medicine is
contained within calyxes the bud itself
is
dozens or hundreds even of
individual calyxes they're all next to
each other and each
calyx one of these calyxes has a hair
coming out of the top
that's all those hairs that you see on
the bud there these are
delicious and full of goodness these
calaxes
and the hairs are almost pure thc as
well
inside the kit we also provide you with
a pack
and so you inside you have
some scissors and papers
we like organic raw here's how you trim
the most important thing to remember is
to not cut these calyxes these calaxes
that we've just talked about that
contain all the
cannabinoids and all the terpenes we
don't want to lose them or
half of them we're going to aim only for
the parts that we want to remove the
leaflets
that are still attached to the flower
when we're trimming we're only using the
tips of the scissor we're not cutting
any red hairs and we're
just removing the individual leaves one
leaf at a time
removing the leaves one by one
individual
removal of leaf one by one not
cutting into the plant not damaging any
of the hairs
leaving all those beautiful hairs intact
leaving all those calyxes whole and
filled with medicine for you
the machines that process most of your
medicine
will tend to just make a cut
like this which will not only cut
that little leaf right there it's like
using a sledge hammer
to open an egg it's
all they're trying to do is get rid of
this one little leaf but that machine or
that
person trimming will take their scissors
and they will literally
remove that whole
side of the flower instead of taking
their scissors
and removing that leaf that needed to
come off
as you can see them see swollen right
there individual round swollen calyx
with hairs coming out of them right
there
this is the calyx right here this is
what not to cut
and this is what most all the machines
and most
trimming processing scenarios stories
will be destroying
and so don't cut the calyx that's the
most important thing with trimming
that's all i got to say
with this people are shaving the calyxes
people are cutting the calyxes
we need to preserve the calyx the flower
in its entirety and its wholeness
and respect it as its fullness and
stop shaving it you love herb as much as
we do
and the ritual preparation of flour
become
to become medicine for the body mind and
soul is your spiritual process
afterwards soak it in oil and then wipe
them off
yeah you want to slide the scissors
behind the leaves so that you're not
damaging the bud behind it
and only removing the leaves that don't
have the crystal on it with the veins
because
it's all useful
holding the bud very gently so that i'm
not pressing on the
hairs and squeezing it at all it's best
if you hold it from the stem
or at the bottom of the bud so that you
avoid touching it
too much you can wear gloves if you like
when you do this
so your fingers don't get sticky before
trimming and after trimming
so you can see there's very little leaf
you know we're not talking about a lot
of leaf this is just enough to make one
little infused snack remove all these
from the stems
or some of them from the stems at least
then what i'm left with now is this twig
the stem itself has calaxes on it with
hairs coming out of them see that
those are delicious some people like to
collect only the calyxes
these into these stem calyxes and make a
joint of just
stem calculus that's a popular old
classic grower thing to do for a grower
this way now and when you're ready to
trim
to roll one up what i suggest you do
is cut along the stem
down the middle of the bud
so that you can kind of like extract the
majority of the stem
you don't need to roll it up and smoke
it just extra carbon it's not going to
hurt you just
you don't need it it's not the what
you're going looking for it's
you can also cut your flower up this way
and we'll do the same thing almost
slightly different texture a little
different burn ability
but classic
so this is purple punch
they call it a day tripper
this is a classic roll even
[Music]
free your plant
you