[Music]
in May of 2017 I was diagnosed with
uterine cancer stage four B so about as
close to the last degree that you would
want and I was sent into shock and
numbness and fear all at the same time
and anger because there was a strong
immediate feeling of wait I haven't done
everything I want to do in my life I
haven't touched as many people or
experienced as many things as I want to
do I can't have this stopped now I'm not
ready for this to stop now and probably
anybody who's been in my shoes feels the
same way immediately it's an incredible
shock to the system that you may be
checking out sooner than you wanted to I
went in to panic and I also went in to
research also at the same time and I
started looking for help and I didn't
know where to go aside from I had an
oncologist at that point saying he
wanted me to start my chemo treatment
before surgery so that the tumors could
be reduced as soon as possible and so I
discovered through this wonderful book
by dr. Kathleen Turner called radical
remissions which was sent to me by a
friend who learned that I had just
gotten this diagnosis of a woman named
Dale fig-tree who had helped herself
cured herself through nutrition after
she had been sent
you know through chemo and radiation
30-plus years ago and she shared stories
when I reached out to her she's still in
practice in Santa Barbara of her clients
and how well they're doing and one of
the things that she recommended I do was
check out California providers and get
myself doing CBD oil while I'm gonna go
through treatments and she said it was
well vetted by her and it's the only
recommendation that she would make for
that type of medicine and so I think all
of us in this position you're
overwhelmed people are coming at you
from all different directions telling
you what they think you should do or you
shouldn't do many of my friends didn't
want me to do the chemo my family wanted
me to so it got difficult to know what
was the truth for me and having Dale
victory be the first point of reference
that felt like somebody I could relate
to and I could trust I just decided to
go with that so I also because the
diagnosis happened and then the
opportunity to start chemo happened so
close to that time there was only three
days myself and my family had no time to
prepare for what I was about to go
through and everyone was leaving town it
was Memorial Day weekend doctor
connection he said somebody needs to be
with Hilary observing her because who
knows how she'll respond to this chemo
treatment and I called you I reached out
to California providers when I first
came home from that first round of
treatment and I was in quite a bit of
pain but it was a pain unlike any that I
had known before it was like my bones
were in pain like a fever that just
wouldn't break and typically they say
that you don't experience that unless
you're given a white blood cell boost
shot but I did have pains in my bones
and it
was non ceasing pain and so you sent
Patrick the cabinet see to be de oil and
the cannabis oil shipped it overnight
and a friend had given me some cannabis
edible cannabis that I took with me for
my first round of chemo which really
helped me relax because I was quite
anxious as anybody going through this
experiences and yet I was so grateful to
be informed that when you're using
products that can come from any number
of places they may not have the same
stringent quality control and there
might be pesticides or residue or
petroleum emulsifiers which is also why
Dale factory said you were the only
reference that she would feel
comfortable giving so it felt good to
know that I was taking in something that
was not aggravating and already toxic
overload to my system and it was a lot
to ask of that medicine even to help
that first round of chemo was quite
strong but I didn't get sick the entire
time I was through that first round I
had no nausea and I was told I would
have incredible nausea and I also was
relieved that although nothing sounded
appealing I was hungry by 3:00 in the
afternoon each day and needed food I
felt I needed food not intellectually
but physically and so I was able to eat
the food that people were bringing to me
and I was able to sleep because I was
tired from both what I was going through
and I think the assistance of the
cannabis oil was helping me have sleep
so I would also share that right when I
started the treatment my doctor dr.
Godfrey connect me who's an incredible
oncologist was very receptive when I
informed him I'm going to try taking
cannabis oil
and CBD oil I've been told that it might
be beneficial and he said absolutely he
left the room and came back with a
script for that prescription without
hesitation and without judgment he'd
said he'd had enough other patients
mentioning it to him that he was open to
seeing you know if this will help
absolutely try it so having the blessing
of my oncologist for that was very
helpful as well so I didn't feel guilty
or anxious about counter indicating what
I was doing from the Western standpoint
and as that first round waned off in its
side-effects it took about four or five
days I would attribute the CBD oil with
helping me also have less fear about
this road I was starting on because I
knew I had five more rounds ahead of me
I knew that my hair was going to fall
out shortly I was unclear how well I
would do through this experience my
prognosis was not great at the time and
the level of ease with which I was able
to live out those first five days after
the first round of treatment surprised
me and surprised my friends but I was
able to be somewhat released from an
overwhelming sense of doom and fear
because my anxiety never got sort of the
better of me and I was told to take
Advil for the pain that was happening in
the bones and I tried to balance that
with the advil and the CBD
by day but it didn't touch it and I
didn't like the idea of taking the Advil
because my liver was already taking such
a hit from the chemotherapy so I started
utilizing the cannabis oil which was
specified for evening only during the
day when the symptoms were really acute
the higher THC level and it really
helped taking the highest THC level
during those four or five days where
you've just come home from your round of
chemo as opposed to just taking the CBD
oil in the day really helped mitigate
the pain and it did intensify the
munchies and I was experiencing some
symptoms of being high or being stoned
as it said in common vernacular and
instead of judging that or being anxious
about that I allowed myself to just
accept it and surrender to it because I
knew that this medicine being natural
was going to have no negative side
effects on my body and therefore I
didn't need to be worried about it I
just needed to allow myself to use
whatever I had available to me to help
me get through without tensing my body
as my sister who is a nurse said Hillary
you need to do whatever you can when
you're in pain to help ease the pain
because otherwise you're adding more
cortisol to your system so with the
blessings of even my family and friends
I continue to use the medication the
cannabis oil and the CBD oil when the
intensity of the chemo rounds left by
the end of the first week I had two more
weeks to start rebuilding myself until
the next round and then I was okay to
just resume using the CBD oil by day it
really helped with still keeping an
appetite because as anyone going through
chemo knows you lose your appetite and
you become very finicky about what
sounds good and the finicky wasn't
really ever able to be
overridden it was difficult to know what
I was going to be hungry for in any
given moment and something could sound
really good and my friend could bring it
to me and then I'd look at it and I
think I can't I can't do it but the
hunger was always there and for sure by
2:00 in the afternoon thanks to the CBD
oil I had a very strong appetite and so
I was able to put weight back on within
a month I went from 127 down to 117 by
the time I started my first treatment
from the way that cancer was taking the
muscle tissue and within a month's time
with the CBD oil and the acupuncture and
the supplements and the protein powder I
was back to 125 126 so feeling my body
weight come back and feeling my lack of
anxiousness really helped my mindset
feel like I actually I'm going to
survive this and once I had that thought
and I felt my body resoundingly support
that thought I think I held on to that
and that's what got me through the next
five rounds is just trusting that I am
gonna get through this and that there's
something coming from my going through
this that I'm gonna be able to pass
forward to others and it's going to open
me up to a new life as well so I was
taking the the CBD oil not in a tincture
during the day but thankfully you sent
it to me in capsules already measured so
I didn't have to guess at what I needed
you also sent me the cannabis oil to
take at night in three different
gradients of strength to build up slowly
and a tincture if I ever needed to add a
little bit more so by day I would take
the capsule of the CBD oil titled
sunrise which was very helpful sometimes
you need it spelled out for you and then
just before going to bed I would take
the cannabis oil but this was that was
the regiment in the two weeks prior I
mean the two weeks
after my first round of chemo or second
or third or fourth but during the first
week after any round of chemo I was
often taking the cannabis oil in the day
as well to help with the pain that I
would experience in my bones from the
chemo so the CBD oil I would take in the
morning started religiously and then I
would take a cannabis oil often in that
first week coming home from chemo around
12:00 or 1:00 after I'd gotten some food
in my system and yeah yeah
sunrise yes is it 3 2 1 oh hell yes and
that prominently a-ok cbda is the first
number that's the 3 and the tha is the
second number that's the one so they're
all cannabis oils okay okay yes yes the
second one is anytime which is the
tincture right which is a 20 to 100 L
okay then the third one is called relief
and that's a 1-2-3 oil so that means
that there's one CBD to 3 THC so that's
the nighttime oil so the relief is
generally the nighttime oil even though
you found it effective during the day
time immediately following the
chemotherapy right and then you found
the three to one oil to be to be
effective throughout the course of your
correct
I found the three to one oil to be
beneficial every day throughout the
chemotherapy throughout the six months
and then I found the evening oils the
relief oils that I would take before bed
to be very beneficial during acute pain
in the daytime which was usually just
for about the first four or five days
once I was home and then I would just
resume taking the relief oil in the
evenings
starting with twelve point five
milligrams through a whole bottle and
then graduating up to 20
five milligrams I started noticing that
I was having much easier time of going
through the chemo than others in the
infusion rooms when I would show up and
I knew that there were multiple prongs
of things that I was doing as I said I
was doing nutrition sort of a ketogenic
diet more so I was doing intermittent
fasting right before my chemo and just
drinking vegetable broth during chemo I
was doing acupuncture and I was doing
the cannabis oil in the CBD oil and I
would start to have conversations with
the infusion nurses and they started
sharing with me that they were curious
because they were seeing how well I was
doing and how my body weight looked and
how my temperament was and my appetite
and I started sharing my experience and
what I knew and my resources with some
of the other patients on the floor with
me who were open to it and receptive to
it and many of them didn't know where to
go to find cannabis oil or CBD oil and
they were intimidated to just go to a
dispensary down the street or friends
would bring them buy things or bake
things for them and it felt so good to
be able to tell them of a product that
was created by a cancer stem cell
researcher and where it was absolutely
imperative that all of the ingredients
were clean that it was emulsified with
an organic ingredient and that it was
set up from the standpoint of being
interviewed by you and learning what my
experience was what my needs were and
then getting sort of a customized
treatment that made such sense to me and
it made me feel so good that I wanted
everyone who was going through this
situation as I was to have that benefit
as well and again I felt lucky because
my oncologist did not have a stigma or
resistance to me doing this medicine and
neither did my family or my friends but
I started to get a little bit on my
soapbox because other people who thought
it was okay just a smoke wherever they
got something or who were just offered
it I really wanted them to understand
that they might be taking something into
their body that may have pesticides or
herbicides on it and that it's more
important that they really get access to
a safe source of the cabin oyd of the
CBD oil you could expect you know some
relief from the symptoms the reason that
smoking was not an option for me as the
cancer had metastasized to my lungs and
to my liver and so the idea of putting
smoke into my lungs felt completely
wrong and I know that it's hard on your
lungs regardless if you have tumors in
them or not that hot dry smoke so I was
relieved to also be able to have it be
edible for that sake you know that I
didn't have to smoke it it was only five
or six years ago that a dear friend of
mine who went through an ovarian cancer
experience didn't have access to safe
cannabis and just smoked what her
friends brought for her on occasion she
felt a lot of relief and the two of us
from the symptoms as you were saying and
she didn't have metastases in
her lungs but as far as whether or not
it was actually helping mitigate her
cancer or halt the growth or the spread
yeah probably not but both of us
commiserate in and said I don't know how
anybody got through this without the
cannabis assistance because it's I think
the reason I can safely say that others
either fell off their conviction of
surviving the treatments or gave up is
because it's so hard to be sick to your
stomach and feel wretched and lose your
hair and lose your muscle and lose your
eyelashes and your eyebrows and your
confidence and not have a day where that
isn't the case and when you have
something like the cannabis oil staving
off the nausea so that you can eat so
that your body can stay stronger and
you're building muscle again and your
feelings of despair are also softly
absolved because you're not in a state
of fight-or-flight or fear continuously
because you're more relaxed as a result
of the cannabis oil so you have moments
where you can have perspective and you
can realize you know what I can get
through this there are cases of people
who survived stage 4 cancer it's not a
death sentence any longer and
all of those factors are why I feel so
strongly about giving this testimonial
because my prognosis five years ago
probably would have been we're just
gonna try to give you some quality of
life for however long you can get it but
both the Western cancer treatments have
come so far luckily for me and the
integrative approach with Eastern and
Western medicines have become more
acceptable that it no longer is a death
sentence
instead it's maybe a rebirth really and
I think that the nutrition the
meditation the acupuncture the
supportive oncologist and the cannabis
oil all played a part and why I'm doing
as well as I am right now
I had a 95 percent response to the chemo
in 99 percent shrinkage to the only
tumor that still seems to be seen on my
lungs we don't know if it's dead cell or
a tumor marker and my ca-125 markers
last week are down to six and they
started at 232 so I just I'm gonna keep
going
and I'm gonna keep using the CBD morning
sunrise oil to work on the inflammation
which is happening now as a result of
the immune therapy that I've now started
and then I'll continue to do the relief
oil in the evenings to try to approach
supporting my immune system and halting
the development of the cancer spread if
that's possible so I have started taking
immune therapy as my next tier of this
regimen and it's a new relatively new in
the oncology world medicine that in
effect goes in and helps your t-cells
register that the cancer cells that they
might be finding
in fact cancer cells that need to be
eradicated holds them together like a
staple in effect so that your t-cell
stays attached long enough to then do
its business and take care of it the
side effects which aren't nearly like
chemotherapy you don't lose your hair
you don't have nausea so to the Western
medicine world it seems like you don't
really have side effects but in in fact
I've been experiencing a lot of
inflammation and our thrit ik symptoms
in my joints and if I compound and go
running or stretching too
enthusiastically I've actually incurred
injury and then the injury is very slow
to heal because of the inflammation so
the anecdote to the Western world is
take a leave or take some oxy coat and
when you first experience these symptoms
when I herniated my back just recently
and the side effects of the immune
therapy creating this hyper inflammation
in my body it's become very challenging
to heal the herniation it's taking
longer and it's painful because of the
hyperinflation so I've been utilizing
the relief oil by day as opposed to the
oxy cotton because the oxy cotton not
only did I notice after taking it three
nights in a row that I felt worse in the
daytime emotionally I also didn't like
the idea that I was taking something
that I was potentially gonna get
physiologically addicted to and I didn't
like the sleep that came from it there
were weird dreams and it was a bit
restless once I'd wake up around three
or four in the morning so I decided to
not use the oxy cotton any longer and I
resumed taking the evening prescription
of the cabin oyd cannabis oil
the relief by day to help with the pain
and
[Music]
and it's helped I'm still having to do
the physical therapy to heal up but it
turns out that immune therapy does have
side effects it can cause hyper
inflammation it can also be hard on your
thyroid so I'm gonna need to approach
this with nutrition and supplements and
the cannabis medicine to help my body
get through this period of time because
I will be on the immune therapy
potentially for a year could be longer
it's such a new medicine they don't know
how long to put patients on it is one
year enough is two years enough they
just don't know yet so I'm sort of one
of the guinea pigs of this new medicine
but it's quite exciting because it
really is allowing your own immune
system to go after the cancer cells
although unfortunately the side effects
of the inflammation are the same issues
that created a comfortable situation for
the cancer to develop in the first place
so I'm gonna weigh that out myself with
what feels right but again I'm really
grateful to be able to have safe access
to the cannabis oil to assist me with
the pain safely I don't drive when I'm
under the influence of the stronger
relief dose in the daytime but when I am
taking the sunrise dose I'm very clear
I don't feel altered I don't have any
side effects of stone enos and as long
as I am good about my diet and eating
sort of every couple of hours throughout
the day I tend to also be fine without
strong case of the munchies by the end
of the afternoon but it's really been a
huge help and I want everybody that I
know that's going through this to have
this same access for the same reasons
just as you've gone through this
experience incorporating cannabis into
your recovery regimen your conversations
with your doctor with other cancer
patients you're meeting when you go to
whatever various clinics and facilities
you go to with the nurses with my doctor
I think he was open but he's quite busy
and he was receptive and respectful but
it interestingly enough it was the
fellow working under him who wanted to
get the information from me so that she
could pass this on to her patients she
had more time to spend with me in the
room she asked for the website I gave it
to her because she was impressed she
said you know really you're doing
exceptionally well from where you
started to where you are now and so I
think as a result of how well I have
responded to the chemotherapy and how
well I've gotten through this whole six
or seven months more of the nurses also
on the infusion floor are asking me as
well what can I share or what what are
some of the things that I know have been
beneficial so they too have asked for
the information and for the website for
the California providers and just this
last week when I was getting my last
round of immune therapy one of the
nurses on the floor asked if I would be
open to speaking to a group of women
that collect once a month that are
called mothers with cancer down in the
South Bay to share what I've learned and
what I'm doing and it makes me realize
how specialized this is and how few
people actually do have access to this
information and how lucky I feel I am
that I received the input from the
different people I did along this way so
the nurses are impressed and asking
questions I think that sea change is
happening because my oncologist did ask
enough questions about the acupuncturist
which is a little bit more comfortable
probably for him and he is now referring
patients to her where is the first
several months of going in and espousing
how well I feel like I'm doing as a
result of the cannabis and the
acupuncture he was polite but I don't
think he was impressed and by the end
seeing my results he's now impressed
enough that he's starting to make
referrals so I think that the proof is
always in the pudding and that's why I
think more people are asking me and I'm
also being more vocal about wanting to
offer information when I see people on
the infusion floor and I know intimately
what they're going through I know how
hard no matter what time of life it is
for you no matter what your age how
frightening it alone you can feel so I
love being able to approach these people
and ask them if they're interested in
learning some of the things that I've
learned and if they are then I share
with them and every time I've been
received with thank you so much you know
I didn't know where to go and Oh
somebody had mentioned that I should
start taking some of the cannabis and
didn't know where to find it I think
nine times out of ten any cancer patient
is now become aware that people are
suggesting or mentioning or having
stories of somebody else that's been
benefited by using cannabis it's in this
particular ilk of people cancer patients
I think it's the more common new
conversation in terms of helping you get
through it but again it's access to
knowing where to find it for most people
they just don't know where to go and the
idea of just going down to a local
dispensary is very overwhelming or
intimidating or non
doable for many reasons probably for
them so it was encouraging to me to see
that my doctor was open-minded to it
that obviously he's heard enough of it
now that that's changed how he perceives
it and he was really supportive which
was really encouraging yes where did you
sow with the dropper the 20 to 1 boil
I've just recently found it to be more
useful since going through this
herniated back and not wanting to take a
leave or ibuprofen to help reduce the
pain and the inflammation I've on
occasion just given myself small drops
under the tongue and in probably 30 40
50 minutes or so I start to feel a
lightening of the intensity of pain
around the herniated area I'm able to
stand up a little bit more upright and
work I was able to work on a landscape
designer by trade and I had a job that I
had to do and it was painful to drive
out to Silver Lake to do the job so I
was just taking the tincture with me and
just dosing myself very lightly very
minimally a couple of times a day while
I was on the job site and it helped
tremendously I didn't have to take
ibuprofen or Advil which I didn't want
to do for my liver because I also had
had metastases in my liver and it just
gave the slightest bit of relief but I
thought was interesting is I didn't ever
feel the high from it I just felt the
pain relief probably because I was
taking such a little amount I'm not I'm
not quite sure but it worked so it just
became my pain management okay so it
really was helping that yeah so the
level that was in the tincture really
was helping with the inflammation of it
because it really helps with the pain
and that's that's a common response that
we especially with back thing we have a
lot of patients who respond really well
over 21 cancer from from back pain oh
great yeah as well as the 1 2 3 formula
the relief for me whether they take at
night because they can sleep through the
night that's exactly right that's
exactly right frequently not taking
anything during the day right
as far as cannabis except for that
nighttime dose so your responses is not
unusual that's great yeah I I would say
one thing that I would suggest to
anybody using the cannabis oil and the
CBD oil is I became aware that I needed
to increase my fee Lewis I could feel
somewhat dehydrated in the morning after
taking the relief oil at night and that
ended up being a benefit anyway because
you want to be taking in a lot more
fluids when you've gone through
chemotherapy to help flush out those
toxins so if you're just good about
drinking some water for singing in the
morning a cup of warm water with lemon
or just some water by your bed and then
drinking more water than normally
throughout the day that really adds to
the benefit of all of it it wouldn't be
just one tool that will help me heal
from the cancer and luckily in Los
Angeles and I hope broader there are
integrative approaches that are becoming
more and more available and more common
and so I knew that I would need
nutrition from the assistance I got from
a nutritionist that I consulted with I
knew I would need the supplements and
the acupuncture I knew I would need the
CBD oil and the cannabis oil and I knew
I would need the chemo and all of them
together and the meditation and the
clean water played a part in me
realigning myself and my life and
healing my body letting my body heal
from the inside out yeah
so I don't think
I don't think we can succeed in getting
ourselves well again from something by
using just one tool in the toolbox
because it wasn't just one thing that
got us that SiC and the more that we can
start to understand that the eastern and
the Western are here for a reason and
that together those two fields are what
will give the optimum holistic approach
to healing
so nothing yeah nothing can do it all by
itself frequently because they've
experienced agree yes and then they're
fearful of it right but there's a
ramping up or a titrating of the dose
that helps you to reach a maximum
tolerated dose that if it's done
correctly you don't really experience
what what some people would consider an
overdose of cannabis but yeah lethal
overdose by any means it's just you're
you're it's more than you're mentally
capable of handling at that point in
your in your life okay so and this is
great this is another this is probably
one of the primary reasons why I was
such a fan of you and what you guys are
creating because when I was given some
cannabis oil edible from a friend for my
first round of treatment it was from
some dispensary in Venice and it was ten
point something milligrams I think and
not being used to eating that much oil
cannabis oil I was unprepared for how
strong it was
I had experienced being stoned earlier
in my life so I wasn't afraid but that's
a really good point that anyone who
hasn't experienced being I it could be
intimidating if they would just went
straight into it without gradually
building up a tolerance
once I spoke with you and you sent the
capsules in there gradated you know
gradually from 12.5 to 25 to 50
milligrams I was surprised it took about
three or four days for me to get used to
the 12.5 in the evening because I was
also taking it a little bit earlier on
in the evening because I was still
wanting to deal with the pain and you
were absolutely right by the time I was
done
midway through the bottle of the 12.5
there was no problem I wasn't
experiencing heavy duty I was sleeping I
was waking up rested I was not having
the pain in the same way during those
weeks so I I don't know if I'm answering
the question appropriately but i I've
strongly encouraged people to call you
because when other people have told me
about having to go to a dispensary and
guess what the amount is that they'll
need or when they've tried to figure out
if they're doing it in drops how many
drops they need and they can over dose
themselves it can be especially if
you're older and this is not a common
experience for you it could be super
intimidating and you might just snore
the baby out with the bathwater so
having it come already in gelatin
capsules measured out with the right
time to take it because midway through
chemotherapy you really need it to be as
simple as possible having it say sunrise
and having it say evening was very
helpful when you're fumbling around for
bottles in the middle of the day or in
the evening and yes I think that I think
most people have experienced an altered
state to one degree or another whether
it was through alcohol you know they all
maybe knew what it was to have too many
beers when they were in high school or
college or too many margaritas or maybe
they know what it's like to have taken
some other type of recreational drug and
I think one of the things that's unique
to people going through cancer is you're
already in such a state of surrender
when you're going through chemotherapy
treatment by virtue of you have to your
life is on the line
you're willing to do whatever it takes
including taking incredibly toxic drugs
into your system intravenously with the
hopes that this is going to save you so
you're a lot more receptive to trying
things that you would not have
previously I believe when you're going
through something where you're fighting
for your life and the more you can just
be in surrender and and the ease you
feel of taking something that you know
is natural and for a change is not
harmful to your body into your body to
help it's a huge relief and so some of
the side effects if you're feeling some
of the stone enos actually can come as
quite a relief as well because it can
help you relax and as I found it also
helped me have more of a perspective
about what I was going through I
actually had moments where I got so
quiet and so meditative and so
appreciative of the natural world around
me again cancer can give you a timeout
button from your life and it can help
you read introduce yourself to what it
is about living that you knew as a child
that you'd forgotten and you feel more
inclined when you're under the influence
I felt of the CBD oil by day or the
relief oil by day if I needed it to be
outside which I also think is a hugely
therapeutic part of healing for anybody
is to be in nature you end up finding
that you feel more drawn to the things
that are more natural to you by virtue
of the experience of slowing down and
being relaxed and being open minded
which the CBD oil seems to be conducive
towards so any of the anxiety about
being out of control or not feeling in
control that a lot of people experience
if they get too much of anything that
alters them is mitigated by you creating
the capsules according to who they are
and what they need in such a way that
they just no I just need to take that
one capsule that says sunrise in the
morning and one in the evening and I'll
gradually work my way up but I won't
ever be out of control it's really
helpful and it's helpful to know that
you can be called that I was able to
call either of you at any time if I
needed to to ask questions was also
tremendous comfort because there's a lot
of questions sometimes that come up in
your mind about what you're doing and
what might work and what might not work
and to have somebody on the other end of
the phone who's kind and thoughtful and
receptive
[Music]