[Music]
so I'm really interested in what you
think about the elevation team of our
and phenotype in the cannabis plant
through earth conscious through
microbiology conscious through
environmental conscious and breeding as
well I guess ways how how do you think
that that that intertwined we we're
seeing a real dichotomy in the cannabis
industry between what I'll call factory
production of cannabis and I've seen
some very sophisticated operations all
under LED lights artificial media and
there's a uniform product that results
but whether this is really something
that's going to be truly therapeutic is
an open question somewhere in the middle
I've seen indoor operations with all
organic media and a real effort to
create a biological foundation for
healthy plants and it shows in terms of
what the plants look like they're
trichome density and all those good
things on the other side is regenerative
agriculture which philosophically and
conceptually really appeals to me is
trying to maximize the potential of what
the plant can do but
there again there are different
considerations I'm fond of saying that
if you want to produce good terpenoids
like in lavender you actually need an
environment like in Provence and France
they have a very poorer rocky soil and
it's actually that stress to the plant
that causes it to produce more of these
protective materials so is it possible
question is for a plant to be too happy
and it's not going to produce as much of
these materials because it's getting
everything it does need from the soil or
in the question sure is it producing all
of it because you're giving it an
ultimate nutrient from what I've seen so
far the answer is the latter we have a
situation where a plant that's in a rich
soil and he has the proper mycorrhizae
there has the ability to uptake anything
it needs and under those conditions you
definitely going to have a happy plant
and my suspicion is you're going to have
the most therapeutic kind of plant it
would be helpful at this point they have
a few more scientific studies that
either confirm or refute this kind of
concept but it is a question we can
easily answer
pretty amazing but I think that we're
noticing now from breeding maybe like to
see varietal for 1213 years and just you
know not keeping a mother for that whole
time but you know picking out varietals
each year for seed production that
visually looks like that all the factory
look like that are growing the same way
and that's the way that we do our
breeding so you know it's not so
scientific although we have done you
know labs and different tests we haven't
done it in particular of what we're
seeing with varietal starting to raise
their CDG CVG especially so we'll get
something maybe even a one-point
whatever and have varietal for a long
time CVG levels are really skyrocketing
the other thing that I noticed is that
and I want to ask you this next is that
the THC goes down and other cannabinoids
raise up well certainly I think that's a
good thing somebody who believes in the
entourage and the benefits of these
other components it shouldn't all be
about THC that is in contrast the aim of
production in most of the factory
situations either super high THC or
super high CBD again I have no
confidence that that's going to produce
the best medicine
so I like to see this diversity and
experientially what we hear from doctors
that are using diversified material as
they're seeing better results that it's
working better for a variety of
conditions also better toleration by the
patient's you know it shouldn't be all
about getting a high THC number like if
you're milking heavily one cannabinoid
then it's almost like a ratio thing the
other cannabinoids will go down to well
it doesn't need to be we're seeing some
more balanced normally you've got one
that's predominant and maybe another one
that could have close to the same amount
or more often a lower amount but we're
also seeing some very balanced ones
where they're actually reasonable
amounts of four different cannabinoids
there's really a max amount of weight
that can be well that's absolutely true
I don't believe anything above 30% 25 is
logical upper limit and that would be
from a top bud that's well manicured
where everything has been done to
maximize that number but that'd be a
total so it is a reciprocal relationship
you could have 25% THC but you can't
have 25% THC and 12% of CBD you know a
trichome is only a certain percentage of
the mass of a flower so there are limits
but yeah I'm very interested in seeing
these balance king of ours again in
contrast there is tendency the approach
at GW Pharmaceuticals was definitely
specific cannabinoids in the highest
concentrations and then if necessary
could use that to blend sativex is in
fact a combination of a high THC and a
high CBD kimura BER so that's another
way to do it a blended medicine ideally
it's nice if you get what you need from
one plant but that is going to take a
lot of selective breeding and a lot of
experimentation with patients to see
what works so what about the idea you
know not only our soil beds and really
rich microbiology environments that are
heavy and fungi and a continuous feeding
cycle good for cannabis as we know and
we need to study in it we need to
absolutely so there are two issues here
one is what's best for the plant and its
therapeutic potential the other is
what's best for the earth and the
environment that's no contest we already
know people should be doing this because
it is the most ecologically relevant and
helpful you know idea that you can have
a rich soil you haven't added any
nitrogen there's not going to be any
runoff that's getting into the water
table
producing elgible ohms downstream this
is critical because you know things are
changing we're going to have an
increasingly harsh environment on this
planet and we need to be doing
everything we can to mitigate the harms
and regenerative agriculture is
absolutely one of the top priorities
yeah and we're really noticing that as
cannabis farmers right now because we
are getting pathogens on our plants that
we've never had before in amounts that
we've never had before of course that
definitely has to do with the trade of
this plant and being able to make clones
and then you're passing on the pathogens
with the clones and you're even up
passing on you know pathogens of
chemicals and and long-term systemic
things but what I wanted to get to is
not only are we noticing that deep rich
soils are good for the cannabis plant
but because of these pathogens in our
environment being so pressing and so
toxic we're also noticing that the plant
does best in a multi you know faceted
garden beds with many different
varietals in there that are feeding
Colin aiders and I'm wondering about now
the idea that it just only seems natural
to me and to a lot of other cannabis
farmers and growers about compounding
this medicine with other herbs and
utilizing you know the grams spectrum of
herbs on this planet to help with
cannabis what do you think about
compounding
oh it's something I'm rich I I think
there's great promise it is something
that hasn't really been accepted very
well yet by the supplement industry but
that could change I mean they have to be
considering the competitive advantage
they would have I'm actually surprised
that some of the bigger companies
haven't come out with cannabidiol lines
at this point I've explored this with
some of the companies and said basically
if you're interested in doing this I'd
love to be involved but nobody's taking
the bait so far I think it'll be coming
trouble is again government's sorting
out the regulations on this kind of
thing and it is a morass scientifically
it shouldn't be difficult legislatively
it's extremely difficult