[Music]
our next panel which is the industry
perspective uh Mr Nate Bradley executive
director with California Cannabis
industry Association uh Hezekiah Allen
chair and executive director for the
California growers association and Keith
Stevenson executive director of the
Purple Heart patient center my name is
Christie noblick I'm um excited to be
here to um provide some feedback so
thank you for the opportunity um I'm the
owner and uh co-founder of KAC
infections we a chocolate uh
Manufacturing Company Edibles company uh
located in Oakland and we also do um
distribution throughout the state I'm
here um as a member of uh ccma and ccia
the California cannabis industry
Association um I sit on the uh on the
board of directors there and I also
chair the manufacturing committee um the
uh ccia has worked with um with the
legislature to um to provide feedback on
both Mera and prop 64 and we're excited
to continue to do that with you to um
work together and um provide some uh
collaboration so we can make sure we get
the system done right um as a part of
the association we've uh created 12
major points that we are looking to uh
focus on um I'm only going to talk about
four today um but to uh to highlight we
really want to uh emphasize the
importance of one system so medical and
recreational coming together and we
think that will um ease in the ability
to uh become
compliant so um one of the first items
is um the importance of a phas in with
the licensing uh program so uh Lori Ajax
mentioned this earlier as well but the
ability for a um licensed business to
also be able to work with unlicensed
businesses for a set amount of time and
that will just allow the industry to um
get going and won't uh won't bring
things to a complete standstill um the
other item is uh the thresholds for
ownership So currently Mera um has 5%
ownership uh we'd like to see that um
come up to where prop 64 is with the 20%
ownership um the concern there is with a
5% ownership component there will only
be or there'll be a restricted access to
Capital um and that could potentially
stifle growth for our new growing um
industry and also could uh could present
problems for publicly traded companies
if 5% is that threshold for ownership
they may be coming in and out of
compliance um uh as a publicly traded
company um so we'd really like to see
20% on that ownership component and then
um also we' like to um see the
elimination of the Cross licenser uh
lure restrictions with mcrsa um to allow
vertical integration like just like we
see it in prop 64 that's been proposed
there um so MRSA is restrictive and um
prop 64 has that uh vertical integration
component um and then uh finally the
last issue and this one um is of the
utmost importance to me personally and
to um the groups we represent is uh
distribution
and so um we would like to see the uh
the distribution component that's
brought up in uh prop 64 um uh versus
the one that's in Mera which requires a
third-party independent um distributor
as a manufacturer a large component of
my business and really of the way that
the industry is operating right now
allows for both manufacturing and
distribution um so we're we're uh
definitely concerned that um restricting
the amount of distribution licenses just
to those who are solely doing
distribution um could have serious
implications on the industry and uh
specifically around um uh Innovation and
kind of the uh entrepreneur
entrepreneurialism so we would like to
be able to bring products see products
brought to Market um through
manufacturers cultivators um everybody
having access points um in terms of
distribution so thank you thank you
please Mr Stevenson I will I wish to
speak about a few topics one is multiple
permits Under One Roof also known as
collocation uh definition of premise
also suitability also known by some
cities as Equity based permits um modify
the closed distribution model under the
Mera and allow for both third party
Distributors and licens inous
Distributors owned by licensed
cultivators manufacturers Andor
retailers and eliminating cross-
licenser restrictions in the Mera by
allowing vertical integration as
currently authorized by prop 64 um my
name is Keith Stevenson I am the owner
and operator of the Purple Heart
dispensary Purple Heart patient center
dispensary which has been serving
patients since September the 18th 2006
and is the longest running dispensary in
Oakland as a former resident of Los
Angeles I went to a
aviation maintenance college and became
a licensed technician for United
Airlines for 17 years before two hiip
replacement surgeries forced an early
retirement which led to my involvement
in the medical cannabis industry I
started Purple Heart from the ground up
and currently have 26 employees I am the
textbook definition of a small business
owner I am fortunate that unlike some of
my colleagues I have not been
incarcerated nor do I have a criminal
record I am also so fortunate that the
Cannabis industry has given me and has
opened many other doors that would not
have happened in other fields before I
give my input on a path forward in the
new cannabis world I would like to thank
Miss Ajax and her staff as I was the
second dispensary they visited and I
appreciate their efforts to make
themselves accessible and learn about
the and learn about my industry while
distinctions between the medical and Adu
adult use cannabis Frameworks are
important discrepan discrepancies
between the two Frameworks will
complicate implementation for state and
local agencies and make compliance more
difficult for
lenses with that stated key points
include multiple permits Under One Roof
also known as collocation multiple
permits Under One Roof is helpful to the
geographic Fabric and Zoning of cities
this maintains the composition of
businesses in certain hubs helps create
natural clusters and has benefit icial
to Public Safety as the businesses are
easier to monitor whether it's a dense
urban city or smaller rural City
consolidating various usage and permits
into one location is a better use of
space as an example a medical excuse me
as an example a medicinal cannabis
campus similar to what biotechnology
companies or public private research
Centers do should be encouraged excuse
me definition of premise similar to a
previous topic the final definition of
the word premises as determined by the
licensing entities will have a
significant impact on local
ordinances as well as on a licensees
ability to legally operate once St
license are issued with so many cities
and and counties Banning or severely
restricting cannabis businesses in their
communities it is critically important
that multiple licenses both Medical and
non-medical be permitted on one premise
this model will allow cannabis
businesses to relocate to locally
approved hubs encouraging excuse me the
creation of natural clusters and
minimizing potential impacts to Public
Safety as clustering multiple businesses
in one location is easier to Monitor and
regulate suitability also known by some
cities as Equity the War on Drugs has
been a war on lowincome people of color
as part of the remedy Alma must benefit
lowincome people of color and lowincome
communities of color any effort by
proponents of mass incarceration to roll
back the cening reforms to limit
Community reinvestment or to create
barriers to economic participation by
persons with limited capital or prior
drug rep records would
undermine excuse me basic fairness of
the act and reinforce the institutional
racism of the the War on Drugs
considering that men and women of color
have been
disproportionately punished by the war
on drugs and suffered iness harm many
individuals with past drug offenses on
their records have been excluded from
participating in this new industry
thereby furthering historic
inequities modify the closed
distribution model under the MCA and
allow for both third party Distributors
and licensed in house Distributors thank
you so much
cheers owned by licensed cultivators
manufacturers and our retailers strict T
excuse me strict track and Trace
requirements in the merca language will
already be tracking cannabis products
from seed to cell the state already has
the authority to audit the operation of
all
licenses mandating that excuse me
mandating that distribution only be
performed by an independent distributor
will not reduce or prevent unlawful
verion and could have the unintended
effect of increasing diversion and
earlier points in the supply chain prior
to the distribution choke point my last
topic eliminating cross licensure
restrictions in the Mera by allowing
vertical integration as currently
authorized under prop
24 the Mera language places restrictions
on the number and type of licenses
cannabis businesses May acquire prop 64
does not not include prohibitions
against Christ cross licensure and
permits an existing vertically
integrating small business in the
industry to be licensed by the state
without forcing it to divest itself of
any part of its Enterprise to facilitate
enforcement and compliance there should
be parity between cross- licensure rules
in the medical and adult use cannabis
regulations with that I look forward to
your questions thank you Mr Allen please
thank you very much um it's an honor and
a pleasure great responsibility to be
here today discussing the path forward
after prop 64 Sher cavayero sherff Alis
chair wood and indeed chair Ridley
Thomas um we think all four of your
committees need to play a very important
role in this going forward my name is
Hezekiah Allen executive director of the
California Growers Association
membership organization with more than
900 members 40 board members
representing communities in 17 counties
from LA to Humble my comments today
focus on closing the gap between mcrsa
and prop 64 first and most cannabis
cultivation is agriculture and should be
regulated by the department of food and
agriculture Cher cabayo your presence
today and your committee's attention
here is is a great uh breakthrough in
this policy area and I'm going to
primarily direct my comments to you and
and vice chair matthus though he stepped
out of the room first and foremost one-
siiz does not fit all for cultivation
licensing both prop 64 and mcrsa in uh
have tiered licenses mcrsa contains
Cottage specialty small and medium to
ensure that regular requirements and
fees are appropriately scaled to the
size of the grow prop 64 creates all of
these licenses with the exception of the
cottage cultivation license additionally
prop 64 creates the type five unlimited
scale license in 2023 when it comes to
cultivation licenses we have two
recommendations and a word of caution we
would like to ensure that the type 1C
Cottage cultivation license is carried
from mcrsa into prop 64 we would like to
restrict the type five license created
in prop 64 at least until such time as
the federal government authorizes out of
states sales word of caution California
is already overproducing cannabis going
bigger isn't going to make regulating
any easier we recommend that this
legislature maintain limits on the scale
of each grow while continuing to ensure
unlimited licenses will be available for
small and Specialty Growers when it
comes to hemp proposition 64 is a big
step forward hemp is a huge opportunity
for Farmers with lots of flat Acres
marginal soils and who might have some
issues with water if they need a
resilient crop that can be used for a
lot of different things this is the
answer however there are some very real
challenges both legal and operational
and we encourage the convening of an
informational hearing focused
specifically on implementation of
measures related to hemp it really is
that big for our Farmers there's a
critical code section in the MPR mcrsa
that was emitted from prop 64 BMP code
section 19328 establishes restrictions
on the types of business licenses that
an entity May hold simultaneously
because the section was omitted it prob
64 opens The Floodgate to consolidation
and conglomeration we call on the
legislature to correct this with
legislation our Growers are especially
vulnerable and we do prefer the 5%
threshold for cross ownership we would
like to note that agricultural co-ops
and existing code are a great way to
achieve efficiencies and onboard
investment Capital without pushing
independent businesses out on the flip
side there's a critical section that was
included in prop 64 but omitted from
mcrsa we strongly encourage the
legislators to include the prop 64
residency requirements in the mcrsa
ensuring that California businesses have
adequate time to meet the requirements
before the the flood of outof State
interests moves
in unfortunately prop 64 and mcrsa both
agree in the emission of a critical
license type non- storefront
dispensaries when we talk about
balancing between access and
neighborhood impacts delivery services
are a critical component over the last
year we have worked through with local
government and law enforcement there is
no known opposition to these Provisions
at this time they are included in AB 64
we strongly encourage the establishment
of a non- storefront dispensary license
in both prop 64 and MCR
SAA oh the marijuana tax included in
prop 64 is hugely problematic we
recognize that changing the tax language
is going to be very difficult though the
task is simple conform the marijuana tax
as closely as possible to AB 2243 and SB
987 that were deliberated by your
legislature last
year specifically a very high concern we
think that the cultivation tax could be
a barrier for entry for as many as 75%
or more of the state's cultivators if
not clarified the proposition is
inconsistent in describing when the
point of tax is due when the product is
harvested when the product leaves the
cultivation site and when the product
enters the commercial Marketplace that
is a huge discrepancy in code I've been
a grower all of my life I know that
Harvest is a long process times are
tight money is tight we need to shift
that burden to the point where the
product enters the commercial
Marketplace or else we just won't be
able to make ends
meet that's all I got for today
everything you've heard from from the
local perspective from law
enforcement uh from what the agencies
are doing I mean do you agree not agree
I mean obviously there's still policy
issues that we need to discuss whether
it's Transportation or um cultivation
sizes or potency for instance but in
terms of the coordination and the work
together you do you feel like that's
fruitful it's working it's not working I
mean how are you seeing this with your
daily businesses
sure so um I would say overall we've
been engaged uh multiple times by the um
regulatory bodies so we've met a few
times with the health department um
we've been to a few of the stakeholder
meetings that Lor has put on so um I
would say overall input we've been able
to um Define some pretty clear channels
for giving input and it seems as though
you know we're we're in February here so
we have a lot of work that still needs
to be done but I would say we're on the
path to getting there um a full
implementation of the system in January
still seems difficult there's obviously
a lot to be um accomplished but uh I
think that the uh industry is very
willing to participate and um and kind
of people's hearts are in the right
place um the industry is very patient
focused um and so uh the with the best
intentions I think I think we'll get
there so I I'll I'll reiterate um that
and say that you know our experience
with the agencies has been um fantastic
you know this has been a seemingly
hopeless and impossible task from the
time you guys set out to write the
legislation took years to get to the
Breakthrough that the mcrsa was um the
reason that I maintain maintain hope and
confidence that this will get done is
because of the coordination we've seen
between the agencies because of their
access because of how uh available they
have been and so I speak very highly of
the work that they've done it has to be
noted that in the absence of Regulation
there are a number of business models
that have grown up that maybe aren't the
the the way that the state would would
like to see our Marketplace move forward
and so there is tremendous strain
particularly as those business models
are disrupted and so we are trying to
work through those tensions our
organization has taken the approach of
just tracking as closely as possible
with non-traditional allies local gov
law enforcement and really trying to
present not just a unified industry
perspective but a unified stakeholder
perspective and you know it's slow it's
tedious but the agencies are giving us
hope and confidence at this point okay
I'd like to say personally um I think
it's incredible what the state agencies
have been able to do in a collaborative
effort my initial irritations were with
the Boe just trying to pay taxes I was
bounced around from Oakland to San
Francisco to San Jose and you know
you're talking about carrying large sums
of money only to pay a bill and now that
the state has taken appropriate actions
and saying hey this is one of the
Premier issues that we've got to deal
with is intake of the revenue I think
that the fact that the state has come
together and and worked across board
with all the various entities have shown
a willingness to get this thing done for
now you take into consideration where
you have Mera and miss a jaxson her
staff and others were working towards a
common goal and then you then you
interject proposition 64 as I would say
the gold post has been moved and they
are and the state agencies are still
doing a phenomenal job and working
together and seeing this through it's
you know just dealing with Merc alone
was
a insurmountable task and then you add
to that and you exacerbate it by adding
prop 64 and you know I read these
articles and it's these articles are
somewhat written in a in a unfavorable
manner towards uh the state agencies as
well as the legislators and I just want
to know from someone that's inside of
this looking out that I understand what
you're dealing with and I I appreciate
the work that everyone's doing
together thank you let me um ask uh
because you know some issues were
brought up and with your associations
and with your businesses you know
concentration in certain areas
um Edibles was another one and you know
just the public safety aspect how are
you guys dealing with those what are the
discussions you're having with folks uh
not just in your associations or things
that you're hearing I'm you know like
most people if you're in the in the
world everyone's talking in in that kind
of industry or in that world so how are
you dealing with those
issues well when it comes to issues of
of having product
and when the language which takes place
next year uh January 1st we test all our
products to the level uh that we're
comfortable with and it's higher than
what the state probably would ask for so
the inventory that we have on hand I
believe that we will be in a position to
continue to sell that inventory however
based on what I'm hearing from the state
we we'll probably limit our purchasing
power or abilities in the fourth quarter
and and kind of just let everything
bleed out
you know I'll point to the um over
concentration issue um and and raise one
of our membership's uh primary concerns
which is under concentration and
ultimately I think the best way of
ensuring a balance between neighborhood
impacts and access is to make sure that
there's one or two stores everywhere and
there's not two dozen stores anywhere
and so you know I I definitely defer to
the league of cities in that regard with
the local control issue we are we are
definitely encouraging folks to um be
very mindful of their communities for
example in Sacramento we supported a
Community reinvestment Fund that is a
voluntary 1% um down in in your District
particularly Mr Ridley Thomas uh we are
working with folks on measure M to
ensure those considerations are included
in the postmeasure D framework too many
of these businesses in any one place and
not enough in another place there's sort
of flip sides of the same problem and
what we'd like to get to do is get to a
point where you know things are are well
regulated um
and you know not banned and not
concentrated ultimately hit that hit
that nice Middle Point again just
working as closely with the league with
the with cesac with rcrc with the
various stakeholders who really know
more about those topics and trying to
track very closely with them as we move
forward thank you
please um for when it comes to um Public
Safety for Edibles um earlier Dr Karen
Smith from the dph um was speaking about
the threshold set by the food
manufacturing industry indries and um
cannabis manufacturing can get right on
board with most of those um what's being
done in the in the rest of the world um
so we need thresholds so we need
thresholds for pesticides we need
thresholds for microbiological
contaminants that will also um potency
as well so um that will M maintain
consistency and potency from product a
to product Z batch after batch year
after year um but that responsibility
should um be shifted to the manufacturer
that's also how it's done um in the in
the rest of the world um and with
regular food manufacturing um so license
holders will need to be hold uh held
accountable for those um thresholds and
for meeting those um also I think a huge
area for um to show kind of how
responsible the industry is going to be
is in marketing and advertising and
under no condition do any cannabis
operators want to see their products
consumed by children that is bad for bad
for consumers bad for business bad for
the industry as a whole um so nobody
nobody wants that um so part of the work
that we've done with the manufacturing
committee is um come up with some uh a
code of conduct for marketing and
advertising and it's um borrowed from
the distilled Spirits Council um and it
just talks about what we're not going to
do basically so we're not going to show
people um overly impaired we're not
going to print um you know uh Santa
Claus on our marketing materials it's
very basic but very thorough um points
and um I think it's there's a lot of
Education that we need to do uh among
the consumer base um but there there is
certainly a responsibility on the side
of the manufacturer to not make products
that are attracted to children but we
also need to educate consumers on where
to store them for example so they need
to be Out Of Reach of children and kids
need to know these products in this
package or in this child resistant um
exit bag for example these are not for
kids these are for parents um and I
think once we start having those
conversations uh we'll be well on way to
resp I think that's what Dr Smith had
said was uh opaque uh you could see the
product and then the child
resistant uh features that are
accompanied with them um we are running
short on time thank Mr chidley Thomas I
would argue that there's no such thing
as underc concentration in these
businesses it's probably not even
legally defined and I'll take the two
that would be in the mer Park and give
them anywhere else anywhere else
literally and while you say that the
local governments are experts they're
not they're simply stakeholders the
experts are the people who will bother
me in the middle of the night when these
businesses are
overrun particularly the dispensaries
now it's not the whole supply chain and
this is something that the voters in
their wisdom decided to embrace and many
members of this legislature support but
it is
unacceptable if this system is so porous
that it allows for substantial
concentration and I will blow your phone
up as it happens one thing I would think
that you can help us with in Los Angeles
in the immediate notwithstanding measure
M will be whether or not we can get the
unlicensed businesses or these different
business models to quickly come into The
Marvelous Light
and the there are there's only so much
that local government the community
groups that the Press can do the
industry is going to have to step up so
that's I'm not necessarily asking for a
response but with due
respect because of how overc
concentrated it becomes there will not
be many of these facilities in the
Palisades and I'm quite sure I didn't
look at all how it passed but it passed
a little higher on the West Side than it
did in South Los Angeles it passed in
South Los Angel y all did a good
marketing job but um there's it's just
not even it's not even comparable what
happens to miss Nook from the industry
Association to this legislator's years
it sounds like that you're arguing in
your opening statement for Less
regulation that's unacceptable that will
not be something that will hunt now
Oakland is different from Los
Angeles the Bay Area was much more
accepting a various types of marijuana
being distributed in your areas good for
you good for the people that you work
work around that's not the same in Los
Angeles nor will it be tolerated when
things like cash uh carrying businesses
get robbed stores get broken into and we
have a concentrations of individuals who
are trying to access these Services if
they're not using one of the mobile
distribution services so it's a little
different uh the argument that you bring
but
regulation in and of itself and the
reduction in regulation is an
unacceptable argument for this type of
Industry so I would caution that as you
come and testify and your industry
Association that you pay your membership
dues and you employ Advocates to Market
on reduced regulation is an unacceptable
argument it doesn't even stand to reason
because of things like being able to
test whether or not somebody is
intoxicated yeah and I that's not even
the word Mr Ridley toau us things that
we discussed in the earlier panel I get
but Mr chairman to be clear this spoke
to that in her opening that they wanted
essentially in a condensed version of
that reduced regulation or the state to
appreciate that the uh indust the
industry is needed to mature that's an
unacceptable argument that is really an
unacceptable argument the best case
scenario for this would be something
like three tiers where wholesale retail
and distribution are separate and do not
have ownership states and capital
frankly will come to the market Capital
will come to those businesses and just
because you want to profit from one part
of another maybe some something which
you have to give up for being in this
industry is to not be able to have
different parts of the supply chain but
to me that is an unacceptable argument
to have reduced regulation and what is
essentially a a nuisance
industry and I refuse to allow us to
normalize this discussion and it is
different for different areas that's all
I have to say Mr chairman so I think uh
you've made your your point and where
you on these issues and um I think when
Miss noblick I think it was was talking
earlier it was about the different
tiered sections for
transportation um I'm trying to figure
out just for
clarification are we moving you're not
asking for Less the way I heard it was
not less regulation but that we mooved
to a regulatory body within the scheme
workk of the two propositions that have
passed and I think that's kind of where
we're at yeah yeah I I'll I'll just
respectfully um clarify what I meant to
say there so I think that um the two
points I was trying to make was that
businesses that don't have a license
will be able to work with businesses
that are getting up to speed or I guess
those that have licenses and those that
don't have licenses will be able to work
together for um for a set amount of time
um but I think where I misunderstood is
um in allowing of a vertical integration
was it potentially that so um we just
prop 64 allows for vertical integration
so um we're not suggesting that we go
outside of either of those two systems
but that we uh bring Mera closer to what
we're seeing in prop 64 so um I don't I
guess I'm I think we need I think our
industry needs regulation um you could
take a look at my business we've been
operating as though we've had regulation
for six years we test all of our
products as um Keith had mentioned they
do as well we test all of our products
for food safety um for microbiological
contaminants for potency and um I can
sit here and tell you very uh honestly
that I fully believe that we need Safe
products out there and we need to make
sure the right players are operating in
the right way so um by no means do I
think the industry needs to continue how
it's been because um we're we've grown
up past that and it's time to it's time
to adopt sensible responsible regulation
so respectfully chair brief comment
related to vertical integration and and
and the independent mandate for
distribution um and to be clear uh chair
Ridley Thomas our organization did not
support prop 64 for some of the very
reasons I think that you point out we we
think it relaxed regulations too quickly
of course there's a concern about
regulatory capture from the government's
perspective our our concerns are more
focused on on Market capture but they
are are very similar uh pieces of the
same issue um you know we we don't see
prop 64 as relieving the Mandate for a
license distribution tier in the supply
chain we simply see that it's allowed to
be cross- licensed with other lenses
this will in effect create uh one of the
worst outcomes whereby well- capitalized
well positioned businesses will be able
to vertically integrate realize those
efficiencies and and gain a competitive
advantage while the smaller most
vulnerable businesses particularly The
Growers will continue to be left working
with an independent distrib because they
simply can't afford to cross license the
micro business does uh license type that
was created by prop 64 does create some
relief to this but at the end of the day
um what we want to be very careful about
is that as we ease regulations which I
think you know some stakeholders are are
certainly calling for um we don't want
to do that in a way that it
disproportionately benefits well
capitalized businesses that that if we
if we do ease those restrictions but
it's a very high financial burden we
produce some of the worst outcomes
possible and so just wanted to be um
attentive to that issue we do tend to
prefer the more regulated framework in
the mcrsa as a starting point and as we
get our bearings as a Marketplace as we
figure things out and have better data
then we can move forward into a more
relaxed
framework all right thank you and I know
uh everyone's working hard to create
that regulatory scheme workk and
framework for us to to operate off of
we'll continue to have additional
hearings to talk about some of these
things and I know we'll be debating some
of these policy areas in terms of
vertical integration Transportation
tiered not tiered system uh in the near
future as we continue to move forward
and I know I believe each of the chairs
have probably talked to each of the
Departments as well and a number of the
stakeholders that continue to come into
our offices on these issues so um
definitely looking forward to those
discussions but Mr wood just just just a
comment kind of a clarification you know
when mcrsa was put together one of the
reasons that we looked at at limiting
vertical integration was was the desire
to keep businesses smaller um and so I
you know grandfathering in existing
businesses that are vertically
integrated isn't isn't an issue for me
what I'm concerned about is the Mega
business that comes in grows in an
unlimited scale or limited only by
geography or water or whatever at huge
scales that that that can then um test
their own products manufacture their own
products and sell their own products in
their own stores I don't know of any
other industry out there that does that
certainly not you know at that at the
scale which that and so that's one of
the concerns that after hundreds of
hours of deliberation with the
legislature we chose to do it a certain
way so obviously we see we see a
conflict we see a conflict here um
distribution from the the legisl legisl
perspective was a tax collection Point
primarily a tax collection point so what
I don't what I didn't see in prop 64
which I still failed to see is how we're
going to reconcile that because how are
we going to collect the taxes which was
a big Push by the Coalition of of how we
were how this was going to play out well
for California billion dollars in taxes
where are we going to collect those
taxes without some sort of a component
related to distribution or testing or
something so how that all comes together
so that the promise of the taxes for the
legislature to protect kids to to
protect the environment to to protect
against the black market is actually
realized so we'll see how all of this
all of this plays together um but you
know certainly from a business
perspective the concept of unlimited
vertical integration I think um there's
there's a challenge there that that
certainly is in in in huge conflict with
with what the legislature envisions so
we'll see how it plays out yeah we
probably could have a whole hearing just
on
that just on this this one topic Mr
Stevenson please and let's move on yes
when we speak of vertical integration
one of my most expensive um line items
in our budget is purchasing cost of
goods if I'm able
to produce the majority of the things
that I need inh house that allows me to
be a much more fiscally responsible
business and I operate under the premise
that when I initially started doing this
people went to jail so as the indust
industry has chosen to grow up and
expand I've been forced to grow my
business which you know either I can do
it if I want or I don't have to I'm
choosing to do it what I do not want is
for the Legislative Assembly to limit
the size and growth of my business I'm
not concerned about anyone coming from
outside with unlimited amounts of money
I'm not consider I'm not concerned about
any multi- conglomerates because as long
as there's a a a federal State issue
they're not going to come into the space
I don't anticipate these businesses
coming to the space for at least 10
years Mr really Thomas and Mr soles you
come from areas you represent areas that
have high unemployment I'm I'm very
aware of your area Mr really Thomas I
grew up in South Central Los Angeles
this is an emerging Paradigm an emerging
market that has the opportunity to
gainfully employ those individual who
are unemployable
I asked you to look at this in a
different light I understand what you're
dealing with in the LA the issue in La
is not with the industry it's the lack
of oversight by the city of Los Angeles
we don't have those issues in Northern
California so when you guys and I'm not
being gender specific when you all look
at this business model I want you to
look at it with a clear concise
state of mind that this has been that
this has been permitted since
1996 and it's time for the industry to
grow up and please do not limit Me by
legislative
laws thank you thank you thank you guys
for your comments and for being here
obviously like I said we could probably
have a hearing just on this and we will
have an additional followup hearing
because I know there are other
associations and alliances and whatnot
that weren't able to be on this agenda
because it was already packed uh you
know we started working on this hearing
last year right after the proposition
passed so uh we'll continue to hold hold
another one um as we can as we move
forward for this upcoming year and then
obviously we'll do the oversight as
legis as a legislators in coming years
to see how everything is going along but
thank you guys for your testimony and
thank you for being here
[Music]
he