[Music]
for a lot of people they've only sold
flour so for most people the only thing
that they know how to sell is flour I
grow flour I sell flower but in the new
white market where they're gonna enter
well who's gonna buy a thousand pounds
of your flour it's especially when it's
sold by the 8th of the quarter maybe in
a dispensary so you know you're talking
10,000 20,000 30,000 people a lot people
on it by pocket and so what you have to
understand is that the markets have
stratified in cannabis they've changed
and so California cannabis is basically
half oil production half flower
production five years ago 100% flower so
in five years you know you're talking
half the market is now oil and oil means
all forms of concentrate but if you look
at the all forms of concentrate you're
gonna find that basically one thirtieth
of it is rosin shatter fresh freeze and
the other twenty nine out of that thirty
slices is all distillate which which is
basically stuff used for food production
food grade
for edibles and predominantly for
petting and so the pen market is
probably 46% 47% of the total sales in
California
so people are obsessed with pen sales
and it's the new change in how we smoke
people don't roll pot anymore I don't
I'm old school it's what I know but for
everyone else's ecig in and the likes
devices the pen is really this new mode
of usage and because of it it's it's a
very interesting thing because it used
to scare people who sold flour because
the trim people that I call them that
depend people basically have a trim
people they would just want trim and
turn it into pen they never want to pay
any high dollar for the flower because
they add plant-derived terpene so they
don't need quality terms they can take
anything and make it into something but
as we go forward with the shortage of
clean cannabis and testing testing makes
the distillate market the toughest
market to get in because it's a
concentrate market so therefore if
there's 88 percent of the flower that's
really needed for cannabis and legally
is dirty that means there's only 12
percent that means there's only six
percent to cover all distillate because
six percent of that flower is gonna
cover the flower and six percent of its
going to go to distil looks that's the
breakdown in California so if there's
only 12 pounds six are going to
distillate six are going over to flower
that
is a massive amount of product needed in
a highly regulated tested market I think
that that's one of the things that the
farmers who are clean or organic who
didn't get into the business to make the
money as much as they are actually been
doing it for time as a lifestyle their
margin should be a lot less in the
margin meaning the cost of production if
you don't have an incredibly expensive
lease on your farm and you're in Humble
where the cost of production is
relatively I think it's the lowest in
the state you have an opportunity to
grow intelligent choices farm them
correctly and turn them into products
that then sell in a market that has an
incredible velocity velocity is speed of
product through the system so if I made
a hundred thousand dollars over a year
that's awesome but if I made a hundred
thousand dollars in a week it's better
because that hundred thousand in a week
now capitalizes me and lets me use that
money as a tool versus as a paycheck and
there
and as we go forward its velocity of
return that really determines the
farmers quiddity the amount of money you
have to use that
that's your capitalization amount of
money you have that invest all of these
things you need to survive and your
choices dictate it so I grew a thousand
pounds and I didn't sell them till next
year
whew that's a tough one you might not
even survive through the winter because
you got trim costs and all this other
who's paying it and so for a lot of us I
think that when you look at cannabis
you'll look at it more stratified
meaning pieces of your flower go piece
of your total go as flower and you'll
find the markets that want those
specific things and everything else is
going to go into these other forms until
the the large entities come in and
vertically take over the business
imagine if we were all small crop
farmers for Philip Morris and we were
all producing tobacco for them because
right now it's impossible for them to
get the total quantity but once they
have the ability to get into the system
five years and totally no regulations in
terms of scope and probably a lot less
restrictive legal system then all of a
sudden that would change because they
would vertically fill their supply
chains but until these supply chains are
filled
you have a window of time and I think
that for a predominant number of the
smaller farmers that's how they have to
see it is that they have to recapitalize
and pay the cost to get the farm squared
away to get their lives in order so that
when the next transition comes they're
not left like they are right now which
is basically underprepared can you talk
more about a distillate and
what the challenges are to making the
desolate murmurs distillate is the
product that's been cleaned up from
crude so crude is basically the throw in
cannabis that's clean meaning no
chemicals in it did not chemically grown
if you're using a two-part fertilizer
that's not what I mean
what I mean is you're using illegal
products that are going to taint the
cannabis that you've applied yourself
chemically so bunch of sides pesticides
growth regulators if it doesn't have any
of that stuff then this is perfect
because any of these products can go
into basically hexane extraction where
they take the material that you have and
they use hexane to strip it all out and
that has all your lipids your waxes and
the chlorophyll in all the cannabinoids
no terms and then they take that product
and they run that through a distillation
system closed paths and something some
short path some kind of something's
going to peel it off
and that gets rid of all the heavy waste
the lipids in the chlorophylls and all
the other components and it's left with
now something that can be combined with
the vehicle or a solvent and nowadays we
use in terms of solvents but before they
used all polypropylene glycol which is a
carcinogen so now you may know not to
use it but most pens will poly propylene
glycol pens prior and so now they're
trying to figure out how do we use
terpene mixes to keep the distillate
liquefied enough to function
independently so the challenge is
creating these formulations that make
them work but the bottom line is the pen
market is so big and regulated cannabis
requires clean product then for many
farmers you'll find yourself growing
product and then what do you do with it
you'll be able to have people come to
your property and extract it through
hexane labs that are permitted on
trailers so this year I had fresh frozen
done at my property where I had a group
of individuals come out and harvest all
my canvas and go into freezers and then
blow it and then return it to me so I
could sell it to my store this is
different this is basically where that's
just being blown right on the spot and
it's coming out looking like kilo sized
black abalone so the machine can spit
out any size but typically it looks like
you pushing out about a key at a time in
its load form
and then those keys get vacuum wrapped
up with all the invoice and they get
shipped out to the to the to the
individuals distributors need this
product all edible and pen industries
rely on crude that's just like saying
you don't care about crude but you're
buying gas if they don't have crude
coming out of the ground there is no
gasoline at the gas stove so crude is
the basis of all of us and it's one of
the simpler methods to utilize for
farmers because it allows them to put
themselves into a position where there's
bulk sales shatters concentrates they're
not bulk sales you have to be able to
move into stores in most of the stores
most of the larger places that used to
do a lot of this work became vertical so
they started to purchase there in their
own farms so they could grow their own
cannabis they own their own distillation
facilities so they can make their own
products now they can sell it as pen and
they can control the whole path and for
a lot of people that was how they made
their money with shatter and super
concentrates was they put it into places
they couldn't those places in a vertical
also and so what you need is some place
that's gonna take it in a level that's
bigger than you can produce you want
there to be a mouth too big for you to
feed yourself and most people can blow
their whole farm of of crude and it
would leave but I challenge you to blow
up a whole farm a super concentrate and
sell it in one shot
because it's gonna have to get sold and
bled into little pieces through whereas
the pen market is insatiable they need
the raw material different than I need a
finished product to sell it store one of
them is you selling coal and and the
steel mills need the coal they can't
make the steel without the coal and you
were the one making the coal and if you
can understand that and it's easy people
just don't understand this because we're
pot growers and pot sellers know you're
in the cannabis industry you wherever
you were you were but you are no longer
that if you want to stay in business
business is going to tell you what
you're going to become and if you get
too emotional about it then you get to
go bankrupt and so if you make the
decisions it means you're flexible and
you move to where the markets expand if
people still wanted to smoke a sativa
from the 70s it would still be selling
but it's not so growers had to change
that's huge people do not understand
what I'm saying when I talk about this
shit
[Music]