[Music]
whistle if you have your own company
right
now whistle if you have your own company
and you sell
products whistle if you have your own
company and you sell products and you
develop
Partnerships whistle if you communicate
with other human beings all
right the reason I state that is because
when people hear the term pitch they
often associate it with some sort of a
Cheesy car salesman activity trying to
sell you this vehicle and you know you
look really good how do I get you in
this today it's nothing to do with that
so before we do that I'm going to start
out with what you shouldn't do if you
are pitching not talking about Investors
are very important and we'll go through
that in a moment normally this is a 3day
process I'm going to convince it down in
about 20 minutes and take questions for
as long as I possibly can to help you
with your business so first and foremost
here's what it pitch should never be
this is an actual pitch from a company
uh before they came to us we'll just
call them XYZ XYZ provides professional
consulting services to develop and
support online business solutions from
startup to Fortune 500 companies XYZ
assist clients to maximize their return
on investment in the cloud and providing
implementation development and value
added software Solutions
horrible terrible do not explain things
with jargon you know what a great pitch
says who you are what you do why it's
important to the other person can you
hear me is that better wow that's l so a
good pitch should tell you simply here's
who I am here's what I do here's why
it's important to you now developing
that takes a long time it's very very
difficult to condense your big business
and all the spreadsheets you've run and
grass and condense it into one simple
thing but some people are really good at
it for instance the rapper Eminem is
fantastic Adit he has a song that starts
out I don't make black music I don't
make white music I make fight music for
high school kids that's a great pitch
it's simple right think of what you do
and what it provides to other people
starting a pitch should not begin with
the great things that you do and how
much you love your product and huge
words no one understands it's not about
proving how smart you are it's about
proving how well you can communicate
with any level of intelligence okay
great pitch is simple it explains things
in very very simple everyday common
person terms so when it comes down to
understanding what a pitch is I think we
have that who you are what you do why
it's important to other people or or in
particular the person you're talking to
at the moment so pitches come in very
very different states we're all doing it
you're at a networking event and you
meet someone don't you have to answer
those three questions who are you what
do you do why is it important to me
right so it's really important you have
this polish sometimes you have 1 minute
on stage to pitch investors sometimes
you have 3 minutes uh people come to us
and say I need to develop my 20 minute
Ted Talk please if that is in your head
until Ted calls you himself uh remove it
from your mind it does not matter the
most important thing you can do is
explain who you are in 15 to 20 seconds
and get intrig the purpose of a great
pitch what a great pitch does it opens
up the the it stimulates dopamine in the
mind just like a drug you are selling a
verbal drug when you are selling a pitch
you have to stimulate the dopamine
someone's bringing o that's interesting
I have to know more the best result of a
pitch is not how do I write you a check
it's ooh how do you do that or where do
I go from here what's the next step is
to get buying indicators from people so
I want two entrepreneurs to come up on
stage with me today who have who would
like some free pitch and
bu all right well I'll speak frankly
fucked all you then if you don't want my
house
that two of you come on up I the cancer
survivor absolutely come on up come on
[Applause]
up three come on up you're courageous
and active I like both of those two
turns okay so what is your business hi
I'm an event
planner what kind of events do you a
cannabis events when and what are the
outcomes of these event uh people come
they enjoy entertainment comedy
brolesque uh dance performance
and edible canvas samples do you see how
this already developed from I'm an event
planner to hosting cool events how about
you come up come up come I don't like
teaching I like experiential learnings
uh I'm an entrepreneur coming new into
this industry learning to make an
extract for cidis patients and um
looking
to that's okay uh hi my name is Claudia
and I own a brand new company that is
proficient in marketing in the Cannabis
industry perfect so these are actually
all pretty good concise pictures but
let's work on so the first thing who are
you and what you have an interesting
story you've already shared it right if
I were you the way I would explain my
story and stimulate dopamine is I'm a
cancer survivor and I attribute my
survival to the Cannabis plan because I
have survived this process this this tur
turbulence in my life I now believe in
freting of business around the holistic
effects of speaking further into that
why' you get do event planning I do
event planning mostly because the events
I've already been to in LA
are a lot of guys who are getting really
really high and I want to provide
something else for women for anybody who
wants to do art okay so you're again
we're talking about setting a frame
right A lot of people in the movie
industry in the city framing frame your
work so because I've been to so many
awful events with Stoner dudes
everywhere I've decided to take a stance
become an event planner create amazing
cannabis related events that provide for
legal medication and enjoyable formats
right how did you get into
Brandon or why well mostly got into it
because I saw Brandy needed a lot of
help in this industry uh was really
wanting to strive to Break um the stigma
of the teach and Chan and just bring
more of a professional look to this
industry good so here is the the most I
I relate everything to movies by the way
so a great pitch anybody seen Good
Fellas does anybody remember the first
line in the entire
movie for as long as I can remember I've
always wanted to be a
gangster right it sets the tone it tells
you this person has passion and gumption
for his chosen career field so in the
same the same context for as long as I
can remember I disliked how things were
branded I decided to take a stance I
look at this industry I understand it
well and now I provide xynz services to
people so thanking about it who you are
very important that you explain who you
are why you're doing what you do CU it
makes you relatable to me right I don't
care really what your business is or
your p&amp;l or your graphs and spreadsheets
I care about why you do what you do then
I care about what you do and then I care
about how we can do it together right so
breaking these down you guys are very
succinct but very Bland so remember this
in your pitches for as long as I can
remember I've always wanted to be a
gangster as long as I can remember I've
always wanted to be an entrepreneur as
long as I can remember I've always
wanted at all great events start
everything that way it's such a great
framework context it shows your passion
for what you're doing follow yeah I put
Who's Who uh does anyone to sleep
yet you will be never mind so here we go
in your pitch I want you to refine it
very suly and tell me exactly what it is
one by one your new
pitch that's just it's a trick question
none of you can do this and like s
seconds it's a total trick please thank
you for being brave and coming out I
appreciate it thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
so some necessary requirements of a
pitch because you know Todd and I work
together Todd's a partner at 25 Ventures
Todd has been on the investment side of
you know my bullshit for generations of
being able to pitch products to
investors and actually get capital from
them moreover them telling me to kick
rocks more than I can possibly imagine
so if you're not taking enough shots
getting enough failure you're not
pitching enough people it's just that
simple but from the other side of the
table that's all that counts I can tell
you how to craft something beautiful and
be able to tell an elegant quick story
but you have to know the other side of
the table my career started out managing
money so I totally understand I've been
pitched as well when you're talking to
an investor primarily the first thing
you have to understand is what they
invest in you have to be able to pull
yourself into a bucket quickly I am this
person here's why I do it here's the
company and the bucket I belong in cuz
if you're talking to someone who invests
in you know Elder care might make sense
to talk about cannabis but they're
probably not interested in cannabis
space or it's something new to them or
if they're a fund they may not legally
be allowed to invest in anything but
elder care so get your background right
away find out who you're pitching to and
then make it interesting to them if you
can figure out right away what bucket
you belong in I'm a software company oh
I I I invest in software I want to
listen more and I've developed this that
does this oo I like the way that that
works now you're building a pitch a cinc
pitch that allows you to communicate
with people
because again pitching most people think
is a primary oneway Street where I'm
going to pitch you and and you know I'm
going to live this glenary Glenn Ross
dream of selling and having nobody buys
anything any longer they want to be part
of what you're doing so you have to
understand that a pitch its primary
purpose is not to get a check it's not
to close the deal it's to interest the
other person and get them to take the
next step everything has a process
investors have a process they meet you
they like you they see your idea they
see if it fits into their structure and
and and by the way at the end of the day
investors invest in people they can go
have a drink with that's what they
invest in don't forget you're a human
being don't get caught up in so much
into the science there's a lot of
cannabis companies a lot of science
involved in this get caught up in in the
value it ads as opposed to telling me
and this is the most common mistake
entrepreneurs make when I ask someone
hey what do you do most commonly they
tell me how they do it
right they tell them oh well we provide
you know uh software that pulls from
apis or data like at the end of the day
okay you make it easier for me to go
from one social network to the other
right remember the value you provide so
if I'm an event planner I'm throwing
events in the Cannabis space I make it
amazing to enjoy cannabis with other
people that is actually the value that
you provide it's not the event it's not
the process it's not the how it's the
what it's the value that you get to now
the next this is extremely important
thing to do when you are developing your
pitch okay and of course we can help you
with this we're not here for that when
you're developing your pitch if you
cannot explain what you do in six
pictures with no words you don't know it
well enough it's that easy we live in a
world of
degressive communication we are not we
are not moving forward as human beings
text is actually outdated pictures are
how you explain everything they're 100%
said we live in an illustrated World
here's some interesting facts every 60
seconds around the globe there are 250
babies born every 60 seconds my high
school class at 241 my high school class
is born every 60 seconds there are 1.8
million people who like something on
Facebook there are 300 hours of
information and and video uploaded to
YouTube there are 22,000 pieces of pizza
consumed every 60 seconds put that on
top of the fact that you have a baby and
spouse and money and a job and taxes and
a career and an automobile with a broken
tire and you have Twitter and Facebook
don't don't don't neglect the fact that
this is important the fact that right
now while I'm talking to you I have a
pretty good social presence feel free to
find me look me up and connect but I
have a pretty good social presence right
now during this speech I've probably
gotten 25 emails uh there's probably
been 13,000 tweets that have gone
through my message board unknown
hundreds that have gone through Facebook
these are all huge distractions that
keep me from actually being able to pay
attention to what you're pitching me if
you acknowledge that and take heed of it
right away and understand this person
has the same problems that I have
they're not a Target they're a human
being and they have kids and they have
distractions digital distractions a
device in your pocket that's literally
going off all the time especially if
they're busy people if you can
understand those things you will learn
that is really important to be concise
not elaborate all of you have been
programmed by our educational system to
fail at pitching do you know
why your teachers God BL God bless their
soul not rest their soul God bless their
soul uh have a very difficult job to do
but what they teach you is backwards we
live in a world right now I have I I I
spoke at USC a couple weeks ago and I
literally showed the class of
entrepreneurs who by the way learning
entrepreneurship in school doesn't make
sense either you need to learn it on the
street but I showed them a message from
a very prominent CEO his email to me was
nine work
my reply was three we will get together
and discuss this thoroughly in the end
but for right now nine words three words
were sufficient because in the world we
live in we are taught from the time that
we are children hey we're going to do a
paper on Abraham
Lincoln and I want you to write 1,000
words about the importance of Abraham
Lincoln couldn't you just as easily
looking put together six bullet points
ended slavery had a cool be shot in the
theater right is is that is that what
your brain actually extracts and flex
but we live in a world of digital
distractions with reduced attention
spans I don't care who you are your
attention span 10 years ago was a heck
of a lot more than it is today and the
older you get the worse it gets it's
kind of a curve it's a bell curve when
you're little it's very short and then
when you're old it's very very short so
as you get older you have to understand
the older person you're talking to the
less time they have to pay attention
more importantly they're taking in so
much information on a daily basis that
you have to become very memorable in
their process extremely memorable
everyone here has limited storage space
everyone of you see 5 to 8,000 ads per
day your eyes take in 100,000 words
100,000 words sounds stupid but take a
step outside look at all the words you
see in this room this is all data your
brain is taking in if you do not
understand and know how to navigate that
quickly in entertaining manner that
provides some sort of memorable EXP
experience you are destined to fail
pitching there's no Miracle pill I can
give you you need to learn how to
explain who you are what you do why it's
important to other people really quickly
smile on your face with the intent of
them saying that's interesting how do
you do that it's really how all comes
down to pitching is not a science it's
an art form and it all comes down to
your ability like I'm not standing up
here with some proper posture in front
of be yourself be who you are but
explain quickly Who You Are what you do
why it's important now a couple things I
can give you when it comes down to
learning your pitch here are some tips
so if you have a notebook or an iPad an
iPhone I suggest that you write this
shit down because it's pretty
important does anyone mind my language
my I'm very transparent person um but
important thing here identify seven
bullet points about your company the
things that are important what you do
why it's different from everyone else so
on so forth seven clear identifying
factors that make your business
different from everyone
else's put those down memorize them and
then put them in order remember a pitch
is nothing but a very very short story
done in verbal and visual format it's a
story it all begins with Once upon a
time once upon a time some problem
existed and every day people experiened
this problem and every day things got
worse until one day I had this great
idea to solve this problem and because I
saw Sol that problem this this and this
so remember once upon a
time every day every day fill in those
lines until one day I had my idea for
the solution and because of the solution
this happens and because of that this
happens and then the seventh point at
the end is and everyone
lives this is a story format that is
embedded into you as children that you
can follow that's retainable be able to
tell in one minute your Once Upon a Once
Upon a Time story it's extremely
important here's some tips and insights
we generally don't share in the general
public but once you have your seven
items identified chronologically in
order and put it in some way that
doesn't put people to sleep once you
have that cool little story these are my
seven points I want you to memorize a
pitch that says who you are what you do
and why it's important and then I want
you to do it with your eyes
closed seriously sounds strange I want
everyone in the room to take the butts
of your hands and put your hands
together like this
look at your middle finger one is longer
than the other
right
right one is always longer than the
other this is not this is rhetorical one
is always longer than the other so now I
want you to take your hands shake them
out I want you to put your butts of your
hands together and your put your hands
together in the same format close your
eyes and for the next 4 seconds I want
your brain to tell your fingers to be
the same length be the same length
be the same length finger middle finger
be the same length with the other finger
open your eyes your fingers are the same
length it is undeniable and categorical
the amount of pixelation your eyes take
in is so distracting and defocusing to
your brain waves that you will actually
confuse yourself with your eyes open
saying I can do with my eyes close is
ass backwards it's actually harder then
you're standing stand on one
foot no no no assistance okay put your
foot down stand on one foot with your
eyes
closed holy crap is that hard right so
remove when you're trying to put down
your pitch if you close your eyes you
don't see anything so it means you hear
and you produce you produce noise and
you hear noise very clearly and you will
hear your own bullshit you will find out
what sounds good and what does not sound
good to you immediately it's it's just
it's undeniable not to mention the fact
that these seven bullet points about who
you are what you do why it's important
to other people with your eyes open
you'll get five of them nothing your bad
this just everyone everyone gets five of
them all the time and they always those
other two if I have just thrown that in
there it would have been awesome with
your eyes closed you never forget those
other two bullet points if you can and
this is proven we work with hundreds and
hundreds of people on this if you can
tell your pitch with your eyes closed
succinctly in the exact format which is
who you
are why it's important to the other
person with your eyes closed and it
sounds good to you it probably sounds
good to other people so make sure that
you are following these simple practices
so instead of boring you for the 15
minutes which I always advise we teach
people if somebody gives you 5 minutes
to pitch learn how to pitch in one and a
half Albert Einstein said it best if you
can't explain it simply you don't know
it well enough if you know your business
well you can explain it like a dummy to
a hillbilly in Arkansas he can
understand your complex business guy
living in the Hills never had a TV he'll
get it so what we always advise get to
Q&amp;A that's where imp is made that is
where people get what they want from
what you were saying and that's where
you get to show off how smart you are so
I'm more than happy to take some
questions Todd will also come up here
Todd has been a private investment V for
a Swedish billionaire he's been an
investment banker comes from the
financial background has been pitched
hundreds of deals over the course of his
career so happy to answer any questions
you have did you have one are you the
mic kind to with I like it anyone have
any
questions oh there's one there's no no
way that I've explained enough that you
don't have any questions or have I it's
[Music]
mystery hello hello my name is Rosemary
and I'm a um can you put your mouth
closer to the microphone okay there we
go I'm a newborn care specialist you are
not the newborn now I am and some people
call us a baby nurse but I am really
interested in the way that the canabus
industry can help children who have all
kinds of problems is this about pitching
well yeah because now how am being
concise and how am I going to present
this to the public to the phys the
question is how do I present cannabis
specifically exactly good so all all of
you have the same stereotypes built into
you that the rest we work with we we we
work we are Frontier advisers we work
Frontier Law Group cannabis companies
every day and actually Michael we talked
about this today with his board they
asked the same question have you done
this before no no one has done this
before in cannabis but the stigma of
cannabis and creating a company that
you're pitching to investors you know
that was called like 5 years it's called
drug dealing I need launder money to
move and believe me I've been in that
business as a college student as well
exactly but in the Cannabis space you
can't explain you're a canab if you
label yourself as a cannabis company
you've automatically eliminated 80% of
potential Partners just stigmas not to
mention the fact that cannabis unless
you are selling Pure Flow or plant in
it's pure format you aren't a cannabis
company you are a hardware company a
beverage company a software company
whatever it may be the fact that
cannabis is a chemical that is involved
in your product should not impact the
way you pitch it whatsoever all it does
is address the market you can and cannot
serve legally that's all so there is no
there there is not a different way to
pitch a cannabis company from a software
or a a construction company but all the
same you have a product that product has
a market I want to know how many people
can buy it what you sell it for how
you're going to make money and how
you're going to do this and scale the
business up to the point where it's
worth me putting my money in time so I I
always feel like it's a homeopathic
remedy to drugs and that's what infants
are given steroids and all kinds of
things that are so bad for their human
intake so so I'm gonna interrupt you
because uh we hear this a lot a lot so
you we work with a lot of canis
companies and pitches so we hear it all
the time um the one thing you can't do
is convert people from their in in one
minute you cannot convert them from the
existing stereotype they have in their
brain understanding your way of thinking
you can't so why try so what do you do
you have to explain the core of your
business what you do simply like what is
your business that you have do for kids
well right now I'm a baby nurse but I
advise people on care for their children
who have um unusual circumstances like
no um so okay so so in your instance
right now you know you're a child nurse
yes keep it simple and you explore
alternatives to traditional medicines
and pharmaceuticals to provide better
solutions to children with less damaging
impact exactly you don't need to use the
word cannabis no in a pitch I just want
you I want you to say one thing to me
when I'm done with my pitch how do you
do that and then I will tell you I do it
through using CBD or canis how do you do
that I just did
it you explain the fact that you a nurse
and that you explore natural and
homeopathic alternatives for children to
provide the same results if not better
than chemical substances can provide to
the human body
exactly right exactly there you go
anyone else so I can make sh next one we
solved your problem
ma'am yes
sir over here hi I'm deina and we're
starting a company for enabling people
to grow cannabis at home but the
question I have for you is we are
looking for investors and trying to
create a pitch deck do you have any
recommendations on pages on information
that we should make sure that we include
in providing a pitch deck when they
first have interest and say send us
something and you're not able to talk to
them to continue to gain
that
concise uh yes so the basic business
model format for a pitch tag is as
follows title Slide the problem you
solve the solution Not Your solution but
the solution product
explanation Market size how big can it
be be very succinct with it your
competition business model go to
strategy and then your team you know you
can move those around I you're a startup
so startups always ask should I have a
no you don't have a your all your
financial slide is a luery it's just
fake numbers so you know that's a second
meeting with an investor uh but always
be prepared to be able to send somebody
a four slide deck about the problem the
solution the market size your five your
product and the team that's it most
people don't just just so you know most
investors if you're an early company
they really don't even care what your
product is they care about backing good
people and supporting them you know
don't don't go to people say I want is
your money and contacts no you're
looking for it's a fundamental you ask
for you ask for money you get advice you
ask for advice and you get money like
always remember that smart people will
always help
you yes
sir oh I'm back
here I think that's for hello my name
yeah my name is Mitch I just recently uh
in the process of taking over my dad's
35-year-old company which is packaging
machinery and robotic which goes into
how everything gets
packaged I'm very interested in speaking
with you automated right and U I just
started an offsho called canpac USA
which is specifically Niche marketed for
the Cannabis industry just with site
makes it Niche now there's the other
thing the other stigma in the Cannabis
industry is there's a lot of fakers in
the space there's a lot of people that
say oh yeah I do this for cannabis
there's really no difference in how you
Market Pres present promote sell
products there's none there's no reason
to coin yourself or pin yourself in
there you're providing for a new
industry right so what do you do
differently is there anything from a
robotics or packaging that you do any
differently than you did before uh
mainly from the legislative standpoint
we had a situation recently uh so it's
compliance packaging you're comping St
staying up with the legislation
specifically in Colorado um California
and the other states where legislation
can
dictate how much how does legislation
impact
packaging it it impacts from the
standpoint of how many milligrams or
milliliters of THC can go into a certain
bottle and those
bottles uh the Machinery that fills
those bottles are custom made so so I I
get it the question I'm tring to make
sure we get every speci the question is
what's that you're taking over your
dad's industry your dad's 35-year-old
company and you're moving it into the
Cannabis space because another another
Market of it and what happened was is
when I was going on as Burmeister
packaging nobody was really listening
per se so when I started canac USA and
been promoting it as that now people
seem to be listening a little bit more
but I was wanting to
know how can I penetrate the market
more as an expert both legislatively
speaking because that has a lot to do
with the types of machinery and Robotics
that are used in the filling the capping
question penetrate the market so
penetrating the market is a go to market
marketing Strate we we do all this stuff
I don't have that answer for you if I'm
just being frank and I don't know enough
but what I can tell you is it all starts
with your ability to explain what
differentiates you from the rest of the
worldly so being able to explain the
fact that your packaging follow state
laws and compliance for cannabis
companies would be my Niche I wouldn't
promote it as a Canabis company I would
promote it as a manufacturing and
packaging company that follows can State
regulation that removes you from
stereotype and it immediately puts you
into a position of authority gotcha
thank you very much you bet anyone
else one more one
[Music]
more none none more oh there we
go grab that
mic you're tonight's rapper go thec go
specific that women should do while
pitching that and tend not to do like
I'm glad you as this cuz there's a lot
yeah there's a lot of stigma I think
especially I'm from Valley in terms of
investment I'm so this is actually the
way I was going to start but my
background if you don't know anything
about me I've been working with women
entrepreneurs since before you were
called women entrepreneurs when you were
simply entrepreneurs uh I was part of
the team that broke the actual
information and statistical breakdown of
venture capital realizing that 74% of
all venture capital returns Returns come
from women L Investments which account
for less than 9% of their actual
allocated funds does that make sense to
you so 9% of their Investments go to
women who produce 74% of their money
that's asinine so the fact that that
even exists and the stigma is one that I
don't try to promote but I'm happy to
answer your questions I've been doing
this for more than a decade with women I
work with springboard Enterprises
largest women Le Enterprises how do
women pitch differently than men they
don't it's not necessarily in what you
say women tend to a little longer winded
because of a lack of confidence I'm a
you you've already also labeled yourself
in your brain by saying I'm a woman
entrepreneur so it means you try to
prove that you're smart way harder than
everyone else but in actuality the women
who explain things in very few words
pause and look at the bridge of your
nose sell whatever they want to anyone
the fact that you are succinct just like
men there is no difference there's no
sexism in pitching there's none either
you have a good pitch good business or
you don't the fact that you're a woman
is only a hinder
before you get on stage and Pitch once
you're on stage you're an entrepreneur
so the secret sauce for women is to
learn how to be more succin than men
because I can tell and Todd will back
this up Todd how much do you hate
hearing 35 minute pitches about a
company I think I've listened to over
15,000 pitches and it's brutally
horrible to sit behind lots of money
they want to put it to work have to wait
through that and only invest through
five companies a year have to 6,000 a
year it's brutal please make it short
shorten it up be concise be Illustrated
women have much first of obviously we
support women L businesses we work with
a ton of them but women have a better
ability to explain things in pictures
see the way the pitching works is I tell
you a beautiful story like you're a
child I look at you and I tell you about
once upon a time that there was this big
problem that my idea became came to a
head when I realized it was an actual
problem here's how I figured it all out
speed you up and I get you excited the
entire time behind me is a PowerPoint if
that PowerPoint this is what women do
all the time by the way if that
PowerPoint says word for word what I'm
saying to you what the hell am I doing
in the room but if that PowerPoint shows
an illustration of what I just said just
an illustration it embeds it
neurologically in someone's head I see
it I hear it I see it I hear it I see it
I hear it I see it women are so good at
this it's unbelievable just un uncor
that part of you that and let your
creative juices go when you pitch
verbally pitch like a very short M AR
aren't most smart people you know don't
they answer a question yes like watch
any movie with a real smart person are
you telling me the end of the world is
going to occur CU this asteroid is yes
that's what I'm telling you you believe
that person because there's a saint they
don't say well actually the trajectory
of that asteroid is about 36 off from
it's you know normal yes I'm telling you
the world W because of that so keep it
simple keep it visual thank you so much
for your time I'm happy to answer any
questions thank
you thank you so much
[Music]