[Music]
so the first poll we had was do we think
that green houses are using less energy
than indoor cultivation facilities and
we see that a that's interesting is
about just slightly over half okay so
the next one that we're gonna have is
about light higher lighting watts per
square foot correlates to higher ppfd
higher light received by the the plant
canopy and the last one more light
equals more yield greater yield okay
about two-thirds disagree with that 100
70 70 percent okay thanks for coming and
I'm gonna let Nick introduce himself and
just take it away is that okay okay that
was quite the setup because it sounds
like I have all the answers which I do
not in these questions of course it's
all it's all dependent right where are
these greenhouses etc etc so the data
I'm going to present is a set of data it
doesn't necessarily represent everything
but it is based off of a minimum of one
year's worth of 15-minute electrical
electric interval data monthly fossil
fuel consumption if they consume fossil
fuel and a year's worth of production
data in terms of dry usable product so
it's a decent data set I'll start with
that so how much energy is used in
cannabis cultivation facilities is the
first question I asked and so this is a
plot of what we have found in a recent
study so what do we see annual energy
consumption along the bottom the x-axis
and that's all fuels annual production
on the y-axis and then again that's dry
usable product and we see wow really
tight correlation here right our square
2.96
people familiar with our squared values
what that essentially means it basically
means that the
dependent variable how much production
you make is incredibly tied to how much
fuel you consume
so the 0.96 means that there's an
extremely strong correlation between
these two things so maybe that's not too
exciting or profound in and of itself
until you consider that this data set
includes indoor mixed light brand-new
construction retrofit a couple thousand
square feet up to over 30 thousand
square feet
fossil fuel heat electric heat and
vertical stacking so all of that is
represented in this data set and yet we
still have this incredibly tight
correlation between total energy
consumption and total facility
productivity that to me is is pretty
interesting and not necessarily what we
expected going into this so what is
driving that energy use well we find
that there is a pretty strong
correlation between the lighting power
density and the total fuel consumption
on the y-axis so we go okay so lighting
power density is driving consumption of
energy to an extent at these facilities
all right well what's what's the deal
with lighting power density how does
that impact production well this is odd
why is our production going down as our
flower room lighting power density goes
up what we are finding here that is not
reflected but we know from the project
details is the facilities with higher
lighting power densities have the
fixtures mounted way up high so they had
to mount way more fixtures in order to
get the PP ft that they're looking for
at the canopy the the facilities with
the lower lighting power densities not
only did they have lower overall annual
energy use but they had better more
consistent ppfd I say better more
uniform PPF ppfd across the canopy so
again not something we would have
necessarily expected to see here but
lighting power density ppfd they're
related right I don't think so the poll
says now people didn't think so and that
is reflected in the data as well right
so lighting power density and ppfd not
related again why is that it's how
you're mounting these fixtures so right
away this tells me that we've got some
in terms of lighting design in these
facilities there's something we can do
right off the bat just by changing the
layout of the existing fixtures to
improve the light delivery in these
facilities
but ppfd in production those are related
right surely there's a correlation
between ppfd that everybody wants so
badly in production now there isn't what
the what's going on here so again you
can see that we've got ppfd values down
around 700 and those facilities are
still producing on the order of 350
grams per square foot of flowering
canopy then we have facilities all the
way out at what is that like 1,100 ppfd
that are making about half of that right
so what is this what do we learn here
what does this tell us does it mean that
ppfd is not important no it means that
it's not everything exactly right so
what remains if it's if it's not ppfd
what else is what remains what is what
is driving the production in these
facilities if I hear them yes we heard
co2 what else did you say Nadia co2
temperature yeah yeah genetics
yup how about just cultivators skill
right because we saw multiple facilities
in this data set that were all but
identical on paper HVAC systems
basically the same Lighting's basically
the same P PFDs basically the same one
facilities literally producing double
the output of the other facility so to
me there's a lot to be learned in terms
of best practices cultivation techniques
and then what are those strains specific
impacts on energy and energy efficiency
so this is food for thought right this
doesn't necessarily give us all the
answers and it's definitely not
something that we could extrapolate out
nationally to every single facility but
this is a solid data set that we have
you know very carefully reviewed and
analyzed and there's not much to
interpret here you know this is not
based off of modeling this is just
straight up utility data and production
data so how is the energy used this
one's going to be fun I think indoor
what percent of indoor energy use do you
think is associated with lighting
horticultural lighting
just yell out some numbers I didn't hear
anyone heard 4060 alright what about
that that seems like a lot doesn't it we
were surprised by this this was more
than we had anticipated for these
facilities natural gas use really quite
low that's a little bit influenced by
the fact that some of these facilities
are all electric heat but nonetheless
large component they're associated with
the lighting so again how can we ignore
lighting as an element of facility
efficiency when it's responsible for
around 70 percent of the total energy
consumption and this is one of the
things that we use we're talking to
cultivators to go look you may or may
not be into LED just yet but how can we
not at least have the conversation with
this sort of result what about green
house is anybody want to take some
guesses on what the split of energy
consumption in a green house might be
HVAC how about this so substantially
less energy use to lighting right
because we're supplementing natural
light and a heck of a lot more energy
use on the heating in the fuel side so
that first question that we asked which
was our greenhouse is substantially more
efficient or do they use substantially
less energy than indoor not in this data
set what we found in this data set was
when you consider all fuels they are
within about 10 percent of each other in
terms of total energy use and also
relative to production because we're
kind of looking at everything relative
to production as a metric to normalize
to so this does not necessarily agree
with a lot of the national literature on
the subject but again this is not
speculative this is very straightforward
simple data and analysis that we've done
here so this for this data set you know
we are extremely confident that these
are the numbers and again this helps us
focus on well what do we look at what
are we trying to do at a given facility
we trying to impact its carbon footprint
are we trying to reduce energy we're
trying to save energy costs because
while natural gas might be a big
percentage of your car
your consumption in this particular
location at least it's a fraction of
their operating costs they're still
spending way more on electricity than
they are on fuel so a little food for
thought as we proceed in terms of what
is the data actually showing us and how
do we improve our understanding of these
facilities and in my opinion it's
through more data right we can't really
figure out what's going on here until we
look more carefully until we get more
data and as Derek said you know the
power score was extremely helpful as we
reviewed this data set and the more data
that we can get into power score the
more that people are publishing and
sharing this data we can really start to
understand what is going on these
facilities and how do we better optimize
these facilities and this is a picture
from my daughter's theater last year we
did Alice in Wonderland and I just
thought was a pretty picture to end with
so I'll leave it right there thank you
[Applause]
all right thanks Nick
so we're gonna have one more poll now
for Brian's presentation but I was wrong
I thought that more light equals more
yield so if you were wrong about any of
those I would encourage you to stand up
come on please anybody I know that some
of you were wrong there we go come on
join join us you learned something yeah
okay
all right this is the next poll so what
do you think is a bigger factor in the
climate impact of cultivation is it the
amount of energy used in a cultivation
facility or is it the electrical grid
mix and the fuels that they choose to
use on-site so it's looking at about
8020 so 80% of folks are choosing that
the grid mix and the fuels that you
choose are going to make a bigger impact
on your climate footprint of a facility
so with that I'm gonna have Brian join
us and have his presentation brought up
Thank You Gretchen Bryan Jungers senior
manager at esource which is a boulder
colorado company used to be part of
Rocky Mountain Institute back in the
1980s and 90s and then spun off and
we've been our own entity since then but
we really focus on utilities and their
customers and energy efficiency demand
side management renewables and
distribute energy resources so I'm gonna
quickly blaze through a little bit
history on the data and the analysis of
energy and climate impacts some of the
backlash from that I talked about the
elephant in the room
Evan Mills as John Morris mentioned
earlier get into him a little bit and
then talk about on the aggregate what
what's going on in the public record
what do we know or think we kind of know
about the overall total impacts of this
industry and give you some key takeaways
from my perspective so who red up in
smoke the 2012 study I'm back in the day
cool okay I get a number of people it
was really groundbreaking because there
wasn't anything in you know the the
intellectual literature on this industry
yet it had been behind closed doors
black market and Evan Mills and and
Scott Surabhi came out and did a
detailed careful analysis based on a
very limited amount of actual monitored
data from these residential grow
facilities in Mendocino County and they
came up with these numbers which there
was a lot of pushback from the regulated
industry saying these numbers are
inflated this is not representative but
the reality is that no one actually came
and replicated their study you know down
to the to the line item and so they were
never really refuted and this it was
intended as a call to action to say hey
we need to regulate this industry we
need to have policies in place so that
energy efficiency is incentivized we
need to help growers be as efficient as
possible so it was a fairly benign noble
intention to start but it led to
this really kind of crazy media frenzy
right did everybody see that three of
these these are real headline articles
and three of these are from the last six
months so this is a not by any means
over and almost every article that comes
out quote seven mills and his 2012 study
and they also often refer to the fact
that the city of Denver about three or
four percent of Denver's energy use is
for the cannabis industry and so I
wanted to dig into that a little bit but
first I wanted to let you all know Mills
is not done he recently sent out a draft
of a chapter that he intends to publish
in a book about policy or a collection
of papers and I got news for you all
it's not any better than his 2012 study
in fact it's much worse he does not do
any new detailed engineering analysis or
energy analysis he points to other
analyses including one that I assisted
with from a new frontier data and Rai
saying that they're not rigorous enough
that they lack intellectual rigor he
essentially says that greenhouses are
just as bad as fully indoor grows and
and that all growing should be done
outdoors we are optimizing the
suboptimal and that it's it's outdoor
cultivation or bus nothing else is
really acceptable I have lots of issues
with this and I could talk for half the
day about every issue I have with this
but essentially evan is is becoming
something of a sensationalist with with
this piece in particular he doesn't
really give any consideration of
industrial conventional agriculture as a
baseline he only compares to residential
and commercial building use not to
industrial which industrial and
conventional AG are much better
benchmarks and baselines to consider and
that's just the tip of the iceberg
there's there's a bunch more but I'm
gonna move on so yeah there's lots of
reasons why we're all doing this why
we're looking at indoor agriculture and
controlled environment agriculture and
why we care if if there weren't good
reasons to do it
there wouldn't be an industry and we
wouldn't be investing all these efforts
so it's kind of silly of him to do this
because he's not taking a lot of
feedback and and improving his analysis
he's just kind of doubling down on a
somewhat limited perspective and I don't
think he knows very much about
agriculture unfortunately so let's look
at Denver so Denver three to four
percent of energy use in the city of
Denver is going to the cannabis industry
but this is the retail facilities this
is processing extraction like the whole
nine yards right and if you've been to
Colorado if you live in Colorado you
know that it's not just Coloradans that
are consuming cannabis in Colorado right
I mean when I've talked to folks there
something like half of the sales and
some of these facilities are for
out-of-state folks so it's a lot of
cannabis tourism and and as the United
States changes their their policies this
is probably going to change but they've
published a lot of their energy use data
and also the production data and sales
data and so I went and compared Mills
efficiency production efficiency numbers
to what I think the production of
efficiencies actually are in Denver and
Mills would have said that you could
only produce about a hundred thousand
pounds in Denver based on how much
energy like the upper end energy use I
have in that range but the actual sales
are like almost three times that so
people are obviously more efficient and
the data that Denver has shows that
growers are becoming more efficient over
time now if we drive up the road from
Denver to Boulder Nick would did a great
job but are you talking about this so
I'm not gonna belabor the point but I
mostly just wanted to look at the carbon
intensity of the growing happening there
so they report a little over a hundred
pounds co2 per square foot of cultivated
space at Boulder County so that is
largely because it is a lot of coal in
the grid mix there in Colorado right so
I was part of a study with ICF that we
did on behalf of the government in
British Columbia and we found numbers
were very different
Brad Queen did a DSM evaluation on
behalf of County of Boulder some folks
have probably seen this one of the I
think the most interest
thing that came away from that study was
simply that a lot of growers are not
getting any sort of signal back from
their energy use because they are master
metered and they're not submitter so if
you aren't measuring what you're doing
there's no way you're gonna be able to
really effectively and consistently
improve upon that so just getting folks
metered and having the energy use data
coming back to them huge step in the
right direction right but from the the
BC study that I was part of with ICF
what we found was really interesting is
that the Canadian cannabis growers were
less efficient whether it was warehouse
or greenhouse they were less efficient
than the US growers and we had data from
well over a dozen different data sets
and facilities from all over the world
we had data from Europe data from North
America US Canada so across the board on
average the US growers are more
efficient but the climate impacts were
much lower in BC and it's simply because
it's mostly hydro right so they don't
have any coal in their mix so even
though they're less energy efficient
their climate impact is lower so yeah if
you guess that you're the most the
amount of energy you use is has a bigger
impact on your climate footprint then
where you're located largely that's not
the case and so we actually found that
the greenhouses had higher co2 impact
than all indoor warehouses in BC so you
know in that climate and it's mostly
because the the climate impact is
natural gas driven right it's because
the heating from these greenhouses is
really making up a significant portion
of that of that climate impact so just
want to encourage everyone to go out and
read the best practice guides if you
haven't already they're free they're
available on the website I participated
in the lighting technology but tack to
produce the lighting guide and it's
great and I hope that we can get out to
more growers in the future so a few
takeaways you know I think the only way
we're really going to build a fight
negative press like what came out
following MML study is to do our own
very critical analysis and publish it
and get it out there
we can't just hope that it'll go away
because it hasn't gone away and I think
may yet actually even get worse over
time so yeah if anybody wants to publish
any studies with me let me know reach
out happy - yeah good AC Tripoli let's
do it
thank you so the 20% of the room that
guest energy consumption is a greater
contributor to climate impact please
stand dance no one's standing and
dancing it's like they want audience
participation but they don't want to
participate so all right this is our
next one six gallons of water per plant
per day is a good rule of thumb to run
with this is a number that's been said
to me in many places so just curious who
thinks it's good
where did six come from okay fine
nobody's gonna have to dance with this
one all right I'm going to welcome Ted
to the podium
[Applause]
everyone my name is Ted Grantham I'm a
professor at UC Berkeley
coming from the Department of
Environmental Sciences policy and
management I'm a bit of an outlier here
and that I don't work on energy I work
on water and to date I've mostly been
focused on outdoor not not indoor water
use but I'm super excited to be working
with new frontier and REI on a water
report that I think will address both
the indoor and outdoor aspects of
cannabis cultivation
I think another area that we have in
common is an awareness that the lack of
data and lack of good data has been a
enormous barrier to our understanding of
cannabis cultivation systems generally
and also a barrier to good policy and
that's really the approach that I'm
coming from as a research scientist at
UC Berkeley and I can share a little bit
about what we're doing at the UC
Berkeley cannabis Research Center and
then tell you a little bit about our
water work specifically so about two
years ago a group of faculty at on
campus
met who were interested in cannabis and
this included anthropologists and
wildlife biologists hydrologists land
use scientists lawyers and we recognized
that there was a real need for better
peer-reviewed scholarship around
cannabis given the importance of this of
this crop to to the economy all of the
policy debates happening around cannabis
and to the potential environmental
impacts and so we realized that by
working together we could really help
advance some of the underlying science
to address these needs and our approach
really builds on not just you know pure
pure research but also as engagement so
we work through UCI's Cooperative
Extension network to work with farmers
policymakers regulators other academic
and identity is to really create a space
for dialogue among among growers among
industry and
and other other interest groups so our
our focus is quite a bit different I
think than some of the other UC research
centers that have focused on cannabis
and that we're really interested in
understanding and studying cannabis as
an agricultural system not as a drug or
a medicine so we don't focus on the
medical and public health aspects of
cannabis in California rather we focus
on things like agricultural production
practices environmental impacts the
policy setting and really the community
level social impacts of cannabis
production which to date has largely
focused on the north coast but we've
been expanding our footprint to other
parts of the state in terms of our water
work the story is actually a little bit
similar to the story that Brian
mentioned and that some of the concerns
over over water use have really been I
think sensationalized in the media and
there hasn't really been great science
to support our understanding of how
water use by cannabis primarily outdoor
cannabis growers could be affecting the
environment there have been there's a
lot of anecdotal evidence from from
raids on trespass grows or illegal grows
from different parts of the state of
poor water management practices here on
your left you see a kind of a pump
perched precariously over a over a
stream diverting water directly from a
stream the photo on your right shows a
stream that's been sort of dug out and
and kind of diverted into a into a large
pond that's supplying supplying a farm
and so when you know when enforcement
agencies and and in the media witnessed
practices like these it rightfully does
raise alarm bells but the question
remains how reflective are these
practices of the broader broader grower
community and these really the questions
that we wanted to wanted to address and
we have some really basic questions
right and and it's pretty remarkable to
us when we kind of looked at the
literature that these questions haven't
been answered you know where do cannabis
growers get their water and how much
water are they using fortunately through
you know the passes of prop 64 and some
of the regulatory Pro
have been developed to develop a legal
cannabis market we're actually getting
new data from growers on their water use
and the results that I'll be showing
today are from a data set that was
developed through a regional regulatory
program that started in in 2016 and it
basically reflects data from grower
community in this region in in the
twenty six seventeen year and these data
include information from about a
thousand farms it includes information
like the size of the cultivation area
the type of the cultivation area whether
that's fully outdoor mixed light or
indoor and includes water sourcing input
to storage and water applied applied to
plants so our first question where are
cannabis farmers getting their water
they rely on a variety of sources
including groundwater wells streams
Springs and and some rainwater catchment
and we look at the the relative
proportion of of use we see that the
vast majority of farmers are relying on
on wells and then we just kind of walk
you through focus on the gray lines
first so this represents about 60% of
all growers in the region are using
wells in this dark line part of it means
that those those users are using more
than more than other other sources in
addition in addition to well so a lot of
growers are only using wells as their as
their water supply we also have you know
a fair number of farmers using surface
water supplies like Springs or sorry
like rivers and streams to meet their
needs fewer using rain catchments and
this off-site basically represents you
know things like water trucking or
municipal water supplies and so this was
a surprise to us I think there was an
assumption certainly by the kind of
regulator community that growers were
primarily relying on surface water
diversions which is which is really a
huge concern and given that where these
grows are they tend to be concentrated
in watersheds that support
of species like endangered salmon and so
that's really one of them the major
environmental concerns driving policy in
this region so the second question how
much water is actually being used so
there's really only one other study
that's been focused on outdoor cannabis
water use and this is a study by Scott
Bauer back in 20 2016 and yeah this was
absolutely I think a good faith effort
to think about what cannabis water
demands might mean in the context of
water availability and thinking about
potential impacts to streamflow in these
sensitive species that we that we care
about and they use this at you know at
the time this was well before
legalization getting oxidizes data was
very difficult and so they they did
communicate with some some farmer
associations to come up with some a
rough estimate of cannabis use and
that's where this six gallons per day
per plant estimate over over the hundred
and fifty days of the growing season
came and so they basically use this this
this water use estimate applied it to
the number of plants they viewed on
through aerial imagery analysis and then
scaled that up to the watershed to
estimate the total demand of cannabis in
a watershed relative to supplies and
they study these little watersheds here
in different parts of the of the state
so through this analysis of of these
about a thousand reports we get a much
more nuanced picture of of water use
apologises a little bit difficult to see
but let's first start with water use
overall and first of all what we see is
there's a strong seasonal pattern in in
water demand and just if you're curious
these this shows liters of water this is
basically scaled to the median farm size
which is about a quarter of an acre in
in the region but the pattern is really
what I want to highlight here because
that initial estimate of cannabis water
use just rely basically estimated a
constant demand from the start of the
growing season to the end of the growing
season
the water extraction profile for users
that rely on perennial sources like
groundwater largely explains this this
this trend that we see here right so
these are the majority of users that are
using groundwater basically are pumping
water on demand to meet to meet their
needs
in contrast growers that rely on
seasonal sources like like Springs where
you know flows may either cease entirely
can become quite low or less reliable
they tend to be pumping water kind of
your year round and the reason they're
pumping water in the winter is because
they're moving that water into storage
to use later in the growing season and
for those subset of growers that
actually had large water storage
capacities like ponds they had a
completely inverted pattern of water use
where they're basically getting all of
their water in the winter months filling
up those ponds and have very low demands
in in the growing season in the summer
now this has really important policy
implications because under the current
state water board regulations any
outdoor grower is actually prohibited
from taking water from streams in the
summer months so if you're a grower who
relies on streams you're either going to
need a build storage to to meet your
growing season demands or put in a well
and wells ground water generally not
regulated by by the war by the water
board and their cannabis policy so we
ask the question do cannabis growers in
this data set at least have enough
storage on-site to meet their growing
season demands in other words can they
comply with these forbearance
requirements and what we see is that the
vast majority do not and so this
basically again shows that that for
these growers that have rely on seasonal
sources they're gonna they're going to
need a either build a pond which is can
be you know very cost prohibitive
they're gonna have to move on to
groundwater which has its own challenges
or they're gonna have to drop out of the
of the permit system so just to
summarize this is just really a brief
snapshot of some of our water research
and our research portfolio broadly but
through this work we found that wells
were the most common source of outdoor
for outdoor canon outdoor mix light
cannabis cultivation in the region the
amount and timing of water really
depends on your water source on the in
the amount of water storage capacity
available and that we found that most
farms had insufficient storage to meet
state permitting requirements which
could be a really important barrier to
compliance for growers that are
attempting to enter the illegal the
legal system that's all I have today
next time I'll tell you about our
wildlife studies we're doing some
wildlife camera trapping and looking at
how a wildlife use basically acts use
use farms and round farms so this is a
cool photo that I'd like to share yeah
thank you okay so I'm just gonna do a
couple summary remarks and then we're
gonna open it up to Q&amp;A we learned about
energy we learned about carbon and we
learned a bit about water and all three
of those things are going to be better
supported by the new developments that
we're doing for Power score so I just
wanted to remind folks from the speeches
we heard from Nick that power score was
used as a baseline for comparison for
his Boulder County assessment brian has
been involved in helping improve power
score and we really hope to see an
increased use of utility programming's
utility programs using Power score to
get the benefit while being able to
trust the data integrity and accuracy
and then Ted mentioned how the cannabis
water report is a collaboration between
Berkeley and our III and then also that
we are going to be using information
from these studies and the water related
information to be putting into power
score as a baseline so that we can make
a baseline for water and then lastly as
I mentioned yesterday we're gonna be
pulling in carbon shadowing for the
actual energy sources that people use to
the point that Brian made about mixes so
that we can actually understand what's
the carbon intensity of these different
facilities based off of the fuel sources
that they use the mix of their grid and
then the choices that they make inside
the facility
so I invite folks to pepper us with
questions I have some that I could ask
but I really prefer to get them started
out here don't all jump down at once I'm
Corinne good morning thanks Nick for
that presentation that you showed on
energy I I wonder what the greenhouses
though in the data set that you had was
that can you talk a little bit about the
geographical distribution of the data
set that you had was that all up in the
you know the north any in the south yes
so it was all climate zone 5b hey which
one's the dry one somebody knows you
that's not right you made that up
whichever the dry one is 5a I don't know
it was all 5a and an important thing I
did not I pointed out how there was a
lot of variety amongst those facilities
there was one commonality which is that
they were all HID lighting there was not
an LED amongst them that was a mix
between HPS and C mhm but that is a
important I think detail that I left out
also you are the first to see that data
outside of the reviewers in Boulder
County so you're all very special
there's a follow-up question from the
slide oh how does energy compared
between sealed and ventilated
greenhouses so more we'd see more HVAC
use in the sealed greenhouses you know
they have full-blown HVAC systems and
not only they're dealing with the loads
from the lighting but there's the you
know the solar radiation that's helping
increase the heat in that space as well
so you know lighting loads are quite
similar that they're both using within
this sample all of the mixed light
facilities we're using some form
threshold control to turn the lights on
and off energy use is pretty similar on
the lighting side HVAC use was
definitely higher for those sealed
facilities
nineteen facilities yeah so I wanted to
ask about what you know as far as energy
reporting and gathering data like what
are some of the challenges of scaling
that up I know some of it's been
self-reported but you know how do we how
do we do that accurately at scale sure I
mean I think that's a lot of attention
of the power score is for enough folks
to adopt it become a standard and then
it helps to set the framework for how
energy is reported and you know and in
what format and so that we can compare
directly I don't know that there's any
other standard out there
I mean individual utilities have a ami
data and they're collecting data
obviously but outside of that there's
not a lot of standardization the issue
for me is the standardization in other
words you're you're tying it all back to
either high pressure sodium and you're
not going back to what Mother Nature is
doing outdoors it would seem to me you'd
want to look at what the when you're
comparing LEDs or anything else
what's outdoors what what is and it's
not just ppfd in the power range that
plants are looking for and with regards
to standardization of using indoor
agriculture as a way to then upscale
cannabis when you look at the almond
that's using one pound of water per
almond so when you look at six pounds
per four-hour cannabis I mean six
gallons per cannabis I think we we need
to also look at standardization of where
we start to do the measurements and then
the slide with the regards to the amount
of yield going down
these are sation beings these plants
shut down when they it's too much
they're so putting more light on it it's
not going to make it grow plus where do
you go 18 hours of light part of the
world I'm sorry do you have a question
yes the question is how do you determine
the standards from which you from which
you be able to make these measurements
because they're all over the
place depending on who's presenting well
a baseline has to be drawn somewhere I
think we can all agree there's baselines
that we need for outdoor growing there's
baselines that we need for some of the
great awesome stuff that Ted was
presenting on how are people getting
water how are they storing it when are
they using it and those are folks that
are using a resource brought to us by
the earth how people choose to light is
not necessarily what I think we're
trying to talk about in this panel and
so I think what I'd love for anyone to
comment on is like how do you make a
baseline for an industry that in some
opinions is unbeatable I've been asked
this question many times over the years
and I think you simply start with what
people are doing to the extent that
folks are sharing and we have we can
have some confidence in the data you see
what people are doing right now and then
you look at the range this is the low
end this is the high end you know set an
average and then start to try to ratchet
it down but the problem is so much data
wasn't collected for a very long time
for legal reasons and then isn't
collected or reported now for
proprietary reasons and so having faith
in the data that's available it really
limits our ability to set a baseline or
even talk about setting a baseline so
I'll jump in on that as well because
we're doing a baseline study in
Massachusetts right now Commissioner
Doyle I need to catch up with you at
some point wherever you're hiding back
there yes and it's it's really
challenging you know because there is so
no facility no to facilities I've ever
been in are alike they're all a little
bit different right so there's just a
lot of ways to skin the cat because I
like to say all that matters is there's
one more dead cat so it's it's very
difficult to set baselines but within
that effort to try to figure out what
people are currently doing we are
finding there are certain systems or
certain parts of the process that there
is a lot of consistency and it is
reasonably comfortable to say okay this
is standard practice for this technology
in this phase of cultivation
but like veg lighting mmm it's you know
is it t fives is it single-ended Mel how
wide is it LED and we see a wide variety
of lighting technologies for that so
it's more difficult to say this is
standard practice thanks very much
um one question that came up when I
first started pouring into doing the
literature review of the available
studies and what is the baseline how
could you compare X to Y whether it's HP
s2 LED or something else and one of the
things that I found with the first
studies was the SMUD studies done with
seven leaves and amplified farms I think
and both of them the first one didn't
control for strain and then the second
one tried to tried to at least sort of
correlate these ranges of energy and
production based off of strain type and
then I started learning more and
basically learned that even strain name
doesn't really mean anything in genetics
and you could have green crack in one
place green crack in another they're
totally different plants too for
genetics so having it controlled by
strain wouldn't be accurate so I just
wanted to open that can of worms is
there any way to control by plants so
that you're actually comparing apples to
apples we're just starting a study of
that very thing with a cultivator who
runs his facility like a lab and is one
of the only may be the only cultivator
I've run into that dedicates a room to a
strain so everybody else I've ever been
they have a mix of strains in a flower
room and that pretty much precludes the
ability to figure out how the strain
might impact energy consumption I'll let
you know when we're done if it worked or
not yeah and I'll say exactly the same
thing that the folks that are really
really controlled facilities and they
they're tracking very carefully genotype
phenotype genotype and and they can
report on all of that you know to a very
precise ability that's when you can
start to actually work back to a
standardization I just want to make one
when one comment on with respect to
water and that and this is a Brawley
with water and energy that it's
incredibly it's still very difficult for
for the research community and
university researchers to actually do
these types of studies where one might
look at you know the various responses
of particular strains or cultivation
strategies to variation in energy or
water applications we're still
prohibited from actually working with
the plant it's still considered a
federal one Schedule one drug and we
risk our university funding if we even
come you know basically in contact with
with the plant so I just wanted to
mention that we're still a long way away
in the research community you know
publicly funded research community from
being able to ask these you know ask
these relevant relevant questions so
it's really going to depend I think on
partnerships with industry at least for
the foreseeable future to to get these
these data that are that are so
important so this is a question directed
to you Ted I think that I heard you say
that there's not regulation on wells for
farms and I'm just sort of surprised
about that there's not a regulation on
the number of wells or how deep they go
could you speak a little bit more to
that if I'm yeah yeah so this is yeah
one of the fascinating aspects of
California water management and water
law and that we have you know this this
this strong distinction between the way
that we regulate surface water and
regulate groundwater and only surface
water is really under the purview of
regulation under this about the state by
the state water board and you know
groundwater historically has been
entirely unregulated there has been some
recent policy changes there's a law
passed during that hide the last drought
called the stand well groundwater
management act that did bring some
groundwater into into regulation in the
in the water policy there there is a
provision that if it could if it can be
shown that you know groundwater wells
are sort of hydrologically connected to
surface water then they can be sort of
considered to be under the authority or
jurisdiction of the of the of the state
but that generally you know there's not
only any evidence that the state is
hungry to exercise that that
jurisdiction at this point
there's really trying to to tackle the
the the surface water issue so all right
I think we're do you wanted one okay all
right here I I've been a little bit
concerned with the whole format of how
this is being presented and let me give
you an example the terminologies of
consumption or use of water seems to be
interchangeable as far as it's been used
here and that's decidedly not the case
now let me give you a very clear example
if you had an old time middle operation
that had a water wheel and he's
diverting a stream over his wheel and
that's where he's getting his power - is
he using water well I guess he is but
he's not consuming water and I think
generally the idea is is that if you are
able to return the water in the same
quality that you took it in then it's
not consumed so the real question I
think usually is how much what are you
consuming not how much water you're
using now in plants the obvious thing is
that they consume very little the the
they use a lot for transpiration and the
question is is what's the significance
of that transpiration as far as water
use versus water consumption and that
gets integrated back into your climate
control your dehumidification whether
your reutilizing that water whether it's
in some way being contaminated or
something like that and until we get
more precise use of words and
definitions I think the data will not
have much significance that's a great
point and I completely agree there's an
important distinction between applied
water and consumptive use of plants I
think in a lot of agricultural crops
there is a substantial fraction of water
that's applied to the crops that is not
lost through about the transpiration and
that could potentially return
to the environment with respect to
outdoor cannabis cultivation the the
practices that we've seen has primarily
been very high efficiency drip
irrigation is sort of the is that is the
standard where we don't really see any
evidence of you know sort of substantial
return flows or you know not much of
that water you know is is is ending up
back and back in the environment at
least not to you know not in any way
that we could actually measure and
detect a response and say the stream
from which these these waters are being
are being drawn so I totally agree there
is a need to get to bring sort of more
refinement and nuance to our
understanding of crop water water
consumptive use and those those dynamics
we're not we're not there yet
but I would say for cannabis at least
from our experience and outdoor grows we
have I think looking at applied water is
a pretty good proxy for for consumptive
use thank you everyone for your
questions
um just again another little plug we've
done a lot of improvements to the water
side of power score and we'd love
anybody with what water stakeholders
feedback on that in terms of what are we
asking are we asking the right questions
are we going to get the right
information that you would want to know
so thank you all and I think what's the
next thing
[Music]
wonderful Thank You Juan Carlos yeah
well let's give a hand to the panel