Jew or three of you were on a panel at
the emerald-cut just a few months ago
where Richard Mendelsohn was speaking on
cannabis appellations and he said that
it's almost like mining for gold so it's
not enough to find the gold whatever
that is so to speak we're talking about
cannabis but to be able to mine it right
those were words that I remember it's
saying I have rough notes and in
thinking about that you can see that
we're talking about science in so many
different ways the cultivars this is Dan
kind of practices and I started to read
Appalachian Napa Valley
Richard Middleton's book and there's a
wonderful quote at the beginning so
before we go anywhere else they just
think if we listened to these words here
that he opened this booklet so Robert
Lewis Stevenson quote and it's very much
a description about wine and how wine is
like mining but if we think about
cannabis cultivation I think very much
there are a lot of the same things here
so this is from the rich California
earth and the quote is the beginning of
vine planting is like the beginning of
mining for precious metals the
winegrower also prospects one corner of
the land is another tried with one kind
of grape after another this is the
failure that's better a third is best so
bit by bit they grope for their clovers
oh and their love feet those loads and
pockets of Earth's more precious than
the pressure sores that yield individual
fragrance and soft butter those virtuous
bonanzas where the soil is sublimated
under the Sun and stars to something
finer and where the wine is bottled
poetry these lie undiscovered Cheryl
conceals thicket and Bowers them and the
minor chips the rock and wanders further
and the grisly means is undisturbed but
they bide their hour awaiting their
Columbus and nature nurtures nurses and
prepares them the snack of California
earth shall linger on the palate of your
grandson Robert Louis Stevenson from the
Silverado squatters so if we think about
how this is very much a science and that
gold is not enough but being able to
mine it right I'd love to hand this over
to max Montrose and he'll lead us in a
presentation max please take it away
thank you so much
I've been really excited to see cannabis
appellations become a thing for many
years now and it is going to help family
farmers in the Emerald triangle who
deserve to prove that their cannabis is
special and so how we do that is going
to be really interesting and I think
cannabis Psalms can actually play a
really big role in that and so you know
a cannabis Somalia's is pretty darn new
and so I just want to briefly explain
what it is and what we do and then of
course interact with other participants
and answer any questions that name-o and
when they have the first thing I'll say
is you know us as the cannabis industry
we keep alluding to this thing that we
know about which is this expertise which
is more than an expertise it's next
level expert which is a Somali a but I
have to tell you that the wine community
it drives them crazy that we say
cannabis Somali eh
and for many different reasons and so
one thing that's true is this expertise
does exist throughout many other
industries and so you have wine
Somalia's you have beer sister owns
cheesemongers coffee cup and within the
trichome institute when we were
developing how do you certify someone
who's actually an expert in how dynamic
cannabis is and how complicated it is
and what is it actually we came up with
the term in Terpening and so for us a
cannabis psalm is an interpreter and so
what we're doing is we are interpreting
terpenes and we're not just trying to
pretend like we're gas chromatography
and if we're detecting little oil verse
marcene we're actually with the
trigeminal nerve of your face you can
detect if these varietals are either
stimulating sedative or actually in
between that spectrum cannabis isn't one
or the either
it's a massive spectrum with multiples
in between as we all know and so what
can
songs do is well it's it's actually very
similar to a wine Psalm what
interpreters do because cannabis truly
does have an appellation it has terroir
it has two pissah tea vintages historic
family farmers pairings tastings in so
much more it's probably closer cannabis
and wine than cannabis is to beer or
coffee or cheese or any of those other
things and so that's why it's meaningful
that there's such a thing as a cannabis
song or an interpreter and there's some
really big differences at the same time
you know the one of the biggest
differences is the wine industry is
thousands of years old and the cannabis
industry was born yesterday and because
of that there's tons of problems such as
the strain name dilemma even the
speciation dilemma the fact that our
industry thinks that it's indica or
sativa when it's neither that that's a
big deal
another huge difference is you know
grapes is a perennial fruit that lives
in the earth for decades
cannabis is an annual Bush that lives
one lifetime and so I actually have more
questions than I do answers in terms of
how are we as an industry going to prove
that the geography of origin impacts the
cannabis in terms of where it's grown
how do we test for that and that's
something I would love to dig into in
this in this panel and then I think at
the end of the day the most important
thing and if you want to move through
some of these slides please feel free I
think one of the most important
differences between a wine expert and a
cannabis expert is a wine expert is
really cool like it is really cool that
you can do these incredible things that
you can taste that the capacity of the
russian river in a pinot noir is unique
due to the geographic origin that's cool
and being able to be a cannabis expert
at a really high level is very cool too
but something more important than cool
is that it's important to have a
cannabis expert in this time period
because even though we have
legislatively mandated lab testing and
thank God that we do thank God we're
testing for pesticides microbials and
all the things typically labs don't look
for what we consider to be quality
typically labs don't look for the flush
in sex nutrient lock nutrient overdose
if the cannabis is ripe or not or where
on the spectrum between it being a
stimulating drug or a sedative substance
it is it lying within labs don't really
do that and because we have the strain
named dilemma because but attenders
aren't legislatively mandated to be
trained licensed or certified like
plumbers or people who cut hair or nails
it's critical that we have people that
have an ability to assess cannabis for
its qualitative features what they are
so at the end of the day consumers have
they know two things not just a stray
name and a THC percentage but is this
product I'm about to consume okay for me
to consume and at what level what level
of the quality is this and how you know
that
and after I consume it what's it going
to do to me those are two really
fundamental things and that's something
that interpreting does we can help with
that so we've got courses books tools
online tons of stuff that trichome
Institute but something that you're
looking at right that was just shown
below there is that's our objective
analysis for grading cannabis quality
for all of the things that labs
typically don't look for and what a lot
of those practices can do especially
when when it comes to to pissah t is to
know how and why cannabis varietals that
are grown in specific regions in
northern california are important and
deserve labeling that's more meaningful
than cannabis that isn't to me I believe
that that has more to do with quality
than it does with a strain name
or the genealogy of the plant and I'm
also not sure how we're going to prove
the geographical origin but I'm really
excited to find out and and open it up
to the other awesome experts that we
have on the panel so thank you so much
thank you so much max thank you it was
so great to hear your perspective as the
beginning and then just thanking right
into how some of the things that
cannabis sommeliers look at we have this
set of regulations draft set of
regulations for abolition that address
things like cultivars practices and
standards and so looking at the the
definition of cultivar here it's defined
in Section 9000 a is a means it means a
cultivated variety trade designation or
strain of cannabis
I'd love to hand this to you Eleanor so
that you could provide us with some of
the key issues or things that we should
know about the state of cannabis
genetics right now and how it relates to
even just cultivar selection and some of
the concepts that a petitioning group
might have to look at when they're
deciding what to do as it relates to an
Appalachian petition so max you couldn't
team me up better I am so excited that
you really were asking you know how can
we really place these plants in the
environment in which they're in so my
training is in population genetics and
my specialty has been in the
intersection between agriculture and
medicinal plants and so we see this in
at this intersection between the place
that plants are grown and the expression
of the genes that are housed in their
genomes across all plants and it's
particularly powerful in our medicinal
plants and our culinary plants that we
love so much and so when we look at
cannabis we do have the stream name
issue we have a lot of diversity that's
out there but we also know that we have
plants that hold pipe we have
characteristics that everyone can
recognize we have names that have
historical that historical meaning
and deep value because they point to the
history of this plants as a either a
clone that's been held in propagation
for many years or isn't a family or
lineage a plant that's been propagated
and routinely selected for those
individuals that are displaying true to
type right so this is what we see in the
evolution of all of our most special
plants the more we love them the more
diversity we seem to have in them so
this can be seen in apples or grapes or
any of our other and really beloved
plants and so with cannabis we have a
situation where the genetics has really
been pushed forward in a major way
because of its history with prohibition
and so we have this irony that the the
prohibition of cannabis has acted to
really increase the diversity that we
see you within cannabis and so we have a
really amazing opportunity now to step
back and make definitions of those
plants and so when we look at cultivar
and one of the most important
fundamentals of the entire appellations
program is the definition of cultivars
whether you're going to include them or
disclude them in your proposed
appellation standard you really need to
have a definition of what those plants
are and so fundamentally when we do this
with any plant whether it's a new
species or it's a cultivar that we've
developed from a population of plants we
do this through definitions that
fundamentally include herb area which
press that plant and preserve the
definitional qualities of that plant and
so this is a really important
fundamental first step is the defining
of this plants and then when you want to
and so we've started candor which is an
herbarium that specializes in cannabis
and really specializes in documenting
the community's history with these
plants just ownership of the community
to those plants and also make those
definitions that make sense to the
community that's been stirring those
plants from the beginning and so once
you have those definitions you can move
into what we is genetic all G by E
experiment so it's basically you take
genetics and you put them in specific
environments it can either be the same
environment or you can put the same
plant
many different environments and in doing
that type of experiment you really link
the expression of those genetics and the
outward phenotype with the place so you
take the genetics and the environment
into account so you can really
understand how that environment is
driving the expression and so you know
if you take some of your Hayes's that do
really well in this beautiful coastal
area and they need certain conditions
and you move them to north carolina or
to arizona you're gonna have very
different plants in their expression
because of that interaction between
their genetics and the environment and
so these are things that we really we
know intuitively in our communities oh
this plant grows well here oh this plant
doesn't do well here and it's taking
that information and then also going the
next step in doing these experiments
that really look specifically at how the
environment and the genetics interact
with each other so I'm just going to
take the second Eleanor to take us even
deeper into some of the regulatory
material in the initial statement of
reasons the CDFA had noted that there is
to some extent an uncertainty within
cannabis genetics testing just the
ability to account for what you have and
to be able to establish that it is in
fact what you think it is
and the CDFA noted here that the freedom
to require a prohibit list of cultivars
allows the petitioners to self define
and I'm wondering you know I've heard of
you farmer groups talk about this I know
Swami will have something to say about
this as well um you know it must it will
be difficult for a petitioning group to
decide upon or to come to consensus
about even what cultivars they want to
include in their petition and you know
whether or not they're going to exclude
cultivars altogether at all will be a
fundamental and difficult decision but
you know what kinds of discussions have
you had with some of the farmers or the
stakeholder groups that are interested
in pursuing an apple
and perhaps also I want to make sure
that I free the green box upsets mommy
can chime in as well on cultivar and you
know what different issues our farmer is
going to encounter here you know what
what what is you know maybe some
concepts to keep in mind and you know
maybe some glimmers of help as well yeah
I can quickly speak to that again
prohibition has left the scientific
community out of the loop for a very
long time in our agricultural sciences
are deeply under invested at this moment
and so that's something that we see
picking up pace as we have more and more
lifting of that veil of prohibition over
the scientific aspects of cannabis
biology and agriculture and so we will
continue to learn more and more and have
more and more tools scientific tools to
understand not only diversity in our
agricultural populace within cannabis
but also our global diversity of canvass
in general and then just to speak
specifically about the regs and in
making those decisions about cultivars
to include and not include you know it's
sometimes always easier to point to the
things you don't want then to bring in
the things you do and then there are
other groups who instead of having an
extrordinary
amazing plants that have been held in
community have been specifically
selected to do well in their region and
so there's become natural plants to
include and they have a deep history not
only with the land itself being selected
on that land but also with the
communities that are taking care of
those plants as an annual and propagated
them and move them forward generation to
generation so I'm going to Swami has a
lot to say about this so I'm going to
pass it over him well we're talking
about how the plant responds to the
environment and first of all the
cannabis plant is known to be what they
call a bio accumulator or a fight or a
mediator and just for you to know that
there was an experiment done after
Chernobyl nuclear power plant
and they planted hemp all around it
because they have pulled the nuclear
radiation out of the soil and so
basically you know where they say in
computers garbage in garbage out
it's the same with cannabis whatever's
in the soil if the plant is going to
pull up a good bit of that and that will
be reflected in the actual flavor and
the end of the plant and so that's what
you know max refers to as insufficient
flushing and so on so but there are a
ways of growing cannabis that you know
even flushing doesn't come in and so
what we're talking about is legacy
growers here in the mountains all over
California not just in an ephemeral
triangle but also down in Big Sur and
Santa Cruz and over in Grass Valley and
up in the various mountains and so on
they all have their own traditions and
as Eleanor was saying that over time we
found in various areas oh don't grow
that one on the coast you're going to
get powdery mildew and don't grow that
one over in Grass Valley because it's so
hot and dry and so on and so I mean I
know being a judge in the Emerald cup I
really encounter a lot about cannabis
experts people who know more than me in
so many ways and so many people out
there who you know who've been buyers
and clubs who have been growers for so
many times ears or breeders they can
taste something and they say oh that's
that purple Urkel and it's probably
crossed with that train wreck or
something like that people have an
amazing ability through their nose and
also through tasting the actual smoking
to really pinpoint and I have another
friend who's like a third generation
been growing since he was 12 and he can
pretty much tell you almost which
mountain that grew on from the shape of
the bud and from all the ways that it's
uniquely done but remember in the old
old day is up here in the mountains and
all over people were crawling under the
bushes with maybe a bag of soil or maybe
they just had the soil in the earth and
you know they were growing tiny plants
and they were saving their urine during
the winter to use that for nitrogen
fertilizer and so on so these are the
old techniques that nobody uses those
anymore but that's where we come from
but over time people have really
developed their their techniques and so
there's a science and there's an art
also that the science of it has to do
with we're we're now moving into what we
know
regenerative agriculture and things
known as the soil food web living soil
and things like this and so when you are
attempting to source virtually all of
your ingredients either from your own
farm or within the immediate locality
then like I've got wood chips from my
oak trees I got oak leaves you know I've
got my compost I've got my worm bin over
here and so on all of those are putting
inputs that come from my place and so
they are now creating even more so in
association with the plant and its
natural environment and over time we
talk about the biome that the total
environmental arable life around but
also the microbiome the living organisms
in the soil and all of those things have
have importance and so these become
standards in the sense of do we say ok
in Mendocino we had a long tradition
nobody grew more than like you know 25
or 30 plants whereas up in Humboldt they
always through a thousand plants and so
there's all those are like traditions
that are different within just across
the county line and so those are kind of
things that the standards would be
produced by the petitioners to say well
in Mendo we might say well if you're
growing more than half an acre you don't
deserve an appellation but up in
Humboldt they say that's ridiculous
everybody's been growing an acre and
things of like that has it have to be
hand trimmed right hand packed or you
know do you have to use integrated pest
management all those things become
standards which then you see the thing
is that the plant also is always
responding to the environment in the way
it makes its terpenes so terpenes are a
protective mechanism just like trichomes
are a protective mechanism to protect
the plant and especially its seeds so
you honor your environment is creating
the threat or the dangers to the plant
and then the plant responds with its
terpenes even in relation to its
genetics genetics will have a propensity
for a terpene but the local environment
will say that terpene is much more
expressed or much more potent or maybe
not even present actually and Kevin's
Audrey a dear friend of mine he said he
has two farms one on the coast and one
up at like 22,000 feet same strain same
program everything else completely
different plant the way it expresses so
they're just our people who really can't
tell the difference and it's the nose
that knows but it's the I call it the
ensemble but actually was 500
ingredients it's actually a symphony of
everything in there that's all working
together and so there's a whole way of
judging this and we're working on that
and we're making that more precise thank
you so much Swami I tried to switch
around in some of the slides you know
you can see even having some of the
scientists and practitioners you're
speaking about it that standards and
practices very much overlap I want to
say sometime Swami as well when we talk
about standards to invite you as you
started to discuss whether or not a
baseline standard or a more explicit
requirement of terroir would be useful
here you know spoken it Wow
cannabis is this bioaccumulate expresses
and pulls up so much of the natural
environment sometimes the individual
farm but of course also you know the
both the micro Vario and and their
region itself natural the standards and
the difference between standards and
practices I'm still trying to come to
grips with actually understandings that
are measurable certifiable or something
like that we could say well I think the
base and the baseline would be its in
contact with the natural soil in the
ground that it's in full Sun and for the
long season is the way I like to say
though they still without artificial
life in the flowering section so in the
French concept of terroir there is a
statement that says no barrier between
the plant and nature and then I think
this is the kind of the key concept but
also the other part of the concept is
brought up several times is the cultural
or the fact of what the farmers do so up
here in the mountains and all over the
place if one farmer had a disaster maybe
the rats ate there starts
other farmers would give them starts you
know if someone got raided by the police
people would give him their shape there
was this community up here that was all
a solid community because we all shared
a risk in the prohibitive era right and
so what's happening now is the community
split between those who come in to be
legal and you are still braving the
winds of fate and growing out in the
wilderness and so we used to be one
community and that's one of the issues
we have to come across but with
standards now we have to realize what
are the important standards you know do
we say for you to be in our group you
have to be hand trimmed right and that
would be a standard and that's kind of
verifiable it's not actually measurable
right and then maybe you say okay you
have to have like six six feet between
each plant right or you can only grow
you know you can only have like three to
four pounds per plant as a stipulation
to disqualify a certain thing but all of
those kinds of specific standards
practices and so on would be created by
the group that comes and I agree with
other speakers would say three is too
small it needs to be more of a consensus
of several farmers in the same area
maybe eight or nine something like that
and of course it's hard to bring people
together to agree on things but over the
years everyone is kind of figured out
what grows up here and the best way to
do and like I say so many people are
moving into regenerative farming that
you know it's actually an expression of
not just the soil but of a state of
consciousness about how we can repair
the earth of the world by using
regenerative agricultural methods rather
than chemical salt based fertilizer
methods that are mostly used indoors and
at an industrial agriculture you know I
I just wanted to take that point to loop
it back to that quote that we were
listening to at the beginning because
when I think of mining I actually think
of it being extractive and I think of it
being you know damaging to the
environment and here when we're talking
about this intricate gold mining working
with the soil this interaction the
essential and exclusively potentially
between you know the farmer intermedia
environment and working with it when we
bring in regenerative agriculture
principles those standards if people
choose them then it almost is not so
much extractive but being back in
balance and even more of something to
help the natural environment continue to
flower whether it's you know the
pollinators or any other okay you want
to get that natural segue to Alec Dixon
because I know that he has many thoughts
on these issues as well in terms of what
he sees even now with testing you know
whether there's certain kinds of
terpenes that appear in more isolated
areas where there isn't big AG present
to even you know what a farm might do
individually to have you know these
broader terpenes or other expressions
within you know the ultimate product
from their place i know and i like as
well you may have some thoughts about
what Swami shared on the bio accumulator
aspect of the cannabis plants so lots of
questions right in a big long
yeah get off me everybody hope a breeze
well it's yeah it's an honor to be on
this panel the part of this conversation
it's really exciting progressive
conversation I think that the whole can
meet and learn more about yeah so
there's been a lot covered
I would love to jump in on a few areas
you know one you know kind of around
cannabis classification around terpenes
and understanding and having a more
sophisticated understanding of that to
really start to define what cultivars
actually exist within the cannabis plant
pool and genetic pool and chemometric
pool you know kind of from there kind of
getting into you organic agricultural
practices and ways of regional
superiority how you know the really
advanced kind of you know teamed with
microbe approaches kind of can actually
help to you know double secondary
metabolite production within the
cannabis plant
you know whenever it's grown in various
ways in various regions and then you
know from there there's the whole
conversation around bioaccumulation
properties of this plant and you know
the extreme kind of testing regulations
that are put in place but you have to
start kind of on the on the chemometrics
um so you know at SC laboratories you
know we've been open testing cannabis
excuse
for last ten years and over the time
we've you know done and ran over 120,000
terpene tests on on on strains of
cannabis that we've tested and came
across and in the recent years you know
we started working with bioinformatics
assists and data statisticians to help
us cluster data to understand more about
the nuances of the conversation around
indica hybrid sativa and you know
although we're testing currently 35
terpenes you know and there are hundreds
of compounds and ultra-trace amounts
that are expressed you know really what
we see with cannabis classification is
about five to nine terpenes that
essentially define 99% of everything
we've ever tested and from understanding
more about the primary secondary
attributes and cannabis with regard to
terpenes we can really start to dive in
to understand what cultivars actually
exists you know what we see from all the
the sorting of data is there's about
five primary smell groups and each
primary smell group then has two to
three subgroups you know you can kind of
think of it like wine system whites and
red wines and then you know the various
grapes that are in each of those
categories but essentially we see about
five primary sub primary groups you know
two to three sub groups is about ten to
twelve archetype profiles that
essentially define everything you've
ever tested and from there you can
really start to understand obscurity and
rarity and what what what types of
really really unique you know profiles
that the plant produces that you know
seem are seeming to be related to
landrace your recessive traits that are
within various strains from around the
world and so so kind of taking it from
there
you know like we then see you know kind
of a you know on the back so much of the
work of you know kind of the great
laning soil food web and the really
advanced pursuit to understand how to
optimize organic farming practices in in
the teaming with microbes approach to
you know biomimicry you're helping to
recreate you know perfect environmental
conditions means so much of the work of
the small food web is it really does
help to begin substantiating through
science and through testing on various
secondary metabolites
by the plant terpenes being in cannabis
secondary metabolite but seeing kind of
how advanced organic practices can
actually you know increase in double you
know secondary metabolite production
within the plant you know very much
based on region very much based on
organic practices and is is is not as
broad as a whole county but is this very
kind of myopic to an individual farming
practices level or the the surrounding
farmers in that region that have kind of
gained so much experience in serving
this plant over such a long period of
time so kind of you know segue in that a
little bit you know kind of from
terpenes and kind of you know the
expression of what we see and how
organic practices can enhance you know
these these secondary metabolites
produced by the plant grown in various
regions you know it kind of then kind of
goes into the conversation around
cannabis as a bio accumulating plant you
know this plant is the great bio
accumulator of the 21st century and we
are now testing it to a level that
nothing has ever been tested for Quality
Assurance around public health and
safety and for different chemometric
markers to you know help identify
quality and substantiate kind of you
know market value in various ways when
it comes to bioaccumulation and for the
QA concerns with contaminants you know
we you know it's a really fascinating
kind of see from the testing level
because you know right now we're almost
beginning to start to see California
splitting up into you know red zones
yellow zones and green zones you know
which really start to define and
highlight the various difficulties
vulnerabilities and massive
opportunities that exist for farmers in
various regions and when you start
talking about yeah I like I I just
wanted to add there because when we were
talking about even how to show this data
or this image you provided me with a
slide of an area in the Central Valley
that are like we didn't include it here
but you can see you could describe it
may be you know areas where there's just
all sorts of EPA violations and the like
and then you know a whole mountain range
on the other side with nothing
and so I wonder looking at this 90 106
geographical features one of the things
that petitioners will need to show is
that at least as that bring stand now
under be 90 106 be substantial evidence
that the geographical area is
distinctive when compared to areas
outside the proposed boundary and other
relevant areas which produce cannabis
for sale in the marketplace I know
you're from the Central Coast I've spent
some time there with different
stakeholders and we've had lots of
conversations about this even just in
you know your region can you imagine you
know being able to establish that
geographical boundary where you can see
for example an isolated area a canyon
that's away from big AG that maybe
doesn't have some of the things that
we're talking about pesticides and other
contaminants and it's maybe more
pristine yeah in so many ways you know
now that cannabis is being tested at
this level for compliance testing with
any product failing having to be
remediated destroyed you know over
thousands of these kind of fails going
back at the beginning of 2018 we've
really begin to start to kind of create
a map overlay of regions that are you
know under incredible threat to you know
for cannabis farmers growing in these
regions because of the neighboring
because the history of land because of
the agriculture practices that that were
taking place long before they were
farming there or from the neighboring
regions from the way the farmers tell
their soil and kick-up metals that can
then completely fail an entire cannabis
crop just from that simple act and yeah
and in so many ways what we're you know
the kind of a SAP elation conversation
to me is really fascinating because
through the lens of testing you know so
much of what we've seen is is really
kind of starting to show you know kind
of the the avenues and the pathways for
for people's success and small craft
farmers artists and producers have been
doing this all their life with the rich
rich and vast experience to grow this
annual plant that is you know very
harvest specific and very and very very
sensitive to to actually have an
opportunity to really shine
this time where there's you know massive
you know kind of efforts to mono crop
this plant and to kind of commercialize
it in such a way and so so in a lot of
ways yeah the the through the testing
kind of we're really beginning to see
kind of how much is being affected how
much cannabis farmers are being affected
from being planted in these areas and
and and in in so many ways it's not that
all areas of AG land in Salinas or in in
kind of you know kind of in Santa
Barbara or in Stanislaus County anywhere
where AG takes place you know presents
unique sets of challenges to any farmer
that's going to grow there and cannabis
in so many ways through being this bio
accumulator and kind of helping to tell
the story it's really beginning to you
know breathe uproot a lot of the history
and legacy of the Green Revolution and
chemical induced approach to AG and in
the process I think it's also going to
be very much a beginning to help
accelerate the slow food movement
decentralized agricultural approach
understanding where your food comes from
where your medicine comes from and and
yet holding food and all other
industries to a new standard Wow thank
you so much Alec I'm getting thumbs up
from salami I feel like we've all had
these dialogues a couple different times
in different ways that's a great place
to leave it do it can we have any last
minute last notes Blake or that's it
well the proof is in the nose and I
think Mac says the same thing and that's
what's telling you because the nose the
terpenes give you a precognition what's
going to be doing I cannot wait to learn
more about the research Alec is doing
with SC labs in these terpene testing
and the culmination of the types because
interpreting has discovered that there's
kind of five cannabis types as well and
it's chirping dependent and that the
trigeminal nerve can detect where that
spectrum is so I just want to hang out
with you and compare data and knowledge
and Swami I can't wait
smoke one with you and Ellen no I want
to learn more about awesome research you
guys are doing everybody on this panel
is really doing the coolest coolest
research that's the most meaningful I'm
very proud of the cannabis industry and
thank you all just so much for yeah for
everything this is just such a cool
thing to be a part of just gonna do a
brief introduction for each of these
great panelists that are has stayed the
course and are here to lend their wisdom
and after that I'm going to share a
quote or two that I think will guide us
through this and then we'll let max
Montrose take it away so this panel
science and sommelier comes from a
couple different angles we have Alec
Dixon who is one of the cofounders of
healthy labs he is the director of
client relations he has five years as a
consultant in hydroponic industry
formerly serving in the Navy he's an
outreach director for veterans for
medical marijuana and on the board of
the director of the women events
Alliance for medical marijuana
Santa Cruz one of the longest-running
compassion programs in the world a lot
of intersection here and then we have
mock max mantras from the trichome
Institute
he is a cannabis sommelier an educator
an intervenor he will be explaining what
intervening is he is someone who both
provides cannabis education and even
certification as it relates to came in
cannabis sommelier ship and I invite you
max is a little bit building more since
I know there's so much that we can share
there Swami chipton is also joining us
he's a cultivator in Mendocino he's a
journalist and advocate I know you've
done extensive work with the Mendocino
cannabis Alliance serves on the board of
origins Council I have the pleasure of
visiting his farm where he and his
partner Nicholas Trudeau
farm under the full Sun some in native
soil many other things to learn from
from Swami and if you want to learn more
I really enjoyed seeing him on the news
hour with his partner Nicky for their
farm and their their cultivation their
brand and Swami select and then last but
certainly not least we have owner prints
from leaf works she's the CEO and
co-founder and also the founder of
kinder herbarium which I understand is
one of the world's cannabis or variants
which i think is going to serve these
are variants will serve a pivotal role
in doing some the work we're talking
about right now
she is PhD geneticist I know there's a
lot more to add so please Eleanor when
we get to you fill that in as well
and with all of those BIOS and so much
more could be said