[Music]
we're based out of northern Humboldt and
with talking trees farms we do
cultivation kind of indoor/outdoor we're
in the East County East North County and
in South County so we're in a little bit
of different Appalachia and run five
different farms the smallest is probably
just only a little over 1500 square feet
and then we go up to about 34 thousand
square feet outdoor all outdoor well
outdoor and then like hoop houses for
light debt and the smallest ones are you
know obviously like our older farms that
when we were first start and so they're
a little bit more in the shade and it's
been interesting to find certain what
strains with work and and like talking
about climate and amount of Sun that you
get so it's it's always tricky to find
out what to grow where that's always a
learning process right and some things
won't need as much son and we'll finish
early and still produce great cannabis
and then some stuff if you're doing more
of the fuelie stuff they just want that
full Sun
okay well you won't be surprised that
blue dream and Green crack pretty much
grow good anywhere they thrive in the
shade they're just all around I mean
they get a bad rap but all around
they're great strains for what they can
do and where you can grow them and then
once you get into the full Sun I mean
you could pretty much grow anything in
full Sun although I will say you can
some strains like a little bit more
shade I think Girl Scout cookies for one
is one stream that likes a little bit
more shade not too much but but for the
most part things like a lot of Sun can't
say that I have a favorite strange
variety is the spice of life we do a
little bit of everything we've
transitioned mostly into raised beds
light depths and are getting away from
full season plants just to do the two
harvests I personally enjoy growing some
more smaller plants than trying to grow
the 12 foot tall plant you know it's
it's not where I'm interested in in
dealing with it's a hard to deal with 12
foot tall plants and if you lose that
plant you lose a lot of material so I
think we go with raised beds mostly and
do global amending we try not to use any
liquids I pretty much used three liquids
throughout the whole season which would
be earth juice catalyst molasses and a
finishing llama I'm a newer product
called crescendo other than that we just
all dry amendment in global amending our
soil which is great because you know I
don't want to be throwing away bottles
and bottles and we would be throwing
away lots of bottles if we were using
synthetics or any brand of nutrient
that's in a bottle catalyst is the
product actually it actually just got
pulled from the shelves last month I
mean it's from earth juice which is a
brand it's been around for over 20 years
so they've been in the agricultural
nutrient business for a long time and
catalyst that's been one of their
flagship products it's one of their only
to this point one of their only organic
products but it's just an enzyme
macronutrient just just boot plant
booster yeah yeah they had to change the
name they couldn't use the name cat I
was like really curious does it go or
was it not organic and they were
mislabelling it but the local store told
me it was because California a gruel's
are just kind of ridiculous so they
can't they can't call it catalyst
because that's what it does so I have to
change the name to it with a X and add a
list or something we definitely bootys
our TVs are massive we brew like a
minimum 500 gallons at a time so we use
from four to eight massive tea bags at a
time I probably unique way of doing it I
don't like make small batch and then add
that tea into a reservoir
I just brew a massive batch that old ax
that'll handle that fifteen hundred
gallons that we feed at a time and so we
brew it overnight yeah maybe not even 24
hours sometimes you know it's hot I mean
some of my water tanks stay around 80
degrees the water so I think they're
brewing fast and if we left it out 24
hours we probably killing
microbiology cuz we're in full Sun and
where the tanks are so we do shorter
brews and sometimes we'll add in some
bat guano and accentuate the actual
compost tea and make it a feeding or
sometimes we'll just top dress and just
do straight compost teas
not yet that's a goal to make our own
worm castings in our own compost that
off all things in time got a one one
step at a time like I said earlier
varieties of spice to life so I don't
stick to one compost if I'm you Bruna
compost I'll buy three different types
of compost cuz I'm sure everyone's got
something good whether it's Malibu
baseline dr. earth I don't want to just
focus on one cuz if they had a product
issue that I'm you know dealing with
that so I use I spread things out you
know I give everybody a little bit at
the chance with with their different
composts everyone's got different style
of compost whether it's manures and or
plant-based so we use a variety of
compost we switched that out over the
season and then besides the compost in
the castings and that as in the calcium
the biggest thing I've been adding is
epson salts lately because we're all in
off-grid well water and once we get the
water tested we're know it's really hard
super high in calcium and so that's that
tends to lock out the phosphorus for the
calcium magnesium is not in balance so
we've been at an epson salts and we'll
just been really noticeable difference
in terms of occur through the buds
growing out and the phosphorus not
locking up but otherwise the only
difference in the step stages of the tea
brews is when we add guano's so if we're
in veg we'll add a like a 931 Guana to
that when we go to transition i'll go
with like a four four four and then I
have a second transition I'll split it
with a 4 4 4 and a 2 12 - 14 - so kind
of like you start slowly introduced - hi
Fras and then then I'll go to all - 14 -
particularly I like the rainbow grow pro
bloom and grow rainbow pro bloom and
grow nutrient mixes that we add into our
teas our biggest success with and is
with the global amending like we do we
don't actually feed at all while our
plants are vegging it's all in the soil
so we mix in a pretty hot mix we have to
let it sit for 10 days
and thankfully I'm not putting those
together as a company up there called
soil escape solutions that really makes
my life a lot easier because they're the
soil scientists they know that that
aspect of it more than I do and so that
has helped us a lot so we get their
global amendment which is you know what
I've done for years just throwing a
little bit of that a little bit of that
but now it's like the equations are
there the proportions are right and so
that just sets us off on like I'm
awesome veg stage and so actually we
don't even feed until we get into the
second week of bloom Weill a top dresses
and start doing teas I pretty much
that's all I do is drive around and
check in and bring supplies and oversee
and and I don't do as much of the
touching of the plants and the
wateriness I might have done 15 years
ago oh man I finally got hit with the
rust it might this June so I'm dealing
with that prevention is always the best
is key you know and some we were on a
preventative program I mean we do a lot
of sulfur in veg we don't want to use
Sol for after the first week of flower
but right now I'm actually dealing with
and learning a lot about these Russert
mites they don't like into like plants
that are into flowering past like four
to five weeks the buds are too developed
they don't seem to attack that they're
like fresh growth fresh blood
development so if you if you can handle
it early in veg prevention is key sulfur
is probably the most organic effective
product against those kinds of pests and
then there's bio fungicides like
venerate grande evo grande and those are
all made by one company I can't think of
the name and they also make a product
called regalia which is more PM oriented
thing with PM is once you have it you
can't get rid of it so again prevention
is the key and regalia is that product
so we'll mix regalia and grande Evo are
compatible and we separately foliar and
I'm not a big foliar spray I don't I
don't foliar feed my plants
it's not really my technique at all but
for IPM pest prevention we run them
through like we run them through my pump
system so we're pumping a hundred
gallons of spray at a greenhouse at a
time through froggit nozzles so we're
able to just do high-volume spraying and
at this point we're doing it like every
other day to get these little fuckers in
check got us hand spray but every aisle
of the greenhouse has its own hose and
so we use this for feeding and then we
also have a separate water system set up
for dripping because we mostly do drip
we only hand feed once a week and then
the other natural drip drip water drip
but we don't I don't combine those
systems because I don't want the feed
system clogging my drip lines so they're
separated and then we feed we run the
foliage through our feed system and so
there's a hose down every aisle another
greenhouse and so they just turn on the
pump the tanks there they're not
carrying around a pump sprayer I got a
backpack pump and it's pretty it's
really efficient it's like a little
nozzle they make I think DRAM might even
make them yeah they're really great you
can get half gallon one gallon two
gallon and four gallon a minute
and it just dispersed this kind of like
a pump sprayer would and so we don't we
use the two gallon a minute I've tried
them all two gallon a minute is what we
like to use four gallon minute kind of
hammers the plants but the two gallon a
minute how many issues with piano at all
this year
spider mites very easy he's got to deal
with them right but these new mic see
fucking can't see until you know they're
a problem is like a lot of people are
having issues with them and I've been
lucky to not have to deal with them till
June that costs it's just a very added
expense and throwing organic prevention
at them and then the time that my
workers have to spend after nine o'clock
spring
plants never gets dull never gets boring
on the corner
[Music]