[Music]
the conversation we didn't really
complete is one on banking and that's
why it's a pleasure here to have tim
schafer with us the california deputy
treasurer public finance I want to share
with everyone what one company wrote me
so the this is bloom box and these these
folks provide b2b software as product as
a service and they said legalization
didn't help us with investment capital
because there's no way to safely bank or
insure these investment funds smaller
investors cannot incur risk larger
v-type VC type investors are still bound
by so-called vice clauses commonly
embedded in their partnership agreements
that prohibit even indirect investments
in federally scheduled substances is
this really strictly a Schedule one
issue a complex question with an equally
complex answer let me start
let me start start here banking banking
many businesses is a question of a
banker being able to engage in
reasonable risk management let me give
you an example that has nothing to do
with cannabis many banks will refuse to
open accounts for check cashing services
for horse racing tracks for payday auto
lenders for cardrooms why because often
these organizations can mask occult
activities which will create regulatory
risk for the bank so they avoid it now
notice that it's perfectly legal to be
in the
room business or to run a horse racing
track assuming you've got licenses from
your locality to do that introduced the
notion of cannabis a federally scheduled
truck and then the problem begins to
metastasize the problem metastasizes in
this way in my view bankers are
risk-averse and if this is a risk
management business the default position
can easily become risk avoidance rather
than risk management if there is no
clear pathway to economics that would
work that introduces the next facet of
the risk and that is because there is
this growing wave in our nation to
discuss cannabis the fact that it may be
d scheduled scares the bank's why well
because they can set up an apparatus
that will require a great deal of
investment only to look up and discover
that we're now off schedule 1 and we're
back in the same category as a card room
or a racetrack and so forth and therein
as I think one of the Rubik's cubes that
need to be solved one of the things that
I would encourage you all to become
familiar with hezekiah mentioned this in
the last panel is this document right
here I'm not going to read it to you
it's available in a state treasurer's
website the title of it is banking
access strategies for cannabis related
businesses
I can give you just a few seconds of
what the four primary recommendations
are first at least for the here and now
develop a system that will accommodate
the cash industry rather than trying to
force it into the business figure out a
way to accommodate the cash industry a
little bit better than we're doing we
call that inside the office the armored
car bus route strategy
number 38 bus run by Brinks that makes
us scheduled stop everywhere and picks
up currency to pay taxes and fees to the
state to the local agencies number to
develop a data portal those of you who
are familiar with the Washington system
know that the cannabis control mechanism
in that state are are figuratively
speaking kind of bolted on the framework
that was used for liquor control number
three investigate the feasibility of
establishing a state backed financial
institution that would cater to or
accommodate the industry I hope I get
questions on that later
and then finally in this to me is the
big one develop a consortium of bankers
regulators cannabis industry folks the
stakeholders that were discussed in the
last panel that our medical customers
put them together in a group that will
devote some energy and time to lobbying
federal legislators and federal
regulators about the evolving nature of
it those are the four things you'll see
in their report and we're underway with
each of those four now and I grieve to
him I think if I can add a little
perspective from the bank side up about
a year and a half ago I ran America's
fastest-growing Bank for a period of
three years we grew from not 1.9 billion
over 13 billion that period of time
aggregating to pause is the most
difficult thing that's possible if you
take a look at it you've got to if you
have a perspective a asking for deposits
or giving a loan obviously asking for
deposits more challenging so we need to
take higher risk strategies that involve
eb-5 broker-dealer cash businesses the
the regulators are spent approximately
half of the year so about 150 business
days in our offices and again measuring
and analyzing our high-risk businesses
banks themselves can hold 20
five percent typically if it's well-run
of their collective deposit base in
high-risk and what that means is it's a
fight for what high-risk deposits can
actually sit on that balance sheet so
with that comes in here and risk the ten
mention so and again if you take a look
at the smaller banks that are
participating they're about three
hundred banks across us right now that
actually actively engage in cannabis
business to actually have a kyc an AML
program and BSA program that facilitates
it actually costs tens of thousands of
dollars if not hundreds and on top of
that if you look at these smaller banks
they don't have the technology some of
the core processing solutions to
actually interpret and understand
exactly where that money is coming from
so that entire process on an ongoing
basis ends up costing hundreds of
thousands of dollars because you need
personnel and staff to actually manage
that as well so that's the main
challenge that they're having in to
Tim's point it is very challenging and
the natural mentality the banker can be
risk averse the other side of this
challenge is the actual payment side so
if we think about Visa MasterCard AB in
basically is where all the transactions
pass through if you think of every
hundred dollars it passes through AB in
only one dollar can actually be high
risk related and so by definition
cannabis is high risk so we also need to
come up with additional payment
mechanisms that will help evolve
industry so it's not only just a cash
business lately I've been saying that
we're we have two policies at play one
is to allow cannabis and the other is
prohibited and the it's impossible to
move forward unless one is gonna win and
so we're back to you have to organize
you you have to go to the legislature
the courts aren't gonna help you have to
actually force this issue and the
absurdity of the contradictions between
what is really happening and what the
population in this country wants and
ultimately Congress has to do something
about it that's my perspective I've gone
back and forth with Fiona and other
folks in the state government about a
bank and well it's a really wonderful
idea and I support it there's just too
many I think too many barriers because
of federal prohibition to allow it so
until we get Congress to do something
and this is just an old song and I feel
kind of stupid keep bringing it up but
until we you know
get our congresspeople to actually do
something about it and organize
effectively rather than the old
left-wing firing squad you know that
joke how does the left-wing firing squad
line up in a circle and so you know
everyone's gonna have to learn how to
organize and work together put the egos
aside and then we got to go to Congress
because that's where ultimately I think
this has to get fixed from personal
experience our companies we've lost two
bank accounts just this month one of the
reasons was we deposited more than five
thousand dollars per month
into the account which as a business
owner having five thousand dollars
deposited in cash it's not a lot of
money especially in a cash business and
the other was because even though we're
a non plant touching business we accept
money from plant touching businesses and
that account was subsequently shut down
and right now I'm gonna have to talk and
find one of those three hundred banks
because I have tried to open new bank
accounts and we have to put our website
down our website mentions cannabis and
we have been unable so far we've only
tried this week but we've been unable to
open a new bank account which is very
discouraging especially for someone who
has to run a business so we'll see you
know what changes we can man I've been
have to read that report too but
hopefully these rules can change quickly
because it's it's that's one more
deterrent to run in a cannabis business
on top of all of everything else thank
you this is also a huge challenge I
don't think that banks have an incentive
to enter into this space because they
the the way that they grow their
revenues through acquisitions of other
banks and so they don't want to
jeopardize those acquisitions by
entering into cannabis space so they're
deferring and and staying away from that
and no I'm from Portland Oregon
so in Oregon we have two main credit
unions that provide banking services
checking and savings five hundred
dollars a month for it
and savings account and that's to cover
the costs but they only have 600
accounts total and there's over 4,400
businesses in Oregon right now that are
cannabis related so that's the kind of
draws a picture of or paints a picture
of just the extent of how little banking
is offered to the canvas industry right
now
[Music]