[Music]
[Laughter]
thanks for out here good how are you I'm
Richard paradigm the director of the Cal
cannabis cultivation licensing division
for California Department of Food and
Agriculture well we were just discussing
a few minutes ago about kind of how
things have been going so far in 2018
and some of the challenges that that
we've all been dealing with really and
trying to see how we can just
communicate and have some conversation
around some solutions and maybe some
ideas and see where we can go from here
it's been an interesting year
and I don't think any of us knew really
what to expect when we voted prop 64 in
fully we thought oh well you know we've
been in this prop 215 for many years
since 98 was it and you know myself as a
farmer had been working under that
medical model for many years in my
County actually had a 99 plant limit for
many years and so we cultivated under
that for a while and as soon as there
was anything you know a legal road to go
down we chose that option and we've been
working towards that ever since okay and
it's been a you know it's been a real
challenge because it's it's like here
you're pulling people from the total
darkness who didn't want to be regulated
wanted to hide out in the country and
grow their cannabis and and do their
thing into this total light world and
you know into the white market and a lot
of people weren't ready for it a lot of
people dabble in it and they're kind of
not sure if it's for them and and you
know from my perspective in Mendocino
County we have a you know a lot of
cultivators as you probably know
and it's been a real big topic
conversation around like so are you are
you gonna get licensed oh no well I
don't know if I want to do that you know
and so everybody's having these these
inner internal conversations within you
know the community about is it right for
them and whether they want to do it and
so I operate mendocino direct
generations which is a group of about
sixty farms and Mendo okay and so I try
to help people become licensed figure
out you know the right way to do things
interpret the regulations and apply them
basically and and help them get to
market we have a couple brands and stuff
but we do a lot of farmer education
around everything tracking trays to
pesticides and farming techniques and so
I really want to see my friends and
neighbors survive I really want them to
get legal and get you know get out there
and get their license and they they've
come across a lot of hiccups along the
way like we were saying before and one
of the biggest challenges is at the
county level and I know you're obviously
working at the state level right do you
work with the county officials closely
to help them learn and implement these
yes we do and that's one of the unique
things about this new system or this new
world that we're in starting in 2018
with having the dual licensing right
with both state and local licenses
that's one of the issues we've seen this
year as we've started to take
applications for temporary licenses is
seeing people from the industry having
difficulty getting their local license
so we've been out there working with the
local governments we've gone up north to
the Emerald triangle and done training
with the local officials staff to
explain how it works it at our state
level what our requirements are
understanding what the local
requirements are and really helping them
to be able to educate the farmers when
they come in
and say how do I get started so we've
been doing that but we realized that
there's like you said we've gone from
nothing to everything overnight without
a real type of phase in and so we did we
went from we went from you know when I
started at Cal cannabis in it was in
August of 2017 we had 10 people and we
have about close to 80 today so we've
really scaled up and had to also
implement you know to IT systems are
online licensing and the track and trace
in a very short amount of time to get
everything ready for the industry so
it's been a lot in a very short amount
of time and like you said a lot of
unforeseen obstacles in 2018 that we've
had to all overcome and it's been a
learning experience I think for all of
us you know and the other thing is the
difficulty with going from emergency
regulations to re-adopt in emergency
regulations and now to propose permanent
regulations what my hope is for 2019 is
with these proposed permanent
regulations out there once we get
through the process with Office of
Administrative Law and the regulations
become final
that's our you know we really we've been
trying to be heavy on education but
really having more types of materials
for the farmers to understand what the
regulations mean it's hard to pick up a
packet of 76 pages of text and read it
most recent changes it was like 31
binders I think that was the bureau's
but maybe from the bureau's social media
page we didn't have as as many but we
had a couple boxes that we've dropped
off as well of all the reference
material and everything it took to get
to where we are today it's been a heavy
lift but I also understand we understand
how hard it's been for the folks out
there that are trying to get licensed
and we too are there to help people get
into the legal system
you know we have people that we have
people that are staffing an 800 number
that were and we answer emails every day
I've been really really when I'm
speaking at events I've been really
pushing to have people who are applying
for a state license call us if they have
questions before they apply yeah read
our reference materials we have a lot of
good reference materials we have guides
to you know the application attachments
guides to how to fill out the
cultivation plan but I've been really
really focusing on having people call us
or email us if they're not sure before
they apply that way their application
could get through a lot more efficiently
yeah you know I'm seeing some at the
county level in Mendocino County a lot
of people are getting hung up at the
building and planning so they really
want to be selling their cannabis on a
legal market and and they might even
have cannabis that they just harvested
right but yet they cannot sell it
because they can't get through yeah and
we understand and that is the the
uniqueness of the dual licensing as they
do need to get through local you know
for the temporary licenses it was a must
you have to have a local permit license
or other type of authorization for the
annual license you don't have to provide
that but we still notify the locals when
we get a state application and we have
to ensure that the applicant won't be in
violation of any local ordinances or
rules and so there is that communication
with the local local government and so
if someone isn't in compliance the
locals will let us know and then we
can't we don't move forward until we
hear from the locals is there any things
that you're looking forward to
implementing that might make this system
just a little bit smoother for farmers
so that we can I know it that we were
supposed to have this on a head start as
cultivators we're gonna get ahead of the
game before the big guys came in
yeah I think that we're you know we're
we're obviously going to be focusing on
more coordination with local governments
one of the things that we'll be doing as
we get into 2019 because we'll be
issuing annual licenses but also
provisional licenses and I don't know if
you've talked at all about the
provisional licenses those are intended
to help applicants that are in a
jurisdiction where they're not totally
ready or done with their California
Environmental Quality Act so so if a
local government doesn't have their
sequel process complete but they're in
the process they that applicant would
qualify for a provisional license and
that would allow them to sell their
cannabis yep they would be still paying
the the annual license fee the annual
license application fee but they'd be
able to have a state license and they
would be in the track and trace system
as well what we'll be doing in 2019 is
as we see those jurisdictions that
aren't done with sequa and they're there
their applicants are candidates for
provisional licenses we're gonna be
doing education with those local
governments about how they can get their
sequel process done so we're gonna be
basically you know going on the road and
helping educate the local governments
how they get ready and then another
thing for the small growers we had a
some one of our supervisors was speaking
here yesterday about our appellations
program that's coming in 2021 and
that'll be that's something that we see
is really you know going to be more for
the craft grower the small grower where
you know we're talking about
appellations of standards practices and
varietals and i know that that's been
very well received in the by this by the
smaller growers is something that they
see really benefitting them yeah I
actually had some of the the people who
are working in that department come to
my farm and they did their very first
they had a lot of fun we educated them
on Swami was there and we cut it through
and really you know that was my team I
would I think I had a conflicting
engagement otherwise I was going to be
there with them so hopefully I can come
back up we're really just wanting to
open communication and you know show you
guys what it's like to live our
lifestyle and cultivate cannabis and
that we're not like weirdos really like
we're like everybody else and we just
you know we really love to show off our
work when talking about applying from
the state level because I know that
there there are some obstacles at the
local level but from the smaller farmers
when they're applying for the state
license are have you heard of anything
where there's areas that need to be
cleared up or areas where they're having
difficulty you know we're trying to make
sure we have enough information out
there to help them through the process
but have you heard of any areas where
they're struggling or need more help
from us I feel like a lot of people feel
like that like customer service has been
really good and the website is a little
hard to navigate I think a little bit
more education would be very helpful and
that's just basically I think the
biggest problem is interpreting the
regulations and and boiling it down to
some really basic points yeah I think
that would help people a lot but I think
one of the the biggest things was we
were under the impression that the micro
business license would be something that
would be available to all small farmers
that we could really get an edge up on
the regulated market we could have our
own just
we could have our own manufacturing we
could process we could package and we
could pull to date and/or have a retail
right and I think a lot of people have
that in mind myself included in that I
really wanted to do that because I
already had a couple of brands for
various like a topicals company and such
and I'm really just like an entrepreneur
and I just love to like you know do that
kind of stuff and so I thought well
that's perfect for me I really want to
do that and but it turns out in my
County Mendocino County I cannot get the
correct I can't get that permit because
of my buildings basically so I'm in the
wrong zone it's not allowed in my zone
and so here I am somebody who really
wants to be doing this I can't afford to
buy a new piece of property nor would I
want to move or any of that kind of
thing and so I want to be able to just
basically do what was working well for
me right and just keep going with it
instead of this stop start that's been
happening and so in my community tons of
people would do the micro business if
they could we could really work on that
that would help small farmers a great
deal I think a lot of people would go
for getting a micro business license and
you know the micro business licenses are
under purview of the Bureau of cannabis
control because as you know there are
three licensing authorities in
California but we work very very closely
with the bureau
I attend all of the cannabis advisory
committee meetings and the last meeting
that was earlier this year the last
meeting for 2018 that was a topic of
discussion that's going to be picked up
at this next meeting I believe in 2019
to really continue that discussion about
micro business I'll be there part of the
discussion and working with the bureau
and you know doing what we can to try
and help that along that was that was a
big topic of discussion people talking
about the vision that industry had isn't
really what's there right now
and I think that's also you know broken
promises about like the one acre cap to
when I asked my constituency about like
what do you want me to ask Richard
parrot and they're all like oh make sure
you ask him about why what happened
there what happened with the drop of the
one acre cat yeah and that one is still
under litigation and I'm not trying to
hide behind it but but because it is in
litigation and I've had I've had to
answer this question at legislative
hearings I had to answer the question
earlier this year at a public hearing in
Ukiah and I got in it I don't know if
you were there was in it was Martin
March it was a joint legislative hearing
with Senator McGuire and assembly member
wood and because we're being sued
because we're being sued
I can't I'm not able to discuss it
because it is being litigated so for the
record I've been advised by our legal
office that I'm not able to discuss it
I'm sorry
the farmers felt like we were gonna get
a leg up and we were gonna be able to
cruise for a little while until these
larger corporations were allowed to
start stacking licenses and and all
these kinds of things and I already kind
of see that happening and it's it's
disturbing in my area I'm seeing farmers
jump ship okay and I think mostly it's
because they just don't have the money
to scale up and nor do they want the
headache and they just feel like well
maybe the universe is telling me it's
time to do something else with my life
and but they might be you know some of
my neighbors and friends they might be
like 65 years old and they're starting
fresh with a new what am I going to do
now right and so that's my concern wise
with my community and my neighbors and
my friends and and I really you know I
want to see them all thrive yeah a long
term yeah well that's that's I mean
that's good for us to know we did we did
you know receive a lot of comments about
the acreage cap to as during our
rulemaking process so all that
information is out on the Department of
Food Network cultures website now it was
all released on December 7th so the
draft final language and all of the
responses to comments were actually
published on the website so those are
out there for people to review as well I
wanted to ask you about nursery licenses
because that is part of the cultivation
license right
I personally applied for a nursery
license and I have a lot of people in my
constituency in Mendocino generations
who have an application in for that but
in our community as well there's a lot
of people who have that for seed
production and whether or not they're
selling plants or clones to anybody else
they just want that license so that they
can keep the genetics alive and they can
make seeds and and keep the heritage
alive really ultimately and so do you
know much about what's coming for the
nursery licenses I feel like we feel
we're all kind of in the dark about what
we can and can't do the regulations
around the nursery is still a little bit
murky yeah that's one of the things is
you know with with the emergency
regulations going through to are the
original version
and then the read option and now having
our permanent regulations those are
things that we'll be focusing on getting
more almost like I'm envisioning almost
like one or two-page fact sheets about
different parts of our licensing and
that's what we're gonna be working
toward and also you you talked about our
website earlier it's there's a lot of
information and we just have one huge
page on our website we're in the process
of revamping the entire Department of
Food and Agriculture website and for the
Cal cannabis division we'll have new
information that will be a lot more user
friendly and kind of organized in ways
that that I'm hoping the applicants of
the industry would find easier to use in
reference but we're gonna be shooting
for is almost like fact sheets on
different topics and nurseries will be
one of them yeah I'm looking forward to
finding out more about it I haven't
doped too far into figuring it out I
just applied for it and you know always
if there's questions just call us call
us or email us or although we're super
busy our stuff are we're answering the
phones during our work hours and we're
responding to emails so if you're not
sure about something call us or email us
and we're more than happy to help about
phase three testing of the year do you
have any insight for us as to how you
see that playing out I don't because
that the testing is under the bureau but
they Bureau oversees the testing labs
and the testing process
we're definitely you know following it
but I don't have any any specific
information about Phase three but will
be will be definitely following you know
they were worried about the whole
testing thing in general and I actually
been seeing that it's it's better and
we're having more
you know good results from it in general
but you know with the track and trace
like being implemented we haven't really
got there with the farmers besides right
and I know you wanted to talk about
track and trade sure yeah just I think
there's been a lot of maybe
misunderstanding about track and trace
we keep hearing that people are saying
when's it going to be launched when will
it be alive
it was live at the start of January at
the start of 2018 annual licensees will
be using track and trace not temporary
licensees there were a lot of questions
as to why we chose that but when you
look back at 2018 and you look at our
original emergency regulations than a
readapted version of the emergency
regulations and now our draft permanent
regulations with so many changes and so
many things to be learned during the
temporary licensing process if we had
had the temporary licensees in track and
trace that would have been I think
harder on the industry because with
cultivation what we found are a lot of
cultivators got let's just talk about at
the beginning of the year they've got
both a.m. licenses because they weren't
sure which way they were going to go
when we readapted the regulations and
clarified that you could eat have either
a or an M and it didn't matter you could
sell to either an AR em a lot of them
made decisions wha I only need one
license that would have been a lot of
maintenance in the track and trade
system people retag implants retaining
product so annual licensees will be
using track and trace we have between
the three licenses once they're proof
between the three licensing authorities
we've issued 23 annual licenses so far
and about 17 have actually been
credentialed and are in the system so
those are going to be our first users
when we get into 2019 and we're you know
we'll be done issuing temporary licenses
at the end of this year and then our
authority goes away so as in 2019 we'll
be issuing a lot more annual and
provisional licenses then we'll see
people flowing in to track and trace and
they'll be using it and I know in your
jurisdiction you also have a local track
entry system as well we had sick Pat cow
origin and you know that was a whole
crazy thing in itself I was actually the
12th permit in Mendocino County and so I
was thrown into that right in harvest of
last year okay and you know we did our
best and it was really complicated
mostly the the biggest complication was
actually just learning the system that
you know their website but it felt like
to me that the track and trace just kind
of came to an end that sticker was
really unusable after it went to my
distributor for instance they said well
what am I gonna do with this because
they weren't using the same system okay
and so the Buc kind of stopped there and
they just threw that package away and
they put it in my packaging and they
didn't put a new sticker on it because
they weren't in metric yet okay so it
was just kind of like why are we doing
this when it just stopped
yeah we've been we've been you know we
talked with all of the third-party
vendors Sigma is one and so they're
working on being able to interface with
metric for their
the licensees that are youth that are on
a local system so they're there working
on having their Cal origin system be
able to integrate with metric so and we
you know talk to them frequently I know
that they've done what they need to do
to get certified to be able to interface
with metric so and the goal is there for
those licensees that are in a local
system to as much as we can limit any
duplication of entry and duplication of
effort so we're working on that too I
appreciate your time thank you you know
I think that the biggest advice would be
to you know we're all in it together
we're all working together I'm my hope
is at 2019 we're through I think the
heaviest lift on getting the regulations
done
I see 2019 hopefully as a time for us to
really work on education and starting to
try and you know work out the kinks in
our systems really have engagement with
industry with all the licensees be able
to hear from them and look at things
that can be fixed and tweaked along the
way I continue to tell everyone what we
put out is our start this isn't how the
program is going to that's the good
thing about regulations is that we can
you know do subsequent we're all making
efforts to fix things as
move along I always say this isn't what
the program is gonna look like a year
from now two years from now even three
years from now things are gonna change
in morphus we all learn more and figure
out what's working and what's not so I'd
say you know hang in there with us and
communicate with us and if you know if
you all have questions call us and we're
there to listen and work together to you
know their goal is to get as many people
into the legal system as we can that'll
be better
[Music]
you