one of my favorite recent stories is I
don't know if you guys know Cody bass up
in South Lake Tahoe who runs a
dispensary and recently got elected to
his City Council so that's the kind of
change when stuff gets interesting is
rather than just say oh I don't know the
politicians aren't on our side we can be
the politicians that's when the
interesting change starts to happen we
can show up at the city council meetings
we can show up at the town halls we can
take the seats on those advisory
councils and that is how we affect
change is not by sitting around and
complaining and watching what's
happening and having it at be something
that's happening to us this is a living
evolutionary process that we are part of
and we can change it