[Music]
Eddie finalists with phantom farms at
Oregon here in the one log 1 log
dispensary we're at the regenerative
science of cannabis conference my name
is Chris Trump
I run a 700-acre macadamia nut farm on
the Big Island of Hawaii that we've
transitioned to 100% natural farming and
having all kinds of success we had a
profitable year last year that made up
for the 10 years before that more more
profitability than 10 years before that
so it's um it's something we're talking
about today we're talking about natural
farming and some of the some of the
problems people had some of the
questions people had one of the first
questions I got to talk about today was
how do you scale this for for commercial
operations and sitting with no one
better for for talking about that in
cannabis than my friend Eddie and for me
there are some definite dynamics to
doing natural farming you know in a
wheelbarrow versus doing it on a large
scale and I had some pretty significant
learning curves
I did a 90 thousand pound pile of IMO 3
and I had a rain event I had a week-long
rain event and I wasn't undercover and I
had to scramble to save the pile and
eventually I had to spread it in the
rain because it was I was gonna go I was
gonna get enough water saturation that I
wasn't going to be able to do any more
aerobic fermentation and so there's some
some physical kind of logistical
difficulties you can run into then
there's also kind of the learning curve
so I teach five-day classes to kind of
help people overcome a learning curve
and made videos but even still there's
nuance that you kind of have to be
willing to let the
says teach you a little bit so if you
can if you can get over having a failure
and not calling that the end but saying
that's part of the learning journey then
you're gonna have fun with it and you
will totally learn eventually because
it's like anything practice makes better
but um at even scaling natural farming
for your grow and your as far as
cannabis grows go you're pretty big
how's that been it's been awesome and to
relate to what you're saying about
making mistakes definitely you have to
make a lot of mistakes to scale up and
but yeah we're doing foliar a lot of
folding with the K and F it's working
super good you can see instant results
the plants are just standing up you know
the Leafs and everything and but yeah
like I would say you have to you just
have to make all the mistakes and it's a
journey and you just got to keep
cruising and and it's a it's you get to
learn a lot of things about yourself and
everyone else around you in the farm and
it's super awesome I love it I can't say
enough good things about it I mean it's
it's a it's just so awesome to not have
to deal with chemicals anymore and I
have to rely on store-bought products
and it's yeah yeah you were telling the
evaluator point gherkin
profiles changing what is that like yeah
so we've been on our indoor facility
full LEDs living soil beds we've been
hitting three to four percent Terps
every time which is pretty hard to do
for with salt fertilizers and we've hit
as high as seven percent Terps so and
then the weed itself is just a better
product it's more vibrant it's the aroma
the yeah it's just really nice stuff so
yeah the issues of scaling and all of
that I would say you're better off
learning on a small experiment than
learning with something giant and you
know so I did a lot of added years of
playing with things and becoming really
proficient before I try the 90,000 pound
pile of IMO and it went it was going
perfectly other than an A
that I couldn't account for you know
would have been awesome so I would say
get your learning curve out with small
experiments rather than an entire farm
or some big expensive costly problem if
you mess up one of the another question
we got was people are encountering you
know they're they're starting off really
well and they're having to fall off and
in kind of the effects of natural
farming you know I don't know who you
know is experiencing that but if that's
a question we're being asked that I
would say that probably has more to do
with an understanding of what it is and
then some something with the system
being off just because we've had so much
success and you know kind of across the
board and it's mostly people that have
taken the time to really get into it and
learn if you're you're trying to fully
do it with just online resource
especially IMO there's some nuance it's
kind of like baking you know learning to
make a souffle you could have the same
ingredients as a guy next to you and his
souffle it looks beautiful and Rises and
yours is like this flat mush pancake and
that has more to do with technique than
anything and so bacteria will will give
you a boost initially and you'll have
fall-off whereas if you can get
diversity of microbial life fungi and
yeast in your soil you're gonna have
this kind of Perpetual climb to health
and production is that been your
experience I you know I have I've just
been seeing success so I have not seen
any any bust but yeah definitely with
the IMO's it's been it's been difficult
it's arduous for sure trying to figure
out how to be in the right place at the
right time and but like I said before
you know just making the mistakes and
learning from them and and just you know
rising up and so it eventually it'll
kick in and
it's all good yeah do you run into like
how do how do you know when when to
apply or like I was like when do you
apply it is something I want to know is
the transitioning ignorant farmer when
do you play how do you use it
my Mouser or I am both you'd say that
though after taking a five day class you
kind of were equipped with that
knowledge like you understood when I
needed to apply it how that whole system
works that the problem is the knowledge
available online is limited and or it's
hard to sift through and you know sorry
for that it's just it it's a lot of this
is difficult to learn remotely where
when you're feeling it and smelling it
and seen the nuance in person it's it's
just a little easier so that's difficult
that question though is one I got a lot
so I did this week will actually launch
an online class on the nutritive cycle
so it's kind of when to apply these
foliar applications depending on your
plant growth cycle natural farming Co
and but they getting things wrong is is
generally pretty easy to do and it's not
it's not a big deal if you're doing it
on on a small scale but yeah the risk is
greater a greater scale yeah the bigger
the bigger it is the the more you're
running into problems you know I started
watching his videos and doing all the
stuff and that's a great starting point
but as soon as I started you know
reading the literature I went to his
class I learned way more than I ever did
by watching the videos and trying it on
my own
so there's a lot more information out
there than just the videos and and that
said the the some people do little bits
and pieces of the natural farming system
and that's totally cool there's nothing
the the reality is this is just natural
farming isn't the answer it isn't like
the magic bullet you're not going to
have guaranteed
everything's gonna work out for you
financially if you play with natural
farming it's just there's it's an
elegant method to use the principles
that are already at work in nature and
so what you have in nature is just this
cool interconnectivity of light and
water and microbes and and soil
nutrients that the plant could take up
and that's that's special and you can
get into and access that a lot of
different ways you know there's their
systems all over the world we're passed
down knowledge has been applied
effectively because farmers are good
scientists basically and but natural
farming is an elegant method it's a way
to kind of take these principles of
nature in a kind of easy to access
package and make them applicable on your
farm one of the things people ask is how
how what if I'm gonna use just one part
I don't want to get into it or I already
have this thing I do what should I do
and I would say if you could wrap your
head just around I am a one and two I
Mateusz a great thing where you can put
it in some water and and get it on as a
soil drench or something that would be
awesome
maintenance solution is crazy easy if
you can overcome or get o hn or make
some it's just you can you don't have to
know anything you can just apply it once
a week and you'll have ad general health
and and production to your plants and
it's it's really simple you don't
there's not a whole set of processes
once you have those tools on the Shelf
fpj brown or fermented plant choose
brown rice vinegar and oriental herbal
nutrient on the shelf you can just spray
it on your plants any old time and get
the benefit from that you do that pretty
regularly right yes so we defo leo or
once a week and then we stop in week for
a flower and yeah it works killer yeah
super good do you think you could talk a
little bit about your experience with
the master
like the guys here going to learn from
his doctor faster Channel
I had the privilege of about the time on
our farm we had some events that caused
us to say hey what's going on in nature
with these benefits these things were
seen that happened that weren't
explained in conventional farming so we
were looking for answers we were willing
to kind of check what we knew at the
door because we had saw seen some things
that happened on our farm where there's
health came when we left the land fallow
and so we started searching and about
that time a friend of mine David Fortas
got a grant and brought Master Choa to
Kohala a little tiny town in on the Big
Island of Hawaii so I feel really
grateful it's part of where I share
knowledge because I literally was
farming in a tiny rural town in Hawaii
and this dude from Korea decided this
was the place that he was gonna land and
this knowledge was gonna get first kind
of transferred into English and so I'm
super grateful for that and hanging out
initially Master Choa did a lot of
teaching with his daughter Gian Cho and
she she was really good at translating
into practical she doesn't work with
them anymore but in the beginning that
was really helpful to kind of master Cho
is he he saw chemical fertilizers coming
to Korea and he said I need to give
farmers another way this isn't gonna be
all good so there's kind of a little
foresight like this might not work out
so well and he made this system and it
came some from Japan studying with the
doctor and enzyme theory and and there
was a lot of cool knowledge that was
passed down in Japan and then it came
some from having a dream and waking up
and trying it on a farm for years and
you know finding these methods are
effective and and a few other doctors he
studied
under in Japan and then some traditional
practices in Korea and combine them just
to kind of an elegant accessible method
hanging out with them is fun getting his
slap you if you do things right or wrong
so big big back smack and great non
politically correct jokes and
demonstrations to explain how nature
works so I don't usually tell those
because some were offensive to our
Western mindset but um he's um he's
somebody that has been beaten to death
for sharing natural farming knowledge
green government after the Korean War
was looking for communists and he was
sharing knowledge on farms with farmers
and that coming together and community
was a little taboo at that time and so
he he's paid costs for for sharing this
knowledge and he's continued to and you
know he taught me how to taste soil and
and no no the the nuance difference is
you know this is has good microbial
balance this is too high in nitrogen you
know this is doesn't have anything going
on and you know fun fun stuff so there's
some the the real beauty of natural
farming is it's an invitation to be able
to look at your plants and look at
nature and kind of understand what's
going on when you say you kind of have a
sense of like oh this is this is what my
plants need right now or I need to do
something has that grown for you
definitely yeah I I'm stoked when
actually with the day that we have to
foliar I'm always like I'll do it so I
love it you get to see kind of some of
what your plants mean you kind of see
their changes and their shifts that do
you feel like your observation is grown
as a farmer sure
and and to you know we're on we're on
cycles right so it's like pretty
repetitive you know it's repeatable
basically so you know we flip the lights
to flower and we know and you can see
you know you can see the changes so yeah
I got a chance to hang out with Master
Choa myself a couple months ago on the
Big Island and just nothing but respect
for those deaf
they're super nice you know they they've
brought in this thing they're bringing
it to the states and and they could
attract you trademarked or patented it
and they're they're not you know they're
they just want to share with everyone
which is which is very commendable you
know that's what it's all about just
trying to help each other out and you
know not trying to hit a home run off of
it yeah so it's a culture in natural
farming there's there's some giving and
ingratitude involved which i think is
pretty cool to perpetuate you know to
continue people wonder about like oh
what it was the best plant to use for my
fpj and you know and then they see you
know tropical situations they're using
papaya so they go down at a local
supermarket and buy a bunch of papayas
and make fpj and that's not really it
you're gonna run into problems with that
anyway that's something that's pretty
common and on the online kind of
information as people go in and buy and
pineapple or something for flavor and
the problem is those fruits are all
bleach washed and and really the only
microbial life you have on them is gonna
be what the guy who put it on the
shelves had on his hand or what you had
on your hands when you're making fpj and
and so people get these blooms of weird
stuff happening on the surface the F
PJ's and I usually know oh do you you
know you store-bought fruit I'm assuming
that you don't grow bananas in
Washington and and there's so one of the
keys in natural farming is this can be
really inexpensive I really can because
of the amounts you use and using the
right amount at the right time but the
the things to use for some of these
nutrients are stuff that's wild in your
area and you really got to turn your
your sight on so to speak it's gonna be
a bit of a mental shift more than
anything because you got to drive down
the street or walk in your local woods
or or go you know in your neighborhood
and you look for these plants that you
basically have overlooked your whole
life you know ivy or ice plant
or you know lemongrass all these things
that just grow everywhere nobody ever
takes care of them they're always
healthy and thriving and vibrant and new
shoots and and those actually are plants
that are getting complete nutrients from
their soil they're good at harvesting
nutrients they also are full of plant
growth hormone so why do why do we put
kelp on our farms you know why do we buy
kelp products well because kelp is this
extremely vibrant fast-growing strong
plan it's one of the fastest growing
plants in nature it's full of beneficial
plant growth growth hormone and minor
minerals from the ocean and so you take
these plants that are growing and
thriving around you that are taking up
nutrients really well they're gonna be
packed with nutrients and they grow so
well in part because they have these
these strengths these beneficial plant
these beneficial bio chemicals with that
your plant once you micronized it
through fermentation your plants
actually gonna benefit from these
complex foods that we don't even know
the bottom of we don't know all the
reasons all these things are our food
for plants and and taken up so so kind
of cruise down through your neighborhood
and and look for the things that are
free you know the thing that nobody's
gonna care if you whack you know hundred
pounds of that because nobody even
realizes it's there it's just always
growing and healthy and that's gonna
actually probably serve you a lot better
than a papaya from a local food
supermarket might even be able to create
some jobs by harvesting some of that
stuff been doing like you know fire you
know yeah blackberry shoots the old
blackberries are gonna have big gnarly
thorns you probably don't want to mash
on that but in the spring you see all
the blackberry shoots shoot up that's
all that's got a entire plant energy and
beneficial biochem most chemicals being
forced into it and you can just whack
all that and straight benefit from your
your your local resource that's free why
buy it when nature is literally this
plant has stored all the nutrients it
can collect and shot it into these
shoots for you to get ready to harvest
and yeah you're dancing you're ready to
go get the the blackberry shoots yeah
man
what were questions you would ask me
yeah I mean I so we started off just
doing FP J's and we were like dude we're
Korean natural farming this is awesome
like don't look at the plants and crush
it
you know we'd totally thought we were
doing it but I wish I would have talked
to you and you and been like yeah that's
that's like the stepping stone you know
that's just the beginning
yeah so but I mean like I said we made
all the mistakes and cruised crews
through it and you know now we're now
we're crushing it so and you were I mean
as far as farming you were there was
some difficult years right yeah
definitely
for sure and so where are you guys it's
good I mean so like an Oregon right now
if you if you're if you're if you're
surviving you're crushing it and that's
where we're at right now so we're like
barely getting by but yeah it's it is
what it is the organ markets is so
docile the price drop you know hit the
bottom and but you know thank God for
the Korea natural farming because if we
were you know buying all these store
inputs still we'd be probably not in
business you know so yeah I'm not a
cannabis farmer just a farmer of you
know tree crops and I am a market garden
in Boise Idaho right now but that's the
farmers plight kind of all over the
world you know it's not it's not just
here and it's not just cannabis so I
hope that this knowledge is actually
like hey there's a profitable way to
farm and you don't have to bleed money
until you go out of business to be
organic
here's a solution that where you can
have steady yields and a really healthy
crop so I hope for my kids that our food
system shifts and changes that there
able to buy from the low street local
grocery store real you know medicine
food you know food that's really helping
their body and you know making them run
fast because right now some of the stuff
we're facing as far as human health is a
direct result of our farming system and
I think that can shift I hope we can and
and and I hope that there's hope in this
story for farmers that are struggling
with their with their bottom line maybe
in like the fermentation and digestion
my translation of the new tree is better
for the plant and why petrochemicals
cause these problems yeah so I mean with
chemicals you're you're you're killing
your microbiology and so that's not what
we're trying to do here we're trying to
nurture and harness microbiology and so
you gotta you can't use any chemicals
cuz you're just you're going backwards
yeah I used to wear like hazmat suits
for your your sprays right and that's my
decides insecticides fungicides and yeah
you had to wear a mask and a Tyvek suit
and it was horrible you know and but
that was really like that was how was it
presented to us it was like this is how
you get rid of powdery mildew you have
to spray you eagle 20 you know you have
mites you have to spray of it you know
and it's a quick fix and and that's you
know KNF isn't like that you have to
have fortitude you have to build it up
and and so it's not just a quick shot
you know for shot in the pan or whatever
yeah and plans in a system where they're
getting through biochemical
communication with microbes they're
getting the nutrients they're demanding
and needing when they need it and as a
result plan in its cell walls and will
create complete proteins it is the last
thing a bug wants to eat because the
amount of energy to deal with that cell
wall is so difficult they they're
they're not going to
you make a bunch of babies and and
thrive because they're there no they
don't have a good food source they have
a difficult food source it's like
dropping somebody off in the Alps and
saying here build a family you know it's
it's going to be hard and and so when
these plants are able to create complete
nutrients they're able to have their own
self defense against bugs etc and you
know some some people are are using
chemical fertilizer and they're like I
want to make a shift there's a big risk
and you could even just add in an IMO or
an lab2 what you're doing you want to do
it well you know just willy-nilly with
this stuff and you'll make something
funky and it won't really help you when
you grow but doing something well in
conjunction with some chemical nutrients
you can actually get crazy results
because the only thing that make those
chemical nutrients totally available to
your plants are microbes plants can
thrive in a vacuum so even if you are
growing with chemical fertilizer you are
already relying on microbe microbial
life to help your roots uptake those
nutrients and bringing in some more
microbial life will only help with your
yields and your general profitability so
yeah I think yeah farming stuff yeah
it's some and it's yeah and you guys I
mean we we farm for a dollar 25 a pound
in our product yeah macadamia nuts but
um no it's it's a calling and and it's
it's wonderful like the gratitude you
can have to be able to play in soil and
with nature and just a beauty that
exists in the whole process
I think approaching that with gratitude
is part of what natural farming is that
there are some things we didn't create
you know we're not we're not creating
this beautiful symphony of
activity in soil and microbial life and
and light and photosynthesis and you
know all this cohesive you know energy
we're just benefiting from it and you
know whatever it is you're growing and
so I think there's a great deal of
thankfulness we can have as we
approached nature and the gift of days
[Music]