and so we've uh developed a technology
that we originally bought about a year
ago and we've enhanced it a lot and we
now have a way of delivering cannaboids
uh through ingestion through eating and
drinking that um have the highest
bioavailability rates ever measured and
we've done inv vitro testing to to make
sure that that works and so far it does
work and it works very well and anytime
anybody can absorb a a molecule that's
having some some major effect on them um
and they can absorb it more efficiently
than they could before that's a good
thing because at the end of the day it
means they can use smaller amounts to
get the effect that they need and
anytime you're ingesting smaller amounts
of powerful molecules that's just better
for your body there are a lot of EDI out
there and there's a lot of different
ways to ingest different molecules like
cannaboids and there's some numbers that
people need to know so generally if
somebody smokes a joint they absorb
around 30% of the cannaboids um if they
Vape uh that number drops usually to
somewhere in the neighborhood of 20 to
22% if they go sublingual and put drops
under the tongue the absorption rates
into the blood are usually around
12% and unfortunately if you eat a a
marijuana brownie or a cookie or what
have you typical absorption rates are
only about 5% so you can see that
graduated kind of uh range of absorption
and this is all very well known to
science it's because of the way the body
absorbs powerful molecules so although
um Edibles are a preferred method of
ingesting uh with regards to societal
objections they're not a very good
method for absorbing molecules so our
science has done something that's really
cool and we actually work on a molecular
level these are this is patent pending
technology both in the United States and
worldwide where we combine the uh
cannaboids with longchain fatty acids
and basically what we do is we kind of
manipulate these molecules I'm not
allowed to say exactly how we do that
because that's our secret um but we
manipulate these molecules and when
we're finished the body recognizes the
fatty acid as opposed to the cannaboid
and what happens in our testing we did
some invital lab testing this summer The
Summer of 2015 and those test results
came back and they were marvelous they
were remarkable and in one of the tests
as an example we had 4 99% Improvement
in absorption of cannabidiol compared to
Baseline without our technology so
fivefold increase in absorption which is
an amazing C change and what it means is
you could effectively use one as much of
a of a baked good or an edible product
with our technology as opposed to
without it and get relatively the same
effect that makes everything different
you can use less it's uh easier on your
body or you can use the same amount and
have a more profound effect that that's
up to the customer to decide we're all
profoundly affected by the major kind of
impact we think we can have not just on
our Market or the canabidol or THC
Market but on other markets so we've
extended our patents and we filed
patents pending on U canabidol on uh THC
but also on fat soluble vitamins also on
non-steroidal anti-inflammatories so
these are things like ASA acetaminophen
and ibuprofen we all have that in our
homes and the the really big one from a
market perspective is nicotine we file
patent pendings on the delivery of
nicotine and all those other molecules
because we have reasons to believe that
our technology actually delivers all of
those molecules at a more effective rate
than they can be delivered today a lot
of people think that you absorb Foods in
your stomach and and you don't uh only
about 5% of what you eat is actually
absorbed in your stomach 95% is absorbed
in your small intestine and the small
intestine likes certain molecules or is
more efficient at absorbing certain
molecules than it is compared to others
one of the things that it's very
welldeveloped to absorb is our fats um
and and that's not hard to believe
because there's an obesity problem all
over the world so the body's very good
at absorbing fats and so our kind of
Brain Trust if you will was well is
there a way that we can combine healthy
fats so longchain fatty acids are things
like sunflower oil which is a relatively
healthy fat very minute qu quantities of
it really minute quantities of that with
a payload such as canabidol manipulated
in a very particular way that nobody's
ever thought to do before and what we've
done is we've kind of the body into
saying oh I I smell I taste and I absorb
a fat and it also gets away from some of
the problems with some of the edible
markets that have some kind of pretty
strong flavors and pretty strong um
odors we generally don't have that in
our products or much much less because
again we wrap those molecules in a kind
of bubble of fat if you will and what
the body smells and tastes are those
very Savory and and and good tasting
fats so we've kind of gotten around the
problems of of absorption by tricking
the body into thinking that it's
absorbing something else so for example
we have a product on the market right
now called vipo tea and it's tea it's
not hemp tea it's not marijuana tea it's
black tea it's Chinese black tea but
we've processed it with our with our
proprietary technology and we've placed
hemp oil and canabidol and tpin within
that black tea so when you drink that
tea you know what you taste you taste
black tea it has a slightly earthy
smooth kind of texture to it that black
tea doesn't really have black tea is a
little bit sharper but other than that
there is no hemp or marijuana flavor or
smell to it and we had such success with
that over the last six or eight months
that we've actually unla launched a line
of seven other te's so we now have
English breakfast tea we have green tea
we have herbal teas um a whole variety
of teas and they all benefit from
avoiding the strong tastes which are
objectionable to a lot of people in fact
we are launching um a protein energy bar
in October of
2015 and it uses our technology no trans
fats no artificial sweeteners no
artificial flavors or colors no corn
syrup nothing like that super super
healthy bars with the benefits of full
spectrum hemp oil and they taste
delicious I have eaten them we've gone
through about 12 different recipe
formulations over the last year I've
eaten them a lot they are delicious and
they taste like a really really high
quality protein bar which is exactly
what a food should taste like the food
not something else we have a a
two-pronged business strategy as well I
mean we're very proud of the technology
we're very proud of our products but
we're running a business and so there
are two parallel themes to our business
the first one is the cannabidiol space
CBD so under the CBD molecule we are
launching we've already started with our
vova tea um we're launching coffee hot
chocolate and the protein energy bar in
the next 45 days all of those products
benefit from our technology and we use
uh canabidol that's sourced from the
hemp plant and under US federal law we
are allowed to use extracts from uh
imported hemp uh within our food
products and we can sell those products
Nationwide throughout America and in
fact we can sell them in certain other
countries as well that from a business
point of view allows us to produce our
product in one location and sell it
nationwide which is something that a lot
of the other fragmented businesses in
this sector are not able to do when they
operate in only one state um and it also
gives us benefits of scale um so we can
establish a national brand which we're
we're well in the midst of doing and and
we're conducting all of that so we are a
CBD company when it comes to products so
when we're selling Nationwide we also
are able to sell outside of the medical
marijuana uh channels so for example if
we were able to get into a National Drug
Store chain a National Grocery Store
chain uh herbal Health Centers uh gyms
uh any number of locations uh it's
really up to us as a Food Products
Company to be able to do that so that
gives us a lot of traction that a lot of
other companies in the medical marijuana
space just can't have and then the
second line of our business is sort of
uh the the IP or the intellectual
property side of the company and from
that point of view we really see
ourselves as the Intel inside for the
pot business and what that means is we
know that our technology works on cannab
cannaboid uh absorption we know that
it'll work very well for the molecule
THC we as a company don't focus on high
THC products but we have nothing against
them whatsoever and we are happy to
license our technology to all of those
companies in the space that do sell THC
products and again with our technology
the benefit to the consumer is that they
can consume far less in order to get the
effect that they're looking for which is
a a public good and it saves them money
as well so there's an intellectual Pro
uh property licensing component to our
company and as time goes by if we're
fortunate and if the lab tests in the
future um bear fruit which we think and
we hope it will um if those things
happen then we can also look
additionally down the road at the
potential for licensing Revenue in some
of those other molecules the things I
mentioned earlier like nicotine or
non-steroidal anti-inflammatories now
those markets in some cases are 300
times larger than the legal marijuana
market so we're talking about uh
completely different business models and
different competitors there's a lot of
things that would come into play there
but they're they're very significant
markets and we like to have a role to
play in them we do think that the
technology that we have invented is new
it's novel and it hasn't been discovered
by neither the pharmaceutical companies
nor the tobacco companies nor anyone
else in the past which could mean that
we do have something here that really is
a breakthrough one of the things we hope
is that people become more educated
about the way their body works and the
way these these products are absorbed in
your body and and you realize in fact
that not only um not only it might not
be a good idea to buy a product that has
100 milligrams let's say of THC in it
that's a lot puts a lot of Demand on
your liver it puts a lot of Demand on
the rest of your body and with our
technology you may get just as much sort
of bang for the buck out of a 20
milligram product as somebody else who's
advertising 100 milligram now think of
the differences that that brings to the
consumer it means they can pay less
money because they need to purchase less
it means they're putting their body
through less stress as it tries to
absorb some of those higher amounts and
it's just a good thing for the industry
overall so we really embrace the idea of
using smaller amounts but using it very
effectively that's really what we're all
about so another thing that people
should be thinking about is what else is
in that edible that they're consuming so
for example is the product made with
butter or is it made with sunflower oil
or is it made with corn syrup or what
and the reason that I that I mention
this is that people really need to know
that the different ingredients that they
ingest as they're ingesting the THC or
the CBD will affect not only how much of
the THC is going to be absorbed but if
it's a high cholesterol fat it's just
not good for you so it's really really
important to read the label just as
important as it is in the grocery store
when you do your weekly shopping it's
important to read the label and know
what's in there so lexaria energy with
all the food products we produce or ever
will produce we are talking about truly
healthy foods no artificial sweeteners
no high cholesterol fats no trans fats
that really matters to how well you
absorb the molecules and to your overall
health
he
[Music]