cool oh connecting here he is
hey guys how's it going thanks for
joining
hi yeah good to see you
good to see you too thank you so much
yeah it's a pleasure it's a beautiful
day here
gorgeous yeah have you had cold nights
we have yeah i uh i was talking
my wife is a little uh disenfranchised
with our gardening this year because
typical uh farmer you know push
push that envelope how soon can i get
the plants in the ground and we had so
many starts that i was like i'm gonna
risk it with these and
we got a late frost and things died so
she's bummed but we got
lots of starts to go in so it'll be fine
yeah
did you lose your pumpkins my giant
thousand pound pumpkins i lost all but
one um
so i'm gonna have to reseed those yeah i
was kind of bummed
that's that's my first time ever uh
messing with a uh award-winning uh
pumpkin seed figured it'd be a fun thing
if we had to forklift a pumpkin out of
here
you have one it might be the one it
might be the one yeah it survived
in spite of things hey
tina if you give me just a second i'm
gonna get just a little bit of
firewood to start the fire
that's amazing you go for it i'll be
right back
okay i'm so excited
[Music]
so who's going to bite who's going to
boise this this summer man
we got it we got to get there and spend
some time together and inoculate our
bodies with all the
antivirals we're going to need for
changing our changing our uh
changing our world
be covering how and why to use it yeah i
mean i could start
i could start a little bit i mean
potassium has an interesting place in a
plant world and
the reason i think sunflowers are so
cool is because think about it they're
growing in the desert
like they did they come up they're hardy
they come up
before the frost they're one of the
first presenters
and they uh they thrive in any
environment including drought
and one of the one of the qualities of
potassium
is that it's uh it boosts the metabolism
of the plant
it's a protein synthesis kind of thing
uh it's
the water maintenance the water balance
in the plant it's the one thing that's
present
in the stomata of the plant that opens
up during the day
so it kind of has this opera so it's
like
it does that action the more the plant
can open up and receive
um what it needs to the more vigorous
that plant is going to grow and the
bigger it's going to produce
and all that so it's a drought tolerance
it's a pest and
disease
you're like hearing it loud and clear
hold on i'll turn it off
i i kind of like it there you go there
you go
there we go there we go there we go
um yeah and potassium deficiencies don't
really affect the root mass they
sort of affect above ground so it really
it really is kind of
a major um component when it comes to
how the plan is going to do
in a season especially with drought and
we're going to be
you know in colorado we're seeing a lot
of extremes in weather and the
sunflowers are always they just so
resilient
kind of doing potassium's
and uh i've been playing a lot with
boron and potassium and boron work
hand-in-hand
do kind of the same processes
there's a week-long hint of intensive
that chris puts on in boise yes there is
and i'm telling you i practiced kind of
well i didn't practice knife i thought i
was just thinking
[Music]
uh for a good year before i went to
chris's class and there is nothing like
a hands-on class to teach you what you
need to know about
so many of these little
details that can't be
okay they have to be shown you have to
taste it smell it see it
and then you know it and then your body
knows it and
and then you get to go home and practice
it your nose doesn't forget
nose does not forget oh it's so true
um let's see what else oh
the chart i might i'm gonna
i'm gonna ask if no i'm not gonna ask a
chose slappable question i'll ask it a
different way
i'm very curious about the biochar
aspect of the wsk
because i've been chris i've been
extracting it using it as a
mineral and that's not knf so i'm very
curious because biochar is fascinating
me right now i'm using it a lot of my
soil mix
i got as i sort of was listening to
master cho's videos and put together
soil mix that he he suggested and i'm
in love with it my i transplanted all my
houseplants
and like they're so happy and they like
look at them they're like crazy happy
that one's not
all right well i uh
now i feel like i wanna so typical
hawaii you know fashion born raised in
hawaii
or back and forth some to california but
we're slow motion you know the the
process is you know everybody comes over
for dinner and they they get involved in
the cooking process and everything where
it's like
moved to the mainland and everybody's
like oh if i invite you over for dinner
when you walk in the door
we're sitting down to eat so different
culturally from uh
so uh i apologize so uh
for for starting the fire now but here
we go we got the fire going
um i'm going to talk a little bit about
what you need to uh to do this does that
make sense
all right so today we're going to use
a dutch oven
it's a simple tool for making small
batch biochar
um just really really useful so in here
i have some pre pre-charred um
sunflower you know the head the stock
etc we'll go a little bit longer on this
i pre-chart it so take a very short time
to kind of
finish up and then we'll start some um
sesame stock you know just to show
kind of how to use that material as well
so this is
a black sesame stock full of potassium
you can also use
asparagus if you're asparagus grower um
especially
uh if you don't want to like take away
from your produce
um so you don't want to take your your
wonderful asparagus heads that you're
gonna take to market those big um
photosynthesizing um kind of vegetative
heads that you let the asparagus grow
so in asparagus farming you are are
letting some of the asparagus kind of go
to seed go to flower
so that it's photosynthesizing and
bringing energy down into that plant you
don't want to harvest a hundred percent
because you you'll lose long term you'll
lose production in that asparagus patch
so you let some of them go
and get really big those big heads full
of seeds and
and leaves etc are perfect for making
biochar especially at the end of the
season when they've done their job
they're starting to harden off
or dry out taking all of those and
making your wsk with that is a great
material
sunflower so sunflower asparagus these
concepts aren't really
isn't something i was taught by master
cho or learned in korea
but it is in line with the natural
farming
concepts in that he said you got to
figure out what works
this is how it works in korea you got to
figure out how it works
mainland usa or in hawaii so what what
i've done with that
um if you want a little bit of
kind of the contents of potassium ppm
you can go over to
other videos frozen
not me not
uh it may be for them as long as you can
see me then
we got we got a live feed um
so not a lot of people grow sesame in uh
in the u.s um it's just not something
super common
and because of that we didn't have
access to this
part of the ingredient list but if you
go
over to aquaponic growers i think it's a
facebook group
group or aquabonic cannabis growers
maybe
it's moderated by steve dredd steve
raisner
in their file section they have a
document put out by duke university that
has kind of the
um accumulator list of all kinds of
plants where you can get a
a feel for um kind of the content of
some of these plants that are common to
you
so maybe you don't have access to
sunflowers
or um you know
asparagus or sesame what other things
are just
crazy off the chart in potassium where
you can
you can extract that so sunflower
and asparagus is way up there in the
potassium levels
and you can jump jump in there and
learn about that so great great
substitute for us in the us
because most people have sunflowers
and um it's just a readily available
thing
so yeah so first step is charring
our um
our material so this is mostly done i'm
going to throw it on
and we'll let the fire go to work on
this
finishing up now the key to biochar
is a limiting of the oxygen you're
allowing to come
into your material what that does
is it causes a kind of releasing or a
discharge of the syngas
which is kind of the nutrients if you
will or a lot of a lot of the other
compounds in your material
and it leaves behind a lot of the
mineral and carbon structure
so we're going to
go ahead leave the lid on our dutch
oven which allows a little gas to escape
with pressure but it isn't allowing
oxygen
in to turn this to ash we won't get a
white ash
because of the lack of oxygen so that's
key for the biochar process
so i'm just going to throw that right on
top of the fire
stick it in there
and we'll let that heat up i got to get
a hot mitt
[Music]
and that that should be done in pretty
short order because it's already mostly
done and then i'll show you
kind of chopping up our sesame and
loading it
but um the basic recipe for
um for this is a i'm gonna throw my
headphone on can you hear me all right
all right basic recipe is that we take
this finished biochar
we throw it in a
a sack here i'm gonna use um this is a
nut milk um
bag you can get these at your kind of
local
natural grocer or something like that
you can use a cloth bag cotton works
great
um but you need a tea bag for this part
and so you throw that in at about a 1 to
ratio you can use a little bit more char
if you want
but don't overdo it don't do 50 percent
char 50 percent
water because you will
just waste it won't all go into solution
you'll be wasting some of that char
so you're better off using about a one
to ten and
with this we don't use vinegar we use
water to extract
and just that um that sitting in water
there's enough pull from the water to
get some of our potassium into solution
we have a water-soluble potassium at the
end
you can agitate you know every couple
days you know just give it a little just
like you do if you're making your
english breakfast tea you know take it
take a little
dipping of the tea bag and uh
salts work way better
yeah man yeah
you you go with that yeah yeah
um no uh it's it's
it's it's true that lots of people grow
with uh
with um those those kind of things and
i'm i'm not uh i'm not a i'm not an anti
to farming methods as much as i'm an
advocate for
ways that we can we can do it less
expensively
and with great yields to affect the
bottom line of the
farmer so if i can get the same yields
and uh and as good or better quality
while spending a tenth as much
we're we're in a better place um
financially and that's a big deal
and in concert with the microorganisms
so
subtle is better that way
all right one second i'm gonna get i'm
gonna fill up a bucket of water
and get myself a coca-cola
wait coca-cola
now i want a coca-cola
yeah right we're talking k nf up in the
house yo
i do salt i know it's crazy no it's you
know what
people people like to uh control a
little
that's what the internet's for if you
don't have trolls on the internet
i'm not calling you a troll man but yeah
you don't have i love you
if you don't have people throwing stones
you know what good is this
we all get bored we only like negative
news anyway
you're right now okay
watching that char go down
yeah i have a egg uh one of those egg
yeah fancy when i used to have money
bought toys um i have an egg
barbecue pit that i put a crock down in
like that and build a fire up around
it's
really effective i do uh charred rice
hull oh he is
you guys awesome right chris we love him
um
so yeah charring rice hall is amazing
too lots of silica in that
so
we love negative news so so much that
it's got us
locked in our houses that's how much we
love it
just give the microbes a chance to speak
um
who is i can't
so what would you guys have for
breakfast this morning
i want to know i had granola and a
banana two bananas actually
can't talk coronavirus well you know i
mean okay let's talk about that let's
talk about
viruses and pathogenic stuff
you know they're mostly opportunistic
right and nature abhors a void
uh it's always wanting to be filled by
life it's uh
nature is prone to life that's what life
is
right so when there's a void when we've
killed off all the beneficial organisms
then the things that come in
are the are the very pathogens that are
going to hurt us because that's the only
thing that can survive
so the way to um
to work with that and also in concert
with our immune system is to bring in a
biodiversity
of organisms that then sort of do the
work of overpopulating
and allowing for an environment where
there's a communication in a community
that goes on within our systems and in
our plant systems and in our
soil systems that are in concert with
one another
and thrive accordingly so
yeah microorganisms
have everything to do with helping us
uh deal with pathogenic viruses
that's why we should all get together in
boise so that we can all hug each other
and get our immune systems functioning
and learn about knf from chris trump
when's your class chris
class is i think the first or second
week of
august um you can find it if you go to
naturalfarming.co and uh
go up to the tabs and click classes um
you can get a link to it there
yeah it'll be fun you can come down
there's a bunch of
people that have been doing this for for
years now
that are going to be returning get to
share their experiences and they end up
being a lot of your
hands-on uh teachers yeah
so tina what's your experience been i
mean you've you've been playing with
this now what
what kind of results are you seeing as
far as uh
changes in the garden well i
i applied it for the first year in my
indoor grow my cannabis grow
i only applied it to the cannabis um and
it was
an instantly dramatic um especially in
terpene
expression and just overall quality of
the medicine
and then in deriving the medicine like
i do spagyrics or alchemy as well so
just having
the the final expression through
medicine and it's
just mind-blowing but last year i
applied it in my
outdoor garden and um
it's just it just blows my mind i walk
out there and i
lift up the areas of wood chips and
there's just
massive amounts of haifa um and they're
all at the roots
like they're all at the root like of my
garlic i mean they're doing the job that
we know they're supposed to do they're
just out there doing it and
because they're indigenous they've
survived the winter and they're thriving
the season
so yeah it's it's mind-blowing
every day i go out there it's
mind-blowing
yes this is a mexican coke it's
the only coke i love um and it has
very simple ingredients instead of like
a 20
20 ingredient list it's like a four or
five ingredient list
and uh yes mexican coke advertisement i
get paid for this
just kidding you can break down metal
with that
yeah you can you can cops carry it if
there's an accident they carry in the
back of their car to totally dissolve
if there's a blood that is going dark
but if there's blood on the street
they'll dissolve it with uh coke yeah
you can you can
completely decompose a slab of meat in
like 24 hours drop it in a thing of coke
so really good for your insides right
cleaning out yeah
um that's cool tina the
to see those kind of around and
communicating with your garlic balls
and that's pretty fun it's
i don't know it's kind of you know as
much as natural farming is a method
um my my favorite aspect or the thing
that i find
that i want to most communicate is
what we're trying to do is is
continually
understand nature a little bit better
science is wonderful for that
and we're actually pushing on
trying to understand as soon as possible
in the scientific community how
microbes make fertilizer monsanto's
number one r d
expenditure for
between 2017
or i think it was 20 20 17 18.
this is just when i was researching it
and i was talking to a guy his whole lab
in san diego
was rented for this research and how do
microbes make fertilizer
is the question they're asking and
the reality is microbes in community
is something we know very little about
even in the
the whole of the scientific
research community we're we're just
beginning to understand
yes we can we can pull out one microbe
and kind of
you know turn it around what does it do
but
um we use the example of human
communities
that a um you know if you take a
if you're an alien and you take a
blacksmith shop and you look at it in
isolation
why is this guy keep making tools you
know why does this guy
keep playing with iron it doesn't make
sense until you look at the farmer
who's attaching that tool to the back of
a horse or tractor
you know it doesn't make sense in
isolation and we have
sometimes skewed or limited views of
what microbes are good for
if we isolate them and don't understand
that they're a part of a community this
thing that they're producing might be
one tap in a chain of steps to produce
healthy plants and so it's really a fun
journey and in natural farming
getting stuff like this where i'm
telling you to go look up
the accumulation of nutrients that
plants
i am sitting in the heat zone of this
fire i'm going to switch sides
it's already a warm day
they say smoke follows beauty right
but to to to look at you know
taking our natural environment and
getting some of our
necessary um crop nutrients from it it's
it's such a cool thing and
and a kind of liberating thing for a
farmer who maybe had to go to the salt
store
you know where they're not getting
anything here
i'm in quarantine and i'm producing all
the
farm nutrients for our farm you know in
our house
with my kids and it's drinkable um
so fun stuff right right
yeah i want to i want to talk i want to
talk
i want to talk to you sometime about the
faculty of the anaerobics too
like that's speculative anaerobes
yeah yeah it's been really interesting
because like i have really clay soil
so you know the places where the stuff
i've been gathering
that's doing best has been in the sort
of wood chip areas that i've been able
to build but when it comes to my clay
soils it's been
really a different kind of
learning process that that what's
actually
eating the clays and making them a
plant available are the this whole
same kind of diversity but deeper down
in the soils
of anaerobic communities that are that
are very much
in this kind of layered consortium
of activity that just brings a whole new
level
to this this expanded awareness of
nature that we learn
by practicing korean natural farming
it's
beautiful super cool yeah
they're they're cool in that um you know
i i'm actually going to jump on
with some people at the future cannabis
project um
later today yeah two right
i think at three times okay but i don't
what time is it for you you're in
colorado yeah i'm in colorado i thought
it was true but yeah definitely you guys
are checking on that specific
okay oh okay yeah i'm excited to see
that i love the cannabis
uh the future cannabis project they're
amazing they do good work i'm glad
you're gonna be there
and i'm sure we'll talk a lot about that
but the cool thing is
they're um a lot of these
anaerobes and and facultative anaerobes
there they don't do
um the same process with breakdown that
like a fungi does
and that they're they're processing
things or breaking them down
but they're leaving behind um
yes i am making
and this is going to be our wsk water
soluble potassium
and uh we're going to show how to make
it uh in the next
few minutes here but they're um
the the anaerobes uh what's neat
so say like um you know we get into
organic and it's composting
and you send away your compost for an
npk analysis
and uh you know it's it's nothing in
comparison to
uh typical especially if you have a
highly fungal compost
it's nothing in comparison to a typical
salt or whatever
part of that is that fungi actually
bring the nutrients into their body and
create
their their body structure um
with those nutrients and that um
to to be able to see those
nutrients that they put into their body
structure you'd have to get out the
million kelvin torch or whatever and uh
it's um you know so it's tied up in our
typical
analysts analysis methods for for
looking at nutrients whereas
a lot of these anaerobes or facultative
anaerobes you're going to
they're going to break things down but
they leave kind of the nutrients intact
so you're going to get a
much better npk reading
if you're fermenting with an anaerobe
because they're not making the
structures in the same way that the um
these big aerobic microbes are but
what they leave behind uh is ready food
for um the fungi i'm gonna show you
something you keep talking i'll be right
back
so yeah the um the the way that they can
work in tandem
is uh is pretty incredible and to say
one's good and the other's not good is
you know it depends what you're doing
what you're trying to accomplish and
for me you know farming trees
i actually want a very low
bacterial ratio to my fungal vape ratio
i want a 1000 to 1
fungal bacteria what are we looking at
so this is that swarm book you know i'm
just giving you all my secrets right now
there are no secrets in life
um so look at the little bugs eating
this this is the clay that i made out of
the facultative
anaerobic bacteria and there's like
millipedes
like it's literally crawling
with bugs like everything yeah
they're just eating like this was a
whole ball they're eating clay
they ate it this is what they did it
blows my mind
well and some of those bigger um you
know
things like worms and and millipedes uh
part of what they eat is the microbes
themselves so when you're
producing all kinds of of microbes and
getting that total
quantity up you know mommy daddy worm
are getting together and saying hey the
food source is infinite
let's uh let's make lots of babies and
that that whole
engine you know it's kind of think about
like a
giant diesel engine you know you gotta
you gotta kind of charge the glow plug
to get that whole machine moving
eventually you do you want the
whole gambit you want the um the big
fungal life but in nature that doesn't
happen instantly
it's not an instant thing i try and kind
of we we talk about
and kind of especially people who live
in the city you know and
they can instantly you know order
anything um
sometimes like okay let's now step back
and start to understand what is the
speed of nature
you know how does how does nature work
and you know and
and what's the speed of nature and you
know people
talk about these um you know
moving towards that goal of uh you know
nice fungal profiles in comparison to
our bacterial profiles
and if you're starting from scratch or
you're starting with depleted soil
you're starting with
you know solid clay um that takes a
a process you know i usually put it in
the realm of three years
to really be at full full cycle
um with with the whole diversity of the
microbial community
um and and those anaerobes and factual
data banner roads they play a role in
that
yeah they really do
well yeah
cool man where where on the islands are
you i'm guessing you're in the islands
um why pahi i'm probably saying that
wrong
cool i'm glad you're you're uh your
garden's going well man
see look at this the smoke's now coming
coming
all right let's check our um let's check
our material see if we got a whole bunch
of char so
you want to be careful with um
with this because if you're checking it
and you have a bunch of syngas built up
in there
um you don't want to necessarily open it
right over the fire
and uh get all that um
ignited and it can totally ignite
so and it'll rush out the sides
it'll actually shoot out the sides yeah
oops
so let's see you see that here we'll
lean down
let's have a look
[Music]
all right so you see if you were
watching from the beginning
you can see how we have a pretty good
change um from what we started with i
had a little bit
left over um material
as far as uh oh this is hot a little
leftover material as far as
there's some a little bit of green or
plant structure kind of that
stuff left i wasn't quite to biochar i
did pre-do this so we'd be pretty close
and wouldn't have to wait very long but
now we have kind of like
glass you know as far as
this is really really close to finish
biochar i think
it's good enough at this point for what
we're doing
so i am going to drop this in a bowl
and we will
we will go ahead and begin with our
water soluble potassium biochar process
and then we'll i'll show you making up
some more if you're starting
from the beginning with uh with this
here let me go ahead and
drop this down so you guys can see what
we're working with
and maybe i'm gonna move a little bit
away
from our fire
there we go all right how are we looking
can you see the
dutch oven yep sweet
knock it over
all right so we finished our biochar
of our material um
in this case right now this first round
we used
um sunflower
um next round what we're going to use is
black sesame stock which we'll show you
in a second
is there a difference between the dark
sesame and the white sesame plants
i don't know that off the top of my head
okay i'm sorry
that's okay a look at that duke
university accumulator list you
mentioned
beautiful patinas on this i don't know
ooh
all right let me drop it in watch look
at that fall apart can you see that
nice yeah so this is completely charred
at this point beautiful um you know if i
drop that on the ground
that'll just turn into a hundred pieces
um it's it's not it doesn't have those
um
organic compounds holding together its
structure anymore we've kind of
we've charred those off and we're left
kind of with the plants
you know minerals if you will um not
caught up in organic compounds and
that's what we want because that's
what we're easily extracting
i got to be careful there's a lot of
heat in this so as i have it open and
exposed to the air
i'm going to start turning to ash quite
quickly
and so i need to be careful with that so
i'm going to throw this in here to cool
and i'll throw a lid over it or a cover
um so that i don't melt my
my bag with hot biochar
and we'll make a fresh fresh batch here
um using the sesame stock
i'll show you that and then we'll come
back to my cooled biochar
and make some wsk
gorgeous
do you think that the the conductivity
of char
helps with the helps with this
particular process
definitely definitely we're we're
so conductivity kind of mineral um
you know i was just talking to steve
reisner over at
potentponics last night and he would
take uh
you know he's demonstrating uh a uh
fellaine of a fish and he'd take that
fillet
and uh when he's done he'd take a rag um
you know freshly caught um tilapia or
something he'd take a rag
soaked in a high saline solution he'd
wash his hands with it and he'd lay it
on the filet in front of a big group of
people he's demonstrating for and the
filet would start to jump
uh this you know totally totally
boneless
skinless filet would start to jump on
the table just freak everybody out
and that's just uh kind of that that
natural reality
of conductivity and and salt so i need
to cover this
or as it cools i'll get some ash and i
want to kind of avoid that so i'm going
to go ahead and throw
something on this to cover it but i
didn't think of that
so let me see what i got
wow i'm going to try that experiment
with a fish
i'm going to do that
i want frankenstein
yeah nerdy stuff it's so nerdy
i did i did share this oh go ahead sorry
go ahead no you go ahead
i was i shared this earlier but i wanted
to like i just read just like
10 minutes before we came on a billion
trillion electrons can be
stored and exchanged in a single gram of
biochar
very cool a billion trillion
those are not useful facts useless facts
those are
important to understanding how nature
works
that's cool i don't know what to do with
that but uh
i don't either that just means it's
pretty active
i think the fish jumping said it all
so i'm gonna just drop this in um i have
my clippers to make sure it all fits
but i think most of it's already the
size
um a friend
at flavor kit on instagram gave me her
black sesame stocks
i did not grow these so thank you
labor kit at flavor kit she's in
the flavor kits she's into things that
that grow and uh talks about them on
instagram
sweet
you can make this with fresh green
material or dried material
fresh green material will just take a
little longer
um i if if somebody asked me which is
better i would probably say drying your
material
is is a little bit better if you can you
know keep it nice while you're drying it
you don't want it to degrade you know or
rot or anything like that while you're
drying it so
as long as you can dry um properly
you know hanging something in a cool
dark place is a good way to dry it
um but yeah if you if you can't if you
don't have good control for drying
something
then go ahead and use it fresh um and
that will work as well
hey chris yeah i'm learning some i'm
learning something about ig live right
now
what's that we have i guess we only
haven't i guess i only have an
hour i have one minute and 30 seconds
remaining
so um
well what we can do is we can we can
pause right now
um yeah tell everybody you're gonna
restart and start
right back up let's do that if you'd
like to all right go ahead and drop it
and i'll follow you as soon as i see you
go live
okay cool come back everybody we're
gonna do this right now
i'm gonna show you how to do it all
right all right bye
yay sorry guys i guess there's an hour
to it
i'm glad you're coming back yay
all right we're gonna go he's gonna
follow me soon
good info right oh we're learning so
much i'm so
this is what happens when we get
together we we share information and we
learn
so much more than we thought we knew
here he is
um here we go you
go over guys it means you're you're
you're trusting the process and you're
here to
you're here to learn hey
hey so uh
in this world of negative news and and
craziness where are you finding your
humor
me or in general in general you
oh man i i i feel like i was born for
this time i feel like
i call it the great pause because i feel
like we've been given this time
to like just re renegotiate
our relationship with our world and with
each other and
i'm also like an optimist like i just
never stopped
being hopeful and i'm in love with life
and i'm in love with nature and dude
it's like just to see the animals taking
up being
affected in such a beautiful way
it makes me happy when the skies are
blue and you know
heck yeah heck yeah how about you
you've got to stay home a little bit
right i've gotten to stay home from
i like that um my my current uh
comedy source is uh an instagram uh
page called uh neat dads at neat
yeah it's basically uh endless series of
dad jokes
nate as in neat like me
like what dads usually aren't yeah well
or what dads think they are oh oh like
me
okay i get you
all right jumping in here with
our material so i just filled it up
um you can pack it we can fill this to
the brim
and fill every slot totally or we can
fill it loosely
it's up to you um packing it's great
in that you get the maximum kind of
um accomplished with your with your fire
or whatever you're doing so however you
want to do it but
pack it or loose wet material or dry
either way works how much you make
doesn't matter it's how you mix the
ratio of water
and your finished material that does
matter so we're going to do that right
now
our biochar from sunflowers cooling and
we're going to
throw this on the fire just to show you
you know step one to zero
or step one to finish with um making
biochar so
bring this over throw it on the fire i
might need to stoke my fire a little bit
let's see yeah i do need to stoke my
fire just touch here
i'm gonna grow sesame for the first time
this year i'm pretty excited
why why test me what what uh what
benefit or or reason what do you think
for this reason
oh cool all right for this very reason
but also
yeah but also to eat because i just love
sesame i want to just play with it
i'm also growing sweet potatoes to try
to work with the sugar i want to make
imo's using sweet potato
oh we do that in hawaii some really we
played
yeah we played with sweet potato um
you know we put it through a wood
chipper
oh cool and then dry it
i was drawing the whole potato over my
stove
and uh i thought next time i'm gonna
chop so you chop it up
fresh yeah chop it up fresh and then lay
it out on a screen
um to dry and you're not
cooking it uh no
oh you totally can cook it i think that
would
that would be maybe even better
because i think it converts to sugars
right yeah totally positive
um however you know uh if you're making
a lot of material
that's a lot to cook yeah i know
okay i got some we're usually making 100
pound 200 pound
so we have the you know stuff when
cooking you know
uh slop for pigs or whatever we can cook
potatoes but
you're still um it's a lot of work to
cook that much material
yeah you're right
all right you can see me just fine yep
and our biochar has cooled
so i can handle it
this is how well can you see this
there we go pretty shiny yeah
and so just i mean i could literally
crush this into powder
with no effort it's completely charred
and black all the way through
and you get this cool shiny patina
that's just a little bit
of the kind of organic
oils and
compounds left behind but um
yeah really really cool just um
neat to have this what was solid
kind of material just fall apart in your
hands and so a really finished
biochar is ideal for this
now i have my my teabag structure
i'm going to go ahead and hopefully
none of this is hot but i'll be adding
water to it immediately so
no we've cooled pretty nicely just warm
otherwise i'd hurt my container here
so i'm going to make a gallon
and so a tenth of a gallon by volume is
about what i want
for charcoal and so
this is about right this is kind of the
target amount
so i got about a softball here of
material
in my bag
hi sister
and so now what we're gonna do
i'm just making tea so um
clean you know cold water if you have a
little bit of chlorine i probably
wouldn't even be that worried about it
because we're not
dealing with microbes here and
chloramine actually
or chlorine actually occurs in nature
thank you for saying that helps to to um
actually make available nutrients so
it's a it's an interesting thing
in the concentrations we put it in our
our water and stuff it's not good
but uh in general it's not an evil thing
it's a part of
our soil naturally i would probably
want to avoid chloramine to negate
chloramine you can add humic acid but
that's not really helpful
in this so
i am just going to go ahead and pour in
my water
over my tea bag here
and i want to cover this um just to keep
critters out i don't need to seal it it
can it's going to be a breathable lid
um but i want to keep critters from
messing with my material so now
what i'm dealing with let's see if i can
switch you up for light
purposes what i'm dealing with is
a container full of water with a tea bag
full of biochar made with
sunflower and i'm going to let this sit
for seven to ten days
and then i pull off my tea bag and i
have my water-soluble potassium
on the shelf ready to go and you use it
at a rate of one to a thousand
when applying and you can add it into
your maintenance solution
um or you know
you can add it in even at a rate of one
to two thousand
um in something like uh you know
vegetative growth formula
which would be maintenance solution plus
fish amino acid
you could bring some of this in um it
can be included in pretty much
any of your applications as you need it
so really easy to make if you have the
tools
and definitely easy to use
as it's just sprayed on in foliar manner
so i'm going to set that on the shelf
and i come back to it um
in about a week i mean you have
questions on that i mean is it
that same pretty straightforward yeah so
are you going to keep it at one to a
thousand all the way through
and flat generally in use i'm gonna keep
it at one to a thousand
or one to two thousand meaning a l a
lighter
even a lighter deletion or a uh diluting
it more
um you just you bringing it in
somewhat regularly i don't need a lot of
it
this is um easily taken up through the
um
the leaf tissue itself so yeah nice
that's gorgeous so simple crazy simple
yeah and so now my
biochar is going and this will probably
take
you know dry material like this will
probably take
a good 15-20 minutes
to fully um make biochar
nice yeah so we're having people ask
about other
plants have you heard of anyone using
banana peel or bio charring banana peel
for these
for this for the potassium i
haven't and i don't know
what the potassium content of it by uh
banana
peel is um i will take this opportunity
to discourage people as
i as much as i can from using
bananas from the store to make your fpj
yeah especially if they're full of
pesticides etc from the typical um
um banana creation in the world today
yeah so don't go to the store and buy
your
gnarly banana and uh use it on your
favorite things
but yeah you could try banana peels i
don't know off hand i didn't i
they're the one the reason i gave you um
asparagus and sunflower is it that the
absolute highest in the accumulator
category for potassium
so these are we're talking way higher
than
things you typically think that have
potassium yeah
excellent alaska grow sunflowers
in the summer somebody's asking if they
can use bananas in alaska yeah you can
use organic bananas
if if that's all you can get you know
ultimately you gotta use what you can
get
and uh so i'm not gonna you know throw
stones at you doing the best you can
um i can't speak to bananas i'd have to
go look it up
yeah there were just some questions
there and i almost feel like some people
are concerned
with the fact that we need to start
utilizing our waste
stream if we can't stop eating bananas
then perhaps there's a use for the waste
stream of it
so i think i'm going to hear it on that
level but i think if if i had an
option between sunflower and asparagus
at the end of its season or bananas i
would definitely go with the sunflower
asparagus or sesame
yeah yeah and that we can we can look it
up that that sheet we talked about
on um aquaponics grower uh
aquaponic cannabis growers um at the
page
on facebook and they have a
files section and you can find
by duke university file on accumulators
and you can look up something that you
have in your area
that's that's potassium rich if you want
yeah and i'm growing up tobacco and
tobacco stem
and i'm using a tobacco fpga and i'm
using the vinegar
after the fpga and i'm really i don't
know what the qual i don't know
the compounds that make it such a
good one i gotta correct myself real
quick tobacco
tobacco i'm sorry i've totally i just
mixed up my things tobacco is um
is the potassium source typically taught
in korean natural farming
i'm showing you sesame which is a
typical straight
phosphorus source uh sesame is a
phosphorus accumulator
and so um yeah
sorry about that tobacco is a typical
it's a
typical potassium that makes it makes
the head
um but yeah so amazing oh my god
yeah so tobacco stems would be excellent
as your potassium source
and then yeah so far with sesame um
for phosphorus so tobacco would be an
excellent potassium source
sesame for phosphorus we would not knit
then
typically when we use bones to make a
phosphorus we got a
calcium phosphate um with
with sesame we're going for a straight
kind of phosphorus
and so we do do it the same way char it
and then soak it in water
um for for a phosphorous nutrient that's
beautiful
i'm glad we got there that's gorgeous
okay yeah
and i just since people are joining and
maybe some new people have joined i want
to make sure
everyone understands that you're doing
another presentation this afternoon
uh with the future cannabis
the future cannabis cannabis project
project
um is it youtube or facebook do you know
i think it's youtube
um yeah yeah so
you can check them out at the
futurecanvasproject.com
and um yeah it might
it would probably be an interesting one
um as you know some some people
um there you know question uh the
advocacy of korean natural farming and
you know and i think that's healthy to
have those kind of discussions on
you know what do you see in in your your
attempts to
you know promote a regenerative
agricultural society and um and how do
they differ and
so that that'll be some of what we get
into you over there today
nice all in love and uh
yeah should be good nice
totally yeah
yeah do you want to uh walk around a
little bit and look at uh
fpga materials sure let's do that
because it's now it's a now thing it's
now time to be doing these fpgas
yeah so what don't you want to use for
an fpga
we covered it a little before but you
don't want to use
um conventional produce that you're
buying at your typical store even
organic produce it's basically bleach
washed
um even if it is organic they're able to
bleach wash it
um and so you don't have any of your
indigenous
microbes or the things that typically
are found on that plant to ferment
itself
so you'll typically get some weird
growths
and strain of blooms of green stuff
as whatever's in your air is trying to
digest this for
subjects or item
you might be losing you might lose
connection as you're as you're
traveling outwardly
sorry about that i jumped off of uh i
jumped off of wi-fi i was walking away
from the wi-fi
yeah yeah
yeah so um you know if if you don't have
a plants you know indigenous microbes
that live on that plant and grow with it
um you'll be relying on whatever's in
your air whatever was on the hand of the
grocer or the 10 people that touched
that
banana before you those microbes are
what you're going to be relying on to
ferment your
fpj rather than if something still has
its microbes present it can
ferment itself in those microbes so i
just discourage from
store-bought even if you live in a city
a short travel once a year just outside
to find a place where
some great healthy weeds grow abundantly
would be great would be enough
another thing not to use is poisonous
plants
you're going to be consuming this you
don't want to use here's an example of a
poisonous plant
growing here does anybody know what this
is oh
it's queen anne's lace
and so this this is pretty toxic and
would make a terrible fpj
because i wouldn't want to be
introducing those to the veggies my kids
are going to eat
and yeah so definitely don't want
highly poisonous plants another thing
you would
be only have to learn once and you might
not survive it would be to use like a
poison oak or poison ivy
you'd probably die um as as that
material got into your lungs or your
digestive system so um i was can i tell
what can i tell a tobacco story
because i do use tobacco cj but i think
i am only going to use it in drench you
don't want to use it as a foliar because
i decided
to start eating some of my fpjs on a
demonstration to some
uh young horticulture students and i had
a minute amount of the tobacco fpj
it didn't affect me right away but i
woke up the next morning and
as i got up to walk out of bed i
was walking in a different direction
than where i was looking so i literally
had to
focus somewhere else to walk the
straight line
it has a neurological effect wow
that is quite profound and lasts for
quite a while
all right yes hemlock poison hemlock
they're right i think
it might be synonymous with queen anne's
lace but it is hemlock
i always i think called it queen please
um so what are good things to use
i love comfrey everyone's asking about
comfrey coffee is amazing
coffee is amazing so are dandelions
this is just a side pasture we don't
cultivate
i'm in a new property dandelions are
amazing
these guys the leaves the new growing
tips
all amazing i have this other plant here
it's prolific
weed i know it's not toxic because
animals can eat it readily
i don't have the identification but this
stuff is great
always healthy the bees love it
no no bug pressure and
it grows abundantly
the the key is if something is growing
abundantly without
care it is so good
at accumulating nutrients from your soil
in your area
that it's going to be nutrient rich if
you start using
you know things just because you're like
oh i know that tastes good
but it struggles in your area or it's
anemic
that the the nutrient density in that
tissue is going to be actually
less than just some weed that you think
nothing about
so yeah find find things in your area
that are abundant and thriving
we have this big patch of dock which is
an
edible weed um and
i'll be using fpj
and i mean dandelion
dog and a few other things to make fpj
actually tomorrow
i have a question about the dandelion
yeah
so at dawn the dandelion flowers are not
open
so do you think that there's a different
mechanism at work when it comes to like
that
the undifferentiated stuff that you're
trying to harvest
hormones and enzymes is it different in
a flower that's not opening it
at dawn or do we harvest it at a
different time
oh yeah um always at dawn
and it'll be um they're accumulating
nutrients
and and processing the nutrients they
accumulated through photosynthesis the
day before
and they're not um they're not working
hard to regulate their temperature
so they you know at the end of the day
we're tired uh a plant's the same way at
the end of the day they're tired from
photosynthesis
and that big engine they're running and
then regulating their temperature
early in the morning they've taken all
this rest time to
kind of process all their nutrients and
store them
for into their growing tips for new
growth
this is uh i have one in hawaii but this
is my new
toy for boise i've been missing my
uh cement maker so i'll be making my
episode in this
tomorrow it's exciting
that's a lot of fpga yeah well i'll only
make it once you know i just
encourage people you know you don't have
to make new stuff all the time
and they'll make it once for a year and
you're you're done making stuff um as
fun as it is to make this stuff
it's not really the point of natural
farming the point is
productive crops
with a low amount of effort as possible
and yeah yeah
so i ha i had an experience
how close to harvesting plants should
you be making the fpj
because i last year i did i would go out
harvest as much as i can
then spend part of the day processing
this year i'm
i'm gathering smaller amounts and
processing it almost immediately
is there a difference in quality when
you do that
um yeah i mean
ideally you do want to process it asap
um you know having stuff like
uh cement mixer and some other things
that are used to process
quickly can be huge
yeah so i can get a big batch done first
thing
um but yeah as best you can if it takes
you a few hours to chop everything
but you got it you still have you know
those nutrients aren't flowing back down
or leaving those root tips you still
have them there
and so we're we're kind of hopeful that
that's
um we're not losing a whole lot in the
processing time
wait i don't have a data driven answer
on that for you
yeah yeah yeah that sounds good
gorgeous totally let's let's do a quick
peek and see how
charred we are so far on this uh
material so we just put this on what 10
minutes ago
i'm gonna burn my bench here
that's okay
look at that that's so pretty
so we're a good way on okay i gotta put
that on so right away just by taking
that off
because of the heat i started ashing so
i've lost some of my material by
checking that
because of the heat as soon as i exposed
it to oxygen
right away in the center you might not
have been able to see it but
ash started forming and i started losing
material quality so
it's a really important balance between
oxygen
in this process so we want to make sure
that lid stays on nicely
so that the material cooks
outside of an oxygen-rich environment
yeah is there a different quality in
biochar depending on your region
no no yeah it's all the process
quality of process is yeah
okay and how long can fpga be stored
typically
like and i know it depends on how you
handle it and how you make it initially
but is there a decline in
quality over time um i i typically tell
people to
to make it um for for six months because
that's absolutely
safe um however if somebody's storing
their um material
and you know in the sun in a hot
environment or don't have a good cover
on it you can cause fpga to deteriorate
just from poor storage technique so
finding a concrete floor
in a cool dark room um your your fpj
will last for
a good year um and i
i have some that you know it just was
processed properly
and stored nicely and
it's good five years later but some
sometimes stored improperly or maybe
too much moisture or too little moisture
fpga can accumulate moisture and then go
off
kind of start getting towards alcohols
and vinegars
or too little moisture fpga can start to
evaporate or lose moisture
and get very much like a syrup or even
not syrup more like a taffy you know
where just
it's so thick and you'd have to re-add
water to even you know it comes out like
a like a goo
you can hold it and slowly drip it you
know so i've done that
yeah and that's just a running out of
water in a dry environment so it kind of
depends on your environment and hawaii
it would be typical that things would
accumulate moisture
in idaho it's typical that things run
out of moisture
so same thing with im02 i'm spritzing my
imo 2 in idaho
to keep it from overly drying out okay
it's good to do that with your amos too
you don't want to let them dry out
either
i am o2 could you spray wca and w
calcium phos until two weeks before chop
i'm not saying that you should but could
you
anything microbials and no so um
i assume you're talking about cannabis
and
um what i
have um experienced
um in interacting with just great
growers
um is the kind of
absorption qualities that some of your
your
your plant has and uh so what you want
to be aware of is
anything that could affect flavor
especially if you're
you're going down to an isolate or some
sort of
after market processing or after chop
processing
if the flavor of the vinegar or the
flavor
of the kind of calcium phosphate were to
affect
your quality that would be a huge no-no
and so you need to be careful
um spraying on the leaves right before
you're harvesting
and even in the in the flowering process
that you don't
negatively affect flavor however a lot
of these nutrients
can be taken up in the root zone so you
can
take the same principle the same
application rate
and put it in your watering system so
that you're getting this
this feed but not putting it directly on
those
those nodules of oils and
all flavor that will absorb it and
potentially affect the flavor it going
through the root system and going up to
the plant will have
a drastically different effect it won't
it won't have such a um
kind of lasting flavor effect so yeah be
careful caution to you
yeah i usually do foliar up until about
five weeks into flower and then i go to
drench
that's how i typically handle it
personally but everybody
yeah yeah and other other growers only
do
foliar in vegetative growth and once
they get into flower they
only do drench and other growers i've
talked to you
you know don't think it affects labor at
all i am not
have to beg ignorance on that
all because i don't know i haven't
tested it
yeah and side by side
let's just briefly mention the
importance of that oh my goodness right
it's how we gonna grow as a community
um question about fermented sea water
fermented sea water is already diluted
when you made it so um yeah
you you can go ahead so seawater is
diluted i think it's a one to thirty
seawater
a one to seven hundred lab
and a one to maybe 300 fpj
and that those are already
diluted quantities and so you can apply
it you can also cut it fifty percent
um or more if you want it to kind of
spread
okay yeah yeah i love it well thank you
for
i thank you for your time chris thank
you for taking you're so generous with
your time
and your knowledge pleasure so cool to
talk with you on all this and all the
work you've done to
kind of put this into practice and share
it it's neat
yeah so just yeah he's got a class
coming up in august everyone so
there's nothing like a hands-on make
sure you're tuning in to that he's going
to be speaking again at you with the
future cannabis project on youtube so if
you want
more of chris make sure you you join
that
and anything else we should add should
we just
call it good yeah i think that i think
that was great i think we got to
talk about all kinds of good stuff and
uh i went ahead and pulled my
sesame stocks off the fire but i'll
leave them closed
to cool so that i don't get ashy um
as it uh finishes but we'll get um
get a bit more charcoal being made as it
just sits in this super hot pot
um but i don't want to lift it before it
cools unless i could cool it quickly
and because i'm not going to add this to
water right away i'm just going to leave
it in there
and then this you see that beautiful
kind of
patina color that's happening in the
water yeah that's gorgeous
yeah so that's you know kind of our
our nutrient our mineral in there
diffusing into our water column yeah
darkened over time
yeah and it'll continue to do that nice
and seven days on that just like every
other application seven to ten you know
um yeah you don't want to pull it crazy
early but
if you go a day or two over it's not the
end of the world
but you don't want to leave it in there
for a month um you can get some really
weird things happening
um with just stuff growing and stuff
good to talk to you tina yeah keep up
the good work
and uh yeah cool to see how you continue
to
play with all of this and and enjoy the
the journey yeah yeah
it's a it's a fun community to be a part
of and it's just great to have you at
the helm
you're a brilliant teacher and i just
you know i learn a lot from you every
time
so thank you thank you cool
well until next time then okay until
next time
bye everyone see you later
[Music]
you