Jackie Macwan and I am uh I'm the owner
of band aid consulting firm um which is
is a direct result to this Facebook
group that Susan says I started um but
I'm I'm here today because I am forever
indebted to a plant and the people
provided for me in this room today I
thank all of you that that risk their
lives and their safety um in order to be
in this industry um so at the beginning
of this year I I began a Facebook group
called California City and County bandat
if you're not a member and you're
looking to be up to date on current
marijuana policy in the state I'm
obsessed um I saw uh the first wave of
bands hit our uh state after the passage
of Mera last year and in November I I
saw about 10 come through in one day and
I realized that there was something
going on that we weren't aware of and uh
the reason that I saw this was due to
some Google Alerts that I had set up uh
my background is I worked on Wall Street
for 18 years as a stock broker so I am a
research junkie I crave information and
um I saw this first wave come through
and I didn't know I didn't understand
and I I I I knew there had to be other
people out there that wanted you know
more information like this so on January
2nd I knew uh that our legislature would
be reconvening Statewide on January 4th
there was set to be massive bans uh
being implemented across the state so
that was uh this was actually the second
wave but uh most people think that that
was the first wave because it was when I
I formed this group and um January we
got Mass occurred um the league of
California cities was on a road show
encouraging all of our local government
to ban instead of regulate um they were
pushing that erroneous deadline that was
passed um in Mera uh which was the March
1 deadline and by the time it had been
repealed we had I believe 240 localities
that had uh banned marijuana so my
background being that I worked on Wall
Street I was craving this information so
I set up 540 Google email alerts one for
every city and every County so 482
cities and 58 counties so that I could
see everything going on I still have all
those Google alerts set up and I still
search what is going on you know with
with our cities and counties and with
they're regulating and right now I
believe about 20% of the state is either
implementing regulations or talking
about regulations and that is up from
about 10% just just a few months ago so
we are definitely seeing progress and
now I'd like to give each of our
speakers a chance to introduce
themselves gami hello everybody um
there's a lot of stuff that I can talk
about but I guess uh the one that I'm
going to talk about is uh property in La
property is probably the worst
legislation that has ever been written
to you know for a city in the history of
the world and so but it kept us alive
and that's why you know it's good that
was the only thing now we're in the
process of working with the city six
months ago we gave the city of Los
Angeles an ordinance that was written by
Mayor Brown which is one of the most
prestigious law firms in Los Angeles to
ensure that they have a framework that
they can work with that won't be suable
we're working with the city that is our
main um it's different now uh when I
started this 10 years ago we had to beg
to talk to uh elected officials Mr ket's
always welcomed us and was always
wonderful but most of the city council
members you know it was like we were
begging them please listen to us things
have changed now um the politics have
caught up to the science and so
everybody understands that medical
medical marijuana is just that it's
medical and that um also that there's a
lot of of to be gained by um tax income
in the city which everybody you know
really likes that I think that's why the
politicians are so ready and and and so
able now to help us go along because
they know we're here to stay we're not
going away and that better for them to
regulate us in a correct Manner and and
so that they can collect their taxes for
the city and everybody can be happy
so um I hope that in March uh we're able
to do something in the city of El to fix
D because it needs to be fixed and so
that we can join the rest of the state
and being regul regulated by Mera and
whatever else comes along and we can all
Step Up in Los Angeles thank you
go ahead Paul thanks yummy well I don't
know where to start but I could say I
was the author of prop
D so that bad introduction but let me
start at the beginning um I was just
having a meeting with uh some folks
about talking about cultivation and they
said so where do you get your marijuana
because I've been involved in this issue
very visibly for years I'm like I'm not
a marijuana on a user and they were
astonished but now have I ever smoked a
joint in my entire life well I wasn't
College in the 70s I'm not going to say
anything about whether whether I inhaled
or not but but I'm not a marijuana user
I'm involved because I got elected to
the city council 1988 but I was involved
in founding the city of West Hollywood
in
1984 and we did it for all kinds of good
reasons and all of it went perfectly and
and except the AIDS crisis hit and it
hit with a Vengeance we are the hardest
hit City per per person um in the
country and so I personally as I mean
this is a disease that in West Hollywood
mostly hit gaymen um I'm a straight guy
I personally knew over 200 people that
died of AIDS um and there were many many
more um at one point we had uh over one
person in every 10 housing units in the
city had HIV or Aids um and in the
beginning we had we had no medicine for
it um there were the only thing we had
was medical marijuana and it improved
the quality of life and it kept some
people alive longer um it dealt with the
nausea it dealt with the wasting and
kept people with an appetite um there
were there were so many elements to it
it dealt with the pain um and I have
friends that are alive today because
they lasted long enough to as a bridge
um to to get to the stronger drugs
people like Richard Eastman who some of
you know um and others are still around
today 30 years later um and so that got
me involved in the issue and I've been
involved from that time that whole 30
years and so um when John
vasconcelos uh drafted
sb420 um people were really terrified to
be associated with marijuana and the
legisl lure so I was the principal
co-author on the assembly side um but
there weren't a lot of other co-authors
I think there might have been one other
person um people ultimately voted for it
it was written in a very compromising
way to get passed but it was so vague
that it its regulations caused as many
problems as they solved um ultimately we
tried to correct that with prop D and in
Los Angeles we took so many different
approaches every step we took in every
direction uh CA caused us to get
hammered legally so no matter what we
tried it didn't work uh prop D was the
only thing that stuck but before that we
passed things uh that were were more
permissive um and we legally got hit we
actually had a vote at one point to uh
to ban marijuana and that passed and
that passed 13 to1 I was the one vote
against it on my birthday and yet we we
found that there are too many legal
problems with that so we repealed that
right away also um I only had one
colleague who was an enthusiastic
supporter um I think because of his
presence on the council prop D passed
his name was Bill rosendall I don't know
if any of you know him or remember him
wonderful guy um but he was a medical
marijuana user because three years
before he died he was diagnosed with
with fourth stage cancer and was
literally just about about dead I
thought he was going to last a couple
weeks um he reacted well to
chemotherapy and he survived all of his
side effects and the pain and lack of
appetite and all kinds of other things
because of medical marijuana it kept him
alive for three years and I think that
made the council see that they had to
accept something uh again prop D was
vague partly because we were told it had
to be we were told we couldn't license
um because it was illegal by our City
attorney so we sort of had a list of
people that uh we would give a wink and
a nod and under prop D they would be
compliant and even then we didn't have a
list of who they all were uh so
sometimes uh we would crack down even on
the people that we were supposed to not
crack down on um and our City attorney
would go after them um at the same time
uh we had 135 that were semile legit in
this this
unclear way we probably have a thousand
that are illegal that have popped up and
we try to prosecute them and close them
down and for everyone that got closed
down another one would pop up so that's
been a mess um State legislation I think
will help I think we will uh we will
figure out how to deal with things that
we should be dealing with like
cultivation I mean right now we we we
deal with marijuana by Immaculate
Conception but somehow it gets to the
dispensaries once it's there it's legal
um if we catch you growing it in LA we
prosecute you if we catch you
transporting it to a dispensary we
prosecute you of course this makes great
sense so we are working to try and
correct it it's also a question of how
many dispensaries we're going to have
which ones are going to be legal we
think around 65 of the original 135 that
were compliant are still in business um
do we Grand B them in uh there's a lot
of question about uh Fair distribution
ethnically geographically in the city I
think there's an appetite to fill that
all in uh so there's equal access uh
across the city um once we we passed
prop 64 which I think is absolutely
inevitable there's going to be much more
demand so I think if we have two few
dispensaries will have the problem that
my Council has reacted to it's not that
they are anti- marijuana but there were
there were some nuisance factors there
are some bad operators um of of
facilities and uh council members
responded to constituent complaints well
if we if we have too few dispensaries
we're going to have lines around the
block we're going to have a lot of the
complaints that my colleagues complained
about um so we we have to at least
provide uh enough dispensaries to meet
the demand so there are a lot of
confusing issues La is kind of a mess on
this but I think we will we will clean
this up um before the deadline for
permitting goes into effect hopefully a
lot sooner so we can not arrest people
for no purpose um and we can get this
show on the road and start doing it the
right way I'm not sure my colleagues
care that much about the revenue I think
it'll be a nice added bonus um one thing
I should say is we thought we were going
to have to put something on the ballot
our City attorney is opine that we can
do everything but tax by ordinance so I
think we should just keep our 6% set tax
where it is at least for for a while and
just focus on doing this right not put
it on the ballot pass an ordinance that
works and get
going isn't it a breath of fresh air to
hear a regulator admit that there are
problems with an ordinance and thank you
Paul uh Janine tell us a little bit
about you thank you uh well first first
of all I'd like to welcome everybody
here uh to Long Beach and the second
district uh we are in my district which
I have been uh representative for just
about two months um so welcome everyone
uh I'm originally from Texas uh and I
grew up uh always knowing that marijuana
had medicinal purposes my mother used it
and she the first time I did she gave it
to me uh to help with my cramps and said
you go to the doctor and cry or you know
you can do this and it was something
that that was the frame that I always
had and so I came uh to the issues of
medical marijuana to the debate about it
with a very open mind even though I'm
not an avid user although also college
and high school and I'll admit I did
inhale um and so uh when I started
running for Council it was uh one of
those issues and in Long Beach and I'll
talk about the history of our you know
sorted uh debate about to regulate not
regulate and what to regulate in a
minute uh but I came to the debate uh
and the conversation very openly in
support of it um wasn't going to try to
walk the line that I think other
electeds have tried to walk in the city
because we have a more conservative
background uh because we've kind of been
timid of regulating it uh very openly
being able to say we need to have access
to medicine for all of our residents uh
that doesn't uh hinge on a delivery
system where you're putting people at
risk uh for robbery that doesn't hinge
on other cities uh you know getting
their tax revenue and Long Beach missing
out but Long Beach uh is definitely uh
moving in the right direction and as a
regulator I think it's really important
to start in cities and partner with
folks like you uh because as much as we
can be supportive of an idea or a
Concepts how it works is it's the devil
in the details as we've heard from LA
and other places whenever we try to do
ordinances uh sometimes we have to learn
from those mistakes and so working
closely with you all to talk about what
works what doesn't what's the right
amount of dispensaries to have grow and
everything else and so I'm really happy
to be here with you guys today and to
learn from you all uh to move forward
because I do believe that in November uh
Long Beach has two ballot measures which
I'll talk about but mm which is medical
marijuana bringing that back to the city
right now it's banned and then another
initiative that the city council put on
the ballot uh to tax both medical and
recreational at a higher rate than it's
already taxed uh and so I'll talk in
detail about both of those as well but
welcome everybody excited to be
here thank you Janine Nathan tell us a
little bit about your about you my name
is Nathan vosberg I'm from the city of
Kinga we are currently the only uh City
in Fresno County that has moved forward
with regulation if you look on weed maps
there is a very giant hole in the
Central Valley about like this which in
my opinion has promoted a very gray and
very black market area um you know when
the issue came in when the issue came in
January and we were asked to make a
decision um to me personally I thought
in my mind you know this is something
doing research beforehand that could
help a lot of people and and when I
looked into the audience and our
audience was pretty much at that point
in time I think maybe they're the only
people that paid attention to the
agenda um but they were 100% in in for
this at the time I believe Almost 100%
uh our next meeting it wasn't so nice
people found out what we wanted to do
with regulations and we had a big group
of people show up that were not in
support of what we're of what we wanted
to do and it was really an interest
interesting thing to try and somewhat
sell our citizens on the
idea and we went
through quite a few different phases in
in trying to do this uh we fought the
medical battle we went back and forth
with our citizens on who supported this
for medical use and then we went through
you know the security and and what comes
along with bringing facilities uh which
were initially talking about a
dispensary and that's when we had our
first 50 vote which pretty much shocked
everyone in Fresno County because
everyone including our Sheriff was
completely against this kind of idea
kind of shocked the council too we were
kind of like you know interested like
hey we have a group of people in front
of us and those people wanted it so we
did it so what I'm here to tell you guys
is is that I want to thank every single
P person in this room for providing us
with the with the data with the ideas
with the research to move forward
because without you people this doesn't
work like in counsil in
government our job is to promote what
the people want and to make compromise
most of the time and finding out how to
compromise in between something where
people are what I'm finding a 50/50
split in our conservative area maybe
even 6040 on the other side um
California wise it maybe 60 40 7030
towards AUM passing but in a very
conservative belt of the Central Valley
it may be flipped and so trying to
figure out a way
to uh compromise with both sides has
been very interesting and we've been
taking the data I've been you know when
I joined um Jackie's Facebook group it
was for just that to get the data I
wanted to take the data back to our
Council and say hey this is what other
counties and cities are doing and this
is the information from the people we
have visited um lots of different
dispensaries we've we've visited grow
we've visited uh all kinds of different
places to try and figure out like what
is best practice what are the things
that come with this what are the good
actors what are the Bad actors and
everyone in this room probably has had
something to do with uh you know us
trying to figure this out and I just
want to really thank everybody because
without that it doesn't it doesn't work
and and I couldn't my people wouldn't
relate to this in Kinga at all if there
wasn't other people saying hey this is
what we've done and this is what it's
worked and this isn't just um you know
your cliche of potheads and Stoners out
there this is your people that are
seeking some kind of help that don't
want to go the traditional route or the
traditional route isn't working for them
and so um I'd like to thank Susan for
putting this uh together and I'd like to
thank Jack for her Facebook group who
has allowed um you know our city and
other cities like us and so what I'm
going to talk about today is that
Journey that we went on and the
different perils that we've went through
trying to move forward to provide
opportunity that's what this is this is
opportunity because if you think that 50
that we're going to do something for 50%
of the people in my place that that
support medical and the other 50% of the
people who don't believe in it well that
just doesn't work work I mean that's
what we found we found that that doesn't
work because you have a divide in people
you need to find a topic or a narrative
that fits everyone and we found that
jobs and economy fit everyone's
narrative now I want to show you guys
something I have I have this green
wristband on right here this green
wristband is in support of the thing
that we couldn't do in Kinga which was
we couldn't pass a dispensary so we put
it on the ballot so the ballots coming
up and this is my support right here for
that ballot measure to say that I
support a dispensary in Kinga however we
had to compromise we had to say we
listen to our people and our people are
citing security concerns and all kinds
of things um you know to do with
dispensaries and I feel really bad that
we couldn't get that moved forward but I
do feel confident that our people will
come around and say hey you know what
you guys are going to show us the the
opportunities and we are going to
respond when we vote and so um for
everyone here today you know I hope that
you follow us in Kinga we have lots of
opportunity popping up in the Central
Valley and I believe that with a little
push that the rest of the valley is
going to turn green as well so I
appreciate you guys for coming thank you
very
much thank you Nathan you know it's
important to note that by him sticking
his neck out by kolinga moving forward
with regulations there are now two more
cities inside of Fresno County looking
to regulate that called him up and said
hey we want some of these jobs too and I
attended one of those City Council
meetings and it was jam-packed with
people that did not care one way or
another about marijuana they were there
because they heard jobs were coming and
their lives were going to change thank
you Nathan uh next up is Don sailor from
Yello County thanks Jackie it's a
pleasure to hear the stories of these
three city council members in their very
different settings but but you see some
common uh commitment to doing the right
thing for people I'm a County Supervisor
I'm in my second term in Yolo County I
was a city council member for two year
two terms in Davis California and a
Schoolboard member for two terms prior
to that in the same Community I worked
for state government for about 25 years
before I retired in 2003 my jobs in
state government were five years with
the legislative analyst office
nonpartisan fiscal adviser and 20 years
working for the Department of
Corrections and the Department of the
Youth Authority in Corrections in the
mid 80s my role was to build new prisons
and realized we can't build enough if
we're going to continue on the
trajectory that we've been on Yolo
County is about 210,000 people it's 1,00
square miles about 85% of that is Farm
country there's a hundred-year
partnership between the University of
California Davis and Growers Farmers
they their the wave of a waves of
Agriculture have have uh have have been
really amazing there's innovation in
farm country there's something that I
think of as the square tomato the square
tomato is this unique partnership
between genetic manipulation and
Engineering so that we can produce
tomatoes that have a longer lifespan a
longer shelf life harder on the outside
and still juicy and very nutritious on
the inside so we can Harvest them and
have them shipped to a place where they
can be processed and we created at the
same time time harvesting equipment that
could handle that equ that those those
products and get them to to Market and
as a result of that our county is the is
the world's leading producer of
processing Tomatoes it makes no sense in
the world that we don't acknowledge the
agricultural enterprise that cannabis
brings and Yolo County is perfectly
situated to do that I'm excited about
the the changes that we see a foot
because we can see better research on
the effect effecacy efficacy of
medicinal uses of cannabis for specific
maladies that the human uh suffers from
and University of California Davis is
the home of a medical school life
sciences uh Powerhouse as well as a
veterinary school and and just an
amazing an amazing conglomeration of
Partnerships with with the agricultural
Community Yolo County when we were faced
with the the this this thread of a March
3rd deadline we tried to we struggled to
try to find a way to balance the
interest this March 3rd deadline that
you're either going to have to regulate
or do some other uh ban and it the
easiest thing to do in the world was to
Simply fall back and say no we're not
going to do any of that that didn't make
sense for our County we we had we think
we have 800 to a th000 growers in our
County currently 210,000 people 800 to
th000 Growers that's a pretty big number
we know that in the fields and Hills
that we already have cultivators so
cultivation is a thing that we wanted to
really look hard at we found a way to
balance uh I think an ordinance we
adopted it in February it's an interim
ordinance we'll be considering uh some
some tweaks here in the first week in
October and we're looking at a December
adoption of a final ordinance that's
based on what we started with and lots
of input from community members uh we
think that probably 800 to th000 of
those Growers out there we figure about
20% of them will want to become want to
come out of the Shadows who want to
become legitimate operators and we
already seeing I mentioned that we had
about 11 the other day well I had a
conversation with our a commissioner uh
last night or this and this morning and
we now have 53 uh uh Growers that are in
the process of becoming fully permitted
I'm I'm looking forward to sharing with
you some of the experiences that we've
had uh and some of the some of the
challenges that we're continuing to face
but I I will I will tell you that if you
look on the website and this is my last
comment for this round you look on the
website for adult use of Mer yes on on
Prop 64 you'll see this long list of
people who have endorsed amama uh and
I'm still stunned that when they asked
me if I would endorse it I said well of
course and of the 300 County Supervisors
in California mine is the only name on
the list so I want you all to talk to
some of your friends who are County
Supervisors CU it was I'm feeling a
little lonely right now