we're going to now drill in and ask a
few deeper questions to our panel
members and um at the end here we're
going to save a few minutes for
questions from the audience you just
stated that measure D was the worst
ordinance written in the history of the
world and then Paul caret admitted that
he wrote measure D what is your
relationship like today because of
this love mros as well I'm sorry I led
Mr caret and I love Mr rosenal as well
they're the only two councilmen that
actually work with us I don't think it
was his fault that it came out as bad as
it did but actually yeah it didn't
permit us it didn't protect us and and
and those of us that have limited
immunity what happens is that the cops
law enforce want to come and and
challenge us then we have to prove to
them that we have limited immunity and
then after that you know hopefully
they'll leave us alone right it's the
worst slob because it doesn't didn't
give us anything it it gave us the right
to exist under limited immunity but the
rest of the illegal clubs in Los Angeles
exist the same way you know so I'm
sorry but you have to agree with me that
it's it's really really bad and that we
have to fix it and the ordinance that
glaca wrote goes in hand in hand with
Mera and all the things that Mera say so
that we qualify and able to do that but
it is it was it is the worst legislation
for a city that I can imagine that could
ever exist hopefully things will be much
better going forward with the other
cities when they regulate now before
measure D passed you had gathered
signatures through glocka uh and put
your own measure on the ballot that was
measure e yes that is correct there was
also a measure f yes that is correct so
you had e d and f yeah was
great and can you talk about you have to
say d passes 60% of the voter and the
other two because we backed off of e so
we never you know advertised it or
anything and the F people I think got
like 30% or 40% I'm not sure I just know
that D got 62% of the votes so at least
we knew that the city and you know the
the the voters wanted medical marijuana
in fact we did uh a poll about 6 months
ago when we commissioned the new
ordinance and it came back at 82% 82% of
La voters that were pulled said that
medical marijuana should exist in the
city of Los Angeles so I mean we have
the people on our side it's just we need
to figure out how to do it so it's done
correctly as far as regulation is
concerned so in hindsight withdrawing
measure e do you believe that that was a
good decision at that time would you
still do that today yes we had to
because the city was putting up D and we
were told that if we didn't go with the
city we would never win so it was about
staying alive so we went with the city
we won by 62% of the vote it was bad but
it was
good but we're going to fix that we're
going to fix that in hopefully in March
so and so one week ago another
organization called the ucba trade
Association submitted 100,000 signatures
to place an initiative on the ballot for
March of
2017 this would allow priority licensing
to the 135 property uh dispensaries that
have limited immunity from prosecution
for being a dispensary um can you talk
about what you like or dislike with this
measure the fact that 135 dispensaries
will be grandfathered
in that's what I like about that measure
okay
um um we've decided glaca has decided
that in the interest of the patients and
our community in the city of Los Angeles
that we will work s side by side by the
city uh ucba has elected to walk another
path and all power to them
um the the things that are wrong with
ucba uh initiative and we're going to
say one is that if you AB but two
residences then you'll have to move so
there's a lot of dispensaries that are
propd the 135 or how many were left I
you said 65 I think 85 but anyway um
then those places will have to close CL
um it doesn't affect me because I don't
a but to Residents I have a dispensary
in in in uh Chatsworth um a property
dispensary so I don't a but to Residents
I have parking I have space none of the
stuff that's in the initiative affects
me personally or my dispensary the
problem is is that anybody that knows me
knows that I'm a prop D girl that's my
family those are the people that stepped
up and in my opinion are the ones that
should be grandfathered in because we
fought year after year after year to be
alive and to be recognized and so I
believe that the property dispensers
should be grandfathered in and I that's
the one thing that I agree with in their
initiative but you have a new feeling
now that you've already gone the route
of the initiative and you've gone the
route of compromise and um how do you
feel the best way to proceed uh with
implementing full Mera implementation
the way we've always proceeded working
with the city being their friend um
trying to educate them trying to come to
understandings together we don't want to
fight with them there's no reason to
anymore we don't have to talk them into
the fact that we're medical they already
know it you know so now it's all about
good regulation what we can live with
and and and that's it that's the bottom
line and I to me working with the city
working side by side with the city is
the best path for glocka to go and
that's what we've decided to do do you
now view an initiative as a
fight
um I
think that the initiative was brought on
like last time we wrote e to force the
city to write something and put it on
the ballot hopefully something better uh
we had to choose to go with the city
because that's the way that we had to go
um I like my
way I want to choose to continue to work
with the city side by side and giving
them the support and and education and
all the things that they need for us so
that they can then you know craft
something that'll be good for our
community and the community at large
thank you yumy and thank you so much for
everything that you have done over the
years you've helped so many people your
Powerhouse we're all grains of sand in
the pale and sometimes the pale fills up
with lots of grains of sand so fires can
be put out I'm just a grain in of sand
in the pale that's what I am and and I'm
just doing what I believe I should do
cannabis gave me back my life so now I'm
giving back to cannabis and she's humble
as
well thanks
yammi Paul in 2003 you were the
co-author of S420 which allowed the
collective model uh can you explain how
that idea came to be you know who
decided to put all of these different
entities together to allow what was then
uh commercial licensing
essentially well I I wish I could give
you a better explanation but I won't
take credit for much of it it was it was
the late Senator John
vasconcelos that really did all of the
work and the Coalition building around
that I think uh it was viewed that
215 uh was too vague and we needed to
actually provide some direction um
unfortunately uh there were a lot of
folks that were very squeamish about
supporting medical marijuana at all so
it wound up being a compromise measure
that was pretty vague uh that wasn't my
call my only real involvement was to
support it on the assembly side to be
the Principal co-author to get it passed
and so I'll take a little credit for
helping get it passed um I think it
probably should have been written a
little more clearly uh but then again I
had the same problem and same
opportunity in the city uh with a
council that was completely all over the
map um and and really there was no
consensus I think It ultimately got
consensus partly prop D because uh we
could see Bill rosendal and he was still
alive and still coming to Council
meetings because of medical marijuana
and and how much that helped him and so
I think it w it was too personal for for
some of the council members to vote
against him again it was it was vague
didn't deal with a lot of the issues
that I would have liked to have dealt
with but we were lucky honestly to get
it through the council this is not a
very supportive Council and we had some
members that were very strongly opposed
uh some just on on the basis of being
anti-marijuana but more most being being
responsive their constituents who
complained about some of the nuisance
Factor now a lot of that has changed uh
in a few years we've had uh more than
the majority of council change so a lot
of the folks that were really
anti-marijuana mostly are gone
um many of the council members have not
had to deal with the issue at all um so
I I think we actually have a more open
Council now also uh our council
president herb Wesson I think has helped
sort of take control of the issue and
he's trying to come up with something
reasonable uh he and I and another
council member ner Martinez led the
effort to put together a working group
to try and come up with answers um ultim
Ely uh uh we wound up not going with the
results of that working group but
deciding to have the rules committee
which uh council president Weston chairs
actually um make more of the decision on
where this goes so we're going to have
three major public hearings try to get
input that way um I think since the
working group we've gotten a lot of
input from folks in parts of the city
that don't have a lot of dispensaries um
we've got a lot of input from folks that
we want more women-owned dispensaries we
want more minority-owned
dispensaries um and hopefully more
dispensaries in general than the either
85 or 135 so I'm not sure which
direction this is going to go in but I'm
hopeful at the end we address all the
intuitive things that we should address
like cultivation like Transportation
like delivery um like having access
throughout the city and not just where
people perceive the most money to be
made or whatever um so there's an
overabundance in my district and there's
some areas that have virtually none so
we'll try to correct all those what we
do with the initiative I'm not entirely
sure because we may just have an
ordinance to deal with this or we may
put an initiative on the ballot um to
try and pass our vision rather than the
vision of a group that happened to put
it on the ballot um or we may pass an
ordinance before and then ask La voters
to turn down what's on the ballot
because we've already dealt with this
appropriately it's it's all all very
much up in the air uh but hopefully at
the end of the day we'll do the right
thing and and put uh the vagueness of
this issue to bed so there's basically
many directions that this could go in in
fixing measure D you have an initiative
that could be on the ballot in March in
a special election you may issue your
own to compete with that or you may just
try to come together and create create
your own ordinance and in theory I think
we can also adopt what's been proposed
so that we don't have to put it in the
ballot we can just agree with it and and
implement it so that's also technically
a possibility but I think there's some
issues that that that initiative doesn't
deal with and I think we'll want to try
and resolve everything all in one
shot thank you um what advice could you
give to our audience members that are
currently trying to Advocate their local
elected officials in order to persuade
them to regulate instead of banning this
industry I don't know I'm not sure uh
whether I had great results or not I
think most of the the worst things that
were proposed didn't happen only because
we saw legal threats in every wrong
direction that we looked as well as some
of the right ones um but I think
certainly in terms of medical marijuana
uh to the extent that you can
personalize it and there are people that
are still alive or being well treated um
because of medical marijuana people that
are dealing better with cancer people
that are dealing better with HIV and
AIDS and the host of of medical issues
that can be helped um I think that's the
most compelling uh I don't have anything
against proposition 64 but I I think the
uh the fact that people are actually
helped and and stay alive I think is the
most compelling argument in its favor
now there are some areas that are very
depressed economically and the fact that
there may be more jobs and more economic
activity uh may work in some areas that
uh that I'm not used to thinking about
um but I don't think that's the answer
certainly in the in the greater LA area
I think the the the strongest argument
is that it can help your constituents
stay alive stay healthier um and that's
certainly the argument that I use
because that's what I care about
myself thank you Paul
Janine Long Beach has a very convoluted
history with regulating marijuana just a
little bit can you talk a little bit
about the history of that sure um so
much of this I was kind of on the
sidelines watching and and like many in
Long Beach assuming that because we are
uh quote unquote Progressive City that
we would uh more easily be able to
regulate uh medicinal marijuana than
other cities but what we found is in
2010 uh we had uh my predecessor suja
lenthal along with other council members
decided that they wanted to move forward
uh with regulation and in 2010 they went
forward with a application process and I
have dates down just cuz I don't like
the pros are in the room so I don't want
to mess this up y these are like the
guys that have been doing this work so
you guys can correct me
okay
um in 2012 uh they actually we banned
medicinal marijuana because the city was
sued uh and at that time that lawsuit
went up to the California Supreme Court
and it was uh kicked down um denied and
so in 2012 what they did uh the industry
guys they went out and tried to put a
ballot measure together uh to adjust
this uh ban and they were shy 18
signatures 18 signat and so the city
council said obviously uh we are in a
city that supports uh regulation and so
they gave it to the Planning Commission
it went through a process we put
together a task force uh and in that
time we had uh elections and so we had a
turnover with some council members and I
believe and this was not what my
industry guys wanted me to say but
that's too bad uh I believe what
happened was that we had a shift in
culture uh from a a city that was saying
okay we wanted do the right thing uh and
trying to figure out the details and
trying to work with uh organized
industry trying to work with uh small
business owners to find out what was the
best model and I think this goes to what
uh council member caret is saying is
that you have intention to do good uh
but you don't know what the outcome is
going to be and in addition to what the
outcome is going to be you have to talk
about messaging and how we frame it and
so during that time of trying to come
back and say okay we want to go ahead as
a council and put together an ordinance
that wouldn't go on the ballot but that
the council would have the ability to
vote on the good thing about doing that
is that the council can then make
adjustments should there be a a negative
impact that you hadn't planned on the
council can then take another vote
adjust the ordinance uh and so that is
the the good thing about doing it uh
with the
council uh we have a a new council
member and a lot of frame around uh
Public Safety and that frame has kind of
gotten a wedge within our city council
where we felt like we were on the right
path we then have this conversation
about Public Safety that that has to be
number one it's no longer the
conversation changed from being about uh
medicinal purposes it changed from the
stories of you know Joey or Martha or
other people that would be impacted and
it changed to just about public safety
and this is why you guys in the industry
is so important to be able to come back
and give us uh facts like the fact that
the UCLA uh said
did a study a 5-year study where they
went outside of dispensaries and said
okay what what's crime happening and
what are the impacts of having
dispensaries in our neighborhood and
came back with no significant
correlation in crime increasing and so
we know whenever we regulate uh from
talking to you guys from making sure
we're working with industry um education
centers that when we do that together we
can have the facts that it has to be
about medicine and it has to be about
what's really happening on the ground
and taking away the fear taking away the
fear of what an impact might be to have
uh these shops in our neighborhoods and
so we tried to go through that process
we were I remember that night very
clearly we're at Council we thought we
had a vote uh on an ordinance that had
been worked on since 2010 you know going
back and forth with City attorney with
council with Mayors we thought we were
going to have a vote and unfortunately
there was a lot of opportunity to try to
as we talk about find that middle ground
and it's hard to find a middle ground on
something like medicine it's hard to
find a middle ground on something like
medicine that it's really the outcome
has to be the best interest of the
patients and the best interest of
residents uh and not you know pandering
to uh one uh type of of special interest
or another but it has to be on on that
basis and so we came down to trying to
get to that middle of the road and I'm
really proud of some of my colleagues
um who are now my colleagues um that
said you know what we're not going to go
down the middle path we're not going to
um you know say only delivery and no
shops we're not going to say only four
delivery services or only four shops and
we're not going to do that and I know
that that was a hard night but you know
essentially they threw their hands up
and said we we can't come to consensus
on what a good policy would be for our
city and so uh folks got together they
put uh they collected you know thousands
of signatures and now we have on the
ballot uh in November measure mm which
is regulating uh medicinal marijuana
allowing for shops to be Citywide also
regulating um grow and dispensaries and
Retail we're looking at somewhere
between 800,000 jobs and we're looking
at making sure that residents can have
access to their
medicine and they even it repeals the
old uh ban it repeals the old taxes and
it puts in place a new tax and for
retail it's like between 6 and
8% uh which you know personally we know
that that taxing medicine is it's a
little it's hard to do you know legally
there's some questions there but also
just in your gut should we be taxing
medicine whenever it's about making sure
people have uh access to that and so I
think the industry did a great job about
making this policy uh very
uh you know that has a longer distance
from schools
uh making sure that it's very highly
regulated for an industry to put this on
and so we have measure mm on the ballot
now uh that you know we know is going to
pass we just we need to make sure we do
all the work I'm committed to doing the
work with those guys um making sure that
that passes and what's been fascinating
is that the the district that has fought
the hardest against uh any kind of
conversation around marijuana is the
district that has the highest percent of
support and it's amazing what polls can
do you know it's amazing what polls can
do and so I think part of it is also
sharing that information and making sure
that that elected leaders know that
their constituents support things like
this instead of living in a bubble of
fear uh about what might be in addition
to measure mm the the mayor and the city
council put on uh another initiative uh
to tax uh medical and recreational at a
higher level should 64 and mm pass and
that happened really quick
you know it came to the floor really
quickly by the way anytime there's
marijuana on the agenda in Long Beach
it's kind of crazy it's a long night
there's a ton of people so I get just to
give you a little bit of information I
get sworn in and my first three Council
meetings all had marijuana on the agenda
every single one of them and it was you
know I'm all about jumping in feet first
and so one of them was the tax
initiative that we we put on the ballot
measure Ma and and it is tough because I
want to make sure that our city has the
resources that that we need when we have
a new industry coming in There's an
opportunity for new Revenue um and this
initiative now says that the city can
tax at higher rates so it can go 8 to 10
for medical or 10 to 12 for recreational
or adult use uh and so we get to come
back and have that debate again but I
think the challenge is how we have that
debate in and making sure it's rooted in
in facts and numbers and what the real
need is in our city is the need more
police officers if if crime is going
down whenever we regulate is the need
really more police officers or is the
need uh to spend those dollars in some
re-entry support uh for people that will
be coming out of jail or no longer uh
you know having a probation hit or
something like that so let's have a
fruitful conversation about what that
looks like uh where the real needs are
and this is again for industry to step
up and and and talk with us about what
those opport unities are but also
reaching out to unlikely allies to say
what is it what is your experience with
people coming out of the criminal
justice system and where are the most
need because we know the cities right
now are struggling with that and so we
want to support uh our residents we want
to make sure things are safe and I think
regulating is the best way to do that as
long as we're doing smart regulation and
we're doing it for the right reasons and
so yeah we have a little bit of a a you
know difficult background but I think
looking at what all the cities have done
we've had an opportunity to learn from
that and hopefully um you know move
forward in the in the right direction so
it does sound like you're moving forward
so thank you so much for your
work in the midst of what some of us in
the industry dubbed bana paloa in
January voted 0 to regulate the Cannabis
industry and shortly after that you
began talking about selling your
abandoned prison to a marijuana extract
company how did that convers ation
begin okay so I actually went through
minutes trying to figure this all out
cuz it's been 7 months or eight months
of this and it's got a little bit
convoluted so in our first meeting in
January we were brought with the
decision to regulator ban across the
board um all the different things
dispensaries cultivation personal
cultivation Delivery Systems that type
of thing and uh we voted 0 to go forward
with it because we had a crowd of people
that were there that were in
support and the very next meeting in I
believe it was in
February we had the darn near the exact
opposite the word had gotten out that we
had voted to do this and a crowd of the
exact opposite came and they held our
feet to the fire which I commend them
for doing so because it helped us in the
process we did not argue with them we
listened to them that was the most
important thing and for anyone looking
how to succeed in a city uh turning on
your listening ears and listening and
writing down what the fears are of the
people will help you gain uh some kind
of idea of what you can do to compromise
and life as a councilman and government
and local government is all about
compromise regardless of whether we like
that or not and so moving forward
our people told us all the issues that
they had with a dispensary because
that's what we were we were set to do
that's what our 50 vote was we were
going to allow a dispensary in the city
of Kinga that has about 15,000 people
and so we we listened to the medical
needs the compassion and then at the
second meeting we listened to the people
that said about their concerns with
crime we had three different agencies I
believe the college the school and the
parks and wreck all wrote resolutions
against what we were doing uh one guy
said that we were prostituting out our
town amazingly enough that was a hard
one to
take so um we had businesses come in and
said that they thought that this would
bring the wrong element of people to our
town
um we went forward knowing this
information and we held workshops we
held like two Workshops the first
Workshop was kind of a back and forth we
brought in um Mr Michael Green from the
fres uh Fresno cannabis club and he went
to town on Mera that was very
interesting that was like a hour
fixation on the law and amazingly enough
a lot of our residents that were against
this uh after they realized that the law
was in support of these angles their
mind started to turn a little bit like
hey hm it's not just a deal deal where
the federal government is against it and
you guys are going to try and operate
outside of federal law uh once we he
explained Mera things started to change
in people's minds but not you know it
wasn't like a night and day thing it was
kind of like you know we're listening
we're understanding and we're hearing
and we know that there's people we're
understanding that there's a medical
need but we're we still have security
concerns on our I think it's our March
30th meeting we had a company called
Ocean Grown extracts and they put an
offer in on the prison right then in
there well amazing yeah they they they
sent it in and it was on our close
session agenda and people were following
you know we went from having one or two
people at Council meetings to having it
full people said that they couldn't
trust us that's what they said we can't
trust you we're coming to council I was
like wow you know this is how we get
people to show up for the local
government I was kind of amazed at that
like maybe we're doing something right
here you know we want people to be
involved uh locally so we had that close
session agenda item and it was to sell
the prison but we have discussion at the
same time uh about the the marijuana
thing and we started to
reframe the idea into cannabis we
followed lead and rooll we council
members uh started doing some research
on this myself I started looking at you
know listening to the public actually to
be honest with you the public kept using
the word marijuana and they kept tying
all the bad things to what this word was
so I started watching and attending
meetings for other councils and Other
Board of Supervisors and I was listening
to the crowd and the people and they
were using the word
cannabis and that to me was a
GameChanger it was kind of like when
they used to call them drugstores and
now they call themes how they changed
yeah they nice little change right there
right so I started we started change
that narrative and change the narrative
into cannabis and at the time that that
the city of Kinga which I'll tell you
our city was primarily into the oil
industry Kinga had a nice oil boom and
we also had a very nice um prison
industry um and I say nice because it
provides it provided people with a lot
of jobs and there was a lot of people
like me that were against the prisons
when they came in were're saying hey you
want to talk about bringing the wrong
kind of people this is going to bring
the wrong kind of people and it
did and so when AB 109 passed and one of
the other propositions and it basically
said hey you got to dump these these
prisons a lot of them because you're
going to dump we're going to take people
and not put them into prisons for this
and uh when Arnold Schwarz neger wrote
his thing and basically decriminalized
major portion of marijuana um what
happened was is the states weren't
willing to renew contracts with a lot of
the prisons the city of Kinga had a
private prison it was called Claremont
custody Center and we staffed the prison
and we charged for bed space and when
the prison went down and we could no
longer do that uh that prison was
providing about a million dollars of
Revenue into our community now I know
that medical patients and medical people
don't want to hear about the revenue
portion of this but let me explain why
this is important for Kinga because we
had fiveyear period where we were losing
a million dollars a year and we had
citizens that had moved there that learn
to like police and fire like hey we need
these Services there's police officers
there when we need them and firemen and
ambulances take us to the hospital well
we're in a huge problem here is like 75%
of most General funds in small
communities go to police and fire when
you lose a million dollars you have two
choices you can either cut or you can
create Revenue well
me being in business myself I understand
population is a huge deal population
make uh in location you know those are
your two things when you look at factors
of creating a business well Kinga is not
in a very good location we're probably
12 miles from the I5 we are centrally
located but we're kind of like in this
desert oil kind of community which you
know if without a good population
doesn't make a lot of people want to
come there when they can go to places
like Hanford and Fresno that are larger
populations and sit closer to the to the
I5 the corridors and whatnot so we had
these two industries the oil industry
and the prison industry the prison
industry got taken away the drought came
across and hit us really really hard a
lot of our farming Community we lost
that and then the oil companies start to
pull out and so Council has given this
opportunity and saying hey what do we do
you know we're moving from the January
1st we're going to February we're going
to March March and the narrative had to
change at some point in time because we
weren't going anywhere with the battle
back and forth with medical marijuana we
may have gained a couple percentage of
people who said yes this is a good idea
and we didn't think so beforehand
because they watched the videos of the
kids seizing and and having a change
they watched the videos of PBS putting
on saying that cancer cells can be
killed with THC you know we put the pl
the plaster County video out there to
help you know get some people but that
wasn't the GameChanger the game Cher was
when you when you tell people we can
provide opportunity opportunity in
growth in the economy to fill a void
what that was that was left behind by
other business that's when I'm not
kidding I seen the look on the people's
faces and they were like you know we
need need jobs and so you hold on you're
not talking about bringing a dispensary
to town so that's when it changed when
we stopped talking about bringing a
dispensary and Ocean Grown start talking
about purchasing our prison now I know
that a lot of people may not agree with
those that tactic and think to
themselves well that doesn't provide the
the need for the patient but we were
trying to look at an overall and if we
can get a company to come in that's
going to make medicine that's a step in
the door that's a a foot in the right
direction and then you know so that's
where we that's where we are we sold the
prison uh $4.1 million uh that should
take care of our initial uh in debt so
the city of Kingo will be out of debt
and then after well in doing that
process we had to create an ordinance
well the way that we wanted to create
the ordinance uh we had a lot of back
and forth on and so what we wanted to do
is we wanted to get them in business in
a in a quick amount of time because of
our financial needs like we had
suggested going to calfire to get rid of
our fire department not because we
wanted to but because we couldn't afford
it and we found out it was going to be
more expensive and so you know we really
have a big Financial draw of eight of
negative $800,000 a year that we are
negative in the whole that led up to
that 4 I mean that $3.6 million deficit
and so the financial goal was first and
I'm sorry to say that to everybody but
that was the truth you know Financial
goal was first but it doesn't stop the
rest of the agenda which is getting the
people the medicine and changing the
outcome of how cannabis affects
everybody in this room and everyone that
could be having the Cannabis to be used
as medicine so when we create our
ordinance we did an interm or an urgency
ordinance that urgency ordinance allowed
for everyone that was in that zone which
I think it was light manufacturing
industrial to be able to participate we
had a couple different places that were
close to close to school so we put in
the ordinance that had to be 1,800 ft
away from a school we our ordinance is a
little bit more stringent than Mera uh
and the reason was is because our
citizens required that in order to to
move forward and we thought that that
would be prudent to do that and then
when we're talking to the industry folks
they wanted protection from law
enforcement and our city seem to be a
very unique opportunity where you still
hear of counties getting raided today
because you have multiple Sheriff
agencies you have multiple federal
agencies teaming up with Sheriff
agencies that are going around and
they're picking off the people in the
counties even if you have a big if you
have a big County and has multiple
Sheriff operations one might not talk to
the other and then they go and they they
hit that type of thing so Kinga we're
trying to create a safe place with
regulation and whatnot and I think that
there's going to be a lot of opportunity
in the Central Valley for that type of
thing and we opened up this new area
that we've I think we're going to
probably have five or 10 companies come
in and uh there's still opportunity for
anyone that's in this industry you know
I think the Central Valley would be a
great place for you guys to come and I
want to thank everyone here for giving
us your ideas thank you very much thank
you
Nathan Don you currently have an interim
ordinance in place allowing one acre of
outdoor cultivation what are some of the
pitfalls you are facing as a regulator
in implementing this
ordinance I think some I'd like to talk
about some of the challenges that we're
grappling with but first I just want to
congratulate Nathan what they've done is
they've they've taken a prison that used
to house pot offenders and people who
were Brown and Brock people who were
captured as a part of this criminal
mentality that that prohibition has
created and they've sold it to to help
their city and to produce medicinal
cannabis that's just that's incredible
and this is one of the Delights is of
attending conference like this is to
learn from from each other so I I really
appreciate that so our ordinance is a we
we wanted to we're seeing this through
largely the lens of Agriculture and
those other lenses that you can look at
uh the current state of cannabis through
medicinal what's happening for patients
how do we get the best e efficacy for
the for the for the medicine or we can
look at it as revenue or we can look at
it as public safety and social justice
all these issues we're one of the
because we're an agricultural County and
what our County government deals with is
unincorporated areas outside the cities
outside the built areas the industrial
areas and Commercial spaces are all in
the incorporated city so we're dealing
with outdoor with with I heard the
phrase the other day Su grown or outdoor
grow areas so we're dealing with with
agricultural settings and we're dealing
with a lot of lack of information
misunderstandings among
ourselves uh and and certainly among the
communities that that uh that we're that
we're working with we're also dealing
with people who have in many cases have
been growing in the in the fields and
hills and forests for some time and are
interacting with their neighbors on a
regular basis and have found already
some some peace and ways of ways of
dealing so some of the so our the
ordinance has a, ft away from any uh
school or sensitive such such such kind
of sensitive area where children are are
likely to congregate so thousand feet
away and then we have in order to
address the the most common concerns
that we knew about of odor and noise and
Light we have a 75 ft from any grow site
to any uh structure that's occupied on a
neighboring property so it's very simple
kinds of conditions that that go into
effect now since it's an interim
ordinance we're taking the time now to
go and talk with each of the communities
so we've had Town Hall meetings in
several places and we hear it's very
interesting because the the fears as
Nathan mentioned you hear the fears from
people but often times in the same
comment
before they even take a breath to change
to another sentence someone will say I'm
against this I don't like this at all
and how do I get into the business and
it's it's so we're see we're hearing
that kind of of mindset changing even
while we while we're talking to folks so
some of the challenges that we've got As
in in agriculture we want to make sure
that we're dealing with water quality
issues that we're that we're providing
the best advice and the and the most and
the safest regulation framework for
pesticide applications so those are two
very importants that's an agricultural
commodity and our agricultural
commissioner is very is is very involved
in this he's the he's our our thought
leader in our County government and he's
also the the glue the connector between
our County regulatory apparatus the
Board of Supervisors the planning people
the environmental health people and the
grower community and so John John Young
is is the gentleman's name he's he's
been out listening to everybody and then
he takes their their views and he's
starting to he's doing something you
don't see in government hardly ever he's
sharing uh interim drafts or or draft
ordinance language he says okay you're
concerned about residency so here's what
it would look like if we put residency
language in the permanent ordinance now
residency is a very weird and
interesting thing that where where some
people would say well we don't want
Outsiders to come into our little County
and buy up all the property because
they're going to put these massive
speculative pressures on the property
prices and that's going to price out the
organic farmers who are raising foods
for our community supported agriculture
and so on so we've got that's a real
issue for us so people are talking about
ways of addressing it residency comes up
as as one of them another is that in
order to achieve these uh the the
buffers that we're talking about in some
cases you have to have a certain creates
a de facto minimum size for a for a
property parcel well that's an effect on
some folks who have smaller properties
and would like to be involved in legal
cultivation and getting a permit so
there so there are dynamics that go that
way as well so we're asking we ask
people questions is an acre two large is
it too small is it just right for a
commercial grow and the answers that are
coming back are are it's not consistent
it's was like well 30% think it's too
large 30% think it's too small and 30%
think it's just right so we are
threading the needle and we will be will
be threading that needle I think that um
so those are some of the implementation
issues that we'll be dealing with oh
there's another there's one one last one
that I want to raise on this in this
topic and that is that we have uh
different sort of uh areas or sub
regions within the county and everybody
always feels like well my neighborhood's
getting targeted for x or y whatever the
thing that's going to be so we have uh
we Yolo County our agricultural economy
is very diverse we have large scale
production agriculture with tens of
thousands of acres under cultivation and
very few people working and we have very
small farms 20 100 acres where they're
where they're very labor intensive in
producing organic crops for farmers
markets and so on there's no reason to
think that that cannabis can't exist in
that same with that same sort of
analogous situation where you have small
Growers
larger Growers some are growing for
different kinds of markets I think
that's actually kind of exciting to me
to think how that might all work out uh
we but as we think about it and we think
about how that lands in individual
neighborhoods some of the folks are
interested in making sure that that the
cultivators are dispersed throughout the
county that it's not all in one location
others are talking about well maybe if
it was if we had more cultivators in a
certain location certain area then we
could provide for greater Safety and
Security for all
concerned that's and I I said that was
the last one but there is one more and
that's the the vagueness of the
interaction among the various legal
Frameworks that we're dealing with you
all know that more you know a lot better
than I do but we for the first time with
the Mera the state has given us a
framework that we can work with we we
were we were as lost local government
was as as was as lost and stalemated as
as the industry we couldn't figure out
what to do if anything and so we
basically all stayed out of it most of
us did or a lot of us did anyway so now
we've got a framework that we can make
some sense of but there's still so much
vagueness between what's at the federal
level what's used to be the state law
what will be the state framework so
we're just trying to navigate to thread
a needle on all this and make some sense
of
it you are trying to make sense of it
and um you know the title of this panel
is called cities counties and bands omai
we're about to get to the omai part
right now um just 12 days ago on
September 14th at 7:00 a.m. in the
morning a simultaneous raid occurred in
yellow County as well as uh three of the
homes of the Farmers on one of these
licensed facilities um by an outof count
taskforce called Tri County drug
enforcement team or Trident which is an
initiative of the Central Valley High
intens drug trafficking area or hi haa
um they came into Yolo County with a
plaster County warrant um and kicked
doors in and um and took down a half
acre of a legally licensed farm so don
can you tell us how you feel about an
outer jurisdiction law enforcement
agency coming in and taking down
something that you permitted and gave
your blessing
for so I said that there were about 50 3
Growers that are going through the
permitting process about half of them
are are in place and one in
particular has a couple of them have
been really shining stars they they look
at us and they they look for guidance
they want whatever we tell them this is
how things will work they immediately
comply uh they bring in they they set up
the irrigation system set up the
drainage they make sure that they're
doing all the right things uh they apply
for the state for the regional water
quality control board permits they get
all of it in place and then then
something like this happens and this I
know that many of you here in this room
have heard this story or even had it
happen to yourself or to somebody you
know but it's pretty darn scary when you
think of of U 7 in the morning your
front the front door is broken in nobody
says I'm you know this is a I'm a law
enforcement official open your door
please they break the door in uh they
show up in unmarked vehicles and four
different locations in three different
counties uh with guns drawn where their
little kids involved and they handcuff
people and put zip ties on them and they
throwing uh throwing people against
walls and against and they're making
them kneel on the ground and they're
interrogating them without giving them
mirander rights for hours out a time
this is this is a a terrorist activity
if you think about it if you just think
about what's what's
happening and
and and the same and then the meaning of
terrorism what this means is they're
trying to in to instill fear they the
the tactics deliberately instill fear
and there and it comes at a time for us
when we're we're walking to monitor our
ordinance and we're working to develop
tweaks things that we might want to
change and we now have this added
dimension of well what was the offense
was there something that's being alleged
that is illegal that we didn't know
about or that and we're not hearing any
specific charges even in fact none of
the people involved in this incident
have been charged with anything and yet
1,800 plants that are that are designed
and and connected to a collective for
for medicinal purpose have been
destroyed and the people involved are
very shaken so psychologically shaken
they thought they were doing all the
right stuff they're deliberately working
hard to make sure they do the right
thing and then so we're we're still
sorting this out and to have this be
done from a this shadowy group that
comes in unmarked cars with no license
plate indication and and from another
County from another County it's not even
Yolo County we're not part of this three
County it's El Dorado pler and
Sacramento I mean led by led by pler
County district attorney and his Strike
Force but we we we are still struggling
to figure out exactly what this was
about and how it affects uh the people
involved and I know that the people
involved are are very stunned so I think
of it as as an act of
terrorism so don you just called this an
act of terrorism um by Trident and I'm
wondering uh do you believe that this
will hinder your progress as your county
is is making very big strides in
crafting sensible regulations well I
think that that it it sets it it's it
sets up a whole series of questions that
we we have been working to look at the
whole cannabis World Through The Eyes of
of Agriculture and how does this
commodity work how do we how do we
support it in the same ways that we've
supported other agricultural Commodities
how do we regulate it and so on we're
looking at it and by the way we have not
talked about revenues we haven't looked
at at this from a taxation purpose we're
charging fees that we think will will
will absorb the cost and allow us to do
some code enforcement for the the non
for The shadowy Operators so that's
that's what we're kind of looking at and
it and it we've also been looking at
more and more the medicinal value and
I'm excited because I want to see us all
look into the greater research
possibilities and I want Yolo County to
be a place where that is where that's a
a center of that kind of activity but
now we have a whole other series of
questions that we know will be asked by
by my by well by members of the Board of
Supervisors well really was there
something going on here is there
something in the shadows that we need to
shy away from so I think that to the
degree that we allow that to that U that
that fear to come from our community
members or from our from the the
decision makers to the degree that we
allow that to change our course then
then the terror has succeeded so I think
there is there is going to be some
discussion about that and by the way I
just I I did to say this is how I feel
about it now there's we're assured that
this investig this is an interesting
comment here because we're assured that
the investigation is still
underway now that that means you know
it's not over so there's something yet
to happen there's some this great
Spectre of maybe there's some illegal
act that we don't know about yet so we
can't I probably shouldn't even talk
about it right we've seen the affid I've
seen the the affidavit doesn't look like
it's criminal what they're talking
about but now we have this this Spectre
as that's that's going to it's going
certainly going to change the
conversation to some degree I don't know
how or when I got the call about this
raid uh it was a farm that I had helped
consult Sultan and uh you know I I
really have to say Yolo County uh
Regulators Rose to the the occasion and
they got on the phone and the a
department got a hold of this lead
Detective from this outside County task
force and said please stop chopping down
these plants this is a licensed farm and
that that coded or that uh lead
detective said whatever AG guy and hung
up the phone on him so uh these people
really did rise up to try to protect
that farm um and I'm just so proud of
them so please give it up for you KOLO
Counting