[Music]
Susan you want to take over with some
questions hi my name is Paul bregman and
I'm a physician Colorado consultant for
medicine women my question is as you
develop policy I think it's important to
think about education mandating
education for the bud tenders and also
the f phes the cons the dispensaries
because those are the and I just like to
get your impression about that because I
think that would go a long way to
furthering the Cannabis cause in the
communities anyone want to take that
Janine hello okay uh I absolutely agree
I think one of the positive things about
regulating is the opportunity to do
education both with uh The Growers with
the retail uh and with consumers and so
uh here in Long Beach what um we are
doing is we're making sure that these
jobs are also good jobs and we're
working with UFCW to do that and with
that I think comes a level of
professionalism where we can say here's
an opportunity to go through some uh
training some uh professional
development with the doctors with the
Growers again with retail uh that this
is the opportunity about having it be
public because we get to talk publicly
about not only from a professional point
but from a consumer Point uh for many
years I volunteered at LAPD I was on the
board of directors of several
nonprofits and one day they came to us
with a proposal they wanted us to buy
them equipment to bust the Cannabis
Growers uh I voiced my strong opposition
and we had a long debate about it and I
said you know it it's legal now and they
said well it's legal to sell but it's
illegal to grow so my response was okay
you bust the local Growers now the drug
cartels are going to come in and they're
going to take up the market share the
demand isn't going to go away so and as
you know councilman carretes we we have
overcrowded prisons we have people going
in for violent offenses and they're
getting out early because our prisons
are overcrowded now what they seem to be
doing is that they're following these
Growers on the way to the dispensaries
uh and busting them for possession and
they get a felony record for something
that shouldn't be a felony and I'm
wondering how we can work with our local
law enforcement and kind of just uh curb
this I mean these people are coming to
me because they have mold fungus yeast
algae you know and I'm trying to help
them make a pharmaceutical product but
they're scared to come out with what
they're doing and they're scared to ask
for
help well I I think it's difficult in
Los Angeles because we have laws on the
books right now that make it illegal so
it's difficult as a council that hasn't
come up with any consensus on how to
change it to say hey stop enforcing I
mean if if it was my call personally uh
we would do that but I'm one council
member in Los Angeles one council member
really can't do anything it has to be a
majority of the council and I just don't
think we're there yet I think our our
only real step is to try and do this as
quickly as we can and come up with a
process whereby it's legal to grow
within the city and it's legal to
transport within the city and we have
some control over how it's grown so we
don't have a lot of pesticide use and
all the all the right steps
and then just do it I think in between
um I'm not sure I have any other good
advice other than don't get
caught be
careful the uh ordinance that we gave
the city in Los Angeles includes um
manufacturers uh Standalone cultivation
edible makers because we want to be
included in the umbrella that Mera
created we want those cultivators that
have been and edible makers and
manufacturer that are illegally
producing right now just because the way
the law is set up be able to uh step up
to a permit so that they don't get
busted so hopefully they'll pay
attention and we'll do an ordinance that
you know does all that for everybody yes
my name is Laura clavan and I'm an
attorney and my question is this
especially to Mr Taylor from the the
county of YOLO uh there's a are you
aware of the new case that just came
down it came down August 16
2016 on the case of us mckintosh where
the Department of Justice is being
prohibited from process Prosecuting uh
entities cultivators dispensaries and
people who transport as long as they're
doing it within the uh legal permits and
legally uh it's TI to in Appropriations
bill by Congress that is supposed to end
September 30th 2016 but there's some
changes taking place that are going to
put a stop to some of those
rates I'm not aware of that case but I'm
excited to hear about it and the the
challenge in this case and I think many
others the example that I'm talking
about is that there was there's no
charge file there's no court proceeding
there's no due process and the property
of the of the farmer was confiscated and
the D so I it's a it really is is
something if you all have suggestions
about how to deal with this kind
of it seems like Rogue law enforcement
activity to to me on the until I hear
something more that's the way I'm
thinking about it
so even even what you're talking about
we're not even talking prosecution I'm
here to I'm speaking about this because
I know that many of many of the people
involved in this in this industry in
doing this work are very familiar with
this but you might not have heard uh
somebody from who's not a grower and not
a user and I don't have the story the
personal narratives that that many of
you bring uh but it's shocking
I'm a grower from Northern California
and I just kind of wanted to put a
northern California tinge on this
because we have Central and Southern
California what I want to say is
marijuana law in oh excuse me cannabis
law that's a very important distinction
cannabis law in most of California is
based on nuisance law and if you're
familiar with nuisance law it's driven
by a complaint there is not a search
warrant that's needed it's only a
neighbor's complaint and you are never
knowing who that complainer was likewise
you don't get a day in court you don't
get an appeal it can be cut down
immediately right in front of your eyes
and in addition to that they charge you
for coming to do that and the police
force keeps the money this is police
busting you for profit and this happens
all over the place in Menino County and
humo County I know of at least 150
personal issues that I've talked to
people in the last couple of years this
still goes on children are are
absolutely abducted from their families
out of their mother's arm calm down calm
down I really don't have a question I
just wanted to make sure that everyone
here knows that this is going on up
north and I'm I'm applauding you I'm
applauding all of you for being
Progressive mesino county is still stuck
in nuisance ordinance and I wish all of
you would call our supervisors in mesino
county and point out the reality of jobs
of money of patients and also of we want
the farmers want to work with the
regulators and they don't seem to want
to work with us in Menino County that's
my
question okay this is our last
question I got it okay hello my name is
Dr Maria Teresa ferer
Rosen I was a pain specialist for 40
years at UCLA Medical Center I was a
professor and I started the first pain
center at UCLA way back in
1974 I know I don't look that old um but
anyway some of you weren't born
yet however I followed W the what you
call the W guideline for uh treating
pain with opioids at the top and we
didn't have cannabinoid uh I retired 14
years ago happy traveling around and all
of a sudden about 6 months ago I started
reading about medical cannabinoids and I
resurrected my license because I said I
need to help
people because this is a gift from God
it's an
herb I would like to ask a question
please because I'm going to open my own
Clinic I'm deciding which county I'm
going to go to and it seems like each
county has their own different
ordinances ordinances that seem to be
different one County to another I'd like
to start it in a friendly place that's
not going to close me down okay that's
you Jackie is that a question to me who
is regulating at the moment is that what
you want to know I have it all in my
head I'm obsessed I will talk to you
after this um I I I can certainly give
you my own advice my advice would be La
could be friendly but we're not there
yet so if you're thinking about going
into La I'd wait to see what our
regulations are that we implement but
it's actually what I want to close with
um you know I was talking to Amanda
Raymond before I got up here and she
gave me a really great quote she said
politicians have a feeling about
marijuana they know what that feeling is
what they don't have a feeling about is
us you you have to create these
relationships with these people I was
able to call YOLO um supervisor Don
sailor when I got the call about the
raid and write on the phone to get him
involved because I have that
relationship you know um we cannot
expect our Regulators to make sensible
regulations if they don't know what we
need and um it's really hard for these
people sitting up here to vote against
us if we have a relationship with them
we've communicated with them what our
needs are so um get involved in
progressing the conversation about
regulations with your local elected
officials do not wait for anyone to do
that for you um and I'm going to close
with with my favorite uh quote and I I I
don't know who came up with this but if
you are not at the table you are on the
[Music]
menu that's it guys
he