all right so mr toad
just sent uh a whole bunch of seed packs
down
and we got some more here
and then i realized that he sent a bone
clone
shipper and then i realized that there's
actually a
i thought it was just a an
empty one but i realized that there's
actually a uh
a clone inside so this came down from
norcal to socal let's see
how well it did
okay
so here we go
okay look through there and tell me if
am i on camera yeah
okay so this is the
outer seal
this is a rugged device
gemma is my camerawoman
gemma you want to pack some more seeds
later today
yeah amazing okay so what do you think's
inside here a plant
how did you know because you told me
yeah okay
okay so this plant just traveled in the
mail
do you think it's still alive okay ready
get on the other side you got to watch
to make sure we can see it
okay ready yeah one three two one
go it's still a lot it's a cute little
baby
it's still alive it is still alive
what is that cherry pie that's the name
of the plant oh but it's probably cherry
is it cherry well it's called cherry pie
so where are we gonna put it
eventually we'll put it outside
it does that's shocking okay we're gonna
put it right over here
is the camera facing the plant no
all right and there
is a happy emma would you stop sticking
your finger in my butt
but it's sticky now okay can you hold
this okay hey hey can you hold this
and aim it at the plant right there okay
so i'm gonna take this collar off
okay let's lift it uh
there's some tape here some scotch tape
i have no fingernails there we go
we're gonna take the scotch tape off
how's our camera are we being steady
with the camera
yeah okay that's good
oh jesus it made it the whole way and
then i
snapped it in half oh my god that's
it's nice and moist underneath oh good
how long did it take to get here uh
probably two days
well that's moist and then look at this
see those little lights in there
can you see the lights let me see
yes so those lights give it just a
little bit of light
and now we're gonna stick it there for a
little bit
and then we're gonna bring it outside
right to the garden
say that's our lesson for today
everybody