[Music]
how's it going welcome to the oa farm
just want to show you guys a couple tips
on how to use some of our products for
uh cloning
if you want to come over here we're
going to just take a snip usually i like
to just kind of look at
look around you can see we've taken a
couple off the top here and
oh this is a nice one here so look at
that
gauge it cut it about right there let
that go
it's kind of like how i like to do my
clones not too big not too small
easy i take that first clip
right on that 45 a couple clones there
and snip off the top now there's a lot
of
a lot of i don't know what you'd call it
science or different ways of cloning
so this is our way and we snip off the
top we've been doing it for years
it's kind of ocd i know there's some
science behind it
some transpiration but uh that's kind of
how we like it nice and clean
easy and we do is if you're using the
microbial solution
we like to do is we'd like to do a brew
this is a four gallon brew pack
we'll do a brew for 24 hours and check
out the website
for the those videos and what we'll do
is actually take the whole clone
and we'll dump it right in the entire
brew and just give her a nice bath
all the cuts you've just made
get some biology some beneficial biology
in those what we'll do is we'll actually
take a tip
dip it in fpf at one milliliter per
gallon
we go straight into the router now any
router is fine for you guys doesn't
doesn't matter whatever works for you
again i know there's a lot of different
ways just kind of some tips we like to
do
and then we actually take make sure we
don't go all the way through we're kind
of
almost to the end there we like to give
her a little bit of room and then we dip
it straight into the biological solution
here
there we go she finds a nice home so
easy
though if you like to more questions
feel free to dm us go to the website
info organicslivegarden.com or on the
contacts page of
www.organixxlivegarden.com thanks a lot
[Music]
guys
you