foreign
[Music]
welcome back to Heart Rock Mountain Farm
here we are in our
mail Garden
and we've only planted
one two three four five
four and a few rows of
what has had
13 or 14 rows planted and they're deep
rows I mean each each row has 13 or 14
holes in there but it's kind of nice
having a small relaxing Nail Garden this
year and we're kind of tucked away in
here
um
and you know behind us is a big cattle
ranch in the National Forest
so the wind currents
take any stray pollen
far away from here
and
this is where we'll do our final
selection usually I only will flower out
you know no more than 10 males per
variety and that's just something if I'm
really trying to narrow something down
and I've you know I've already selected
for a structure and nose and now we get
to look at you know the bud structure
and we get these uh bouquet up and into
our pollen boxes
and then I'll make my final
I make my final notes
on
the cultivars
here we have our love laughter
and
I noticed that this one has the more
sweet Fino versus like the eucalyptus
Pine
so and I really like
the Strong Nose on this one
so I'll go ahead and give this one a
star
and
let myself my future self know later
that this was a sweet
you know
and then we upgraded the hanging tags
this year
because every year you'd always lose a
tag in the mail guard and be like okay
whoops
so the hanging tags is a good way to go
and
we drop that in
our jar of water
Falco number two brand brand new one
because I lost mine hiking
here we go
you can prune away extra leaves
and then we will end up with a
nice little bouquet
of male flowers
so when you're done there did you just
kill it off
yeah
um
yeah I really don't need it's our
CBD one I really don't need a lot of
pollen from
from that
although we I think
people always always hit me up in the
past to buy pollen and it's just so much
work to collect it that it's not worth
it but might be a
a good year to do it
and then this male is the um
eucalyptus pheno
of the love laughter
and I definitely
running low on level after seeds and
hope to do
a couple generations of work here with
them
you know it's kind of like you're taking
uh a cutting a very long cutting
um
and this method you know we just kind of
develop this out of
necessity
you know growing from keeping
less than a dozen males to 25 males to
75 males to our biggest year which I
believe was a we had 150
varieties of males
in the main Farm
did not get seated
but I was I spent a lot of nights that
year
up to two or three in the morning
you know working on processing pollen
and you know spraying down the garden
afterwards
and how much pollen can you collect from
a bouquet like this
a couple grams
which is a lot of pollen
you know if you were to like cut it
enough to make like tens of thousands if
not hundreds of thousands of seeds
especially uh
in the pollen boxes
they just
and it's a way that you know you can do
this on a smaller scale to really get a
lot of Pawn and a lot of diversity you
know because we're collecting pollen and
we're breeding Outdoors you know we're
not breathing in indoor under lights or
in you know greenhouses or anything
and that's probably enough pollen from
that one
and then
I like to
very slowly bend the rest of the mail
over to the ground
and cut it and then I'll come through
and
you know
spray this pollen off because if I were
to let this mail just dry here on the
ground and the wind could come pick it
up and take it off you know the the key
of the game is to get the the males just
as they're opening into the pollen
but we're kind of in a unique
environment for location to do this type
of you know outdoor pollen collection
that is not recommended for
um
everyone to do it this way
but the pollen boxes we're gonna go
walk these two love laughter meals
upstairs
and show you the Palm boxes
you know someday I love that little
cot Barn for pollen collection
foreign
when you're doing pollen collection you
need water and a spray bottle so I will
Mist off my arms and hands after there
and if I were to go out into the main
Farm
and I didn't I would definitely prefer
to change clothes but you could just you
know Mist your whole body off to kill
the pollen so then we're going to take a
look at these pollen boxes here
um
my first prototype was a cardboard box
but you know after a season of cleaning
them in between these use they were done
for in the wardrobe boxes were pretty
expensive
and what I did with the Wardrobe boxes I
would pre-slit the sides tape them back
up had an extra square of cardboard at
the bottom for the plate but this is
much better
um
technique so we have a sliding drawer at
the bottom with a Plexiglas sheet
okay
and they're numbered
this one here is 33
um
and then they'll sit in the in the jar
of water there for
a couple days a week sometimes if I
don't have a lot of males to move
through I'll let them just get
completely dry let them suck up all the
water and sometimes if you'll notice a
meal will be really thirsty and it
hasn't dropped its poll in it you might
have to refill that jar of water a
couple times you can do a light nutrient
solution
um in the your jar of water to give them
a little extra but and this room's well
lit which which is helpful
um I've I've haven't tried
maybe David would um Silver Dragon Farm
but he he adopted this Tech I think he
does it in the dark and then we have a
lid
with a hole in the middle and we stir up
some pollen which
we'll show you later
this isn't nice
looking man so this is
you zoom in on the flowers here this is
like the ideal time to cut a male like
there's
per bud you see like one pollen sack
opening if you were concerned about it
you you wouldn't let one open you would
let it get Chunky
start to open cut it jar it
and in a may like that you might need to
refill the jar a couple times for the
nutrient solution to finish but you know
they will
drop pollen in a jar of water
and what India if you don't you don't
need a box
you can just put that jar of water over
you know parchment paper on the counter
you know in one mail and you know it's
moving around your house make sure
they're not getting wind
and you can collect pollen
Lemonhead F3
this is that Tahoe Kim from Willits that
my my buddy made this is a really nice
one and
at least the F1 really hard to collect
pollen from which is interesting a lot
of times the male buds match the female
buds not the case
with that F1 where it had nice you know
chunky
dense buds a very sparse pollen but this
F3 now that's that's going to get some
pollen
and
you know we're hitting about three
percent terpenes in our no-till living
soil with it you know 25 to 30 percent
total cannaboids mostly THC
nice relaxing Indica body high
actually you know for me it was nice
because it wasn't like psychoactive a
lot of conscious is so psychoactive for
me it's not a relaxing body high but
this one lemon head was really nice and
relaxing and actually looking forward to
smoking some of the fresh stuff
I mean are you filming yeah this right
here look this is so and you get like
look at the structure like this is out
of all the Lemonhead males we're keeping
which is
you know maybe 10 of them because I have
different lines like this is a beautiful
bud
and that's one thing you really want to
look for that's why you want to keep
more than one male per variety so you
can see them flower you can see their
full expression and then this is a
gorgeous male flower
and um
yeah
they're edible too
and it's a a very light stimulant
come on
oh yeah that is
a beautiful bouquet of
lemon head flowers
you wanna try
it's like the newest delicacy
again in between males
you know you just miss yourself off
your tools
that way you're reducing cross
pollination which you know will happen
you know in a on a craft Farm like this
like it's really easy to tell when you
see when you get a purple plant where
you shouldn't have one but it's usually
just you know one pollen grain either
making it in the field or collecting it
in the field
I mean you definitely gotta um
you got to look for Herms in your males
I find keeping large populations of
males
the past couple years I find more
hermaphrodites in the mail Garden than
you do in your in the females
and it they're sneaky and just some
hairs on this that's really one good
thing to look out for
and
you know you can see
which ones are having more or less pest
damage it's always good to take notes on
but definitely look out for
hermaphrodites in your males almost more
than your females from my experience and
because you're if you if you keep that
pollen
yeah it'll have that that trait
um you know we don't want to breed
purposefully for intersex
and the main reason I strip away the
leaves is
you just fit more
bouquets more stems in the jar that way
but when I go to dump these out of the
jar like it's molded and rotted out in
the jar
by the time if I let them go long enough
and um
yeah and as you you know sometimes
you'll find that little sneaky
hermaphrodite as you're like harvesting
the mail so it's definitely good
to pay attention to
um
and it's something that I've just
discovered keeping large populations of
males I haven't come across any this
year
and that's another reason to keep
more than one male per variety
there's always a bump because and
sometimes the pollen
you know doesn't keep collect
and with the onset of the hemp aphids
it's even good to spray your male Garden
your male plants because too many aphids
can ruin the pollen
in your collection boxes
and so just like an uh just a soap is
good enough preventative to
uh knock back the aphids
because they will destroy trays of
pollen
just
what do they do in the pollen
um
you know maybe it's like they're
shedding actually it just cakes it up
and it it uh and maybe they're like
excretion
you see we do have like a light wind
blowing this way so I also see which way
the wind's blowing and kind of do my
Harvest that day
but I think with the empty boxes we have
upstairs we're going to be able to clear
out the majority of this mail Garden
today
all right we'll run these up
put a little palm box because we just
want to prevent the wind from hitting
these even a slight breeze so that when
the pollen drop it just falls to the
bottom
of the box
when I take the Mayo flowers out of the
pollen box this is I dip them in water
so it's like
definitely a Dom
and bubbling up real quick I just filled
this up last night
and see this this area here
doesn't get harvested it's a crossover
branch
and anything that's touched
thank God pollen's not in metric that
you know imagine having to track and
Trace there wouldn't have been the way
and there's really no
you know psychoactive use for pollen
this is like basically hemp
what do you mean me and Max have been
smoking these
huh we've been smoking this
the males yeah just for fun yeah is it
working
just kidding okay
well someone someone told me that
they've smoked pollen on Instagram
now I already harvested the Lemonhead
Skittles males so these are all just
different Lemonheads so this is that was
three different seed lots of
lemon head f3s
you know and it's also important to take
your seed Lots down different lines
because you might it's a it's a lot of
work to take a a line down the road
and if you go different Forks you have
more of a chance of that if you made a
mistake with one you didn't make it with
the other
and then when you get several lines
way down the road to like your f8
generation
then you can cross those with each other
and and easily exchange traits
you know like oh this one's got the nose
and the smell but this one has the pest
resistance
so you cross them together
and that's uh that new
and can transfer those traits
welcome to dude Bros Farms
foreign
so now
we have a male bouquet that's been our
pollen boxes for several days and this
one actually the the flowers are
starting to dry and we have this high
tech
device here and we have a Plexiglas lid
and we're gonna shake this baby up and
send that pollen down
to our plexiglass sheet in the bottom
are you ready
oh yeah he's a duster
and we'll give it a few minutes
to settle
d
the boys sterilizing your instruments in
between use now we're gonna remove this
old bouquet here
take it over to our disposal tub
which you know if you're into the
natural farming you know this is just
your Dom here
and I'm gonna Mist it as I put it in
there because there's pollen on the jar
give a little rinse
let's see and I was right that was a
coffee seed bun those coffees just dump
pulling
and then um this coffee F6 seed Lot B
now we're gonna remove our tray very
carefully always taking a take a big
breath in and hold it
that is Kate
and before I touch anything I get out my
jar
get out
silica packet don't skimp on your silica
packets you know
make sure you get a good one because
that's going to protect your pollen
and your Harvest and prevent it from
caking if it's not quite dry
coffee F6 c-line
B
and then
and you know the reason some people use
like a would run this through a sift
I just use a couple cards so very
carefully remove the plant material
um
just because they're easy to clean and
dry in between uses because you know
I'll do 10 boxes in a row or 15 boxes in
a row and
uh
so I'm just very light pressure here
in my hand
and it's just removing the plant
material
now I'll bring the plant material over
the area that I scrape
and this is a lot of Pawn
and yeah I mean if you wanted to you
could run this material through a sieve
but I mean this is going to be more than
more pollen than you're going to need
or you could even take this material put
it into
a bag or a pollen
sleeve and put that around a plant and
use that dry material that we're
scraping off the table there to make a
branch of seeds
I know I've seen some people do that
Tech I know forest with sunroots uses
that Tech
but they put the bag over the plant
it's definitely a safe way
to make seeds in your flower garden
and then I usually store this pollen
you know in a cool dry dark room
why I'm using it for the pollination
season and then I put it into single use
jars and into the freezer
um
for long-term use
pollen's only viable for about 20
minutes after it thaws
also if your plant material was totally
dry
you wouldn't need to separate it
from your pollen
you know just in case there's any
moisture in here and just for you know
for long-term storage
and then when I do my single use jars
for the freezer I do
take apart a silica packet and I put
silver packets in the little jars with
the pollen and
in the vacuum seal the jars into a
vacuum seal bag with more moisture
protectors
you know
because of the work involved in pollen
collection and preservation
I really want to make sure that you're
going to be able to use that pollen
again
and a lot of that work is the risk
involved
because most people are also growing
flowers
okay fucking
pretty clean
now we're gonna
and you're gonna get the the money shot
here as we get this in the jar
that is
a lot of yellow cake remember
but no not actual radioactive material
pollen
thank you
[Applause]
yeah it's my current one in an old one
they're nice like the thin card on that
you know
all right
and then I got a
very wet rag here
foreign
do the same thing to the
the pollen boxes spray and why
there is a lot of pollen
and this material left on the table
so really get it wet
that sometimes when you even stream it
like pollen will come up so it's nice to
like have a mister and a little stream
see that there's still some dust still
kicking up
foreign
agriculture is community and sharing of
information you know it's like
you know saving trade secret Tech is is
part of the problem in the world
yeah
yeah I mean it's basically like
you know
Jordan let's see what this
oh yeah Jerry Lotus
you better light and we could plug in a
light there no it's all good
take it too
yeah it's fucking gnarly that's not up
to uh
or filmmakers Union code this wire
should be taped down
Gary Lotus
[Music]
thank you