[Music]
when we're looking at product out here a
little disappointed on the concentrates
especially when it comes to cartridges I
don't think a person should be paying
over 40 dollars for a good cartridge
when I say good cartridge there
shouldn't be any propylene glycol in it
MCT oil any other additives that could
be harmful to the consumer as well and
then also flavor additives which is very
interesting so I noticed that a lot of
companies out here are using way too
many what we call naturally drive
terpenes so they're buying terpenes from
various companies whether it's in Oregon
California other states and it just it
doesn't give the user a good experience
it doesn't taste like a particular
strain it's very strange and I don't
think these companies and I don't think
these bud tenders that are selling these
products are also educated on what's
actually going into these products as
well so that's where we come in so we
actually create a lot of cartridges in
California I'm sorry Colorado we have a
very efficient process we're using
distillate cannabis derived terpenes
very good flavor flavor profile good
potency and ultimately affordable and I
think this the portability aspect that's
going to help change that market shift
from the illicit market again to the
regulated market so it's fairly insane
why I'm seeing cartridges good
cartridges that are over $50 seeing live
resin that's $100 plus right
pre-tax exactly and so you know you add
37 percent tax on that I mean that's
insane so the average Joe out here
cannot afford concentrates and I think
that's the way that the industry is
moving when you look at market analytics
for example you see a lot of people
that's reverting to more infused
products and concentrate over flower'
I think the days of just combusting
flour are coming to an end now that said
I think California has incredible flour
out here similar to Colorado I think you
have a lot of bad product but when you
go to those select dispensaries right
it you can find some really really good
stuff again just similar to Colorado
it's kind of roll the dice so again
we're barely excited to come out here
hopefully we'll be open in about ten
months or so and again bring those
high-quality concentrates basically to
the average Joe and really expand that
concentrate market so Sacramento what we
noticed and and kind of parallel to our
brand is we really want just like hard
everyday people just working for us
Sacramento also seems to really want
cannabis business dollars very business
friendly unlike other cities within
California and those are the type of
municipal allies that we try to align
ourselves with right right so we didn't
think that LA was super cannabis
friendly especially with the high taxes
also with the application process out
here as well same thing with San
Francisco and we also thought that
Sacramento was kind of just a good
midpoint where again we can do some
pretty heavy distribution just across
the state as well so where do you plan
on sort because you're you're doing an
extraction seeing the source flower
where you plan to source from that's a
good question so we are looking for
partners for that as we speak and what
kind of
greenhouse you wanted from a certain
region or appellation yeah it's a good
question so I think off the bat when we
first start our our production I think
we're going to be focusing more on
cartridges with that since we do go
through a distillate process we don't
necessarily need the most incredible
expensive flower to extract since we are
you know kind of stripping all the
terpenes off and other things like that
right
so I think we'd probably be looking more
for like greenhouse to begin with maybe
outdoor we do have some specially
trained raw material acquisition folks
who do go to these cultivations
who do study their processes look at
their quality of flower with that - we
want to make sure that these companies
that are providing us raw material are
doing not just the minimum testing but
making sure that they're even going
above and beyond so again we're looking
for you know specific pesticides we're
looking for a specific microbial content
for instance in California total yeast
and mold isn't tested so we want to make
sure that that is above or I should say
below a certain threshold so tripping
profiles all that different stuff again
we want to make sure that we're we're
venting those raw material partners
correctly
that is correct yeah okay and so what
are they looking for like when they go
to basically buy biomass right yep
shrimp yeah what are they when you just
mentioned like what if things they don't
want yeah so I think a lot of things
you're looking at is what's going into
that fire to begin with so when we're
looking at agricultural chemicals such
as like fertilizers and even pesticides
as well we know that certain fertilizers
have a lot of heavy metals in it when
you're looking at a concentrate company
if you're using a very clean low metal
fertilizers for example that translates
into the concentrate you're gonna have a
very good flavorful concentrate versus
we have a lot of cultivations out there
that are using you know pretty common
agricultural chemicals and we noticed
that those don't translate super well
when those things get extracted so we
want to make sure that there's clean
chemicals going into that plant as
naturally as possible and so having into
a clean extract so I'm not one of those
acquisitions people I would have to ask
them what that California market is
looking like I imagine that it's it's
quite more expensive in Colorado
Colorado what we're seeing on a
wholesale price for trim we're seeing
probably an average between $150 to $200
a pound for trim for like yep exactly
it's down so right now in Colorado
there's an extreme price war occurring a
race to the bottom is how it's been for
the past two to three years that we are
still seeing a pretty level market
unlike Oregon for example where they
actually have a huge surplus of product
that's just been hanging out Colorado
actually has done a very good job
regulating the caller
Colorado market in the sense where we're
balancing that market where we don't
have this giant surplus and we actually
don't have that shortage either and I
think with outdoor cultivations in
greenhouse in Colorado it's just been
making that process a bit more efficient
so again that's kind of driving down
those prices a little bit and making
product ultimately more affordable for
the consumer with your product portfolio
of extracted products what's popping
like what's what's new and getting hot
what's kind of I mean you have like beat
tanks resin you have like bras in you
have all these different products what
for you guys is kind of trending up in
there yeah so what we're seeing right
now in Colorado is definitely high
quality affordable vape cartridges is by
far the most popular product not only
for residents who live there but also
for tourists or visiting Colorado relies
a lot on tourist dollars we obviously
have some of the best skiing in the
country of course we have a lot of
people come to Denver stuff like that
that's that's right that's right that's
right
and so and especially like the music
scene over there you know if you go to
Red Rocks in Colorado you're seeing a
lot of people use their vape pens you're
seeing a lot of people using their vape
pens on the slope a lot of people use
them at home too it's just very easy
there's a lot of people who out there
who are a little hesitant of you know
taking a DAB and using a torch or
turning on an email people just like the
ease of that high quality vape cartridge
and with your big cartridges what
company
sourcing from what did you pick as a
that is a good that is a good question
we actually have our own suppliers
actually out in China where we actually
custom make a lot of our materials
because we noticed that a lot of
suppliers in China don't have the best
products especially when it comes to
product safety and stuff like that so we
actually have very very we have one
partner in particular and again in China
who is making a lot of custom vaping
cartridges and actually a lot of custom
packaging for us as well and it's so
important to vent your clientele in
China because I think anyone over there
is going to try to sell you anything and
again one of our main concerns is
definitely public health and safety
it's definitely not in our interest to
get any of our clientele sick right we
want to make sure that they're having a
very good safe experience different
companies that manufacture them
differently which would have different
levels of safety issues right and it
seems like so what from what you noticed
in the market of big tanks not
specifically what you're using it but
like what are some of the health risk
components of that hardware yeah you
could get clean oil and it goes into
these bags yeah and they don't test you
know they test before it goes in right
so yeah I know it's clean it's safe and
then someone's inhaling heavy metals
so what are the components that you guys
have noticed that are the leading causes
of potential when we look at a lot of
current studies and of course this needs
to be studied way more than it is and
we're actually very much looking forward
to hopefully some more legitimate
studies coming out but what we're seeing
is definitely like non ceramic based
vaporizer cartridges do have actually
quite a bit of heavy metals when that
oil is in there
and additionally again we still don't
even know even how that translates
versus you know when you do inhale from
that cartridge how much of that heavy
metal is actually coming out how does
heating it impact that heavy metal
intake as well right there's just so
much things that we don't know and we
always want to be on the air of caution