[Music]
some of the common things that were seen
from established growers who are
sophisticated operators who let's say
have a number of grows across the state
of California and have been preparing
for this transition and who are well
prepared to comply with all the state
regulations with regard to cultivation
and already have really you know a very
well-known brand and distribution system
and all of that so get what the state is
attempting to do and is in the process
of doing is one of the biggest
challenges is the I need a home for my
business or I need to be able to have
the city or county in which I'm
operating issue business permits so
that's kind of number one is you know
where do I land or I am landed and can I
move forward in that area do they have a
permitting process in place that's right
that's right and then what we're finding
now if you look at City okay so so how
to address that maybe let me speak to
that first how to address if your
municipality does not specifically
authorize cultivation or any type of
cannabis business now this is when even
though I am a lawyer and I'm a business
and corporate attorney to the cannabis
industry we do especially over the last
several years you know there's a lot of
political work and political strategy
that goes into working on these types of
matters these days so and it all the
analysis is always client and site and
moment in time specific so it isn't
because the child the challenges the
political mechanism is not in place yet
that that's that's the challenge I want
to be able to have a cultivation permit
from my County but that political
mechanism isn't in place how do we get
there then it's understanding what is
the political process in my particular
area who are the players involved right
it's this it's a really a political
strategy and that type of very detailed
and out analysis what will it take to
get me there is it meetings with
particular people within the Economic
Development Department is it a very
coordinated effort and organizing
amongst other growers like we did in
Santa Barbara County saying here's you
know we've got a bunch of farmers here a
bunch of flower farms that are all I
mean many of whom are having some
challenges because yes that's right and
so you know people are foreclosing on
their farms or what do I do you know
like not being able to kind of support
themselves anymore well geez here's this
cannabis industry or men at many
cannabis farmers that had already
located there over a long period of time
so kind of recognizing that there's a
collective need getting organized
understanding that a political process
and interfacing with local elected
officials and various agencies requires
coordination sophistication thinking
about what is good public policy in this
area how do we how do we explain that we
are indeed responsible community members
what sort of messaging is going to be
around this and listen listen to what
the needs are of the community don't be
shy about that political discourse
involves many different perspectives one
has to be calm and understand that the
way that things are best done usually
involves that we sit around a table and
we listen to each other and we come up
with strategy and we come up with you
know some solution that maybe doesn't
meet everyone's need as needs as much as
they act think that they have needs but
you know is is is this building
collaborative effort and we're seeing
that done in Santa Barbara County it's
really such a lovely thing so you know
however it takes two so you're positive
about what you are currently seeing
where Santa Barbara County is going as
it relates to cannabis cultivation
absolutely at all of that said nothing
as we I think become older in life we
recognize nothing is fully black and
white right and there are so it's
contoured there are challenges there
right there and there will be challenges
in this process and the role of the
industry or the role of the growers is
to identify that this proposal by the
county is not workable and why that is
and give support for that in terms of at
the hearings through talking with media
through talking with each other through
talking with their neighbors who are not
in the cannabis industry so continuing a
process of education around why a part
of you know a proposal by the county
wouldn't be workable right this is a
conversation so is it positive at least
the county is having the conversation my
god they have they actually have town
hall meetings and will take meetings
with folks in the industry so that very
open door process is a really remarkable
one when you have that you know we have
so so so many cities and counties that
don't even want to have the conversation
don't want to talk to people who are in
the industry or really make that
political process and incredibly non
transparent one so that instead what you
see is and now we'll skip to here's a
challenge that folks are having instead
what you see is a municipality says
alright we want to get in the industry
or we've got some folks who are pushing
us to allow the industry to site their
businesses in our municipality we like
the idea because of revenue jobs and
whatever really positive public pot or
we believe in it as a what you know
whatever reasoning behind it and so
because but for whatever reasons not
creating a transparent or very public
rulemaking process or a very short and
time frame for that or very little
feedback from the community you have a
finalized
set of local rules the local ordinance
owning ordinance and maybe a regulatory
ordinance in the
that deals with kind of operations and
applications and all of that that gets
finalized 3-4 weeks later the
application comes out and two to four
weeks later a very voluminous expensive
application that may be a $70,000 like
what is being proposed in the city of LA
to the fees just to apply for one permit
comes at no cultivation - for anything
in the city of LA so you know they come
out and suddenly you you know you're
kind of one is kind of scrambling to get
organized and on board for you know for
an application and to kind of try to
secure that permitting in that
particular municipality and so that's an
example you know that that's an example
of a challenge that that many many folks
are facing which is okay now we have a
process in play which is also not
necessarily a well-oiled machine in
these municipalities because they've
never permitted these businesses and so
trying to scramble and put together
their best effort to apply through what
is a very expensive incredibly
voluminous incredibly complicated local
permitting process we've run some of
these numbers for folks just in terms of
what is it gonna take to get through a
local permitting process state licensing
let's say you rent your property and
build out in blah blah blah you know
kind of depending on the license type
but we're seeing you know from 750,000
to 5.6 million I mean now we're talking
about like volatile manufacturing but
you know a lot of my role these days is
having real honest conversations with
folks about what all of this actually
involves financially and otherwise
because I want and I want I want us all
to make good decisions for our lives and
really the only way we can do that is if
we have accurate information and there's
a lot of information that's not knowable
and there's a lot of inaccurate
information out there so you know really
just again as as I spoke about at the
bee
this conversation taking the time to
really understand in detail what does
this process involve to get to the
regulated market what does that involve
for the legacy grower
[Music]