Scot you had a post where you were
talking about extracts are you moving
more towards extracts versus compost
teas and then can you talk a little bit
about extracts versus cheese and kind of
for sure your mindset for sure so I
think really you know kind of a
confusion that's happened is you know
there's dr. Laningham who's who came up
with all these methods and you know
she's kind of known for saying tea
saying tea saying tea compost tea
compost tea compost tea and what happens
is people then go just do any version of
what they define as tea so there's a
extreme variation between what dr.
Elaine Ingham defines as compost tea and
what the market does across the board I
can't think of anything that's more
varied in any thing I've ever done in my
entire life and so the two major
obstacles with compost tea is you're
doing you're doing animal husbandry
you're growing animals and you're
growing life in a tank and and you
either are not quantifying those
organisms most of the people that
possess a microscope just kind of look
through which isn't bad but there's a
lot that you can't see if you're just
looking through in the early years there
was a lot of really bad information as
far as organism identification so I feel
like an entire community went chasing
after the wrong goal because of a couple
key people I think that's starting to
get sorted out a little bit now that dr.
laning hims courses are far more
accessible but essentially what we ran
into in the work place is you know
really the first few jobs I got were to
teach people how to brew tea and what
that would look like is I would go to
the facility we would set up a recipe I
would verify with the microscope that it
was what it needed to be and then we
would replicate it over multiple days so
I could leave them with a compost tea
recipe
through that first year it became really
apparent the problems with that because
what ends up happening is the climate
changes the temperature changes the
conditions change for that life and I
don't think you know the market wide
really understands how varied those
results if compost tea brewing can be
and when we start to communicate to
people these obstacles and we say you
need to be checking and and it kind of
turns into this like class warfare
emotions like people get offended like
I'm saying you're not qualified to do
this but I mean technically that's
what's happening and and if you want to
brew tea you should become proficient in
identifying organisms to actually
quantify them because you're either
brewing life or you're either brewing
disease and we went from facility to
facility in facility and we just kept
tracking the issues with people brewing
tea around that same time like from like
2014 to 2016 I think dr. Alaine really
started switching more to the extract
model and so the benefits of tea is you
excite organisms and they produce glues
and they stick to surfaces that's great
if you're covering leaves if you're
trying to penetrate to roots they never
get to the roots they stick to the soil
surface
so dr. Alaine was seeing a benefit to
adding compost extract to the soil
versus compost tea because it the
compost extract you're dislodging
organisms into water and then those
organisms will travel as far as the
water does and so you actually get to
the desired result quicker using a
compost extract versus a compost tea now
the downside of the compost extract is
you use more compost but the upside is
there's almost no volatility there's
almost no detriment that could come with
it as long as your compost doesn't have
detrimental aspects to it and so at the
small scale you can brew some compost
tea but as we started to get bigger and
bigger and bigger we ran into remarkable
obstacles at scale I don't necessarily
say this publicly because then I get
nasty emails and things from people that
manufacture tea equipment but the larger
the tank you go the worst
gets the last thing that you want my
opinion is a 500 thousand gallon tea
brew I apologize the people but that's
the math of it and so there's a lot of
obstacles to brewing tea because you're
trying to do it on a time line like
you're trying to you're trying to
reproduce rabbits on a perfect time
scale that fits into the commercial
space and it doesn't work it doesn't
work and so if you start a tea brew that
has a 24 hour life cycle and you come in
next morning but then you doesn't you
discover an irrigation leak and you get
occupied for four hours well now that
tea that may have would have been
healthy is now full of disease and
problematic and then you put that on to
your plants so there's a lot of issues
with tea at scale compost extract is far
lower volatility again we start moving
up in scale we're not working with
technically trained people we're working
with agricultural employees sometimes
and so it's far easier to explain to a
non non trained employee how to do a
compost extract I thought the
fascinating part that you guys discover
was the difference in high elevation and
low elevation lack of oxygen and those
chemical nightmare yes a total nightmare
and that you know like I said 2015-2016
that was really the first jobs we got
was teaching people how to brew tea
because that's really all they knew from
dr. Alaine they knew that we were
involved dr. Alaine they wanted to get
in and so now what my wife and I do is
you know we show up with a couple
55-gallon drums and a pump and a sump
pump and 130 foot hose and I mean you
know the wife and I can apply compost
extract a 30,000 square feet and a
workday yeah we just we just edits and
it's no volatility it cleans out you can
rinse out the thing because what we also
started working what running into is you
run into OSHA now if you're trying to do
a regulated facility you got an OSHA
person making sure you conform you
cannot have an employee climb up on a
ladder to get into a 250-gallon tank and
a regulated facility and it's just not
gonna fly and so now you got to build a
platform and then just you're
multiplying problems to do something
that we don't know
sorry advocate and you know for for
Sarah and I the real like profound aha
moment that will by far go down as one
of the most profound experiences I've
had in many workplaces we were trying to
brew tea at a facility that hired us to
treat two that were about fifteen miles
apart and we were racing back and forth
to set tea brews at both facilities and
we came to the one facility was getting
dark it was outside we're running out of
time and at that time we were using like
200 300 gallon tanks we'd put compost
tea bags in there we'd aerate it for
20-30 minutes we'd swap them out we do
that a couple times until we hit the
targeted values and we just didn't have
enough time to do that and so Sarah was
like well I'll just hand to extract the
amount of compost into a five-gallon
bucket
we'll pour it into the top of the tea
brew and top it off and go home and get
dinner and the funny part about it was
she did it faster than me and she got
better extraction rates because the hand
extraction rate was more efficient than
the aerated in the 300 gallon tank and
that we haven't looked back since people
don't want to hear it they're not
impressed by that we there's a lot of
jobs that don't hire us because they
want these Wizardry tea brews but you
know proofs in the pudding we haven't
turned back cents you know and it's far
easier for me to show up to a facility
with two blue barrels blessed out the
extract wash it out turn it upside down
and get in and you know that's you know
previously I used to advocate like
55-gallon Brewers and we were using
these stainless steel ones and we'd have
our facilities get them ya know I'm a
big that you remember when it fell on
the employee yeah so that tank fell on
one of the employees because she saw me
and I I would always try to be really
careful to not fill it up with water and
move it but I screwed up and I needed it
to go like 30 feet to the left
and I'd already filled it up and I was
just kind of in today tired stressed and
so I picked I was kind of dragging this
tank down this concrete thing to the
next row
well the non-english-speaking
agricultural employee that had to
execute that task
after I left did that same bang and she
pulled a 55-gallon stainless steel
Brewer on top of her and that was the
end of that game I was like that's not
going down at all and so you know a lot
of these workplace scenarios of
practicality like I think that's where
Eric and I really are very similar in
that we always want to find the most
practical low-cost easy solution and you
know people that make and sell Brewers
don't want to hear it people that want
to buy Brewers don't want to hear it but
I'm telling you we get remarkable
results using small barrels and the most
employees want to clock in and clock out
it's you know as much as everybody who
wants to be in cannabis and wants that
job in it or whatever it a lot of people
turn it into the clock in and clock out
and if you don't make it easy and
somewhat desirable it just becomes you
know it becomes the next guys job and
the new guy and the next and it just
moves on and so a lot of these jobs now
we're not saying everything is easy
there's work involved but you have to
make it safe first of all and if it's
not safe that's an issue and secondly if
it's not something that people are like
feeling passionate about it drives down
morale as you're working with a big team
of people and it all it takes is one
you know seedling or one you know cell
to start to have that you know
uninspired attitude and it drags the
whole bunch down and a lot of these
corporate facilities don't give a fuck
about you know they're not there to make
friends and you can they see that shit
and you're gone quick so I mean at the
end of the day you know making these
facilities smooth and enticing for
employees is important because again
once you start getting to that clock in
clock out passion drives down and we're
not actually leveling the point well
what what happened what kind of evolved
us to the barrels is we were working on
a large AG project we don't just do
cannabis we do anything and we did a
farm that was 6,000 acres of corn and
soy and we had like six 250 gallon tea
brewers that were in IBC totes which
kind of solves a problem of scale but I
have objections to as well but
nonetheless we were running those and so
Sarah and I developed the SOP and and
determine how many minutes how much
compost how much time
what process yields the appropriate
result and then we turn that over to
employees and as soon as the employees
take over that job we start having
problems with the numbers on the extract
we start getting undesirable aspects to
it the quality goes down because they're
not able to clean it they're not super
motivated to climb in that thing and
scrub it like we do so you start to lose
repeatability and so that's really where
the 55-gallon barrel excels is that its
small its compact it's consistent it
keeps it even it keeps it in small
enough batches to go from space to pace
to space and and it's repeatable and
it's easy to clean out and we see this
in other areas like Frenchie cannoli
doesn't make hash in a 400 gallon barrel
he makes it in the same damn size that
the little washing machines are because
you get better extraction rates and you
get more consistency and so we just
tried to replicate that model and like
eric says is produce a standard
operating procedure that's not painful
to an employee that doesn't add undo
process or headache or reasons to get
yelled at or any of that thing and the
55-gallon drums solves all those
problems it keeps the extract into a
small container so you don't magnify
variation you get really consistent
dispensing of organisms across the
property from corner to corner and most
employees can rinse it out with a hose
turn it upside down and clean it
properly which is the actual goal and
that is one of the major components
that's missing from the commercially
produced tea brewers that is becoming
very apparent in the regulated market
and we've worked with some facilities in
Vegas which has a remarkably difficult
microbial things to navigate and we
tracked several facilities over the
course of a year and saw microbial
issues popping up with certain types of
tea Brewers and process and again you
know we moved away from a lot of types
of equipment
you know as unsexy it is and as
disappointing as it is we by far get the
best results using a couple blue barrels
and $100 pump from Home Depot but if you
listen to dr. Ingham so much a compost
heap was really designed to do the glue
binding was to bind the particles so
that you start to have the ability to
take soil that had inadequate
tilth and increase it and we started
using it as these inoculants and the
thing was that as you start to learn
you're you're not qualified on the
microscope so you have no idea what
you're brewing and you end up seeing
pathogenic problems resulting from your
work because you're kind of using voodoo
science and I think the compost extract
is excellent because it's you're able to
take what you want to take and put it in
but I think the compost tea designed for
you know building ground that isn't
ready for cultivation and preparing it
laying the cover crops in binding the
soil gluing it together
I think that's the purpose of it more
than where the way we use it sure no
because I was I was a brewer too and I
got to a size in blue tank where I was
probably like 250 but it got to the size
where it was I gotta climb up in the
damn thing to clean it it becomes a
nightmare you can't flip it it starts to
become too big to service yeah and I
didn't want a centralized monster tank
to feed through because I'm like you
start leaving residue in the lines
you're starting to have pathogenic
contamination because it has to be clean
and you start to realize you're doing
the same thing you're starting in a
closet and you're trying to multiply it
out to acreage yeah and yeah and and
also too it's a it you know what we do
now is also a you know millions of
square feet of evolution and compost tea
is a remarkably powerful tool you know
one of our counterparts Nick Thomas
Eenie goes by humankind Oregon he uses a
lot of compost tea and you know if you
properly brew tea and you get it onto
the plants I mean next morning there's a
new branch it's some wild apple I mean
if you do it right and you hit the nut
that dr. Lane defines its pure
witchcraft but a lot of times the
compost tea is a fourth-quarter decision
not the way Nick uses it but like to
combat disease or whatever so you're
throwing a Hail Mary at fourth quarter
and you know what my wife and I have
done if Don was like how do we circle
back to the very beginning to circumvent
problems to not need a fourth quarter
decision and that strategy is getting
back to a compost extract starting at
the beginning starting with organisms
that are distributed evenly from corner
to corner start with a tank that doesn't
also bring disease and then monitor that
process effectively and appropriately so
you know you can't you can avoid there
excuse me you can take a compost tea and
you can knock out powdery mildew we've
done it before we used to do it back in
the earlier years but it was just it was
too complicated as a business strategy
so we stopped doing it but you can come
up to a facility and stop a whole bunch
of nightmares with a really good tea but
we can also go back to propagation start
fresh start with a good extract use the
microscope to quantify your trajectory
as you go from start to finish and you
can avoid getting mold by making
watering changes by making feed changes
by you know in a lot of cases making
environmental changes mm-hmm so we you
know what came with regulation for us is
you know prior and in the black markets
it was a by all means necessary approach
you could spray Michael butanol in the
last week if you really felt like that's
what you were going to do and because we
can't do these we have to get back to
the beginning of the root cause identify
what the actual issue is and avoid
hitting that island altogether