[Music]
or near and dear to my heart and going
through what the legislature and and has
been an ongoing debate with the
regulators it our compassion and trade
samples we all get that they don't want
brands to give me free samples way to
every consumer who walks down the street
but when a new brand is trying to get
into a retail operation in any industry
they get yeah when they put out their
regulations they have to put out an F
what's called an F SOR which is a final
statement of a reason that explains
every single rule they make and in that
particular section they say exactly that
they believe that it could create
diversion of products and that was sort
of it wasn't a very long answer if I
remember correctly it was just saying
that past experiences with that which I
assume well must have been based on the
unregulated or less regulated market in
California well I don't want to say
unregulated the you know the Bay Area
has been very highly legacy market this
also comes back to an element of trust
and you know sort of an evolution of
misinformation and stereotyping and a
lot of these rules when you look at
cannabis being regulated like for
lutonium sort of you can connect that
back with Prohibition and reefer badness
and that's really the reason of this
sort of very slow tightly regulated
incremental approach and so when you
could
towards cancer patients talk about what
it was like then and what it's like now
when you have to look that same cancer
patient in the eyes and be like sorry
well that's been really tough because we
started a program many many years ago
called the helping hands and where we
gave free cannabis to low and no income
patients the c---berkeley actually
modeled that and made it a law for all
retailers and once it sews anybody with
a doctor's recommendation and once these
new laws went into effect and the bureau
said that we could not give free
cannabis to anyone without and MMIC card
which is very explicitly stated in the
law but they there were certain
exceptions that were made by different
regulators for that particular exception
and they so we have had to tell people
that have been on this list that could
not get MMIC cards or have had a lot of
challenges getting MMIC cards that they
were removed from the program and so we
can't give them to them for free anymore
and so we've lost probably half of the
number of people that were part of the
program which is really sad and we I
mean we we give it to them at a we don't
give it it we sell it at a very low rate
like under market rate but we have to
sell it where we're not allowed to give
it away to those patients and that's
really unfortunate and it's you know
made a lot of people drop off the
program and gotten it's it's been tough
because Berkeley patients group has
really been you know Alexi operator of
compassion and yeah yeah that's not
going away I mean the medical the
medical program that we that exists
today yes but I don't think that medical
cannabis is going to go away I think
people patients are gonna be using
cannabis as more research is being done
every day on on the benefits of cannabis
and specific cannabinoids and the
conditions that they help and so there's
gonna be a ton of medicines just not the
compassion just not in the traditional
medical marijuana market that we are
have known and are familiar with you're
a very nice person you really are
I'm a little bit angry about this
because I think it's unacceptable that
the state would not allow the people who
need this medication to get it at for
free if they need it and I'm outraged as
a patient that I have to pay a sin tax
right which is essentially literally an
act to get this and I can barely afford
it
so as a consumer and as a patient I as
working with him on this we're gonna
continue this fight because absolutely
it all comes down yeah on people like me
and Jen drive those people into the
black more absolutely you know I
wouldn't more point on the compassion I
think an argument can be made I'm not a
lawyer but I truly think that it is a
violation of prop 215 and 64 to restrict
the compassion programs and donations
like they are right now I'm also not a
lawyer like a class action I think so I
think so yeah absolutely
because it wasn't supposed to interfere
with any anything crupp 215 said prop
215 said safe affordable access and for
people that can't afford affordable
means free and that's how this isn't the
entire compassion probe this entire
industry was birthed out of compassion
out of the AIDS crisis and I mean if
there's anything that should remain in
this ever-changing industry it should be
the compassion and the social awareness
that birthed it so where
as a whole it's it's shrinking okay so
we've talked the compassion kind of free
giveaways but then talk about the tree
mm-hmm
so when brands because I would assume
it's part for a new brand to come in
yeah it's a very complicated process
with a lot of moving pieces and you know
a different people have were we have to
make sure that everything is done
aboveboard completely compliant and you
know when it comes to different people
have different interpretations on how
that works and I think you know some
people take the rules more seriously
than others so it's it's it has just
become a challenge that is not necessary
and again this also goes back to this is
a an outgrowth of reefer madness
propaganda and prohibition there is
absolutely every other industry does
this there's even pharmaceuticals to do
this you can have you can get samples of
pharmacy you know scheduled to narcotics
for free and the one of the arguments
was the you know the diversion and the
tracking and things like that but this
is it is 2019 we put a man on the moon
in the 60s we can we can code in a
little line to make sure that you know
trade samples get into metric and get
into track and trace this is not this is
something that pharmaceutical industry
does this is there there are so many
ways to do this and this is the only way
that new business that we're going to be
able to help new businesses get a
foothold in the industry because right
now only ones with with huge resources
are going to be able to have the
manpower to create teams that are going
to be creative and working with all
everybody - to get these new samples to
market or not samples get these new
products to market in various ways
so the best way for a company to get
their their product introduced to the
consumer base is to be able to have the
employees that are selling those
products be able to speak informatively
about them and be able to answer
questions and figure out what exactly a
particular customer is looking for and
if they don't know they're not going to
recommend a product and even as a
business you know we want to know what
we're selling our good products and so
if you can't do that it you know people
your your store is base and your
reputation is based on on the products
you sell your quality products and the
service you provide those are your two
key retail components and so there has
to be a way to both support new small
businesses and ensure that you are
providing the community and the customer
is with the the best products to
completely I see them as different
they're both free weed moving hands but
as far as a sensible out is one of them
baked into the law and the other at the
whim of one of those three regulatory
agencies or are both those no free
anything to anyone
law or they both whim of one of the
three regulatory agencies trade samples
is regulatory that would be the bureau
and and and they are more than aware
there's a bill there's a trade samples
bill right now that's moving through
sponsored by Senator Skinner or senator
and go Skinner and Flo canna and that's
going to make things if it makes it all
the way and the governor signs it which
I I certainly hope he will but yeah I
mean people of really this has been if
this has been a debate and an issue
since there were subcommittees I don't
even know how many this must have been
27 I don't know when it was but there
were there were all of these stakeholder
meetings with the regulators as they
were developing these regulations and
even after the first round in the next
round we've been debating trade samples
since the very beginning and I think
that this is something that people are
not going to let up on this needs to
happen we need to get normalized and
treated like normal like any other
business
we don't even know who a real patient is
you know what what's a real patient
what's a you know so they're good
they're potentially they'll be giving
away you know I mean it doesn't make any
sense but the state wants control right
they're the new middleman they're the
new drug dealer you know as far as
cannabis goes and everything they're
promulgating at this moment is
pretending to maintain control
absolutely I mean yeah that's that was
what that's prop 64 that's melkor so
that they are the regulators and but
they were they they are they serve at
the pleasure of the executive branch and
the governor's office and you know
there's politics politics is involved
this is a third less of but still
somewhat of a third rail issue and
there's a lot of a lot of familiarizing
that needs to be needs to take place and
it's taking place and I think as every
year moves on and people get used to the
idea of legal legalization legal
cannabis there think it's gonna be a
process I mean look at Colorado Colorado
just passed delivery they've had yeah
yeah exactly exactly yeah mm-hmm yeah I
mean I always say you know provision is
been going on for more than 80 years now
and we're just at this very early
starting point so I hope it doesn't take
80 years to make up for all of that but
I think it's definitely not gonna happen
overnight and that's that's one of the
most important things that I've learned
in this crazy process over the last few
years is that really have to take a it's
important to take a short-term picture
but you really have to take a broader
more long-term view
of everything all of these policies all
these regulations all these laws that
may work very well for you in the short
term but long term might not work so
well and there's a lot of things that
could go wrong and that you maybe can
anticipate but maybe you can't
anticipate so it is and not everything
is as much of a crisis as it might feel
like and there's you know I've seen
burns rampant which is completely
understandable but being able to
prioritize and be able and take a ticket
just take a broader view a more
long-term thing instead of thinking like
six months to a year which is important
I mean you don't don't negate that but
also think five to ten years from now
now we don't know with anything any of
these states are gonna look like ten
nobody's hit ten years yet but I think
that things are going to change a line
some of these rules are gonna most of
them are probably gonna stay the same
but I think there's gonna be some
significant changes you know another
thing for patience the Edible potency
cap needs to be either removed for
patients or raised for patients it not
necessarily adult consumers but for
patients I think 100 milligrams for an
edible is not fair and too expensive and
should be
that is an agency level descent decision
now curse' does not put a potency cap
yeah yeah what's in their regulation
yeah so my last question is a heartful
how much weed does a government liaison
have to smoke to keep her sanity as she
deals with the government depends on the
strain yeah like I hit my 11 years in
the cannabis space last month this month
today's 31st no no for 11 years I feel
like it's time to retire I worked for
normal national normal in DC yeah there
wasn't really an industry back then