what has it look like for businesses to
work with one another to set up these
agreements to set up contracts to ensure
that there are products on the shelves
and I'm sure there was disruption when
we went through these various moments
January 1 2018 I know in the city of Los
Angeles there was a lot of disruption so
I want to hear from Pamela first and
then Jared I'd like to hear from you as
well we've seen with our operators that
legacy operators and early adopters tend
to have the most difficulty here because
they're used to saying this is somebody
I trust they're used to saying you know
I didn't put things in writing because
that was evidence and that was evidence
that I was teetering in this you know
almost regulated limited immunity
whatever it is that these times had and
so it's really coming around to this
sensibility of what is traditional
regular business we have this
conversation a lot what do other heavily
regulated industries do we're not
reinventing the wheel in cannabis we are
simply adding another widget to a
commodities market and so contracting is
the cornerstone and the fundamentals of
good business because there are
provisions and there are things that are
coming as we march towards ever close
our full legalization at the federal
level what does that mean that means you
can get to federal court when we're
talking about negligence claims and
we're talking about products liabilities
claims that are coming there are things
like treble damages that happen when you
can get into a federal situation so
they're looming they're waiting we've
seen prop 65 lawsuits that are coming
you've got to be ahead of it you've got
to know that when you're a retailer if
you're contracting or you're a
manufacturer and you're contracting to
get flour how that flour is getting to
you where is the custody and control who
is in control of it who is responsible
if there is a rate an accident
hijacking who is
responsible for this product are you
covered from an insurance perspective
who where does it go if you're using a
transport only licensee they can't hold
custody to the product so on one end of
that transaction somebody's covering
when somebody else is moving physically
moving the product when you're talking
about our QA QC procedures here in
California protect the consumer that's
what they're driven to do so the point
of testing is right before it gets B to
C that's when the distributor's
responsibility that means if you're a
man if you're a cultivator and you're
selling product to a manufacturer where
that product may get contaminated if
it's that it's clean when it left the
cultivators but by the time it gets the
manufacturer and the manufacturer
doesn't test it before they manufacture
it and all the sudden it gets
concentrated and at the end of the line
at tests dirty whose responsibility is
that that's a contract term that's where
you need to be panning out all of these
different levels of how you interface
together as a supply chain making sure
that the excise tax is collected and
paid you are responsible from the state
agency's perspective for everything that
you do and everything that it goes along
the pivot points on the supply chain so
you're gonna want to know that everybody
else in that line is doing the same
thing you are and the best way to
protect yourself and your business is
through these agreements and it's a
difficult lift it is not easy it is
expensive you're going to start to see
the prices coming down working with a
good lawyer you get a what I'd like to
say is a suite of agreements that then
you're just tearing off of so if you're
a vendor ask a distributor to send you a
distribution agreement don't read it
read it yourself
have your lawyer read it go through what
red lines you want to do and then have a
meaningful conversation we're all
figuring it out that's the great part
about this industry is it is community
based we've most of us have been here
we're working through these issues
together
use it as a collaborative framework but
please don't cut the fat when it comes
to your legal representation and putting
down on paper where responsibilities
liabilities and warranties go when we're
talking about packaging and labeling and
where that little California universal
symbol needs to go and the primary panel
this is my plea there are four things
I know branding we just talked about
being very expensive your logo is not
one of the four things that needs to be
on the front of your product I'm sorry I
understand I have this conversation
several times a day it isn't it's the
net weight in US and foreign metrics it
is the universal California symbol which
should be in scale size to your logo it
should not be the tiniest thing with
your big logo and then you've got to
name your product a vape cartridge is
not correct
it's a cannabis vape cartridge needs to
identify the product name and it needs
to be on the part of your product with
the ordinary course of business that a
consumer sees I'm sure that Jerrod and
Adam go through this all the time when
you're checking these products do you
take them into your store do you run the
risk of the BCC coming in and somebody
saying hey they're getting easier and
easier to identify I don't know if
jarred and out and went away in but
these days I walk into a dispensary you
can zero in on a non-compliant package
much more quickly so this isn't the time
to play around it's the time to contract
put all the terms in writing make sure
you understand what they are evidence
that you're meeting all of these other
ancillary regulatory protocols and then
you can go about the business of being
profitable and being ready to survive
into 2019