[Music]
not one wanted to write things down why
because it was a ledger of all of your
then and still from the federal
government's federally illegal activity
right it's a very sense of concern there
was a lot of I believe the person that
I'm working with and therefore a
handshake deal was enough and those days
were great and still from those
relationships you can then have
meaningful contracts and as we take
shape and start to legalize and
normalize and want to be a major
commodities player across the board we
have to look at what same and similar
industries are doing its what the most
important aspect is of growing your
business right and if we look at same
and similar heavily regulated industries
Pharma food alcohol tobacco they all are
heavily ensconced in both compliance and
most importantly contracts and its
contracts throughout the supply chains
so when we're looking at that we need to
make sure that at all these different
intervals as the product or as the
flower turns into product that turns
into where it's ultimately sold you have
different pivot points and different
concerns and different protocols that
you want to have in place when is the
best time to work on an agreement it's
when everybody's happy and excited to
get to the task of doing the work when
it's not great to discuss what terms you
want to have is when you have an issue
so we want to plan for the worst case
scenario under the best case
circumstances and that happens at the
outset now that being said since we have
a history of
not engaging in contractual obligations
or agreements those first conversations
will be difficult we have a good amount
of evidence to suggest why these are so
important think about the first recalls
that have been rolling out from the BCC
where the products needed to be recalled
because the tests came back the
certificate of analysis was incorrect
and then uploaded later to the BCC whose
responsibility is that is that the
retailer's responsibility the
distributor's responsibility the
manufacturers responsibility does it go
all the way back up to the cultivator of
the raw source material where along that
supply chain is it your responsibility
and does everybody along that supply
chain have insurance if you have not
contracted for that if there is not
evidence to suggest that these types of
claims would be covered by the insurance
that is along the supply chain those
different actors then at the end of the
day it's going to be everybody's
responsibility or it's going to devolve
into litigation in the courts which are
not favorable to cannabis claims at the
moment we want to look at a specific
example we can look at testing lab
agreements with distribution first and
foremost it is interesting of note that
the testing lab is the only licensed
type along the cannabis supply chain
that is not currently required to carry
insurance it is not currently required
to place a surety bond with the state so
when they take in your batch samples
currently according to the BCC it cannot
be released until the test is performed
therefore if that testing lab all the
sudden has too wide of a discrepancy in
their COAS
and the BCC says stop you can no longer
take taken product or you can no longer
a process certificate of analysis what
are you supposed to do let's say you
have a million dollars of product
waiting in a distribution warehouse
we'll pause for a second but just note
is that your distribution warehouse
words or a third party distribution
warehouse that you're now taking up
space
because a testing lab is not allowed to
continue to process your testing to
release it to go to market whose
responsibility is that and we're talking
about highly sensitive equipment that
may take weeks if not months to fix
where is your product if it can't be
released because you can't have a
secondary test until the first test
comes back and you can't force a
negative test when you're not allowed to
issue any other test the products
sitting there according to the VCC
currently and this is important to note
so that if we have these 15 days of
comments and this has not been addressed
by the BCC it should be an out crying to
the regulator's that this cannot stand
because this is an issue that really in
the real world can happen so to
paraphrase you give it to lab a it's
stuck at lab a until lab a can clear
that now when you look at it from the
regulator's point of view they want to
prevent lab shopping right they want to
prevent the fact that you could go to a
different lab until you pass muster
however if the BCC is the one that shuts
them down because they can't issue the
test
there should be two bifurcated scales
there should be the ability to take
those samples and under custody a chain
of control either send them to a
different lab that's owned by the same
lab a so lab a one if they have multiple
labs throughout the state or to a
separate lab entirely or to cancel the
test entirely take new batch samples and
whose responsibility is the batch sample
is it going to be that lab a that
couldn't fulfill their obligations or is
it the cultivator that's now responsible
for a second set of badge tests if you
don't have an agreement I can promise
you that lab a is gonna walk away saying
this is no longer my issue
so tell me what you would be counseling
a cultivator in Santa Cruz or Monterey
County - what clause clauses would you
have them put the contract with what
other party with a lab with a
distributor with whoever I need to have
it with your distributor if you're not
self you know if you don't have your own
distribution vertically integrated
business or if you're a cultivator
that's just moving product up along the
supply chain you're going to want to
have in-house R&amp;D we'll talk about why
that's so important to have that
baseline test if you're moving product
throughout the supply chain but in this
particular instance you're going to want
to make sure that your distributor has
an agreement with the testing lab a for
intervals of time and what those look
like so that you can clear a product and
that testing lab and that distributor
have an agreement that in an instance
that they cannot fulfill their
obligations whose responsibility is it
and what remediation there can be
especially in light of knowing what
these current issues are with the way
that the BCC is interpreting their
regulations and to go back to if you're
a cultivator and you're just moving
product throughout the supply chain
between a cultivator and a manufacturer
and you don't have to use then a
distributor technically there's no qa/qc
that's required you need to think about
what happens if I use a transport
distribution only licensee that licensee
is not allowed to take custody and
control of the product that means that
at some point either the manufacturer
has to carry the responsibility all the
way through to it gets to the
manufacturer or the manufacturer takes
over responsibility at the time that it
gets picked up from the cultivator and
arrives at the manufacturing facility
because that middleman that transport
only licensee is now invested with the
right to take on the custody of their
responsibility that means if you don't
test the product when it's flour what if
it gets into the distribution transport
only cargo area and it gets contaminated
and then it gets to the manufacturer the
manufacturer turns it into a
manufactured good
whatever that contaminant is
concentrates together and all the sudden
tests dirty where who is responsible and
if there's no evidence if there's no
issuance of a certificate that says this
was tested it was clean it was put into
here that was my responsibility there's
coverage there's insurance that insures
me to get the product to manufacture to
the manufacturer and then the
manufacturers liability sets in and I'm
absolved of liability as the cultivator
and if you don't have these things
buttoned up there's no way to know and
then you're in he said she said issue
you're going to court the courts can ask
do you have an agreement you're gonna
have a purchase order purchase order
isn't going to go into the devil of the
details of why the the recall procedures
are what the remediation procedures are
way whose responsibility was it at what
point in time at the supply chain these
are all things that really need to be
discussed and are going to be unique
between the parties so you can generate
a suite of template of agreements which
is what I'm hoping that we'll see as an
industry there's practice and pleading
agreements all over the place and other
same or similar industries that we can
borrow from Terms of Service disclaimers
all of that and as we work through that
you'll be able to then just start to
tinker with the it with the specific
terms that have to deal with your
specific transaction between two parties
party a and party these insurance
carrier as well because if you don't
have a closet says who's liable both
insurance like the insurance companies
are all about not paint out right so
they're gonna be like well it doesn't
say that you're liable so why do I need
to pay out so can you sort of say that
this also sort of dominoes into your
each respective parties insurance
carriers and claims and things like yeah
you're gonna want to have as an
attachment to these documents the
insurance carriers making sure that the
insurance is going to cover these types
of risks and making sure they know that
you're transporting cannabis I know that
seems weird in today's world but we're
still seeing people not exactly be on
the up-and-up we're a wellness company
you're a cannabis company you're gonna
wanna have is an exhibit there I'm state
and local licensing and what those
requirements are so that you're not as
the end consumer is the end retailer
taking in product that you can actually
sell because he'll license was expired
so there's all of these things that you
need to be aware of and they can be
documented through this agreement
process right we have to have child
resistant packaging that meets the year
and the poison Prevention Act of 1970
when you are procuring packaged material
right when you're the the actual package
that you're going to put the product in
does that company certify does it have
some sort of certification that they can
provide you with that would go into that
agreement that says all of the packaging
is child resistant and meets the
nineteen seventy poison Prevention Act
so that if somebody calls you out on it
you can say nope I've contracted for I
looked at and if there is an issue where
it does not meet that requirement you
have that company on the hook they've
made that agreement that promise with
you that you can take to court
[Music]
even manufacturing the manufacturer the
brand and you the packaging supplier
yeah so you're gonna want as the
manufacturing entity when you enter into
an agreement with the packing source
material provider whether that be in
China or somewhere domestically that
they understand what your needs are what
your requirements are that it must be
child resistant and it must meet this
1970 poison Prevention Act and there are
certifications you are actually supposed
to have that certification readily
available if dph were to ask for
[Music]
contracts on both sides of the
you know one when they're dealing with
retailers too when they're dealing with
yeah distributors in that instance who
are looking for a final form product
right unless you are the same
distributor that also holds a
manufacturing license your producing
final floor product you're taking it in
um they're gonna look for the testing
you know they're gonna distributors with
manufacturers they're basically looking
at terms of service when you're looking
at recall procedures what that's gonna
look like right if the product has to be
recalled because there's some issue that
they've now taken in and it either is
discovered through testing that there's
a problem or there's a leakage in you
know the cart that all of a sudden
they're gonna have to recall it up do
you have mechanisms in place for that
what are the time frames what are the
responsibilities who's going to have to
deal with that a distributor is really
specifically going to want to know how
they're going to engage with the
provider of that products with the
manufacturer of that product from retail
to do it from from a distributor or to
retailer you're really gonna want to box
out again how that distributor is going
to deal with that same situation in a
recall right are they going to have the
back stock how quickly are they going to
be able to get it to you why under what
circumstances is a recall trigger and
for them they're gonna want to look at
from a retailer's point of view making
sure that that distributor has good
testing agreements in place in order to
fulfill orders since we're looking to
likely have a secondary level extinction
event with bare-bones products on the
shelves when phase three testing comes
in um making sure that the labs of which
we know there may be one to two that are
currently going to be ready are you
dealing with one of the distributors
that has access to one of the labs that
may be able to do that
that snare the retailer would say we'd
like to carry products that you're
distributing but can you show us which
lab you're working with so we can have
comfort they can ask for that when
you're doing contract negotiations the
the door is wide open for you to ask
these critical questions right at the
time that they become issues you're not
asking questions you're demanding
answers you're demanding action and
wouldn't it be better wouldn't you feel
more comfortable as you're marching ever
closer to the first of the year in the
onboarding of metric and the onboarding
of Phase three testing and any new
requirements that come out that you have
a course of action if things go south
if the inevitable occurs if a CoA comes
back dirty if there is product lost in
transit if there is CHP pulled you over
and then it takes in an entire shipment
of product and puts it in to a detention
facility that isn't in the humid
controlled and potentially loses an
entire crop of product whose
responsibility it had happened it will
continue to happen while we have this
federal overlay of illegalities these
issues are still going to happen and if
you're not talking about them now you're
likely causing yourself harm in the
future these are tough conversations I'm
not sitting here saying they're easy I'm
not sitting here saying that every
operator is ready willing and excited to
engage in this process it's expensive
it's arduous it's continually shifting
but if you're not investing in yourself
and your business and putting in place
practices and their agreements that deal
with these complex issues when they
become issues nobody's in the best
headspace to address them they're
scrambling to survive their own
livelihood they're scrambling to make
sure that the people that they took the
product from if it's a distributor
they're able to pay
when those trigger points for payment
are done and they're different for
everyone along the supply chain right a
distributor is going to want to do Co D
care on delivery they're gonna want to
make sure that they collect that excise
tax right up front if I'm representing a
retailer I may not want to pay that
excise tax right up front so it's
important to also have your own
representation right the time has come
where people are gonna start to need
general counsel in house that there's
all of these things in flux note in the
BCC regulations it says every contract
you have should be on file at your
facility they're anticipating you having
contracts by that sheer statement alone
so the the times of a handshake deal are
over it's time to embrace having
contracts and learning what needs to be
in them and working collaboratively
together at the beginning that'll be
easier the more finite these contracts
get the power players are going to be in
a position to push the contract terms
that they want so if we're in a scenario
where the market customers are
experiencing a defect in the product
there is leakage in the vape car right
and it's systemic so people are coming
in to all of the different retailers
across let's say the state really right
because we have statewide distributions
and that's what every manufacturer brand
is after so you've got statewide
distribution you've got a leaky vape
cart people are coming into the
dispensaries in droves angry saying my
product is defective they're calling the
BCC with their you know enforcement line
and there's something that needs to be
done correct okay so we've got this
scenario in a in a contract list
environment and let's say there's
potential harm in the leakage right
it's contaminating with the filament in
the vape card it could potentially harm
somebody now you're looking at somebody
who's looking to sue over products
liability
and the more normalized we get the more
products liability you get at the second
that you can get into federal court
where there are treble damages in this
area and negligence starts to apply
that's a whole nother bag of worms but
so if you have no contract that one
person or that class actions of persons
can go after everybody along that supply
chain because everybody had a hand in
that product getting to where it is so
you want to build in indemnification and
places where you the operator depending
along where you are in the supply chain
says I'm no longer responsible or
somebody else is responsible so you
backtrack it right if you're a retailer
and you're dealing with a distributor
what are the recall procedures I noticed
that this is happening then there is a
recall out people are bringing in the
product I have to destroy that product
in accordance with my waste management
procedures it's a cost so where does not
cost to come from am i assessing not to
the distributor because that's what's in
my agreement and the distributor should
have an agreement with the manufacturer
and in that instance the distributor
goes to the manufacturer and says you
have to cover this cost and we have to
get product to these shelves or you no
longer gonna have that shelf space right
this is a systemic issue and then the
manufacturer goes back to who they
purchase that may part from before they
put the oil in it and they say this is
not what I contract for this is a major
defect this is a fundamental flaw in
this product and you have now caused a
series of chain reactions
so you're responsible liable and you
need to cover that cost so you can see
if there are specific provisions along
that supply chain you'll know what to do
from your vertical and then the next
vertical will be their responsibility so
the distributor may be in a situation
where they have to pay out and then they
go to the manufacturer to get their
payment the manufacturer goes to
somebody else now there may be lawsuits
anywhere along that continuum but
wherever you are
retailer to distributor distributor to
manufacturer manufacturer to supplier of
the the cart itself of the device
those are insulated agreements so you're
protecting where you are along that
supply chain being cognizant that the
person before you may not have done
that's exactly a hot potato liability is
genuinely how the law works right we're
along that supply chain is there
protection and where is my liability cut
off by an intervening cause of somebody
else oh you know that will happen I mean
it happened with lols when they took
about laws was a testing issues well the
COA changed after 48 hours so the
testing lab in that instance I believe
reissued the CoA which went to the BCC
if they were acting as their own
distributor which I believe in that
instance they were I can't say for
certain but if you were your own
distributor and you had a cultivation
license and you were doing pre rolls and
the tests came back you would want to
have a provision that puts that testing
lab on the hook that if they change
their their mind if they change that CoA
after 24 hours after issuance really
after the point at which it goes to the
BCC and that product has been cleared to
market that they then would be
responsible for any of the monetary
costs associated with a change in the
CoA so the issue there was you approved
it we then released it to dispensaries
up and down the state had you dinged us
at that initial point we would not have
put in a hundred dispensaries right had
reputational issues had issues that were
monetarily where those retailers may not
use you again you lost market share it's
bad
from a public optics perspective these
issues are much larger than the that
very small issue to begin with
right they balloon out and in a space
where we have pure saturation of new
products and new brands coming in every
day a recall of that sort of magnitude
or the inability to get your product to
market because it is held back waiting
for a testing lab that's been put on ice
by the BCC for some issue with their
technical equipment you could lose that
market share without really the ability
to gain it back so we're not talking
about small things we're talking about
the arrows that could take out your
business and we're asking you to put
words down on paper that articulate
responsibility I think if you peel back
this idea that the lawyers are trying to
get in and they're trying to make more
money during this tumultuous you know
wave of regulation they're not we're
putting contractual terms on paper that
ensure that all the parties are doing
what they said they were going to do and
if you strip it away to that bare basic
necessity it's just taking the terms and
the agreements that you've said that you
would do and putting them down on
writing we can look no further than back
to July one where retailers were left
holding the bag with manufactured
product that didn't meet the
requirements on July 1 that weren't
switched out as they were prom
with no recourse not was because nobody
put down the I promise I will come on
the 29th or the 30th or the 31st and
change out that product into an
agreement that was signed executed in
writing that you could take deport
hurray for agreement
[Music]