[Music]
we're going to talk about why agreements
and contracts are so important and how
they set you up for success for the
long-term of your business
collectively on the panel today you've
got probably two to three decades worth
of legal experience which is a really
invaluable lesson as we charter these
waters that are consistently evolving
and turbulent during the emergence of
cannabis regulation here in California
and across the country if not the globe
so first I'd like to outline what we're
gonna talk about this evening we're
gonna go through investment agreements
and then agreements throughout the
cannabis supply chain focusing on what
that supply chain looks like here in
California first and foremost I don't
know all of you but I say this
consistently as we talk about investment
agreements moving into 2019 the way that
I look at it for my clients is that
you've got three options as you move
throughout this process you're going to
be an acquisition target and whether or
not you are the crown jewel and
somebody's Canadian IPO which is the
topic to shore at the moment is going to
be how well you are set up with your
contracts and your internal structure or
you're going to be able to survive an
acquisition event otherwise you will be
extinct if there is no secret option
number four and in order for you to
survive in one of the first two buckets
and be a desirable acquisition target
you need to have good investment
agreements so with that I'd like to open
it up to our panel to
advise or give an overview of what are
some of the fundamentals for in good
investment agreements startups and what
you look for on the back end during a
due diligence check as an acquisition
target you can start with Michelle if
you've been in the industry longer than
the last two years then you know that
back in the day pre legalization
papering up or making contracts between
businesses and other businesses or their
investors was never really something
people did the whole point was to not
leave a paper trail to avoid getting
arrested by the cops etc so now that
we're moving into legalization you know
now it's getting better
getting people to learn how to be
comfortable with us papering up
everything so back five years ago it
would be a very typical deal where
someone's cousins friends lawyer brother
or something gives a 100 grand cash to a
dispensary and then I promise I'll give
you 10% of my proceeds that's not gonna
fly anymore you know now we have to pay
for up all those investor agreements
these private offerings and it's a lot
of paper and there's a lot of due
diligence involved and again back to the
same problem of not keeping a paper
trail due diligence is a challenge in a
company that isn't accustomed to keeping
accurate books lots of these companies
books are cooked they handwritten
receipts it's very hard to get a true
accurate feel of what a company's
financials are are so investors have a
unique challenge in this and industry
than they do in any others and it's very
hard to value a company for those
reasons there's a lot of obviously
cannabis related disclosures that you
have to put in your investor Docs things
like you know telling potential
investors that cannabis businesses are
subject to
AEE and don't have access to banking so
you can't really properly track your
investment where all your funds are
going mix it's not really for the
faint-hearted investor but you know
these are all kind of things depending
on the nature of the transaction how
much money is involved a accredited
investor or not accredited investor
there's a lot of different things that
go into it and it's kind of really
specific to each situation but the over
arching the premise is that you need to
have you need to be properly papered up
for two primary reasons one you face
extinction after being acquired you face
crazy securities fraud related
accusations charges fines whatsoever you
know what have you and then you also if
you're gonna try to impress a legit
investor and they see that you don't
have things buttoned up on paper they're
really gonna think less of your company
and whether or not you're a viable
investment so all around it's a it's a
challenging transition but and it's not
a easy one to go through but there are a
lot of different things to go through
that are very specific to cannabis so
I'm Michael Chernus I've been an
attorney for more than I care more years
than I care to tell you and been
practicing in the cannabis space for ten
years and the ten years has seen a lot
of changes in terms of what all work is
because it used to be keeping you out of
jail and trying to keep you out of
trouble and now it's really about
protecting you as Michele said through
papering transactions and and in that
way it's not unlike any other industry
there are nuances having to do with
federal issues and there's uniqueness
about the regulations that that you have
to deal with in the cannabis space but
with respect to investing in startups
what what I've seen
when I've been brought in to like
private equity transactions
recently is there are challenges that
are unique to cannabis and I think one
of the challenges is this is a brand new
industry we're in day one how do you
evaluate a company's financials when
there's no history to base it on how do
you evaluate their for any of this stuff
in other industries when you're making
an investment you have some track record
maybe to look at or at least you have a
track record of an industry that's or
another comp in the industry here you
don't have that at all so I can't tell
you how many times I mean it happens
today a client who want to invest six
million dollars to buy a piece of
property and these licenses and the
financials project blah blah I'm like I
don't even listen after that the
financials are just there made up
because there's no history it's not to
say that financials have no basis in
reality but you really need to dig in
and try to get underneath these
financials there's different ways of
valuing companies there's different ways
of doing financial projections and you
it's really incumbent upon you to look
beneath the paper and try to get some
understanding of where the numbers came
from so that's one huge issue another
huge issue that we keep coming across
especially if you're gonna be on the
debt side and you're gonna do a debt
transaction that maybe involves a
convertible note where if the borrower
doesn't meet its obligations your debt
turns to equity the question is so now
I'm an equity holder in a licensed
business how am I gonna actually
effectuate that ownership because every
city has limitations on how licenses can
be transferred so you may now be the
owner the equity holder in a licensed
entity in LA or some other city but is
LA gonna honor your rights as an equity
holder are you gonna be able to execute
upon that interest
those are huge questions that
know that anyone really has a good
answer to and then there's there's other
nuances that keep popping up like we're
investing in a company that is a non
profit mutual benefit corporation it's
supposed to convert to a for-profit
entity it hasn't happened yet are there
going to be problems with that so those
are some sort of unique things that we
keep coming across as well as you know
potential liabilities that we maybe if
you're an investor potential liabilities
that may pre-exists your investment a
lot of which are hard to calculate
because not all these businesses have
great track records and just to give you
an example you may be investing in or
acquiring an entity that's been
operating under the collective model for
five or ten years but maybe they didn't
pay any sales tax what is your
responsibility for that who's gonna
carry that liability so from my
perspective as somebody who's to do a
lot of litigation but the due diligence
focuses on those kinds of issues
liabilities what's gonna happen if
things go sideways will I be able to
execute on my interest okay I'd like to
know from you since you're representing
growth companies from idea to exit which
I like as we see the great constriction
or consolidation of the market with M&amp;A
because some operators maybe got a
license but didn't have enough money to
effectuate that license to get it
through Landry's entitlement to
operation how are you advising clients
and what would you suggest for
maneuvering through that M&amp;A process I'm
Jay I work at Clark Newburgh were
women-owned law firm in San Francisco
Sacramento Santa Barbara in Los Angeles
I grew up to be a corporate lawyer which
everybody dreams about becoming when
they're little and the neat thing that
we get to do is help little companies
try and become bigger companies right
being an entrepreneur is super difficult
in any industry cannabis
that much harder a couple thoughts one
of them is no one ever regretted
spending too much time with their
attorney right people regret like not
having flood insurance people regret not
spending enough time with their attorney
find an attorney you like and you're
willing to say I screwed or even a curse
word find an attorney you're really
willing to share what's going wrong
you'll never regret it
corporate law is moving really quickly
especially around cannabis lots of
companies have been operating with non
profit mutual benefit corporations with
LLC's with corporations spreading their
operations between different companies
for years filing inconsistent tax things
all of this can be fixed but the sooner
you start the better which I've heard
the other panelists talk about there's a
planning process that you can really go
through to clean some of these things up
before you become in this M&amp;A process
the biggest challenges we see are
companies who don't realize until it's
too late we have companies come to us
and somebody wants to buy them for
millions of dollars and they're so
excited and it turns out they never
actually purchase stock in their own
company
this isn't rare because they thought
they had done it because maybe a couple
years ago they're cousins friends
husbands neighbors nephew got them set
up with a non profit mutual benefit and
they started operating but they never
actually purchased any equity in a
company the crystal equity where they
never issued themselves membership
interest in their nonprofit and we say
there's this universe of acronyms that
you've got to get a hold of and you can
get a hold of there's also I'm trying to
find a nice way to say this but there's
not always awesome advice but there's a
lot of people giving it
accredited investors hasn't been
requirement in since November of 2016
right some of your investors will be
concerned about this but many of your
investors shouldn't be concerned about
this at all all of your companies can
raise up to five million dollars with
zero accredited investors you don't have
to disclose anything to them this has
been an SEC rule since November of 2016
and I'm not saying you should do that
but it's an option that's available to
everybody the most important thing that
I think cannabis companies need to know
is this corporate law stuff can destroy
you but it can also empower you if you
set this up right you'll get great tax
rates if you set this up right you'll
have clear ownership
you'll feel empowered to raise money
through convertible notes to find a
great M&amp;A exit but this is really one of
those like you have to get your vaccines
you have to spend more time and money on
this then you want to early because if
you don't you get that horrible news
that somebody wants to buy you for ten
million dollars but you don't own any
stock in your own company like that
happens because people are confused
about what they actually purchased a
couple years ago if you find out too
late you don't own stock you think okay
I'll just buy it but if you buy it today
and sell it tomorrow
you get nailed on taxes you could lose
like a third of the ten million dollars
that you're hoping to get I know much
more about investment stuff then I will
about the supply chain stuff so so I'm
gonna okay I'll finish up but on the
deal with corporate law is it's scary at
first and then it's really empowering
right it can like really the purpose of
the Corporations code is to let you
start companies that grow and expand and
become more valuable and they can do
that cannabis companies like any other
companies should use the Corporations
code to build and they can do that and
you can do that with a lawyer you love
with a lawyer you love happily every day
Lord Allah love your lawyer love you a
lawyer Albatros that takes you down if
you don't invest in it it's very
difficult and it hurts right it hurts to
have to spend that money it hurts more
later when either you can't take ten
million dollars or your evaluation
should be a tax and all the sudden
you're getting pennies on the dollar
because when somebody does your due
diligence when they look up your
proverbial skirt as a business and they
see you haven't kept minutes ever right
they asked for a corporate book which is
very simple and when you're doing a due
diligence and you don't have one you
can't show the train of events and
transactions that you've had then all
the sudden this valuation you have this
great business that you put your time
energy sweat tears into all the sudden
becomes greatly diminished and somebody
can say that to you simply by not having
records and not loving your lawyer so
with that building blocks or with that
framework in mind really we want to turn
to the devil in the details and that
comes with how are you going to run your
business prior to finding that exit
strategy and that's where we want to
look at how the supply chain acts and
how agreements with between supply chain
actors occur I think we can start at the
natural place which is cultivation right
we have no industry if we have no
cultivated flour to then turn into other
manufactured products or sell at the
dispensaries and so with that comes
sourcing agreement and how if you're a
manufacturer do you go about sourcing
your products and what does that mean
how do you interface between a
cultivator and either a distributor or
cultivator and a manufacturer and what
has our panelists been exposed to and
how do they advise operators to maneuver
if somebody comes to them and says I
want to purchase from you X number of
pounds a month or a supply any time
you're dealing with a cultivator you're
gonna have to deal I guess any operator
between any awkward you're gonna have to
deal with your distributor so the
distributor contracts and the connection
between the cultivator and the
manufacturer or the cultivator and the
retailer you're all going through the
distributor so that are kind of that the
mandatory middleman and that's where all
the details get a little confusing the
we've been seeing a lot of a lot of our
at least my work load lately has been
dealing with these distribution
contracts in light of the new
regulations which as we all know keep
changing which we probably won't expect
a final version that's adopted until wet
like early 2019 something like that so
these distribution contracts and at
least I've been seeing they they change
they look completely different when they
were first started up last November and
they're evolving as the regs are
evolving and now it's a completely new
template or new beast and every single
time we have to take a look at it but
things like from the cultivator to the
manufacturer I guess I'll just use like
a case study let's say we have a grower
in Salinas County a green house who
wants and we got an L a manufacturer who
wants to source the the the Sun grown
from up there does how do we get it down
there does the cultivator have a
distribution license can the cultivator
who has the distribution license
transport that down to LA or does the
manufacturer in LA have a distribution
license can the manufacturer use its
distribution license to go up north and
go get the flower itself or do we just
use a third-party distributor who has a
transport only license to just take it
from A to B
so you there's a million ways to skin a
cat each business has its own licenses
as its own internal strategies what have
you but but depending on who's gonna do
that part that just the transportation
the testing of you know collection of
the excise taxes that's all distributor
so you got to really make sure whatever
distributor you use whether your self
distributing or using another party you
got to make sure you trust that
distributor that distributor is buttoned
up is a good operator knows what it's
doing and in those contracts there's a
lot of and then there's other things to
think about is that distributor not only
transporting and testing but are they
gonna be packaging for you you're doing
all the you know the packaging and
labeling compliance so someone else
could even do that part for you you can
add another party just a straight
packaging company and so you got to
figure out where all these players who
are gonna fit all these pieces whether
that's you by yourself or up to four
different companies who knows and
depending on how that business structure
is modeled then you can kind of get into
what this contract is gonna say and what
that contract is gonna say it's gonna
give delineate everyone's roles and
responsibilities and obligations clearly
it's gonna determine things like if the
packaging ends up being non-compliant or
if the product gets recalled due to
contamination who's footing the bill for
that who's responsibility is it are you
splitting the baby how are you gonna
figure that out and we got a lot of I
got a lot of people asking me well
what's the standard what's the standard
rate for distribution fees there's no
such thing as a standard rate in
cannabis there's no such thing as
standard anything in cannabis so those
are all business questions how you get
up those numbers how many different
operators you're involving in this
supply chain really will impact how you
structure your contract but at the end
of the day the most important thing
a lot of people just go into the
contract hoping look they're gonna make
my product for me I'm a brand they're
just gonna make it for me and they're
gonna sell it out and they're gonna give
me
royalty fees for it's not that simple
you guys got to throw in all this other
stuff about what happens in the worst
case scenarios we're gonna be the debbie
downer attorneys who tell you about how
easy it is to get married but how
difficult it is to get divorced but it's
very true
so you got to contemplate all these
worst-case scenarios and figure out
beforehand and agree beforehand what's
gonna happen like I was tiling Pam
earlier we've got I've encountered a
brand who is a brand that was co-packing
with another manufacturer that
manufacturer use a distributor licensee
transport only to you know transport
product from A to B to the retailer that
distributor has all the cash taking it
back to the manufacturer and gets pulled
over by ATF one hundred and eighty
thousand dollars in cash seized federal
forfeiture and now the parties are
fighting about you file the forfeiture
action a you file the forfeiture action
we got the licensee who doesn't want to
raise any red flags you obviously got
the brand who wants their money but you
know now you got this an uncomfortable
situation where there's a lot of money
that you need to get back but no one can
agree on how to do so so think about
horror stories like that prepare in
advance I know it's no fun but it you'll
you'll thank yourself for it later we've
seen a lot of brands that were very
profitable and knowledgeable prior to
regulation where you had to go and
source a license they have a brand so
they have something that they can
license in the market where somebody
else was able to capitalize on securing
a property and getting through licensure
how do you go about doing these
licensing
agreements so that your brand can
survive through another licensee they
think that is something that is of
interest and is a very vexing
complicated area of putting those
contracts together
I actually know the answer to that
question but before I before I get into
that I just want to touch on the
cultivation issue what makes the
cultivation and the manufacturing a
little bit different as far as I'm
concerned is cultivation your product
can go down two paths it can go to the
distributor retailer path which makes it
similar to manufacturing and then as
Michelle was alluding to you're dealing
with issues of who's gonna package it
you're gonna package it yourself you can
have the distributor do it the testing
all that risk of loss stuff which is a
big issue risk of loss or you can agree
that some or all of your product is
going to go to a manufacturer to be
turned into brownies and oil and
concentrates and if you go down that
path in some ways I think your life is a
little simpler because you don't have to
deal with a distributor for that piece
of it you can just have somebody
transport it there's no testing that's
required by state law before it goes to
the manufacturer you should certainly
test it on your own but these are two
very different paths I mean I have some
clients that are doing rows where all
product just gets freeze I think it's
called free shipped directly to a
manufacturer to turn into oil and then
other people obviously they want to get
their product out there is flour and as
a brand so those are very different
paths and they involve different
different contracts and considerations
and then you know there are these
concepts and maybe Jay could talk more
about it but you can enter into a
requirements contract if you're a
distributor or a retailer where a
cultivator has to meet all of your
requirements and give you as much flour
as they as they can produce and if
you're on the other side of you're a
cultivator there are contracts where
basically
you may be obligated to give all of your
flower to a particular distributor or
retailer as much as they want so there
are different ways of like engineering
those kinds of contracts but the
question that Pam asked me which is
really I think a an interesting question
is we're a brand we have some traction
out there but we don't have the means to
get a license we don't want to get a
license we don't want to spend all that
money on real estate how do we stay out
there and actually I think what at least
when I'm seeing is there's a lot of
brands out there that have just opted
like it makes more sense to not have to
go through the hassle of hiring someone
like me or Pam to get a license and
instead we can just hire someone like
Michelle to negotiate a contract between
the brand and the and the manufacturer
so white labeling is huge I have a
client and Michelle and I have been
actually on opposite sides of a
transaction where she represents a brand
my client makes the stuff my client
packages it my client distributes it her
client designs it so and that model that
white label model and for those of you
that don't know the terminology
essentially there's a manufacturer out
there that's got a license to
manufacture they have the machines they
make the oil and they can put her
clients label on it or J's clients label
on it or my clients label on it and
maybe there's some there's gonna be
nuances and differences in terms of the
mixtures and the terpenes and the blends
and all that but that is a different and
in some ways much more affordable model
for a brand to survive what makes it
challenge
social media I mean I have clients that
have brands and you would think by their
social media like their Apple but really
they're very small but the social media
and the PR makes them seem much bigger
than they really are
but in those contracts there are so many
complexities
because you have the brand on one side
which hopefully owns intellectual
property which is like a whole separate
conversation how to acquire it what it
is and then you license the intellectual
property to the manufacturer so the
manufacturer can put it together and
sell it and then the manufacturer will
either turn it over to a distributor or
there'll be the distributor and so all
those different pieces have to be worked
out it's not super complicated but there
are some details again dealing with
who's gonna have insurance what happens
if a product is contaminated whose
responsibility is that well you design
the cartridges the cartridges are
defective well you put the cartridges
together with the packaging it's your
fault so those kinds of issues have to
be worked out and honestly I don't think
they're unique to cannabis they're just
unique for everyone in this room because
it used to be that you just grew it put
it in a bag brought it to the dispensary
and you just waited for your money but
now it's a little bit more complicated
and it's a little bit more mainstream I
think it's helpful sometimes imagine um
somebody's like behind a soundboard with
like 16 different like levers to twist
right that's a commercial contract one
of the levers is who's responsible which
percent you or me it's responsible if it
gets seized in process right between the
two places are you 100% or my a hundred
percent like there's a knob how many
days late is the product before there's
a penalty that's another knob so each
one of you probably has one or two
transactions you're constantly doing if
you're a cultivator you're constantly
selling to dispensaries or to
distributors or to manufacturers if
you're a manufacturer you're constantly
buying from cultivators and maybe you're
sending it out to distributors there's
one or two deals you're constantly doing
spend a couple hours with one of these
people and figure out what are like the
ten things you're always negotiating in
those two transactions
what are the 10 things you always have
to deal with and then they'll tell you
the six ones you're not thinking of
spend the time get to good form
agreements for the two deals you do
every day right and then get a little
familiar with the ten different knobs
because wool writer and Greek but you
guys can negotiate with your
counterparties you know what 15 days is
too many okay so this parts gonna be 15
days who should bear the risk if it gets
seized in the road who should bear the
risk if it gets moldy like these 16
different knobs
you know when Google sells something it
doesn't do a new contract each time it
takes the form of selling stuff and then
goes and it sales people fill in the
blanks it's more complicated than that
but you want to have a couple forms that
you use all the time so that you're not
reinventing the wheel right so think
hard about what are the two or three
things you're doing several times a week
or that constitute like the bulk of your
sales and your purchases and then invest
like make this tool make this template
the goal for us is you get this really
polished like mercedes-benz that you can
drive because you know how to use the so
we got like a soundboard we got a car we
got all kinds of things but the goal is
for you to get this tool that you can
use all the time there are a lot of
knobs it does get really intricate but
you probably do one or two transactions
several times a week right like this
will get commodified and the sooner you
can have some like confidence in what
you're doing I think the sooner this
will get demystified right because we're
buying and selling agricultural products
that become finished products
you can you guys know how to do the
business side of it we can show you how
to do the legal side of it and then it's
perfect I mean what Jay said was really
empowering to you to be able to ask
those questions and the only way that it
will become normalized that agreements
are the mainstay of this industry is by
you as operators requesting them of each
other because I think it's important to
note that we can sit up here tell you
how important agreements are but unless
you were willing to invest in them
invest in yourselves and ask that of
each other as operators that's the only
way we're gonna see this normalization
now we've also talked about regulatory
changes we're seeing those potentially
coming by the end of the week we've also
seen some interesting legislation which
as we've talked about distribution
agreements I it's interesting some of
you in the room may be distributors what
does SB 311 have come into play it was
an urgency bill it came into effect
right away as soon as it was signed and
it allows for distribution to
distribution transfers right
distribution agreements down the line
the storage only part of what
distribution movement throughout the
state means a few of our products coming
from up and humbled and it needs to get
down into LA and we're also under this
California driving restrictions you can
only have a driver in the car eight
hours you can only stop in a secured
area when your store product and these
COAS are moving along the supply chain
how has that affected distribution
agreements and how you're advising
clients JC your heads shaking vigorously
so you have some common I just moved
here from Oakland so a lot of my clients
are still in North Bay and they spent a
lot of time like looking at naps to
figure out how long does it take to
drive from Mendocino like how far could
they get before the driver needed to
like stop and where could they get
licenses and I think at this point they
have a license in Culver City they have
a license in Mendo and that's kind of as
far as they can go
I unfortunately don't know about this
new legislation that it sounds like will
change their business plan so you should
talk to my clients I feel like I should
be the moderator and you should be on
the panel but she knows that she knows a
lot so so SB 311 has to do with sort of
plugging a gap that was or a disconnect
between mikasa and the regulations
mikasa had contemplated that the product
would go from manufacturer to
distributor from distributor to retailer
or from cultivator to distributor
distributor to retailer but you have
these distributors that are up here and
you have retailers down here and the
logistics of it made it really
challenging so the regulations
contemplated that you could have a
storage only or transport only
distributor where there could basically
be a handoff from the primary
distributor if they will if you will to
somebody else that would then take the
product the rest of the way or store it
so that it could then go from your spot
to the retailer because so the way they
divide up the responsibility is that the
product can't leave the cultivator if
it's finished product it can't leave the
cultivator and if it's finished product
it can't leave the manufacturer until
it's batch tested and it goes to a
quality control check so the distributor
is in charge of that
the distributor can then take it from
their facility to the retailer or the
facility or the distributor can take it
to another distributor who would then
store it and then transport it to the
retailer without that second distributor
having to go through the same batch
testing and quality control process so
what SB 311 did again is it reconciled
mikasa with a change in the regular
nations that had authorized that sort of
secondary use of a distributor so if
you're a distributor what SB 311 now
allows you to do is essentially
piggyback on another distributor that
might be located a little closer to the
ultimate destination the products are
going to but here's the wrinkle the
money so the distributors are performing
generally like five different functions
they perform a quality control function
to make sure the product is labeled
correctly they promote they perform the
batch testing process to make sure it
gets batch tested before it gets
released they have to collect
cultivation taxes they have to collect
excise taxes they have to then remit
those taxes to the California ftda or
whatever it's now called and then they
have to transport it but if you're now
using that transport only person to do
part of the transport how do you divvy
up the dough how does who gets what like
that's a nuance that again like there's
no right answer for that there are sort
of some standard rates that are out
there but it's just another thing to
think about if you're if you're a
product manufacturer or if you're a
brand I am in LA but I want my stuff to
be in the Bay Area how am I gonna get it
there who's gonna be in charge of that
is it me is it my distributor is it my
manufacturer these are all things to
kind of be worked out there are nuances
to nuances exceptions to exemptions this
is how contracting works and talking
about distribution one of my favorite
agreements that comes off of a
distribution agreement is testing lab
agreements and it's ones that I don't
see done often enough especially with
distributors - testing labs and riffing
off of that is recall procedures every
distributor should have recall
procedures if and when there is an issue
with a testing lab I know we're gonna
hear from operators later but one of the
critical components of why testing lab
recruitments are important is we
testing lab equipment is very sensitive
and it is very expensive and anytime you
have sensitive and expensive equipment
the subsidiary to that is that it will
at some times fail or need to be
recalibrated and what happens from the
bcc's point of view is that anytime the
bcc sees discrepancies that are too wide
and you as a testing lab can no longer
issue a coa or certificate of analysis
what happens in the following situation
that i will present to our panelists
it's called a legal workshop in this
situation where you would have a testing
lab who was taking in product there
discrepancies were being called into
question by the bcc and in in this entry
room where they're trying to work with
the bcc they continue to take in batch
samples from a distributor that
distributors product is then in cue from
the current regulations pursuant to the
readapted regulations that we're working
under it says that if the bcc were to
pull that testing labs ability to issue
a cui then all of the products is
stopped in the pipeline because it
cannot go to another testing lab either
a testing lab that is owned by that
testing lab licensee if it has multiple
labs it can't move it and it can't
contract with another licensed testing
lab to test that product so that product
is sitting either the batch samples are
sitting at the testing lab and have you
made an arrangement between the testing
lab and the distributor if you have to
take a secondary set of batch sample
testing or if it's sitting not at your
distributors warehouse it's sitting in a
transport only storage storage
distributor it's taking up space there
and how long can it take up space so
what is a distributor and then therefore
a manufacturer or cultivator who's
waiting for this product to be released
do in that situation and it's
interesting to note these are white
testing lab agreements are important the
only licensed type in the entire supply
chain that the BCC and their infinite
wisdom has said does not need to carry
insurance is a testing lab so what is it
that you would advise your client to do
and I'm gonna section you all if you
were the testing if you were
representing the testing licensee if you
were representing the distributor or if
you were representing a manufacturer or
cultivator who had given their product
to a distributor so if anybody wants to
jump out first and say who they yes
we're gonna roleplay this who is who if
you want to represent one of these
clients raise your hand or I will assign
them I do it at random okay Michelle you
are going to represent the cultivator or
the manufacturer Michael you're going to
represent the testing lab and J you're
going to represent the distributor what
do you advise your client once the bcc
has pulled your the testing labs ability
to issue any more cos and the product
has already been taken in do you if you
guys agree to switch roles you can
Michael who said I could issue it it's
already been done and we're gonna
highlight why you need to have a good
contract so what would you advise them
if in the situation that we have now
where they have not contracted and what
would you have advised them originally
so we can see what this agree why
agreements are so important even though
as a testing lab maybe you're not
obligated to carry insurance you're I
mean it would be it would be
unimaginable not to happen they would I
can't imagine that they wouldn't have
insurance and and honestly like I think
the magic that would happen here is in
having an insurance policy that
contemplates this
kind of scenario like I give you I gave
you I give you amazing credit for having
thought this up because I don't think a
lot of people are at this level where
they're thinking of this issue what
happens when you're the manufacturer and
you've entrusted your product to my
client and my clot it my client
basically has a freeze order my client
is unable to continue doing operations
hopefully my client has insurance but
really our hands are tied and the issue
I think has to do with hopefully
contemplating in advance what that this
scenario and apportioning the risk of
loss but I would imagine frankly that
everybody has insurance that would
address what is amounts to a business
interruption situation that's my two
cents
not that I wouldn't love to take credit
for fully coming up with this
hypothetical but it is in part based in
an actual client issue or issues that
are occurring I would say and it is
interesting to note that sometimes
testing labs can actually be the most
difficult to insure I'm sure that we
will hear about that in our next panel
where the operators are discussing it
but they are not always able to provide
the level of insurance of these types of
situations and business interruptions
because this is what you're contracted
to do so if your shut down by the BCC
and you've been potentially issued a
prior warning about the situation and
you're still in taking products how does
that affect your contract negotiations
right because the BCC by the time
they're pulling your ability to issue a
test there have been multiple steps
where they've intervened because they've
seen an issue usually you're not having
such a jarring circumstance where the
BCC is coming in unannounced so at what
point and have you previously contracted
for it if you are the distributor or
the manufacturer cultivator to say you
shouldn't be taking in any additional
tests with this oversight that you are
not allowed to cure the issue on the
back end once you take it in-house so I
don't know if we want to look at it from
a distributors point of view I don't
know the answer to this question it's a
strong question I what occurred to me
was to say to some of my clients this is
a good exercise for everyone ask your
Lord here are the three things most
likely to go wrong here are the three
things we know are going to go wrong in
the next two years do our form
agreements provide for what to do in
that scenario you talked about risk
factors a couple minutes ago the way
companies often come up with risk
factors is they sit in a room and say if
we miss next quarter what will have
happened to cause that like what are our
likely failure patterns basically I
didn't think of this failure pattern for
testing companies it seems like we
should think about it but if you ever do
sit in a room with your lawyers for
three hours and say we want to come up
with a really good form say to them at
some point here are the three things
that are going to go wrong in the next
four years they're going to happen at
some point we want our agreements to
provide for some path out of that
everything is a defect everything has
some failure rate and that's fine your
agreements can provide for like a detour
for you know what's the I don't want to
see self-destruct button but alike happy
route out of a jam a parachute that's
great that's great that's great yep well
usually cultivators and manufacturers
even now nowadays they very rarely are
not gonna have a contract already in
place so first things first let's take a
look at the contract that's in place
which hopefully is a good one hopefully
it it it passed the buck off to the
distributor it's the distributor's
problem hopefully there's
indemnification clauses in there
protecting the cultivator and if it's a
really really bad contract and it
doesn't give you all those
safety nets then we're still gonna
analyze the contract which hopefully
exists for for at least breach breach
causes of action and it's you know it
also kind of depends whether or not
there was a contract between just the
cultivator and the distributor or also
was the cultivator having a had a
contract relationship with the testing
laboratory then that's called privity by
the way well do the contract who did the
cultivator had privity with the
distributor the lab everyone up the
chain so you kind of need to assess
who's liable to who who has a duty to
whom in this in this supply chain
situation once you analyze the contract
and it kind of smells like good
old-fashioned litigation with the
testing lab that's how you're probably
gonna end up getting your money yeah so
we'll do though we'll do that we'll do
it that way I'm suing your lab my right
and whether you're doing it in concert
with the distributor or not or whether
you're suing your distributor because
remember when do you pay the money when
have you contracted for that release of
the money for the products because J and
I'm sure you're sitting in this
situation is the distributor I don't
want to pay the cultivator or the
manufacturer until I get a clean CoA
right because I can't resell it so if
you're taking it in at what point to
your point about the knobs and the
levers when is payment being released
and so there's a lot of different
nuances in this one fact pattern we
started in one place and we're talking
about 17 other different issues that
take you down a different path I think
what you've heard and what you've
experienced with this exercise is that
there is no one right way to do a
contract and there are multiple
different parties that are gonna
experience different levels of
discomfort when things go wrong and they
do so to riff off of this example which
I also think is important is talking
about both recalls and defects because
this is something that I'm sure if you
all of your operating is a big question
I've been
this question by some of my operators
well if I don't like a product and I
take it in can I destroy it as defective
it's not selling no you cannot
defective has a very specific reason it
is already a term of art in what is it
California Code of regulations what is a
product defect it literally has to be
defective that does not mean it doesn't
move off your shelves that does not mean
that people don't like it but what
happens when there's truly a recall what
happens in an instance again with a
testing lab a CoA comes back and then
all of a sudden there's a discrepancy
and after 24 hours or 48 hours and let
me tell you once a CoA comes in product
is moving right it's going from the
distributor to a retailer so within 48
hours even 24 hours sometimes product is
on a shelf and so what happens and in
how far can a testing lab if they have
to start issuing a recall because there
was an actual discrepancy in the CoA
that was reported how is that
manifesting itself and there are you
know there are only specific required
recall procedures for the Department of
Public Health right although even though
it doesn't say it for the BCC or for DFA
they don't have specific outline recall
procedures if you're a distributor your
requirement for the BCC is to provide
inventory control and recall procedures
so it doesn't necessarily matter where
they are housed between the three
agencies at the end of the day this is
the distributor has to have this in
their inventory control plan as does a
retailer how do you go about doing that
and whose responsibility is that and
where is it in your plan bringing it all
the way back to what Michael originally
said about either applications or
licensing your product if you're you
know advise clients as they move forward
with this and you're doing a licensing
agreement and your licensing agreement
with your brand also has to contemplate
brand reputation what do you do in a
recall procedure there is that
something that you would negotiate
between the in a white labeling
agreement if you have to do that to
protect that brand integrity where does
that happen
does it happen with the distributor is
that part of a distributor or
conversation with the testing lab or a
distributor with manufacturer cultivator
I'll let you guys opine on that well in
the case Michael and I have our my
client the brand is responsible for
designing the product designing the
packaging making it nice and pretty
Michael's distributor / manufacturer
client is responsible for assembling at
all making sure what my client prepared
is compliant with packaging and labeling
etc making sure the product the actual
extraction actual assembly is conducted
by Michaels client so there's obviously
two very distinct roles here kind of
some overlapping I guess in the
packaging and labeling compliance area
but in our situation you know we put
recalls you know who's responsible for
recalls is depending on what the recall
was for if it was packaging and
compliance
I am packaging and labeling I think we
slipped a baby on that because of our
our shared rules in it if it was due
completely to product contamination or
something that Michaels client did he
was responsible for that so that's kind
of the the fair approach that we took
with that at least does anyone still
want to be in this business like so so
so you know he listening to us talk Ike
and imagining myself over there I would
imagine that this is distressing but
there the reality is the good news is
that there are lawyers out there that
and they don't even have to necessarily
be cannabis lawyers but it's probably
better that they are but there are
lawyers out there that can help you with
these problems
like you make the stuff we hell it's
it's like what Jay said we we we
collaborate with one another so we get
paid and we stay up late at night to
think about these issues so that you
don't have to think about them the
reality is that that you could you'll
never anticipate in a contract all of
the things that can go sideways because
if you did then there wouldn't be a need
for litigators because what litigators
do is they litigate the gray areas and
while as a former litigator it's you can
reverse engineer where disputes have
happened in the past and try to keep
them from happening in the future by
addressing them in better prepared
contracts you could have a contract
that's 100 pages long and you'll never
anticipate things that you haven't
anticipated there you just can't so you
can include in a contract
hopefully you'll address like as Jay
said you'll identify the ten things that
really matter and you'll scope it out
what happens if somebody steals
something what happens if it fails a
test what happens if the product doesn't
taste the way it's supposed to taste
who's responsible for that and then
there's like a bunch of stuff that no
one's thought of you can cut put in a
contract some catch-all provisions that
protect you and I think actually
Michelle in the contract that we did
added some language that I thought was
really great for her client and didn't
really rub me the wrong way and it it
was broad enough to kind of protect
against an unanticipated situation it
was something like hey listen you're
making my company's product you know our
reputation our goodwill is on the line
like carry yourself accordingly to
protect us so it's sort of like a
provision that maybe if there's no other
provision in a contract that
specifically addresses a situation
creates a duty on my client's part and
that if I fail to do something that's
maybe not specifically or expressly
addressed her client can rely on it to
say hey dude look you really knew better
and you
should have done that better so I guess
what I'm saying is don't don't be
distressed and try to trust us to help
you as far as the specific question that
you were asking I honestly filibustered
and I don't remember what it was but I
know I had a really good answer for it
that's save for later so that everybody
stays he'll figure it out and come back
at the end I'd open it up to everybody
else's questions cuz you've listened you
I'm sure all understand that the devil
is in the details and you should what
love your lawyer it's like my new
favorite saying but does anybody have
any questions as we wrap up one into the
question was we've been focused on see
corpse but what is the benefit or why
how would you advise between a c-corp
and LLC incorporation so at the point
where you're selling your company you're
probably either one or the other so you
wouldn't have the ability to change if
you go from a corporation to an LLC
you'll get a big tax basically when
you're selling your company you want to
get long-term capital gains you could
get that either as an LLC or as a
corporation so from the sellers
perspective it doesn't really matter
because you want the same tax treatment
either way from the buyer's perspective
there's a whole bunch of other factors
that go into it
you can convert from an LLC to a Corp or
former Corp to an LLC one of those paths
is expensive one of them is not but you
wouldn't do that right before the
acquisition because you would kind of
eliminate the goal long story short it
doesn't really matter if you're an al
Asiri corporation when you get sold for
your personal tax consequence don't
worry about that the only thing I would
add is that that that whole issue of
what do we want to be and when it comes
up at the startup phase it's not one
size
it's all I mean personally I prefer
using LLC's because I find them easier
to work with in corporations but they
have different tax consequences there
are different there are ways of turning
LLC tax consequences into the same as
corporate tax consequences in terms of
like using an S Corp or just having an
LLC that's taxed like a corporation but
corporations and LLC's have are taxed
very differently there are different
280e consequences especially from the
purview of state law which is a
complicated issue I'm sorry I brought up
but I can talk to you about it
afterwards but it's definitely not
one-size-fits-all and I don't mean J
would know better than I but I don't
think I don't think there's a straight
answer for that it really depends on
your own circumstances depends if you're
in retail are you on the production side
what are your 280e consequences what's
your exposure to risk the question is
we're dealing with an industry that's
legal under state law that's illegal
under federal law and what's is there an
issue for enforceability of contracts is
that more or less it so I think
historically there was a larger concern
with contracts being invalidated both
under state law or in state courts and
in federal courts I'm not aware of since
the legalization effort I'm not aware of
any courts in California California
courts state courts refusing to enforce
a contract that selected California
courts as the forum I think a lot of
people are fearful that federal courts
will not enforce contracts and so they
will put in a contract a forum selection
clause that requires you to litigate in
federal court the thing I don't know is
I don't know if you ended up in federal
court if a federal court sitting in
California
would refuse to enforce that contract I
am not aware of that situation I'm
actually aware of some situations where
federal courts have in fact enforced
contracts I'm not aware of situations
where federal courts except for
bankruptcy courts have said no can't
touch it
it's illegal federally because at the
end of the day whether you're in federal
court or state court and even if you're
in federal court the federal court is
enforcing a contract that's governed by
state law and under state law it's
enforceable and it's legal but it's a
great question I don't know if anyone
else wants to chime in it's also
assuming that your contract is legal and
like it's between a legal licensed
operator and another legal licensed
operator if you are one or both of you
are in a legal business that probably
will be held and enforceable if you try
to enforce that contract in state court
there's a case called gullickson GU LOI
C KS o n it's a Northern District of
California so federal court case I think
late 2016 but the northern district
court basically said cannabis contract
that's okay because it's based in
California law there's a new law a year
and a half cannabis contracts are lawful
objects of Commerce in California
they're like selling water in California
he's right you want to stay out of
federal court and just to correct the
record when a corporation converts to an
LLC that's when there's this asset sale
type tax when an LLC converts to a
corporation that's a smooth tax
consequence
drop and drop the mic lawyer correction
disclaimer I would like to invite you to
thank the panelists with me who did such
a great job and imparted incredible
[Music]