[Music]
that quasar that's the same heating
element that Frenchie has on his food
isn't it yeah that's a lot of hash - you
keep doing what you're doing that's a
lot of happen what are we what are we
smoking here that one is from the girl
off this year it's said an orchid
gorilla yeah the NorCal grow off it's a
funky strain we found out it was called
caramel cream caramel creams and what's
up that's a really interesting bud
structure and you've obviously smoked
this oh yeah
we're just starting to get into it
and what are your thoughts on it it's
kind of interesting hi Shannon I had
some earlier was it today or yesterday
and it reminds me of a headband okay
yeah cuz you get that you know that
feeling of wonder your forehead and then
we enjoy that you're very
non-discriminatory yeah so that's all
right so and so where'd you pick the you
pick you everyone gets phones right so
we're gonna phones from where was the
drop this year it was up at Satori
wellness okay up in the Kennedy Hill
pray yeah it's a great dispensary up
there I love heading up that way so we
did the pickup up there and we all got
our clones and what was funny is this
year the clone pickup was just the day
before the Meadowlands and so instead of
going all the way back down to Sonoma
County and then back up to Meadowlands
we wound up taking our clones camping
with us for three days at the
Meadowlands event and they stayed in a
teepee with us the day before I the day
before it was the day before Meadowlands
we had to pick up party up it's Tottori
wellness and then we all grabbed our
clones and there is there's a bunch of
us at wound up going back to Meadowlands
and camping with our clones well that's
how I was gonna ask like you bet you
like baby here oh yeah yeah we put a
teepee with us okay have a good time I
think so I think how could you not
mental ends is one of the best you know
it's like a big deep breath for
everybody to get out in the woods and
just stop drink and realize that God
knows we've been living in if I could go
hang
a campground with a bunch of other
people who like smoking we like one
Saturday a month or one weekend a month
that would be amazing
this guy's on top of this shit not the
beer and all the displays all right so
that's for somewhere here I quit
drinking last one I did not quit
drinking the alcohol does not stick to
the attic and yeah there's just a big
article on Yahoo Finance today about how
people doing can no Canales that was
beverage it's and and after about six
months all of the cannabinoids of step
to the liner's oh no cannabinoids in the
beverage really well like I like that
like Skycam an idea was doing a fucking
illegal dabs and venison he's like I
don't think a CVD water that said
normally does that give you over actual
water you guys it's got CBD in it to
shit's got electrolytes you bring the
Durbin poison oh you have it cuz
somebody is from tuning in from South
Africa and smoking a great local grown
cultivars there's a jar the Durbin right
here
fantastic Durban brought over by an
Rosenthal in the early seventies you and
the package
that's why Shannon should be on talking
about that yeah here's a sticker on the
stick that you're gonna get from me
[Music]
[Laughter]
that's one thing I said is as long as
I'm down here getting back up some tough
part so is this like the whole Fiddler's
greens lineup dad for the tinctures for
the tanker yeah it's just attention
their timing is amazing
[Laughter]
alright let's let's hold off alright so
tell me about the tincture is there
extracted solvent lessly right there is
no extract that's right it's an infusion
yeah there's strange specific whole
flower we grow the flowers ourselves on
our farm in Sonoma County we have the
very first primitive farm in Sonoma
County for outdoor cultivation and we've
been growing the ACDC for many years and
it loves the Petaluma windgap where
we're at Panama windgap and we infuse
the whole flower directly into organic
olive oil so we don't use an extraction
we don't use solvents or chemicals or
isolates or reconstituted funkiness just
whole plant goodness in organic first
pressed virgin olive oil and we do an
ac/dc for our high CBD strain we AG push
for our high THC strain and then our
kindred spirit it's a balanced blend of
both strains so you get the full
cannabinoid and terpene profile from
both strains and then we offer these
three in both the raw form in the tan
boxes and that's non decarboxylated
that's the flower as it is on the plant
so it's CBD a THC a CBG a all the acidic
cannabinoids which are extremely
bioavailable they work amazingly well at
low dose as a whole plant and like a raw
vegetable versus a cook that's been
actually way better for you and you need
less of it for the same efficacy exactly
and then we have the exact same three
but these have been decarboxylated
cannabis has to be heated to get you
high Jodi found a grocery store and got
a six pack and then came back with all
this stuff too so that's amazing you're
gonna get shit done exactly take care of
the bosses
that's like me with my parents when
they're playing go
like remember the scene with the old
couple and Caddyshack it's a peach one
that's like me and my parents on that my
mom's like half blind she can't see
where her balls go and they like dribble
like eight feet that way so I want to
talk brandy like where did the name
Fiddler's greens come from Fiddler's
greens is a mythological place its
sailors paradise it's where we go and we
die
it's where the music never ends the
dancers never tire and the cups are
always full and Shannon and I are both
sailors and have the nautical theme
there and it also has been adopted by a
lot of military the fort firebase and
hamlin province Afghanistan's Fiddler's
greens one of the I think it's the E
Club at Fort Sill Oklahoma they
artillery base is Fiddler's greens
there's hundreds of Irish pubs and eight
pillars green and that's you know the
myth is that once you go there when you
die it's kind of a purgatory before you
have to go to hell and us being sailors
we know we're going to hell and once
it's your time to go you fill your cup
up one last time from Fiddler's Green
and March off to the gates of hell but
if your cup gets empty before you reach
there you have to turn around and go
back to Fiddler's Green to refill it and
Rudyard Kipling wrote a great poem about
it that I believe the army cavalry they
you know I love it when we have the army
Cavett's come in because they'll come up
and recite the entire poem to us at the
booth all the time yeah it's it's pretty
cool and then we also named our
distribution company high-tide
distribution because we want to raise
all the ships and you know be I'm a boat
captain a sailing instructor and we just
had the knot of what I love is you want
to raise all ships and that was
definitely not the philosophy of all the
companies that are just imploding right
now mm-hmm
and it's like Karma's a bitch yeah
together we'll survive separately we're
all down you know I'd go fast we go
further you know and this is there's so
many people that get Sonoma County there
is an estimated 5,000 cultivators before
prop 64 and now there's 18 permits I
believe and that's not sustainable and
that's not what the communities about
and this is you know the people who have
been you know kept this go
the real rebels and misfits and outlaws
and and the people who you know had the
balls to do this when they were sending
helicopters and and jackbooted thugs and
guns after us and the bureaucrats are
ruining that and we can't stop now we've
got to keep going at them and change the
rules and change the laws and make it so
this plants available for everybody fuck
these hippies were just here to make
Kennedy on that board shouldn't he be a
crow three hundred feet from my house
and my parents won't let me have friends
over and my friend's parents won't let
the come over because they're afraid of
the grow near my house there's drug
dealers we're hanging out with tinctures
and that smoking weed so it gets to it
okay so so for example I take the CBD
THC blend because I smoke CBD and THC
all day I don't need those cannabinoids
so the raw tinctures like we were saying
or better for you but it's a they're
cannabinoids that people don't get that
often in their normal diets since the
Kemp started gross stopped growing
fairly the cows the pigs the chickens
don't eat anymore so we don't get as
part of our natural diet which we were
supposed to but was coffee nature was
made illegal so now any opportunity you
can get to get the rock in AB annoyance
he at the CBD a the THC a so confusing
at high super high CBD well so that for
example the ac/dc raw is a forty to one
CBD a to THC a so that is zero
yeah and these are those plays you're
killing me
you guys oh it's under this bed you're
going to reveal chats can't what do you
want to really join up
let's do the grow off but hand me my bag
behind you there it's weighs a ton
this is the the CBD a THC a balanced but
there's still no TVs personally no THC
in it this is the best one because we're
gonna see her smoke see THC we don't
need that so the raw version wait so
what's the ratio on this one it's
technically a one-to-one but very
different from a normal one to one where
that you're getting all the genetics of
ac/dc which is a forty to one CBD a THC
a and then all genetics emoji coach
there's a high THC a oh it's a mix
formulated together to make a balanced
version of them
I think it's very people have anxiety
but not pain or pain but no anxiety and
things but supporters are different some
people CBD a horse great I don't know
either
some people th tau or excrete it's like
a multivitamin for your endocannabinoids
the childproof so we recommend you have
5 to 10 drops to start and it could be
treated as a sublingual which if you
swirl it through your mouth for 30
seconds a minute or so it'll go into
your bloodstream through your cheeks and
your gums and it'll take effect within
fifteen to thirty minutes however if you
just swallow it straight away it acts as
a yellow an edible goes through your
digestion gets processed by your liver
and you know does the conversion to 11
hydroxy metabolites just as an ordinary
edible would wait but can can all of it
good like if I hold it in my mouth long
enough all of it will go through the
bloodstream
I'm sure the majority of it yeah most of
you swallow is left not swallow it's
mostly saliva membranes are so thin here
that in about 30 seconds just absorbs
right into your bloodstream because so
many of you can have it receptors in
your head you get relief real quickly so
instead of eating in an Advil or an
edible or a xanax that's go through your
stomach acid your stomach and kidney
deliver this just goes straight there so
you're maximizing your bioavailability
it also gives you more option to treat
different types of sleep deprivation so
one of the big questions we ask people
and they say I can't sleep is well do
you have trouble falling asleep or do
you have trouble staying asleep and it
means a big difference in how you're
gonna go at the promise fucking
exhausted yeah no problem with that but
if I don't have fucking huge doses of
THC in me when I go to bed I have insane
dreams my brain goes crazy I go to work
on how to use yeah the THC will keep
your brain from going too far the REM
cycle so that you still get a good
night's sleep but you don't remember
your dreams as much so if you a PTSD is
like that it's showing really great
effects yeah
however if you wake up in the middle of
the night and you smoke again it's gonna
kick you back into the REM cycle where
you're gonna have a lot of dreams right
or if you take too much before you go to
bed you wake up to pee you're fucking
tripping we're not saying this you know
so are we are saying this from
experience we we're testing out the
quality of certain FICO's full extract
cannabis oils or people calm Rick
Simpson oil and so we started taking
doses every night before bed and ramping
that dose up every couple days to see
how the effects were and what would
happen and we skipped a few days of
there and ramped it up when we doubled
or tripled the boat it turns out for
grains of rice both of us woke up the
next morning tripping eight hours later
eight hours later
you go to bed you expect to wake up
sober most people come on start get
together it's just cannabis mmm look
who's right so so tell me about growing
uh what was the the grow off cause of
our guy caramel cream it's delicious
yeah he smoked that joint up some
morning I was fucking stop yeah I was
telling him it it kind of reminds me of
headband
it was a really hot did you just grow
one clone everybody gets yeah for the
grow off everybody gets the two cuts and
then you take them back to your farm and
grow them the way you do there's people
who do it
indoor/outdoor a greenhouse light DEP
and then farms like us who are full Sun
full soil clothes that she came to
meddle lands with us the weekend I was
like I think you may have been looking
for a store I know it's like well he
doesn't need to do that I will
definitely be a sight to be today I
should just I just be that past also no
hero
wait we also have so talk about this
what we have there this is their house
brand of CBD yeah
so Judy do you ever smoke out of this
thing this is a soccer mom tool yeah
know what it's fucking awesome cuz it's
vaping hole flour instead of instead of
oil yeah did you feel way better I love
it I just flew up to the northwest and I
had to stop off at a few different
airports with that and I was able to fly
and hit it the whole way and so the
first thing I said to the founders was
like I saved these things just to reuse
them for ya if you guys don't make that
someone else is it's not very hard to
figure out
yeah fillable ceramic yeah yeah actually
ceramic would be cool mm-hmm yeah it
would be perfect or you they make the
little ceramic one-hitters you know for
the dugouts those are nice Richard is
sending me a prototype no shit oh man I
love the old they could make a fortune
just selling the pokers because I think
anybody has ever owned a prototype has
bent or lost the poker on those things
that was the first pipe I ever smoked
out of when I was like in sixth grade
really was my so I'm the youngest for
the next brother is four years older and
so like he used to have a fake drawer
and that's where his weed was and when I
discovered it
your studies interaction with this thing
people love it yeah I guess such a
simply doing the packaging is crazy bout
them recyclable yes because I think the
whole lines consistent packaging right
like if someone else created a product
they'd have to use this yes well they're
sourcing from a lot of great farms we're
providing flour for several of their
SKUs and then we're also helping them
find flour from other good farms and
we're trying to keep the farm intact all
the way through the process so that you
know the end consumer knows where the
flour has grown what region who did it
what's the terroir so by the way people
were making fun of us for hanging out
with a Tish tinker is an hour thousand
different ways to have cannabis yeah so
you get three minutes on it
I usually Howard this thing so it counts
down you bought 15 hits ah but before
you yeah
got a great two kids fucking mark I gave
him three packs and I love you sure he
didn't got freaking nine bags wrote all
but Sanders names on him and then pull
one and then wrote on each stick what it
was and then post looking three of them
in each bag nice I was like wow man
that's fucking all right so sticking
with packaging is this good enough where
you fuckers if you need to feed him
lines you can but uh but like what was
kind of like one of you guys were
looking for a source in packaging form
factors and providers what were you
looking for it's a really tough thing
because the the packaging and compliance
laws are so difficult you've got to have
all of this room for everything that
they require on their from you know the
California cannabis symbol to your lab
testing you got to have tamper evidence
seals you got to have child resistant
packaging prop 65 the prop 65 everything
causes cancer what six times the last
three years yeah we have to keep
changing or using as this glass yeah so
I mean that's like a consciousness I
mean it's more expensive than plastic so
absolutely so can you talk about those
decisions like one guy just want to be
environmentally conscious and absolutely
and well the regulations make it very
difficult well and that most everything
with that's affordable within the price
range is all coming from China and of
course right now we've got the
coronavirus and we've got whole
provinces being shut down and we're just
coming off of Chinese New Year and if
you don't order around Chinese New Year
and so we've been really putting in a
lot of effort to find locally sourced
sustainable small family businesses who
are putting on this all together so use
China like not being able to live
as another reason oh yeah it was like
American whatever like packaging
providers and then be able to tell that
story it's it's a real challenge
especially for people that are in the
cannabis industry that start out as
farmers and then as the cultivator and
they're used to having to do everything
from your seed stock your clone stock to
amending your soil you're developing
your hydro or developing your your
indoor system to growing the plants all
the way through the system being the the
horticulturist and then you would do
your own curing what you'd have to build
out in another room so you got to have
carpentry and electrical skills or
somebody that does that for you and then
you do your trimming or you bring in a
trim crew and then you sell it and get
your money and now the people that that
was the whole industry and you've
controlled it from end to end now we've
got marketing and packaging and
compliance you have to have a whole team
of people that specialize in every
little thing because when you go into a
dispensary with a product now the
compliance officers are back there with
a microscope and they're going over
every letter of a bat shop they open
every box and if things don't match up
things aren't right they are obligated
under the regulations to reject it and
send it back which jams up the whole
system and so this is where a lot of the
extra cost is coming and then the legal
market is we're all having to jump
through hoops to package repackage
unstick Arista Kerr change the size
we've even seen where the purchasers had
a ruler measuring the size of the
California cannabis symbol because
there's specs on that and if you just
make a photocopy sticker and put it on
there it might be just a smidge off but
it's out of compliance and because
everything's so complicated now
everyone's following the rules but
slightly different variations of 1264
they joke about it being like the Bible
where it's a great story being
interpreted in a hundred different ways
which is crazy gonna be n/a we have all
sorts of different places they require
different things of us you know this
place you can't do this this way you
can't do that that's kind of that I view
all the religions it's like Judaism to
Christianity to Islam like they all
believe the same starting stuff and then
it's like Christianity is like no there
is this next dude called Jesus and then
Muslims are like no no no no we agree
there with Jesus but then there was
another dude after him named Mohammed
but they all agree with everything
before and they're really virgin I gave
up religion for Lent again alright so
because you also have the pre-rolls and
then you have the human bomb with it we
have a healing balm as well that we use
the Ross sit at kindred spirit and we
named it kindred spirit because THC and
CBD are spirit molecules or sister
molecules they take care of each other
they boost each other up they temper
each other out they make each other work
better together and that's also the name
of the sailboat that Shen and I rebuilt
and lived on for a while as kindred
spirits so we like to tie it back in and
that's another thing with your packaging
make some make it mean something no just
listen you guys say you lived and you
guys knew each other from what Island
from st. Croix in the Virgin Islands you
over 20 years ago there I was there
about ten years and you yeah yep we live
together from 2001 to 2004 yeah I think
2004 by the way it's Celtics double over
I thought football was over I was quite
a walked into bricks hidden those and
they had a plan and we started out
making pot icecream in the Virgin
Islands over 20 years ago and we would
make pot brownie ice cream sandwiches
and wrap them in foil and we had a
sticker on him red beards nice creams
and we had a little mobile ice cream
cart pushed it on out of the boardwalk
but so we paid bills in fact for Shannon
and I our first date I was selling pot
brownies out of the backpack at the
locals at that time we have and really
well but it's 12 and 12 year round so
you know your veg cycle is a little bit
different and then curing you know you
have a lot of humidity that's why a lot
of the Caribbean flour has that golden
or brown color especially humid areas
because they're curing it in places are
drying it in places where they don't
have AC or or humidity controls so
they're generally doing it just blocked
from the shade with as much air flow as
possible so it doesn't rot but the
Caribbean and that you know the
equatorial places you know there's some
great land race trains that are gonna
start popping back up again and it'll be
interesting to see because if you can
green house and light depth and get your
your plant sized up you could do some
really big full season turns in the cab
game they're gonna have to do mix light
way around cuz I said good twelve twelve
the whole time and he can't do an indoor
grow because the electricity is so
unreliable down there you'd have to have
a generator almost running for what you
eat is like what zelich has like you did
the other day Peter where you need a
glass greenhouse with Nick's white
inside you can do a combination of those
things and solar solar and led to reduce
you know your electrical and also
reduces the heat in there because you
know the Caribbean so hot already and
it's so humid you got to grow some
really strains that are mold and mildew
resistant
he's a good candidate down the road
and if I can uh uncle Sal so are there I
need genetics that you took from there
that you grew up in Sonoma
there was but we had a partner who has
them but yeah that's one of those things
if you're in the industry at all you're
gonna have you're gonna Ryan run into
some safety people and so we've lost a
lot of our genetics over the years and
we found new ones and then we have like
our Durbin it's burned grown in our
family of cultivators for over 20 years
and so it's a family thing so whoever
needs cut somebody always has cuts and
we've always just shared and helped each
other out that was grown in the Virgin
Islands to for a little while the turban
that you guys now have up and yeah some
cuts made their way to st. Croix
allegedly growing up in Sonoma like
progeny of what was growing in st. Croix
it came from Sonoma County to st. Croix
I believe they're out yeah there's
cousins there's a lot of people that
have this and have shared it out within
the screen as I was my question was
gonna be did these South African
genetics acclimate themselves to st.
Croix and then we're then moved like
like kids like like army brats moving
around the world were their parents or
something being like I totally new
climate I don't think so not so much I
mean if you keep cloning the same mother
in that location yeah you're gonna start
seeing that changed but I think if you
just take a cut to in a new environment
it's not gonna have that memory to do
the next generation if it's moved
immediately now I always think about
plants that like grew up and just
perfect weather environments and then
suddenly like they're moved to like a
much harsher environment well that's a
sin that's one of the theories on why it
produces cannabinoids that the Indus
Valley where it was in those areas when
the plates shifted and the Himalayas
were formed it was forced from more of a
sea level up into a higher elevation and
it forced the plant to produce the
cannabinoids and in the resin glands -
as a UV protection on the plant and so
they believed that drastic change in
elevation during its development was one
of the causes for the production of
cannabinoids so were those tectonic
movements like in a couple of days or
ever like millions of no idea about that
like a gentle acclamation of like gentle
earth 20 million years right no yeah
that would be it would CalPERS like how
long did mountain this take to four
[Laughter]
where's where's your young Jaime to pull
up over here have my car here that's the
only reasons restraints these clouds
have seen the best lowers to me or
sometimes led the way
[Music]
or Tuesday night when I drove home from
here I was like super high and my
contacts were like dry and glued to my
eyes and it was just like stress
miserable problem for me there talk
about the package you got to make your
package thing mean something just don't
go to a marketer and say this color
pattern and this is the logo that's
going to be an eye-catcher of this
season's go look at the dispensary
shelves there is it all looks like the
same company design happen there's no
personality big part is just nothing
like this has no personality and I like
that no it's fun mm-hmm yeah that we got
a little Cresco it's very clean
everything's very crisp I get it
but it doesn't show your personally
really 11 people in this company no
we're still a family run business so
it's important for us to have our social
so how many people came from st. Croix
to work cuz you what once was five of us
well there's a lot and a lot of people
you know we've gotten from California
and wound up in the Virgin Islands and
came back and and it's just if you drove
California Washington Oregon and Idaho
like we're in California I was born in
San Diego okay oh yeah sure we've lived
in Tahoe Marina del Rey
then we Juneau Alaska I've earned some
seat I'm working out of Juneau Alaska
Vancouver British Columbia Lake Tahoe LA
San Diego Ensenada I wouldn't know I was
a professional captain at the time and
couldn't touch anything unfortunately
from what other people's
it was crippling it was some really nice
stuff because some of them some of the
first strains I ever got to smoke were
from Alaska and like Alaska Thunder fuck
in Northern Lights and this is all grown
indoors yeah you know what I was saying
about like like let's say you're some
happy land race and some chilled
Mediterranean environment and then like
the next seed pops and it's in like a
shitty indoor grow like not a good one
but I get terrible one you're just like
I don't know sometimes this dress makes
the plant perform better yeah like our
ac/dc if you give it a perfect
environment and an indoor grow with all
the right nutrients and happy soil and
perfect light and temperature and
humidity it looks like an octopus on
quaaludes yeah it just kind of lays down
I don't know oh he fell out of my paw
and then also production of cannabinoids
and terpenoids
defense of the plant so the heavy wind
or predation or bugs strengthen and
build the plant up no we go out and
that's what I'm miss doing that and
there's yeah
I started making edibles and cultivating
and you know now being in the business
of cannabis I haven't touched a plant in
years you know would love my cultivation
team to death but I wish I was with them
everyday instead of you know outside
this isn't too bad but yes but all the
hoops we have to jump through instead of
just being cannabis people you know it's
it's the most regulated market in the
world and it's led by the misinformed
and yeah
yeah this is my favorite one I use this
one every day because we as we smoke we
get a lot of decarboxylated cannabis in
our diets and so the acidic cannabinoids
especially the balanced ratio of the
kindred spirit mm-hmm and so that
balance is the balance out all your
other major systems so you've got your
mood you're paying your appetite it's
all balanced out by your endocannabinoid
system and the kindred spirit is
actually ac/dc and og cush so you're
getting twice the genetics working
together not just a one-to-one strain
mm-hmm so you're maximizing the
combination of cannabinoids in Turkey
there ain't no cannabinoid system which
in turn is maximizing the balance the
rest your systems are you guys gonna
make a hash weave yes we've we used to
make bubble hash but you know the old
backyard style with the trashcan and the
bubble bags and yeah that's in the works
now our manufacturing site is getting up
and going and we're starting to back can
that be on site yeah oh no no we have a
manufacturing facility for that so we
have cultivation manufacturing and
distribution we had to do that and keep
ourselves whole through the market
because it's you know we couldn't find
anybody to represent us the way that we
wanted to be where's how are you doing
fresh frozen are you like drying and
curing and then using that no we use we
believe in the Cure and it actually
helps retain the acidic cannabinoids
that and the olive oil
long slow cure is one of the most
important parts of the plant you can
grow the best cannabis in the world and
if you don't cure it it's gonna smell
like a and tastes horrible and smoke
horrible and you know why go through the
but you got an aged wine you know you
got to let it ripen and you accidentally
and you got to let the cannabinoids and
terpenoids to cannabis the market but
when you're making medicine it's
important to let it cure properly so it
settles into a song
the right cannabinoids in Turpan choice
people who talk about fresh frozen for
Hashmi and talk about like freezing the
maximum essence of that plant just as
it's harvest absolutely that's a one way
to go and I love it it's very fresh and
and bright tasting but I believe in the
old temple ball making hash you know I
love listening to Frenchy can only talk
about it he likes older cured flour to
make his hash with as well what are your
thoughts what are your thoughts and what
we're seeing right here you know I'm new
to the concentrate world I've been a
flower guy my whole life clearly the
bong is my best run and but they've
enjoyed trying two different versions of
concentrates and so this is uh George
green thumb
that's also oh yeah that's why they have
the illegal grab bars down by this
allegedly one gene C code reading this
right yeah all guns are a legend
that's one of the craziest things about
the industry now is for so many years
you know you didn't tell anybody your
real name you didn't loan them let them
know what you're doing you never let
anybody come over to your house or talk
about what you did or how you did it it
wasn't that long ago I know
[Laughter]
No all right there's two on the bottom
all right I assume it's glass there's
pineapple Thai over there from all right
so yeah what are these two
all right so we think that caramel cream
was the grow off flowers of this year
and then the other was the pineapple
Thai I thought there were three on the
table before no just just to either
durbin did your server yeah
the pilot I finally smell like pineapple
this year's they say we press it up now
because of the regulations we couldn't
grow these in our permitted space we had
to do this in our personal garden off to
the side man like I said I wish I could
be out there every day that was one
thing all the other plants know they're
your favorite yeah they're a little
isolated down there actually yeah well
in the year we wanted to grow off we we
really let the plants just go for their
own we had a end none of the Hugo
culture yeah we did it in the Hyuga beds
and it was turned into a challenging
season we helped another farm that was
having issues we help them through their
harvest and just didn't have time to
give to the grow off plants and they
just took off and ran and loved where
they were we took first place for
potency with with that year and third
place for terpenes yeah so you own a
distribution company sue yeah we have
the farm we have manufacturing and
distribution but it's all out of form
and function because we could we made
all of our own products before but we
couldn't find anybody who could do the
way we wanted it done and then the same
with the distribution when you know
we've been growing CBD strains for seven
years now back before anybody really
knew what it was we got our original
seeds from lawrence ringo and that was
for us our tsunami and been working with
it for quite a while and when you walk
in with flour to somebody and say hey i
grew this beautiful flower but it won't
get you high you know they were
originally they call it the hippies
disappointment because they grew these
great-looking flowers and then smoked
them and they didn't
but they noticed how much better they
felt after they smoked it and he's
always saying why didn't get us high but
it was a much better feeling they have a
better balance the CBD and THC back then
mm-hmm and that's what Lawrence Ringo
was noticing because he had back issues
and he knows he was able to to do more
things and so they started working more
on breeding the CBD strains if you
smoked like eight joints of super high
CBD would you eventually just get super
at like with the THC catch-up no it
would be like trying to get drunk off of
non-alcoholic beer alcohol exactly so by
the time you got to the 30th one you
would be out of your system from already
before that but if you did it within
like an hour good question there's no
way well we've also done good day
because if you drank this whole ball you
wouldn't get high have you ever tried it
we've taken quite a bit of it what CBD
does is it changes the way that THC
binds to the cb1 receptor and it lowers
the threat of how high you're gonna get
with the THC but it makes it last longer
because it slows down the reuptake and
Road transmitters and so you're gonna
find that balance that's why a kindred
spirit with the balance of the two at
the CBD and the THC but what's your bet
do you think of Jodie drank that whole
bottle he would get higher or not no I
don't think so we've taken a lot of that
[Laughter]
CBD is also can be very focusing like
you know almost an adderall where you
just want to sit down and do things you
could drink a small bottle of the OG and
that was yeah that's 300 milligrams it's
all THC well there's there's just a
minimal it's the exact same thing as
this but this is not decarboxylated
cannabis has to be heated to get you
high and so this is THC a this is the
exact same plant probably came from the
exact
same branch except this the cannabis was
heated and decarboxylated before Oh in
the olive oil
and this is the raw natural plant the
way it is in the garden so if you think
if you think dressing so each of those
went through a different process yeah
flower this one was in the oven fern for
a period of time a couple round number
now so ever so like we try to be so open
and transparent about everything we do
and then we realize you know some things
we have to keep really know
and we're just open people so it's it's
tough for us to like you know go oh well
this is what happens and this is how we
do this and we just love talking about
it it's so much fun but this one you
know this is THC a is amazing for aches
pains its scrapes exactly arthritic dog
you're a threaded gram the info
anti-inflammatory anyway a car two
months ago when I use that as my
anti-inflammatory yep I use this after
doing a long demo because your feet just
getting all nasty but it's it's great
but they won't snot psychoactive so if
you have the day job you have to work
with kids and you need THC for the pain
relief you can do THC a without the
secular activity now this one is the
exact same flower this one will get you
a high as a giraffe's ass because it's
been decarboxylated and heated but now
you don't need the third glass of wine
the ambien the painkiller at the end of
the night use your natural
endocannabinoids system to find how many
ease as the Masters SoCal salesmen how
many shops do you visit a day and how
many like what do you call them now not
like patient appreciation but we do
patient education just because we make
when you make five products that will
get people high education means
everything so
his passion to sell that okay well we
have to learn to talk about this so we
go and sit and work oh yeah if they
don't come up to the booth we're gonna
bring them up to the booth does your
mama sleep does your grandmother have
arthritis do you have a dog that is
anxious or as arthritis is your Kindle
an adderall I can help you even if it's
not for you - it's like a sublingual
edible I promise I travel it just take
the label off but we really had to dive
into the education to be able to explain
this to purchasers who explained it's
the blood tenders who explained it to
the patients and so we try to educate at
all the levels and so we go and listen
to the people who do the research the
doctors and the clinicians we go and sit
in their continuing education classes we
go to medical conferences we've had to
go to learn everything about the
endocannabinoid system and cannabis
dosing and and learn about the support
groups and all the people that are
actually putting this to practice every
day as a medicine as you know a healing
tool and so we're trying to raise this
you know they didn't go to college for
making a prescribing medicine for babies
and puppies this looks like it's made in
like a 3d printer right it's like with
silicone injection molded it makes yeah
ash ash hole I think it's called
vegetable or same thing it's got a
little pokey thing sticking up
[Laughter]
again oh there we go yes a hash bowl is
better I still reflect on the brilliance
of HuffPo offering them as their as the
awards for the other oh yeah to think
that the top three people in every
category in the air old cup and now have
a pop coat in their house yeah you see
that this year Peter wait the trophies
at the Emerald cup this year were
personalized puffs COEs can we get our
product into your head it's not just
throwing fucking shit a little bit of
sticks I fuckin love my Paco I couldn't
and I wouldn't like them to gift one to
us so we gotta give a shout-out to one
ease these guys yeah it's one so the
yeah the back the bat on the side is a
lot like so it doesn't just
automatically side you have to pull the
bat down with your thumb to say get this
to slide yeah it's like child yeah pull
that down and then slide the lid and I
always love I've been carrying one of
these for over 20 years with me that's
one of the best things ever you know to
have with you but the problem is when
you're with a group of people it's a
bummer to sit there and have to pack one
for each person and knock the ball out
and it's relatively clean uh yeah
there sure is it's a it's a nice mix
salad I used to like those things
because I would rather people thought
that I was smoking pot and smoking a
cigarette and so it's always frustrating
you're like I saw you smoking a
cigarette now it was I love that is I
love it
me too and there's so much fun I
remember being in a bar and Billy Bob's
seeing Willie Nelson at Billy Bob's
and having this in my pocket and we were
standing a couple people behind the
bouncers and you could still smoke
cigarettes and bars back then so I took
that thing took a big puff blunt in the
back of the bouncers head put it back in
my pocket and stand there like nothing
happened watch them run around trying to
find out who is smoking pot and then
wait till they settle down and then do
it again so what was in here it's a
mixed salad it's a little a little
Durban some Mama's boys some Sour Diesel
and yeah it's captain's blend sir so
what what genetics what are you guys
growing that's not going on in the
market what's the personal row like
Durban for sure well it's that the
Durban is just being released now we
don't see it they don't see a ton of
Durban in the market right no I guess
commercially yes so what what are you
growing that isn't making it to market
yeah the pineapple type the skittles
yeah we did some co2 caramilk the Carol
cream yeah that's the stuff thing is you
have to make so the most use you can out
of your permitted space and that only
leaves you your six personal plants
outside of that to do R&amp;D or personal
stuff and it's nice because for our farm
we grow a bunch of all of our six plants
and then it's going to be divided among
the staff so you know we all get to
share this is the first time we've
released
ACDC to and you don't see it Sunday
ac/dc flower in the market most of its
blown for cars for a while well it's
been in our tinctures there's so much of
it yeah we had since it was such an
awesome representation 30 to 1 CBD to
teeth straight out of the garden so we
so we uh we finally took me on the best
of the best the top of the tops and
threw them into jars and when you spoke
this ac/dc it's amazing it's just so
calming and relaxing imagine without me
the cycle activity that's how you know
you can smoking zbc all day it not get
high but you feel fucking great
yeah as I like to say that CBD does have
psycho activity but it's
non-intoxicating believe that the
burning end up yeah because because it
it's calming it's anti-anxiety it makes
you feel better it focuses you it quiets
the circus running between your ears it
allows you to you know to have that yeah
[Laughter]
on that one Ebola if you look at it it's
we're talk about how you have to pack
one for everybody pull the the bat out
and then close that back up and then
look on the side there you go that's a
bowl and now if you stick the bat into
the small hole on the side where your
thumb is yeah there you go
now it turns into a bowl so you can pass
it around or no you still draw from the
turn wait you still draw from there but
you fill that less you got there you go
but then where's the bowl huge bowls and
adjust the money so it turns your one
hitter into a pipe oh I would
I missed that part right but then you
can light this like uh-huh just like an
old you know the old-school pipe I got
that at the head shop on Abbot Kinney in
Venice it yes find that place I've
walked out there twice yeah yeah in the
middle of oh shit those dudes you should
have seen the first time we did this hit
the fuck you come and get clubbed oh you
hit him too that hash I know it tastes
so good that we fucking at one point
there was probably 30 people in this
room and just I was one counter that's a
candy yeah it fucking just jars and
stuff like that all over the place
that's something like sitting room was
just fucking Wow rushed high and then
when everyone fucking disappeared we
everything a total like any an hour and
a half and then there's fucking band
outside just a little bit like six
people fucking just dancin and fuckin -
it was awesome I was with a ticky
Singler one of the guys don't ZZZ I was
like listen my body's throw this party
but I have no idea what to expect
it's an LA party it could be anything my
friend you want to go he's like we're in
LA let's go to shot so we walked right
in shout right down so I can held card
for an hour
then went outside and fucking rage for
like two hours
high is the fucking lab rats and boot
like fucking beers and shit fucking
booze lights
I like $15 something like that together
shit yeah you walk you they give you a
cupcake to my Bellator on cupcake like
that's the way to start your fucking go
ghetto style I mean it's a good fucking
base for most people yeah let's ask her
like Sam those cupcakes I don't think
you understand how much how much actual
cupcake that is like yeah we have you
know ready for that fucking about 20
miles a lot in the two hours it takes
for it to kick in especially the part of
you do a lot yeah well you're gonna do a
lot of smokiness in between them