if you have a strong enough case you
don't have to go all the way through
trial because you can you can file some
earlier earlier motions and submit some
earlier defense that may be able to hit
to avoid going to trial or you can bring
enough evidence to show the the other
side that they're not going to win you
can file certain motions to avoid going
to trial you can get to the place that
that you can show them look guys if you
force me to the result of this is going
to be that you walk away with an invalid
patent it's going to cost us both a lot
of money but you're gonna walk with an
invalid patent now can any one person
endure the cost of that no the the the
the good news bad news it's a good news
bad news thing nobody is going to be the
target of litigation that's that
expensive unless they themselves are
creating an economic big enough economic
target but if you create a coalition and
this that's why I'm so big on creating
we need to have a mutual defense so that
whoever is that first target has a hell
of a lot of support behind them and
that's why this this litigation that's
happening in Colorado has me troubled
because I I'm not involved in it myself
but I don't know I don't see the whole
community coming up to say no damn way
no no way is this case gonna turn out
the way it it could possibly turn out
this is you know this one I'm talking
about yet
United or true United cannabis
yeah and it's it's basically a patent
that claims any liquid formulation that
is that is no it's at least at least 95
percent of one cannabinoid either CBD or
THC and it doesn't even have to be it
doesn't even have to be pure it just
yeah
it's the bare minimum for FDA standard
so 95% is like yeah and so the defendant
filed an initial motion to get the case
dismissed on the basis that this is a
product of nature and shouldn't be
patentable in the first place and that
was thrown out because the the the judge
in this case considered that that
purification took it beyond being a
product of nature but I I mean I think
they're gonna lose on novelty grounds
they've gotta lose on novelty grounds
people have been purifying things for
way before that whatever the date of
this patent right so but what I don't
see is a coalition of the entire
community standing behind this defendant
saying we're gonna kill this patent dead
just for the purposes of showing that
there's a coalition behind defendants I
would I would think so but maybe not I
don't know I honestly don't think we do
I don't think like there's probably only
about a couple dozen of us who know
about the case really and even those
like I know about it I've made exactly
zero posts about it see they're mostly
because like I know about it but I don't
know about it I'm not a patent lawyer I
don't really know what's going on to the
level of detail that you do when you sue
someone when you sue someone for patent
infringement if you win great you get
some damages you might also intimidate
everyone else into taking a license but
if you lose because of on the basis of
patent invalidity your patent is gone
you can't sue anyone again with that pet
for that patent at least as to the
claims that get invalidated and so it
would be if I mean and I I'm not I have
to have to say this carefully I'm not
expressing a legal opinion about that
patent I haven't analyzed it as a lawyer
I'm I'm I'm echoing the sentiments of
the community that say there's no damn
way okay I want to be really clear about
that this is
not a legal opinion but what I am saying
is that if the patent is invalid the
whole community ought to be standing up
to say let's invalidate that patent now
before it gets asserted against anybody
else in the community that would be a
community benefit with it with a capital
C the capital B and there ought to be a
D in there somewhere so and and that's
that's the that's exactly the kind of
coalition that that ought to exists yeah
I don't think any of us knew that we
were getting involved in an agricultural
industry that has been subsumed by an
information economy like we were we were
pop farmers and most of us were pop
farmers like most of the people who I
learned how to grow weed from did not
have internet connection like until the
last couple years like we were not an
information economy was not something we
had prepared ourselves for we were
worried about cops the state the cost of
coming into compliance
thieves yeah no we were not thinking in
terms of like okay how am I going to
secure my data what are they going our
they going to take my IP and leverage it
against me that was just not in the
vocabulary and the vernacular of a
cannabis farmer about five months ago
six months ago yeah yeah no exactly yeah