[Music]
so about a year and a half ago and some
of my neighbors and friends who we all
live in a alternative back-to-the-land
community up in Mendocino County and we
were you know naturally just talking to
each other about the industry a lot of
people there grow and we're like how are
we gonna survive this tsunami that's
coming at us we don't even really know
what that means yet and you know what
what can we do to like make it through
and retain this like natural like pretty
sustainable chill lifestyle out in the
country how do we continue that and so
we decided to band together actually
combine forces with two other friends
when you're gonna interview Janet pretty
soon I think so she was one of those and
we started working together to form
Mendocino generations which was a farm
collective that we started about a year
and a half ago at this point and we
quickly grew from three farms to we have
43 farms right now and so I'm the
Operations Director of Mendocino
generations and we help farmers get
compliant we help them kind of navigate
this crazy maze of new regulation and
rules and you know local and state level
too and we help them with marketing
branding and so on so we felt like you
know a strength through unity was like
the only way we were you know going to
survive this
for the most part we all have one
unified goal and voice there is
definitely difference in opinions on how
things should go and need to go
especially because of people's personal
circumstances around their permitting
and so that has maybe caused some of the
biggest discrepancy and
opinions I think but for the most part
we're all really supportive of each
other and you know so-and-so over here
has a boundary issue we're gonna help
think of solutions or you know maybe
they just really want to farm and they
were not attached to that land they
could move and we could help them figure
that out there's a lot of different
benefits to collectively you know
working together and so I get to
handpick all the farmers that are in the
group which is a great benefit I like
interview them all I get to know them a
lot of people come to me word of mouth
or they know one of the other farmers in
the group and so they've heard about us
and they come to find us they seek us
out and so most people are pretty much
on the same level they're back to the
land sort of you know hippie folks and
Mendo and they fit really well together
they know each other they have good
rapport we go to each other's houses for
meetings and they've developed
friendships over time to that you know a
bond because of this group so some of
the biggest issues that my farmers face
I would say at this moment
besides the empty pit of money that just
kinda keeps coming down this black hole
is the building and planning regulations
I guess would be the biggest problem at
this moment and that's just because
different agencies within our local
government and the state government I
think they're putting down regulations
on growers cultivators you know
processing facilities distribution like
they don't really understand how we have
been doing business and how this is a
huge change for us this is like you know
takes a lot of sorry to be crass but
takes a lot of balls to do what we do
and stand up when it's kind of this gray
zone about are we doing it right are we
doing it legal and then what is legal
mean and people are you know taking a
huge leap towards compliance when really
the government and these regulatory
agencies in our local area don't even
know what it means to cultivate they
don't know what it's like they don't
know how much it cost they think we're
like moneybags
and they're trained to really capitalize
on that and you know until they really
understand that we're real people we
have real lives we have families you
know this is not a cash crop so much as
it used to be this is like just basic
survival and doing something that we
really have a lot of passion for and we
love so much and that's why we're doing
it now a couple of the biggest problems
right now with the building and planning
department in my County is that they
want us to have any building that has
cannabis in it to be commercial building
most of us out in the country where we
grow cannabis in my area is pretty rural
people did class K permits a long time
ago which means the county just kind of
like clean slated them moved him along
like here's your permit you're all good
to go but who would have ever saw this
coming so now how do you get your class
K garage or your shop or your dry shed
to commercial compliance it's a huge
endeavor and it's gonna cost a ton of
money and so now the county because of a
lot of us standing up for ourselves and
what we believe in and being the squeaky
wheel you know the squeaky wheel gets
the grease these days like if you go in
and say hey I'm a real person and I have
a real problem can you help me there
really I think open to that and learning
as they go to and so you know they're
changing things a little bit to help us
so now they've created this AG exempt
category where you can have a building
that only touches cannabis like it
doesn't really have multi purposes in it
they're helping us by you can apply for
an AG exempt permit for that building if
it's only a single use for cannabis so
drying shed for instance or a storage
shed
so that's one big change that's happened
and the next I would say it's positive
for some people but for other people who
naturally use a building for multiple
things like aren't gonna be able to have
a AG exemption permit for that building
and they're still gonna have to go down
the road of commercial compliance and
actually that's my case I have a
building that's like a guesthouse on the
top and a garage on the bottom and our
cure and dry and like storage rooms are
all connected in one building it's
easier for powers you know it's easier
for everything so that new regulation
change it's not gonna actually benefit
me but one of the other great benefits
is like working with well - working with
a group is I can send my farmers to go
to these like board of supervisor
meetings and say hey stand up for this
issue can you mention this write a
letter and we're all like collectively
helping each other stand up for each
other and that's been really empowering
and great I would say in Mendocino
County the local government is pretty
open to cannabis now they were quite
resistant in the beginning really not
caring I don't think that much and a lot
of them are actually coming out to farms
now and visiting these facilities and
meeting us one-on-one having personal
conversations who run into them at the
grocery store we you know reach out at
different events or we have mutual
friends and that's kind of the way we
were like building a rapport with them
like oh these are real people these are
good people these aren't just like you
know crazy dope growers like giant
trucks that have all this money like
they think that we all are so I think
that they're coming around but I think
there is still some resistance
especially in these new departments that
are having to get involved because the
state is going down the legal road right
so some of these people on building and
planning for instance or like anti but
because they never had a deal with us
before and so once they establish
friendship relationships or rapport with
people we come into the office every day
ask questions I'm like here representing
43 farms they're like oh you're a cool
person like you're great I'm gonna help
you now and so now they're starting to
kind of come around and and be more
friendly and it's like a regular like a
its normal with the state licensing I'm
not really sure what to say about that
yet I am nervous about it personally and
I would say our collective and our farm
group doesn't really fit into one of the
licensure categories and so I don't
really know where to go with that at
this moment personally my farm it's
pretty obvious but for the rest of it
I'm not quite sure yet how that looks
every day it's something new literally I
opened my email or I get a phone call
from somebody and they say have you
heard about this you know about this yet
or what are we going to do about this
and so every day it's just like I kind
of feel like one of those I'm like
training for the army you like run
through the tires and then you climb the
wall and you like launch over this thing
like every day it's something new and
you just have to like just roll with it
and you know you have to be flexible or
you're just not going to survive this
industry
[Music]