the abilities to be able to get yourself
contractual protection and I think with
community protection and support is
really just try not to screw each other
you know fundamentally man choose not to
burn the guy you're doing business with
and that seemed to work for a long time
I mean to me it's pretty simple
and I think that that you know in my
perspective from someone who traffics
genetics what I want to be able to see
is and what I've always done is I've
always given credit to the people whose
cultivars I use or material I use or
information I use because what happens
then is you promote just like Jason was
promoting NAT and gene saying hey man I
ran his stuff that was killed and my
friends run his stuff that's a courtesy
he didn't have to say it but he wanted
to say hey you know you guys are some
some guys that I respect and I
appreciate and what it does it adds a
level of legitimacy that you can't add
yourself I had this discussion with
someone today about the internet saying
the Internet guys tell you this is how
you promote yourself and I'm like no
really give a about them it's it's
just banter it's crap coming out their
mouth perpetually and you just turn it
off what you want is you want other
people to validate what you're doing in
an honest way because that resonates in
a way that you know is true because
they're not getting paid for it they're
not a shill and I think that that's part
of it is that you know you recognize
other people's farms and you commend the
product when it's legitimate and if you
don't have an ability to move your
product but you know someone who could
move product you push that product and
you make sure that person gets credit
and with the breeders you know don't
pirate their work you know what would
you had so funny one cuz jeans a mean
king but he was talking about how they
would rename in these varietals so they
could just get rid of the breeder and
there was this whole meme about how the
breeder was diminished minimized and
wiped out so that we can name anything
we wanted but it's it's such a true
statement because you're so you're so
desirous of your own success that you
forgot how you got there and I think
when it comes to with the breeders that
if you can keep them alive in the
conversation all the time you know in a
courteous sense where this is the
material I got from Jason this is what I
used if you want to buy more you can go
to them if you've got questions you can
go to them you become innocent
credible referral network and I think
that the thing that protects you from
in life most is money your own
money makes you pretty safe because you
can afford infrastructure tools
connections and that's really what we've
been deprived of right now is liquidity
and so we have to kind of pull up our
skills until we can rebuild our
liquidity but hopefully this bout of
poverty teaches us how to behave a
little more intelligently in a communal
form so that when we do rear eyes up
again as a craft culture you're able to
actually take the education that we just
got about how you better stick together
you're gonna die and then use it to
create the models of protection so that
you end up having individuals that can
do the work so that all you have to do
is do your work a lot of people would
rather just grow and farm than have to
spend all their free time breeding - so
I mean that's my opinion on it it's it's
you you you you gotta you got to be
honest with whose work you're pirating
and make sure you kick back credit yeah
I would agree with with that Kevin I'm
sure you guys have had it happen I've
had it happen where where groups get
ahold you work and they renamed it as
their own and they don't give credit and
I've I feel like the the history and the
story is a big part of why things are
appealing and so I I always try to be as
forthcoming and factual with with all
the information that we put out there
about what we're working with and you
know there's there's companies out there
that are just getting rid of the names
altogether where it's it's it's the all
the all the history of you know hundreds
of years of people carrying this plants
just wiped away and now it's it's this
new just a whole new way of categorizing
things and you know I don't know really
how I feel about that I like people
being inventive and being unique but I'm
also you know very connected to the
history and you know there's something
that that might not say so well about
about just totally renaming people stuff
you know maybe maybe if
if you come up with a name for a
specific Fino like that that could be
okay but but still it's the the whatever
fee no of this strain from this person
and still be honest about where it came
from and you can still name your fee
knows and as far as protecting your
genetics I think the open cannabis
project or you know somehow doc
documenting the genes as open-source
that's the only really other alternative
to trying to patent your stuff and keep
other people from having it I want other
people to grow it but I don't want
people to grow it and then take it from
me and say I can't grow it that's crazy
and that's literally something that
could be going on right now we've got
you know a number of cannabis patents
that have already been issued that are
gonna be problematic in the future I'm
sure there's gonna be challenges to them
but I think one of them is any one to
one that doesn't have mercy and in it
it's technically under patent right now
is that correct there's there's
something there's some very broad
cannabis patents out there right now and
I'm sure there's going to be more down
the road and you know documenting your
genetics through through groups like the
open cannabis project or or you know a
way to to combat that you
about spectrum utility patents the
genetic data is holding for a lot of
reasons but it's harder to translate
that information so more data and that
would be really useful to have prior art
argument for any so anybody that didn't
hear that he was saying chemo type data
is as or possibly more important than
the you know the genetic testing so yeah
and and that that can be hopefully a
discussion all on to its own that I
would love to delve deeper into that and
how we can protect the community's work
as a whole one thing I wanted to touch
on is you know yeah when when you talk
about you know you're saying you're
gonna go try and sell your product to
people assume self-interest and so they
always take whatever you say with a
grain of salt
but if they overhear it from their
friend that says no no his stuffs dope I
like that or I like this type and and
you're gonna take that you're gonna take
that in maybe a little more deeper or
what I'm trying to say is is support
your community and the other people if
you see something that you like you know
let people know and hopefully others are
gonna return the favor to you and and
that that's I feel how we build the
community together and help help each
other survive
so so you know definitely I think people
take it into account a little more when
when they hear it you know around you
know through somebody else or through
the grapevine or I heard that this
that's that's how hype builds is is you
know people over here from somewhere
else that oh that's the one and and yeah
there is something that's that's you
know genuine to that is there's there's
reasons behind why those things got
built up it can't all just be pure
advertising or you know there's there's
got to be some you know human element to
why something
you know become successful and so yeah
just support support your neighbor
support when they're doing good let
people know it you know and and I think
that that from all of us that came from
the era where you didn't rat on people
which seems to be a foreign thought
nowadays ratting out on people screwing
people over isn't Wratten and so when
he's saying you know make sure you
support make sure you also call out
things that you see wrong because
they're screwing him they're gonna screw
you and by the time they get to you they
might not be anybody protect you and so
a lot of it is if you're seeing
unscrupulous stuff you don't have to get
out and broadcasted on the general world
but you can tell your friends man I
could ask all the time about would you
do business with this person and I try
not to screw anybody in a way that would
cause problems but ultimately if I know
that you have a history of pikin people
I always just say the same thing I would
be cautious and what that means is that
I can't give you a recommendation and
that you should do your homework so I
don't have to go too deep into it but it
just says that I can't vouch for you but
I'm not gonna throw a rock at you that's
throwing a rock at you and and that's
important because someone said would you
work with that distribute or I'd say I
would be cautious and then they realize
that there's some reason because I'm not
in a business against them so therefore
why am I having trepidation and it's
because I saw something or heard
something and I'm just like look you
don't need to get screwed either so you
don't have to go and you know
shish-kabob them but if people are doing
good work you know make sure you let
people know and if and if people are
doing stuff that are unethical in a way
that's gonna really cause problems
they're not gonna hold back against you
either most people hold back because
they're afraid of ramification they're
afraid back in the day was they're
afraid they're gonna lose all their
teeth well now that that's not one of
the tools and I don't really think it
should be a tool but it was a very
effective one you have to be able to use
financial and financial is to protect
each other and make sure that the people
that are doing this work on getting beat
to death
and that they're still around for you to
utilize as a resource and you you have
to preserve as many these resources as
possible because without it you end up
having a shrunken population of partners
to do stuff in the future and for me
like what I've done my whole career I've
needed the people around because I only
can do so much myself and my success was
really built off of all these
relationships I made with other people
and over the course of time we did
better than we did worse so don't
anybody screw you
yes yes I believe so that what you could
do is if you did a licensing agreement
with the breeder you could also bring
material that you have and do
collaborative projects that material
would then be able to be jointly
promoted you'd be able to have stock
that was unique to you because all the
material from the cross would be held
the tool you could figure out what was
the cultivar you wanted to release into
the public as production material not as
a cultivar unless you're building a
nursery if you're building a nursery
then you say hey nod I want to work with
you on a project I would love to take
some of the stuff you're doing put with
something I'm doing let's find a cut
let's put it into the market let's both
be honest did the work yeah there's
a good one
and then I'll both you can do combined
breeding and you can do licensing that
allows you to be able to use your
respective IP and then you can then find
individuals that you can license the
clone to because one of the problems is
overproduction of varietals and so you
end up out competing the success because
you've got too much of the same material
and you know that I think that's crucial
but I think a lot of us just need more
legal help with that where we need to
have more people like Beth come in and
attorneys that we're like president was
great to have an attorney present
yesterday because he could kind of say
listen this is how we see this happen
and then you're able to get a better
idea because I don't think any of us so
at least 95% of us haven't been involved
in patent protection of genomic material
you know I mean I'm somebody messing
around all the time but it's that's not
what I do I still have lawyers that I
work with because I don't have time to
go to law school and I don't want to
it's not my thing but I need them yeah I
think licensing is cool because really a
license is just a contract between you
and your associate and you know it
certainly it's not you know as binding
as something like a patent it's it's but
it's more voluntary and I really I do
encourage folks to do that kind of thing
I mean like look at you know jeans
pre-rolled line like you know that's in
a way like that's good for everybody
because
you know that pre-roll person might not
have had quite such a namesake or
following and so you know it's good for
their pre roles and and it's cool for
Jean because he gets credit all that
stuff and just one more thing like I I
keep hearing you know everybody we're
all a little scared and we all like know
that the these big powers that have deep
deep pockets are coming and you know you
might sort of react to it and do
something that you might not otherwise
do you know get rid of all your your
purple strains or something dumb like
that but just remember that like when
booze became legal there wasn't like a
Jim Beam or there wasn't Budweiser or
course those kind of evolved out of you
know there being quick and successes but
then you know in the mid 90s all of a
sudden there was this thing that came
out it was like micro beer and I never
thought in a million years that there'd
still be breweries opening in Humboldt
County that are thriving and just the
same with wine like but it takes a while
for that to kind of mature like you
don't go into the gas station down the
you know over Piercy or whatever and and
stick your nose up at the new microbrews
but you do a third you know maybe you do
or maybe you don't but at the Coors I
like PBR I don't know but that stuff
hasn't had a chance to really like you
know like the PBRs and the course and
the Budweiser's of cannabis no one knows
that that's who they are yet
and so it's gonna take at least probably
like another year maybe two before that
really develops and then what I what I'm
really confident about is that the you
know the regenerative and the small and
the real craft actually then starts to
have its you know days in the Sun you
know pun intended and you know and I
think that's the same with strains too
I mean God remember how freaking long it
was just impossible to you know like
it's you just had to grow og and then
you grew a bunch of this really cool
awesome stuff for your head and but you
just always you know kind of had to grow
a G and I think that that's gonna change
too so you know let's just remember that
we are pioneers and like I think you
know what me and gene said about like
well I'm not ignoring the fact that the
markets saying one thing but I'm also
not giving up on where my frickin roots
are and to where my convictions lie and
stuff like that