[Music]
other terpene profiles with weird oh
geez and Kem's and all that stuff I love
that kind of stuff but there's no real
reference in my life so therefore I kind
of just take it for what it is
versus like lemon or citrus I guess pie
and even to some extent if it's sharp
enough just in those smells it's almost
like you close your eyes and all of a
sudden you're not smelling pie that's a
crazy phenomenon that I see just with
these certain varieties where I already
recognize that smell so heavily from a
different place that it's it's
especially I don't know so strange when
I smell it in pop and it doesn't just
smell like some other type of cannabis
like way below are you saying about the
citrus what you started saying before
you
oh well the citrus I think more so than
the pine is that we have such a close
relationship with it since we're young
how many oranges we've eaten during our
life
oh absolutely I mean I I guess we're
going to talk about the the citizen you
go into all the things of like that
limiting or the citrus smells in general
making us more happy we have this
attraction to them but specifically what
I'm talking about is this phenomenon
like there's a lot of we'd especially
like a lot of them are dank smells that
I'm really interested in but they all
are like pot if you little thing about
pot when they smell it and it's a cool
dank smell but it's it's weed I'm
talking about these specific types of
weed and I see it a lot with orange
where if you just close your eyes and
you smell it you don't really smell weed
you smell some crazy citrus experience
no but there's enough variation within
there the like if maybe it takes 10
different citrus ones but then there's
those ones that aren't like citrus weed
they're like citrus citrus and that's
just a crazy experience when you close
your eyes yeah
and I don't wrote that plan what I
smelled you
[Music]
yeah when then furthermore when it ties
in with this other thing that I don't we
talk about it but it's like there's
these certain varieties and I saw it
with this our tangi I've got it like
that
the HP 13 this is older straighten that
weaves mess with a couple like Diesel's
over the years we'll do this where it's
this lingering mouth coating throat
coating flavor that lasts and it's
especially crazy and not all strains do
that a lot of ones taste like weed when
yeah what it could smell I have the
greatest pot whether it's somebody
else's are mine and it smells really
good and when you smoke it tastes like
weed and then there's other weed when
you smell it and then you smoke it and
it tastes and smells and whatever the
experience of smoking it's of that of
whatever you smelled before it was being
burned now you're tasting and smelling
all in the experience of yeah oh my god
you're putting me on the spot my brains
fried yeah I know depending are there's
just so many ways that could go bro I
got this I've been growing this dogshit
strain what I'm looking for is this
certain Fino of my you know of my
cultivar where when I walk by it itch
you smelled
it's like nose curling like like
disgusting like you could taste dog shit
in the air like it's just like this is
the sky and to the point that it even
tricks me and I'll look at my shirt and
it's my plant and I'm breeding it you
know I'm breeding for that and I said it
smells like dog shit like a hundred
percent and the nastiest plant the
nastiest dog shit nose curling you could
taste that shit in the air it's like
you're like oh that's the plant that's
what I'm looking for that's the ultimate
that I got I'm like that's the one the
one that's just straight up so that's
what I've started breeding with you know
and then
we started breeding a high CBG a variety
of that starting from dog shape which I
really don't know at this point if it's
how I'm getting like four three to four
percent see BGA whether it's some
interaction between the bacteria and the
fungus and the plants or it's my my
special it's the the light manipulation
or the full spectrum lighting that
whatever I'm doing with the lighting or
or or it's the genetics you know or a
combination of all of it so I'm trying
to figure that out which is kind of like
searching for like three needles in a at
once in a haystack so what while I'm
going what while it's my production
facility so I'm doing like research not
only am i pushing the edge on my
production facility you know you know on
a bunch of other levels with soil and
and new you know Zhu Dom living whatever
full spectrum lighting but then you know
I'm like looking for these needles in
the haystacks while I'm doing production
so I'm doing research while I'm doing
production which is kind of you know I
don't really recommend it it's really
like writing and a dangerous edge you
know cuz yeah because there's a lot of
variables so I kind of backed off of the
research last year and put the seeds
aside you know those seeds aside you
know just so I could focus on them and
just survive you know through compliance
so that way I could have the opportunity
to pick that project back up you know
what I mean because I was like alright
this is just too much going on I can't
I'm gonna I'm gonna blow this project
and even and whatever I did yeah I just
didn't you know because I would have to
do tons of testing to test for the C BGA
when you know we were getting like three
four percent at a week like nine eight
nine in like three months it was still
there like too much all my weed I went
through all my test results because I
wasn't looking for it at the time so
then I went back through all my test
results and I saw it all in all of my
test results of that cultivar that I've
been running
so then I was like oh because well
that's what I was that's what I've been
breeding for I just didn't know I was
breeding for that until I figured out
because one day I was in my bar and I
was in my office and I was like it was
just nagging at me like go look at the
test and like and I was like okay my
wife really needed me to do some pay for
something and I was like all right
and I was like I got to pull it up she's
like came in what are you doing I need
that paperwork and I was like I just
have to look at this you know I'm sorry
you know I'm just late stalking you
telling me to look I was like holy shit
wow that's like 4% CBG eh
huh and then I called the lab and was
talking to them about it I was like okay
that's the she was like that's insanely
high like you need normally it's like
under 1% it was like it was like 3.8
percent you know so it was like 17
percent it was like 17 percent THC you
know three points something for a three
point eight percent see BGA yeah I was
like woah okay so then I went back
looking through all my tests I saw that
it was reoccurring then I tried to do
some more experiments didn't have enough
money to do all the testing that I would
need to do on on you know how many seeds
I popped and I have to test each plant
at week five six seven eight nine and
then have clones and cuttings of each
one of those plants and let's in the
metro and them I mean and I was like
well yeah I just don't have you know in
Sonoma County is not really making it
easy so they're just like no you're like
can I just have this they're like no
you're like well I just like I was
already doing that they're like no you
know so you're just kind of like you're
are you different yes so you're only
doing what you were doing that's it
nothing more until you know they'll give
you your use so I'm waiting for them to
through it's almost three years I'm
gonna have a three year anniversary
party party that I didn't get my used
apartment yet it's gonna be a great
party yeah no totally you know it's like
that's why I called the Sonoma triangle
where use permits go to disappear said
the truth right you've heard of the
Bermuda Triangle and the Emerald
triangle the mists fight yeah we've got
the Sonoma triangle yeah where my use
permit is like disappeared somewhere
it's it's it's circ it's complete it's
closed anyway so yeah that's been like
the script you've heard their complete
they're closed
we're working on it thank you very much
no we talked with our planner it's
closed because my wife is like yeah yeah
no my wife's on it she's really good at
crawling up everybody's ass she's she I
called I was like you are a proctologist
baby man that because that's what you
have to be to get shit done you know
what I mean
so yeah that's how I totally yeah she's
very thorough so yeah and generally
people are wrong so you have to do it
yourself and and represent yourself and
trust your instincts and and just do
what you you know and if you don't like
the answer somebody gives you it's
everything's like the DMV you know you
go to the next person just the world the
world is like the DMV if you don't like
the everybody's wrong half of
everybody's wrong nobody knows what
they're doing no matter what your
lawyers and doctors everybody's flailing
or winging it on some level so just like
you know you go to the next person the
prerequisite before you because wait
wait for a month
yeah because because push yep because
perception is everything nothing is what
it seems and our strengths are our
weaknesses and our weaknesses are our
strengths you know so
yeah yeah exactly that's the hardest
thing to do is nothing that's why I call
it the the no-till nothing style because
you know the hardest thing to do is
nothing a lot of times it's just human
nature to want to impose our will and
fuck shit up that's just like our you
know so we feel useful we create a fire
so we can put it out but like then it's
just like that downward spiral you know
it's like flushing yourself down a
toilet you know just you know like don't
go there don't go there just like chill
you know and just like let it just
naturally you know organically like
happen you know and that's that's yeah
this is epic
that would I know yeah yeah it's the
five-year-old this is epic like some yes
some Africa but it changes it changes I
was up at the Humboldt conference and I
shared a jar oh yeah and it is top notch
if you have any interests yeah yeah we
were there last year right Todd talked
about expanding and that was like really
condensed yeah that was all when you
only have so much time yeah and you need
to get the job done yeah like the cup is
so much there's so many different you
know it's hard to really focus on just
the regenitive you're there and you know
here we're just there's so much you you
know you it's hard to even know there's
an outside yeah yeah just stuck here
your soul don't in place that's a stone
you can't leave so Nicholas who's five
they have their own pots and they do
whatever the hell they want in them and
it is literally a free-for-all dude it's
crazy what it is really do you just give
them like full like I'm gonna no no no
seriously the seven-year-old in veg is
like actually I want to chop and drop
okay okay well that's the season you
know he learned a hard lesson but he
literally is crying he's like oh I
killed it it it's done for the year you
know but he's seven and he's learning
that you know and it's like oh that's
what we grow in the garden you know that
those experiences you said but you said
that was the sunshine so this was gift
the seats were gifted to me from a young
man who's doing beautiful names named do
Sean who was also at the Humboldt
conference so this is like coming full
circle closure in the loops yeah
and this is on purpose I met up with
people at the Humboldt conference that
were like we're gonna share some
genetics and see how it changes because
we're what are the my understanding it's
her loopy fruity yeah give me a second I
can look at my phone I like really no
hold on SEC yay for phones I hate them
and they're so useful so so he was
interested in people growing it out in
different microclimates to see how it
expresses itself differently do John
gets the reality that there's stuff
going on in the soil and then you also
understand that actually if you have the
life around just the rhizosphere just
around the roots you don't have to have
it in everything but it will grow right
and so you can have a pot if that's all
you got and you can put that life back
in that pot
and it will do special things like it's
crazy and so my kids have that
understanding and so we play with the
pots we experiment it they don't they
don't they know it's a garden but they
call it the laboratory thank you it's so
great like my seven really inspiring it
makes me want to like dude it's how we
grow I'm training my side oh yeah you
know that too but also you know have
them plant their own seed you know I've
been honestly afraid to enter the world
but on a personal level on your personal
you can do that right I mean that's like
legal
I'll give you can I mean opposed to like
my license borrow it
my kids are not allowed in my
greenhouses or whatever stuff like that
but you used to like five years ago no
not on write on record no I'm definitely
not admitting that I had my no you and
not really ever supposed to have your
kids see because legally what do we give
people I mean I'm not saying it's a
problem but I wouldn't necessarily want
to you know going records thing that I
had my kids running around in my
greenhouse I would never do that
that's wrong that's wrong that's just
wrong we're not there yet
how's that yeah I would never do that to
my children and outside in the sunshine
oh my god in the sunshine running
through a cannabis plants with terpenes
everywhere
it leaks healing them and and and loving
on oh my god we go by the way weird oh
yeah would you like some care yeah pick
some South Africa ground cherries and
some potatoes yeah that's usually what I
grow
cherry kale over there yeah flowy so my
kids are learning about patience and the
plants are teaching them about that yeah
yeah we got the I only know that because
the plant taught me yeah we got that and
literally how it works and I'm just I
got something else to share guys listen
up there's a whole other world out there
holy shit I love the headlamp you can
really see stuff
the Kindle or the television or the iPad
or whatever and I hook up a microscope
to the TV and I'm showing them their
plants and the soil and the light and oh
yeah I need one of those microscopes and
it's this big and so this microscopic
creature dude it's better than it's so
crazy there's this thing called a micro
arthropods like it's on the screen right
and it looks like Godzilla walking
through Tokyo walk right claws forget
pincers and shit
fungus is going like ah I can't move
okay it's it's alive right you've been
in a garden it's alive and you can see
it and that actually tells you how your
plants are growing it's it's so epic
it's so amazing okay up if you if you
haven't looked through a microscope at
your soil it'll blow your mind son bolt
groan is that is that Johnson son bolt
goes perfect yeah this is Sunshine's
but growing on the Central Coast in
living soil pushing that this this minty
and nice fennel terpene alright that's
what you were talking about yeah I'm
talking about
okay well the fennel has this terpene
the smells flavor right and and it's
that smell when you zoom in it's that
smell when you're at lika an Indian
restaurant and there's that little bowl
of mints and you're like I'm not quite
sure what those are but I'm still a
little hungry you know and you haven't
and it hit you with that licorice but
it's also minty you know what I mean
and it's a plant that literally just
grows on the roadside and it pumps out
seeds and it's happy to grow anywhere no
Mullens different but it's an amazing
plant - fennel smoke yeah yeah it's
healing
so it's just putting the puzzle pieces
together
if the microbes in your soil don't have
those puzzle pieces to work with it
can't change the picture it's literally
just adding biodiversity adversity
that's what it I am adding to your bio
of building your biome adding to
diversity yeah and you can do that on
site you can encourage that growth for
pennies yeah without animals just
through plants yeah just through a plant
you just can't you to learn to work with
it in a little different way and it
starts so really grew then you don't
need to like necessarily you know halt
manures rights and then you have to call
them you basically work chop and drop
cover cropping yeah compel once I done
with my tomatoes this year I'm like you
guys got hit with a frost it's all a
this snip cross cross cross breakup done
and then I put compost and molt over the
top of that and I let it just mellow
overwinter they do so much work over the
winter like that's when your soils
really doing the work I know and then
they put in that in the spring yeah and
so if you're not loving on your soil
that's your when you realize that and
when you really realize and get that
that's that's oh yeah Horton step in
here I go on vacation with my kids like
their stretches a time where I I'm like
alright close the gate and you're like
we'll see you when you get when I get
back but I've got the rest of the team
already working in there so there's
confidence and so if there's a weird
temperature spike or a weird chill in
the air the microbes literally keep the
soil warmer like your compost pile heats
up to a hundred it'll catch fire wait
what caught fire the party of life
literally caught the shit on fire and
you can't even see
it's that powerful and you just kind of
work with it's pretty insane yeah it's
amazing it's pretty insane it you're
just getting the team running and all in
the same page but what were you saying
specifically about the fennel like
because you were talking about like
cutting it down and then that kind of
mulch it like okay so you're taking that
input you're processing a turning point
is with a lot of fennel growing on your
proper know how you know I don't why I
have a small grow I have a big beautiful
community right it's like even like you
and I were talking about it's like Mike
Arden it's too small to feed my
community so I work with other farmers
to help them understand how they can
grow strawberries and hundreds of acres
in the Santa Maria Valley in a healthier
way and now I'm helping to feed my
community see what I mean it's it it
shifts it just a little bit but it
changes the program like literally he's
got a program and now he's got life as
part of that program it's it's it's
beautiful and it just took some time and
to work with people help them understand
and cannabis is like the conductor at
the orchestra and it changes the music
depending on how many pieces are in
front of you to work with right and it's
it's there when I take my seed the seed
I take a handful of where that see is
going to grow and I take it and I put
intent into it and then I take it and I
put it in water and get the water
soluble these microbes are 70% water
wake everybody up and I soak my seeds in
it
my Caesar literally sucking in we're
really basically can take your seeds and
go out in the forest and get some
leafmold soil no see but my rope is all
those things put in stacked right yeah
so I take that and so there's no
transition there's no shock like
everybody sends out their little poor
pictures of root porn you know I missed
a camera or whatever and I'm like oh
poor little babies because you're
exposing to something that that's not
how it's grown right it changes it
versus oh I know what to do here and
those genetics run and they've got all
the team with them but that's where that
Orchestra all those players in front of
them if you're missing that's the timing
of it all it is but you got a spin
something to know the timing of it yeah
that's like kung fu right there it's
mushed yeah that's some kung fu right
there cuz the timing is everything
microbes the kungfu but they are like
you right you because i can be like hey
this person overwatered which meant they
sent that environment into an anaerobic
state
yes fermentation is powerful and your
plants we use it but you don't want your
roots like that because those those
microbes that go anaerobic they
literally they fucking fart alcohol and
burn your stuff off that's what they're
doing
so it's excrement is alright like we
breathe in oxygen exhale carbon dioxide
they're like okay i'm gonna take in all
this good and pomp out poison because
that's how they grow from over-watering
do let me show you a picture I have a
thanks thanks it's a simple thing right
but most people don't think it's a big
deal because they don't understand why
it hurts your plans it's ripping them
out of where they're literally the it's
called the rhizosphere that's just
coding with life it's coated with life
from too much water and you drown it
you've seen that plant right it looks
like it got drowned and that's what
happens because they breathe the soil
freeze
[Music]
but the thing of it is oil like it so
the grow water yeah oil is the habitat
so it's like you saying my plant grows
in the Amazon the diversity the life the
layers the depth of water that this the
birdsong the the storm or the the dust
from the plains of Africa being lifted
up across the Atlantic and coming down
as minerals across that's how they get
fertilizer like what it's like that's
what the plant wants to do that's how it
grows oh that changes things and you can
start small because the microbes are
even smaller so you can literally start
small yeah system to do that in that's
why I was saying yeah I've got yeah
there's products out there too that are
starting to really turn the corner to
understand that no no it's not about NPK
there's if you want to help your plants
the first thing to change there go stop
using nitrogen just think of that how
would that change how you grow if you
didn't use any night do you mean like
out of a bottle yeah that's so easy to
write nitrogen it's ridiculous
only out of like it's a dead grass I go
and like it's not used like weed rack
and use like a month old dead grass to
turn into like a jLF and like that yeah
you know which is but we were kept from
that technology because like you know
the nutrient companies don't want you to
know how easy it is to make nutrients
out of how to make liquid nutrients out
of
you're making it plant-available yeah so
you're taking what you got and turning
it into what you need yeah you can do it
oh yeah no I thought we did yeah we did
that this we've been doing that for I
haven't been doing it anaerobically but
I've been doing it you know no-till
style so talk about some stuff but maybe
do anaerobically versus real quickly
well real fast
anaerobic is just a category right it's
what do you prefer that that's really
all it is
but that preference changes what you
promote and that's why I like
lactobacilli is so important because
work in that middle ground and actually
it produces an enzyme that kills the bad
guys so literally it's like if you're
having a problem where it's leaning
towards and you can see it like you can
literally look at a soil sample and I
can tell your plants drowning before the
plant is drowning because those
creatures that like that anaerobic
environment they start to multiply and
you can see
you can see them and at that point
they're gone okay we're over but that's
an anaerobic environment that is created
because there's not proper drainage you
know what I mean that's different than
creating an anaerobic environment to
cultivate specific bacteria you know
from from the plant to feed to the plant
which is kind of the completely
completeness of you know using like a G
DOM liquid fertilizer which is you know
made from in my instance I used cannabis
leaves because that's the methodology is
that a plant know not what you got but
what the plant needs it's not about me
it's about you know the plant only needs
you know what's already there so it's
connecting its own
yeah what do you got bro okay so it's
both it's basically both it's just
there's just like it's just like kung fu
it's just like different styles of
kungfu it's not that one is better than
the other or they don't all work
together or when they do we fight you
use you learn you know so it's not like
a competition it's a friendly right you
know we get in a flow where there's were
like hard but it's easy yeah you know
but it but it isn't evolution your
process so I start out with collecting
the members of the team that live in the
area and so that's going to different
habitats it's going to the healthiest
undisturbed leftovers I'm pretty no like
that's where you find what grows there
on that smallest yeah but that you're
not you know if you're if you're not
sealing them then they're not
cultivating anaerobically you know cuz
there's air and so you collect them and
then you can take and you're and you'll
know it because it'll stink like crazy
yes like there's something primal where
you're like that is not healthy don't go
there
done that right you flip a tarp or
whatever little oh there's that dog shit
right well I don't I don't know I mean I
think that I think that comes back to
perception is everything because in some
cultures you know state they like stinky
stuff
will do maybe Americans don't you know
but Koreans you know KN app curry they
are not afraid of like when I mentioned
I mentioned certain K you know Jew Dom
style you know you know applications and
people get like weirded out like be
crazy
you are like dirty dogs but it is so
beautiful I do like when I put it in
your mouth and it's like custard sweet
and it is the biggest shift of
perspective because you go everything I
say is saying that this is not healthy
and yet there's something to it too
right and you you experience it anew
it's it's really kind of a weird but
it's good Owen son cycling or on using
or using cannabis health healthy or sick
to to make products for further cannabis
growing right yeah definitely using it
in the compost pile and chipping
chipping stocks we love gently Chappell
like
we'll cut a field will cut all the
product on the field or the greenhouses
everything left please run through the
chipper and that's our you know that's
like and the one like that I really
piece you gotta like condense the
material down you know somehow yeah like
for things that take a while to break
down here's the thing is like this we're
doing a lot of chitchat for work sudden
oak death
that one's easy but like what I'm saying
is that the recorded that because that's
interesting sudden oak death is I live
with that I live in at an oak forest so
so if it is there a negative effect on
the cannabis plant by using oak that was
down that died due to sudden oak I
understand how it could that's dangerous
okay so taking all and some of the
didn't die on oak but I'm just going
through or I'm using like a pile of
chips that you know which run through a
chipper from The Electric Company
you know they left like 20 yards of
chips from my property so yeah like that
these are oak dominant piles there's
four oak redwood but you don't know like
the percentages or anything in the pile
I do it's predominantly 10 oh I'd say
for Santana easily and maybe more 80%
1000 words and maybe a couple of drones
literally very few madronas down there
so what what like I've found is that if
I can use stuff that's been down 5 10 15
years
run it through the chipper I need way
less nitrogen in order to get a pile
cooking and let the rain hit it and it
breaks down really nice a lot more fun
Glade on yeah that's like Duff at that
point you know it's stuffy
yeah yes oh yeah yeah yeah yeah totally
yeah let the woodchips get all you know
just inoculated they're just like thick
I'll dig into it I'll harvest the spots
that are just like cooked with like a
white you know fungal hypee where
they're like they're just like like just
decomposing at this one layer you know
quicker then like up heat you know
they're just it's just eating it that
one layer so much in chip piles yeah
where we have things like what I guess
is like ecto but this strand like where
these through where the where it starts
webbing together but it's in dense
pockets like so okay so you go a pile
and it's chipped up especially if it
looks like real rotten when it went in
and it's already a super fine a lot of
fines coming out we could get it wet it
like a 1 or 2 heavy
we get some water into the piles trying
to keep the spot piles low and we'll see
it that the web's run through it but
what's weird is that they don't run
consistently they run maybe light at
first as they're building up but then
into these heavy pockets and those like
Justin knock you like yeah they just
like go into like a ball and just like
eat everything and then go from there
after we read Jeff lowenfeld book the
teeming with fungi yeah
Jeff's book so in towards the end of the
book it teaches you about where to find
fungal hypha theory in in the wild right
and so we found out that you know like
long term of what full term outdoor
cannabis plants are like really
beneficial to you know a fungal dominant
you know association with your bacteria
mixed in in there right so my neighbor
was basically it's the one who gave us
the book to read was like you know we
can go find these like whole pockets of
dense mycorrhizae in the forest it's all
just like right there next to we're
broken oak trees are like falling on the
ground so like we literally just went
off in the woods a little bit and like
right where you would see where big old
branches had fallen down our trees had
fallen down you could like push over
like the top like decrepid layer of what
was bargained stuff and there's just
like hole just in dense pockets of it
where the I I assume where all that
comes from is the microbes in the
yes and mycelium are eating the wood
tissue inside of the the log or whatever
that's falling down right so that's
that's where that's where I've
personally experienced like finding it
in the wild in in old-growth forests
that hasn't been disturbed for at least
sixty years you know so that was just
cool to find you know right right right
but you're saying of talking about like
wait the specifically you know what I
mean
you were saying specifically how you
know what the tan oaks I think you know
like what if it's infix if I've been
I've been wondering that myself if it's
like dangerous or not to use the tan
Oaks but so I'm just trying to
out-compete whatever whatever's there
that yeah I like I just I don't see how
there's any like Cano concern to me and
growing cannabis like maybe if I was
raising it was if I was tricking me if I
was raising little tan oh I'd also be
like should I be using this as my soil
component but like I just see it as
something that's available and works way
sooner so we at for instance we have
this big pile that we're working with
its fir dominant and it's more like
twenty years down and it was already
bucked and run with dozers and stuff it
was like um you know waste in making a
pond a long time ago and so we've been
working this ferpa and I'm like okay
there's stuff in there and I also have
like in different spots these like 50 60
70 year old firs that they that they
dropped and they couldn't get out at the
time or whatever happened and I have
access to them and I'm more okay with
thinking about using that stuff but like
fresh fir just doesn't work in our
situation I don't think I think it's too
acidic
it's got like a lot of I don't know
there I think there's a lot of anti
microbials
in it just just by the nature of all the
terpenes
exactly yeah yeah I don't you I don't
have much fur in that yeah it's
predominantly ten of which and I've been
wondering that is this dangerous am I
gonna you know if it's in fire with
Sutton okay yeah i don't know i don't i
did that probably know i just being
driving with it so yeah like I asked the
lab I asked one of the labs and and he
thought it was fine too
also heavy metals I was concerned about
heavy metal waterborne but I want I
watched how its spread on my property
for my my property it was chainsaws PG&amp;E
like we want we watch it come in on the
power lines and spread through our
forests for sure and they they told
afterwards when I asked them yeah they
they'd for sure yeah that will happen
I've seen that happen to with PG&amp;E come
in and they're just carrying it on their
trucks their chainsaws have it they have
it they've been working in it all day
it's in their pant cuffs it's on them
that's you know what I mean that's
either coming in on them it's here
they're in the air so it's kind of
everywhere
it's kind of hard to hard to hide from
it at this point you know I have dicey
Mountains just dying you know up where
I'm at my neighbors Hill is just like
drowning out but by me it's not so bad
honestly I must say where I'm at it
doesn't seem so bad work
what may because we're actually working
with the forest and and letting it
breathe you know
maybe because we're letting it breathe
just the simple cuz I'm cutting so many
trees down or that fault you know I live
in a like wherever you're standing and
there's no tree there were ten ten oak
trees on the land we can verify this
like you know that's how thick it is and
I have north east and west facing so
it's challenging I fight for space
I fight trees oh yeah whatever
for light and in flat space I have to
like you know fight for it with like a
chainsaw and an excavator you know to
keep my spaces my life my flag or or not
even flat but just whatever and if it's
hope dominant then I would say you use
that to your advantage
yeah yeah it's what I've been doing I
just need my I've been predominantly
using like ten oak chips hi fungal tan
oak chips as my base and then I'm using
I have this hundred-year-old wisteria
patch that's mulching this
hundred-year-old wisteria
leaves for a hundred years and then I'll
be gathering up ten oak leaves I'll
gather up ain't rotten anything I could
find that high fungal rot even like
different color I'll go for like
different like a yellow fungus on the
redwoods on the Redwood deaf I've been
growing old yellow I call it I'm trying
to grow old yellow and get it to pop
I've been trying to get a morels to pop
in my my my beds inoculated with them
some morels
I don't know they'll take a minute to
pop up it's it's still early to tell but
I was really just yeah I thought that
would be ideal
that would be cool it's giant morels
popping up under your care cannabis
plants that I'm stir talking mushrooms
that pop up in the Cardinal what is that
all right on right now really yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah right on
yeah absolutely yeah give things a try
toke first so it kind of sets your
palate
would you like to pass around if you
guys would like to feel like they're not
sweet super sweet right I can't wait to
talk to what oh yeah