so we have our dab station here with
Andrew we have three different companies
that brought us different sauces and
stuff talking trees
pink lemonade live resin is what I'm
going with first love the live res and
protect the whole plant apex has brought
us some beautiful things papaya and very
Caribbean of us I can't wait to try it
I'm excited for that a lotta gelotti's
always delicious heck yeah
and then nug brought some diamond yeah
diamonds strawberry-banana diamonds oh
yeah look at that over 80% right now
badass yeah diamonds awesome
yeah so we're gonna try the talking
trees pink like look lemonade live resin
can't wait to do a dab because I'm not
drinking tonight very exciting excellent
thanks Angie yeah so this right now is
just a be nails email set up it's called
their Trinity series so this is a quartz
dish so you're gonna get the best flavor
possible nice I always prefer quartz
right low temp dabs quartz and then this
little recycler pulls it on up through
and a little cyclone motion so it's
pretty fun really easy on the lungs and
not gonna splash in your mouth when
you're in your dab so that's what we
like to keep it clean fresh and at a low
temperature so you're taking a DAB
before yes alright just making sure
ma'am so you ready yep go ahead I'm
gonna pull for you
beautiful cranky right
oh wow does that taste code goodness
yeah pink lemonade live resin from
talking trees okay I can have another
one of those oh we do okay perfect then
I'll wait for the next one we're going
to the whole lineup I love this game yes
please what we got from apex next apex
we have possio possio let's go this
guy's looking free from oh my god get
the fuel coming off of that yeah it's
fantastic let me get you a little
fresher on here gonna clean this bad boy
out for a second fresh tastier q-tip
industries never thought they would good
day yeah all right a little basket here
cheers my friend let me know when to
pull for you
so yeah it's the fuel absolutely
yeah it's good very different for the
pink lemon absolutely oh yeah yeah you
can smell that just knows alone
something on the diamond love a diamond
boys best friends also here we go yeah
this one holy shit yeah that smells like
strawberry banana wow this is a
strawberry banana turf diamonds from nug
I love my job
you ready all right Cheers on number
three the turf diamonds
[Music]
smooth goodness Wow
so yeah this and a couple other devices
alongside with us too we also have the
vape exhale here if you haven't seen
this device before it is a rig that is
all electronic full vapor pattered they
the vapor path is all glass all the way
up through so you get the cleanest hit
possible so you have to come by and try
this yeah wait I've run through them all
again yeah yeah got all the best devices
here tonight all quartz dishes man so
you're gonna get the best taste and
that's no test for that for sheer cost I
mean that terpenes off the nodes match
the terpenes and your mouth is amazing
how it's all best of the best ready to
talk about Turkey and speaking of
terpenes actually over here we have the
true terpenes these are some of their
most expensive terpene combinations that
they have available this one on the end
is one of my favorites balancing its
found in Valencia oranges mainly you get
your nose on that man that for that
ounce right there is four hundred and
thirteen dollars in that little vial Wow
one of the more rare and what do you do
with this so you would I'm just using
this tonight as a nose exercise so we're
kind of pairing this with some of the
concentrates so you get a nice sensory
experience you smell some of the
terpenes go to along side with it can
really affect what you taste after you
smell like that once you trigger that in
your brain for sampling but all wine
guys yeah or we could take a little dip
of the Terps and mix it into your
concentrate to give you a little bit of
it I am you'll hold out I'll be this
first round those works saving the big
stuff for later my friend for a big
diamond yeah example thanks Ange I
appreciate that no problem I can't wait
to go back
typically this is gonna be the workhorse
right so this is gonna be banging out
the dabs super quick in and out
depending on how long the line is
but as far as taste goes I don't really
have one that's better than another it's
gonna be depending on the experience
that you want right so if you want more
of a traditional nail and rig experience
come to this guy if you want something
brand new try the vape exhale I would go
this route this one does deliver a much
bigger hit with a
our amount of concentrate so this one is
also good for beginners too so you can
just take a tiny tiny little hit off of
it and walk away and be okay with that
so you don't have to finish all of your
your dab out of something like this over
here and then this guy we have a nail
with a torch so depending on if we are
allowed to have open flame in here or
not we'll figure that out and that will
dictate how this one runs tonight so
kind of giving a hodgepodge of different
devices and experiences for people in
the night at the Groff I can't believe
this