[Music]
my name is Kyle Kazan and I'm honored to
be moderating this afternoon's exciting
and in many ways groundbreaking
discussion about
cannabis uh who I am I'm a California
Native who went to USC I was a police
officer who spoken out against a drug
war over the last uh 10
years uh my company forms and manages
private funds to invest primarily in
real estate globally but now also in
cannabis in
California wow thank you thank you um we
have assembled today an amazing panel
who I know you will enjoy listening to
and learning
from our panel and timing have lined up
amazingly today yesterday Roar backer
far the roar backer far amendment was
passed into
law for those of you who don't know what
that is uh Congressman War backer is
here and can and will be explaining uh
last Friday the draft marijuana
regulations for the State of California
released and the head of that is Lori
Ajax and she is here
[Applause]
there was a discussion seemingly every
day about o the opioid epidemic in the
United States along with the addiction
and death
Associated there is a small but growing
movement of plant over
pills Dr Daniel pelli is here with his
expertise as is Dr Menard so we have we
are covering all the bases for Science
and law Dana racker currently serving
his third 13th term in Congress Dana
roer represents California's Scenic 48th
District which is in Orange
County he graduated from palis fy's high
school which is the best high school in
the world since I also graduated from
there uh he attended Harvard junior
college and received his bachelor degree
in history from Long Beach uh state in
1969 he received his master's degree
from the University of Southern
California also the best university in
the
world Congressman Roar backer has been a
champion of states rights issued for
marijuana he is one of the founders of
the Cannabis caucus in Congress his
racker far Amendment first introduced 14
years ago in 2003 and finally passed in
2014 prohibits the justice department
from spending funds to interfere with
the implementation of State medical
marijuana laws this was the first time
either chamber of Congress had voted to
protect medical marijuana patients
[Applause]
Dr Daniel pelli is an Italian born
American scientist he received his PhD
from Colombia in Neuroscience as postto
at Rockefeller
University Danielle joined the
University of California Irvine where he
is now Luis Turner Arnold chair in
neurosciences and professor of anatomy
and neurobiology pharmacology and
biological chemistry you guys should try
to read all that he is editorinchief of
cannabis and cannaboid cannaboid
research the only peer reviewed Journal
entirely dedicated to the study of
cannabis its derivatives and the
endogenous counterparts in the human
body he was quoted in the documentary
ride with Larry I think it was a
surprise to him it's worth a view if you
haven't seen it and has since become an
internet
sensation he deserves a round of
applause too
and Lori Ajax Lori Ajax is the chief of
the Bureau of medical cannabis
regulations appointed by Governor Brown
in February
2016 she was previously chief deputy
director of the California Department of
Alcohol Beverage Control or ABC so every
liquor store bar
restaurant where she had served in
multiple positions for over 22 years
including Deputy division Chief District
administrator and supervising
investigator Lori spent 10 years in
Private Industry prior to her state
government career she holds a Bachelor
of Science degree in criminal justice
from Cal State University Sacramento she
is the marijuana Zar in the state of
California Lori flew in today from her
office in Sacramento Lor
well I just got back from uh Washington
last night and uh it is always nice to
be home I live right across the Back Bay
there in Costa Mesa and uh you know I
you've noticed that I have this arm
sling on and uh just so you'll know no
they did not try to twist my arm to go
to the other side on this issue and uh I
know that happens sometimes you know I
was uh uh at a reunion recently and uh
this guy was telling me the story about
the fow who had all of his high school
Chums uh visit him uh and host a little
party for them 20 years later after they
graduated from high school and this guy
had been fabulously successful at a
beautiful home in a swimming pool and
everything and he took about uh 20 of
his buddies out and and the pool was
covered and he said I want to show you
all something and uh i p pushes the
button and the covers come off the
swimming pool and there the pool is
filled with alligators and sharks and
pythons and all sorts of horrible
animals and uh anyway he said look I
really wanted to do something for you
and and and show who's the most
courageous we always had to prove who is
the most courageous well I will give a
million dollars to any of you who will
jump in that pool and swim to the end
and they're all looking at each other
and nobody steps forward of course says
okay I didn't think any of you were
going to take that deal come on down we
got a barbecue down here and as they go
down for the barbecue hears a splash and
he looks into the pool and there's a guy
swimming across the pool beating away
the Sharks and the alligators finally he
crawls up on the end of the pool and the
guy says my God I didn't think anybody
would do it but you're going to get your
million dollars and he says I don't care
about the million dollars I want to find
out who pushed me in that pool
uh so here I am in Washington I don't
know what that has to do with shark
pools but uh yes uh sometimes Washington
can be a shark pit for people who are
principled and I have tried to be
principled which means that I make
people on the liberal side of the end of
the spectrum mad at me half the time
really mad at me and people in the
conservative end of the spectrum really
mad at me half the the time but that's
okay I mean I believe in what I'm doing
and that's what it's all about isn't it
and one thing that I believe in is I
believe that this country was founded on
the ideal of individual freedom and
liberty and it is up to adults to
determine for themselves what they
consume on their property period zero
that's what freedom is and
uh and this idea of Ideal where we have
limited government
and where you have individual personal
responsibility for themselves for
ourselves this idea where you have uh
constitutional rights and you have
criminal law being handled at one end of
locally and not at the at the federal
level these are all fundamental things
that our country was supposed to be
about and these are uh but a lot of
people have been talking about doctor
patient relationship that's another
principle that we've always lived with
the doctor patient relationship
marijuana laws in this country have
violated every basic principle this
country stands for for the last 75 years
it's time to stop
it and um so well I have always voted
for uh liberalizing marijuana laws
whether medical or adult use
marijuana uh this it's there as we all
know there are serious uh side effects
to having something outlawed like
marijuana and uh and that is uh we end
up with a situation where money that
would be going to uh local clinics or
whatever or or financing a regular
business now end up in the hands of drug
cartels in different parts of the world
undermining Democratic institutions so
there's actually a by product that is
felt elsewhere and also of course uh we
have basically turned uh the police uh
into a situation where they now have an
excuse to stop just about anybody and
frisk them which I do think is not what
our founding fathers had in mind for
Freedom when they talked about liberty
and justice for all and of course they
never they never foresaw a federal
police force like like we've established
now with the DEA coming into local
communities bashing down doors trying to
excuse this by the fact that somebody
has a little baggie of of weeds for Pete
sakes and see uh you know this is why we
were able to go in and Bash down that
door then we end up what giving military
equipment to people who are coming into
our own communities it's
ridiculous and so this has had a very
serious negative impact more than just
the individual freedom but individual
Freedom was enough for me so with that
said I've been trying to vote this way
and I failed for many years I've been in
Congress now 28 years but I finally
found the formula with some of my
colleagues on the other side of the
aisle on the Democratic site of the
aisle and uh that formula was
Republicans believe in states rights the
10th Amendment they always talk about it
so I said let's challenge
uh let's say that if a State legalizes
the use of medical
marijuana the federal government cannot
use the funds that we have to supersede
what the people of that state have
already decided and
uh
that that amendment that Amendment
because instead of doing the job
ourselves and saying this is the law for
the whole country we left it up to the
states and with that in
2014 I was able to pass what they call
the roacher far Amendment which I'll
give you the exact numbers of the of the
vote which was
219 to
189 so what does that tell you that's a
pretty close vote I uh what made the
difference was that we had Republicans
coming over and supporting the idea of
states rights
and without that we would not have had
the success that we've had and since
that time of course we've had these
years since 2014 till now where we've
had uh a new industry being created
based on the idea that you have states
rights and the people of 45 states have
somewhat modified if not totally
legalize the use of medical
marijuana uh we just recently
as you was announced uh
yesterday uh was a big day because I
obviously I had to work to see that the
roacher far Amendment which says the
federal isn't going to interfere I had
to work really hard to make sure it was
in the Omnibus Bill which is a a bill of
all sorts of things put together to keep
the federal government running till
October now uh it didn't so the roacher
4 Amendment didn't just appear by Magic
you know I had to really run around and
talk to people and twist arms and all
the rest so uh and they uh of course uh
we managed to succeed and let me just
note that yesterday we succeeded in in
placing Roar again making sure the law
was in that we it's legal in those
States where people want to use medical
marijuana where the states have made it
legal uh that happened it just happened
the same day as National Prayer day so I
just as a Believer I say further proof
of the existence of God we won that one
there you go and
uh so what is the uh what do we stand
now and what's uh why why we must do
things look uh the the side one of the
side effects of all of this control you
see there are certain people who believe
in the nanny State they believe that
government should be watching out for us
even in our personal decisions you know
we got to have you can't buy a big glass
of Coke it has to be a medium-sized
class of coke now no no I don't believe
in that but a large number both
conservatives and liberals believe that
we're going to try to watch out for
people by controlling their own
decisions over their own lives and we
now have to make sure that
that benevolent
uh feeling and reason for being involved
does not oversee what we consider to be
personal freedom and liberty and there's
been serious consequences to that and
one of the serious consequences has been
we have not done the medical research on
the on the cannabis plant that we should
have I mean there is no reason in the
world why a cannabis plant has not been
the focus of major research to see if it
can help us people in various situations
why is it that we can do research on
opium but we can't do research on
cannabis how stupid is
that so anyway uh I have uh you know
there's a an an epidemic now as we know
in opiates across this country and I'm
going to leave you with one story and
just say we need to make sure every
member of the house if you have a uh if
you're not in my district uh make sure
you contact your member of the House to
support this this this thing this
situation with us that's really
important for you to do second of all
there was a statement issued by the
president of the United States uh I
think it was today uh explaining why he
did sign into law uh the Omnibus Bill
and that reflecting directly on the
roacher far Amendment and he stated uh
some people in the Cannabis community
think it's a little bit uh uh nebulous
and it is nebulous every time you get
involved with with lawyers and
politicians things are going to be
nebulous so people can maneuver but uh
but nebulous doesn't mean we've lost
doesn't mean we've lost ground it just
means it's nebulous and it's up to us to
try to make sure that people go the
right course uh and the president said
that he would uh uh he noted our the
amendment and then he noted that uh uh
but he will be enforcing the law now
does he mean enforcing the law as as Rob
backer far does he mean the law that
makes marijuana illegal federally well
there there's a contradiction there
however the ninth Circuit Court of
Appeals and several other courts have
cided with us saying it is clear that
the intention of Congress now is that
federal agents shall not go out and try
to supersede state law in those in those
states where they legalized medical
marijuana so for the president actually
to enforce the law at least up until the
the the Circuit Court of Appeals level
the court system is siding with us and
not with those people who would just
take us back to the Dark Ages where your
lives are all going to be controlled for
your benefits you know no that's not
going to hopefully we're going to that
if we have to in fact if we have to take
it all the way to the Supreme Court we
will win we will win on this because we
have already gone through several Court
layers and the judges understand that
that's the intent of Congress and that
is thus the law so don't freak out when
you're here when you look at the
president's statement and think that
well that leaves open other Alternatives
it does but we have other forces at play
as well legal forces I'm going to leave
you with that and let others get up and
and talk but I want to leave you with
with uh one story and uh some of you
have heard me tell that story but I'm
going to tell finish it tonight in in a
different way and that is uh as most of
you know I was elected mainly I was
elected 28 years ago because I had been
Ronald Reagan's principal speech writer
in the white house for seven years and
that sort of impressed people here I uh
you know I I had no money I Had No Name
ID because when you're a speech writer
for the president you're you're supposed
to be a ghost writer and I I held that
stand
and so I had no money and no name ID but
I had 50 pictures of myself with Ronald
Reagan and I won by a landslide of
course with the and my people are they
all outspent me Etc
well uh so I was elected as as the
Reagan
Republican and even you know I tell I
had a beard then and uh so that was
really cool they elected me even though
I had a beard and and I I had to shave
it cuz my wife well right before we got
married she she she pulls this one on me
you know I'm not going to get married to
a man with a beard you know come on you
know the wedding's two weeks away shave
the beard okay so I shaved the beard and
I remember I was walking downtown in
Huntington Beach and I said to myself
you know my constituents they remember
they all know me with the beard you know
Reagan uh roacher is the guy with the
beard next to Reagan and so I said well
I'm GNA walk down talked to some voters
and I stopped this guy said hey I'm
running for congress and I want your
vote the guy looks at me he says you got
it buddy that bearded bum who represents
us
now but let me leave you one this last
thought I didn't know what this would
mean for me all I knew is I believed in
individual freedom and I believe in what
our founding fathers had in mind for our
country that's all I knew when I got
involved with this particular issue and
I didn't know that I had some very
conservative supporters and didn't know
how they would react so there was a guy
who came into my office who was a uh
retired military officer who was now was
in Aerospace and I asked him and he was
the typical roacher voter so I said
okay uh how do you feel about the fact
that the guy you've been supporting all
this time is the point person for
legalizing medical marijuana in the
United
States and he looked at me he said
uh you don't really know me that well do
you and I said well you're in the
military and a pilot and now you're in
Aerospace and I says yeah but what you
don't know is I have three sons two of
them or three of them uh marched off the
day after 911 and signed up for the
military okay and so I said yeah said a
couple years later two of them came home
the third one who came home wasn't my
son anymore he was on the ground in
convulsions
and what could I do and and he said
nothing we did could help him and uh and
and he said we took him to the VA and by
the way this is sinful that we don't
allow the VA to handle anything that can
help our veterans should be given to
them so anyway went to the VA he says it
wasn't helping them and they kept giving
him giving these other things that may
turn him into a zombie and finally after
a year he said some guy from VA pulled
us aside come and see me downtown we did
he said look I can't tell you this at
the VA property but uh he said uh you
your son needs marijuana here's a
prescription here's how to use it and he
says you know my son hasn't had a
seizure since that day now now he said
so I'm going to come over and give you a
hug okay but he called me a couple days
ago so if you guys have heard that story
before he called me a couple days ago
and how is your son are the seizures
still gone he says yeah the seizures are
still gone but there's a problem I said
what's the problem well the VA has got
him addicted to these opiates and he's
like a zombie and they want to and when
they try to take him
off they they're insisting that they he
stops using the mar the marijuana as
well and the seizures come
back this is outrageous this is insane
and and I will tell you right now uh uh
the oh and then here's what he told me
he says and and we're in a crisis and we
need your help his son was there and
they were trying to get him off opiates
and then they're demanding takes care of
everything which is going to throw him
into a seizure so he went out in the car
uh to consume some
cannabis now the people who guard our VA
hospitals uh the the the parking lot are
federal employees and they arrested
him and they said will you help and of
course I'm going to help for God's sakes
this is a this is the type of nonsense
and and just
inhumane ignorance that comes when
people are trying to run other people's
lives for them yeah everybody can be
well I'm sure the people who made these
uh decisions were well intended just
like those congressman who voted for one
of the bills we put up that said the VA
will be free to uh to prescribe Mar
medical marijuana in those states where
medical marijuana is legal and that was
defeated by like three or four votes now
I'm not those people who voted against
that they were not mean-spirited they
don't want this man to suffer but we now
know we have to get the word to these
people that the not only the veterans
but our senior citizens and every and
lots of other people are suffering
because of this effort on their part to
protect them from themselves how stupid
is that we are smarter than that but
they all have good Souls you know we're
not telling the telling you these are
evil people doing this no it's not we
need to reach out to those people and
change the law and give freedom to our
people and give some help to those
people are suffering who cannabis can
help so God bless you thank you very
much
so first I'm going to go to Dana I'm not
going to ask about the pool and the
snakes and the
crocodiles um so a lot of people in here
are thinking they're either in the
business thinking about getting the
business um and the question I get asked
most often is Jeff
sessions what do we think Mr sessions
might do as he tipped his hand coal
letter that kind of thing
Jeff sessions uh Jeff sessions is a very
good friend of mine I've known him for
30 years uh he's in factly more than
that I actually met him when I was still
a teenager and he was a teenager and we
were involved in conservative
organizations and every one of the
conservative organizations that we were
part of uh uh stressed uh the
constitutional government including the
10th Amendment to the
Constitution uh which leaves things like
this up to the states and I have
reminded him of that many times and uh
so uh let me just
note uh he he is an honest man and a
person who's got a good heart and just
like a lot of people who want to help
you along by telling you what to do with
your personal life they are very well
motivated in that they really have good
Hearts they're they think they're
helping you out and Jeff thinks that how
horrible it is when he's seen you know
he came up in the 60s and saw people who
were you
know getting really wild and that's
impacted on his vision of what it's
going to be like uh so it's it's
difficult to tell him that yes normal
people and actually people you like like
veterans and Senior cens and a lot of
other people not just young people
wanting to get wild uh need to have the
freedom to use cannabis and that should
be up to the state government and the
people therein uh quite frankly I am uh
I was here not as a federal
representative I wouldn't think I'd want
as much regulation as we're talking
about here in the state of
California uh but that's up to you not
up to me and uh the uh but Jeff sessions
uh I talked to him I will have to admit
I talked to him
yesterday and uh on a number of subjects
this was one of them and we have agreed
that we're going to have a meeting where
we will indepth look at this issue and
uh you can just rest assured I don't
know if you uh after listening to me
speak if I hope that you trust the fact
that I learned my lessons about
Communications from Ronald Reagan the
the great communicator and I will put
all of those to work to try to expand
the realm of freedom for you to live
your lives and those people who want to
use cannabis to go right ahead and use
it adults to use that cannabis I will do
everything I can in that discussion with
Jeff to push freedom for us and I'll do
my best and I can't tell you I can I I
can only predict this if session goes
the wrong way and convinces the
president to reverse his position in the
campaign remember the president
specifically said in the campaign
medical marijuana should be legal and
adult youth should be left up to the
states he said that several times now if
Jeff uh convinced president to renig on
that I'm sorry but I will tell you this
much I will tell him that I have no
doubt that it will go to the courts and
then and the and the Circuit Court 9th
Circuit Court of Appeals has already
verified our position on this and we
don't expect other judges to find fault
with those with that decision so it will
be a huge waste of his time and money
and why wouldn't he do that so I'll make
the case we'll see what
happens
Dana so
what is your advice to people in the
business thinking about entering the
business growing a few plants at home
or if I put out something and said you
should invest with me what advice would
you give those people today in
2017 in May of 2017 the issue has not
been definitely settled yet so people
who are putting money out there are
entrepreneurs who are putting money in
into the Cannabis business and
especially the medical dispensary
business and they are taking a great
risk uh there are profits that should
come from risks that's that's as simple
as that this is the way free enterprise
system works and uh I would hope that uh
no one here begrudges them once it uh
becomes legal in this state and if we
manage to secure the uh uh this
uh Arena uh from federal intervention I
hope no one here uh begrudges these
people the right to make a profit and I
know this is the Republican part of my
personality coming out here but you have
a lot of people right now are taking
great risks in order to get medical
marijuana to people who need it and yes
uh they should uh if if we move forward
which is not certain yet I mean
uh not only Jeff sessions but who knows
uh uh even I don't have to tell you
folks but during Obama and now even
during Jerry Brown
uh I have not gotten the cooperation
from the Democrat side that I thought I
was going to get I mean uh we the the
the uh Attorney General's office under
Obama did was not supportive of the
efforts that I was making uh we made
that despite
what was going on with the president and
the Attorney General then and of course
Jerry Brown has not stepped up to the
plate either so you don't have it's
settled yet and as if you folks are
going to move forward remember it's with
that with what I just said that means
the future is not charted we will make
the future that's the great thing about
this country those of us in this room
the freedom belongs to the activists and
and I would hope that we all know that
we have to be very active in with our
with our elected officials and by doing
that we will protect the fre our freedom
to consume but also just as important
the right of people investing now to
make a profit so that they have done the
right thing in providing us the Cannabis
that people want to consume for their
medical reasons so I don't know if that
answered your question but that's what
it was
how can our Representatives protect
cannabis stakeholders from federal
intervention if local law enforcement
can be deputized as federal
agents well you we have to go to the
courts you know the court has to
determine what is the law and uh if you
deputize some local person to become a
federal agent at that point that person
if if it is the
uh for talking about the Department of
Justice at this moment and at least
until October of this year and hopefully
we'll get it
renewed uh that that person will be
breaking the law and uh whether if that
person is now on the Fe a federal law
enforcement officer working under the
control of the Department of Justice I'm
sorry the courts I have written along
with uh a majority of other members of
Congress written into the law that state
law will be
respected and whether or not they're
trying to get around it by uh
deputizing a local local law enforcement
or not they still come under the
jurisdiction of the Department of
Justice so I don't think there's any way
they can escape that again however this
may be decided in court and and so far
uh you know I've had to actually when
we're talking about whether or
not these various political figures that
we would have hoped would have been more
on our side on this issue whether it's
Jerry Brown or or Obama uh I was hoping
they would be but we I've had to end up
calling judges I literally have had to
call judges and write judges saying by
in the last few years when these people
have been in
power and they U and they actually
ignore the fact that we have put this in
a restriction into the Appropriations
Bill and I've had to call judges and say
look if you have a federal prosecutor in
your court today and he is Prosecuting
someone who's involved with the medical
use of
marijuana and this state and your state
has legalize the medical use of
marijuana there is only one criminal in
your court and that is the the uh guy
who is the prosecutor not the defendant
and uh so and and quite frankly I
remember doing that once and a the
federal court of appeals backed me up on
that in this particular case so uh we
what's the answer the answer is uh they
try to do things like that we'll have to
go to the courts and uh as long as we
have this
Coalition between the 68 Republicans who
believe in State's rights and the
Constitution and the Democrats on the
other side of the aisle who by the way I
think are motivated by the fact their
political base wants that which is
there's nothing wrong with that in a
democracy for go go for your political
base so that Coalition is the one who's
writing the law now not the people in
the executive branch their job is to
enforce the law after it's made by the
elected representatives so there you
go my uh question is for the congressman
there's a lot of talk today about doing
research and my group is ready to do
just that we're funding the next four
years of the tech neon in Israel's uh
research on cancer and we have a top top
Pediatric Hospital in the country ready
to do seven different clinical trials
with us and over a thousand children as
you may know the University of
Mississippi Mississippi that has the
contract with naida to provide companies
like mine with flour is growing what I
call Weed it's contaminated it's poor
quality many universities have dropped
out of clinical research it's being
cited on papers that they think their
their trials were of poor quality
because of the poor flow that they had
to to use what kind of advice can you
give someone like myself and my
organization who desperately needs our
own DEA grow license none of which have
been handed out yet what can we do in
order to change these regulations or get
a better policy in place so we can get a
federal DEA license to grow quality
cannabis for dying patients the uh the
great the greatest sin that I think has
been committed uh in this whole era of
where people want the government to be
the nanny government and take care of
our lives and thus have perpetuated what
I consider to be fascistic controls over
our personal lives Liv the worst effect
of that has been is that we have
basically
restricted the knowledge base that we
have on this plant this if we learn in
the future through opening up and we
need to open this up dramatically This
research you're right the Mississippi
thing that is a disgrace that is a
National Disgrace that we have left one
University with limited amount of of
ability to to look into into this issue
uh and if we learn in the future which I
believe uh the evidence seems to
indicate that there are some real uses
it's anecdotal now we need to prove that
but when that is proven I I think that
we need to look back on these people who
have ignored uh the potential goodness
of this uh in order to save us from
ourselves they're going to save us
wonderful they're going to control our
lives and uh that's what happen happens
when anyway I will fight to make sure
that research dollars by the way just
let me tell you this I don't people come
to me every
day with a disease they want to
have that they want to have researched
every day and I say I'm not going to
focus on one
disease I'm not going to do that I'm not
G but I will support increases in the
general level
of research in this country which I
always
have and I believe that when we look at
the general level of research we need to
make sure that that we don't eliminate
areas they have some people want us just
to focus on their particular problem but
when it comes to cannabis we've
eliminated an area of honest
investigation so uh you can count on
some of us there there's a lot of people
now that are that are aware that I am so
proud that the Israeli government has
taken the lead on this but I think at
the same time I'm proud of them I'm
ashamed of our own government for not
being taking that same stand on open
Research into this a long time ago so
thank
you okay I just wanted to make one uh
one comment concerning the the schedule
one issue and the and the University of
Mississippi um
I I know very well uh people at the
University of Mississippi I they're very
respectable scientists and everything
the issue is that really uh we can't do
research in the current regulatory
scenario that's all I have to say we
cannot schedule one seems like a uh the
schedule system seems like a reasonable
logical regulatory system it is
completely illogical and it's completely
wrong and the only thing that he
actually achieves is to really blocking
preventing researchers from doing their
job because everybody else who wants to
use it don't really
care and I want to reassert again what
the doctor just said and I'm sorry
Hillary Clinton wanting to
reschedule that means nothing the fact
is it could end up a disaster if there
was not schedule the right way it's
better if someone says deschedule all
right let's think about that but
uh we could we could we could end up we
could end up with a worse situation if
it's just rescheduling we literally
could end up where there's less research
and there's and that the there's further
controls over each and every one of us
here so we got to be very very careful
when we're talking about rescheduling
[Music]
he