[Music]
my task is to bring you to the world of
medicine and i' like to start off with h
an email I received not long ago this is
one of the emails I receive uh basically
daily so I'm going to read it for you so
dear Dr P it says I have read about your
work on marijuana
I'm the father of a three-year-old girl
diagnosed with
autism I would walk through fire to get
her a
cure can my want help my
girl I got to say I've read this to
people so many times every time I read
it it curdles my
blood as a father as a
scientist I got to ask myself what what
is this man asking for me for me as a
scientist what can I do to answer this
question and the question that so many
other people are
asking can cannabis help in what can it
help as a scientist I have to put these
questions in a different
way I have to
ask what medical conditions if any can
really benefit from cannabis
what are the risks associated with
cannabis because there is no such a
thing as a benefit without a
risk and what can cannabis teach us that
may lead in general to better
therapies and as we approach these
questions I like to make very very clear
that emotions are
wonderful but we need
evidence we need
data we need evidencebased
answers opinions are great for debates
but when it comes to
decisions I think they have to be
tempered by
facts so I'm going to share with you
some facts and being a professor I
brought my slides and uh I'll walk you
through them I promise there will be
many chemical
structures
not so how does cannabis work many of
you know this let me just remind you it
contains chemicals one of them is quite
famous is called THC another one is
called CBD and the structure of one of
these compounds is shown so one of them
is shown here
THC so how does it work well when people
use the compound use the drug it enters
their brains and it Encounters in their
brains A protein that sits on the cell
on the surface of the brain cells these
are called neurons and these particular
proteins that
recognized THC in cannabis just like a
key is recognized by a lock these
proteins are called the cannabinoid
receptors and we have a ton of
cannabinoid receptors in the brain and
they are spread throughout the brain
they're present in specific regions of
the brain but also they're very very
very
abundant and what do they do when they
are activated by THC
well what they do is something similar
to what they do when they are activated
but they're our own compounds what I I
call the brain's own cannabis our brain
makes chemicals that have chemical
structures different from those of THC
but similar enough that they will
recognize the canabo receptor just like
THC does these compound are endogenous
cannabinoids so we call them
endocannabinoids just to sound
smart what do they do they do a lot of
different things and they're really
important things they control feeling
they control emotion they control
pain memory as well as
pleasure these are the functions of a
molecule our body
makes and we experience it every day as
we live our our lives these molecules
are regulating these different functions
of our body we should be aware of that
because it's very important to
understand what then cannabis does to
this endogenous system what does it do
well by activating the cannabinoid
receptors in the brain THC will produce
the effects that I'm sure you're quite
familiar with because your friends told
them about them it stimulates appetite
it relieves anxiety it alleviates pain
it impairs short-term memory and also it
can be
addictive these are the effects of THC
that pharmacologists like me that's my
job I'm a
pharmacologist pharmacologists like me
have over the last 30 years
characterized but how can we use these
effects from a therapeutic perspective
which once of these effects which we
have studied in the mouse in the rat in
the monkey and also in people can
actually turn into a real therapy and
this is what I'm going to try to briefly
go over with you in the next couple of
minutes the first one the one I want to
really stress and I wish this is if you
have to only take one thing out of my
boring lecture tonight is this chronic
pain one in 10 Americans experiences at
least once in their life excruciating
pain that comes from damaged nerve or
from inflammation chronic pain is
profoundly regulated by the
endocannabinoid system endocannabinoid
system is actually one of the main
Regulators of pain along with the other
system you have heard
before Congressman Nora Baker mentioned
the opid system the two systems are go
hand in hand and we have I'm going to
show you some
data we have data showing very very
clearly that comparing a placebo to a
cannabis the cannabis will perform
better than the placebo in alleviating
pain intensity in humans in
fact the Academy of Science the National
Academy of Science in a panel I was
honored to be a member
of uh last January concluded as you can
see written here in the slide that there
is conclusive and substantial evidence
that cannabis is effective as a
treatment of chronic pain in adults this
is a statement that comes straight out
of the conclusion of a study that
involved nine months of work looking at
24,000 papers and let me tell you being
a member of that committee I it was not
exactly a walk in the in the
woods chronic pain another one very very
important chemotherapy indu nausea and
vomiting I'm how many of us tonight have
family or themselves who have gone
through the ordeal of having
chemotherapy or experiencing one of
their family with
chemotherapy well THC in cannabis but
also
CBD the other component of cannabis they
act in regions of the brain that
stimulate appetite and reduce nausea so
this is an effect I like to stress that
is opposite to what the opes do opposite
so the opat cause nausea the
cannabinoids decrease it and the again
the National Academy of Sciences
concluded that cannabis
is useful as a treatment for it's not
potentially useful it's useful as a
treatment for chemotherapy induced
nausea and vomiting finally the third
indications on with the which National
Academy was extremely clear is
spasticity in multiple sclerosis
multiple sclerosis is accompanied as you
will know by these muscle spasms that
are extremely extreme ex painful and THC
acts to alleviate those spasms and again
this is the third and actually last
indication that the national ecademy has
recognized as being uh definitive and
having substantial support from evidence
now the National Academy also studied
other
indications and these are indications
that are often Allowed by States in
which medicinal cannabis is legal as
indications in which cannabis can be
prescribed however
the data do not support necessarily that
they do not support that and don't
necessarily support the opposite the
data are not there yet we do for example
Parkinson's disease Alzheimer's disease
cancers
autism post-traumatic stress
disorder these are all diseases in which
there is a lot of anecdotal evidence but
anecdotes do not no matter how exciting
they can be they not amount to proof to
evidence that we can use so we need what
do we need well we need a lot of work to
establish efficacies in these other
indications we need to establish basing
basing ourselves on the anecdotes we
have now ask the question are these
anecdotes valid for you you you you or
are just valid for the one person that
has told us about it that's an important
point so let's look at the other side of
the coin let's let's look at the risks
the first risk I want to put out there
for all of you and please do bring that
home and please do talk to your families
about it is using expecting and nursing
mothers I strongly recommend being very
very careful if you're expecting you
think you're expecting or if you're if
you're nursing to use cannabis and the
reason for that is that THC crosses the
barrier that defends the fetus from the
uh from the blood crosses it and it
accumulates in the fetus and so does in
the milk so the the infant will be
exposed to THC to CBD and we do not know
what that what that could bring about as
consequences which just simply don't
know while we don't know I say better
safe than sorry just don't do it
similarly
teenagers the brain of a teenager is
Extreme ex remely changing every day
don't we all know that who are
parents and obviously we want we want to
be sure that they are this growth is not
interfered with by anything not alcohol
not tobacco not marijuana either and
especially the frequent news of
marijuana we have to be careful about
for reason I would love to be able to
entertain you with with a very boring
two hour long lecture but I
won't there are a couple of other things
that one needs to be careful about
people who suffer from schizophrenia
people who have heart conditions should
be careful with with cannabis so this is
why this is medical cannabis because
it's going to be it has to be handled by
professionals by medical professionals
and an additional work is needed to
understand and fully assess those
risks so I'm going to conclude by asking
by saying a couple of things that I
think we can get done in the next five
years not in the next 50 years but
really in the next five years and I
would love to be able to be part of that
I think we say that we can say the last
word on cannabis Effectiveness in a
series of clinical indications for which
we still have no evidence of efficacy
for example Parkinson or
anxiety we can assess the risk
associated with medicinal cannabis use
which are probably going to be different
from those associated with with the
recreational cannabis
use and I think we need to leverage we
need to use our new knowledge to create
better cannabinoid based medicines to go
Beyond even cannabis and help the
patients in many other ways now in
conclusion I want to go back to the to
the email I received from this Anonymous
person can we help his girl yes I think
we can not right now but to be able to
answer that question
appropriately we need a societal
commitment to reduce regulatory hurdles
and to to support research and in
particular I want to say to deschedule
or
reschedule cannabis from schedule one to
a lower
schedule to make possible the research
that we need thank you very
much Dr pelli uh you write an email that
pretty much took the air out of the room
everybody just gasped at getting such an
email
so and I know in your position it's you
don't want to give advice but let's say
one of
us received that question perhaps we
have a relative that is dying of cancer
or is going through chemotherapy and
they ask us what do you know should I
should I try cannabis or should
I try some more conventional medicine
what would your advice be I say go to
your doctor uh speak to her or him and
and explain uh to your doctor that uh
you believe that this could be uh useful
for you what I try to do when people ask
me that question I also try to share
with them um some data so for example if
it's a cancer patient suffering from
great pain then I send these these folks
um uh scientific papers scientific
papers you know through the email and I
said bring this with you when you see
your physician
this is the Journal of the American
Medical Association it's not the Journal
of psychedelic studies it's something
very very serious and you have to take
it seriously that's all I can do as a
basic
scientist got thank you uh in your in
your slid show you mentioned under risk
factor
addiction um there's a lot of talk that
I'm seeing this this kind of nent
movement planted over pills and we
probably have a number of people here
that have read about cannabis or
thinking maybe I might try some can you
expand on addiction and cannabis let me
first start off by uh stating what is
addiction in the medical dictionary so a
behavior that we pursue despite our
knowledge that is hurting us that's an
addictive behavior so addiction is not
dependence you can become dependent on a
number of different things and as you
became dependent you can also regain
full control you know in a process that
is complex but it can be done addiction
is different addiction is also a disease
of the brain it's not a problem of will
it's a disease it's a chronic disease of
the
brain now does cannabis cause addiction
when we think addiction about addiction
in the terms I just shared with you we
always think the first thing we think
about is opiates crack
cocaine alcohol those are things that
devastating forms of addiction that um
we are familiar from a even from a
filmic standpoint we remember the movies
right you know and how people in the
movies with addiction behave and we
think well cannabis doesn't do that and
it's true cannabis does not do that the
type of addiction that cannabis causes
and now I think all special ists agree
uh we really no acts to grind that
cannabist does cause addiction the can
the type of can of addiction cannabis
causes is of a different type uh it's
milder it's harder to get but it's there
so it say 8% of the people you use it
become eventually can become eventually
addicted 8% doesn't seem a big number if
you compare it to the
45% you have with nicotine or the
35 40% you have with h cocaine it seems
like a small number but if a lot of
people use it that the small number is
going to translate into a lot of people
that small percentage into a lot of
people so I think uh we need to be
cognizant of this and ask ourselves
always when we talk about medical
cannabis because that's my main my main
concern uh what are we comparing
cannabis to so uh I I spoke about
chronic pain and there is a reason for
that because it's the one condition that
I believe offers the greatest uh uh
promise for cannabis and of course the
big comparator there is what the
opioids and we I don't think it needs
any introduction to anybody that the
opioids although very very effective are
extremely addictive drugs they're very
very addictive and there is no question
that if we compare cannabis to the
opioids the addictive properties of
cannabis are much milder than those of
the
opioids we know this for these are facts
but then there are a lot of questions
and I think we need to answer some of
those question let me let me point to
one in particular if we combine cannabis
and opiates what happens that's
something we need to ask because our
youth are going to do that and also our
patients are going to do
that we don't really know what happens
in the long term and we know what
happens in the short term in the short
term if you combine a small dose of an
opiate and a small dose of cannabis you
got a lot of painkilling effect so
that's called a cism with potentiation
in in case you care but but the problem
is in the long run are we enhancing the
possibility of getting an addiction to
either drug or are we decreasing it
that's again goes to the my last slide
we need resarch on this
hi my name is John stashenko and I have
a question for Dr pelli and Dr reard um
I was wondering if in your research if
either one of you have found or know
where we could find a list of
contraindications for cannabis medicines
you are asking about contraindications
to cannabis medicines I I tried to cover
some of the uh of the potential risks uh
in my presentation certainly um I think
it's important to avoid usage in uh uh
during pregnancy and during uh nursing
as well as in in adolescence at this
point I think is critical that we uh
before we make any proposal about use of
cannabis products in adolescent or
younger uh younger kids um we assess in
that condition in those conditions what
the safety of the product is I think
that is something we really owe to the
public as far as other specific uh
Contra indications um
actually
um medical use is likely to be different
from recreational use so what we have
learned from recreational use might turn
out to be outdated so that's one reason
why I pointed out that one thing that we
we do need in the future is to really
specifically ask the question medical
use say in the elderly is it going to be
uh causing specific effects that we do
not expect let me just elaborate on this
a little bit so if you um if you
consider for example the use of cannabis
in in young people one thing that
cannabis does do it makes
you shortens your memory that that's
something that that happens all the time
now that happens in young people does it
happen in older people in elderly people
we don't really know because the system
the famous endoc canaban system i i i b
everybody with is really changing
changes during life to to the point that
in in late adulthood and in old age it
might be actually have opposite effects
those it has during adolesence so if
this is the case then we really all all
the all the bets are off and we don't
really know what side effects could
happen in you know in a medical uh say
50 or 60 or 70 year old uh subject you
see what I'm saying a lot of research is
still needed
[Music]
he