[Music]
if you have this kind of face when I'm
going to pronounce a few words here and
there like this face U sorry what's
coming out of this is pretty much you
know what it's called it French Canadian
another word uh people living in
Montreal not in kbec city so just uh few
comments on this um pretty much you know
I started my career uh from the lab of
Dr REM Kiron Dr kirion is known to be we
call it you know in Canada The Godfather
of uh neurology and of course
neuroscience and I was working in his
lab to get my post duct and of course
you know I was working on opioids and
tolerance few days after that I end up
working FAS up
control uh we were working only and only
on
opioids uh the primary building was here
in Montreal and of course my boss used
to be in Stockholm
Sweden so 96 at the end of 95 96 we have
this great opportunity because I was
really focusing you know like a tunnel
you're in the big Pharma you have a
protein you have a molec you have to
make it work that's it that's all and of
course that's a tunnel
vision um was not quite happy so called
back you know uh Sweden and I say hey
guys we have a kind of a pre- project
sitting on the shelf sure then I mean we
have something but I don't think you're
going to be interested try
me and it was a nice cannabis program I
mean we started official in
1996 uh that was my baby if you will and
not only that we found with this SP
molecule
um let's let's talk about only an Alesia
for
now uh that was even better than the
opioid we were using in the lab I mean
that was impossible to believe and
until I will Shar your some data with
you um there's this nice pattern you
know that CBD can provide and not only
that I mean this molecule has a
potential that nobody can believe it's
really the peak of the
iceberg so we moved fast forward um and
had this another great opportunity you
know unfortunately the Cannabis program
but that's waso uh uh that can pretty
much you know that was not only a great
molecule we had nice analog you know for
this molecule I mean we were totally
n u well but when you merge sometime
with mastering control and Z you don't
always win uh technically you never win
so so from one thing to another I mean I
end up in not
only in Minnesota but of course you know
it was not cold enough for me so I went
down to
Colorado um from tax lab that I was
managing in Montreal to different C uh
contract research
organization uh it was clear I mean that
there was something to win there and
what I mean by that is companies that I
recently work with
200,000 molecule that they have just as
CB1 antagonist that doesn't penetrate
The Blood Vein barrier from my previous
work I mean an anide at
155 we we made you know a lot of
modification uh it was really impressive
injected locally injected pretty much
everywhere in the uh in the brain as
well
so here we are now I mean recently and I
see my colleague over there
nick uh last year I mean in
2016 we at microsite had pretty much all
the pain models and anxiety model
depression and so on even a PTSD
model but at last uh we found someone
via the network of Nick that we said
fine
we can go fast and furious with the c
industry uh our lab is a schedule one VA
schedule one and pretty much you know
with this Great Adventure in less than
six
months we end up with a nice compound I
mean that we can you can see
tonight so I think for now I'm going to
leave it like this but if you do have
question later on please stop but thank
you very much
have a great even
[Music]