[Music]
how many was Danny Keith I'm the CEO and
founder of cannabis club TV we ran in
dispensary television network with
hundreds of hours of content and which
one of them is the Bova de channel which
is well received yeah yeah which is dope
I mean for you guys to do that for us
definitely appreciate it would you get
the feedback no you were talking about a
little bit earlier with a gentleman we
ran into because he had asked us you
know who's your core audience and we
talked about you know very much the
producers the cultivators the rest of
them but that's one thing hey it's
lifestyle bro it's a lifestyle thing so
yeah so we're we're talking in is
interesting because you're the first to
pitch up you're like yeah you know while
a better part of overdose customer is
the producer is the the grower you're
like those guys come into the store and
then you have the distributors coming in
this store you have the bud tenders in
this store so I think you made an
excellent point of although your your
system your TVs are on the front line
for like better term you're in the
dispensaries that doesn't mean only
consumers are seeing the message right
no you know absolutely one of the things
that we did you know prior to really
scaling was understand the atmosphere
maybe talk to the dispensary owner ask
them what they have going on and just
hang out and it's surprising that you
know a lot of dispensaries are getting
between three and five hundred people a
day on and that's customers right I've
I've hung out in dispensaries all day
doing installs and whatnot there's
probably another hundred 150 industry
people coming through but just
constantly people don't understand this
revolving door be that new industry
where you have the vendors and and the
local reps and all that just coming
through and coming through and coming
through right and I think we talked a
little bit to like in this day and age
especially if you're not using video
driven content to tell your story
are you really losing out even if it's
only living on your YouTube channel or
you know wherever it may be it's like
you know that the message is just well
consumed with video and you know it
didn't take a lot of twisting your arm
to see for you guys to do a channel
because I think you saw the opportunity
to
to have another set of exposure that
maybe you wouldn't get otherwise like a
lot of people see the packs in the in
people's product and they that's where
it stops they don't really go any
further but if they are sitting there
watching and also they put two and two
together you start becoming a favorite
of theirs because now the sudden you're
helping their product stay fresh longer
and be you know more enjoyable if you
will exactly and that's the thing too we
hear from consumers which is surprise we
do some shows where it's b2b and b2c and
a lot of those consumers they'll say
yeah I got this product when I bought
top shelf from fill-in-the-blank
dispensary sure I actually took it out
of that because I went through the
product but the pack was still good and
I put it in my stash jar but now I need
to get more than so you're I mean it's a
great great opportunity for well I knew
you guys were winning in the b2c field
when you I was nice enough to get a
little care package from you and I
brought one home to my wife and she's
like oh yeah I already use those things
I'd peel them out of the stuff I get
back from the dispensary that's like Oh
fair enough so there is a little bit of
that self-induced education with your
product but I think that you know you
guys are a critical component and to you
know extending the lifespan of
specifically flower obviously you know
before the consumer buys it which is
like an unwritten or unknown factor and
I think that that because you've you
doing the content because of you guys
doing podcast like this it helps the
customer understand where your role is
and that's it that's again I mean I'm
I'm fluffing you up right now but I
appreciate that's what we want to do we
want to help you know our whole premise
for our company is to help educate the
consumer not just on flower but on
testing on I think the guy we were
talking to was a lab you know and it's
like yeah you know other brands go
through other brands are not happy with
their labs they see your ad all of a
sudden they're like oh you know so we
try to offer a well-rounded not just the
brand specific side but we try to get in
the b2b stuff as well nice very cool so
you uh if you can share I'm sure not all
this public information we always were
under four NDA so we would have those
kind of conversations but
smile you're on camera so yeah so you
know we tell us what you can share about
some of these new opportunities and new
partnerships you have going on this yeah
absolutely I think you know what we're
doing right now is applicable to other
verticals and other opportunities so in
addition to you know more and more
people especially in the cannabis space
are producing content so we're a really
attractive nuisance for them to be able
to get that automatic exposure I mean
just just for the record on content
providers they have an opportunity to
monetize in line so by the time we get
the content from them they're already
monetizing we're gonna be able to
guarantee them those impressions you
know we started becoming asked we
started expanding our categorical search
right you're you're a fringe one right
because not only you're a b2b but you're
kind of more on the flower side of
things like defamation and so when
there's like definite ends and
beginnings in the cannabis space on
where the people are able to market but
then there's the other area that they
don't know and that's that's where we
saw the need in hydro to kind of have a
space where we can help tell that story
inside those stores they're a critical
component of the process of growing and
everything so we launched harvest TV we
did that in partnership with Green Bros
we're building nice six foot tall
stainless encase stands so the TV's
right in your face
while hydro stores move their stuff
around a lot they do they don't
necessarily have walls sure you're on
camera buddy we're in the field people
we are live in the field this is not a
stage problem these are real dumb people
just do impromptu you know cue cards so
harvest TV is an exciting thing we
launched with grow gin first so we got
there 19 stores across 14 states
Congrats oh I appreciate that
and we're learning that space now a
different set of clientele and we're
gonna be launching in the early part of
March headshop TV so we also see a
crossover right and it kind of just goes
in line with everything that we try to
you know when I look at the way I
operate as a businessman is I first
unidentified a problem then I say okay
well can
I manufacture a solution and then can I
is there a monetizable component to that
solution and then is it really provide a
healthy return for the people that get
involved and you know we sew on our site
we have a marketplace we sell
accessories that like grinders and dab
rigs and yeah for companies that are
advertising lists I can't do ecommerce
and they're not really in headshot are
they're not really in cannabis stores so
they've been asking us to go into head
shop so that you can have that immediate
traction so we'll be fully in three
different categories by the first part
of q2 and then um you know we got some
exciting things going on with
grasshopper kiosks oh no we're gonna be
putting the TVs on top of the
grasshopper again right they are from
the bay they're in Hayward I believe or
Oakland and so we're gonna be the TVs on
top of those kiosks little different
model like you know we've got to be a
little bit more specific to the vending
machine component but that's gonna roll
out it's already in market right now
we're doing a beta and it looks really
well-received and then we're gonna be
doing mobile plays like mobile tours and
buses and we have a deal brewing with
the uber and lyft television company
that's going to be broadcasting content
into oberon lifts so we're taking the
same thing that we did in cannabis and
we're just replicating it across other
alternative markets and we've got a
great library of content and a really
eager consumer of that content and a
marketplace that needs a brand to that
consumer whatever so keep it simple yeah
it sounds complicated just keep it
simple
no and I like the fact that you are kind
of looking everything from channels both
literally and metaphorically speaking
like who are these audiences and and as
a company that needs to advertise you
know we're proud to be the Alpha we're
proud to be the leader but just like
coca-cola sponsoring FIFA you no matter
what position you're at you always have
to promote well there's a lot of fake
news out there yeah a lot of times
people are telling things that aren't
true about your brand and even if you're
the leader you got to straighten that
out yeah 100% and it's nice to hear that
you're targeting our audiences though
because we are recognizing to your point
hydro I mean head shops
that's another I'm really surprised head
shop smoke shops have had a different
angle since the whole cannabis and you
think III kind of thought and I know
you've been in the space for a minute
too
I think we all kind of thought that that
dispensaries would just organically sell
a ton of consumption devices and I think
the regulations made it a little bit
interesting by state like Washington you
cannot you cannot sell except the one
thing you can sell in your dispensary
are cannabis brought right and I think
also like just the overwhelming
inventory levels that cannabis stores
had too so that kind of left head shops
off to the side I think we're gonna see
2019 and 2020 be the year the head shop
yeah you know he's still you get the
supplies just talking to a gentleman
from Canada that's what he say he's like
you know I I go to my local dispensary
they have the oil tanks and they have
the flour that he's like they don't have
grinder aside to buy a grinder wise here
in the Bay Area I had to buy papers
while he's here in the Bay Area I'm like
really I mean that's you would think
you'd get the tools to do the job it's
been my advice people that say they want
to get into cannabis lately on a retail
level I just tell him open ahead shop
and they're like why would I do that I'm
like well there's no regulation you just
need a business permit and a landlord
that'll let you do it yeah there's not
the litany of other things that has to
take place like I wouldn't even do
tobacco I would just do and then just
become the premier place to smoke yeah
exactly true so I agree it's gonna well
with that let me ask you know what other
trend both of us being based out of
California which is in an interesting
space right now we'll just say we new
2018 was going to be a transitional year
but the permanent regs didn't even
permanent permanent regs didn't even
come out until last month what what do
you think for 2019 and 2020 do you think
the the market is going to continue to
mature not just California but
domestically and finally kind of take
that next step it needs to for success
well so everything I do is based on
numbers like people can have a
perception or try to sell a perception
when I have discussions with people it's
about what are the results what are the
numbers I think we've seen that the
state's intent to regulate has
manufactured a bigger gray in black
market now so you know it's manufactured
a bigger gray and black market which
they have to basically dial in and so
the state has to the state has to
realize that they need to do this or
that one over yeah it's okay it's
I think the regulations are gonna be
modified I think you know there's and
they would be you know look anytime you
go in and regulate an unregulated market
that's been on its own for multiple
decades you're gonna have a snapback
right so everybody's like in this shock
and awe that oh my gosh we got this
black market so in California it's but
it's recreational I don't understand
well it's the first round of regulations
so I think what you're gonna see is you
know we already see I have a couple
concepts one I think the states got to
kind of level out or calibrate their
taxation and and ease up a little bit so
that less people are enticed to go black
market that's number one easier said
than done
number two you know the commodity
component of cannabis is is a really
sometimes up and down up and down right
and so I think the stability of price
which I think is going to come from
organizations working together and I
think so
so the stabilization of cannabis so that
there can be money made from good people
would be helpful because sometimes
people really win and sometimes people
really lose and then I think the final
component is you know to stop letting
the consumer drive the dispensary
pricing and let the dispensary and the
brand's just determine the pricing yeah
that then the consumers will consume
because for everybody to think that they
can get you know the top-shelf cannabis
for 45 bucks plus tax you know I just II
I - man if I could get like 45 bucks
level I'm in you know so we got to do
some price adjustments on the market but
nonetheless it's an exciting time it's
not for the faint of heart
it takes a lot of eating bowls of shit
you know to basically get here and I
don't make money is always a driving
agent I think you have to look at what
your process is and then you you work on
your variables within there I work with
a couple brands I mean I work with
Tommy's brand Chung's choice even though
he's an influencer it's not easy you
know we still have all the same market
pressures so you guys do Willie's yeah I
talk to those guys they have challenges
I mean it's just market pressures that
are not predictable
that don't exist another business so
it's the cube thing the five times so
I'm 25 yeah very that's my two cents
awesome man
well what else anything that you know as
far as industry trends that you're
noticing you you're obviously touching
on brands and definitely good to hear
that some of these brands seem to be
maturing and coming into fruition but
what what is your take on you know kind
of trending as far as bigger brands
smaller brands what I have to say I'm
really excited about the the data that's
coming out like people embracing data
you know people were afraid of that at
first you know you had BDS you had
headset people are starting to pay
attention to the data you know we all
you know we all think what we know when
we want to sell to a consumer but if you
just listen to the consumer you tend to
do a little better that doesn't mean you
put all your eggs in one basket and
headsets reports for the last quarter
coming into the first quarter sativa
gummies are like the top-selling item
right so what do you think you're seeing
it's the Jiva gummies yeah okay so it
listen data's important but like also
use a little common sense look for the
sleeper don't just jump on the hot one
cuz the hot ones gonna be passing by the
time you know it's hot yeah it's already
gone and that's a we saw you know engine
I always pointed out huge fan of
sweetgrass kitchen shout out to Julie
and Jesse out in Colorado they're a
little bit more of a boutique compared
to wanna brands rahiba or Dixie but
they've been very even keel in their
growth very successful they came out
with micro dose they came out with these
little 2.5 milligram it was like
lozenges these little chews back in 20
before they were making you micros 15
yeah seriously like everyone was like oh
ten milligrams that's it well we'll do
as much as we can and so that was the
thing that they were going against or
like everyone's race to the top but as
much in as possible we don't want to do
that quite contrary we want to cater to
the mainstream that's coming on all the
know your market routine you know and I
mean know your niche yeah and then just
own that niche exactly true and that's
the news they came into and I even our
the Epiphany grown up
like you did I'm out there in Colorado
I'm like gosh all the people that used
to consume him and get it from black
marketer and come over to legal no those
people already had their plugs there he
had their outlet it was a mainstream
guys and gals are coming in and they
didn't want this crazy race to the top
THC of 30 35 percent renewables and it
scares them it does yeah because they're
thinking they can consume what they
consume back in the 60s and 70s you and
I the 80s and 90s and that was a
fraction I mean even just in the last
seven years they're saying that the
potency has gone up 4x so it's like you
think about that now go back 20 years 30
years what's been the multiplier so I
think the micro dose in your point those
companies are like not just industry
trends but figure out what the next
thing is the next and I think you know
for example so sativa gummies is hot but
you know flower is always gonna be at 25
to 35 percent of the market right and I
think you know people have long since
gone off of THC value and indica sativa
hybrid and they're all high just for the
record 90% are couple land racers out
there but most your turbines are still
some up here but um you know I think
we're seeing an evolution of the plant
to you know I was fortunate enough to to
speak with some doctors at UCLA who are
really not just synthesizing and
bastardizing the plant but really taking
it apart and understanding how many
components are within the plant and I
think we're gonna learn a lot this year
about how terpenes influenced us oh yeah
the combination of th TV with terpenes
and a CBD what does that do for you I
grew entourage effect that is to your
point yeah like what you're talking
about and I talked to a doctor during my
time at wheat Maps that she brought up
she's like we haven't to vulture put it
out there but terpenes a hundred percent
enhanced the hive you know when we were
smoking weed before we knew yeah and
someone say oh this is the OG or this is
the Blue Dream we would we would
organically gravitate towards the ones
that didn't make us feel like we were a
total I don't know I smoked sometimes
and I'm like I started contemplating in
my head too much I'm thinking man I'm a
horrible versus things I think if people
knew you know everybody the case and
then you smoked something like I want to
clean the house right now so it's like
we organic
we kind of gravitated towards what we
want I think as we go forward now you
know I'm a big fan of CBG and CBN I'm
CBA yeah you know CB G's like the most
the best sleeping agent you can have out
there and same with CBN I think we're
just gonna as we continue to learn it's
our job you know to continue to educate
the undereducated I mean we know that
there's X amount of people that are
coming on new as customers
that's why sativa gummies are blowing up
you know they're not blowing up on the
weed head guy the we dead guys not going
in and buying sativa gummies you know so
it's it's one of those things where you
know I think I think we've got a long
ways to go and it's gonna be an exciting
ride man because as it will allow new
things to begin to emerge we started
hearing about terpenes about a year a
little over a year ago I don't think
people fully comprehend that yet and I
think the next winners and flowers so
you're gonna look at like I would say
flowers always gonna have a horse in the
race but you're gonna you're gonna see
like Oh babes going off oh my god now
this I mean right now still if you look
at PDS or headset fifty fifty-one
percent approximately half of all
products sold in dispensaries that they
track are flower
yeah cone three rose projecting like by
two as early as 2020 maybe later on to
2022 that it's gonna be 30 35 percent
gosh I you know I heard of it's gonna be
flowered the statistics guy in my head
says you're right but then the cannabis
guy that's been living in this space
says I don't know if I can back that I
don't know I don't know I Morris I've
always been an advocate on the medical
side but I'm a dryer bait because I know
it's healthier and more reliable than
oil I mean especially the the verdicts
still out I mean the only oil is I ever
consumer from companies and in pole or
name definitely know yep that their
component and their contents are good
you know really reintroducing natural
Terps not food great Terps like PE g or
PPG fragrance or nut oil or all of its
like you just don't know and i think in
the coming years we'll see that maybe
oil isn't the most a time people I'm
hearing people are gonna straight just
smoke turps
that's what I'm hearing down the road
it's like and show us herbs right and
it's like and if you find a Terp that
really activates for you and
again that's look we don't have this
like yes we have a dozen or thousands of
different beers but they all kind of
have the same end result whereas like
we're the plant we're just getting
started to understand and then don't
even let's not even that's another show
to talk about hemp and that whole
component but it's exciting times to you
know to see people out of the closet you
know I have meetings every week with
people that when I first came out of the
closet we're like you're crazy you're
never gonna get another job you just
ruined your career and now they're now
they're asking me for advice and hitting
me up on LinkedIn you know and I just
send in my uh I just send in my vin mow
account and I just say here's what send
me five hundred bucks and we can talk
for an hour you know but we've learned
some crazy stuff by hard knocks no it's
very true when I parted ways with the
cannabis the same thing I had friends
especially in digital media and calm I'm
like well at least you can still say you
worked for digital first media and you
can segue back into this and and I'm
like I don't know I have a feeling in
man within the first 48 hours having
folks like weed maps in high times a
medicine man reach out to me I'm like
obviously this is my calling I mean look
there's no shortage of opportunities
there's a little bit of a shortage of
intelligence in some places but you know
I think you know listen that's the
reason why we're pioneers if you will
like a risk takers or entrepreneurs or
whatever you want to classify it's like
we have a vision we see it we take the
risk sometimes it has a reward most
often the nod has a reward but we go
into that knowing that there may not be
a reward and that's not just not for the
most people I mean you know when people
ask me about getting into cannabis we
had this talk to it's like well what do
you do already you know and so I think
this who you're probably bring it to is
that we need we talk we need doctors we
need logistics we need a charge we need
real trade show people not just promo
people we need real people that can make
sales that understand the sales process
and we need people that can slow it down
and do the right deals not the deal
right now and then we need some
cohesiveness amongst certain players in
the market dispensaries Long Beach I'm
gonna give a shout out to those guys
they have the LBC a that they're a very
organised group of people they don't let
the brand's push them around they don't
let the legal people push them around
they've protected themselves and they've
done that through an organization some
time's frenetic but agreed to process
right and so by do I think we have to
start to see those things too to really
continue to mature the place because
there's always gonna be people that try
to do a speedy Gonzalez around the end
and make a bunch of money real quick
but those opportunities are gonna start
to go away and you know look some people
are gonna make it and some people aren't
and some people are gonna morph I think
we don't I wish I could tell you what
was gonna happen over the next year
you know 2018 felt like since 2000 felt
like a five-year year domestic and
abroad yeah well cool man it's always
good catching up definitely good chat
dude I love talking with you it's good I
love having a the ability to shine oh
she's a celebrity like yeah you know I
think you know just to end it for me
yeah I appreciate what you do and where
you ended up and I know that no matter
where you go that we'll have a
friendship and I think that's really the
networking component of this space is
really healthy there's definitely people
I don't get along with and don't work
with but the people that I've invested
time in and that I have friendships with
they carry over into other areas and I
think that's another thing that might be
impacting 2019 is as as people change
rosters just like the NBA trade the
teams come out different you know and
you've brought a lot of you brought a
wealth of information and opportunity to
Bovada and I hope they appreciate that
thank you take care Thanks
[Music]