[Music]
so Jocelyn why don't you kick us off
pick us off okay cool um what's up
virtual world I'm Jocelyn I am the
director of strategy at headset and
headset is a cannabis data and analytics
company the past year for us in the
cannabis industry we've had a lot of
different crisis that have come up we
have the VAP crisis right happen in
summer through November and now we're in
kovat and so for us we analyze all the
point-of-sale data and adult use
dispensaries and then we report on those
trends so we have been incredibly busy
over these past few weeks in particular
to trying to provide the industry a
real-time read of what we're seeing and
so today I'm gonna go over some of the
trends that we're seeing and then I
think we can just ask some questions to
you all based off those trends because
you really are on the frontlines and so
I think you can provide a lot of
perspective here so um maybe a good way
to start I'm gonna share my screen and
just go through some actual very
exciting charts but so you can see what
is really happening I run our California
strategy and operations and what that
means for me is that I work across the
supply chain I spend my days primarily
working with retailers brands
distributors manufacturers investors and
as recently well really the past year a
lot of associations and our local and
state policy makers the data that I'm
going to be going through right now is
all collected via our participating
retailers point-of-sale systems so what
we do is we aggregate all of this data
we've got almost a thousand retailers
across all of the markets that headset
is reporting on which in this case I'm
just gonna talk about what we're seeing
here in California though we do I'm
covering in some data from other states
I think there's a lot we can learn from
Washington Colorado Nevada so I'm going
to give some insights into what's
happening there but what we do is we
aggregate all of the SKU level data and
then we normalize it so we get rid of
any privacy related information we use
there's various methodologies
to be able to extrapolate the data out
so that it's reflective of the entire
state of California and then we compare
all this data to our text numbers we
compare it to the state make and then we
make sure it's got a good go ahead and
then we're able to report on it so just
just that kind of a baseline here of
what we saw in California or across all
these markets in adult use sales in the
last year um you can see here California
is a really big market it is the biggest
market in the world in terms of cannabis
sales and in fact it you know is making
up almost as more sales than all of
these these markets combined so this
just gives us the gravity of how big the
California market is so as I had
mentioned that there is a lot going on
in cannabis in general but what we've
seen in our first couple years in the
cannabis industry is that life is
actually pretty predictable for cannabis
sales cannabis is much like other
consumer packaged goods industries
I'm sorry other retail stores other
beverage stores they all have very
predictable trends which makes it a lot
easier for a product producer or
retailer to be able to predict demand
accordingly so generally what we've seen
in cannabis is that there's spikes
during some particular months we see
spikes during the holiday season so
November December we see them again
during summer months of course for 27:10
dab day now but what we see here is
we're looking at in 2020 we can see that
on the weekends Fridays in particular
are the biggest day for cannabis sales
so we see this very very predictable
trends but then coded happened and then
what we see here is that things start to
go all over the place
there really aren't any predictable
trends at this point this actually I
really can't stress this enough and our
data team can't stress this enough this
is unlike anything we've ever seen in
terms of like consumer purchasing
everything that we knew is really being
like flipped on its head at this point
so when we see here in mid-march when we
see all of these spikes starts go all
over the place this really is looking at
these four different states and we're
seeing that as soon as the
shelter-in-place order was announced
we saw people basically go out rush make
all their purchases and then a few days
later we started to see sales utha now
and actually now we see in some states
that they're starting to decline a bit I
don't know yet you know are people
consuming more are they just stocking up
out of fear they don't want to make less
trips that's what I'm hoping all of you
all can provide some insight into you
today um but let's look a little bit
closer at the month of March and been
marched in particular because this is
really when everything started to be
translated started to
here black suspect sales line so this is
what we would have expected this time of
year
if koban hadn't happened and so what we
can see is that anything above this line
means that sales are more than we
expected anything below means that sales
are under standard performing so I want
to call out the Green Line which is
Nevada so when we think about nevada
nevada is how the hardest-hit in terms
of estate winter sales on Clark County
which is where Las Vegas is based makes
up 80% of all cannabis sales so we can
see that they've been hit the hardest
tourism is extremely important to the
state of Nevada so we can see there
there's also declined
we saw mid March as shelter-in-place
orders went to effect in California
Colorado and Washington we saw those
cells all spiked and exceed what we
normally would have expected this time
of year and then we see they start to go
back to normal levels just a few days
later so I think I would like to just
pause and take a moment here and um get
everyone else's thoughts like did you
guys see some types of similar trends
and the spikes and are things now
evening out for you or are there any
outliers in your businesses where it's
just still continuing to grow I have a
quick comment about this anecdotally
about when California especially Los
Angeles was put in to stay at home my
retailers the ones that I was going busy
and told me that odd that there were
like lines around the block people
weren't sure what was going to happen
and so the sales were extraordinary but
the shops weren't closed you know they
weren't sure if they were gonna be that
the city or state wasn't sure if they
were going to keep them open and so
after that the it wasn't a panic mode
anymore but then a couple of about a
week and a half ago again this is all
anecdotally
sales started to draw now I'm referring
to Los Angeles not the Bay Area and the
shops I have been visiting or mostly
kind of in the San Fernando Valley but
several have also had to lay people off
because of the drop in sales
I think they've rebounded a little bit
but the question is what's going on and
and why is there this difference in in
in business sort of up and down and I'm
wondering whether it actually has to do
with cash in hand I can I can speak to
the Bay Area trend if you want me to
yeah could you also provide because I
think I've seen you at some of the
Berkeley City Council meetings or so
that was also one of the interesting
things to me is just you know Berkeley
to that reversal for that what 8-hour
period and then I I think it's of such a
beautiful testament also to our industry
and all the activists that are out there
and really voiced themselves and came
forward and helped get this reversed
so could you also as you're talking
about what you saw could you also talk
about that process and how how the
community was able to like come together
and get this reversal to happen because
I know Santa Clara is still facing the
same thing right and some of these other
mmunity a letís are potentially looking
at it yeah it was a it was really touch
and go
so Alameda County in San Francisco were
the first two jurisdictions to put a
shelter-in-place order in in the entire
country and so that happened on March
13th
I'm sorry March 16th March 13th my
birthday so having a March 16th and you
know nobody at 4:00 experienced this
before ever in any capacity and so we
were kind of first thing was you know
reading the shelter-in-place order okay
what
business what isn't it's cannabis
considered an essential business
they have a provision about medical
providers and service providers and
different categories and sub-categories
of that and it says that this is to be
interpreted extremely broadly so there
was a you know I think the first city to
go everybody determined that okay well
we're it's definitely medicinal
medicinal but at the same time so many
patients haven't renewed their
recommendations they're still shopping
medicinally they're just not technically
in the medicinal you know qualified
cannabis patient so more referring to
like someone buying nyquil over the
counter as opposed to a prescription I
think San Francisco was the first city
to say that they were not cannabis
dispensaries did have to shut down they
were not considered an essential
business and that was when and it was
like they had to shut down the next day
and so that created this scourge of
people coming out and wanting to stop up
because people assume that you know that
was going to be an order and everyone
needed to get their their cannabis right
now you know San Francisco Bay Area as a
long long storied history of activism
and and pushing reform for decades and
so this was you know everybody saw as a
huge injustice and a sort of cruel and
irrational move for the city and the
County of San Francisco to pursue and
also they so there was a big outcry by
patients and by industry members that
finally got it back to the city
I guess the Health Director and all of
these sort of determinations are coming
from the Health Department basically in
these emergency orders and shelter in
place orders at least in Berkeley I
don't know specifically for San
Francisco but I'm pretty sure they're
similar
the
city manager and the health department
are basically in control right now
and they get to determine all of these
things there's a sort of de facto
government of these municipalities and
so finally they got the that order
reversed in San Francisco I think that
was eight hours or a day something like
that it was really quick and that was
great and so nobody else so Alameda
County did not determine nobody
clarified if cannabis was essential or
not and if it needed to be closed or not
and so there were a lot of passive yeses
from representatives in the county and
on the city level but there was nothing
in writing anywhere and that was very
concerning but you know it we we if ever
there was a time people needed cannabis
it's now you know it would just be so
wrong to take away this form of relief
and this healthier alternative and such
a you know anxiety carry time I that we
felt that it was necessary to you know
make sure that we were being compliant
that everything was going to be and then
that I guess the state came down with
their and the state determined that
cannabis wasn't essential business and
that was the first time it was actually
stated in writing that cannabis was
essential and the City of Berkeley on
the 25th sent the four five retailers
that are open to only go to delivery
only and none of the retailers in
Berkeley were set up for delivery we all
are the storefront so basically it was
they were gonna shut down the cannabis
accessibility in City of Berkeley which
was crazy and totally unacceptable
there's a we've had a history with the
health department in the city there's
there's been a lot of back and forth and
it had only been a month since we'd come
out of there another fight of trying to
have consumption lounges
then make sure that they didn't banned
flavoured bait products and and that
whole thing that seems like a year ago
now but I had only been a month before
this came out and this happened and they
they told us all to essentially shut
down so BBG was was able to sort of
Europe get like one or two cars going
but it was completely unsustainable in
all of the dispensaries we kind of a
knit together a lot of bay area and cold
cannabis activists we all got on calls
and and sort of you know very well
trained to to activate and react very
quickly to any sort of policy impacts
that affect us and in the industry and
our patients and their customers so we
just sort of reorganized and reactivated
what we had done a month ago and had
everybody calling the city manager and
and call City Council members and really
demand an answer to why cannabis which
was declared as essential and at that
point Alameda County San Francisco and
the state of California had all
expressly stated that cannabis was an
essential business for medicinal and
adult use and so why we were subjected
to the stricter regulation as an
essential business that's following the
exact same you know mitigation and
social distancing protocols as every
other essential business why are we why
do we have to have this excessive more
extreme restrictions on on who and how
we can serve our community an important
point of like and actually I think it
would be really important for you to
talk about your role and Berkeley
patients group for people who aren't
aware because vpg is one of the oldest
if I understand it are the first in in
Bay Area and as I go to a lot of these
City Council meetings you tend to see
the same activists that show up in each
community or each municipality has its
own culture that they're working within
and so one of the things I find really
interesting is one that your role exists
within BPG because there's so many
retailers that don't necessarily have a
policy or an Affairs person
it's really out and working with City
Council and so I think would be to the
benefit of the whole industry if more
people were involved and I think this is
one of the reasons that we often see
policy not being lenient towards
cannabis so could you also explain like
your role and why that's so important to
a retailer in making sure that you have
this this warmness from the city oh yeah
absolutely yeah so I'm the chief public
affairs officers at Berkeley patient
group and BPG is the oldest continuously
operating the center in the country it
was formed out of a group of cannabis
activists in the 90s
well cannabis HIV AIDS activists who
were fighting to get relief for hiv/aids
patients and wanted to make sure there
was safe access to cannabis because
there weren't any there wasn't any
research or any other medication for
relief for those patients and so CPG was
born out of the spirit of activism and
community engagement and community
organizing and so that's always been the
ethos of the dispensary and we have had
you know worked with the City of
Berkeley over 20 years to and you know
help develop regulations and protocol
and and be expressed become expressly
allowed to operate and having these
relationships with the city and the
community are invaluable I mean it's for
any business but especially for a highly
regulated controversial business like
cannabis and even more especially for a
new industry that is evolving and and
developing every day and with all these
new challenges that everyone else is
facing on top of all our unique cannabis
challenges so you know there's it's so
important you you have to stay on top of
regulatory changes such as things like
this because I'm constantly engaged in
the city with the Health Department with
council members you know I I do have
relationships with them and I can
communicate with them and we you know we
don't always agree on everything but I
think we all have this
intent wishes what's best for the
community and what's best for the city
and we have different ideas sometimes of
as to what that is but we all want
what's best and a really good example
vacuum you as to why it is so critical
to have these relationships with your
with your community and with your local
government is you know BBG had a couple
of federal cases
well coo during Melinda Hague is a US
attorney in Northern California and came
after Berkeley patient group a couple of
years ago tried to shut them down and
the City of Berkeley and the community
actually organized and joined the case
on in with BPG against the federal
government
to stop the federal government from
shutting down the city and that was
because Berkeley patients group is you
know I sort of call it a Berkeley
institution it is it's part of the
community we have you know all these
relationships with nonprofits and and
all these support efforts that we do and
fundraising drives and food drives and
toy drives and you know just become a
valuable asset and not just in you know
obviously serving consumers and patients
is a critical part of it but you know as
in every any business corporate social
responsibility and those relationships
can really ensure to the best of its
ability that that you are going to be
secure and sustainable in the place that
you operate and that's really important
I think for public facing cannabis
operators probably definitely more so
than other parts of supply chain because
we're so public and you know whenever
anything goes wrong all of those church
your rules on at least and Berkeley or
retailers in there are for anybody else
and so having we also have that sort of
broader community of activists
that have all been doing this for a
really long time and so we all help each
other out and we knew like it perfectly
was going to do this and and Berkeley
goes this way you know a lot of other
people are going to use as an excuse to
loop their city or their counting in
that direction too and so we sort of
banded together with people that no
don't necessarily have a stake in the
city of berkeley but see that if
something happens in berkeley it could
happen it could start a domino effect
that would be really bad because Alameda
County and San Francisco and Berkeley
declaring these as essential most likely
set the path for all of these other
states that later issued children place
orders to declare cannabis as essential
yeah absolutely
so thank you for that and always
appreciative of all the hard work you
guys are doing I see your team at so
vocal in the industry so that's that's
really really nice um the next thing
that I thought was really interesting
that I wanted to look at was like any
changes and consumer preference so I
know from a data standpoint and looking
at all the adult you cells we've seen
this shift away from free rolls we've
seen negative declines in three rolls
um and then we've seen this extreme
growth or when I say extreme 28% growth
over a 30-day period in edibles and also
beverages have seen growth and so Frank
I'm curious and to interrupt your your
trimmin sesh over there
joins well what are you guys seeing in
terms of like are you seeing any shift
in demand has supply chains but
effective for you all at you know and
any degree and also um like can you talk
first about one what you do and who you
are and then your consumers and give us
like a lay of your land sweet yeah thank
you so much cool and we have the boss
and owner of my boss and the owner of
hella dank CEO Igor a binder is also
in-house here so I'm Frank LaRosa
thank you very much for uh beefing in
the questions and thank you guys for
having me here or thank ladies for and
guys everybody for having us here it's a
pleasure to be among
people in the industry and all that I do
like to refer to it as an agricultural
marketplace it's maybe better this thing
that we're all participating in thank
you so much
you were answer your question more than
I can I mean we we do abuse an amount of
sales in pre-roll specifically we have a
hash yeah give us a breakdown of your
business first who are you guys what do
you do just so everyone knows we're a
hella Bank we we met we're a hash
company and we specifically make hash
from all living slow farms so we're like
we're like a small smaller hash company
I'd say we're specifically focused on
small farms craft farms and and people
who have like sustainability in mind and
army our main products are hash rosin
and hash and fuels and honestly it's
it's an interesting question for us
because hash refuse approvals are
probably our biggest seller out of out
of the out of all the different
categories but yeah we've we've we've
definitely seen some changes throughout
this coated situation we haven't seen a
full-on decline in pre-rolls
like just for us but also we're not like
we're not like a huge part of the
pre-roll market yet and we're also a
specialized part of the pro market where
we only do infused so we're not I don't
know that that might separate us to some
degree as well we noticed like when the
when the when it first hit first day at
home order we saw a spike in sales so it
was like like that week it was like a
bunch more sales I was like have every
week was changing though we had like we
have trip week followed by a really slow
week followed by a pretty normal week
and then as of recently it has been it
has been a little slower it's I mean
quite a bit slower on it's been like
like I feel like
last week was like sixty percent decline
in sales is it people aren't like
sharing you know passing it around and
they're not sharing and therefore you
know can that be attributing to less
sales or do you have any thoughts on why
I mean I feel like that could definitely
could be part of it people maybe don't
want to smoke a whole deal to their face
that make sense present company excluded
by you all and we actually have to smoke
all the boobs to make sure they're good
every single before it goes out but hey
I feel like yeah some people could be
cautious but then there's I feel like
there's also people at least from our
perspective could do the weeks when
we've had spikes in sales or it's been
higher than than we would have expected
with the co bid being not a factor I
feel like it's it's kind of you know
there's some there's still some users
that are buying more even if he rolls I
mean there's always going to our users
like us who will smoke you know we're
willing to smoke a whole hash tube but I
mean we're also we're also kind of
behind the scenes I see the numbers
normally we're out in the field doing
demos and stuff like that we're not
doing anything like that right now so
we're like less less so exposed to the
consumer end but I mean I could
definitely be a factor I feel like that
cleanliness and stuff just like people
not wanting to share with anybody else
we need to be focused towards more
single-use products or products that you
can easily divvy up into single servings
for a single person Shannon what about
from you can you can you tell us about
space gems and wet Wendy Wendy Wendy
Oh Wendy sorry hi I'm Wendy and the
cares
um can you guys hear me okay okay
awesome car um
guy this coded thing I mean experience
it since January actually because I
packaging coming in from China and so on
like January 20th so I think going
through with it ever since then feels
like it hasn't stopped but after we got
our packaging in February 18th actually
is when our packaging got delivered a
month later all of a sudden our sales
were huge but that's just because we
just came back on market again and then
like right at March 16th our sales were
like we put the biggest batches we've
ever put through testing and like they
were gone in four days like we could not
even believe it like I could not get
touch-up you know our struggles are
organic sugar are like our ingredients
so that's not awesome either to assigned
with all this going on and you know our
the truck right before so a truck for
4/20 lesson Tuesday the truck before
that was like a really big truck also
for the truck before that so three
trucks our sales were not that great
they were pretty low and the truck was
not all the way full either but now all
of a sudden the truck is full and I feel
like the stimulus check cuz like these
stands up and unemployment people have
gotten money from unemployment cuz a lot
of people you know a lot of our
customers are service based so like
restaurants and stuff I feel like our
sales are doing really well edibles I
feel like we can't keep in stock still
so that's great I guess I didn't really
say what kind of company I have yeah
tell us yeah absolutely
of course everyone guess we need to know
[Music]
Tony and we do have began Organic gummy
neigh with ice water hatch and no
distillate or anything like that
so we're completely different from
almost all edibles on the market and
they're handmade vegan I'd like a little
tin pretty special and you open it
little treasure so we have 2 2 th C's
and 1 1 1 1 1 2 1 and th these are just
flying the CBDs are doing really well
too but the th these are just flying off
the shelf and then we have like a little
a drink that you can make drinks with
with also and it's doing really well too
and Wendy what's the connection I think
we met at the new CBA Club and so are
y'all connect trees this Waller what's
the connection with Craig he's like my
business partner I guess that's the best
later they're talking trees and all over
ice water and everything is from talking
trees so he was in the background before
then he tried to make its own coming in
his office by yeah I'm a Satori right
now the dispensary and this parking lot
is just non-stop like people are just
coming non-stop like it's like totally
full moons I've seen huge re are you on
and I are you on a mobile device right
now no I'm not amazing
no no no I was gonna ask if you could
show us if you could walk out and show
us the shop yeah see now we can see and
urine McKinley Ville is that were the
shop is yes we're making evil
our shop is in Eureka a space gem and
worried about your dispensary and
there's so many people there they're
pulling into our parking lot oh yeah I'm
seeing a huge spike in sales thank you
for that tour Shannon can you tell us
about Fiddler's greens and what you're
seeing tell you what you do all about
your company give us the breakdown yeah
absolutely can you guys hear me no
excellent um yeah my husband and I are
co-founders at after Delors greens and
high tide distribution we transition
from prop 215 and we were one of the
early adopters early prop 64 compliant
companies we do some grown cultivation
and we make pictures and topicals I'm
super excited about the group of people
on here because I think we do a little
bit of business with everybody here and
I'm a big fan of Wendy's I was actually
going to be able to talk a little bit
about her products and we launched our
distribution company about a year and a
half ago just because we were having a
hard time finding a distributor that
could represent small craft heritage
brands so we launched to support the
Fiddler's range products and have
recently been onboarding other small
brands that have the same sort of ethos
we do in terms of sun-grown
you know environmentally conscious yeah
that's a little bit about us in terms of
what we've been seeing that mid March
time frame we started seeing the big
spike I think everybody was seeing with
the uncertainty about whether or not we
were going to get shut down how much we
were going to be shut down as we had
some pretty big orders going out also
people were preparing for haul of
flowers and Coachella
and a lot of those types of things we've
seen it level off a little bit the last
couple of weeks but things are starting
to pick up again so it's it's been
really interesting it was fun to see
those charts just because I think it's
pretty consistent across the industry in
terms of what we're all experiencing and
nobody's really sure you know are we
staying home and smoking more are we
staying at home and stocking up and now
we're gonna see a drop-off so yeah it's
kind of hard to plan we just we've been
ramping up production and trying to be
prepared
most of the Fiddler's greens consumers
are medical patients we've got a lot of
kids you know with epilepsy and stuff
like that and so we're trying to make
sure that we've got product on hand
we're keeping our retailer or stocked
for those folks can you talk about what
your husband's currently doing that's
not typical yeah absolutely we just
we've been working with partners to do
last mile fulfillment and there been
some changes on their side and we've
been looking to bring that on anyway and
had hired a couple of folks that we
wanted to do that but with the Cova and
some of the safety concerns we have just
we felt better about having Cameron in
the van doing the driving and the
deliveries he was in the marine corps
he's been through hazardous material
training and so he's he's very
experienced in the suiting up and all of
the precautions and so we've got him
running the van he was up at McKinley
bail last week he's in Palm Springs
today was in LA yesterday so we're
keeping him from plenty busy right now
so um the last thing I guess before like
we close out could we each like go down
and talk about and I know this is hard
because like we're also in crow but
right now
but what are your thoughts on like what
does the cannabis industry look like
after kovat for your business in
particular and I can kind of start out
with something that I've been thinking
about I'm really curious to see the
shifts in delivery because I think this
is going to be a whole new e-commerce
world for us I think people are now
moving into this mindset just like we do
with Amazon and uber and etc we're used
to this on-demand and so I'm really
curious to see kind of how things shift
into delivery so that's when the
business side and then for me personally
I'm really interested after this post
open world I think one of the things
that I'm learning is that I'm seeing a
lot more of our community kind of coming
together out of necessity because we had
to to like fight some of these city
policies and to make sure that there
wasn't this reversal of cannabis being
essential language so I think that we're
gonna continue to see more collaboration
among different like sides of our
industry and then taking on some of
these bigger challenges that we have
like taxes you know within cannabis
opening up banking etc so I think for me
it's really from the business side
looking at ecommerce and kind of how
things are gonna shift there and from a
personal side I just think it's gonna be
more collaboration amongst the industry
Sabrina maybe if we could start with you
and then go to go to Tom and work our
way down sure it's definitely hard to
speak with anyhow second legs it's gonna
look like post COBIT I'm trying to start
to visualize what the slow return to the
new normal is going to be I you know my
first thoughts are sort of the what's
gonna happen in terms of like in-store
safety sanitation and social distancing
protocols that has been stepped up in
under these new orders you know I think
there's going to be some practices that
will you know probably remain for
a while it's not permanently and I can't
I don't know you know all of this is
obviously based on on science and our
health experts and our doctors and what
they tell us and because it sounds like
this is going to unroll in multiple
phases I'm kind of I can only see like
one or two days is forward I think from
what I know now but yeah I think the
those sort of protocols the protocols of
like distributor to retail you know
vendor relations and drop-off as well as
you know face masks and and temp checks
and things like that that I don't know
if that's going to flap forever I don't
know how post we're talking but it's far
into the future as I can see which at
this point it's probably three to six
months I have no idea what's going to
happen after that but I also think that
it's exposed a significant weakness and
and challenge and limitation from our
federal status as an illegal industry
and right now we're having all of these
challenges of not being able to access
federal release packages that are being
given to all of their businesses and
especially for essential businesses and
these PPP program which is the payment
protection program and they and it leave
and all of these requirements that are
have been put in place to support these
mitigation and social distancing
protocols that you know can the cannabis
industry which is required to follow
these rules may not get the commensurate
financial relief that is attached to it
or purportedly attached to it for all
businesses so this is exposing a lot of
contradictions on the federal level and
I think we're hopefully going to see a
lot stronger broader momentum on a
federal level
Tom we didn't even really get say we
didn't get anything from from your
background and all that stuff could show
our patient yeah I'm the patient
consumer on the panel today I've been in
the industry since about 2015 I'm the
founding editor of Mg magazine which is
a b2b publication covers the cannabis
industry I'm not affiliated with them
anymore but I've spent these years
writing you know new mobile number of
articles and interviewing people from
you know CEOs of publicly traded
companies to politicians Fiona MA and
others to craft growers and and everyone
in between and I couldn't agree with
Sabrina more I think that COBIT has
exposed the challenges strengthened and
weaknesses and and certainly the
challenges with with the federal with
the federal government but it's it's
also an opportunity and it and also it
kind of puts things into perspective you
know and I think hopefully for many
people that some of the battles that
they are things that they were imposing
will you know not seem so dire
perhaps anymore in Los Angeles they're
opening up you know not just delivery
but curbside something people didn't
want to do any more or beforehand and
you know things like being forced to use
cash all the time which is not as a safe
a procedure as as other forms of
transactions
I think there's that's a very much
stronger argument now that people would
have a real hard time challenging and I
know that retailers down here are
interested and are having those
conversations with local
politicians and hopefully the state
level and and so on you know I'm hoping
that that again after this that that
that will we'll see a sort of a kind ler
gentler retail experience I'm concerned
about a costs I have questions about how
how manufacturers are handling their the
changes to their SOPs which are so
important in this industry and so
important in terms of efficiencies and
and being competitive and they have to
change I would assume that that the
safety of workers would mandate that I
don't know the answers to all of that
but those are the questions that are
first and foremost and then also
cultural ones I come out of the
traditional or traditional culture going
way back and I don't want to lose it and
I I think it's a strong culture and
community but those are the challenges
that we face and even if you know we see
new normals you know we don't want to
see that the the destruction you know is
already under threat so these are the
things that I think about I'm an
optimist but these are the challenges
that we face yeah actually yeah you know
I keep going with this and then I I have
a different question after but we're
going we're going down the line so we're
halfway there
okay cool Wendy yeah I I feel like I
just learned a lot that we might go to
eat Congress I have to say that I think
I was a little shocked at that I think
that we're learning how to deal with
this every day you know I know that the
manufacturing and for us personally like
we have everyone's six feet away and
it's hard but we're doing it and we I
was like shifts the people can't have
everyone at
I can't have team meetings anymore got
to have broken up team meetings and I
really is I really and I feel like it's
it's great because I had been in the
seam since 2013 and have been pushing
space gems since 2013 so have people who
love our product but you know you know
with curbside I see a lot because people
aren't seeing the product anymore
they're not seeing the display case
they're just looking off an iPad and you
really have to push social media or
anything that you can push Reda stood
care packages of a coloring book to
everyone with like thicker sheets and
stuff just to tell people that we love
them and we put a crystal in them and we
mailed off like over 300 of them and
just to people I think that that's I
think we're gonna have to start doing
more of that because we can't do
education we can't do demos and that's
what we really focus on especially with
the ice water hash and a gummy market
where there's a lot of other people in
there but I really hope that every day
where we're presented with challenges of
like this summer it's going to be hard
to wear a mask when cooking over a hot
stove and hot boiling pot like that is
we all wear masks but that is something
that is going to be hard and we all are
talking about how we're going to go
around that because summer does get hot
and I don't see this ending soon
unfortunately which I like to think all
rainbows and unicorns but they don't at
this very moment so we are gonna have to
strategize on how to figure out how to
stay on the Shelf how to make people
still buy our product to make people so
you know know us by brand name because
they're not seeing us and it's on an
iPad or yeah or on the Internet so I
hope that did that answer your question
yeah no I think it's such a good point
because um you know we do have so many
brands here in
I think in Flour particular there's I
don't know the latest number but three
to four hundred unique brands in
California legal unique brands sold in
shops so this is gonna shift all of
their businesses into thinking yes how
do we take this digitally in a product
that really does require that that in
person to really get the sense that
product which makes it very hard because
at a federal level we don't have
advertising at scale Facebook Google you
know Instagram all the all these
publishers as cannabis businesses we
can't go advertise them on that scale so
you have to get really creative with how
you're gonna get customer acquisition
and drive them into your digital
property to purchase that product so I
think everyone's really gonna have to
adapt here quickly and learn from each
other and this is perhaps another
session that someone I think CMA
actually the cannabis Marketing
Association is doing some stuff like
this that's probably a resource for you
to check out in terms of like what is
allowed in terms of different digital
advertising to be able to to help your
business with that thank you and I ask a
follow-up question about that because
it's so interesting and we've been
talking about that do do the people here
think now is a good or a bad time to
launch a new product yes it's a
challenging time but we also have sort
of everyone's attention because you know
they're all inside so I'm interested in
people's opinion about that me
personally I would think going to be a
little challenging because you can't do
you can't see buyers so it has to be
like this they want to be able to see
the product you know it would just yeah
I feel like that name is really
important and so that's what people
usually buy on is the name and they
would have a cinnamon smell our anymore
your we have demos all the time in the
dispensary and that yeah that sort of
person-to-person contact where they can
see the product and then sell the
product and then talk to somebody taking
that part away
and you know it's gonna be challenging
to figure out how to replace that to
bring on new brand it didn't Ken Besant
just launched a new net not even like a
value brand yeah yeah a value brand and
they got skewered for it but uh yeah
this is another I think that we might
have to that brands might have to adapt
to and like a you know if we go into
recession
especially the premium brands thinking
about how are you gonna because some of
them were seeing them drive value brands
and so we still don't know yet our
consumers willing to purchase these more
premium brands or are they gonna be much
more cost kind of conscious headset just
did an analysis on this actually
yesterday and it's it's on their blog
people are still buying premium eights
there hasn't been any change there so
that has been good for for I think the
industry though definitely a shift into
larger package size for purchases so
definitely a lot of growth does a
headset or anyone else have any insights
into demographics I heard from a
retailer last week that his younger
customers had fallen off I guess
and but his older ones were continuing
to sustain the business yeah actually we
do have a lot of information on customer
demographics um I I have to jump to
another meeting but I will say this
because you can find the answer to this
question
headset on the website there's this blue
teal bar and this our team updates every
single day in the markets they're the
states that we're reporting on all the
real-time updates that we're finding is
it pertains to kovat so there's some
interesting trends in there for customer
demographics women actually had much
larger purchases than men probably
because they didn't have item stocked up
on hand generally but we're answering as
many of those questions as we can and if
they're actually Peter if there's any
questions that you're getting if people
hit you up after this
our team is is able to kind of look at
all of this data and kind of report on
so we just need more insight from the
community in terms of what do you need
to know from this data and your
businesses that would be helpful and we
would be happy to do that investigation
and report on that well okay all right
so we'll let Jocelyn go I'm not done
with the rest of you though so so hang
tight everyone this is so fun
hi Jocelyn so say yeah the one thing I
want and and you guys have done it in
pieces but kind of just going down the
line like give me is just the the
stories thank you for everything I think
that was Frank and uh Igor but uh like
Sabrina may be starting with you I mean
you know you talked about fighting at
the local level but like Co bid hits and
what's going like it's almost like the
siren sounds in the battleship and like
everybody goes to their post and kind of
what were you guys talking about
internally you're probably on the front
lines of SOPs and understanding what the
government you know and then just for
everybody kind of like Frank I talked to
you about it before sorry I move these
down but um like what's changed like
Frank you you guys always you have a
history of you know I see Instagram
posts you guys going to visit all the
farms that you deal with and still like
you're obviously probably not doing that
and in taking trim and flower and
showing up the manufacturing facility
with you know or do you guys have to
stagger shifts and then totally not the
distributors and things like that so
just Sabrina Spellman Soph
well so so let's start with Sabrina but
just kind of going down the line
okay well let's see it it's been quite a
whirlwind you know is
it's been a lot of pivoting and adapting
and and shifting and interpreting you
know going from shelter-in-place are we
essential to you know where in what
capacity can we operate and we want to
be equal to every other essential
business and then fighting that fight
and then you know there are certain
protocols for essential businesses that
are public facing and there was an
initial set of protocols so the store
had to adapt to those and then there
were also you know we had certain
employees that had to had children that
were no longer in school and did not
have childcare so there was that whole
situation and and then the city and the
county put out new additional protocol
sister protocols for publication
businesses so again the entire
operations team had to pivot again and
they add they put them out at you know
7:00 o'clock at night one night and it
was effective you know midnight I like
the next day and so you know it's just
been it almost reminded me of the home
sorry my son am I still there okay the
you know the first few months of 2018
honestly and just everyone trying to
figure out what would go going on what
we can do what we can't do how are we
interpreting these rules properly you
know there's what the state says there's
a city says you know just kind of
pivoting and then it's all there was
also you know making sure that everybody
has the proper PPE and you know how
making sure that we can source that
which has become increasingly
challenging and and now it's just sort
of like kind of on
we're on edge because it's in terms of
like SOPs I mean also well I would
include like scaling up delivery like I
mentioned earlier where basically none
of the dispensaries in the city were
prepared to go to delivery only
operations and we were we had one or two
cars I'd literally just started delivery
like a day or two earlier we kind of
assumed something like this was going to
happen we had already done the curbside
oh and then there was also the BCC
getting approval from the Bureau of
cannabis control to implement these new
protocols and invoking their emergency
section in their regulations to allow us
to curbside to put in Plexiglas to do
all of these mitigation and efficiency
requirements that were all made to
follow and so it's yeah it's just been a
constant scaling and shuffling and
adopting and readapting to you know this
new environment and you know hourly
right like I said it was very
reminiscent of 2018 and the beginning of
2018 but I feel like this was this was
more challenging and a smaller more
compact period of time coupled with like
a global pandemic and a sheltering in
place and and every other aspect of our
life being disrupted as opposed to 2018
where it was just our our businesses and
and how those operate was very
disruptive and very stressful but this
is some next-level stressful so that's
that's sort of where to see my
experience and our experience has been
you know obviously experiencing the same
trends that have been mentioned before I
think that the curb size definitely more
active than the delivery there's a big
debate
whether or not delivery that but if yeah
it's yeah I'm kind of on guard I'm just
waiting for the another shoe to drop in
another another rule from some level of
government oh and then there's a federal
you know relief spills and tears and all
of those things that have these like I
have mentioned the labor requirement for
employees and businesses and and links
so also understanding how we fit into
that and where where we can tap into
relief and and lobbying the state to see
if we can access relief there that we
can't get from the federal government so
it's always something with some level of
government and and figuring out where we
fit in what how to comply what's the
right interpretation is and path forward
right right we will pretend and Frank
and Igor as we get on the line they can
join twins what can you talk about kind
of things that have changed in the past
month or so in terms of dealing like
looking backwards down the supply chain
and forwards up the supply chain and how
you kind of interact and deal with each
part of it yeah I mean you mentioned you
know visiting farms yes we're not we're
not when I visit any farms right now for
safety reasons but also it's just like
not the right time of the season I spent
three months like borderline living in
home all like three to five days where
we're uh we're still in our startup
phase and we're we're a really small
team of just like five people at the
office we all live together as roommates
in a day it's in addition to working
together so we're not really like
exposing ourselves to people out there
our comes into our office the main
things I've noticed have changed as yeah
we're not doing any demos
I've personally have been out there
doing a lot of our own demos we have a
brand ambassador as well but obviously
cut all that off so we're trying to
focus more on digital media and we are
we have been starting to you know kind
of target more delivery services and
stuff like that when it comes to sales
but things have been semi normal for us
I'd say just because we're way more
engrossed in the manufacturing process
and then the sales but we do we do sales
as well as far as manufacturing we're
kind of like you know we're we're all
staying healthy we're all trying to stay
clean Li and things like that but we're
also just we're we're able to stay safe
because we're not constantly exposed to
like the customers or anything like that
when we we've been minimizing the amount
of material going in or out
unless it's something that needs to
happen and we've been practicing social
distancing and stuff like that so just
normal stuff that people you know
working in any in any business right now
are experiencing I will say though
there's I feel like there's a shift in
mentality for people since people are
you know more anxious more afraid and
stuff like that so it's something that
we're kind of anticipating as we proceed
in cannabis which is which is really
kind of a bummer I feel like I'm like
I've been making hash for 12 years in a
cannabis nerd for significant longer
than that but cannabis is kind of a
thing that kind of brings people
together I feel like it's like really
been like a communal thing people are
used to smoking with each other and
getting close I feel like it brings
people together you know in America I
feel like there's been a bit of like
even before this like oh good thing I
feel like there's definitely some
programming out there where everybody
kind of wants to distance just weren't
quite you know we're not quite to level
of like Italy or where people are
kissing each other three times before
they depart but then also you know
things like this this go big hit Italy
especially hard maybe partially due to
that but I think that cannabis has been
like kind of that for
in America that's brought people
together so it's um I really I really
hope that that we can overcome this in a
way where we're not going to come out of
it being like I don't want to touch
anybody I want to keep my distance from
everybody I'm not gonna smoke with
anybody ever again and then as far as
like as far as the the currency is
concerned I'm actually pretty concerned
if we go to fully e-commerce you know
yeah I agree
money is a little bit a little bit
dirtier thing but are we gonna really
give up all our freedoms all like total
to a level where all all money is
tracked forever forever a a super big
big brother level if we're to go to
fully Commerce so personally I feel like
yeah I just I feel like we should we
should definitely try to hold on to some
humanity through all this I feel like
you know before we're like yes you know
money is too dirty let's let's get on
the bandwagon let's get rid of it
I mean in general what its gonna do as
far as just to the level of doing that
we're gonna have on our financial system
if we go to full full e-commerce I'm
more of a you know power to the people
type person so I'm not really gonna I
personally don't support that I prefer
to agenda I feel like that's the that's
the thing that that they wanted
beforehand before before kovat hit
there's regular currencies for kovat hit
they've been trying to get us you know
not connect catalyst yeah
not connect with each other on a
personal level and this is just reason
that another reason that about there now
that people have and it's it's them than
fear so I feel like everybody be safe
everybody you know be cleanliness we get
over this thing don't as a message that
out to the people I'd say don't don't
let it rule your life for the rest of
for the rest of your life you know we
had the Spanish flu a hundred years ago
and before COBIT hit you know people
weren't walking around masks because of
what happened in 1918
so same thing here I feel like we need
to come out of this just human still and
not as just some like fear-mongering
like wish like part of some crazy fear
machine but I'd like to really fast just
address the last question that you there
you guys were asked about the just like
where you see things after this and some
of that like what you know I I think
that like where we are at where we're
specifically doing is we're we're
working with sustainable agriculture and
regenerative farming practice isn't
stuff so to see more of those farms come
out of this more more people more
organic farms to taking the next step
and going to regenerative and
sustainable you know that's like what I
want to see out of this whole thing and
that's like the only input I actually
had in this whole discussion and stuff
because basically it's like what I think
about all day and this has been a major
catalyst for information to be spread
and it's an opportunity for people to
either you know go the opposite way and
surrender and actually depend on the
government hardcore or you know go the
opposite and be sustainable like
cannabis has taught a lot of people all
the heroes that I have in this industry
are people that came out here didn't
know what was gonna happen you know or
you know grow up here and and just
really put their all in every bit of
their effort into making a good product
and then that's what they have their
name for you know it reminds me of all
the crafts and like the goods that you
know this this United States used to be
bad asked for for doing so I feel like
we have we have an opportunity here to
seize you know the food industry will
combine with the cannabis industry when
everything goes big and whatever and I
know I'm a romantic optimist in that but
that's my little piece of Frank is not
an advanced nutrients brand ambassador
[Laughter]
Shannon yeah I'm I don't exactly
remember what the question was i I think
it's just kind of adding anything so
kind of short like you had mentioned you
know Cameron's down making deliveries
which was out of the out of the ordinary
for you guys what what kind of
some of the things that have been going
on recently related to Tobin 19 yes so
you know because we're tested to such
high standards I think for cannabis it
was a little bit easier like there was
no shortage of gloves or isopropyl
alcohol in my facility so you know those
were things that we did are ready the
things I think we're struggling a little
bit with Armour on the community side
you know we're a small close-knit group
too like everybody hugs and says I love
you at the end of the day when they're
leaving Sophia that's been a little
weird you know
Cameron was up at Trinity colony picking
up flower at soul spirit last week and
he's like you know I'm seeing an 8 10
feet away from them while we're like
counting the inventory and wearing
gloves than masks and normally we'd be
sharing joints and hugging and
high-fiving so those kinds of things
have been really challenging but in
terms of I don't know it's it's been a
really weird strange world and I think
we're gonna have to battle to to
preserve the community side of it
through this and you know I'm a bit of
an introvert but I really have been
missing hugging and sharing a joint with
my friends you know that's been really
weird for me
but we've also you know like the
teachers are great because you don't
have to if you're not looking The
Dropper late you can still medicate
edibles are great we're working with a
company called O'Meara
and so Sonoma and they're single serving
individual pre-packed whole flower vape
products and so you know I think some of
those innovative products we're going to
be seeing higher use of we've seen sales
go up on those we also work with herbal
Buena who makes a quiver which is a
personal lubricant we've seen sales on
that go ups you know it just it's it's a
shift
and we just we can't forget where we
came from we can't forget the human side
of things but we've also got to be safe
and it's weird I'm not gonna lie this is
a weird world that you know Cameron's
also been joking he's like never wasted
going in crisis and Sonoma County is a
really good example of that we were one
of the first counties to put out a
cannabis ordinance a couple of years ago
and then they pulled back and you know
really hurt a lot of operators but when
the corona staff happened Sonoma County
was the first one one of the first ones
to put out an ordinance and they listed
cannabis as an essential business as
agriculture and medicine and they
haven't back down from that so you know
we have to keep fighting we have to keep
being loud and vocal and pushing on our
regulators you know they're calling us
an essential business give us access to
banking don't make us handle dirty cash
give us access to the things that are
gonna make us be sustainable businesses
stop trying to tax us into oblivion
now's the time to push and really you
know say we're here like ya'll said were
essential stop treating us like
criminals Wendy do you want to go after
that so good I can't say it looks like
so awesome yeah like where do I see this
go either one I I think is kind of like
what what has been going on like what
was one of the last conversations you
and Craig had today yesterday last week
about just dealing with crazy shit
that's going on we just had it as I were
on this I was telling Craig like all the
stats that she provided and yeah
we I think both of us are a little bit
in denial I think that that's okay to
say and but we really see it's happening
and any we're using the mass where
everyone has the gloves all of our
places are six feet with like just
social distancing and everything but
yeah I definitely see that we have to
figure out how to keep present and keep
moving
especially both of our brands and it is
great because we are a big family I
think that there's 80 hundred ten people
that work for Craig all together so we
all there's a lot of there's a lot of us
and you know how it's cool because we
have distribution and retail
manufacturing in the farm so we get to
see all the different things and we all
all of us managers are reacting it's
great that we only personally I only
lost one person to all this team member
and everyone else was adaptable and
flexible to change their schedule and
everything like that but you know right
when this started I do have to say it
was really high intensity just like
Frank said anxiety to keep the team
going but we made it through and yeah I
just really hope organic sugar is like
my biggest struggle I can't even say
that enough like I am like fighting and
then we get organic sugar from a
different source and it's contaminated
and the lab calls me to tell me it's
contaminated you know where we buy all
of our supplies is those places are open
but they're only open at a skeleton
scale and that's what keeps pace I'm
great yeah I work with them and please
bear orders and started keeping
ingredients you
we work with oh just just my ingredient
suppliers okay you know well and what
Wendy's saying is really important for
people to understand is cannabis
products are tested at a standard that
organic food products cannot pass as an
edible maker the fact that you can see
completely organic product and it's fine
and she adds cannabis to it and the
cannabis is clean but the sugar causes
her to fail like that is absurd so these
are things we need to be fighting right
now while we've got people's attention
and they're calling us essential and
trying to get some of these laws and
regulations change so that they're not
so ridiculous
yeah okay yeah I have to say I got the
lab called this morning about the sugar
about yeah the sugar is not good on an
RD that is not good because the sugar I
would usually get would be from Costco
I'm gonna say that I don't mind saying
that organic sugar from Costco and you
know you could only buy one bag and they
will not let me buy anymore I send my
whole team in just to get so we just can
keep moving yeah good these are the
weird things going on right now we're
not a full ounce and we went to like
five shops trying to get paper towels we
tried to order paper towels from Uline
but because we had never ordered paper
towels from Uline they wouldn't send
them to us these are the weird things
that are gonna break us right now yep
totally gloves too well is this a big
thing too it's really hard to find cause
mm-hmm look at Frank showing off like
Saul
don't Lysol disinfectant hand sanitizer
yeah we're making our own but yep gotta
keep it yeah and then I also like to say
I like a whole staff member washing her
doors and making sure we're doing all
these protocols of washing all the
tables and washing the door handles and
you know making sure everyone's wearing
a mask and no yeah a whole Kovac person
non-stop just to make sure for six feet
away yeah everyone's safety right so I
think cannabis has a long history of
meeting these challenges especially
coming you know people who come out of
the traditional industry this
conversation has been really valuable
for me one of the things I'm thinking is
that I think that the activists in the
industry and lobbyists are gonna come
out of this feeling their oats because
if anything the cannabis industry has
proven itself during this time and its
value and its responsibility and so
there's there's many strong arguments to
be made for moving forward taking the
foot off its neck and I'm hopeful that
legislators may start to hear that
because of this event not in spite of it
well yeah I think over the last two
years we've proven we're really good at
jumping through hoops and so it's one
more thing like it's not something
that's devastating to us it's just one
more hoop we're jumping through yeah I
agree it's it's you know we've we've
survived federal prohibition wildfires
earthquakes you know this is just a
pandemic but I'm saying it's a you know
like 28 the transition and 2018 was like
so extreme and and just really this
reminds me so much of that just in terms
of like overnight protocol changes and
and and so many so
I'd spread protocol changes that yeah I
think of any industry it's going to come
out okay and is resilient and adaptable
enough to to survive this it's going to
be the cannabis industry just given
everything we've been through I would
agree with dust I'm even hoping more
that the that the craft side of the
industry also sees a resurgence you know
as a consumer who walks into retail
shops and has forever the move towards
you know just the CPG and everything
package it's been a little depressing
for me I think real cannabis people want
a live through their noses they like
that the types of illness is really
important I'm hoping as a people as a
nation you know as a world that we out
of this that we you know we realize that
we've been fucking things up we move
more towards more sustainable practices
that's the rational reaction to what has
just happened and you know cannabis just
works right into that especially the the
crap side of the industry and so many
people that we know and their voices can
continue to be heard I think it's going
to be a challenge but I what we want to
do that's whom we love talking to and
getting those practices we're seeing
some of that already I think we've seen
two or three of the multi state
operators announced that they're pulling
out of California in the last couple of
weeks you know we're seeing the
struggles that med men are going through
and what I'm hoping is that the small
operators on this call and you know the
small operators we work with that have
been staying lean focused on trying to
get profitable we step in and we fill
that gap
this was our industry this wasn't that
their industry those are the ones that
can adapt yeah yeah
they they tried to change our industry
to fit their idea of it and yeah where
were you
to this environment or more eager than
bad maybe 30 years of experience yeah
that place you know you just want to say
that I'm here with a buyer at Satori and
you know he's mentioning about how he's
wiping down all the boxes and then
letting them sit for 24 hours before he
puts them into the system feel like I
have to say that because we wonder about
that too as a consumer and stuff so yeah
yeah I mean that's kind of like my
protocol where packages land on the
front step I leave them there for like
12 hours then I put them in the yard and
let them sit for you know it's like
groceries come in they go in one place
for like nothing gets nothing good
nothing gets it for like 24 hours the
violet light yeah let's let's wrap on
that but I appreciated everyone this is
the the first of hopefully a recurring
serie and my whole thing I mean my whole
thing you're all small that was wouldn't
like I don't want to mess it on here or
Mednick on here kress go to tell us how
things are going for Cresco I don't give
a shit and I'd rather help you guys out
and get your voices heard and get this
in front of the Laurie Ajax's of the
world and the you know the consumers and
have you know hopefully them be like I
want to check out those space gem
candies with all due respect Berkley
patients group is not small in my mind I
guess it's relative to I mean we're
certainly not Cresco or
madmen I guess in terms of a violin here
though we have a good yeah we we have a
good solid following that we we spent
decades building up yeah I didn't mean I
didn't mean in terms of square footage
but in terms of its purpose its meaning
and the value its brought to this
industry to people all right thank you
everyone thank you