[Music]
all right so going back to somebody was
asking about trends earlier so of course
as you see in every other state and
actually you know you would asked about
us versus the rest of the states well
California versus the rest of the states
incidentally even in when California was
only medical and in states that are only
medical you're actually seeing similar
trends and yes there's slight variations
between the states but what it tells us
is the consumer the cannabis consumer
ultimately state-by-state or
internationally behaves more similarly
than they do differently
so ultimately what are the turns that
we're saying well so we're of course
seeing we're seeing flower decreased
steadily and quickly right so at the
beginning of 2017 in California flower
was roughly 53% right that's a great
question pause that's a great question
let's give up today that's a great
question let's get back to that I love
that question
um I've actually thought it to myself
and ever voice Ted but uh but you're
seeing so I think but yeah so I think q4
and maybe November was the first time
that that flower dropped below 50% in
California right so shocking and then
the major dramatic drop that we saw was
between December to January where flower
dropped about six points I think 49 to
43 percent more 4842 a drop to drop
significantly
right so great question so one of the
main reasons so what what so I mean of
course the launch of the adult use
market and and what that's telling you
right I mean with the with the launch of
the adult use market and with that comes
regulations compliance taxes increase in
price at retail right and for heavy
flower consumers medical consumers in
the prop 215 world who are accustomed to
having bought their flower at a certain
price point for the last
two three five ten years they're walking
in a dispensary January first and
they're like oh hell no I'm not putting
those prices right and so we did see a
lot of the that you know you saw we all
know that a lot of the medical users
left the legal market altogether because
this is California and everybody knows
how to purchase cannabis not at a
dispensary if you are so inclined but
but so so of course you see flower drop
out more significantly than other
packaged consumer or new consumer
oriented products edibles vapes topicals
teachers so with the launch of the adult
US market right we're saying the new
adult use user come in so my mom who I
talked about earlier my chardonnay mom
cousin with two kids right a 40 year old
female with two kids there another one
on the way congratulations and and like
any minute now actually and so so so
this consumer right they're not buying
flour they don't know what to do with
flour right they're buying something
more familiar to them tinctures creams
lotions you know blue bit chocolate
covered blueberries right I mean mints
these are the types of ter exactly so
these these are all you know in lower
dose from entry-level products right and
so that was of course one of the major
reasons we saw flour lose significant
share to these other product categories
we saw that happen now incidentally
right where we would expect to see
another dramatic share share change
right um in categories we saw sorry I'll
take a step back we saw flour continue
to lose share month over month no
surprise with as the launch of the as
the adult use market continued to launch
in the new adult use user continued to
come into the dispensary
what's interesting was between June and
July where we'd expect to see the share
of flour continued to drop we actually
saw the share of flower creep back up
right now let's think about that so July
first
what happened faced you testing right
with phase 2 testing you know if you
think about this up yeah I mean if you
just you think about the supply chain
right I mean the flower you know as you
move down this barrier exactly of less
we have less variables introduced that
are likely to cause the products to Pat
to not pass testing right I mean flour
is the rawest form of the product and
the supply chain the most likely to pass
testing and so there was an abundance of
flour available on the market and a lot
of the packaged products were not
succeeding past making it through
testing
in a timely enough manner not ready
enough July first and so dispensaries
we're all picking up picking up their
phones calling their flower their major
flower suppliers right and of course
these flower suppliers in some instances
the big guys they weren't able to double
their orders for every dispensary and so
you saw tons of small boutique local
flower brands pop into the market in
July with a hundred 150 even even a half
a million dollars in sales folks that
weren't doing any volume before then
because what would you say that you're
seeing like on the license side are you
seeing a huge influx of new brands
you're seeing the same licenses being
used baby
yeah what do you think you know really
what we're seeing is trends we've seen
in every state you know Colorado's a
more mature market at this point and
going back to your point I did want to
make this point so I don't think it's
just a pricing issue when it comes to
flower and the drop in flower I think it
in general is the availability of
products you know once direct sales
kicked off in Colorado in 2014 in 2016
we saw the same shift from flower to
vaping equipment and everything else
like that and it's just because it's
more readily available more educated
consumers they start to learn they go to
their shop the third fourth time they're
more open to starting new products I
mean we right we've seen the same same
thing happen this year in Canada as well
they went from flower being the top
bottom now on the license side and the
trends that we see in California
specifically are several I would say
vertical integration is key to a lot of
these businesses being able to yeah yeah
being able to stack those licenses and
in control on the other side with
outdoor growing this is a big trend is
stacking licenses and growing farms
bigger and bigger and overall I think on
the on the cultivation side there's
probably two outdoor licenses too one
indoor license in this state the vast
majority of licenses colter on the
cultivation side are in Santa Barbara
Mendocino and Humboldt County Santa
Barbara Santa Barbara is the one County
with the most cultivation licenses it's
somewhere around 800 of those 800 it's
only a handful of businesses that that
hold these licenses and they've stacked
these licenses
across the u.s. it varies greatly
because in states like Vermont you're
not gonna be growing outdoor because
you're only going to have one harvest a
year right so indoors big they're on the
East Coast we see large scale industrial
indoor growing in California I would say
the vast majority again it's probably
two to one
outdoor compared to indoor growing and
and really as far as indoor grows the
vast majority of from here in LA County
outside of LA County it's almost you
know you can just assume it's they're
growing outdoor about where do I see
flower bottoming out and it's that's
that's I mean I think that I think the
question there is more so on the supply
side even because how crafty our
supplier is going to get with how they
deliver and package flower products and
and effort into branding and telling the
story of the humble grower and making
the end consumer care about the flower
they're consuming right I think that's
the major question for me on the flower
side is is you know I think Humboldt is
gonna actually be dry whether or not
Humboldt survives I think will drive a
lot of the flower availability on our
market and yeah the branding that comes
with it yeah I think it all comes back
to branding right everything in a
capitalist society that allows you to
actually interact with people and bring
people on and try to sell your product
to them you have to build your brand you
have to cultivate that brand you have to
nourish it as well and yes and I think
that's something that some real issue
that Humboldt is dealing with the right
now of you guys watch South Park in the
Big South Park fan he's seen like last
week tegrity farms is Stan Marsh doing
out there yeah he left the city and he
started his own cannabis bar
is it so integrity Farms and he had
jeweling right you know the jewing
epidemic what's going on and that's
that's real right and so a part of the
episode this guy from big vapes comes
out there the big vape industry he tries
to get extracts from Stan to get his
company to fill these jewel pots back
Sarah and but he kept on talking about
there's no Tegrity in that something
that we're really dealing with right now
do you sell out completely and go into
the vaping industry where it's
everything is smoke and mirrors or do
you still have integrity of the plant we
still appreciating the trichomes the
different colors the different actual
terpenes not added back in like where
you end that where does the culture
actually meet industry and can they
truly coexist in the future well I mean
look at alcohol alright you know
everybody there's Bud Light and then
there's whatever craft beer you want to
talk about and there's a marketplace for
all of those products whether you're you
know midscale price-wise you're you're
not looking for something too great but
you want quality for the price you can
pay then then there are options for you
certainly on the the cheap side there's
there's plenty of that as well be a
product and brand for every consumer
segment right exactly
you know and going back to the license
is the one thing that that I'm
interested to see in California and the
one trend that that I've seen in in
States particularly Washington and
Oregon on as far as the licensing size
initially when those two states were
getting off the ground they over
licensed cultivators and didn't have the
consumer market to sell all of that
product now we see the wholesale price
is absolutely tanked in those states
Colorado is a little bit different it's
sort of leveled off and
gained pretty nice in Oregon right it's
crazy in our averages I think our
average in the data is for five dollars
ago no 100% your price retail and and
when we look at again California I kind
of see the same thing in this state that
I did see in Washington and Oregon where
they're the the majority of licenses out
there I mean there's somewhere around
fifty four hundred active licenses now
two-thirds of those are cultivation
licenses we have 500 retail legal state
license retail shops in this state so
there's obviously it's top-heavy on the
cultivation side we'll see what happens
on the manufacturing the one wild card
in this scenario is delivery because I
mean Oregon has it to a smaller extent
Washington doesn't happen at all so I'm
excited to see what consumer trends
happen as far as visiting your retail
shop brick-and-mortar are you calling
Speedway and especially when it comes to
my mom and my chardonnay mom cousin I
mean that well it falls directly into
our lap because I mean we work with
almost 1200 dispensaries nationwide
delivery services and brands what we've
seen the data that we've seen points
directly to women not wanting to go to
dispensaries yeah so some pretty cool
data we see our online orders are
significantly higher from women women
are more informed shoppers they spend
more time actually looking at the
product descriptions spend a bit on
average I want to get bad data right
here with my team right there say about
like 20 percent longer than men do
online
exactly
so the women are I mean so the one thing
that we do see dying is like the sash
culture that we have in California I
will miss it
you know I will but it doesn't sell
which is which is very very interesting
I see some of these new players once any
names I see some new players in the game
they're trying to go back to that
they're trying to go back to the TNA and
all of their advertisements that sell
right because that sells to men and men
don't buy it sells to the metal put it
but yeah and itself to the men it sells
to the men that are already going into
the shop and buying like you're all
marketing to the same people that are
already buying the product I mean
there's you know from the data we know
to in California this is from her yeah
no no I mean listen oh so two things um
so we do consumer surveys as well as the
retail tracking data right in our
consumer surveys in California we
fielded one earlier this year we're
currently feeling another and we filled
it one last year the number last year
23% of California adults of over 21 were
consumers that's defined as people who
have said yes to consuming over the
plastic over the past six months that
number has since in the last year gone
up to 29% and the rest of the pie is
made up of 38% acceptors people who are
not open to consuming sorry excuse me
who don't currently consume but are open
to consuming and then rejecters who are
not open to consuming but are not
necessarily against it that 38% that's
people who want who are open to
consuming but don't currently yet
consume that is that should be
everybody's target market right I mean
that is 38% of California and adults
over 21 that aren't shopping at a
dispensary or delivery service yeah
I agree with Rico's point earlier is
that I mean for a lot of that sesh
culture you're advertising to the
consumers you already have yes there
there aren't a lot of brands out there
that are going after that undecided
consumer that's looking to make a
decision I have seen it a little bit on
the brain inside as far as marketing
products specific towards women I just
think it's been done poorly in a lot of
ways yeah we've seen a lot of that see a
lot of stuff that's being marketed
towards women I don't know we don't have
enough data to know how well that is
doing yet we were a couple of quarters
into that and then a lot of those
companies just fell off any wait another
year or two to actually see how
successful these marketing campaigns are
knowing that the cycles through
regulations that these companies have
been failing right well I mean look like
the two strongest flower brands that
you're seeing in the market right now
are canned S&amp;M glow canna
now Flo canna they're there I mean you
know they're they are helping the small
grower and their marketing on that
platform and I think they're taking a
little bit more of a tongues approach
right even though they're not
necessarily taking the Tom's approach
but they definitely are I mean we're
talking my traumas the tongue right and
and and kenderson is I mean they are
they're taking the effect based approach
of targeting that new consumer and it's
and it's working I mean they're crushing
it and and you know I do I mean for
people who are entry-level flour
consumers I mean that is the way to keep
the flour alive right because going into
the dispensary and seeing the from my
mom if she wants to consume flour Green
crack not only means nothing to her it
scares her right you know
gorilla glue Durbin poison I mean none
of that sounds appealing right and but
if she walks into a display bolt to her
if she walks in the dispensary and she
sees calm relaxed you know sleep she's
like that's you know also I mean she's
looking for she's looking to achieve in
effect the reason she's coming into the
dispensary is because someone told her
this will help you with your sleep this
will help you with your menopause but
but you know she's going in and she's
like well gorilla glue help my menopause
anyone anyone and are the bartenders
qualified to ask answer that question I
think that's one thing like again I go
back to trends I've seen in other states
and how they may apply to Colorado when
you look at the consolidation effect
that happened in Colorado about two
years ago where native roots goes out
buys those mom-and-pop shops now there
are 23 different locations I think a big
key to native roots success is also
making very open and available shop to
their consumers and having educated bud
tenders that can help the mom that is
looking for help with her menopause then
come in and ask that bud tender yeah
exactly the economics right there right
so what do we do to bridge the
educational gap that we face right now
when the plan is still federally illegal
and you have the government directly
telling its people lies on everything
including cannabis well and and when you
don't have when a lot of the brands and
the many a lot of the operators don't
have access to traditional media and
advertising and and communicating to
their and consumer to my mom how do they
reach her capital I'm not just talking
about money you don't have access to any
of the other modes of communication that
every other industry has right you know
you suppresses link some of the states
that we operate in you can't you can do
online ordering but you can't put prices
online we do online ordering but you
can't have pictures or you can't put
snoops name on it or whatever you want
to do yeah going back to the point you
made earlier to with the trends of
people moving towards those other craft
products compared to just smoking flour
these days you know I think well it has
a lot to do with the science behind this
where we're still very immature when it
comes to what we know about this plant
and the more we learn the products get
better the quality gets better
and the the medicinal effects and
identifying those it's huge I also think
and this goes back to this to the South
Park episode a little bit but I actually
predict we might have a little bit of a
right now VAP is still one of the
fastest growing categories and I
actually predict that we might see a
little bit of a this is a personal
prediction a demise of the VAP no I want
to say demise it's not gonna go away
entirely but I think that some more
research at a research is gonna come out
around how most of the baits are
currently manufactured and also I think
the more research will come out about
the process of vaping I also think yep
and I also think that I mean for an
industry that's very socially conscious
and environmentally conscious we've been
giving the vape and it's sort of a pass
and I don't know how long that's gonna
last because the amount of waste that's
being collected right now and the fact
that we can't recycle those vapes
because they have contaminant product
and you know unless we get this we
encourage the state to take action on
this somehow I think that the people
will revolt
I see the trends on the licensing side
and you know overall I think yeah high
quality outdoor grown cannabis is going
to be a big in in California and
depending on where the federal
regulations go I mean it could be that
everything's grown outdoor in California
and trucked across the country by
coca-cola or whatever else in terms of
trends outside of the flower category so
with edibles category
I believe gummies make up let's see but
gummies yeah let's say I'll say yeah the
gummies make up the majority of edible
sales I mean they're definitely the
dominant category so gummies as well as
vapes within the concept of category as
well as mints with an edibles category
right so if you think about like these
three products right what do they all
have in common
they
user friendliness familiarity
ease-of-use
right um you know these are all things
that for an entry-level consumer right
someone who is like I I want to try this
cannibal cannabis thing but I don't
really know how to do it a vape if they
babe cigarettes very familiar to them
gummies we've all eaten a gummy before
mints who doesn't take a mint I mean
it's one of the easier products to make
it's very simple so I see a lot more of
it that's actually another very good
point that you bring up right because a
lot of what we're actually seeing in the
sales right in sales is you know a lot
of people ask me like should I make a
product you know 10 units 10 milligrams
Hunter milligram total or should I do
5 milligrams 20 units hundred or five
and five and five and ten and keep it a
50 right and I get right now you look at
the data and most of the products that
are selling are 10 packs with 10
milligram doses that's most of the top
selling products right and everyone's
like well that's what the consumer wants
and my question is is it yeah because
maybe no one's making you know a 10
milligram or 5 milligram 10 doses for 50
mil you know if someone's only visiting
for a week and doesn't want to buy 20
doses and they just you know I mean and
so I think that it is a function of both
supply and demand and work they are Co
evolving together so as the new adult
use user right I keep coming back to my
mom and my chardonnay mom cousin because
they are very very they smoke so much
weed and now it's a joke but uh I will
let them comment on how much they
consume but but no because I mean they
are they are those are two very
representative demographics that are
starting to come into the market and and
it's a it's sort of a catch-22 almost of
like well there aren't really products
available for us and people are like
yeah but we're not gonna make the
products if the consumer is not coming
in right so you have to and that's not
what is currently happening what is
happening is that people are actually
it's like the reverse of a catch-22 if
you build it they will come
you know they are buying what's
available it doesn't mean that it's the
best product out there
and and I think it's also what consumer
are you targeting are you targeting a
guy like me that's been smoking weed for
more than half his life and I want to
burn really good flour and hang out and
do my thing or are you going after that
tourists that is coming to California
for the first time and hasn't tried
anything they're from Wisconsin
well edibles are very you know it's an
easy gap to fill and there's definitely
a niche for that there's knit for going
after consumers like me there's niche
for going after female market it really
depends on what product or what
demographic you're going after and then
you know just because that's the product
that's selling in that that the top
market doesn't mean it's the best it
it's what's available now and that is
and actually this court this kind of
takes it all back to something we were
discussing earlier is there's a lot of
folks coming into the industry with a
lot of capital and a lot of experience
and they know they know how to make a
lot of product they know at a scale they
know how to distribute but do they know
the industry do they actually understand
how to make a decent cannabis based
product and the answer isn't is not
necessarily yes and the folks that I see
succeeding the most and I believe will
continue to succeed the most are those
that take that external experience that
external capital and bring in the
indigenous endemic legacy cannabis
operator experience I mean I think that
we can all have a seat at the table it
doesn't need to be black and white it
doesn't need to be us versus them right
and and and in fact that way they better
each other and and so that that is what
I say to a lot of the cannabis operators
right now that are struggling and they
don't know what their next step is you
know should we sell should we scale
should we raise you know and a lot of
them think that they can do it on their
own and continue brute-forcing it on
their own as they have for the last you
know X many years and the I don't want
to be pessimistic I don't I don't I
don't discount their experience or their
knowledge I respect the hell out of them
but the fact is that these people that
are coming in now are going to be able
to they're going to be coming in with a
lot of experience and a lot of money and
they're going to be able to out
manufacture an out price and
everything the legacy operators who
don't have that experience and so with
that I beg you get some help there's
technology out there there's I mean
there's everything these businesses need
to operate at full capability it's just
a matter of going out there and getting
it you know don't be afraid to spend
money on your LED lights too because
they're in it's an expensive initial
purchase but at the end of the day
you're gonna save money over the course
of the life of that light or or saying
this technology build your IT
infrastructures build your structures so
it's scalable so you can continue to
grow your business and operate at the
highest level so that's a big thing the
other thing that I would say that I
think is going to be the next trend in
this industry is edibles without sugar
in it there's a lot of people out there
that do not want sugar I do not want to
eat gummies that's why I smoke weed so I
see a lot of those products coming out
in Colorado I expect to see the same
thing in California
[Music]