[Music]
data is king I guess after cash data is
king right so whether we're scaling or
our customers are scaling everybody
speaks about data to make the company
smarter and build how long has that
customer been in the store wandering
around for a product how old are they
what's their average spend did when's
the last time they came back to the
store are they coming back once a month
did they never come back are they a
regular are they using your your loyalty
program that in a nutshell is what I see
as a smart forward-thinking company that
wants to not only obtain customers but
keep them given that leaf logixx is in
28 states what kind of trends are you
noticing not necessarily within the data
but actually in terms of retailer
behavior and adoption of your services
are you seeing any differences and you
know between let's say the West Coast
more commercially oriented States or the
East Coast more medically oriented it's
definitely how it changes in the future
will be interesting how it evolves
because that it will become borderless
but it's not borderless now right so
there is a distinct difference between
an East Coast buyer which is similar to
maybe a Midwest buyer and then it all
changes when you hit the mountain
mountain time zone right Mountain
Standard time and the difference I see
brands brands brands much more evolved
on the west coast from Colorado West
I think the East Coast I don't know if I
call it ketchup but but because of that
medicinal area that they're not in that
consumerism market and the vertical
integration and the vertical integration
yeah
I did I in Colorado for example they
they used to make it seven if you were
in medicinal I'm in dis selling
medicinal products you had to source
within your own vertical seventy percent
of the product now it's down to 50 or
about to be and it will be phased out
sometime next year is what I'm hearing
but all of that leads to back to data
right so data will trend from brands to
what they come back to purchase the
results we're getting on our
point-of-sale one of the aspects is the
consumer whether they're a patient or
rec customer they leave feedback on what
they liked and didn't like about the
product oh nice yeah so you're saying
that consumers are able to leave
feedback on the products they purchase
through your platform a how are you
actually engaging with a consumer that
way is there an application or do they
get texted so they can go online we have
an e-commerce platform for our clients
our b2b clients and they in turn will
open that up to their patients or or rec
customers and they will leave feedback
on everything from how it helped a
medical problem they had a condition or
simply for recreational the effects on
their body and they'll tie that together
with do they go back and purchase that
product do they try something else and
they can leave that on within that
point-of-sale facility so then next time
they go in that budtender will have a
running knowledge of what that person
likes which is pretty cool not just Bob
but what they like correct and the
effects so when you think about it yes
our industry's nascent compared to the
liquor industry for example but when's
the last time unless you knew Charlie
the bartender at your local haunt when's
the last time you could go into a bar
and that and the person serving you
knows what you
like prepackaged is it perhaps before
you come in and you know the effects on
your body so I'm gonna cool absolutely
and I'm actually gonna follow that up
with some interesting insights that
we're seeing in the data right so we
collect both retail tracking data which
is the data that we partner with the
point-of-sale systems on well we
actually partnered directly with the
retailer the retailer is the one that
agrees to give the data but we partner
with the point-of-sale data we're the
point-of-sale to actually collect to
that data right and so what we're seeing
there is the purchasing behavior overall
in California and we're definitely
seeing everything move away from flower
towards you know as we've heard before
edibles and concentrates and more
consumer or new user consumer oriented
products right more easy ease of use and
entry level friendly products and
incidentally what we're seeing within
though we're seeing about 15% edibles
sales but in our consumer data so this
is what is actually being purchased at
retail right the the retail tracking
data in our consumer data which is the
survey based data we actually see
consumers reporting on preference a much
higher preference of edible edible
consumption then we see in the
purchasing right so while roughly 15% of
sales are edibles the consumers report I
think maybe 20 roughly twenty or twenty
something percent report that they
prefer edibles and so where's that
discrepancy right where wheezing that
difference between the purchasing and
the preference exactly and where is it
going right so a a lot of it is probably
you know at home baking you know we're
definitely seeing a lot more brownie
preferences in the consumer data than
actual purchases in the sales data right
and that's probably more regulatory
based in California at this point since
making brownies has become a whole lot
harder but but I think it's what what it
what it shows and how it was ties back
into what you know the interesting
insights that you guys are collecting on
on consumers response or how they like
the product they're buying whatever the
word is for that preference how they
enjoy that specific product or how it
makes them feel well so so it's the
frequency right the frequency and
consumption is what is not being
recorded between the purchase and the
preference is the how often are they
consuming it right and so knowledge
exactly and so if you're getting that
data and you're seeing okay well look I
mean the reason only 15% of sales are
edibles but 20-something percent of
consumers report that they prefer
edibles is because maybe you know our
chalk or chocolate bars lasting too long
I mean you know if you're if you're a
chocolate manufacturer and you know that
people are that there's a strong
preference for your edible product and
you know the consumers are reporting
favorably on it but they're not
purchasing it as often as they should
well that is an opportunity for not just
the retailer to make different decisions
around what types of products maybe they
want more high frequency products on
their shelves but also for the
manufacturers to produce more high
frequency purchasable products right and
I know BDS is is just went into Arizona
recently yeah so you're gonna bring that
knowledge from other states into their
the the the stores in Arizona or do they
start from scratch there's any type of
comparison so they you give them a
little education on what's happening
outside of Arizona very interesting
question yes so so initially absolutely
I mean generally how it works is a you
know you as a participating retailer you
receive access to the state in which you
participate exist but but yeah when we
launched a state right we obviously
don't have data on that state so we give
our retailers access to another state
perhaps as incentive to participate and
so they are able to learn from other
states behavior to see alright well you
know I mean Arizona hasn't launched an
adult user market yet I mean they
haven't legalized just quite yet but
expect it to 2020 right on and it sounds
about right
and and so yeah and so what's
interesting is you know adult use or not
yes of course there's a lot for them to
learn from other adult use markets such
as Colorado in Oregon that have been up
and running for many years you know
California is still young I don't not
that there's obviously tons to learn
from the California market but it's not
as mature yet but what's interesting is
no matter where we're at in the
legalization phase looking at the trends
and across all states is what we noticed
the consumers actually end up behaving
more similarly than they do differently
right I mean the terms are not that
drastically different state-by-state no
matter where they're at no matter where
they're at in their legalization there's
a border right really with people it's
you know consumers are consumers yeah
and so so that's that's what's you know
I think that overall I mean yes of
course you're gonna have your regulatory
variances as well as some personality
quirk differences between states but
yeah I mean you know the interaction to
get the data right it's it's still
unique that you have such interaction to
get gathered data so with our with some
of our with our set up at Point of Sales
customer will come in they can be
greeted and the person will have an iPad
while their display whatever could be
any type of handheld mobile device let's
call it an iPad and they will get as
they're speaking but in that person's
profile what they're speaking about it's
very interactive and that's stored
they're going back to that data of and
then it follows up with their purchase
and your comment about X percent of
edibles and what people prefer and when
you put that together
what whether it's artificial
intelligence from that route or just
someone analyzing me internally that
you're at that person's company you're
going to make get a copy or customer you
going to get a customer that comes back
right and I think that that's how you
expand your revenue for the customer
yeah yeah a getting the customer to come
back and more often exactly actually I
think where there's a lot of opportunity
is how to get that customer to bring
their friends oh yeah try this this was
the effect on me tell me what what it
was like on you especially with edibles
and that's that's a thing where people
are still you know getting used to
edibles because it's such a in in exact
science of what you're popping in your
mouth right there's still a trepidation
not for everybody but enough of the
parties and that feedback which is data
this is all data related right and so
that feedback of this is how I felt when
I did it and the high quality stores and
we have many throughout the country now
we'll have good standardizations of
product quality standards and you know a
lot of it is just consumer education
right I mean you know and and you can't
blame the end consumer
right because here's here's the analogy
I like to give I mean let's jump back to
you know probic alcohol provision right
no I mean people had been drinking for
you know long before then right it's an
alcohol provision wasn't in effect that
long enough for people to forget how to
drink right um
cannabis prohibition has been in effect
for 70 plus years right catch-up time
for us a lot of catch-up time right I
mean where you've essentially are
cannabis culture if there even was one
to begin with before the 20s or 30s or
for you know what did it exist right
imagine imagine right now you know we
had had 70 years of alcohol prohibition
and I you had no idea how to drink right
like maybe you know there was obviously
the underground scene and you knew
exactly how to find your speakeasies and
how to get your medical card I don't
know I went like this how to get your
medical card um but but yeah I imagine
that that was the alcohol world we lived
in now and I you know we just legalized
and I put a bottle of vodka in front of
you and said go no way I put a bottle of
vodka a bottle of wine and a beer right
and you're like enjoy drink this whole
bottle of vodka and a sip of that beer
or exactly so I mean it's just there's
been you know we haven't from my mom
right for
you know cousin from my grandma even all
these folks that are now thinking about
how to get into this industry I mean
they're walking into the dispensary and
they're trying to figure out what the
difference between wine and beer is you
know how to give it another moving part
we still have to remember our part the
industry we're in cannabis is also
medicinal okay I mean there's the old
joke I'll have a scotch and it's my
medicine but that's a little figurative
cliche right but in our industry that
we're proud of scientific addition oh
and can be fun yeah so so the more data
there the better the more comparative
word of mouth but word of mouth isn't
going to cut it it's gonna be it's gonna
be that you know socially mainstream
mainstream education I mean and that's
and right one of the big challenges is
the fact that all of our operators don't
have access to traditional advertising
mechanisms right so so I do think that
there's going and you know the celebrity
route right like that sort of that's
what people have been trying to take and
it'll be interesting to see how that
plays out but whoever can figure out how
to mass educate consumers on a what the
difference between wine and beer is and
why you take a sip of that wine and why
you would drink that whole beer and when
ya figure out how to educate us on that
not us you know but I know but my mom
doesn't right and you know she sheering
I was trying to figure out you know what
do I take for it you know I'm I woke up
today I'm feeling a little bit anxious
right um what should I take now right
and then later on I'm gonna be feeling a
little bit sleepy and maybe later
tonight I'm gonna want to feel sleepy
even have a hard time sleeping so you
know we're still we're still figuring
that out right exactly
so you're when you go into what's your
poster child customer on your that the
information your system will give them
surrounding data how will they take that
and work with that to build both both
their brand cuz they're a business but
also the the loving education to their
customers absolutely so are most of the
well let's say our poster children
purchase both the retail tracking data
as well as the consumer survey data
right so the retail tracking data like I
said as the data we collect from the
dispensaries where we went through the
point-of-sale and and what they
subscribe to that to obviously
understand what their market share is to
understand what types of products to
manufacture and how to adjust their
price points to adequately meet their
target consumer right so now the second
part of that or the next question is
well who is their target consumer right
and so that's where our consumer survey
data comes in all right which is just
your traditional consumer survey data
but that tells you you know I mean in
California for example I think the
average consumer is like 40 years old
either male or female right so I mean
the assumption generally is generally
that males consume more than females and
yet the average consumer it's pretty
much either
and so just a person in their 40s with
kids and children under the age of 10
right that is the average consumer and
so so of course meaning and of course
one of the fastest-growing demographics
is my grandma doesn't surprise me at all
right I mean the the number of
dispensaries I hear anecdotally telling
me that people coming I mean the number
of people that have come in for sleep
over the last since legalization you
know just just sleep just just leave I
mean they're there it's it's crazy right
arthritis and joints I would you know
there's certain
conditions that you we as humans get as
it's that with the data they will be
educated that this is not you know a
voodoo right I'm so brainwashed exactly
and so so and that is in fact what the
data has helped educate not just the
industry but folks outside of I mean
regulatory bodies within right I mean
look this is your average consumer this
isn't a in quotation marks stoner who's
like sitting in his basement and playing
video games all day I mean which is fine
too if that's if that's your mo awesome
but but you know it's it's so yeah we
how they use that data right is it as
their you know a lot of these a lot of
companies historically and still are
targeting that same in quotation marks
at stoner the person that's already
walking into the dispensary right what
the consumer data shows is okay here's
the percent of consumers right but
here's the percent of people who are not
yet consuming and are open to it and
that's currently in California 38
percent of adults over 21 so 38 percent
of adults over 21 in California are
currently don't consume but but are down
to consume really prove it but they're
not let's just say they're getting that
they're just about to take their leap in
because they've or they don't know right
they're like they're like do I drink the
wine or the beer you know like so so so
those so the question is right and if
you're a manufacturer right now and
you're trying to target a consumer
segment looking at that consumer segment
and thinking alright and when you have
the opportunity to get creative and not
just educate them on here is what wine
will do for you and here's what beer
will do for you right here's what an
edible with high CBD will do and here's
what you know depending on your need
state and etc whoever figures out how to
adequately do that and reach that new
consumer not the one that's already
walking into the dispensary but the one
that's not yet walking into the
dispensary teach them how a to come in B
to buy that wine over that beer and C to
buy your wine over that one it's the
winner is the winner and and there'll be
multiple winners but you have to go in
that direction in my opinion to be one
of the winners that consumers or
consumerism they're smart they pick it
whether it's you know buying a mattress
or a car or a toaster they know from
price to quality
- I like that I don't like that so it's
really they need an education they will
they will get the education they for us
it's lay out the information they will
seek it if it's there yeah because they
will educate themselves fast you and I
and you and I are in that ballpark as
well oh yeah I think we've all educated
ourselves really quickly and it's funny
you know I think that it's the consumers
have the luxury of taking their time on
educating themselves I personally think
that one of the areas we really need to
focus as an entire cannabis community is
the physicians yeah and I have a lot of
friends I have a lot of friends that are
doctors right any other there you know
whether they work in a family practice
or in the ER and they get regular
regular regular questions around
cannabis and they have no idea how to
answer it they they go home and Google
and the funny part of that is going back
to that that prototypical stoner that
stoner knows more about this this
medicine or rec product than the doctor
with the degree yep you know and that I
mean you know we can get into why that's
so big farmers not going to educate us
we have to educate ourselves in this
industry
well these they're not gonna educate us
yes yes as soon as they have incentive
to okay you read they know just like the
liquor industry is joining now but yeah
I think I think consumers and will go a
long way especially with starting with
data and them educating and educating
ourselves we've been talking a lot about
this new consumer or the existing
consumer that's been walking into that
has previously walked into the
dispensary or trying to get this new
consumer to walk into the dispensary can
you talk a little bit about the actual
physical experience that could
humor has when they walk into the
dispensary and how your software makes
it easier or less intimidating yeah yeah
let's do a question
so you whether you're an educated
consumer repeat customer they call you
by your first name when you walk in or
the first timer it's it's there's
differences but but that color of
experience is going to be one of coming
in walking through the door and being
greeted with someone in our case where
you can use an iPad or mobile device so
as soon as you welcome to the store that
that consumer will get an experience of
let us show you on a one-on-one talk
what products were offering and what you
may like and what may be fit that person
coming in they will also normally see a
flat-screen live menu in in the area so
they're already getting an education do
you do any sort of at I mean is the menu
just a static menu or do you find ways
to incorporate that there will be there
will be various underlying feedback from
other patients nutrient tracking the
testing results testing results will be
at a stage where you can look that up on
from the store level and on the
e-commerce level just like if you were
buying a milk and you're on online you
can see the calories in the milk and the
details are like the vitamins in the
milk yes that's their vivid pictures
night nice user friendly images and and
then it flows into what that particular
store wants to promote in terms of what
are you looking for very interactive you
find that that increases their speed of
sale potential of sale quantity of sale
actually all of the above with the
software the that experience walking in
will promote a pre-order so it's a
faster transaction
for the store and that pre-order from
off that iPad of standing by somewhere
near the entrance or cases will be put
into the back office and that order will
will begin to be put together where by
the time you get up to the register it's
already ready you can ask more questions
and a lot of times
besides the questions you order more
product you already have your bag and
you put in a few more into your cart and
I think that's it I think that's a big
benefit in the experience for the
consumer and the store
[Music]