I just saw a Moses talk confident
cannabis you did a fantastic job
presenting sort of a larger data science
project that coughing cannabis is
undertaking in that space it's hard work
in general to take sort of good data and
provide kind of key insights to it
what's what's sort of your biggest
takeaway after working with the data for
so long and what direction do you think
that data is taking shape and the kinds
of good questions that you think we
should ask kind of in the future about
it what are what are the ones that keep
you up at night I think the biggest
thing that's emerged from looking at the
data is how much variation there is in
the chemistry of cannabis not just from
strain name to strain name but within a
strain name from producer to producer
from harvest to harvest and even within
a harvest and it really it turns out
that people when you shop for cannabis
what you're really shopping for is a
bundle of chemicals is a bundle of
chemistry that you think is going to
have produced an experience that you
think is going to produce an effect and
it turns out that the way that we
present cannabis to the market I try and
take a market approach to these things
I'm not a chemist I'm not a biologist
I'm more of an economist and so I think
trying to get market approach and it
turns out to the way that we sell
cannabis to the market in terms of
indica sativa hybrid in terms of what's
a what's the strain aim with the genetic
origin of the strain that's probably not
the best way to help customers get the
experience that they're looking to get
interesting one of the things that's
interesting we're here in Nevada and one
of the great things that Nevada has done
really leading the other states is by
requiring terpene testing for all of
their cannabis products and so if you're
looking for a particular terpene you can
go into the dispensaries here and we've
been our team came in from Palo Alto and
we've been going to the dispensaries
here and just talking to each other
about how fantastic it is that we can
tell what terpenes are in what we're
purchasing I really I just wish every
state would do that I know
there's a lot of legacy cannabis users
who want that terpene information and
for years they've been saying things
along the lines of well it's not just a
numbers game I I don't necessarily want
the highest potency I want some
additional flavor in there and I'm
looking for it the Kiev are kind of the
strain name that we've seen kind of
emerge is really the fundamental
branding of cannabis so when you kind of
go after and identify specific strains
what you're really doing is you're kind
of delving into the brand history there
and it's a legacy it's a legacy subject
and and I think people identify with
those early brands in cannabis even
before the names of companies been
generated that's interesting one of the
things that I talked about mentioned in
the talk I met a few weeks ago a fellow
who ran grows in Humboldt County in the
1970s and 80s just bumped into him by
randomly in the Philippines actually but
I asked him I said what's it what's the
difference between an indica and sativa
you're a viewer a grower and you were a
grower when cannabis was first starting
in America what's the difference between
indica sativa me is it Mersin is it
Turpin alene he said it's how high the
plant grows alright that kind of answers
the question doesn't it that's a great
fundamental approach and if we can find
kind of simple answers to help consumers
on that end I would love to see things
like that come out of your data set and
sort of the data set emerging through
all of the users at confident cannabis
all the labs who participate in that
sort of experience should have some sort
of accessible platform where they can go
and ask basic questions about their
consumers where these products are
coming from and only that but have
stored the horsepower of good
statistical analysis to back it up it's
one of the wonderful things working for
me working at confident cannabis is that
they're true believers in data science
and in the importance of science itself
there's never been pressure to cause the
to cause the tools to produce one result
or another we really let the data form
its own shape and we let the data tell
us what it wants to tell us and one of
the what I was presenting today was this
tool that we've constructed called
connect
which is a way of visualizing cannabis
strains in terms of their chemical
content and we built that for a lot of
different people we built it so that
consumers can figure out what it is
they've been smoking what the chemistry
was so that they can find if they have
an experience that they like they can
find things nearby so they can find new
strains we built it so that dispensaries
can have a diverse range of products on
their shelf and figure out what a divert
and what it means to have a diverse work
it chemically diverse range of products
on their shelf and we built it for
producers to figure out where their
strains fit in to help them diversify
against price movements and so forth so
we're trying to figure out ways that we
can use the data to help our customers
to advance their goals you know we're
trying not to get ahead of our labs or
data providers we don't know if they
want to be producing publishing on a
subject we're not going to research that
subject we try and find ways to use this
this enormous wonderful data set that
we've accumulated to use it in ways that
help the whole industry now from my
general perspective I'm a I'm a chemist
but I'm also a chemical engineer and I
have just general questions to ask of
the data set and I thought you actually
presented sort of the good test data
sets and sort of the general approaches
and questions that you've asked to sort
of answering broader questions again
what what kind of selectivity
differences do we have across the space
to uniquely identify the plants that we
all care about and love and from from my
perspective I think you're providing a
tool that helps all businesses in
between I represent a large investment
firm across the space c21 investments
who's acquired everything from grows to
dispensaries and all the things in
between and from a processor perspective
we're always looking at sort of the
frontier of cannabis and we want to know
how so the market is not only evolving
but the product evolution and we want to
back that with good science and data
when we put a product out we want it to
be something that not only consumers
have asked for but
give them something maybe new to the
experience and we want to use data to
sort of guide those experiences and so
if terpenes are really not uniquely
identifying a plant but it's
inexperienced customers or asking for
I think that's perfect information
that's the kind of information that we
love to hear and good simplifications
like that from these larger data sets
very small conclusions can lead to very
very strong strategic decisions one of
the cushions are trying to dancer early
on was can we build a model for
predicting the strain of a based on the
lay up test data sample based on the
sample data right and the answer was no
and the reason is that there are so many
different products sold under the same
strain names that the data doesn't
differentiate between them there are
some strains that does that where you
can differentiate there are some
outliers but for the strains that are in
common use the Blue Dreams the Jack
Herer is the sour diesels the Girl Scout
cookies of the world there are so many
different products sold under that name
that there is not a way a statistically
valid way of distinguishing whether a of
assigning a plant to one of those
categories or another based on their lab
test data so seeing seeing as how you're
building sort of this larger platform
for integrating all manner of data sets
to ask questions about from from a
larger perspective what kinds of data
sets would you like to see integrated in
the future and what what could
businesses do to help enable that it
would it be as simple as adding surveys
to the space or collecting more public
health type information to policy public
policy type integration to get an
understanding of how product is flowing
sort of across the larger space so what
we like to see that that I would love to
be integrated in three places and we're
already in talks for two of those places
there's one one that we're
the first is to try and develop and
support accumulate data to try and
develop the relationship between these
chemicals and different experiences and
so we're looking to integrate with
companies that have and are collecting
data sets of cannabis experience
reactions and finding ways to tie those
experience reactions back to the
chemistry in a statistically valid way
the danger here is that when you get
into experience you're really talking
about health information and we want to
be very careful about not telling giving
people health advice unless we know that
what we're saying is really strongly
founded in verifiable science and so
we've been looking for datasets that are
sufficiently robust sufficiently
detailed and sufficiently valid unbiased
to support that the second spilly place
where we've been looking to accumulate
data relates to pricing we take a market
approach to cannabis where we're not
trying to figure out what the
biosynthesis of cannabis is we're not
trying to be biologists we're not trying
to be chemists what we're trying to do
is look at how cannabis behaves on the
market what are the different categories
we categorize it based on how the market
categorizes it and so what we really
would like to be accumulating is data
about the pricing of cannabis figuring
out how different cannabis based on its
chemical content and based on the visual
quality of it is selling at different
prices that's the second data set that
we're looking to accumulate we talked a
little bit about that today in the
presentation to explain how our analysis
of chemical differences relates to the
build-out of a pricing prediction model
the third place where we really would
like to be integrating is with
point-of-sale folks and we built out the
skin and the reason I'd like to be
integrating there is I'd love to have a
forward-looking view on where the demand
is going I'd really would like to be
able to get demographics for how the
demand for different cannabis products
is reaching out into different
demographics and we built this product
Kinect Kinect confident cannabis calm
it's free and Kinect lets you explore
different cannabis strains in terms of
their chem
data we really think that there's a
potential synergy there with people who
are doing point-of-sale applications
where we could have connect out in the
dispensary we could link it up to
various point-of-sale systems and we can
help dispensaries figure out what they
want to order for the next month to you
know where the demand is going to be a
month from now to help them pre populate
and pre do pre-orders for their next
cannabis buys and what would that would
get for us is forward-looking
perspective on where the market is
moving and where demand is moving that's
incredibly interesting as far as getting
larger predictions across that market
and the types of discussions those
things enable when you have sort of a
direction again you can from from my
perspective you can align sort of your
vision to it and you can get a very
concise vision of where we're heading in
cannabis and it's great to see everybody
here at the show and see sort of the
up-and-coming technology but trying to
eliminate a lot of that confusion and
getting hard specific data that that
allows for the fundamental backing of
what you're doing really really is
fantastic you've also given us a tool to
the to the broader community something
that we can ask questions of and
interact with and get a sense of how to
essentially make everyone's job a little
bit easier and a little bit more
informed and I think that's a really
wonderful approach information in a very
concise way is a very powerful tool and
it's always been that way in the
cannabis community but again going back
to old claims is an important part of
the scientific process and so it's it's
a wonderful approach I think the the
economic approach to sort of the broader
data analysis and for example are you
looking at all are you forming any other
types of partnerships sort of sort of
outside of
the spheres that you mentioned and
looking at more of like policymaking for
example are you are you looking at
public health sorts of information or if
you had people interested on those
fronts other like the medical community
for example because Dan abysus
is fundamentally sort of a medical
product that's it's kind of the initial
push to the legal space and we have
there's a lot of questions coming from
there we have looked at working with
people who are conducting clinical
trials or at least double-blind studies
of cannabis health effects there's
nothing I can announce about that today
the other group that we've looked to be
integrating with our folks who are
collecting data about the effect of
different production method choices and
different growth choices on chemistry
when I mean pressure myth is what I mean
is when you are growing cannabis there
are thousands of choices that you make
in the growing process when we think
about cannabis we think about the strain
which is supposedly the seed but and we
and we don't think about all the effort
and work and creativity that gets put in
by the farmer but those things matter
how long they leave the plant up
temperature lighting fertilizer water
there are thousands and thousands of
thousands of choices that they make
throughout the production process that
have an enormous impact on chemistry I
don't there are people who believe that
we are our genes I don't believe that I
don't think people are their genes
I don't think plants are their genes I
don't think that's how life works and I
think those choices that producers make
have a tremendous impact and one of the
folks there one of the areas where we've
been looking to team up with folks are
folks who are collecting data across how
different choices in the production
process influence that chemical outcome
absolutely and and sort of that nature
versus nurture discussion I think is
just starting to sort of activate on
this end and as you get more data as
part of this project we'll kind of dive
into it and we'll see how fundamentally
the creativity is
mentioned of various growers and just
various producers across the space has
influenced the direction in the position
where cannabis sits today the the
products we know and love may just be
sort of a broader sense the love you put
into a product is essentially the best
selling point potentially of your
product there may be something there to
it that sort of emerges from the data
and the way you you treat these things
in your talk today we saw it kind of - I
saw two major distinctions and the data
set that you presented and can be
accessed through connect I saw sort of a
serpentine head sort of form and we also
saw separations in THC and CBD are there
any other kind of fluid separations
starting to happen in that data set
there a tremendous number of them there
are so there are groups that cluster out
because of CBD v because of CB n because
of lynn Ahlul because of various
combinations of terpenes and as our data
set is growing we see more clusters
emerging the way that our algorithm
works you have to have a certain number
of points that are friends of each other
before they can become a distinct
cluster a certain number of nearest
neighbors so as our dataset burrows and
we have enough data for more of those
clusters to emerge those clusters are
emerging we have in the in connect we
call some of these things regions where
we discretize the space we look for
areas of the space where some of the
cannabis products have separated
themselves from the rest and we have I
think 20 or 30 of these regions at the
moment and you can go through the region
map and you can see how each of these
things has a distinct chemistry it's
actually a very convenient way if you're
looking for to find a particular
chemistry it's a very convenient way of
finding that chemistry in connect as we
start to get some of these groupings
emerged how do you set sort of the new
bounds for new states that are emerging
and and really how how is it that you
draw a circle around or a shape around
sort of that new grouping and identified
as a unique grouping because I may look
at it and say well I think this is a
unique grouping that's evident and you
see this as a unique grouping and larger
discrepancies may arise in the long term
as we start to form this blob so how do
you approach those sorts of questions we
use math for that okay to be serious
okay so how do we find the clusters the
question fundamentally is about how you
solve the problem of clustering in data
science and the problem of clustering in
data science is that you get data and
there's lots of points and somebody
wants those points to be divided into
you have a million points but you need
to divide them into a sufficiently small
number of groups that a human being can
understand them and what you want is a
data-driven way to separate them out
into natural groups where the groups are
there are a few enough groups that you
can go one after another and look at
them so how do you go about doing that
that's one of the significant challenges
in data science today is different
approaches to clustering and I think in
data science when you're approaching the
clustering problem you really need to
ask the question what usage what what
are these clusters going to be used for
and I think that should guide your
choice of clustering methodology the
clustering methodology that we chose the
purpose of this clustering is not to
take strong positions about how many
kinds of cannabis there are or what the
boundaries between one kind of cannabis
on or another are they are to help
people navigate what's otherwise a very
complex topological shape we have a 3d
we have a twenty six dimensional
construct that we've reduced to three
dimensions with a very complex topology
and we want to help people find their
way around that to navigate that and so
what we wanted was something that simply
discretize is that space but we also see
in the space that we have very
we have areas of the space that are very
dense and we have areas of the space
that are not very dense and we wanted a
clustering methodology that was going to
respect that and that was going to
recognize that you can have a non dense
area that is a cluster as well as a
dense area that's a cluster so the
algorithm that we're using is called
optics we looked at a bunch of different
density based algorithms I tend to
prefer density based clustering when you
have very high dimensional data like
this I prefer a density based clustering
the advantage of optics over the the two
competitive algorithms are DB scan and
HDB scan the problem with DB scan is
that it is non adaptive you have to have
a single density barrier which is the
boundary condition for all clusters it
doesn't respect that some clusters can
be more dense in some clusters less
dense optics can be is dynamic with
respect to its boundary condition it's
actually optics combined with another
algorithm that's dynamic I'm HDB scan is
usually my favorite algorithm it
produces a hierarchical density based
clustering the trouble is that HDB scan
tends to produce too few clusters and
not as many as you want
optics had the natural balance where we
produced or was able to produce the
right number of clusters a sufficiently
small number that a human being could
comprehend them so how do we set our
boundary condition in optics well we
actually do that through optimization
where we have a target number of
clusters that we want to generate and we
have a target number of clusters where
each cluster has a certain maximum a
minimum number of points and we there's
a one parameter to optimize an optics
the alpha parameter and we run a what's
it called
we run a simple optimization algorithm
where we try and vary the alpha
parameter to hit into the acceptable
range of cluster numbers the general
clusters that you provided are just
generally true clusters of the data it's
so yes not necessarily that's actually
right to say this cluster II or these
grouping of farmers you're not giving
selected preference to anybody in the
absolutely right is a data-driven
approach to seeing what this data looks
like
that's right natural shape is not guided
by means that's absolutely true what we
say is how many clusters do people want
to deal with they're willing to deal
with basically I think between twelve
and thirty clusters that's
comprehensible so what we do is we say
we let the data naturally find between
twelve and thirty clusters and however
many it finds that's how many clusters
there are
you
[Music]