[Music]
this is us to do with the CDT FA and the
tax excise tax regulations and this is
very nuanced so in a non arms-length
transaction you tax on the wholesale
price and there is not a clear
differentiation although in their new
round of proposed regulations they are
suggesting an option for this but I
believe that when there is a calculation
of the average wholesale price of
cannabis which is what it says in the
law it should just be the cannabis but
there are a lot of the calculations are
being made based on the product which
means the entire cost which means the
hardware the packaging all of it and I
believe that all of that needs to be
exempt and it needs to just there needs
to be two separate invoices and the
excise tax needs to just be paid on the
cannabis that's what it says in the law
and that's what should be reflected in
the regulations that's a biggie what
about the luxury tax
oh yeah Wow taxes yeah absolutely the
tax in the text they I mean they're the
layers and layers of your local your
sales your ex ice and the way that you
break it down is you're actually the ex
ice is put in first so you're kept your
local taxes is being calculated with the
excise tax already incorporated into the
amount it's a tax on a tax yes the sales
because you're adding in the excise tax
first and then ever all the other taxes
is includes the excise tax yeah the
calculation but the reason that this
exclusion of the of the the parts of the
product that is not cannabis as legally
defined cannabis or cannabis products so
that and that means the oil or whatever
cannabis accessory is a very specific
definition which means packaging and
hard
and all of that that increases the value
significantly and we're already paying a
lot of money for this every this is very
expensive stuff but for vaporizers
specifically on the China the tariffs on
China there's actually I've received
emails and I've seen this I this is
going to become a thing but because the
the taxes on bait pens is gonna go up
because most of these vape pens come in
from China that means the price of the
products going to go up which means and
if they are including these vape pens
the hardware and the price of the
hardware including those tariffs into
the product price that's being
calculated for the excise tax that's
gonna be a big hit that's twenty five
percent and the hardware is one of the
most expensive parts I mean the cannabis
is expensive but so that is that is the
big reason why I say especially and
because packaging is expensive to making
sure things are child resistant and
following all the other regulations that
have to do with packaging it's expensive
so you remove those costs then your
taxes that you're calculating is a lot
lower absolutely so here's another
situation where the consumer has a
potential class action complaint against
the state for over taxing it against the
the mandates of the law against the
provisions of the law I'm sure an
argument probably could be made for that
I think it's pretty clear that yeah I
mean cannabis there's very clear
definitions for cannabis cannabis
products and cannabis accessories and
the seed ETF a to their credit are
giving an option for that for
distributors to market separately but on
invoices but I know that there's been a
lot of disagreement because the there's
concern of exposing you know certain
price agreements with vendors on
hardware I I'm not really sure what the
deal is I don't do
factoring or so I don't know but I do
know that at some point you are ordering
hardware and at some point you're
ordering weed and they are separate and
then you put it together so you know
what the cost is and the weight and the
transfer is all in Metrix so it should
be easy to calculate
but that's so that's something and I
just think because everything is so
expensive any possible way that we can
reduce the taxes and then that we're
moving is the cost to the consumer is
something that we need to be exploring
right now yeah well the the state
doesn't even want to lower the excise
tax in general so far it sounds like
there's not a lot of enthusiasm for that
so yeah what's left of it yeah that's
the economic sweet spot mm-hmm yep yeah
we got Berkeley to cut their taxes in
half and very early on which was great
and very helpful but not not working