Delta time THC there's now a huge thread
regarding that and don't live when we
had a fun little for it for take a
little for a layman's background so so
depending it specifically yeah
everybody's different and I'll all have
their own special ways of a festival but
depending on where or how the different
pieces of the molecule are laid out you
you know the difference between THC
delta 9 and T and C a is th EA has a
carbolic acid molecule in its tail and
no boxer group carboxyl group and in
another thing there's Delta 88 C which
has gotten really popular with the water
clear trend and people would you know
they would throw a bunch of carbon and
some acids and stuff into their boiling
flask and then they'd start distilling
it and it's coming out beautiful water
clear
they sent test results or they'd sent
testing labs and then it's yeah like
very low percentage of Delta 9 THC
eventually we started they got standards
for Delta 88 C then started quantifying
that there's more THC in us that there
is but then there's still a little
missing piece that like you'd see you
know 60 to 70 80 percent cannabinoids
and this water clear stuff that you know
it's all cannabinoids and there's plenty
of isomers and stereo isomers of THC and
these are things that happen through
different reaction their reactions that
happen through heating and the presence
of acids and bases and given the
different environmental things or what
was sprayed on those so that that can
actually be a big indicator
what's happening into the reactions as
well so so good all that distillation
method we're like you put stuff in a pot
it boils at different temperatures and
all that well throw catalyst in that pot
that you don't know is there like you
know people spray put sulfur on their
plants or people you know certain things
get sprayed on plants and when you
concentrate that thing in a hot flask
under vacuum where fires and fire attack
there's a whole bunch of ways you could
do that but to go back to Delta 10 Delta
10 is simply an unknown type of THC that
until recently was it is yes in
different income in different ways they
affect all three of those can affect a
single person completely different no
they've been discovered but they're only
being mass-produced
yeah they yeah macula vanilla and knows
about him and he has and we are just now
mass producing them because we have the
freedom of the market to start and start
playing and then we also have the
competition in the market to try to make
the clearest most beautiful looking oil
which you know well it used to be Delta
8 th DW I mean I we can I know use I'm
saying historically historically when
they first started getting this
perfectly clear bottle of oil
it was Delta eight and they would do
this refluxing carbon acids and but but
but yeah and that was it then they would
use a catalyst in the flask that they
were boiling in one we're talking about
people who appreciate the clarity that
clear net the secret
is that the consumer is that an expert
consumers okay
and what's your opinion on consumers
have been led to believe that the clear
the oil is well and and and that clear
could come from a lot of different
things it can be cut with another clear
oil that it makes you know just diffuses
what color is in there there's a lot of
things that can clarity is definitely an
indicator of purity though it was an
indicator but the a slight yellow amber
tint the these are little little atomic
level refractions that are happening
with chromophores that hold into the the
tail end of the molecule these these are
what a chromophore is uncle mela
these they're they're basically like
atomically small things that will
refract light at a different color so
you have so by breaking that bond you
you like that's when people distill with
certain things on the flask you can
break that at that chromophore bond and
it you can also break that bond by
through chromatography as well which
people eventually developed a method for
Delta 9 THC
does anyone clear water clear yeah
and it that was just a method of taking
a single pass distillate and then
passing it through a series of usually
magnesium silicate or floor so actually
and then but different color remediating
adsorbents that were also being used to
remediate past asides and they still are
used to remediate pesticides and it just
happened that you make water clear delta
9 after remediating pesticides properly
as sometimes depending on the oil and
what kind of colors and that
the condition THC 8 and 10 have been
known for and their-their prevalent in
the same way that THC is in Canada like
there is it kind of like a is it a
totally different cannabinoid that is in
very low percentages in well zombie
health of ours not so much on the
cultivar it's a reaction through
processing so you're not gonna have
those you're not gonna have a bunch of
Delta eight or delta10 any in your
flowers you're gonna have it in a kind
of a crazy their isomers correct and it
was the one thing everything we're
talking about is like the ability to
narrow the bands of what you're
capturing well if you cuz you're right
it's it's these little slices but the
only way that's possible is that we've
now created these massive machine that
will process a lot so we get bigger
trends you know we we see information
come out of plant material from farms
all over California grown differently
going different ways different yields
different strengths different compounds
or the makeup of the cannabinoids in
that specific strain like it's really
interesting we get to see a lot of those
so at the same time as we're narrowing
the focus and really like getting to
chop down into you know now we're we
just picked up a machine that will
separate out individual cannabinoids so
you can collect them individually
it's a centrifugal partitioning
chromatography this company called rodeo
cron
they catch it you guys okay yeah sorry
THC eight and ten are kind of like mine
or like other cannabinoids that we've
known about it but haven't been able to
isolate so on the market are we gonna
eventually see like THC eight tinctures
and THC ten tinctures in the same way
that we see other kind of my hair
cannabinoid totally and we've been
seeing mostly we've been seeing a lot of
THC eight cart hay in cartridges and
there is subsequently a decent amount of
Delta ten THC that's in there well no
they're just calling it if you're buying
a card off the traditional market you
they're saying it's one thing but who
knows what really is in that cartridge
right so but because you can take
garbage oil and by attorney by doing
this process to convert it to Delta
eight clean it up to make it look clear
a lot of guys do that ii buy a really
cheap oil get a little bit of a fraction
of that off and this really nice-looking
oil and then it's just cheaper the way
that that's produced then I like water
clear Delta nine it takes extremely
expensive absorbance and a process to do
it with the Delta eight you throw some
activated carbon in their flask and if
you distill right here you can get water
clear I mean there's a few other a few
other parameters to change but you just
dump a bunch of garbage in your flask
and then just mix it with your oil and
your oil is coming out nicely that was
what a bunch of people were doing to fix
their dark oil especially in the early
day
when people really weren't distilling
very well