Thank You Ariel thank you for inviting
me to participate and thank you for this
wonderful conference it's really
fantastic what you guys have done
I think I'll speak first to what I mean
when I say democratizing medicine when I
first said that I said people think that
we're trying to develop evidence-based
medicine from cannabis yes we're doing
that because you want to put
evidence-based medicine in the hands of
patients but more broadly what we're
trying to do is democratize medicine and
then she said what's that mean I said uh
the answer is healing is a noble art
there are many modalities of healing the
one we popularly called medicine has its
rules its standards of care etc there
are also other forms of healing and and
you're going to be talking about some of
them later today I'm sure but the
purpose of healing the purpose of
medicine is to serve humanity to serve
people not profits profits may be a
consequence of our actions but we make
profits the reason we're doing something
we lose our first principle we have to
help people and by democratizing it
means any human being on the planet that
is suffering needs to have must have
access to appropriate modalities that
relieve that suffering democratizing
medicine is primarily about access and
affordability - so that's what I mean
when I talk about democratizing medicine
I'm here mainly I mean yes I have a
title as something at a company but I'm
mainly here as a patient
I'm a 19 year
answer survivor I still have cancer
I took a drug every day that's oral
cancer medication it saved my life I was
three weeks away from dying 19 years ago
unfortunately that same healing medicine
has had Dilla tereus effects on my
kidneys my lungs and my heart so I spent
a lot of quality time with medical
professionals and I've become a bit of a
professional patient and that the thing
that I find is that patients need good
information and good alternatives and
we're often prescribed medicine that
creates more problems than it solves
you know I'm four I took good good trade
off for me I got to live for 19 years
but now I'm fighting heart kidneys lungs
but it was worth it but but the point is
I had to fight to get on the clinical
trial for the drug to start with it
wasn't easy
so I want to help people that's it I
want to put medicine in the hands of
patients and I want they'd help do what
we can to reduce human suffering
[Applause]
Sheila Sheila Gibson is the lovely woman
who's to my left I'm Sheila is the
founder of aura IP law she started her
career in intellectual property of a
nationally recognized IP boutique and
practiced at several top-tier law firms
during her first 16 years as an attorney
she's worked with clients in many
different industries such as biotech
medical cannabis food packaging
pharmaceuticals free technology
mechanical sports innovation beverages
and more to bring the unique combination
of strong science and IP experience with
a solid understanding of her clients
business needs rather than tackling
client IP objectives in a vacuum she
uses her client business objectives and
considerations to guide her I clean
practice and recommendations in order to
achieve reliable Sealand her she's an
incredibly brilliant lawyer and an
amazing woman and her bio
but I just would rather everyone here
speak because she's doing really amazing
creative things Thank You Ariel and
thank you for inviting me as well and
I'm glad to hear that you had the same
question when Ariel first mentioned to
me that it was democratizing medicine my
first question was what does that mean
to you and so after we talked about it
more it made a lot of sense for me even
as a patent attorney to be on a panel
like this and so Ariel mentioned that I
did recently provide comments to the FDA
and I did that largely based not on my
experience with what the efficacy or
safety data is because I felt like that
was really well covered by a lot of the
public I went I did listen to the
hearing I also went through as many of
the comments as I as I reasonably could
they received I believe well over 4,000
comments and so looking at that and
based on my experience with the clients
that I've helped in this you know
process and and well I'm not an FDA
attorney most of my clients do deal with
the FDA and I I do witness what they go
through and do help them and then on the
flip side of that I've also helped
generic drug manufacturers deal with the
FDA in terms of looking through the
orange book and in validating patents so
that they can enter the market early and
have some exclusivity for doing that and
as I was thinking about what my
experience was and what I could bring to
democratizing medicine because the one
thing that I realized about the FDA is
if they try to regulate all of cannabis
like a drug as they've defined it it
would just you know completely destroy
the industry and I think you know one of
the aspects too is that a lot of the
pioneers in the industry who've really
risked so much of you know their there's
you know
they've made so many sacrifices and also
professionally they've you know
sacrificed as well that it could really
destroy them and those wouldn't be the
people who benefit from you know an
onerous FDA regulation to come out of
that so my comment to the FDA was that
there needed to be at least two tiers of
regulation one based on a generic drug
model which I've had experience with and
that being that when you enter a generic
drug are you when you apply to the FDA
to have a generic drug into the market
you don't you aren't put through the
complete process of you know providing
your you know extensive animal testing
clinical trial all the data that you go
through for a new drug application
you're actually gone through an
abbreviated drug new drug application
and in that process it's more focused on
the chemistry the testing your
laboratory and bioequivalence and so for
something where they have so much safety
data I felt that that was you know a
middle ground that could be applied at
least to start and then to encourage you
know because right now what I'm seeing
is a lot of patents being filed a lot of
what I call land grabs where I'm seeing
you know these very broad patents
covering you know much more than than
what they're deserving of or you know
covering what's in the prior art because
we don't know what's in the prior art
there wasn't a lot of publications going
on during prohibition so we have no idea
what research was being done and so you
know providing a model similar to the
generic drugs where you encourage you
encourage other companies to invalidate
these overly broad patents and enjoy
some period of exclusivity once they're
invalidated and then let everybody come
to the market after that because one of
the things that I believe in terms of
access is that you know really promoting
price competition having more brands
more you know and that's really what the
generic drug Act was about was this idea
of you know you still want to encourage
innovation and there's a place for
patents and innovation but you also want
to encourage more competition in the
market
so that it can become more affordable
[Music]
his TV is actually 43 he has served as
the director seat of the super Sayan a
publication by part of myalgia rehab
program and actor scientific advisory of
yeah I'm happy to answer that but I'd
like to elaborate a little bit on what
John said because I think there's
another part democratising to run a
democracy you need educated voters yeah
so the question I got is education first
you know there's and I think I need to
bring that to the table Arielle first
recent ACR studies showed 90% of bar of
bud tenders across the country have had
no formal education so we're talking
here about other than the pockets like
Pennsylvania where there's actually an
embedded pharmacist generally the
patient who's going to a dispensary
doesn't really get good information they
don't have any easy access right now to
no warnings drug interactions if they're
on a blood thinner if they're on insulin
all those things are tentacle nergic
sudol interacts that's one the second
problem with this source of information
actually relates to physicians as well
and that is I think that I tell two
stories there's there's the when my
patients tell me they go to a doctor
before they see me I'm out of this
picture one person sees a doctor and the
doctor says okay so that's the end of
that discussion that's about 10 to 20
percent of physicians and Ashley right
now at least but by our early surveys
the next group is a much larger group
which is
that's cool I support it and the
discussion tell me how what happened
okay
there is a very small minority of
physicians you know in the country who
are willing to take the time to talk
with the patients about interactions we
heard a lot today here about titration
i'ma I do kind of like another approach
which is micro dosing so I'll start a
one drop increase to three by every two
to three days although really that's the
same thing I do agree we need to
individualize therapies the third
problem is the problem I get is when I
make a recommendation let's say for
cancer news news of nausea vomiting or
any or pain is when the patient goes to
the dispensary they get overwhelmed that
is really one we do not have we've been
hearing a lot about terpenes today in
California we have no requirement
because of the regulatory issues for
terpenes so I get patients who you know
I just lifted my fibromyalgia experience
I know I can do a better job but it's
only about 50 60 percent of my patients
respond sometimes it's because
quote-unquote it stops working oh it
stopped working or I went to a different
dispensary
and I got the exact same strain so the
issue is because we got the labeling
here I mean the good news is as you know
since this year we have toxicology
labeling and you know prior to that many
of the grows in in were actually had
mycotoxins and alike and we're there but
we're not quite where Colorado is where
which requires at least the major
terpene has to be declared so you know I
think it's really confusing my patients
say well you know I got this one here I
got it out of Colorado this high-end
link lie Molina and helped my brain fog
for my fibro we again information we've
got to make educated voters back to your
question cancer it's a touchy issue
there is that we don't really have any
specific data that I can say from our
CTS that says it helps cancer the
general rule is actually one is that
helps the symptoms related to cancer so
cancer douche nausea and vomiting our
classic ones that clearly cannabis does
help their several moderate Evans their
there is some case series there's a
local physician here in the community
you may know Bonnie Goldstein who is
some gliomas and children with some
success in case series but we don't
really have the data
the bigger challenge at the moment for
us as physicians at the moment is you
know a lot of the my patient symptoms
the lack of sleep the anxiety the nausea
really would be helped by cannabis but
I'm giving them chemotherapy with taxol
I'm giving chemotherapy with all kinds
of drugs you know cannabis and we said
is an immunomodulator are we doing a
good thing when we're mixing cannabis
and chemotherapy nude occasions are we
are we actually inhibiting the effect of
the chemotherapeutic agent maybe we're
even making it better no really good
data the preliminary data with a couple
of the chemotherapeutic agents suggests
we're not doing any harm and we probably
could combine but we need more studies
again this is a area of sparse data
unfortunately and but it's something
that we're all trying to face now in the
field yeah so I'm just saying if
anything I suspect it's gonna be adjunct
'iv not a it's not going to be a primary
agent for a given cancer you're not
going to give a cannabis compound you
use it in combination with
[Music]
yeah I want to point out for physicians
if they're interested that's a problem
actually UCLA we have a physicians our
website the cannabis research initiative
also through LA County Department of
Health actually have a a a list of
recommendations and rules and stuff a
the physician handbook for for
physicians are willing to consider
recommending cannabis so there's a start
but there's I don't know but we need to
work on butter's but tender
certification
[Music]
Wow
do you want to take that one I'm gonna
alright so it's the health care system
and medical cannabis the two questions
at the health care system right now has
a we're going through growing pains our
pharmaceutical as we're recognizing we
have some problems in our pharmaceutical
industries that that there's gonna be
some realigning that's going to take
place we're now understanding that
companies that have produced these
opioids are losing market share and
that's gonna there's going to be some
shifts are gonna take place and we might
get control over this over this disaster
there's no way to explain it it was a
failure on every single level that helps
democratization of medicine because
people are saying we cannot we're not
sure about those that healthcare
industry anymore we're gonna go try
things our own way and that's where
medical cannabis comes into play and so
I think that's sort of the where we're
at right now we do have to get control
of our ship we have to get control of
our our healthcare ecosystem we spend a
tremendous amount of my of our resources
are put directly into taking care of
patients but we're not naturally getting
particularly better so that's in
comparison to other industrialized
nations so there's some issues that
which goes back to what John was saying
about where we're in the original
thinking of healthcare was people going
after something difficult people
suffering and going after and doing
anything they can possibly can to
alleviate that suffering that created
our healthcare industry it created our
pharmaceutical companies
and it was just things were a little bit
simpler a hundred years ago and they did
rely on plants for a number of
treatments it was a it was an accepted
thing now we're now we've become now
we've got all these great assets and all
these great tools they now need to be
applied to this this new industry
there's there's no there's no way to go
do this parallel route hopefully we'll
be able to cult you know there'll be
some culling in the healthcare sector I
think directly related to cannabis and
directly related to how it's going to be
used as a common you know whether it's
immunomodulator or whether it's immune
system function whether it's pain
whether it's cancer these are these are
number of different diseases that we
just don't have good drugs to for so so
that's gonna be a natural phenomenon
so our health care system can kind of
prove it's going to take active voters
and like Jack Harris had two things we
vote and run for office do that if you
wanted to market eyes medicine you now
have you now take take you know take the
he'll do it I tried I ran for Congress
this year and I ran on a medical
cannabis platform and and it was
something because I was a scientist I
was like I can help here I know this
thing I develop I'm a pharmacologist
others there's ways to there's ways that
we can do great things if we just tweak
what we're doing and I think now we're
realizing the the institutions are there
the there's a there's a new breed of a
whole new style of companies that are
now coming in to fulfill healthcare
response you know to fulfill things that
we weren't able to we have to educate
our tenders and our and our businesses
need to need to up their game doctors
are ready you know the doctors are ready
we're reaching the point where we're no
longer early adopters this is now going
to be a part of our health care system
but as an industry we have to up our
game so that the patient feels
comfortable the doctors feel comfortable
and that everybody's together on this
did I answer is there anything
quite ready but the point is as someone
who also does clinical research well
it's a real there out there and I think
yeah the point I got when I put the
institutional review boards are
generally very antagonistic right now
they're about trying to do anything
related to cannabis there are you know
institutional boards are have been very
resistant I've had long discussions I
even had a simple survey took three
months to get approval but the point is
generally what would generally what
they're asking that any kind of cannabis
even hemp has to be kept in a locked
storeroom somewhere on the institution
you know or it has to is we heard all
the problems they're getting it from
Mississippi you know generally there it
is really very difficult to this point
to do a randomized clinical trial it's
almost impossible at the moment and that
point is if we're gonna get the
information we need we're gonna have to
reduce some of these barriers I'm hoping
now that the December 2018 farm bill
will allow us to look at hemp derived
products emptor i've terpenes that will
open up a whole new thing but the IRB
czar just a couple months off they
haven't quite heard the message yet yeah
I mean real medicine is always gonna be
a little bit slow it's that that's the
the the medicine doesn't come easy when
you can say like listen this works it
it's you know natural beings human
beings and plants were all they're
really complicated organisms and and so
that will you know that like we there's
some patients but now we can't we you
know there's but at the same time we're
all impatient because we have a we have
a field that needs to be built i the
clinical trial aspects are very in some
ways take away the democratization of
medicine and we now know this we know
our clinical trials are ridiculously
expensive and they're time consuming and
they're not getting the outcomes that we
should be getting and I think that
presents opportunities in this industry
to take to take some of what our
infrastructure is in the industry and be
able to do that type of you know we have
we have phenomenal testing labs that are
showing up that are that are complying
to regulations that are really
sophisticated like we're saying we need
to understand these these the terpenes
and cannabinoids and they do have an
impact on
on very important conditions we have and
and goes back to raising you know we
have to we are game has to get up in
order to be able to go to the
institutions and and and be able to say
hey listen how are we going to do this
how are we going to get that there's a
couple of the the federal government is
just starting to fund pain research
grants that's gonna be an ass that's
gonna be a real asset to get the
institutions on board
California has a hundred million dollars
that's over the next five years it's
going to go once the taxes are paid and
there's revenue coming in that are going
to go towards medical research and I
think those things will will will help
the cause
but yeah the clinical the clinical trial
aspects is a is a even even for a normal
drug there there it's it's it's brain
damage so we have improvements that are
being made you know hopefully faster
than you know sooner than later at this
point
[Music]
right so I I did that for a it's a
company here in well not any longer but
in Southern California and we started
from just one patent application it was
some research done at the University
that then was taken out and researched
further privately and we built the
portfolio and they were getting very
exciting results of course this is lab
results and then we moved to animal
models and they were still getting very
good results and in that process of
going through that you know I was very
we had built this from one single patent
application to probably hundreds of
applications that we were prosecuting
all around the world and I wasn't
overseeing all of that and that was
because they were getting such exciting
results and you know up next would have
been FDA you know they started their
clinical trials you know early clinical
trials to evaluate evaluate safety and
efficacy and and and how that informed
me was you know one of the and this is
why I became so passionate about what
the FDA is doing is because you know I
was I was I was very involved in that
work and very committed to what what
they were doing but then they had
another division of their company that
was also had an inhaled insulin product
that you know really looked promising in
terms of patient compliance where you're
inhaling insulin versus injecting
insulin and the the FDA process for them
nearly sunk them completely and it
certainly killed off their entire cancer
research division and that was so
disheartening for me to go through to
you know because that was all of my work
yet they just slowly abandoned you
one patent family here or another patent
family here until just the entire
portfolio and the unfortunate thing with
you know if you don't have patents
really are a tool it's about investment
it's about getting investors to put
money in and have a way for them to see
a you know have a the patents what they
do is provide them away so that they can
see how they're going to recoup their
money the exclusivity is what's going to
allow them to recoup their money and you
know to see when things are not patented
or something like this where all their
patents went abandoned you really don't
see any research done on them after that
because once it goes abandoned it's in
the public domain nobody's gonna want to
spend any more money on it because they
can't see a way to recoup their
investment and so that's one of the ways
you know that's one of the reasons that
I got very involved in in thinking
through you know a couple different
models for the FDA and it also helps now
because what I see right now in terms of
the work that's being done is
interestingly most of the patent
applications that are being filed right
now are not being filed by a big pharma
I don't know they're filing in Canada
but not in the US I don't know if that
is you know political reasons or they
just can't because it's federally
illegal they don't want to to do that
yet but I see right now a window where
people who are in this the pioneers in
this doing the research getting the data
you know if there's this window for them
to file for patent protection and
because we know what big farm is going
to do once it's federally legalized it's
gonna be all about an IP game they know
how to play that game and if you don't
have a way to either negotiate what
they're asking you to pay in a royalty
by well let me offer you what I have
patented or to defend against a lawsuit
then you're really just a sitting duck
and just waiting to pay royalties to Big
Pharma so in terms of the patent game
that I that I've seen the cancer
industry go through and and just biotech
and pharma
when it came to cannabis that was what
really motivated me to get involved and
to speak out and to try to do more to
educate all of these researchers and
companies and everyone who's who's
putting all of this work into it you
know find a way to make sure that you
have a post legalization strategy well
that's really pretty easy us the policy
US policy towards cannabis research and
drug development is boneheaded
approaching criminal and there's no
other way to describe it we it pretty
much forced us out of the United States
we have two divisions one division
cultivates extract sells products in
Nevada and we work with the in Louisiana
to with LSU for the patience of
Louisiana but a research side we we were
stymied over and over again when we
tried to move towards animal studies for
example so we finally threw up our hands
and we created a new company that's a
subsidiary of g/b Sciences it has the
very unpretentious name of GBS global
biopharma and and I didn't think of the
name but that's alright they convinced
me and we was and and we moved it up
there and created the company and now
and draya's doing our animal studies
with the National
search Council of Canada not only were
we able to do the research they opened
us with enthusiastically with welcomed
arms when we first approached them they
said well there's 25 or 30 companies
ahead of you in line and so we might be
able to get to to you next year year
after that didn't work very well for us
so I sent andreas small dr. andreas
small Howard our resident assassin who
went who went up there and showed them
our data and made a presentation on what
we were trying to do in our research and
they moved us to the front of the line
now that wouldn't happen in the US okay
I think the situation is more favorable
in virtually any country Europe most of
Europe not all but most of Europe
Australia we've had some pretty heard
some pretty good pitches about coming
down there and doing trials and and
there's a more important aspect to it I
want to speak to is that you know in the
US if you if you have a canvas compound
you do a an hour B test and you get F
results in efficacy and safety etc
you're almost you're bound to go to the
FDA approach pretty much if you ever
want to open your mouth about the
results from your your pilot study or
trial you got to go through the full
10-year billion-dollar often death March
as you experience to to getting it to
the patients that's ten years a billion
dollars later
that's why drugs cost so much right so
in Canada they do have a couple
alternative paths they're not
necessarily shorter they're not
necessarily they're not that they
require evidence-based medicine but you
have an alternative you can go what's
called the medical supplements at
route or the cannabis supplements route
which is new category and you can do
your trials publish your results make
claims and start selling it to patients
and that takes a matter of one or two
years as opposed to 10 it's a matter of
a million dollars maybe instead of a
billion that's Canada they're trying to
figure things out and help patients the
US FDA
50% of their operating cost are funded
by the pharmaceutical industry right
there they're in business to perpetuate
a system that profits the farm industry
earlier Michael said that you know the
farm industry like every industry talked
started talking about talking about
healing but that's just like politicians
starting out talking about doing good
pretty soon they get co-opted by the
system the money overtakes their sins
and and if anyway so if we could
reorient the pharmaceutical industry in
the u.s. open up research then maybe we
got a chance but right now patients in
the US are getting a bad deal we
actually got some very good
graft-versus-host which could save
children's lives could not do the study
we did the Phase two in Israel and in
about doing Phase three and the FDA is
aware of it but we wouldn't let us do it
here they have deaf ears right I mean
and here's plugged up with money
[Applause]
[Music]
one thing and then I want to interesting
you know there's there's marketing push
and there's demand pull if you if you're
a marketing guy you either
convince them to buy it or the demand
pulls it to the market the way we're
going to here's our strategy we're gonna
take these compounds to Canada we're
gonna develop it on a fast path as
medical supplements we're gonna get them
in the hands of patients one of our
compound is a Parkinson's two compound
all right let's hope it works knock on
wood
assuming they say it's efficacious we're
gonna start selling it in Europe and in
in Canada as a medical supplement or a
cannabis supplement based on the new
category we're not going to charge an
arm and a leg for it right and we're
gonna let and I I have just
gastrointestinal stromal tumors to
cancer after 19 years we 19 years ago a
group of us formed a non-profit called a
life raft group and it's to help
patients and font sponsor Research
Center what we were one of the first
online viral communities of patients we
got written up case studies and stuff
but anyway the point is right now every
disease state in the planet on the
planet has a viral support group so if
you go to Canada and have a put my drug
a compound that helps Parkinson's
patients every Parkinson page holy hell
raise holy hell nicely because some of
it so there's a there's a lot of us in
it you know we've gotta I mean it goes
back to this is we're improving our
industry and when our in when the
standards of our industry improve and
our businesses improve we're going to
start to get the attempt you know not we
we are getting the attention as a health
care as a treatment as a preventative
there these are words that get used by
the FDA as being as as as rejecting the
new medicines coming in saying you can't
do this you can't do that because the
thing is what hurts this business is
when somebody doesn't somebody in our in
our industry doesn't do what they're
supposed to be doing and then the FDA
says you're selling this product as a
treatment it doesn't even have what
you're saying on the bottle these are
the kinds of things that don't help any
us this is the rise of you know these
are the things that are easily remedied
if you just you know improve improve you
know there's there's a desire to improve
this industry can self-regulate and do
and provide good products then you're
going then then we have an opportunity
to do this in the United States and and
and you know we are we do already we
already have the opportunity in the
United States to do it the businesses
aren't are on the radar of the companies
that want to do the right thing I mean
I'm a farm
I'm a pharmacologist so I was trained to
go develop drugs this happens to be a
broad-spectrum compound that has a lot
of use we're still trying to figure out
those exact uses and how it should be
used and let's you've self titrate it
and think that but that's another goes
back to the demo democratization folks
are trying to figure out what works and
if they find something reliable
that's a patient that's always going to
come back and and be used and they're
gonna find the relief that they have in
some cases we are already doing this we
have an opioid epidemic it has to be
fixed some of the data on that's coming
out from from folks who study the opioid
epidemic is that cannabis is one of the
things that's relieving the opioid
epidemic that is happening irrespective
of Pharma it's happening irrespective of
FDA and it's happening irrespective of
of a congress that is still trying to
get a handle on on moving these things
forward
so the solution is have a good business
do good work
help people you'll get your you'll the
root the rewards will start to come and
it'll hopefully change our culture a
little bit because I know the my folks
that are in the pharmaceutical industry
they're not happy pushing a drug that
they got it created because you know a
ten billion dollar market because it
took a billion dollars to develop
they're not happy with that they're
trying to find and their question
they're starting to you know make phone
calls and and and and start to take the
conversations it's like well what are
you guys doing over there how do you
know we know we know we can help we just
have to find the aim and so in some ways
like I said be nice raise help would be
nice because there's some really good
people that are in these companies that
are trying to get their companies
changed and get them on a track that can
be providing better health care that's
cheaper and and and it's it's start it's
all the way up to the boardrooms right
down to the the mom-and-pop shop and any
many everyone I've ever encountered in
healthcare and all of my trials
tribulations really cared really wanted
to help it's the system that constrains
them and their ability to do so well the
systems suck I want to tell you right
now the institutions are they there in a
they they're going through some some
pains the government's going through
some pains the the industries are going
through some pains these are actually
the right conditions for opportunity
might and it just happened you know it
falls upon a lot of different things
happen to get us into a situation where
we're taking too many drugs we're not
getting help that we're paying a fortune
forum we've got crisis ease out of that
are that are that are not are being
managed by individuals and we're
managing the crisis so so that is an
indication that I mean like there's if
there's a thing about I don't you know I
don't want to make bad drugs I know the
drugs to treat cancer are very expensive
to develop but cannabinoids seem to do
the exact
same thing as those drugs that are
really hard to develop from a lab
perspective so I have great I have great
faith that we're gonna self right and
get this right and the right people will
be there and the right you'll have
you'll have your right attorneys that
are that are fighting for you and you'll
have your right business people that are
saying hey listen just keep on going
takes keep taking care of people and
we'll figure out all the financing to
make sure that you're stable and
sustainable in the industry we're gonna
have doctors that are better everybody's
you know everybody's fighting a battle
somewhere in their institution or their
industry or their government to get to
move these things on and and that's what
I would you know the profound statement
of democratizing medicine is that you're
all involved in this you know we just
have to be up here because like we've
that's who they said hey you know
something come on out you know but you
know that's how it happens you know you
go you know something you have some idea
you can lend some insight to this here
come up on stage you know but these
these are these are great these are the
events the microscopes and machines
these are the events that are that are
that are enabling everyone to get on the
same page and become a unified network
to be able to handle some big boy big
pants like I described in in a
conversation to the health insurance
industry it was like it's grown-up pants
put on the grown-up pants and
everything's going to be great but we
gotta we have to we have to get there
and and these are the events that are
gonna bring us together and you're gonna
find your network and you'll be like
okay there's there this is a very very
very long the supply chains in this
industry are just as complicated as Big
Pharma so if if you're if we already
have really complicated supply chains
and we're resolving those complicated
supply chains then you're a boutique
pharmaceutical company at this point I
whether you want to call it yourself
that and you know some people are scared
of that you know they don't want to use
the term pharmaceuticals oh my god
that's horrible but you know might the
definition of my job is pharmacologist I
can't take my training and say that's
not important anymore because it's out
of fashion what I'm saying is as a
pharmacologist go do your jobs go do
your jobs and and medicine will be
democratized
and let's create a new let's create an
industry that is better than the one
that we were handed
I'm gonna - I'm going to chime in here
because the the term that that it was
actually UCLA professors brought up was
clinical observations study where the
medical community does everything that
they need to do in terms of monitoring
care and if it with a with a reliable it
can't you know the conflicts of
interests removed and support of a
particular you know oh my I have the
ratio the miracle ratio that's going to
change everything then then that's a you
know that's a vehicle that's and it's
going to take a little bit to really
probably you know get that reliably but
you know the oncologists need people to
roof they need they need to you know
their college osorno and and pain
management specialists are in a pinch
because they need to find a reliable
business that they can refer patients to
now and and so so we are gonna figure
out some study things there's also in in
with regards to how we're going to
redesign clinical trials because not
only in the cannabis industry has
problems with clinical trials the entire
pharmaceutical industry is having
immense problems with their own clinical
trials so new tools are having to be
developed using
better sources of data better data
collections how do you recruit properly
how do you retain properly using social
media for good those peer groups that
John mentioned about the fact that those
peer groups help people get on clinical
trials and help them stay on clinical
trials and if we have to if we have to
if we have to design a clinical
observation study with an institution
that can monitor affairs and you have
reliable small business that is scalable
and can do it everything right
has the right tools that's a that's a
real honest-to-goodness thing that like
I said if you have the data and your
duty of doing your data right and and
you are perhaps making use of some new
ways to do clinical trials then that's a
model that can be that can be presented
to regulators and and and let the
barrier of entry go down to say you know
listen we got to go move and then that
lets the FDA and the powers that be that
everything's sort of shifts and
hopefully we'll have some you know a new
way to do clinical research because
we're there no I think it's great
promise but the problem I have is that
the whether it's doable to do clinical
observational studies and registries we
discussed it several times this meeting
but the problem is again educated
consumer my clip you know I'm used to
the big data we get by looking at large
databases but the variables aren't there
it doesn't really help me know about
pain management if the patient writes
down yes
cannabis helped me and it was Blue Dream
which Blue Dream which terpene which
ratio I mean that's the problem we have
we in order for the the clinical
observational stuff to really be give us
information we need we're gonna need to
have the consumer more knowledgeable
about what they're putting in their body
we are a big believers in patient
reported outcomes there's a the NIH has
promulgated standards for participation
reported outcome and how it can be used
in clinical research
there's even implicit compliant versions
of patient reported outcomes so what
patient reported outcome does is
leverages what you're talking about to
get larger datasets but the the key in a
PR Oh a patient reported outcome system
is the questions you ask right and their
own knowledge of what they actually were
dosing with but I think that's an area
that's very ripe for for development and
will become a bigger and bigger factor
in drug development and we're gonna be
be users of it
yeah we got to do a better job of PR in
our our first initial efforts and dejan
Evans who walked away from the tables
actually somebody who's had some
interest for example in the community
college course so there's a whole bunch
of initiatives that are just starting
with yes we're much more aware now we
need to educate but tenders and doctors
and patients and I think we need a
concerted effort the problem is who's
gonna actually pay for that doesn't
necessarily benefit any given one so you
know a lot of its grassroots at this
point yes we're trying yeah I mean I
think I think what I think we need to do
actually I'm horrible to say but
dispensary people if you can if you're
about a budtender you should be required
I believe to have minimum certification
to no side effects ask people of all
want to make head medications are on
there should be minimal knowledge maybe
not the highest knowledge but minimal
and I think with that debt just like
we're doing toxicology but tenders need
to be both better certified and
physicians we're gonna start out trying
to offer CME credit which drives things
that we can make it see it right now
it's not seeing me we can make it see me
yeah position
we have to work through our medical
local medical societies we're trying
that's I think you're right about
writing letters and and using your voice
and never under estimating what your
unique experience and I think that's one
thing I love about this industry is
everybody comes from a different
background and has a very unique
perspective I'm not an FDA attorney I've
just you know close enough to the
process that I I've never written an FDA
comment before but you know you when I
started writing it I realized I've got
this very unique perspective on
something and it's useful still so don't
underestimate what your perspective is
and the power of your voice and I think
it's gonna be a lot of letter writing
and a lot of you know urging Congress to
you know force the FDA force the FDA's
hand and I think that dr. Chad mentioned
about you know let's start regulating
some of these these terms that we're
using either with certification marks or
you know some there has to be a starting
point for that but I think it's all
gonna be about your voice and using you
know the unique perspective that you
bring to this industry yes on that on
this on this what what you can do to
help these things happen are well the
president of University of California
you can find her email she she happened
to be in charge of our Homeland Security
I believe under the Obama administration
there's there it is it's it's it is this
kind of act it's an it's it's it's an
advocacy that that does that that go to
the top people and go to the find the
list of Chancellor's and the deans at
all of them University of California and
say listen can you know what is the you
know what's your plan here let them
engage them and sense of you know what's
your plan here because this is happening
and I know there's a whole bunch of
there's there's a whole lot of folks
that could really could really use some
guidance on this and and show the human
eye you know show that there's that that
what they did the decisions that they
made at the University of California or
any other university system for that
matter cannon can help our communities
and with this you know with these with
this with this research that needs to be
done the medical boards when I was
lobbying and trying to get funding and
all the other things one of the things
that I said it was like the University
of California and the state of
California
can actually go to the medical boards in
California and say you need to give us a
plan you need to have a plan to to
educate your doctors on this and we're
gonna do our part by putting together
some curriculum for med school med
schools Hardman there's a lot of stuff
these guys to have to learn to fit into
one you know a couple of years worth of
worth of time but it is kind of they
have to sort of adjust like how are what
what course has to get pushed out of the
way but at the same time we also know
all the med students want to be trained
in this the scientists are looking for
jobs in this industry and you know it
just happens to be that you know the I
have know where my old alma mater UCLA
invited me back to go talk to graduate
students and I you know most of us when
we leave campus were like we're out of
here thank you
time to go and and and so these are
kinds of things that are going to be
there happening in real time and I think
maybe next year when we have this and we
have this conversation again you'll say
well we might be that much more the
further apart because some high level
people might've said yeah this is we
need to be we need to be doing what
we're supposed to be doing so I have a
lot of faith in the fact that the med
schools are gonna come around this is a
hero right here because he has to fight
yeah give them it give a round of
applause anyone any institutional
medical school professor that is trying
to make this happen is the tip of the
spear and all of this and they they they
have to work day in and day out to
convince a very large very difficult
institutions to deal with to change how
they go about doing it and they're doing
it one time one doctor at a time one
Chancellor at a time when Dean at a time
and and and and that that really is a
democratization and I'm going to leave
this to Ariel because now I'm talking
too much
[Music]
I'm part of the faculty advisory board
for the UCLA canvass research initiative
which includes professors from multiple
departments whether it be social equity
justice legal because we're working on
issues of social equity for dispensary
distribution for expungement of felons
etc this is a long long list and we're
looking at it from multiple perspectives
so it's important that we don't focus on
just a medical aspect you got to have a
university which can look at all the
aspects of going around and what is the
impact on our communities we're trying
to communicate with the city of Los
Angeles to say what are the positive
benefits and also try to buy social
equity ensure there's appropriate
geographical representation in
communities have been underserved