your babies which are your genetics that
you've read can you talk about kind of
like what you've read where you've got
like the parents from why you love it
how it grows how it smokes right now I
wonder should be your favorite today
because my favorite is the diamond dust
this diamond does was a so I actually
created something called the homeless
matrix some of mask actual that's my
background so I create a matrix that you
could use to help you make selections
based on terpene profiles is when you
start to look at turkey profiles and you
look at 40 turkeys variety okay
I know kind of that the spell is well
how do I compare all these varieties and
make a choice as a breeder yeah so the
homes matrix of something I just created
an algorithm we could type in all the
terpene profiles and give you points
into the direction of a choice that
suits you sure sure
like as a consumer or Isaac as a breeder
as a breeder like what I'm looking to
our producer to consumer also as like a
you know I'm developing varieties for
consumers cool we know Lori but this is
you're not like they like a not like for
like a medical bag
it's one experience with what experience
and you know a lot of times that is a
medical planning experience but yeah I
mean it's just whatever the consumer
wants us to develop something that they
like and it's yeah it could be relaxing
could be whatever it is those are there
certain Turkic composite scenes
geared towards them some battles we're
looking at those types of things so but
in terms of over of a variety that I
develop the diamond dust is one of my
favorites because it's the first drain
that I really got to use that that that
algorithm that helped point me in the
right direction on the turf inside but
it's essentially a double dream lemonade
bubble gum I rigged with sour bottle and
and it just it happens to be right in
the middle it's like between like that
really heavy Baba kind of sedative
effect and the really kind of like
uplifting sativa really balanced ivory
right in the middle and it's beautiful
in terms of like the structure it has
really high trichrome production
and it's a good yielder and it's real
vigorous introduction and the effect is
really balanced so it kind of has all
the trifecta the turkey means size the
effect has the aesthetic and it's been a
great variety we're running it
and everybody loves that's my favorite
constraint what's the trick
the terpene profile is um it's kind of
like a sweet Bubba but it it's mainly
limonene Jerry awfully near seemed like
most things
but that's a little bit of a bump it's
like a sweetheart
the funny thing is it's kind of like you
know breathing is a long-term project
it's only like one step yeah first he
was taken - yeah to get to like where
you want to go the intention of
developing diamond dust which diamond
dust is just one stuff in kind of the
progression to getting there I've always
wanted develop an OG turf profile a
variety that's not
[Music]
just because like that that that terpene
profiles so amazing Virginia Tech so
amazing but it just been inbred for so
long the structure is bad and sure
yields are bad so trying to keep that
same terms or flash to start fresh going
in a different direction
you know landraces whatever we need to
free that new structure that's more
rigorous you know that's less prone to
day and still on that term profilin ehe
highs and being from LA that's
Oh G is starting so that's that was kind
of the goal of the diamond does that
mean this isn't quite that but that's
kind of what motivated the development
and who who's been breeding some stuff
that you either want to play with or
that you have been playing with there's
there's a lot of great breeders
I love CS I'm humbled calculator
genetics I mean too many to name there's
a lot of great breeders doing great work
but unfortunately I only have so much
candy I wish I had you know a million
square feet
that's right that's what it takes that
it takes you to the next level really
it's all about numbers you know but
we're trying to be as smart as we can
with without the numbers that's really
all we could do at this it's you know
it's funny that's something that it's
actually part of my we talked to her you
know there's this by some folks in the
industry like oh we just need like new
molecular genomics and stuff like that -
like you know laser in on this thing
it's actually like what actually what's
the most important to breeding is like
looking at a lot of plans yeah yeah it's
like it's probably there's only so many
phenotypes or traits I have you do the
math on traits right you could calculate
out how many varieties you have to grow
to find the variety that's all right dr.
Chitra yeah I was trying to tell someone
this might not be the most artful way of
saying yeah it's like you know breeding
is all about how big's is your fun does
your funnel start out and like how
effective are you at selected yeah
that's that's like the slope of your
funnel right yeah and there's so much I
wish I can remember the
there's an equation to calculate like
the probability of varieties you have to
run to fine
specific traits right that's kind of
what we're looking at it you got a plug
the end and that's how many punch it and
it's big it's really big it's millions
quickly what was the name of your like
what your breeding that you like oh
diamond does okay so with diamond dust
was it just like happenstance or was
like did you just pop a bunch of seeds
and it happened you hit on something
that was a winner or well I mean
starting with good parents is always
important right so you know as a breeder
you're always standing on the shoulders
of giants right and that's all science I
mean those guys have been doing work for
30 40 years so you have to start with
good parents but then it's you know we
just said you have to grow tons of
numbers so there's some lucky ball it's
being smart as you can with what numbers
you're allowed
but at this stage when you can't run
five million plants there's a little bit
of luck
that's what's so amazing to me about the
breeding that's been done in this place
like you know folks that are like some
folks that are like helicoptering into
the space now like their first
perspective is like oh the breeding is
so like amateur and we're gonna displace
it along with it right right and I'm
actually like so impressed with but like
I'm like so impressed with the work that
breeders have done so far because it's
like you take these folks that have like
always been working on they're like
super limited resources super limited
scale right like and and they've been
like super resourceful right super
innovative super creative yeah and
that's what like to me I look at that
I'm like if you if you take that work
and you multiply it by a million what's
gonna happen oh yeah great it's gonna be
it's gonna knock our socks yeah the guys
come in and go through the helicopters
[Laughter]
you know if you introduce a bunch of
resources to it well I get you know like
the folks that have taken us to where
we're at today are gonna be the folks
that they're gonna take us alone
I wasn't that passion that's all about
me there's a passion absolutely
but with the diamond dust did you go
through iterations where you're like
it's close but it's not there and then
you kept kind of like tweaking it
iteratively it was actually the reverse
I was excited about the cross and I knew
it had really good parents and you know
putting the terpene profiles of the
parents through the matrix I was like
really excited about kind of being the
offspring and then like the first you
know 25 seeds I read I found something
amazing and then I was like shit I gotta
get back to that set of seeds and keep
running more and I've been running more
and more more you know hundreds and now
it's like that one's still the best one
so it's a little bit of what you talked
about probability you know run lots of
glass but I mean you could run a million
plants in the first thousand you find
the best one out of a million or it
could be you know nine hundred thousand
and fifty eight so you just you just
never know him but you know I was able
to put like also like you could look at
a billion plants and if you don't know
what you're looking for it's true you're
never gonna find a great one
yeah selection is also important and
that's that's where you know readers
experience they kind of know what how to
select
crucial aspect defeating that's what I
mean with that experience that like
intuition yeah you know that's so it's
irreplaceable yeah yeah you see guys
like choosing this big it's a biomass
reducer but it's not you know producing
right so it just depends also on what
the uses - yeah
the selection of the breeder is is very
important the ability just like what do
you think about for anything about seats
as a production system I think that were
obviously
a little too early to use these it's
like a full production system so I think
throughout door for my oh man
you know kind of like large-scale
extraction I think it's really
once we have better stability
but eventually I mean shit if I could
run everything I know I make loans every
day and I'm like so so the reason you
don't is because you know that's you
don't have a consistency that's right
yeah I mean you know like we're
launching a branded package company
products flower freerolls whatever veins
so this products have to be consistent
you know when you have thousand seeds
you run over
produce flour that you're gonna package
and it's all way different and that's
really kind of a sepia
in my box of seeds and other varieties
there's there's too much variability
because it takes a lot of numbers and a
lot of generations that get to stay with
seeds that you can write in production
well you and I talked before about and
we won't name names but well-known
California indoor cultivators that you
respect who when you try their product
from the retail shelves is not
consistent and they're probably cloning
so like what do you attribute that to
well that's a great question and I think
part of it is scale right I mean you
have guys that are
we've been growing for a long time they
do a really good job of producing
product and then the demand gets so high
it's like you have to start sourcing out
to other cultivators and then you have
different people in different areas with
different facilities growing the product
same genetics but the environmental
differences you know the temperature
difference is my adidas these little
differences especially indoors make a
big difference in the quality of the
body so I think it just it's more of
like I didn't accommodation to several
factors
I demand you know facility design is
different
the nutrient
all those things expected consistency
other but there's just not enough
knowledge of indoor cultivation yet in
terms of
environment stability lighting we're
barely starting to measure those things
and how they contribute to a picture
but I mean there's just that just the
holidays facilities are different rooms
are different so rooms are generating
different types of Rob