I'm going to read you three quotes
they're they're fast so uh some of you
in the house are familiar with some of
these people so Diane Goldstein from
leap which is law enforcement used to be
law enforcement against prohibition now
it's law enforcement Action Partnership
uh Diane Dian made an interesting
comment here she said the Greek
playwright escalus once wrote in war
truth is the first casualty his pres
summary of the nature of conflict and
power has played out on American soil
over the last 40 years as we have
strived to make our country druge free
it's clear that the industry needs to
recognize that they are not just
entrepreneurs but that they are drug
policy reformers and Advocates as well
and can help by continuing to support
drug policy reform organizations that
have been instrumental in rolling back
the harms of the drug war while
protecting all of our civil liberties
okay Lyn Lyman state director for drug
policy Alliance you're walking to you're
walking in today to this whole nice
legal world where everybody can wear a
name tag that says they're with some
cannabis Association
whereas 5 years ago even people were
still doing Federal time for having a
dispensary the advice I give to all of
those people to come who's coming into
the Cannabis industry is understand the
history there is the sense that people
are just wait Waltzing in as if it's
just any other industry I want to
discourage that and remind that you that
a lot of people have died people have
been incarcerated they've had their
families destroyed making sure you're a
good neighbor and you're working with
the community that you are based in and
finally
Kristen ndol who some of you may know in
the room Kristen is a chair of the
international cannabis Farmers
Association in
NorCal Kristen wrote donations from
canab businesses in humbold have built a
community center kmud radio the civil
liberties modering project local
volunteer fire departments technical
rescue and sports and art programs at
our rural schools that's a farming
Community for you she encourages folks
to get involved with our local community
by supporting and volunteering our
schools fire departments parks and so
much more need time and donations so we
are strong as a group but we need to
continue um further onto that