[Music]
what I wanted to start with before I
talk about myself and about my
organization I want to talk about the
drug war and what brought me here which
is social justice and I think we need to
understand and and go back not just to
1914 but to the modern-day drug war and
understand that our drug laws have never
been about the harms of the drug but
about who has been using the drug and so
let me read you a a quote that Dan bomb
uh wrote an article and if you haven't
read his book smoke and mirrors I'd
highly recommend it but this last year
he wrote an article called Legalize It
All Because from my perspective Mar
marijuana is the Tipping Point to get us
to blow up the drug war completely which
has been the largest AB failure of
policy in the United States since
slavery so Dan bomb stated in an article
the Nixon campaign in
1968 and the Nixon White House had two
enemies the anti-war left and black
people people we know we couldn't make
it illegal to be either against the war
or black but by getting the public to
associate the hippies with marijuana and
blacks with heroin and then
criminalizing both heavily we could
disrupt those communities we could
arrest their leaders raid their homes
break up their meetings and vilify them
night after night on the evening news
did we know we were l about drugs of
course we
did and so that is the single best
reason for us to clearly not just blow
up the drug war but to look at
proposition 64 that I will tell you is
not perfect but it provides a social
justice component that no other adult
consumption initiative or medical
marijuana initiative has done in our
nation so today in the United States we
make a cannabis arrest every 49 seconds
so whoever the mathematician is here
starting when this started at 6:30 till
when we in
tonight one person is going to jail
every 49 seconds almost every
minute nine states are voting uh for
adult consumption or or medical this
year it isn't just the five states that
are voting for adult consumption we have
Florida and we have other medical
marijuana states as well so this last
year in 2015 I think it's critically
important to understand that in the
United States we arrested
1,488 77 million people for all drug
offenses out of those it was over 64
4,000 that were for marijuana alone and
when we start
looking at the issues of the arrest is
one of the things from my perspective as
a career law enforcement professional
what I saw occur is that our drug war
policies has driven
a excuse me sorry our drug war policies
has driven a wedge between police
professionals who who used to be peace
officers and would work in collaboration
with our communities to mindlessly
policing people and causing the issues
that we see today so let me tell you a
little bit about who I represent law
enforcement against prohibition was
founded in 2002 by five police officers
four American one Canadian who all had
worked in law enforcement and again
recognize the largest object failure of
policy wasn't in fact our our drug war
since 2002 we have grown from five
police officers to over 5,000 current
former and retired we're not just all
retired criminal justice professionals
representing the spectrum of anybody
who's ever
touched somebody potentially going to
jail or being arrested for the drug for
for drugs our chairman right now is
actually in active duty Gardon in New
Hampshire who has one of the most
Progressive jail
systems that you will ever see we have
police Chiefs in the United States that
belong to our organizations as well as
tons of retired Das retired police
officers retired DEA agents not just in
the United States but across the world I
had the pleasure this year to go speak
in uh the United Kingdom when we opened
up our leap United Kingdom branch in the
House of Commons and so when we look at
what the drug war has done and why
marijuana or cannabis because I hate to
use the term marijuana is so important
for legalization I'd like for you guys
not just to look at California because
yes we've been very Progressive in
California and we've
decriminalized you know if you possess
less than and less than an ANC of
marijuana you get a traffic ticket but
one of the things that that recently
came to light is the drug policy
Alliance who is one of the proponents of
proposition 64 did a report and in the
last 10 years we have arrested almost a
half million people outside of those
infractions for not just misdemeanor and
felonies so there are still people today
going to jail for cannabis and so one of
the things that proposition 64 does if
it passes and I believe that it will is
at 121 midnight is anyone who's
currently in jail for a felony that is
now a misdemeanor what will occur they
can immediately ask to be resentenced to
that lower
misdemeanor for
people that have been previously
convicted and maybe have already serve
their sentences will immediately be able
to ask for their sentences to be reduced
or
expunged because we
know that a drug conviction is unlike
any other conviction there are
collateral consequences to it there's
Professional Licensing there's loss of
of driver's licenses if you're a kid
there's loss of Federal Aid to student
loans there's a loss of housing you you
may not be able to adopt a kid or get
welfare benefits or get food benefits
there is no other
crime other than the drug war that
causes these types of collateral
consequences so what I want to do
because I spent a career in law
enforcement there's Redondo Beach people
here there's Joan there's Beth there's
all sorts of people I I grew up in the
south Bay I grew up in South Torrance
graduated from South High and I think
for me is I always jokingly because I I
blog prolifically and I i' in I started
in this space in 2010 during the
proposition 19 campaign and so I've I've
seen the full circle that comes and I'm
encouraged for the future of where I see
not the social just not just the social
justice issues but where the industry is
is going because I don't see what people
are afraid of which is the alleged big
marijuana what I see is the validation
and the support of the mom and the pop
businesses the spa owners that want to
develop Spa products the cultivators
that are doing CBD water you know the
Edibles the the market is going to
expand and I know that there's this fear
that that adult consumption in
proposition 64 is going to impact
patients rights but what I would like to
say is that one of the leading attorneys
Bill Panzer does everybody know or does
anybody know who Bill Panzer is there
should be a lot of people he's from
Northern California helped start normal
in California one of the leading
marijuana attorneys has written an
article and he breaks down every section
of propos proposition 64 with regard to
patients rights and what he says is
there is no
effect if if the proposition
64 uh comes to fruition on patients
right and in fact it validates them and
in fact because I unfortunately have had
to take kids away from their parents is
it will
support a parent's right to not have
their children taken away from them
simply for being a qualified medical
marijuana patient no different than if I
had to take Viking
so I know that there's hope I'm hoping
lots of questions and and Jackie and I
talked is I don't want to just sit here
and talk I'd like to actually answer any
questions that you might you guys may
have from a law enforcement perspective
so for example if proposition 64 passes
is that law enforcement won't be able to
use the smell of marijuana to search
your car search your
house you know so so I'd like to just
kind of open up the floor to questions
and answers or questions and I'll answer
Peter
S so tell me something you don't like
about the way something within prop 64
that you don't like you've talked about
things you do
like you know I think that the concern
is over prop 64 that there's this
overregulation
and I think that there's this
fear that it's so so from my perspective
is I don't necessarily think that it's
over regulated but but H sitting down
with the people who authored it because
I've been to editorial boards with them
and I'm very involved in the campaign so
I want you to know when I came into the
campaign leap as an an organization
endorse it because it met our social
justice issues I wasn't necessarily 100%
on board and it wasn't until really
sitting down and and talking to the
authors where I've really come fully to
grasp it so I think that the worst thing
about is that people are afraid because
it's 62
pages and yet I would tell you having
worked in the space of law enforcement
and seeing how laws get made is that
this is not necessarily any different
except for one of the things that
happened is they had to address so many
issues of about around regulation so you
know with a tomato you have agricultural
components but the you know the
initiative also had to cover business
and professions and they had to cover
taxing and they had to cover where the
allocations of money went so that's what
made it long but one of the things that
I like about it is that there is in fact
flexibility so from a taxing perspective
it's at a 15% excise tax which is the
lowest tax rate than any other adult
consumption initiative ever so it's so
it so they took a look at you know from
a public safety p uh standpoint is we're
never going to eliminate the illicit
Market you know and nobody has ever said
um in in any of the ballot initiatives
that we were going to so I worked in
Colorado I spent a week in Colorado
during the Colorado campaign doing
presentations to Republican women's
groups about why they should support it
you know so stefon's right this is
really kind of a very interesting
bipartisan uh support it's not just
Democrats that support ending the drug
war there there is actually kind of some
liberty-minded Republicans that do as
well a and you know so I it's there's
those issues there's enough
flexibility that down the road that for
example is people are unhappy that it
doesn't repeal all cannabis laws but the
polling behind that is is that if if we
basically repealed every cannabis law
right now it would never pass and we'd
still be going out arresting people in a
very desperate fashion like we do at
this point because all of us need to
recognize that we enforce our drug laws
differently in weho in Redondo Beach and
comparison to South Central Los Angeles
or in East LA or in Santa Ana and and so
it's you know it it we have to get
people that don't necessarily believe in
cannabis it's not just about the the
people who are in the industry or the
Cannabis consumer or the patient we have
to sell this to all the other soccer
moms that I speak to all the time and
are absolutely petrified about this
issue so that's a long way of answering
your question I think that people don't
like its length
but there's not an understanding of why
it became that
lengthy well if I could just add to that
and we were at the state of marijuana
the other day and Betty ye from the
state controller was speaking and she
made a really important comment which
was that the Cannabis industry is really
the first industry to raise their hands
and say regulate us we want to be
regulated because we want safe we want
safety no number one we want safety and
we want to pay taxes it's not like we
don't want to we don't want to stay
underground anymore more so if we want
to be a real business and really exist
in the rest of the world then we do need
to be regulated I think no we don't need
to be over regulated but we certainly
need to be regulated and I think that
that was a consensus among the industry
yeah and and I think the interesting
part is one of the things that people
don't understand is that the fixes in
the future can't increase so for example
you have all the penalties you you know
yes there's still certain wobblers and
other stuff but but as we go down the
road
we can lessen the penalties if the sky
doesn't fall if everything works out you
know the money allocation for this is
very interesting one of the things that
happens is that for the first time is
money from um the the excise taxes are
going to go to communities of color you
know is it's going to start out at 10
million $10 million a year and at year
five it's going to increase to 50
million a year
for people to be able to it's going to
go to like the business Economic
Development people are going to be able
to do grants to start businesses or to
do education or jobs or other type of
infrastructure that's something that's
never happened in any other initiative
there's money that we're basically
telling the federal
government we're going to do research on
the efficacy in medical marijuana
because we're going to give money to the
UC system to basically I is research the
efficacy of marijuana see what people
don't understand and this is I spent a
lot of time in this kind of weird space
crossing a lot of boundaries is today I
read an article as belli the drugs Zar
admitted that our United State's
government has finally you know said
yeah we've limited the amount of resour
Arch on the efficacy only 6% of the
research by the national institutions
for drug abuse has gone to show the
efficacy of marijuana 94% has gone to
show its harms and what people don't
understand even in the industry is naida
funds 80 to 90% of the research not just
in the United States but across the
world and so you know is the the United
States on a global level has pushed out
this drug prohibition policy and it's
impact I I was born in Mexico City I'm
dual citizen I have I have a cousin
who's a a Mexican federali down there
and we talk all the time and we talk
about the issues that are going down in
Mexico president piano nto two weeks ago
basically stated if California legalizes
he's going to change the Mexican law in
in Mexico and asked for marijuana to be
legalized in Mexico that will reduce
death in the country that I love and
that's the thing about drug prohibition
that what people don't understand is the
only thing that prohibiting a substance
has done is empowered cartels and the
cops and I'm going to be very honest
about that it has completely empowered
us and it's contributed to death disease
and addiction in our communities and
leap exists to change that Paradigm and
and so but we need all your help and so
you know it's one of those very
interesting things I'm I'm kind of I'm
not a patient I don't smoke cannabis but
I'm here supporting people's right to do
so because I think it's a objectively
safer than alcohol because in my 22
years I never once went to a house where
someone who who was high beat the heck
out of their wife their kids or molested
them or raped and pillaged the
neighborhood alcohol all the time and so
I believe that the only harms and what
causes violence is prohibition and if we
ended the drug war completely we would
reduce crime in impoverished
neighborhoods because we would take the
market share from people that are trying
to survive by selling drugs and instead
we can put money back in there for jobs
education infrastructure Public Health
mental health programs all right who
else has a
question I I'm curious um what it oh
it's on yeah uh what is leap's position
on legalizing uh the rest of the drugs
heroin cocaine all that sure so um leap
believes that the regulation of drugs
should be a state byst state decision
because substance use or abuse or you
know regulating the Cannabis industry is
different in California than it is let's
say in New York but around the issues of
things like heroin and cocaine
methamphetamine or other opioids is that
we believe that nobody should go to
prison for
drugs if you commit a murder because
you're high or you get a car and you
drive under the influence or you break
into people's
houses right go right ahead but that we
should Implement public health
strategies so for example in Switzerland
they have what's called heroin assisted
treatment
programs long a and so if you're a
chronic heroin addict you don't go to
jail you get referred to a doctor who
prescribes you heroin you go to a safe
injection facility
and what Switzerland has seen and what
other countries have seen including you
know is uh Portugal it it was
implemented previously in Germany and
the United Kingdom Canada is now uh
nationally going to be be using heroin
assisted treatment program is that it
reduced
overdoses it reduced addiction because
by making it a public health strategy
encourage people to get into treatment
and from the public safety standpoint
the most fascinating thing in
Switzerland it reduced property crime 60
to 80% because you know why people
weren't breaking into our houses or in
our cars or stealing in order to get
money to support their hair their public
health problem so yes we are we want to
see com the complete elimination of
drugs going to prison and you know in
the United States that may be a very
difficult thing but I think what we can
at least do is decriminalize like
Portugal did who has seen some
tremendous results in their country
where you know is you can possess up to
10 days of any drug and you're not going
to go to jail for it unless you commit a
crime outside of it okay thank you we
got one here um as I as I referenced I
did online child protection funded by
the adult entertainment industry and you
mentioned one of the things they're
going to try to do is use you know the
fact that people are involved and about
child protection and I think it's going
to be one of the things that's really
very important in the industry for you
to address and come up with regulations
on because they will use when once you
say kids well so so so here's the
misnomer and and Stefan and we got a
couple attorneys in here that understand
it today in the United or in California
because I've I've had to deal with this
situation you can be an alcoholic you
can abuse prescription drugs and as long
as you don't endanger your child through
some type of physical endangerment you
have to be able to justify it you know
is is you got a mom that's passed out
because she's addicted to prescription
drugs and the three-year-old runs into
the street that's a reason to get child
service involved the problem today is
what you have is drug end danger
children laws that have been
incentivized by the federal government
and um what happens is the California
narcotics officers Association trains
the social workers under the drug
endangered children laws that were
actually started because of the
methamphetamine labs and they're now
using it to take qualified medical
marijuana patients kids away and so that
so they're using the law wrong you know
it's it's you've you've never been able
to just take people's kids away because
they're growing marijuana or their
patients the problem is is that people
don't have the economic resources to
hire attorneys in order to fight it one
of the things that's very clear that has
actually been written into proposition
64 is added protection for medical
marijuana patients so people will say
well why didn't you do it for the adult
consumption market and I say because
it's different in that that it's going
to be like alcohol in the sense of if
you're in your home and you smoke a
joint no one's going to be able to come
in and take your kid because you smoke a
joint if you smoke a joint and you pass
out and your kid gets hit by a car your
kid's going to get taken away so it's
all about responsible parenting and
public service announcements but I think
we do owe medical marijuana patients
that added prote protetion because we
have devastated
families thank you do we have time for
another one
yeah hi I hate these things um you
talked about or it was it was it was
talked about the fact that you could
have 08 or eight grams on each person if
they were pulled over by a
car so that's eight grams of concentrate
and you can have 28.5 gram of butter
Leaf okay is there is there anything in
prop 64 that says that a law enforcement
officer can't say that one person had
all this on them so that they can use it
against people who are being pulled over
so so so are so what you that's my first
question can ask the same second
question at the same time because I know
you'll probably talk about the same
thing and also is there anything in prop
64 that has uh that establishes a task
force or anything like that that begins
to see how law enforce
units in um neighborhoods of color or
places like that are using them are we
going to still up end up in the same
place where we have you know black kids
get pulled over for for grams and white
kids just go off to their party well so
so here's very interesting so let let me
say this about the kid issue one of the
protections that has been put into prop
64 is right now it's a misdemeanor if
you're under the age of 18 to possess
any marijuana it you know you don't get
an infraction like you do if you're 18
and
above so under prop 64 it reduces that
for our children so it's only an
infraction so you can't so our kids
can't go to jail for having 28.5 grams
or eight grams of concentrate or less
not only that but they can't get a fine
because if they can't afford it and the
worst thing that's going to happen to
them is they go to community
service on top of that for our children
is that when they turn 18 today your
records your kids records don't get
automatically expunged is when a kid
turns 18 if they have any marijuana
related arrest it automatically gets
expensed off their record and the kids
don't even have to
apply now that people are are are saying
oh my God the 18 to 21 year olds are
going to get arrested well I will tell
you that I think those 18 20 to 20 year
olds right now are incredibly smart and
they're going to do the exact same thing
that they've been doing since
Proposition 215 they're going to Coop
the medical system and get a
recommendation because we don't change
the recommendation language in any way
shape or form it's the same as Mera the
same as the language was in S420 and if
I had an 18 to a 20 year-old who
wanted to embibe in marijuana I would
tell them to go get a recommendation to
protect themselves from Criminal
statutes so that doesn't understand the
disparities in enforcement practices and
I think that's something that we need to
all be incredibly concerned about one of
the things that happened in Colorado is
from a percentage standpoint what you
saw is that the raw numbers of arrests
dropped
significantly across
Latino um African-American whites but
the problem was is law enforcement was
still enforcing the laws in a desparate
fashion what I'm going to tell you is
that um every organization that was
working in this space said it's not
acceptable but what this is going to do
is going to continue to shine a light on
the law enforcement practices that we we
need to demand change it's not going to
be perfect but I think it's we're going
to be able to get data because I'm a
data driven person and and continue to
hammer away on why we need to continue
to change law enforcement so I I believe
that there's systemic structural racism
in the criminal justice system I don't
believe that all law enforcement
officers are racist but I also don't
believe that you you have to
intentionally be racist to participate
in a system that has a disparity in
enforcement practices so that's what we
need to continue to move towards
changing it's complicated this isn't
going to fix that but it's going to go a
long way to addressing those
issues thank
[Applause]
you say your name uh my name is to
graani my question is regarding the
misdemeanor or the felony going to a
misdemeanor you said that people that
are in jail the next day September or
November 9th will be able to apply um
what can you explain what that process
would take do they need to get a lawyer
in order to do it would they have to
spend money and what happens if everyone
tries to do it at once how long it would
take them to actually be released you
know that we don't know that so so let's
say this on November 8th the drug policy
Alliance is in fact going to be hosting
a party and if it passes at
12:01 a.m. that morning they're going to
be holding an expungement Clinic that
they're going to have attorneys sitting
there and people are going to be able to
come in that night to start the
process so what's going to happen is
it's going to be a combination of things
I think that like if you look at what
we've done pro uh Prop 47 relative to
the expungement the resentencing issues
what you have is you have a ton of um
attorney firms that are working pro bono
with people like the LA Baker
institution with the drug policy
Alliance and other organizations that
are doing clinics across Los Angeles
County and relative to Prop 47 there was
a 2-year um window that you were going
to be able to do it Jerry Brown just
signed a bill that extended that for
another five years so what we need is we
need
attorneys who can help in the pro bono
fashion and then other people if they
have the economic resources to pay for
attorneys they may have to pay for their
own
attorneys all right well thank you Diane
Goldstein that was so wonderful thank
you so much you
[Music]