hey you guys I'm gonna go ahead and get
started my name is Heather Burke I'm an
attorney here in Nevada City I primarily
farmers and I sort of begged Jonathan
Baldwin and forever for me because I
could moderate this panel and the reason
being is that I feel like the
distribution component is absolutely
just fascinating there are some really
great things that distro can do for
farmers and do for the community
and I'm just excited to help build that
conversation today with this esteemed
panel I'm very happy to have so I'm
gonna start and just ask if you could
each introduce yourself and just tell me
like maybe you know in two to five
minutes like who you are who your
companies are what you know is unique
about you and just kind of an
introduction to like where you guys are
at in the sort of distribution services
and and how you're interacting with
those I'm with farmers and manufacturers
in the supply chain right now so why
don't we start with Daniella and right
here from thrive society Nevada City
boom boom awesome hi guys thank you my
name is Danielle and I'm one of the
founders of Drive society we're based
here at a Nevada city and we launched
our operations mid-january with
distribution it's been a wild few months
being out there in the different you
know landscape of the supply chain and I
think that I to sum up our mission for
thrive society is is we're here for for
the industry pioneer sector in the space
we all come from cannabis we all have
multiple decades under our belts
everything from cultivation nursery
manufacturing and distribution and
really love the plant love the way that
this plan is touching and bridging
industries all over the world bringing
in all type of talent and innovations
and it's a really exciting time to be
able to step forward and be proud of
what I do and be able to participate in
the transition globally one day here
shortly and we're a mission driven
company very much based on you know
sustainability and really recycled
packaging working with industry pioneers
that I mentioned and very sustainable
growers so a lot of you guys fit in this
space who've been doing
for a long time and really taking care
of the land while you're doing that so
we really try to partner with farmers
who are eco conscious manufacturers who
are also along the same mission and
vision and work with industry pioneers
across the supply chain right now we've
been focusing on bulk commodity
procurement distribution so that's bulk
trim be buds flour and different oils
and distributing those to other members
of the supply chain for their products
and uh it's been it's been pretty cool
you know we've been all over the state
procuring flour and doing a lot of a lot
of testing a lot of our D tests and
micro extraction tests really seeing
which counties are coming back
consistently clean and it's been very
eye-opening out there and over the next
couple of quarters we'll be rolling out
our first brand so that's exciting I'm
really targeting the medical space
wanting to stick to full-spectrum oils
and really ailments for patients yes sir
engines for patients and gelcaps as well
so really excited to get into the
packaged and branded space and
distribution and and access and activate
all of our retail accounts we also have
a bulk extraction manufacturing facility
over in Santa Rosa so we are working
with a lot of farmers with integrated
partnerships as we call them so you can
grow for a purpose and I can talk about
that a little bit later but there's a
lot of ways that we want to support all
the farmers out there and all the people
who have paved the way to where we can
can step out in the light and continue
to do what we love hi I'm Matthew
I'm with madrone we're based out of
Mendocino California where distributors
focused on bringing Triple A cannabis
directly to retailers and helping them
sell it and really helping them
supporting our farmers by again the best
price they can well at the same time
representing the ecosystem what is
Mendocino we've been we 60 clubs really
more focused and less than bulk even
though we've been doing more bulk and
now more focus on creating products and
working with manufacturers in creating
co-branded products and getting the name
out there but our end goal is
highlighting the high-grade from
we were based out of Fort Bragg main
offices in Mendocino and we really we
really focus on doing everything we can
to represent the farmer at the retail
level that's what we find that a lot of
la this game is is actually walking the
stores developing relationships with
retailers and then delivering
consistently and so that's something
we're focused on because we know that if
we can help farmers tie the supply chain
they only worry about farming my name is
Patrick King soil King and I am son
grown hands-down loving all of it I'm
out of cloverdale California I'm a
distribution type six manufacturing
nursery obviously delivery
transportation my wife has a dispensary
we just opened called red door remedies
so we do a lot of different varieties of
things right now we're doing Co packing
and different things and working as a
service our manufacturing type sticks we
do fields extracts we do the want ice
water hash in house for them we do some
just a bunch of different service stuff
I do pre-rolls and we we do a lot of
pre-roll brands a lot of service white
labeling for other people as well it's
white labeling it's tricky because I
have you got to use my employees you
know license the lights and stuff but we
found through the great attorneys in my
life one of them sitting right over
there for a number of years Omar we've
figured out workarounds in this industry
that is able to adapt cuz you know we're
the cannabis industry we're chameleons
right and we know how to shuck and dodge
so I base all my principles I'm also
soil king of the soil King garden center
so the pics in act I get the pit I'm in
the picks and shovel this industry I
sell the soil i sell i sell my genetics
i do free consulting through organic in
consulting i help the farmers produce
clean medicine i help them through the
harvesting curing process try to pay the
best
living-wage I possibly can to support us
as a team bring it back through
distribution through manufacturing and
head out to market across California
that sounds really easy but that's a
whole complicated nightmare right there
there's nothing no doubt about that but
it's exciting like we're doing this
we're doing it together and let's get on
with the next question well as an
attorney that represents a ton of
farmers I've asked some local
distributors to kind of you know tell us
what services that they could provide to
the farmers what services they're hoping
to be able to provide in the future and
so I'm wondering if you guys can go
through I mean some of those services
that you know it came up in this list of
the different services that distributors
could provide and it's like 40 different
things that distros can do you know we
have this stuff that's regulatory
mandated you know Quality Assurance you
know quarantined during testing
arrangement a testing arrangement
transportation required to be done by a
distributor can each of you guys tell us
like what are the services that you're
currently providing right now to farms
and manufacturers and what are the
services that you guys are hoping to
expand into in the future whether that's
the stuff that's mandated by regulation
or just some of the other cool stuff
that distributors can provide to the
service so if you guys don't mind going
back through each of you and Tony's
coming what'd you do on that list and if
I had service I would read the list but
I have no service and you know what you
do in terms of what your services are
and what you hope to do in the future as
you expand and grow and build in this in
this market sure so you know right now
we just launched in January and we've
been really focused on procurement a lot
of our founders have a cultivation
background and then we also have you
know site on what's happening out in the
retail market space too so in the
procurement process it's not necessarily
about just going to a farm and procuring
we are buying something anymore it is a
whole protocol associated with that
called quality control it's sorting
grading
sesang IPM integrated pest management
micro extractions and there's a whole
education process associated with that
so we've really focused on the
procurement we have a lot of cells that
we do for other distributors and brands
and the rest of the state and given our
background and location and our
connections of course and relationships
in the in the farming space that's where
we've started right now and have had a
lot of traction around that when I
noticed out there is the farmers are
really seeking that support it's it's
scary hearing that there's you know huge
farms happening in SoCal and big
commercial grows and everything's
automated and big out coming in so you
know being a support for small pioneers
as we call them or small growers and
Industry pioneers and really being able
to help them grow for a purpose so right
now we're rolling out an integrated
partnership structure for farmers out
there who want to grow for a purpose
this is going to streamline not only our
sales but also our vendor sells so what
I mean by this is we have a lot of
brands that we work with and they need a
consistent supply of a certain genetic
or they there's extractors out there
that need a consistent supply of a
certain you know phenotype or
cannabinoid ratio within their
extraction process some farmers like to
grow four tops some farmers just want to
grow buck done trim straight for
extraction so being able to be a nexus
in the supply chain right now and really
help not only farmers but processing
clients and manufacturers and brands
Network and integrate their systems
together to where the farmers are
growing for a purpose and then all of
the people on the other side of the ply
chain have that consistency that's the
main complaint out there you know
whenever we have you know forty pound
batches 50-pound batches of the same
strain it's really challenging in the
market for a brand to take that on if
they don't know that they have another
batch coming through regularly
throughout the year so a big part of our
focus right now is streamlining these
efforts and having farmers grow for a
purpose and and connect them with you
know where they fit in a supply chain
and where they want to focus their
energy within cultivation that's what
we're focused on right now and then over
next year we we really want to focus on
our own in-house brands and there's a
few different ones that we want to roll
out one of them is called lifted legacy
and this is very much focused on the
legacy culture bringing back some of the
old strains that we all used to grow
back in the 90s and and on back and
really doing what we do best and having
that you know that consistent access for
the retail market for the consumer
market and launching brands to support
that legacy culture as well so I'm
looking forward to the to the branding
part and the creative part but right now
I think it's really important given that
the supply chain the new white market is
so new it's extremely chaotic a lot of
people are just figuring it out as you
guys all know there's a big lag time
with the CDFA on cultivation licenses
that's really causing some issues but
it's also making the market prices go up
so that's good but I think that
everybody could really use support
within the Pioneer industry and if we
stick together and really streamline our
efforts and our intentions for the year
we can really sustain this way of life
that we love so much so for us it really
started with three years ago we saw
testing being necessary and so we
started pushing for phase 2 testing and
face 3 testing with our farmers way
before so we could catch any problems
then to become compliance helping and
then helping them with licensing and
that's evolved and everyone knows what
the issues happening that way now and
now because these are partners that
we've worked with for five years it's
now getting them ready for track and
trace and these are all things I just
fundamentally need to be done for them
to flow and for them to be able to to
have the velocity we want them to do but
I'll focus as Madone and my focus is
when I saw the drone before I saw them
doing I was working for corporate
cannabis company who just didn't
understand the value of farmers and the
reason I joined the drone and helped
help build what we're building is
because at the end the day I feel like
grading is everything I feel like when
you work with a farmer and you can pick
up the whole product and get them to
maximize the amount for every piece of
it that's when you've helped the farmer
continue what they're doing and that's
been our focus I focuses grading and
then velocity we saw that with like the
pot that everyone you just the triple-a
and now welcome to more and more
partners to grade and then peace out to
where needs to go because like as you
say Kent that this is an ecosystem and
people specialize in focus in certain
things and there's not enough people
focus on getting the farmers to maximize
the mound for the coop and I think
that's something that we've been
building and focusing on since the
beginning oh yeah we are we partnered
with distribution up in Mendocino really
I mean we took it over and who just
really they just would do nothing with
it and we saw it as a need and a way to
grow and build
you