I said because I need to make sure I can
I can get rid of product for my
cultivators and pay my cultivators
before I ask him for another set of it
there and they say well those are great
those are great strains they're gonna go
to another distributor I said it's more
important for me to write up to hand a
chunk of money or write a check to the
cultivator and and and miss the market
and not have enough product going into
phase 2 and phase 3 then for me not to
be able to look somebody in the eyes
that I love dearly and say I can't pay
him I'm sorry you know there's too much
of that going on but that was the right
decision at the table because none of us
and I could probably speak for all of us
didn't realize how large did how hard
the distribution model was gonna be I
don't know anybody actually if there's
anybody that tells you they know this
game she said in the beginning man turn
around and walk away cuz that guy knows
the littlest okay hands down they don't
know nothing so very difficult being a
dis in the distributor because you're
the middleman so and the other thing I'm
a broker like I've been broker in my
whole life right this is no new game
this is the exact same situation I'm
just I'm in bed I'm in business with the
government now the state of California
cities and everybody else but it's the
same game you know you have integrity
back then you always had the product I
always pay everybody pays up front we
pay everything gets paid in my channel
that's why I'm here today right it was a
bunch of money but fronting a bunch of
stuff on stuff I never seen so at the
end of the day I forget what the
questions were but uh you know I didn't
honestly she did say I think at the last
one which is important was what are we
doing now for the cultivator but what
are we plan on doing for the cultivator
next and I'm really excited to tell you
that we're doing remediation we're doing
flower remediation we're handling that
like this is going to be kicking in gear
pretty pretty soon here we're gonna take
care of a lot of flower remediation and
you know it's going to be another
service it's gonna go to me and go back
to your distributor I'm willing to work
with everybody it's not like I'm a
distributor that wants to hold
everything if you're a cultivator and
you did an hour
detest and you found some some powdery
mildews or some molds are some Petridis
or something on your flower on your Rd
test what do you do with it I'll tell
you all right all those other big
distributors out there gonna say yeah
it's worth 100 bucks a pound
we're gonna run it all into a BH no
extract that's where they're gonna tell
you they're gonna make huge margins
right but we're gonna help you
remediated and find a solution that is
still putting money back in your product
your pocket by doing a service taking it
back to you transporting it to another
distributor or bringing in one of our
sub or other you know ways of extracting
it so I mean there's and that's a need
that's a fit so and also pre-rolls we do
pre-rolls white labeling we do okay all
kinds of stuff I think this is why I
find it so fascinating it's just like
fascinating you know what you guys are
doing for the market and how deep it
gets and so it's super exciting and one
of the questions that I have is like a
lawyer you know we want to see a lot of
written agreements like what does it
look like the contracts that you're
seeing today with the farmers are their
written agreements what are the primary
terms like what are the just kind of
basics that you're seeing in terms of
these you know whatever the agreements
with farmers or manufacturers are as for
distro when do you take title when do
you not take title do you need a motor
carrier permit if you're gonna go pick
it up from them and not buy it so they
get you know until after a CoA like what
are the weirdness that you're seeing in
the actual agreement that you're
wrestling out right now cuz I imagine
it's got to be complex and so novel and
it's the first time it's ever happened
there is no industry that does it quite
like this so what are you guys seeing in
terms of those written agreements and
how does that work so my only experience
have written agreements are the ones
coming from our company the so far from
all the transactions we've done I have
not seen yet seen one document come from
any other entity so that's been really
bizarre as far as our contracts with our
supply chain partners we do a
consignment contract so we can come pick
up your flower or your product bring
that in-house have a target price and
then be able to sell that the supply
chain
we pay bi-weekly depending on what sells
that's one contract that we have then we
have a direct purchase contract so we
pay upfront you know when we take in the
money from the buyer and bring it into
our distro as an escrow obviously do the
QC and the rnd test before we procure it
and all that procurement work bring that
in and then pay the farmer so that seems
to be pretty black-and-white and
straightforward now we're developing
contracts around this integrated
partnership model that I spoke of so you
know depending on that farmers business
model they're all very very different
you would think it's oh you know growing
wheat but know everybody's kind of got
their own strengths in it so now we're
really trying to streamline our contract
for either a split contract toll
processing to where you can give me your
flower we extract the whole thing and
then we split the revenues depending on
the operational cost those comes off the
top or we can do an output model so
depending on the yield the grams that
come out the farmers get paid
accordingly that's another type of toll
processing and then there's a few
different companies actually a couple of
distribution companies that are industry
pioneers as well as a processing company
who's really moving forward on this
really unique model that I like they
have anything in the name of the
structure but it's they manage the farms
in a way where they'll come to the farm
once a month make sure everything is
passing test look at their IPM make sure
everything's gonna pass to us and
provide that that management service in
a way that oversight along with
potential capital injection initially so
subsidizing the farm with either clones
or capital to maintain their their
operations and then at the end of the
harvest it's kind of a set price per
square foot that sold back to that other
entity and then they take that flower
and either extract it or sell it for top
depending on the relationship so I think
it's really interesting out there
there's a lot of really great ways that
all the supply chain partners are
linking together and figuring it out
depending on you know whatever ones
focus is so if you want to talk more
about it we have a booth over there
and it kind of spells out our three
different models for these integrated
partnerships for farms and we'll have
our contracts ready for those very
shortly in addition to that we also have
a nursery in mindo so supplying genetics
and making sure all of these clones are
clean really offsets that upfront cost
for farmers to and just streamline
everyone's everyone's integration and
tensions for the year so we're really
excited about that and we need to keep
our machines fed we need to have exact
oils for all of our brands and products
and then the brands we work with need
specific strains so there's a lot of
opportunity to really sync up depending
on what your focus is and so where
you're growing for a purpose every year
so we've been moving towards more of a
once once once we receive COAS cashing
out then before we're doing in terms
model and so now we've contracts I'm a
presence a lawyer so she's been managing
a lot of that I literally just managed
law just the sales end so I can't really
tell you a lot of the contracts comes
from when were procuring but I'll tell
you that like we've seen an evolution of
like contracts with manufacturers and
about what splits in the mid what
happens after split one thing that we
found kind of hard figure out I mean he
was Uzi figure out but was Harlan they
didn't have the velocity was we wanted
them and take all the product and then
do a split afterwards because we're
distributor in sales and that just
became kind of hard so going through
contacts kind of figuring out where the
weak points are that's them they're
doing special involvement partners
[Music]
contracts are great handshakes are
better but contracts are great I'll
never give up the handshake
yeahit's we do a split for all of our
extracts we can do we do the split
there's a or we'll / do a purchase
number different ways you hit it really
well we do a consignment a consignment
first of all our contracts are thorough
they've been you know crafted and
created from our attorneys and they're
legit like they really are and other
attorneys I've read them and called us
up and said am yeah you not only cover
yourself which is good like I said
earlier we want to cover the whole
relationship with a cultivator too so a
lot of contracts that I've written I've
written
I mean I've written I've read are
completely one-sided that cultivators
are signing and they are losing their
asses it's bad it's so sad but there's a
lot of distributors out there that do
not care about you know that right out
the gate but there's some and I know
these ones sitting up here we do care
about you
probably why we're invited to this but
for for contracts we could do it we do
we started out with a 60 after after
testing was approved right but 60 day
payout or if it comes out earlier than
that it comes there's been at one
instance that we had some issues it
extended out but for the most part we've
we've held and we paid pretty pretty
well or before that we did do some we
have purchased contracts as well for
those you know great value you need to
get rid of something you know we have a
purchase contract set up and then the
same thing with the extracts we do a lot
of different biomass contracts you know
I have a lot of different markets for a
lot of different things to land but the
problem is logistics and and price point
and negotiating that at the
manufacturing level for for a biomass
and all and everything's so change
there's no model that's been set or
created yet and for me I self I'm
self-made right I don't have any there's
no venture capitalist you know on me
whatsoever every penny
ever made I threw it in front of me and
I'm standing here today still owning
myself so I'm not sitting where I can
write a you know 200 thousand dollar
check to buy a cultivators product up
front but I'm also gonna pay you within
the time of the contract so you know
it's it's still it's a crazy it's a
crazy model out there there's everything
and it's ever it's it's always changing
I'm sure you guys can see us what worked
two weeks ago is totally different now
right because it's it hasn't been done I
don't care what distributor who has 30
years in the alcohol industry and he's
telling you he knows what they're doing
or she knows what they're doing yeah
this industry hasn't been done if one if
a person says I've been in alcohol
industry and I know distribution walk
away immediately walk away I think to
one of the things that really concerns
me sometimes as some of the distributors
or purchasers it doesn't necessarily
need to be a distributor where the
contracts don't make sense like they're
not written in plain language they're
run in very legalese it's hard to like
connect with usually that's a red flag
to me like if we can't understand it as
just humans you know it sounds nada
songs not right so it's something to
think about in terms of like looking at
contracts and also having a distributor
who's willing to negotiate those terms
with you because like you said you know
we're here for the first time like
nobody's done this before so you know we
can present some kind of language but
doesn't necessarily mean that when we
present it and somebody says well what
about this scenario you know we haven't
thought about that scenario so we think
about it together and then we create
something together that works for all of
us that's kind of how I feel those good
relationships are going to be born out
you know it's recently seen a distro
contract that said they had a 40% on
their contract disto dystrophy 40%
they held 200 pounds and couldn't get
rid of it I'm taking the product away
from that district I'm not going to name
it what it is but what are the other
douchebags in the industry okay so it's
time for us to get off but just a quick
closing thought like are you guys seeing
any trends and distribution anything
that you're seeing that is a positive
it's a negative what do you guys see you
just like a two-second summary of what
your company
it's providing and what you guys see
we're going for the future and just
something that we can kind of latch on
to and look forward to in the future
yeah I'm really excited to see a lot
more collaboration last year you know
with coming out of the shadows as you
call it it's really nerve-racking for a
lot of people who've been in the space
not only that but seeing all the big
capital coming in the new companies
coming in and everyone's really used to
being very private
not necessarily trusting and really
working by themselves over the last year
I've seen that dramatically shift people
are coming together in cooperatives as
Hezekiah was talking about other supply
chain and stakeholder partners who were
sharing information and linking arms
together a big distributors that are all
pioneers want to work with only the
pioneer companies and really stick to
that model so I'm really really happy to
see the collaboration I think it's one
thing that has been missing in the last
couple of decades that I've been in
cannabis in a way of really sharing
resources creating coops for
efficiencies and what you're purchasing
streamlining genetics and really keeping
that operational cost as low as as
possible at the end of the day it's very
important for cultivation so I am
excited to see that people coming
together I think Humboldt has really led
the way in that regard and they were one
of the first counties to allow
cultivation and I've got several events
up there and the hcg a the humble
Growers Association and you see these
just old-school farmers coming together
and it's stronger together you know is
that mission and we've really are so
they've really paved the way and it's
exciting to see Nevada County now taking
steps towards that as well I'm excited
to see who's you know come forward and
got licensing and we're here to support
we're based out in about a city happy to
have anybody come in and talk to any of
us about ways that we can plug in
together and integrate your farms and
with all of all of the sales and the
supply chain efforts so thank you
you