[Music]
let's talk about that purple panty
dropper what is it why is it in
everything well you know that so the
story behind that stream which sometimes
it's not great for me to mention it
because it's not super politically
correct but the purple panty dropper was
something that you know it came from
some sort of hill seeds I kind of call
it some some friends some old time
growers and humble and actually Southern
Oregon - yeah and I crossed it with
purple haze and
Matanuska mist and eventually it just
kind of worked its way into our breeding
program and you know a good breeder
should have kind of like a stud that
they really do yeah and that's what it
is for you it's your mail well it's not
anymore okay it was for you know back in
the early 2000s and you know up to 2010
we used a lot of it but the reason that
we named it that isn't because we you
know are like - anyway it's it's not a
PC name but the purple panty-dropper got
named
when there was a party at the farm and I
woke up in the morning I didn't even
partake in the party and I woke up in
the morning and walked up to the garden
and and sure enough there's this pair of
purple panties like right there at the
top of the trail in this little circle
of open clearing and of course there's
you know plenty of purple budding plants
all around it right I went down to the
party which was still happening and said
you know I got a good good name for a
strain now but formerly it was known as
purple passion so I guess it's always
kind of inspired passionate behavior
whether it was panty-dropping or
just being happy and and so you you've
crossed that into a lot of varieties
over the years and you know the
interesting thing about like when you're
really full disclosure about how you
breed a strain I mean if you whether
something is still relevant is is
another question like will tell
everybody what we've used to make the
variety but it may not be necessarily
very relevant anymore so if it was
originally made with purple
panty-dropper or you know blueberry
muffin but then it's had you know lots
of back crossing happen like any true
good breeders should be doing to provide
like a consistent uniform
seed line then it won't really you know
display a lot of characteristics of some
of those early crosses that you used to
create it sure while you know it's still
you know full disclosure to mention it
and and it's standard practice to and in
cannabis industry you see a lot of folks
who are like this is you know blah blah
blah times Green crack times you know og
or whatever and that's doesn't
necessarily mean that you're just gonna
pick up a bud and smoke it and be like I
taste Green crack and then you know a
hint of OG it might be something
completely new if you've spent some time
working with it so absolutely I mean
we're talking about hybrids of hybrids
hybrids you see these recessive genetics
come out like what was that almost some
obscure trait in one of the great
grandparents or whatever right and
that's why you know we like to reference
the genetic variation that's you know
sort of the hetero homozygosity that you
can find out through genetic analysis
using like FiOS bioscience or a number
of the different
genetic research services that are
available now to cannabis you can
actually like go ahead and submit a seed
line and they'll tell you exactly how
diverse or uniform the offspring will be
so and a lot of our stuff you know we're
pretty proud that it's really really far
into the uniform on the uniform end of
thing the spectrum rather than the
diverse and that said you know like gosh
six seven eight nine ten twenty years
ago we had a lot of diversity in our
varietals and since we've been around
and humble for a long long time you know
sometimes I get some shit about that
people would be like you know you you
use the same you know purple panty
dropper or whatever and I'm just like
hey you know try us give us a try again
five years ten years after you you know
had diversity in your in your garden and
any seed these you know there's really
at this point in time there's really not
any such thing as like a true breeding
cannabis seed when you compare it to
like a major agricultural crop like corn
that's been focused on for you know a
hundred plus years by breeders like with
a scientific method and and breeding
strategy the traditional breeding
practices and and now you know genetic
markers marker assisted breeding and and
you can really have like a row of corn
or an acre or ten acres a corn that are
almost completely identical plants you
know even genetically they're you know
not much drift in the population whereas
with cannabis we just haven't really
gotten there yet and that's something
that we've been really working on over
the last five or six years internally is
making in
red lines and then doing you know real
f1 hybrids rather than you know what
everybody refers to as as an f1 or an f2
or f3 they're not actually you know in
conventional agriculture that wouldn't
be even something that anybody would
even share with the public you know it's
still the realm of fallen chucking at
that point further absolutely yes and
don't get me wrong like we are on camera
and on a microphone up and some I don't
have anything against breeders that do
that that's how I started out I mean you
know if you're misrepresenting it in
some way then maybe that's not such a
good thing and it does can give seed
growing you know kind of a bad name a
little bit I've gotten some of the most
phenomenal product ever out of
completely random crosses you know
friends a friend have done right I mean
kind of bash against it it just touches
on a word that you use that came up
earlier when I was talking with Beth yes
stability right and what stability means
and stability has until recently at
least in my world referred to the
ability for one seed to be similar to
another and you have a line and
especially when we're growing these big
plants that oh yeah part of this one can
be matched up with this other in the
finished product exactly well that's
that's a big thing that we that's the
goal is like we started saying you know
we guarantee you can walk down the row
and of course this is subjective because
it's up to everybody's opinion sure but
cut and throw it into the same bin and
you know that said one of the hardest
things that I've noticed to nail down is
the level of anthocyanin yep in each
plant and that is kind of been sort of
at least one of our golden Grails is
trying to breed a strain that is like
purple every single time yeah that's
like the same degree of purple every
single time right and like our blueberry
muffin strain
that one just you know it continues to
elude us like getting the purple super
consistent the smell on the other hand
like every single time is a blueberry
muffin smell I mean absolutely that's
that's what I've seen in growing it it's
just it's a it's a color difference when
it comes down to the end yeah and how
the color comes in whether it comes in
very much at the end right or whether it
almost starts all yeah and that's gonna
be the case whenever you have purple
cannabis you're gonna have potentially
like the top of the plant or the
Southside might get purple quicker and
the north side not at all yeah you're
gonna have a variable degree of the
purple pigment no matter what so it's
just something to keep we're gonna keep
working on it and but it is it's like
that's the crux of seeds and clones and
breeding and that whole thing is I think
but then what you said like distinct
what we call distinct population crosses
so purposefully being like well I'm
gonna take something that is way over
here from you know Columbia Jamaican
land race and cross it with something
that's much more common and and you know
sort of westernized or American
that's gonna produce a vast array of
diversity in the progeny and then the
likelihood of finding something amazing
is actually increased when you have that
kind of a you know spread of diversity
and but that on the other hand the
likelihood of having something that's
kind of I want want want is also
increased so the more diversity the
higher your chances are of finding
something really cool and the higher the
chances are of having you know a few
entire plants that you grow
just like oh man this is gonna be like
the hardest stuff to sell and so it's
not like what any commercial grower who
wants to be doing and that's why we did
that giant phenotype huh our phenotype
mega hunt project this last summer where
we like looked through 10,000 cannabis
plants you know ten different licensed
facilities throughout the state and
tracked it and we have our own gas
liquid chromatograph so we can test it
and you know we got our data spreadsheet
that we enter all the info and it was a
lot of goddamn work like man I still
like that's why I'm late kind of getting
here like we're doing that right now I
got my family is watching after all the
babies and and helping keep them happy
but we've narrowed them down
significantly so it went from ten
thousand three months ago you know over
the course of the summer ten thousand
cuttings off ten thousand unique plants
quickly you know narrowed it down after
depth you know we we essentially want to
get it down to the best 1% and then from
there you know really now we're like the
best point five percent which you know
so we really want to end up with 50
keepers yeah absolutely
and I mean I think as far as the
stability of the seed stock goes there's
there's kind of two different schools of
thought as what are you doing with the
seeds are you growing them in the nature
that like you're talking when you talk
about stability in these rows you're
talking about seed plans outdoor big
picture planning the plant to be the
plant that it is versus other people who
are saying no I'm taking this seed stock
and I'm doing a fee know hunt with it
and I'm finding the keeper yeah maybe
the two keepers but typically just the
best of the best in their eyes and in
that how great instability really versa
is having a potential to have the one
that's that's so fabulous we have two
programs essentially in the way we breed
one is looking for diversity and that's
the quickest and easiest program you
just take something that's really
different random and you want to mash it
up and you mash it up and you produce
seeds and then you plant them and hunt
through them so that's the really simple
one we never like sell those seeds for
example there sure you know we give them
and share them openly with people that
want to participate in that process and
then the the hard work is stabilizing
something that you've already sort of
identified as being unique and special
then creating a long you know true
breeding line which we're still little
ways from getting to true breeding but I
think you know we're there with some of
our lines to where you can walk down the
row and you know harvest into the same
tote from plant to plant and that's the
idea so another thing we were talking
about earlier but just it's a perfect
kind of segue into this first ability is
the use of the word stability is that
we've always used and when I say we I
just mean my my smaller community within
within this bigger community yeah is
that we use it in reference to what
you're talking about which is that this
one looks like the other and in recent
times with the kind of with all of the
feminized stock going on with all of
that that we've started to see the word
stability refer to its propensity to
hermaphrodite right yeah yeah I noticed
that as well I always assumed that it
would just refer to like the uniform
nature of the rise so that's how we've
always kind of referenced it but I do
I'll get people being like oh yeah so it
doesn't ever hermaphrodite and I'm like
shit if it if anything has a propensity
to hermaphrodite we get it out the door
as quickly as possible so it
you're not in school that that's that's
the good stock that's the pollen source
for the know I saw that post did you see
that recent post I won't mention who it
was but one of the you know one of the
cannabis is pioneers it a really great
person this a little bit maybe missing
misinformed about that was said you know
oh if you have a plant that starts to
hermaphrodite onto you don't throw it
away because you can make feminized
seeds with it and I was just like oh
because and that was like a post it went
all over the place people were like oh
so you know I can keep my hermaphrodite
plants and use any pollen that they
produce to just makes seeds and
basically cannabis is a dioecious plant
which means that it has male and female
parts on separate plants they're not on
the same plant right like an example of
a manisha plant would be corn so you've
got the tassels that produce a pollen
that falls down onto the silk which is a
pistol of a flower which then produces
seeds so that's a Manas cannabis is a
dioecious but many dioecious plants like
cannabis have the capability as an
evolutionary you know like last-ditch
effort to produce the opposite sex organ
if it has noticed it's like you know if
there are stresses or you know all
different kind of things and some of
them have a propensity to do that which
are hermaphroditic varieties and some of
them just can get stressed out enough or
of course there's making sex reversal of
a plant which essentially involves
introducing an ethylene inhibitor that
actually keeps the plants natural
hormone
allowing it to produce female parts for
example and therefore it produces
default which is male so every plant has
the the DNA that that it takes to be a
male or a female but they there's a
switch that essentially you know is
assigned at conception that you know
would make the plant turn one sex or the
other and if the if this even if the
switch is on and like an at an ethylene
inhibitor is introduced then it'll just
go to default which would be male and so
that's where you get the creation the
proper creating creation of feminized
seeds cryo and and there's people that
want to do that with like one specific
strain that has a propensity to
hermaphrodite you know I would say that
that's something that should be frowned
upon and there's a lot of folks that are
doing it you know properly but I think
the biggest thing is that we should
avoid there is the possibility that if
enough like you know misguided breeding
happens that cannabis could start to
evolve into more of a Manas which would
be real shitty because we'd never have a
sense of me anymore so I think it is
important that people understand this
and don't like you know go you know
breeding with just any hermie pollen you
know that's absolutely and so you know
and give I'll give the guy a break
who did that big post I mean he's got I
don't even know a million followers or
something like that but I was just like
no and a bunch of other folks oft on
there and they were like no no like we
don't want people to think that it's a
great idea to just take a hermaphrodite
plant
and and breed with that because the
seeds will be mostly female or all
female that's the worst
exactly yeah well and as far as their
hermaphrodites go I don't know how much
you've worked with plants that show
hermaphroditic tendencies but what what
we see is kind of two distinct paths
that go down one is when it shows it
early on in the beginning of flowering
coming off an apical calyx versus later
on showing it through the flower and
expression of that that same you know
like you're saying like the banana that
comes out at the end you know so I
totally agree this is a very interesting
subject to me and I've been talking with
a lot of people about it in just in the
last couple months so I do believe that
there are two types of hermaphrodites in
cannabis one is a little bit more
genetically inherent and the other one
may just be related to environmental
stressors so like what you refer to
where you've got you know full-on male
and female parts coming out early on in
the stage in flowering stage well that's
obviously I would say you know more of a
genetic inherent hermaphrodite and then
when you have plants that will produce a
little banana
I call it essentially it's an anther
yeah that comes out of the plant at the
end of flowering that's more because you
know this female cannabis plan is like
you know sure there's no good I'm gonna
make my own that's you know some of the
questions we kind of have as we go
through these various these various
stocks that we that we work with where
we have some varieties that it doesn't
the extreme temperature and humidity
differences we have and the differences
in nutrients and even more extreme
stresses like in light depth of having
some of the issues that we see we have
these these cultivars that they don't
really express this and then in working
and I hate to say but I've seen it go
way up as I've started to work more with
feminized stock and I I'm not gonna sit
here and make any statement that I could
see that that's a hundred percent what's
causing it but interestingly enough I
did a phenyl hunt last year in two
separate spaces one in door one in the
greenhouse and I saw more stress
initially in the greenhouse more
variables and a higher percentage of
them show hermaphroditic tendencies we
got rid of all of that we went back to
our mom stock that we taking cuttings
off of and brought forward ones that
didn't show anything as we go forward
now we're not seeing any apical calyx as
throwing hermaphroditic flowers because
we got rid of those but we're seeing
some of the other varieties now that
express at the very end of flowering
they're throw they're throwing this out
yeah and I mean to me like the ones that
throw out the bananas at the end it's a
little less concerning overall for like
the whole species like sure you know
like obviously it's not something that's
desirable at all but you know I don't
think the trimmers don't like it yeah
yeah
but here's an interesting thing that I
noticed this year is we did a ton of
landrace breeding and crossing just
growing pure landraces or whatever we
ended up going to Jamaica last year
Ethiopia and then of course we had that
Willie G's seed that Willie had brought
back from Lebanon and
and a few more too but anyway these ones
that add when people sail and raise
different kind of definitions of that
but I'm talking like landrace like
redline that well so in bread and and
selected by nature not even as much by
breeding so like wild populations or or
populations see you above populations
that essentially just the the selection
is is natural so you know it's it's an
isolated population the selection is
less based on somebody doing fee know
one thing for example and more just like
what grows best in Jamaica you know what
what works in a giant field and Lebanon
that we can get the most hash with the
littlest least effort you know so yeah
like and that's kind of like I mean
eventually who knows you know cannabis
hopefully just is treated like you know
any other crop tomato or whatever and we
can grow as much of it as we want
someday and then you know maybe as a
breeder I'll be like yeah what is
something that we can throw in a giant
field and forget about it and come back
you know six months later and whether
they're seeds or not we don't care we're
gonna make a oh man bio and hash and you
know we're gonna get all the different
uses from it so land race can mean
different things but these these I would
say are the most purest form they're
both isolated and they're selected by
nature and so bringing those back that
actually we I noticed like those have a
higher propensity to throw those little
nanners at the end of the season now
none of them were full-on you know
displaying both sexes like you're
talking about where you have more of
like this manisha Stipe
but they were definitely like commonly
showing bananas what do you look for in
a seed company passion love love love
for the plan it's what I look for in in
anyone that I work with in this
community like we all got families to
feed we all want to have a decently
comfortable life I was like I'm not
gonna play some game of being 100%
altruistic all the time but that money
doesn't and in my opinion shouldn't come
first all the damn time and how kind of
short-sighted it is when people are
constantly putting that that dollar
first and I just I like to see that the
people would genuinely enjoy the plan
that's great I love hearing that and I
wholeheartedly agree you know I always
tell folks like well you know we get a
ton of people that are like we'd love to
work with you or whatever and I i don't
ever say like oh they don't have enough
Instagram followers for me to bother
working with them or some dumb bullshit
like that I try to meet people and
decide like how you know smart and
passionate is this person and that's the
only thing I care about you know like if
you're smart and passionate about
cannabis and and wanting to you know
work in this space and and improve
things and and share in medicine and and
the fucking love for the plant and I you
know you have a half a brain you know if
you're an intelligent person you're
clearly an intelligent person so let's
work together
I think that's I've seen people that you
know started with nothing and
and one year later they're like one of
our biggest collaborative partners
because they just you know are smart and
they know what's a good know a good idea
when they see one or have one or
whatever
[Music]