[Music]
we're not going to pay attention what's
on the front of this magazine but more
importantly on the back hello
California
uh no no no no this is the more
important side of this magazine from my
perspective but uh first and foremost I
want to thank very much the uh producers
of this event uh state of marijuana it's
an honor it's a privilege to represent
what I believe are thousands if not tens
of thousands of entrepreneurs men and
women that are truly beginning to
prosper uh I don't know uh I'd actually
like to get a hand a show of hands who
here is from
California everybody uh well that is
terrific from my perspective because
I've been reflecting for the last 45
minutes to an hour when the last time I
spoke uh to the Cannabis industry in
California and to be honest with you
this may be my official first so
hopefully you guys will be kind and
gentle to me but um I've been here for
about a week now and it is incredibly
exciting to see what is taking place in
your state I think everybody in this
room would agree that it was a
disappointment if you will
when Colorado legalized marijuana for
adult use in advance of California and
then to rub salt into the wound then
Washington state did it uh nobody has
worked harder to legalize adult used
cannabis in the United States than your
home state and I'm incredibly proud of
what you guys have
accomplished that's right I mean it it
really deserves uh certainly more than
uh a 5-second round of applause uh
people have made tireless uh effort uh
made massive sacrifice and I can feel it
because I've been in the market albeit
only a week as a sales professional
literally carrying my Wares uh and we
are finally uh successfully launched my
brand which is that of Dixie Brands uh
through a affiliate manufacturing
partnership with indis Holdings out of
montere California montere County uh we
are successfully Distributing uh in H
products uh in the state serving Today
medical marijuana patients what we hope
to
be adult use
consumers so when I was uh honored to
speak today uh here at the state of
marijuana conference uh they said we'd
like to talk to you or we'd like for you
to talk to our audience about you know
so you want to get into the marijuana
business uh which I'm happy to share
with you uh on certain days I would
encourage you to run the opposite
direction but that day is not today I'm
feeling very very bullish but again just
a quick raise of hands Who currently is
actively in the Cannabis space whether
it be direct to the plant cultivation
manufacturing retail distribution or
serving as an ancillary
service okay a majority so what I'll
call a target-rich
environment um I'm going to go ahead and
move to the next slide I'm also going to
get out of the way it's probably easier
um
and what I was asked to talk about again
is you know trying to either convince
positively or suggest otherwise that you
make a move into the space and the good
news is that we have a majority of the
uh audience already into uh the space in
N excuse me in 2009 uh I was basically
temporarily retired I'm a seral
entreprenur uh and I've owned many many
businesses I'm a frustrated slash a
retired developer uh which in 2008 2009
we all knew what that meant both here in
the state of C California but also
around the country I've owned nightclubs
I've done technology uh telefony voice
and data um and at the time I was
basically
bored and I was in the bar
business successfully Distributing
probably a far dangerous product than
marijuana which is alcohol I think
everybody would believe that that's
right effing
right and I noticed as an astute
Observer that people that consume
marijuana generally drink less alcohol
and when you're in the alcohol
distribution
business and people are smoking
marijuana outside of your restaurant or
your nightclub that poses a
problem and so literally I asked the law
enforcement officers that were outside
of my club that were working for us I
said we have to get these gentlemen many
and women back inside the club because
you know they're smoking marijuana I'm
not sure if that's allowed and literally
in Epiphany he corrected me and said no
we had passed medical marijuana in the
state of Colorado and I was shocked I
knew nothing about it you know I'm
slightly sheepishly embarrassed that up
to that point I didn't have a very
strong relationship with cannabis each
and every day I try and improve that
relationship some days better than ever
uh better than others but uh you know
like our own president probably every
single person in this room that I
understand that marijuana is less
harmful than alcohol and so with that I
went on a journey and that Journey was
really to better understand about this
plant but again I'll sheepishly admit
and certainly I've
been critiqued for it that I got into
this business not to help people you
know boo his that would be the time to
to to boo uh I got into it to make money
and I saw a fascinating opportunity I
saw low barrier t ENT I saw a very
chaotic Marketplace I did not see very
sophisticated High financed players and
I said maybe I could make a move and get
into the space again I want to emphasize
that I got into it to make money and boy
was I wrong because anybody who's been
in this business for five minutes or
five years knows how incredibly
challenging it is to be in this space
it's a fascinating space what industry
can you all think of and we're going to
talk a little bit about it in a few
minutes where you can absolutely
unequivocally help people achieve a new
level of Wellness that you might not be
able to achieve through alcohol opiates
tobacco
even cure a to zed when it comes to ills
uh ailments or illnesses again I can't
make that claim I'm not a medical doctor
but our own very sanj Gupta has probably
done as much for marijuana reform in the
last three years that even MPP with
which I'm a board member has done the
last 20 I mean it's shocking I mean he
literally apologized to every single one
of us in this country for 20 years of
disinformation for sharing that this
plant is a dangerous narcotic come on
this is a
plant collap I mean uh we know what that
means right
it's just not the case I mean we are
absolutely seen proof through powerful
soldiers men like Dr excuse me women
excuse me women like Dr Sue sisly please
don't tell her I said that I'm on
occasion frightened of her what she's
doing for men and women soldiers
veterans that are coming back from
overseas that are suffering from
post-traumatic stress
disorder and 14% these 22 men and women
that are taking their own lives 22 of
them I wear proudly a uh dog tag that
was given to me by this organization I
wear it every single day 14% of them
have alcohol and opiates in their
system I mean this is I'm a businessman
you are business people in this room
when we lose money I promise you I do
everything I can to make it up I lose
$100,000 today I'm going to make
$200,000 tomorrow but 22 today Sunday 44
Monday 66 33,000 men and women are no
longer on this
planet because we cannot treat them
ostensibly with this harmless plan it's
messed
up
lastly well helping people we can make
money the state of California represents
the Glenn Gary Glenn Ros leads all right
if you've ever seen that movie and
there's a Salesman or salesperson in you
somewhere go out and watch it because
this state I don't care if it's 1.4
billion according to arkview or two
billion according to marijuana Business
Daily or 5 to 7 billion which is
probably closer to the reality what
you're talking about both the white the
gray and the black markets it's a big
big market and there's not going to be
one individual one company or one brand
that is going to own it there's going to
be dozens and dozens of people companies
brands that are going to
prosper and that should be an
inspiration to you because again if you
can help somebody you can make money and
ostensibly every single one of us I'm
looking around the room and I see faces
that I met six years ago every single
one of us is truly part of History think
of that think of The Perfect Storm if
that's not an inspiration then I'm not
going to be of help to you today but I
embrac that opportunity in 2009 and got
on to a journey onto a path that has
been very winding and very Meandering
and finds me here today selling cannabis
legally in the state of Colorado with a
fully licensed facility almost duplicate
to what we've built in Colorado which is
had a very very strong regulatory
framework for four plus
years and now d Dixie and other brands
many of which are represented here today
are
thriving I mean over the last four or
five days every time I sit down with a
business
owner the order gets bigger I mean your
state has a voracious voracious appetite
for
cannabis that's
right excuse me I'm fired up so
that's good news so the journey again
has brought me
here I have said this
literally a thousand times the only
thing that is consistent or constant is
change you have to have a delusional
confidence a term that I use and I'm
accused of on a daily basis sometimes
better sometimes for worse but literally
you're typical consumer packaged goods
company changes their packaging every 36
months 36 months three
years in the last 12 months I've changed
my packaging three
times and probably in the next six
months I'll change it at least
definitively one more time the last time
I changed my packaging my Flagship
product which is that of the Dixie
Elixir I went from a 12
Flint bottle glass bottle very
inefficient not echo-friendly uh it was
glass it was Flint so you could see
through it we felt very very strongly
that you as a medical marijuana patient
or an adult used consumer could see in
we called them the uh dingleberries we
didn't want that those oil globules
floating we didn't want RPM raw plant
material on the bottom uh condensing so
we were very very proud of the emosion
that we created gone we started a 8.5
ounce brushed aluminum bottle that we
thought would take the the market by
storm and it did incredibly exciting
fought viciously for this rigid platform
a container really to elevate our game
as an industry so that of my
contemporaries my competitors would do
the
same brilliant idea until the state of
Colorado's marijuana enforcement
division got involved and now today we
manufactur in a same 8.5 ounce uh it's a
p BX it's plastic uh but we have now
what is a childproof tamper resistant
resealable dosing
cup I I mean I couldn't even get my
hands around it for weeks I didn't
understand but I surely this exists
somewhere in the
world wrong six weeks later I said I
must invent this product this platform
this Innovative delivery system again
$300,000 in expense that necessarily
wasn't plan for I didn't have this on my
pro forma every single one of you in
this room that is in a business that is
either serving the Cannabis
industry or is direct to the plant again
commercial cultivation
pesticides God is that going to become
an issue here in the state of California
we are getting crushed by it two
customers to vendors of mine who are
also customers combined 100,000 plants
quarantine for 4 months think of the
trickle down effect 100,000 plants two
retailers sitting on dozens of metric
tons of cannabis that adult use
consumers and medical marijuana patients
need okay they need them we couldn't get
them to the market fast enough that
change is what will separate the ladies
from the girls and the men from the boys
because you must have that delusional
confidence that you are going to break
through whatever the state is throwing
at
you and so you have to learn to embrace
it and again some days that's easier
than others but there are dozens and
dozens of situations or scenarios that I
could present to
you that indicate that the only thing
that is constant in this business is
change
and so when you go upstairs
tonight and reflecting on today's
discussions which I'm sure most of those
are far more interesed what I'm talking
about today really reflect what does
that mean to you I'm obsessive
compulsive and I'm a control freak I'm a
disaster for the Cannabis industry okay
so but my therapist promises me that I'm
going to be okay just use more
marijuana and let
tequila I hear from wouldbe Cannabis
entrepreneurs young men and
women seasoned veterans from other
Industries whether it be technology
whether it be media whether it be
commercial farmers and they say I am
going to get into the marijuana business
what do you
think I said well depends on what day of
the week it is but more
importantly really focus focus your
efforts Focus your business plans I've
been here for 30 40 minutes literally
I've been honored to meet a dozen plus
people that have been interested in
sharing a business plan with me I mean
that's exciting right every single day a
new idea is being formed I hear all the
time trip is it too late to get into the
Cannabis industry are you kidding me we
are literally in the bottom of the first
of a seven game series I mean this
industry is growing Leaps and Bounds
it's doubling on an annual basis and we
put the ceiling at about 50 billion 5
billion dollar but I want to remind you
of something most people do not use
marijuana in the United States or more
importantly around the globe because it
is illegal at the federal level now that
may seem silly to all of us sitting in
the room as we have Vape lounges
upstairs and we have you know adult use
cannabis rampant in the state of
Colorado to a positive effect but most
people in the state of California do not
use marijuana because it's illegal at
the federal level and they're not
perceived as a medical marijuana patient
how silly is that and so if it's $50
billion today and the federal government
capitulates on it tomorrow who knows
what that number is there's no
telling so that's a motivating factor
but again I will encourage you that not
every single opportunity is Right pick a
business pick an idea pick a segment of
this industry that is so fascinating
there is no MMJ for dummies book by the
way whoever writes it it's a free tip
will be a pot billionaire okay a
marijuana Maven whatever it
is the reality is is that today I own 28
companies related to
cannabis about half of those are what we
call Direct to the
plant but the other half are anary
services companies security companies
technology companies equipment
manufacturing companies all selling the
proverbial pick and shovel which is such
an overused cliche but it's it's it's
accurate but I want to be very very
clear I spent the first three years
making literally hundreds and hundreds
of mistakes on an annual basis trying to
perfect how somebody really wants to get
in here uh or they're trying to get out
uh no they're trying to get in it's a
good sign
I'm honored I'm privileged to have
access to all these companies because
over those first three years I built a
brand and a product and we got good at
it we're still not great but we got good
at it and from there we were able to
diversify and through management through
powerful women through powerful men that
work alongside me that I represent
really today which numberers close to
450 to 475 been gone for a month the
company will probably double who knows I
mean it's just it's growing that fast
but the reality is I focused on One
widget which was a marijuana infused
product today we have 150 of them
represented about 14 or 15 Delivery
Systems Tom was so incredibly generous
with this new uh story that came out to
highlight uh Tom you really didn't need
to use trip ink that was a little too
much but uh listen it's a
powerful
collaboration my company is called Dixie
brands for a reason I'm not smart enough
to figure this out myself and I know
that's self-deprecating but I am smart
enough to find an intelligent woman like
you that I can align myself with and
take what I've learned both good and bad
and pay it
forward so Dixie Brands is doing exactly
that most recently Foria which is a THC
infused personal lubricant designed to
enhance a woman's sexuality an amazing
product that I think is going to have
incredible legs these individuals just
needed help uh last month fascinating
experiment uh and I still live through
it we launched two Wellness companies
focused on cannabid CBD derived from
Whole plant
formulation
hemp we launched a wellness company
designed to serve the human beings or
the human race and we designed a product
to design our four-legged
companions pets no one cares about
accesso which is the human being company
it's it's all about therapists I did a
media tour last week every single
journalist all they wanted to talk about
is is Fluffy or Pho going to get high no
can uh cannabid does not have that
aspect to it it didn't matter that's all
they wanted to talk about but the
reality is getting back to the purpose
of point of this slide is that focus on
something that you see is an opportunity
and don't look for the shiny object over
here don't look for the next big thing
over here get good at what you want to
do find a product that you can sell to
me and I'll B buy more of it than you
likely can
produce and there's hundreds and
hundreds of
Manufacturers there are hundreds and
hundreds of customers both on the retail
the manufacturing and the commercial
cultivation side that are jonesing
jonesing for
technology the irony I sat down with the
CEO of CNBC which is where I get all my
marijuana information it's a great
source it seems like and Mig magazine
I'm sorry Tom um but you know the irony
of six years of risk of trials and
tribulations uh I sit on the board
honored to be part Mass rotth Roots
anybody familiar with
massroots kind of Facebook meets
Instagram meets cannabis a powerful
powerful movement semi Anonymous
Community uh that is allowing people to
share their experiences there are lots
of other uh companies that come out uh
this is a company that is likely going
to be uplisted to the NASDAQ in two to
four weeks this will be the first time
in history of the United States where a
cannabis themed company is on one of the
big boy boards you know we're not
talking about OTC ping sheets which when
I got into this business in nine was
zero in
2012 there was probably a dozen or two
dozen today there's probably an excess
of 200 plus publicly traded companies
many of those companies are incredibly
good companies that are committed to
compliance that are not selling
vaporware that are not pump and dump
shops but this is incredibly exciting to
see
what technology is going to be able to
do for individuals men and women that
potentially can't get into the space but
want to participate in that green Rush
another satisfied customer
leaving the risk that we all
take is on occasion
untenable I'm going to ask a a tough
question since 90% of you are in this
industry with me how many people have
been
afraid doing what you do truly
afraid I watched an interview with a
dear dear friend of mine Andy Williams
from medicine
man just a powerful person just a kind
gentle man and he was sharing with a
reporter that he was truly distraught in
the early days I mean fantasizing
dreaming nightmares what I would call
them that the guys in the black boots
were going to be out in front of his
shop the day he pulled up I didn't tell
many people but I used to sit in my
conference room which was a big glass
window I had an office I sat in the
conference room because I could see the
trucks and the people pulling up into my
parking lot every day and I too
fantasized about the guys in the black
boots that were going to show up and
potentially take me off to jail I was
honored to represent the industry Steve
Croft from 60 Minutes did an interview
and he asked me very succinctly he says
trip we want to understand how you sleep
at night because based on our
calculations you've qualified for about
six lifetime sentences for Kingpin
status hit home at that moment
right because I'm a father uh you know I
have family and I provide for not only
my own but for many others through
employment that was heavy
duty gossip but the reality is I answer
it I sleep fine at night and by the way
I don't even use marijuana very often
because I operate at the pleasure of the
state of Colorado just like today we
will be operating at the pleasure of the
State of California and so those fears
those nightmares if you will should
dissipate but again do not mince words
that there is still risk and we all know
the cliche where risk equals reward
and I think that applies certainly here
but the risk that we take each and every
day you have to what I call check up for
the neck up and see where you
are are you willing to work seven days a
week are you willing to work 16 to 18
hours a
day because you have to but also because
you want
to sh falls through the cracks when you
do that but that's the type of
commitment that it's generally going to
take to be successful because of the
previous three slides that I talked
about this looks like my first marijuana
facility that I built in Denver back in
about 2009 and it's probably not too far
from the truth uh we did start in a 400
SQ foot shed uh I won't even call it a
facility but uh uh I don't know where
that is looks like Alabama um so um the
reality is is that yes of
course I would imagine 90% of you of the
100% that are in this room have had some
previous
career and I would imagine that most of
your employers did not hand you an
envelope that was stuffed with cash that
represents the last two weeks
wages I literally have hundreds and
hundreds of friends contemporaries in
this industry that still today pay their
employees and themselves in US
currency it spends but think of the
terror that a young woman probably has
when she has that
payday forget about woman man or woman
and they have thousands of dollars in
their pocket and they have to go home
and figure out where to put it it is
absolutely untenable banking is the
single greatest
opportunity but also the single greatest
threat to an industry that is doubling
year after year after
year we're going to do a billion dollars
this year in Colorado if not darn close
to it we did $700 Million last year in
the state of Colorado generated $76
million to the state coffers this year
we're forecasting about a 100 million
dollars by the way the state has
banking state of Washington uses Bank of
America the state of Colorado use as
well as Fargo I've been with both those
banks no longer uh the hypocrisy but the
infrastructure the most obvious is in
fact the
banking but even
technology you know CRM customer
relationship management software I
couldn't get somebody to sell me a box
to put my products in I had to go to the
the uh the The Craft brewery uh store
and pay retail pricing cuz the guy who
sold boxes in our region wouldn't sell
it to me cuz I was one of them I'll tell
you now that they're lined up out the
door so that's not an indic if that's
not an indication of how our industry is
being perceived I don't know what is
literally every single week we hear from
dozens and dozens of
investors that have an excuse me I just
said investors I meant vendors excuse me
that have an interest in doing business
with us we also hear from investors as
well but listen the infrastructure does
not exist in basic terms for from
previous careers which is a not so
subtle hint that find that Gap find an
area in my company as an example that
has a
weakness and exploit it because there's
dozens of them and I think each one of
those represents an opportunity that any
one of you could solve
for and so there are literally uh
hundreds and hundreds of uh businesses
that are starving for that
infrastructure that I think any one of
you potentially um could create on your
own or more importantly invest
in so that infrastructure albeit a
challenge is also an opportunity again
that's where that delusional confidence
comes into uh
play you know you look around the room
today I mean we are such a diverse
group of individuals men women
Caucasians
African-Americans Asians people from all
different aspects of
socioeconomic levels of society it's the
most exciting thing when I walk into a
store serving cannabis or when I walk
into a conference like this because it
represents
opportunity but it is so
unique it is like nothing that I've ever
involved myself with as a serial
entrepreneur for 20 plus
years I remember vividly sitting in a
room at the fairon hotel in San
Francisco um two years no a year and a
half ago with uh arkview and we had
brought uh Stak holders from all over
the industry into this hotel room we
were going to begin to talk about the
legalization of marijuana at the uh
state level here in California and Rob
campy is the Ed for MPP marijuana policy
projects a trip I would really
appreciate if you could sit down and
make some comments to the group before
we start just because you have an
interesting
perspective I was dressed like this
there was a gentleman sitting next to me
that was equally as passionate I was
about the legalization of marijuana and
I started my Spiel and he said stop
right there enough he goes you're not
even from the state okay I represent ABC
uh Growers and you know your opinion
does not matter matter here I looked at
Rob I said WTF I said uh I thought that
this was a uh a friendly audience uh he
says today I come in peace that was the
words this individual used not important
who or where he came from but I mean
that is an
interesting introduction right to
conceptually launching adult use
marijuana in your state 34 million plus
people you can't get 34 million people
to agree on what day of the week it is
let alone this highly highly complicated
issue and so again as a control freak
and somebody who as a serial
entrepreneur most of his adult life for
a reason because I don't like to be told
what to do that is my character
flaw ask my parents ask former wives ask
my girlfriend you know it's it's it's a
flaw but you have to
collaborate because my brothers at bang
or my brothers at Kea or my brothers at
cushy punch any brands that I've met
with this week we have to find a way to
collaborate because if we don't it's
never going to happen we have to find a
way to work together because again this
industry is incredibly unique and unless
you were alive in 1933 which a quick
glance of the room doesn't look like
anybody qualifies for that which was the
end of alcohol
prohibition which there's a lot of s
James is raising his arms back there you
look pretty good
sir we have to find a way to
connect connecting is what we are doing
today if you do not know the person that
is sitting to the left of you or the
person sitting to the right of you and I
know this is cheesy but please please
please introduce yourself find out what
this individual is doing here today and
more importantly what they want to do
tomorrow I literally host three to five
people that I've never met in my life in
my office a week usually through
Linkedin or Facebook or uh
some random interaction and I connect
with
them because they have an interest a
motivation to jump into an industry that
is doubling every year that has a
diverse group of individuals like you
men and women in in this room and I
don't care if they have the same beliefs
as me I don't care if they're an
activist a reformist or a free market
capitalist I want to connect with them
because they have an idea that I have
not thought about and so people like the
state of marijuana group create these
forums these environments that are
incredibly efficient because I don't
have to go visit every single one of you
you know for the next 60 to 75 days I
can meet a majority of you people
today so again I challenge you whether
it be right after this event or upstairs
do not be bashful do not be abrasive do
not be
arrogant find a way in which to connect
with that man or woman that is sitting
on either side of you
today I'm going to wrap it up uh and
it's a powerful quote
uh which I think should resonate with
every single person here uh because you
being here in this room ultimately means
that
you're you're in the
arena because people that are sitting on
the sidelines aren't ever going to get
in that game and this is a game this is
a game where lots and lots of people are
going to win and the biggest chance of
losing is if you're never going to get
in it
and again you've made the investment
today whether it be the first investment
or one of
many you have to
engage but I was asked to
speak at a uh conference next week uh I
don't even know where it is I think it's
in Colorado oh it's startup week Denver
startup week hundreds and hundreds of uh
individuals that are starting companies
ironically now starting to turn to us as
the experts uh that's crazy um but I
reflected on a quote that somebody gave
me uh some advice somebody gave me years
ago and I kind of applied it but you
know men and women are all about who has
who have children in here I got one 15
years old she's still pretty good uh I
might start using marijuana a little bit
more often these days uh but um it's all
about the betterment of
society and
so I looked at my life and then I looked
at previous generations my great
grandfather worked in the steel mills of
pennil Tucky uh Pennsylvania uh I joke
uh I went to Villanova University uh so
I could say that uh my grandfather
worked in the steel mills so my father
could become a doctor so I could sell
marijuana if that's not powerful I
don't know what is guys thank you very
much I very much appreciate the time
um Alan I know we're behind schedule uh
I don't know if it's because of me or
not but uh I'm certainly available to
ask a few questions if that's conducive
to you or certainly I'll be around for a
little while but uh is there any
question that somebody cannot wait and
has to get out I'm happy to answer
tonight in front of
everybody yes sir
what it excites me about
what man well um when we met earlier I
talked about is forget about the fire
hoses the fire hydrant uh and I can be I
certainly been accused of being quote
unquote greedy I mean I've got a vasist
appetite myself for opportunity uh what
I can tell you is that nobody not even
the sagest veterans in this room or in
the industry many of whom I know
personally have a crystal ball and so
somebody like myself pontificating up
here on stage and again I consider an
honor to represent the industry no one
really knows right I mean I believe that
the federal government is going to
capitulate in the year 2017 I bet Rob
campy $1,000 I will do it again uh next
week at or at the national marijuana
business conference in Las Vegas because
I know he'll be foolish enough to get up
on stage with me but I believe the
federal government is going to
capitulate they're going to defer to
State's rights just like um uh gay
marriage uh you know civil you know
whatever it is uh so that's going to be
exciting to me whether it's 2017 because
I have happy ears or whether it's 2019
like Rob campio believes I don't know
but I can tell you it is not oot Over
the Horizon it is right there I can see
it I'm on my bicycle pedaling so damn
hard to that bright light I just don't
know when I'm going to get to it so that
ultimately is what motivates me excites
me about our industry that we're on
today
oh