my name is don newman
i'm currently the director of
cultivations for highlight farms in
Chesaning michigan previously resided in
Denver Colorado where I was the head
grower for the herbal cure I was brought
here to help get the grow going and
online and also just help with expansion
and moving forward with the company so
can you kind of talk about the execution
of that like
how big is the grow operation what was
the build-out process like what do you
like to see you get to put input into
like what lights we use what grow media
we use but absolutely is the director of
cultivation those are things that you
all have to design you know and what we
do is like a yearly schedule as well so
everything's very detailed and specific
nothing is just kind of on a whim right
so when it comes to big investments and
big companies all this stuff needs to be
planned out so it's very important to to
plan it out and have a good team in
place so you know as far as the
build-out goes it was it was an old
auction facility you know and they they
had like old tractors and stuff so the
old building that we kind of revamped
right eighty thousand square feet and
inside that building we have a
production facility we have an
extraction facility right so we have two
companies as well that are associated
with highlight farms and then we have a
10,000 square foot indoor grow right now
that currently has four Class C 15-under
plant licenses and it's so it's six
thousand plants total and we just
finished 17,000 square foot greenhouse
that will house 7,500 plants as well we
have plans for expansion to another
7,500 indoor plants so for that facility
alone when we're setting done we're
looking at 22,000 plants will be
maintaining their what we do is when we
design those facilities we look at how
we how we operate right it is a very
kind of California we're more of a SIA
green kind of maximize our canopy right
so we use more plants for light and we
should do a shorter veg time right but
for our method that's how we've always
been successful and that's what's worked
for us we grow biosynthetic Li you know
so it's a good mix of organic and
synthetic all biological IPM so once we
go to flower we don't spray and we use
you know predatory bugs to help combat
any kind of issues that you know we are
always prevented we're always excuse me
what's the word I'm looking for
we're proactive not reactive yes sir and
I think that's a big part of growing
right and another big part that I think
people don't understand is getting a
team of passionate people right because
anybody can grow cannabis but in order
to get the true quality that that that
homegrown quality that people love and
know you really have to put your heart
and soul into it and you have to find
passionate people and that takes some
time to do as well on a large scale you
know and we've been thankful that we
we've been able to find a very good team
of dedicated passionate employees and
we've been very successful so did you
bring a bunch of people from Denver
no no we did not bring a bunch of people
from Denver we've just been hiring
locally right and we have on the
cultivation side it's seven people just
for the to manage the indoor grow and
that's a manager and then a team lead
and then five employees and then we have
I want to say a harvest manager two
leads and about ten trimmers right so
they kind of helped with the harvest and
the teardown of the room so we how many
turns are you doing we won a nine week
cycle so we run anywhere from 63 to 68
days and so we'll do 21 harvests a year
and then between that in the greenhouse
it'll total 42 right because I'll each
be getting 21 so and what we've been
seeing we have 48 light rooms and we've
been averaging around three and a half
pounds of light so we're pooling usually
anywhere from 150 to 170 170 pounds of
room so we've been very successful with
the way we've been set up and we're
using right now phantom double ended to
flower under excuse me and then we do
LEC light emitting ceramic 315 watts for
veg but we're also trialing a lot of LED
products as well like we have some
Gavita some thrive Agrotech through this
little convention here we got hooked up
with Spyder so we're gonna be sampling
some of theirs I've seen a lot of great
success with their products so you know
I think there's a lot of opportunities
out there and that's the beautiful thing
about this industry is it keeps evolving
and there's always something more to
learn something
knew that you can gain from this right
can you talk about what you've noticed
because you have a you've worked with a
bunch of different types of lights like
specifically ceramic like what do you
like about it what's what I like about
its place in which it's growing if my
plants are happy I'm happy right so
that's what's important and what I like
is I like that the color rendering index
is 95 right so out of a hundred that's
the closest that they can mimic to
indoor sunlight so it's a very high
rating on that the plants seem to
respond very well to it it's a very
natural light
you get great resin production from it
you know and the plants seem to stack
very well they Bush out very well
same with leds leds I personally think
you get a little better internodal
spacing but you know just through all
these different kind of mediums and
being able to play like I'm not somebody
who's smarter than anybody I've just am
willing to try different things and I'm
not afraid to look stupid as far as
lighting is concerned you know there was
a lot in the beginning with LED there
was a lot of those spider-man lights if
you will the blue the red spectrum
they're kind of very harsh on the eyes
and they were very like cheap if you
will so kind of like turn people off to
the idea that LED could be competing in
this market right or be efficient but
you know since the last couple years
they've kind of you really seen the
progression of that and then the other
beautiful thing too is energy companies
will work with you because you're able
to give back to them and not take such a
demand on the grid that they'll pay for
half the costs nine times out of ten on
upgrading these lights right so it's a
huge savings right there not to mention
your electric bills and everything
but you know just the evolution of the
resin production the terpene profiles
and just really trying to get the full
potential the plant to be brought out in
doors just like it is outdoors right and
trying to mimic that sunlight I don't
think we'll ever fully get there but you
know that we've still got a ways to go
and a lot to learn but as far as you
know the future and what really excites
me is is greenhouse production I think
that's kind of the way of to be
efficient and as far as like you know
once we get bigger and bigger and bigger
right it's all going to be about
efficiency and who can provide the best
product at the cheapest cost right at
the cheapest cost per pound and I think
always when what is your cost per pound
and we have not had a harvest in the
greenhouse our first in outdoor our
first greenhouse harvest will be August
6 so we're actually gonna be
transplanting our first production
around July 1st so we're quite excited
for that but our indoor cost per pound
is it's a little proprietary honestly
that's something that it just do to you
know market demand pricing it's just
things that I guess like you know it's
something that we always work towards
getting cheaper you know and I think
that no matter what when you care about
creating a good quality product you're
not necessarily worried about the cost
right so it's always important to be
efficient but at the same time it's
important to create a good quality
product because at the end of the day
good cannabis is always going to sell
itself this is a de Market that it's a
connoisseur market right and those are
your returning customers the you know
the larger companies who shoot for kind
of that
middle man mentality right hey let's
just try to pump out biomass there's a
market for that but those people are
going to come and go right those
connoisseur customers who loyally
returned to the dispensaries they want a
product that they can rely on right and
those are who we try to appeal to is is
the growers who want to go to the
dispensary right because I'm a grower
myself so if I didn't want to smoke my
own products then I can wouldn't be able
to sit down and talk to you I had a
higher man-to-man right because I
believe in what I do and I believe in
what I produce right since so your
market is kind of that connoisseur
market so way
what cultivars are you cultivating and
are you like chasing pipe strains are
you like
this is what I love to smoke I'm gonna
grow
you know and honestly it's it's a
combination everything right and that's
one thing that I'm thankful you know a
highlight Farms we're always pushing
right we usually pop about a hundred
seeds a month if not more so we're
always hunting new genetics and we're
always pushing the limits and and we
reach out to we have a good relationship
with a lot of readers like relentless
genetics raw genetics right these are
guys we test for so we're able to to get
our hands on genetics before other
people do we want to create the hype we
don't want to chase the hype right and
now while there is quality out there we
want strains that last the test of time
I'll give you a great example right
purple punch is a phenomenal strain
right we all know and love it
it's a beautiful strain looks like it's
the most potent strain of all time and
when you're growing it has the most
insane smells of all time you're like oh
my god this is the mecca of weed right
no once you smoke it you find that it's
those long stalk trichomes that give it
that crazy coated appearance right but
all the oil and the potency is up in the
in the head of the trichome right so
it's not that it's more potent it
usually tests anywhere from 19 to 25
percent at least in my experience
growing it right so it's it's one of
those very deceiving pictures and in
this Instagram kind of
generation that we're in right
everything's about visuals and not so
much about terpenes and again a lot of
that old-school but right like CEM do G
Lemon G right
these are strains from back in the day
Northern Lights right they are not the
most visually appealing but when you
smell them your mouth absolutely
salivates because they're overloaded
with terpenes right and that's kind of
like a lost thing so we try to have a
lot of classics like triangle cush og
cush chem dog right like the actual chem
dog GDP things like that but we also
again we'll go for newer stuff like dos
Eidos right is a classic we do grow
purple punch I feel like purple punch is
great beginner we it right we also grow
the classic blue dream we have a nice
santa cruz cut you know i know that's
one that everybody likes to hate on but
at the same time it's also the number
one selling strain in the industry just
because people coming into it that's
what they hear so that's I guess what
they're going to gravitate towards right
so you have to play the market as well
right like so while we're able to have
fun we still want to appeal to everybody
we don't just want to we grow a lot of
heavy indicas because that's what we
like to smoke right you know rocket fuel
Junior Mints a lot of archive gear you
know so popular og
[Music]
they're cultivators as the equivalent of
like a very accomplished musician who's
told to go play apartments and like
place of like but you know top 40 music
you're like but I could play amazing
jazz music and they're like yeah they
don't want yet they want high THC they
want the popular strains they want the
Instagram strange so you have to balance
if the market wants what you truly love
to be like I wish you all appreciated
this right but absolutely and well and
that's another problem I have right is
people want to blame this industry or
blame the market right why don't we take
responsibility that's my responsibility
to educate people right as a grower as
as someone in this industry to educate
them on hey it's not just about looks
it's about smell it's about flavor it's
about effect right all that matters show
you don't get to corner those people in
the dispensary so now you're relying on
the bystander no but again this is where
technology is a beautiful thing they can
reach out to me through Instagram right
and I'm able to educate that way or and
and I try to stay very open to people
and always very educational because I'm
never here to hide anything I do because
I'm always evolving right so if I teach
you something this year next year it's
gonna be different because I figured out
a new technique I figured out a new
strain right so I'm not scared to share
kind of anything like that you know what
I mean certain things like business-wise
you're not really able to say that's one
thing right that's a business aspect but
as far as it grow you can come to where
our facility will show you what we got
going on right and we're very open and
honest about it because we have nothing
to hide and we believe in what we do so
you said your
so what are you copying and what are you
destroying on what's making your eyes
light up we just got done running a lot
of the archive gear he just dropped a
lot of new moon boat crosses so what
moonbow is is it's a dosey doe stein
Skittles male that he took right knee he
crossed it to a lot of his classic
strains so like Hollywood pure cush
right and that's called a flavor pack
right and so we just ran through we
normally pop around 50 seeds of each
strain just that they say around a 5%
margin and you can find the specific
Fino the breeder wants you to find so
they say about 50 seeds it's a minimum
you can pop for that at least that's
kind of some people schools of thought
right so that's kind of the theory we
fall under so we usually go for about
four packs per strain is what we pop
right so out of there we usually end up
a 50/50 is on average of what you'll
find between male-female right so we're
looking at around 25 females so a good
selection right and just really really
unique terpene profiles that are kind of
pushing the boundaries of something
different you know like just like Rosie
gassy kind of just almost a full
spectrum right like it's very
interesting in a palette if you will
like it it paints like a rainbow of your
senses when you smell it it's very
unique and interesting you know another
one we're about to finish up and take
down from him as rainbow driver so
that's Sunday driver from can Toronto
genetics times skittles and you get a
lot of again like rainbow fruits right
it's melon its
it's oranges it's limes right like it's
not just one it's strawberry it's it's a
whole kind of wave of flavors and it's
just very it's different on the senses
right you're used to smelling like okay
this strain smells like lemons but then
when you get like it's kind of like it
brushes by you almost like you're like
driving by it like like a fruit stand
right you know and you just get all the
flavors at once it's very unique
relentless just sent us a lot of his new
rosette crosses so we're popping some
gelato stuff and then we brought back a
classic head banger from karma genetics
we popped right and that's a biker cush
and Sour Diesel and I think that's one
thing that has kind of been lost is like
a really good sour and I feel like
Karma's doing a very good job of
bringing that back in seed form you know
I grew a Jays cut a Sour Diesel for a
long time and if you've taken any
shorter than 11 12 weeks I mean the
terpene profiles not there right and in
a lot of these commercial Gardens that's
just not feasible you know so we're
lucky to run on a nine week schedule
right so most of the no majority of
everything we grow finishes in that time
and fades out nicely but those kind of
longer running binos seem to take a
little bit longer and he's managed to
shorten that flowering time but still
get those great sours and cush is
brought out of that you know so those
are some of the genetics we're really
looking forward to you know
you know plastics like dosey doe is one
of my favorites kanan rattle pucker
which is lemon G times triangle push
it's like very bright lemons and then
like a dark diesel that finishes it's
almost acidic if you will so very
devastating but great for daytime as
well
[Music]
Duns your methodology Overland
the past five years
to express itself from it
and that's the thing is every time you
you know every time I grow these strains
I learned something new right so it's
always very humbling and that's the term
master grower is always very hard for me
to comprehend because I don't believe
we'll ever master it but what we learn
is is the one thing I noticed is when
you bring in new genetics not
necessarily popping seeds right but when
you bring in new genetics from someone
else there's a rule of three in my
opinion like I have to cycle through
that strain I have to flower it three
different times for it to acclimate to
me right and for me to see its potential
like just like when you get a new house
right you don't have your routine set up
right it usually takes you about six
months before you kind of in your groove
you know same with these genetics right
these are living breathing things like
so they operate the same way and they
can get stress and they have to learn
your feed schedule your style of growing
and acclimate to you so you know I
believe it's about a rule of three for
that to dial in but then again like a
great example right is we're starting to
experiment with different pops so we
always ran royal gold with three gallon
pots right and then we're like okay why
don't we try to gallon pots and we can
get away with less water and we found we
got bigger plants right we're like this
is mind blowing right and so we're like
why don't we try one gallon pot so we
tried the chart quarters right and no
transplanting and saving it a crazy
amount of time you know and labor so
huge cost savings right there and we
found we're getting just as big a plan
but what we see though in these
different mediums is we see different
phenotypic expressions gorilla glue for
example right like I'll get a great mix
of soured of and chem sis and chocolate
diesel when I grow it in the Royal gold
but I'm noticing now in my first trial
of flora Flex pots with cocoa I'm
getting a lot more of the chemists kind
of phenotypic expressions you know and
so it's just very unique it almost looks
like a different cut of gorilla glue you
know what I mean so but it's the exact
same cut and it's just very interesting
how in the same rooms but just changing
the home for the roots right changes the
plant
you know so just these little tweaks I'm
noticing all this stuff adds up right so
you know I think Adam doesn't put it
best he looks at growing is kind of like
a report card right and you start
everybody starts in school with an A and
then you miss one homework assignment
right you miss one water okay down
you're in an a - you the lights
accidentally stayed on for 15 minutes
extra right okay now you're at an A you
know what I mean so all these little
stresses start to add up and then you
lose the true genetic potential of these
plants but the less we stress them and
the better we get them we get them from
clone to harvest we see the true
potential right because all that stress
while we may not think oh it came back
okay a couple days later that couple
days was huge you know what I mean so
you're losing a lot when you're trying
to time these players
transfer plants I think there's good
stress and there's bad stress right so
like pruning is an example of good
stress or topping is an example of good
stress right but like letting your
plants will till they almost die or
light stressing your plants or wind
stressing your plants I don't think
necessarily is the best thing right you
know I think like you know manipulations
like pinching pruning low stress
training things like that right are
beneficial and low wind stress but again
there's beneficial stress and then
there's unbeneficial stress so it's
knowing the difference between the two
and when to apply them
you're experiencing all sorts of
stresses and pressures terpenes are kind
of how the cannabis plant protects
itself like it can sense what's come in
but it will again exude terpenes
deal with whatever the issue is and so
you're
it's her pain expression it's almost you
want that plan to endure different
stresses and that kind of just be like a
host plane where everything's perfect
and it never has to suffer
you know absolutely and again it's just
going back to those good stress versus
the bad stress right and knowing when to
implement it you know I think if you're
trying to snap a bunch of tops at week
six that's probably not the right kind
of stress you want to apply to plants
and things like that right I guess like
what what are your theory is that sense
on this subject right what what how do
you feel about that well that's why I
kind of love your cultivation because I
feel like you know
even though you can play God and a
totally
a fireman
is that really allowing the plant to be
kind of
like you never think a coggle of kid is
gonna turn out it's exactly the best
people you know have had a fucked up
life you know what I mean and those are
your favorite people because they've
been tested they have carried your
you're in the middle of growing the
greenhouse we could probably say it's an
example to some stuff you've done the
past like same strains in the
are you noticing differences like you're
like these are the same genetics we're
growing up right next door to each other
but I'm noticing a difference absolutely
you'll notice you know they'll revert
back to seed vigor you can take a Dutton
plant from Indore and put it out into
the Sun and reinvigorate it right and
it's like why can we do that that says
something right there that yes you'd
like you saying indoor you are not
getting the true potential of these
genetics there's something about the
power of the summit we're not able to
mimic and it's I don't know if it's all
the UVs or exactly what it is I'm not
very educated as far as that goes so I
couldn't explain that right what I do
see that these plants do perform
differently and they perform better
right this is their home and that's
what's got me excited about greenhouse
production is because I'm able to dial
in the environment but harness the power
of the Sun so that we can get the best
about worlds right and that's what I
truly believe we'll be able to see the
full potential what's your opinion
yeah and I agree I mean I I front from a
variety of standpoints I'm not a big fan
of Indore
I think from starting with like the
environment like in California you have
all these desert roads you have all
these it's a hundred and ten degrees
outside and your
an indoor facility when it
HPS lights right and
meanwhile there like LA County is a good
example
LA County is 40%
grows amazing fruits and vegetables yet
that ordnance is that
grow out of doors now
you have to grow indoor in a very small
commercial area in the entire county
and so
the policy is pushing towards indoor but
I think moms like long-term when you can
sell cross-border and I'm not just
saying from Michigan to Illinois but
like
from anywhere to anywhere in the world
right what are you gonna see are you're
gonna see as many indoor growth like no
absolutely not because it's again it
goes back to that chasing that cost per
pound and getting that down always right
and being as efficient as possible and
when you can harness the energy of the
Sun without having to pay these enormous
electric bills
how could you compete against that right
you can so that is the evolution and I
agreed and I think it's just you know
it's just an ignorance on a lot of
people's hearts and a lot of
misunderstanding as far as is what this
plant can provide for us and for the
economy as well right and I think the
more people get educated the more they
understand you know those laws that
people will be more open-minded to okay
we can have green houses right it's not
a big deal if a school bus drives by a
cannabis grow it's gonna be okay
you know what I mean like it's not the
end of the world what are some lessons
you've learned
like fatty pests and pathogens so like
as you scale indoor right like powdery
mildew
you get thrips you get spider mites like
what happens lessons you've learned over
years of doing this
allows you to produce this is your
proactive versus reactive so what are
you doing it kind of
reduce the possibility of hole
I think it comes down to a good IPM you
know and have a good understanding of
environments you know people I taper my
environment like people that will taper
a feed schedule as well right so every
week it's going to vary a little bit you
know until the yet right and so as
having an understanding of that having
an understanding of your gross style and
how to properly prune your plants so you
don't get microclimates right
those are huge factors especially on a
large scale facility having the proper
sprayers to know that when your guys are
spraying they're actually covering every
inch of the leaf surface because once
you leave one spot open
that's how pests build you know what's
the word I'm looking for resistance
right things like that and just having a
good understanding and the proper setup
right a lot of people want to try to do
it cheaply you cannot grow cannabis
cheaply right like it's it's profitable
but it's not to grow good cannabis it's
not cheap right so it while it is
profitable it does take a large upfront
cost right you need heavy amounts of air
conditioning you need age HVAC as far as
excuse me a humidity humidification and
dehumidification right you need
environment a wind movement rolling
tables irrigation things like this and
how you going to water and understanding
all that plays a big part in it
you are implying before that you do full
ears
yes sir yeah what so when are you
putting into this friend like what do
you what do you also will do a
biological spray so if anything it'll be
like a serenade product right you know
again because we use biologicals for to
combat any kind of like pest pressure
you know and so that's how we're able to
stay without spider mites without having
Russell mites without threats without
Ruud aphids anything like that and our
plants are able to stay happy and
healthy and how frequently are you
spraying we're in veg will spray every
three days will spray with a biological
or will spray a beneficial like a
beneficial like a nutrient spray if you
will right like we'll make seaweed in
silica right you know just to kind of
help strengthen up cell walls of the
plants and that way if some reason my
pests don't catch it the silica is so
thick on the plants that the bugs can't
even bite into it right you know I'm
just kind of understanding that balance
again also understanding how to prune
properly alright like and making sure
like you remove as many families as
possible to not have those microclimates
but without over stressing your plants
you know so just having that balance but
again having a good having a good
sprayer and having a good IPM schedule
and understanding how to rotate so you
use like an atomizer
like kindness exactly exactly what do
you use I get DRAM or like it's almost
like a car a paint sprayer where you
know and it's like a handgun and then we
have a big reservoir but the beautiful
no no no like a cart yeah exactly cuz
the hose so you know you imagine trying
to walk down an aisle with a backpack
with trellis up and then turn around
you're gonna get caught up in it
you know I can't ask my guys to be
efficient in that kind of environment
right so it's also creating success for
your people to implement what you ask
them to do and again absolutely we use a
lot of beneficials you know so we'll do
like og bio war mix with earthworm
castings and stuff like that and then a
little bit of kelp of molasses right you
know and things like that will brew
those up will use like the Opilio bio
the tribus or recharge you know those
are great products that we like but yeah
so once we move over to flour though we
stopped spraying you know so that's
where we kind of differentiate ourselves
as far as commercial growers as we try
not to just spray the plants just to
allow them you know I feel like you know
trichomes are so sensitive and any kind
of damage you apply to them it's it has
a long-term effect right you know I've
seen great product that's been sprayed
but you know the less you can spray it
the better it is right just like the
less you stress it the better it comes
out you know so again
we always aim for is trying for the
highest quality so once we move over to
flower our environments you know we just
believe in our environmental control and
then we let the beneficial bugs take
over have you ever personally made like
bubble hash
we have an extraction department that
does yes sir but you personally out of
like home flour but never like yes sir
yeah wait wait flour have you grown do
you think that lends itself to making
the best pack
for home use
in terms of yield or flavor who you're
looking for
what are you looking for when you make
your own personal use what are you
looking for to try cons well I think
like you know there's different textures
of oils right like an OG Kush is gonna
give you a very like sappy oily kind of
right and then a chem D is gonna be a
little bit gritty ER and then a
strawberry guava like it has a more
sandy trek home so you're gonna get like
a drier kind of a sift right you know
and and so it just really depends on
what kind of mood I'm in because it's
always changing you know so you know one
cycle I'll grow some oh geez right and
I'll be very into that wet oil right and
then the next round I'm like I'm one a
little bit of fruit right so I'll switch
it up and then I usually find you get
this this kind of sandy or not always
right but you know the sandy you're kind
of trichome heads from that kind of
stuff but right now it's very much into
the like that just like that wet live
resin you know and just like with the
Terps and everything it's very beautiful
almost like that apple sauce texture you
know and you got to like stir it up back
in your home
Colorado who is crushing like could he
disrespect as a cultivator or an
extractor
oh man there's in Colorado quite a few
people the herbal cure always you know
they gave me my first opportunity and
they gave me a place to call home you
know so I'm always thankful for them
because you know without that
opportunity I wouldn't be able to be
here today talking to you you know and I
wouldn't have met you know my good
friend Ben who gave me the opportunity
to come here so of course first and
foremost them I believe 710 labs as far
as commercial hash who's pushing
boundaries right Green Dot labs is
another one when it when is 710 labs
doing that you think is battery poison
like what do you notice in your life man
they run like no-till beds and their
flour right they're really just about
cultivating the best oils and they don't
even go for at least the way I heard it
right and I could be wrong I I don't
want to be misspoken because I have a
lot of respect for them
but I heard they kind of have some kind
of system where they go for like oil
pearlite not necessarily like pounds for
life right and so just kind of they're
changing the game in that kind of
mindset and the way people think and I
always appreciate that because that's
breaking the mold and they're always
trying to educate and push boundaries
and you know when I look at people like
that it makes me feel like I suck right
and then that's the best feeling because
then I get fired up I'm motivated right
and so you know green dots another great
example he always has new genetics he's
always breeding something new when his
hashes phenomenal you know so he's
pushing a lot of boundaries you know so
you know I believe 710 is doing indoor
they also are in California as well I
don't know if they're doing any outdoor
and I'm not sure I know Green Dot has
indoor I'm not sure if they're doing any
outdoor for that well but I do know like
they also I believe like if your
products good enough they'll like
process for you right so I'm sure they
they might process for some outdoor
people
look at your trike ons
yes sir exactly and those are my
favorite kind of people right it looks
like I think you should be judgmental
when it comes to your weed right you
should be concerned about what you put
in your body like you don't have
something to filter this right it's
getting right directly into your
bloodstream so you should be a little
more mindful right like and it's helped
me be mindful in like my health in
general right because then it's like
okay well now I need to eat better right
like you know for the longest time I was
more concerned about making sure my
plants got all the nutrition while I
give was like eating Cheetos you know
and now now it's like it's helped
educate me right so it's like this back
and forth relationship of like how can I
get the best out of it and then through
that it gets the best out of me you know