okay you guys ready for our musical
guest
yes all right live
from are you guys in tel aviv
all right you guys ready to to let it
rip
all right here is your here is our
musical interlude
[Music]
nice you hear the piano
yep all right
[Music]
foreign
oh
[Music]
such a night
got to steal away
baby your eyes
[Music]
came
here i am
if i don't know
[Music]
sweet confusion
oh
[Music]
you
here i am
[Music]
harmonica
so
[Music]
oh
up
[Music]
boys
thank you so this this is that
the house band all right
guys
yeah so so this this was a tease and a
test for everyone uh next time we'll
have like like basically
this is recording through your laptop
audio that's right
well it sounded pretty good as is so i'm
excited for the future but uh
we appreciate it and they're limiting
factors their neighbors complain
it's uh 9 p.m in tel aviv and uh
they're not allowed to be loud past 9
p.m so
we appreciate it guys uh benny i'll
check in with you
uh tomorrow we appreciate it and uh
have a good end of your evening in
israel yeah
thank you thanks guys thank you guys
see you guys thank you bye-bye
all right back to our regularly
scheduled program