[Music]
here we are at all the flowers we're
talking to a famous sunshine Johnson
from southern Humboldt famous dry farm
cultivator so tell us about your cell
and tell us about what you're doing
right now you're here at Hall of flowers
and you have new packaging so talk to us
about the process of getting your new
packaging together well I'm currently
very busy getting ready for my harvest
preparations on the farm and this is I
don't really have a lot of shots to just
leave the farm right now there's a lot a
lot going on getting ready for harvest
and I came down here to yeah I came down
here to show my packaging and this is it
now this is new this is new this is new
I'll be working on this for about nine
months okay so this is sunshine Johnson
Sun volt grown loopy fruit and her new
packaging which is new there's something
unique about the packaging so why don't
you walk us through it
this is a mason jar canning jar lots of
different uses this is also probably
well not for long but currently the
biggest jar on the shelf it's probably
even got the biggest buds and can I hold
this and you can open it up sure
so it took till legalization to finally
vacuum see all my jars very excited
about this so when you open it it pops
makes a nice pop down and this is now I
I don't know what the shelf stability is
but it definitely helps create shelf
stability
this has got big buds of loopy fruit
yeah yeah there's a package in there and
[Music]
this is what the big butter loopy free
looks like this is from the 2018 harvest
the question that people ask when they
look at the loopy fruit is is that last
year's because my herb is properly dried
and cured it actually gets better with
age and I would not want to release it
too soon because the one thing that I do
on my farm which is pretty it's pretty
common in agriculture to cut early and
rush to market and that is something
that I do not do I let things hang and
get ripe and hear the proper amount of
time and I don't release it until it's
ready so is there an ideal sort of
waiting or shelf time for your flower I
mean you're saying it actually gets
better and this is also vacuum sealed so
it's not going to degrade no and you
want to wait so it's done curing before
you seal it that's a mistake that a lot
of people make so how long is your
occurring process the soonest I package
will be early February late January
that'd be the earliest I would start and
then I would continue I'd continue
packaging all the way up until May so
your harvesting when I'm harvesting in
October and getting about a six month
Kieran it that's pretty rare isn't it
six-month cure yeah and it could even go
longer this actually went a bit longer
than I intended but in the creation of
the packaging took a long time to get
this out but even now people are loving
it
there's all they say is is this is last
year's and then they're like wow wow
this is really good there's no question
about the dollars your process your
curing process alone is the complete
opposite of commodification of mass
production at the lowest costs
so let's talk about the difference
between craft and commodity well a lot
of the commodity market is currently
being driven by simply for cannabinoids
that's it
no terpenes no flood not even any plant
matter just strictly cannabinoids and
that's a real drive to the bottom that's
just a bulk product and the flower
market is a bit different but even so
you still find commodity in the flower
market and yeah the commodity market is
just a it's a real drive to the bottom
and it's also driven on a grading system
so as opposed to craft and so what
criteria is brought to bear how is that
great well you don't really I mean you
you can grade it but really what you're
looking for is you're looking for the
quality standards that produced it and
because the quality standards along the
way are very important because you can
choose to cut corners or not cut corners
and it really depends on what it is that
you're looking for so with with mine I
might resonant for instance I will if
you let the plant get ripe you will lose
color you your plants won't be as bright
green when you cut your resin is going
to turn a slight I don't want to say
brown but gold in color it's not white
it's not it's not doesn't have that
bright white look to it and and the buds
are not as bright green because you're
letting it the plant age a little bit
longer while it's still in the ground
and so if you don't know you might look
at that and if you're just doing a
commodity style grading you're like oh
the colors not right oh the resins not
right and then and so that's part of it
and then also just being an outdoor
grower my stuff is just hanging out
there it only comes once a year I'm not
under a greenhouse I take a lot of risks
growing in this way
and it comes out different I
winburn it's quite windy and in the
winburn can cause the buds to be a
slight can turn even a bit of an
off-color we're in the wind directions
you can get the bud and you can bike a
little bit too toned and that's just
from the wind and there's there's
nothing wrong with that interesting I
didn't even know about wind burn now we
should also say that you grow a portion
of your harvest for you submit tomato
with nausea to make hashish yes thank
you I do is the curing process or the
process different for that when you're
curing for hash is that different does
that go so because the resin so if if
you're curing for flour you still want
to produce a lot of resin yes for my
flower crop I will cut it before the
hash I will let the hash crop go as long
as I can and I will harvest the flower
crop a bit just a little bit earlier
than the hash crop but the one thing
that's important with the hash crop and
one of the things that's also unique to
Naja is that one of the things that I
like is I like a little bit of plant
matter in my hash and the reason why is
because it added it adds complexity it
adds texture to the smoke and if it's
well cured if it's well dried it's
properly dried and well cured when you
go to smoke the hash made from and
there's some of that plant matter in
there it will show itself very well and
it adds that complexity wow this really
is craftsmanship at its purest and then
the idea is to transfer that into the
marketplace right and and to receive the
appreciation that you're deserved the
appreciation yeah I just be true to
myself and that's what's important there
may be some appreciation here and there
it may take time but I don't you know
yeah I just I'm just gonna live my life
to the fullest
very very very chill of you very zen of
you so
how did you get into the making the hash
tell us that very quickly and is that
important to you and you want to
continue doing that yeah the ice water
hash is it's its whole plant medicine
and it's very powerful medicine it's
really it's just I can't even tell you
how many levels it works with people and
and I just I I just really want to grow
the best herb that I possibly can to
make the best hash because I feel that
it's such an important medicine and it's
also one of the most decadent products
you can get out of the cannabis plant
you can literally take the rapists resin
heads and hold it in your hand from that
crop like the literal cream edges which
is the the full melt that you can get
which is very good medicine too
especially for people who have health
issues because it's a vapor at that
point and the plant matter in the hash
may not be appropriate for people who
aren't necessarily in the best of health
Wow you know the way you describe it you
know I'm a hash lover I can't wait to
taste some of it but your process is so
long you're gonna probably be like
curing your hash product through next
May and so the nausea product will
probably come out next July or all
depends it depends really on the hash
maker and he can decide that oh okay he
can decide that he has some other
parameters that he likes getting me all
mouth water that I got you know how are
we gonna when will we be able to
experience this it's on the Shelf good
you can look for the rebel moon or the
North cow diesel and it's on the shelf
it's one of the best value buys out
there and it is I grew the crop just for
hash it's all over the state two strains
no it's it's just one string and I just
did a name changed halfway in there it's
just anyway so the rebel moon is out
there and it's very it's it's very good
I I grew that
just just for a hash crop I let it hang
a bit longer and I hope to let it go
even longer this year now as a part of
your you're really busy right you have a
lot going on in fact you're not even
here right now your brain is somewhere
else right that's great so we're getting
rid of the real actually the real truth
out of you you know this is like a truth
serum so you also do a lot of educating
you know you do seminars you do speaking
are you gonna continue doing that to get
your unique message of craftsmanship and
artistry out there yeah yeah I do I
would like to to stay as or I would like
to keep doing education and even expand
on it would you describe what you do I
mean is it educating are you just
getting a message out what do you do
well there has its own message so that's
what part of it and just along for the
ride in that regard and then yes there
is it is an important time to have a
message and and even no matter how good
my herb is the message can be even more
important let me ask you this do you
have specific messages for specific
groups like say if I say do you have a
message for retailers that you they need
to understand about cannabis
yeah yeah the retailers are I'm not the
direction that the retail market is
taking is it's just downright evil it's
really not it's not a good place to be
and part of it is that I really value my
my relationships and when I work with
someone we work together and what's
happening with retailers is that we I
mean I knew this was going to happen as
a farmer that I was going to carry the
entire tax burden so when you go to
retailer they want to take half of the
half of the profit plus a little more
well what's that little mark oh it's
that excise tax the retailers for taking
half of the profit I just feel that
they're lousy partners and are they
gonna work for me are they gonna work
for that that half and I just kind of
wonder at times now they're talking
about wanting shelf space and if I'm
gonna be marketing everything doing all
the packaging all the marketing I might
as well just going with a delivery
service really and trying to pass some
savings on to the people that's
interesting you've spoken before about
how you feel like direct-to-consumer is
a port important part of your future do
you still believe so I just want to
return back to the retail aspect because
I do have good retail partners out there
and those are independent shops and it's
really important that we maintain these
independent shops and so I definitely
want to be there to support those
retailers that we share similar values
in a similar message app absolutely so
I'm just talking about a general trend
that I see see happening right right no
I understand
in many ways it's about it's it's a
segmented industry and for some people
their values are predominant so they're
finding those people to work with who
share their at their values in ethics
that seems to be a theme for certain
types of people
yeah absolutely yeah and why not you
know it's it's a it's a cutthroat
industry I mean and it's cutthroat out
there so if it's going to be cutthroat
you might as well work with people who
share your values so they don't cut
through your throat yeah it's been a bit
challenging to be a farmer and I knew
that so it's like just a quote and
Anthony B song everyone wants to raid
raid the barn and no one wants to grow
the corn and that's just what it feels
like every day
interesting well you're sticking to your
guns and nothing's going to deter you
you've been doing this a long time your
generational right you come from a
family of growers is this correct your
mother grew and my brother is also a
permanent licensed farm yes our our
original family farm out on the Mottola
who as you told me earlier you have it
all right now you have all the pieces
that you need to move forward so what
are those pieces well it does take I
mean to be to be not just premium but to
be ultra premium there's only like four
things that you you really need you need
a good backstory which I have you need
to show high pioneering and in an early
leadership which I have which I am doing
and you also need quality and
consistency which I spent the past few
years I mean I've been growing my whole
life but I really had to work on this
quality and consistency I had to very
quickly sophisticate my growing and my
drying and caring and take all these
years of knowledge that I have and apply
it and you got to have quality and
consistency the other and then the other
part that you need is you need premium
packaging and the tricky part about
packaging is getting packaging that
equally matches your story and I did
this myself I mean I worked I worked
with people a number of people to help
me bring this to
but this was my my vision yeah yeah so
I'm just very grateful and this was a
big part this was very probably one of
the more difficult parts is to get that
story and put it into a package now your
story isn't just you but it also
involves your community doesn't it
absolutely and that's a great question
and I want to thank you for asking that
because when it does make a difference
I've talked to other multi-generational
growers from other parts of the state
and it's not the same as when you grow
up in a community of growers and that's
how I grew up and the sharing of
information and the community that we
created around our outlaw culture and
our growing was very formative for me
well you're not just a member of the
community you're an activist member of
the community you have a radio show on K
mud so you're really in touch with the
people in your community right yeah yeah
somewhat I mean I yeah I mean I try to
be yeah I mean okay so to the extent
that you are I can't let you go without
you talking about what's the state of
southern Humboldt right now of your
brothers and sister cultivators in
general can you speak to that a little
bit about you know what's going on yeah
it's an exciting time there's been just
just with perseverance and some our
community values of just doing it
ourselves it's it's happening and it's
very exciting to see to see us get
through this and to see where this is
going and it's also been a struggle
there's been abatements going out to
growers and there's also been you know I
I'm there's parts of the county
government that have been very good to
us but there's also still just a little
bit of discrimination left over from
just all of these years
of us being growers and other people
work in their office jobs and maybe them
be an envious I don't know or jealous
but like whatever it is we still there's
still a tiny bit of discrimination among
for us multi-generational growers but
that will change humble County is
working on an equity program and we're
opening up this discussion and I hope to
see some good changes around that and
some healing in our community and also
we were we just have such a great
rebellious spirit and I'm really looking
forward to seeing us all just we're
gonna push back at these market forces
and we're just gonna be ourselves and
true to ourselves and true to the plant
that's really a really incredible is
Appalachian still alive is that still a
plant is that still something that is
important to the region yes marketing by
region is is one of the best ways to do
marketing because it creates this
informal collective and it challenges
all of us to compete in a healthy way of
wanting to grow the best because anyone
who's growing something terrible it
hurts all of us so there's this collect
as a collective we want to all be
growing the best and the highest-quality
and that's the one thing that we have in
Humboldt some of our strongest marketing
aspects is that we have consistency from
a region and that's really powerful and
I'm just very yeah that's wonder that's
definitely it's one of our biggest
marketing strengths for sure so you know
I ask kind bill this and I'm gonna ask
you is there is like what will it be
that like like the 2020 to harvest like
can it will be that was a great year
that it's like like a like a wine
harvest yeah you know yeah there are
some things about the way that growers
like myself who just grow in the full
Sun without greenhouses and I am gonna
protect some of my more delicate
flowers with a with a row crop cover
because these rains coming in the fall
are coming down so hard that they can
just beat down your bud and that's
something that you will see different
vintages if you want to call them that
where if we have some hard rains those
outdoor growers their buds might not be
looking as good and that ripe resin can
get kicked off so that's that's a
concern but one of the things too is
we've been having these cool nights and
the sugars that develop from cool nights
are just some of the best and so there
will be vintages for sure and I feel
that the the hash will capture quite a
bit of that is it is it will it like
like with wine will it be able to be
used marketing wise in the market do you
think yeah yeah there will possibly but
especially with the hash which can be
library Dan aged that actually I mean
and Frenchy always talked about this
about how the temple balls really get
better with age and the best one he ever
had was 15 years old that's amazing and
that is some amazing medicine that's
really about power so one could see like
with uh with corn yaks and with things
where you have a 25 year old
you know temple ball that goes for an
extraordinary amount of money well if I
wasn't such a poor farmer I'd be
librarian and all that hash but I this
is just what happens you got it you just
gotta sell it well I mean it really but
kind of bodes well for a glorious future
if it can unfold the way it should
unfold you know with the right products
being appreciated by the right people at
the right price point in the marketplace
you know yeah yeah that's that's true
and then also this this
commercialization of of this industry is
one of the things that that I feel very
hopeful about is is the home grower the
home grower is going to keep this
culture of giving and sharing and it's
really important that everyone grows
there's six plants
and because that's its I mean going back
to to education I I have a special
connection or I have a connection with
with this herb and I can't express
enough how how much growth I have gone
through growing growing this medicine
and and I would hope that everyone out
there can also experience that tune
wonderful this has been a wonderful talk
and you know the more we get into it you
know the more we can talk because you
know it's all about the details and
getting into it but that's the essence
of craft isn't it it's how you do things
it's the process you know and and that's
what make that's I mean I my sense of
what crap makes craftspeople special and
what they care about is is every step of
what they're doing yeah just having
curiosity and always being changing and
always having something going on just
like always exploring well you know
there's such a strong craft history in
in this industry and we can only hope
that it thrives and survives that's why
we're here I think so yeah thank you so
much