welcome everybody I'm Adriene Giovinco
inspired CEO really excited to kick off
today we're really excited to share this
content with you and be part of
contributing to the collective knowledge
that's out there in the field today
we're going to talk about what happens
when we cut mature cannabis flowers down
and take the months of hard work and
love we put into nurturing these plants
into finished product full of the
compounds patients need and consumers
want the compounds I'm talking about are
cannabinoids terpenes and flavonoids
collectively referred to as secondary
metabolites these compounds often serve
as defense mechanisms by the plant but
have been bred over centuries to bring
out unique characteristics that humans
find useful for medicines flavorings and
recreational drugs all of the parameters
that are at play when the plan is
photosynthesizing are still at play in
the curing stage as we learn about more
later curing cannabis is all about
strategically managing these parameters
to get the very best cannabis to market
there are common practices taught by
generations of successful cultivators
that are widely used at scale to work
but as science makes its mark on the
industry are there lessons to learn
are there more efficient less
labor-intensive ways to dry and cure the
that allow us to capture more of this
valuable secondary metabolites our
exploration has opened up questions at
the same time it's provided answers and
we're excited to take a closer look the
pilots of today's presentation are
inspired CTO Robby bass and inspires
cannabis business strategist Jesse
Porter so what is curing cannabis it's
the process that controls against
product loss and degradation add value
and brand recognition but it's so much
more it's an art it's a science it's an
expression a signature and a sign of
quality the end user wants a product
that smokes clean tastes great and
reflects the potency and effects of the
genetics the craft cultivator wants a
product that reflects all the
passion and hard work that went into
cultivating the genetics we see hearing
as a choke point and an opportunity
controlling the curing process creates
consistent results in predictable
product flow but we always wonder you
know how much product you lost are in
caring the temperature degradation
handling the blood rot to light exposure
could you put a number on it it can have
a significant financial impact and it's
an aspect of cannabis production often
overlooked mismanaged or misunderstood
by entrepreneurs and cultivators of
light appropriate caring will increase
your price per pound and extraction
yields it will reduce the amount of
product loss to bud rot and pathogens
curing will increase shelf life and
importantly hearing cannabis is better
medicine the desired effects potency and
flavor all directly tied to the
secondary metabolites produced during
that flowering phase these flavonoids
terpenes and cannabinoids combine to
create the true entourage effects that
make you love a strain and in order to
protect those secondary metabolites it's
important to understand the science of
what is happening when we care cannabis
and I'll be honest we're all trying to
understand the science behind caring
cannabis and we admit the research on
the topic is lacking we've spoken with
molecular biologist atmospheric
physicists chemists research scientists
cannabis cup winners I even talked to
some guy with a particle accelerator we
talked to cheese makers dry aged meat
producers wine makers and Colin E or
herb manufacturers we pulled out it from
licensed cannabis producers around the
u.s. we're doing our own research as we
speak there are still some unknowns some
variables that need to be controlled and
some tests that need to be done we've
collected some useful data that we'd
like to contribute to the discussion on
caring what we do know is that cured
cannabis is more desirable and
understanding the process will increase
yield and produce cannabis cup winning
results
so what's the difference between drying
and caring we get this question a lot I
usually say you can dry in the oven but
you cure with care and what I mean by
that is trying is part of the curing
story but it's not the whole story
drying cannabis is about removing enough
moisture so the product can be smoked or
otherwise processed I mean throw it in
the oven at 200 degrees for an hour and
it'll be dry but it won't be enjoyable
curing cannabis is a controlled process
that protects secondary metabolites
furthers chemo type expression and
creates an enjoyable smoke carrying
cannabis accounts for the time and
conditions required to maximize
expression and preserve the product and
when it comes to talking about the best
product it's important to know when to
harvest to get the most out of your
efforts this part of the process does
have some art involved as trichomes
develop they go through three distinct
phases and after the plant is harvested
that development continues for a short
period of time the trichomes develop a
stem and a head that I sort of think
result resembles a mushroom begins clear
and the head swells matures and becomes
cloudy cloudy trichomes are at the peak
of ripeness and the goal is the harvest
as many of them as possible when the
trichomes begin to degrade they turn
amber and signal an eminent harvest so
what's the tricolor and what's in it
well here's a drawing of one it has
around 30 flavonoids 200 terpenes and
140 cannabinoids give or take a few and
we don't want to lose any at all this
mushroom had we developed in flour
contains the majority of the good stuff
the secretory cells have the terpenes
and the secretory vesicles have the
cannabinoids we want to make sure that
they are fully developed and protected
through the entire packaging pipeline
once harvested the plant stops
transpiring begins rest firing and needs
to be managed to protect the product the
handling of the product
must be done with care in order to make
sure delicate trichomes heads are not
destroyed and that brings us the factors
of degradation handling is a factor of
degradation but as Brian mentioned
earlier all ten cardinal parameters of
plant influence impact hearing light
humidity temperature co2 airflow and
atmospheric conditions water oxygen
microbes nutrients they're all at play
understanding how each influence is each
other and the cannabis product during
shearing is an important step in the
refinement of the process
first let's talk about temperature as it
drives the time line associated with
moisture removal a hotter than ambient
temperature the faster the product dries
we know that if we draw a product too
quickly however the result will crumble
to a powder and lack appeal one reason
for this is that the temperatures above
68 degrees Fahrenheit can volatize
terpenes and degrade secondary
metabolites temperature will also impact
the speed and completion of enzymatic
reactions within the plant so raising
temperatures 10 degrees will double the
speed of enzymatic reactions but when
temperatures are too cold enzymatic
reactions hole in order to uniformly
cure cannabis temperatures should be
consistent and below 68 degrees at all
times to drive enzymes and protect
secondary metabolites and while low
temps slow passage and development it
can also cause discoloration and
susceptibility to decay mperatures and
time are a balancing act when we think
about curing lights also a major factor
in caring we know that if light is
present plants will continue to produce
chlorophyll which is unwanted for the
next phase but light also negatively
affects oils visible light triggers the
auto oxidation process and UV light
causes photo oxidation both of which
degrade oils especially those
monoterpenes monoterpenes have been
shown degrade rapidly under the presence
of light and high temperatures like in a
matter of hours so I think this is one
area where fresh frozen processing is
fantastic it allows for the capture of
more monoterpenes that what other buyers
deloft in the curing process moving
forward another major influence on the
curing process is humidity humidity is
about the moisture in the room as well
as in the bud and we know buzzer between
80 to 95 percent water weight at harvest
and most of that moisture needs to be
removed so one core concept of caring is
that we migrate the moisture from the
interior of the bud to the exterior
and while high moisture content
facilitates passage and growth in bud
rod studies have shown that reducing
moisture content of the bud below 20%
prevents microbe growth and increases
shelf life the slow and controlled
progression of moisture facilitates
chemical enzymatic reactions and allows
the water to pull more unwanted
materials from the plant but slow
controlled moisture removal requires
more than just some fans it takes an
understanding of pressures engineering
and controlled measurement and speaking
about controlled measurement we need to
reduce the moisture content of the bud
below 20% but precision is important the
difference between 19% moisture in the
bud and 14% moisture in the bud is well
5% right but that 5% of water weight
could easily be worth millions of
dollars at scale millions take some time
to digest that in about time when it
comes to curing time there's a balancing
act between terpenes loss and the
completion of the enzymatic processes
when it comes to terpenes time is the
enemy as they get grade every single day
for enzymes time is a friend who allows
for the completion of the enzymatic
processes with limited time enzymes to a
limited job in the breakdown of starches
in chlorophyll leaving the final product
harsh and tasting like alfalfa take you
long and risk the exposure to microbial
outbreaks breakdown and degradation of
secondary metabolites which will destroy
bag appeal it takes a delicate touch to
balance terpene loss and enzymatic
processes needed to make for a superior
consumable
atmospheric conditions like gases in the
room will influence the curing process
as well one effective atmospheric
conditions is oil oxidation which
accelerates with the concentration of
dissolved oxygen and depends Laurel
Affiliate largely on the oxygen
pressures in the headspace as well as
the ambient temperatures oil oxidation
is an undesirable series of chemical
reactions involved involving oxygen that
degrades the quality of oil oxidation
eventually produces rancidity in oil and
acrimonious flavors and smells and while
all oil is in a state of oxidation you
can't stop it completely
there are ways to reduce it modified
atmospheric packaging m80 map is a
useful system which makes it possible to
regulate the composition of atmosphere
in the headspace and thus control the
rate of respiration respiration is one
of the basic processes of deterioration
and it's highly influenced by the
atmospheric composition of co2 oxygen
ethylene and water vapor driven by
temperature during respiration oxygen is
consumed and co2 ethylene and water
vapor generated map allows you to
control atmospheric conditions that
impact hearing so you can slow down or
speed up respiration and other metabolic
processes this also allows you to reduce
sensitivity to ethylene reduce the
development of disorders and inhibit
pathogen development air exchanges in
the space and the control of atmospheric
conditions are imperative for the
control of the curing process however
it's important to note we need enough
oxygen long enough to trigger those
reactions but we need to limit dwell
time in order to protect the oils map
allows us to control these variables
so what in the plant makes it harsh
chlorophylls lipids sugars carbohydrates
amino acids water fertilizers and heavy
metals can all make the smoke harsh when
we're caring we're essentially trying to
remove or otherwise process out as much
of that other stuff as possible our
plants work hard to create this biomass
and flower enzymes work hard to remove
it afterwards
plants create chlorophyll which give the
plant its green color and undesirable
grassy flavor fats and sugars are also
created during the growth process and
become energy sources for the reactions
as the plant drives and cures but
excessive nitrogen and heavy metals and
the fertilizers can also impact curing
and cause Auto oxidation and long term
storage so proper plant nutrition during
flower and appropriate cultivation
techniques lead to better cured product
that is less susceptible to
deterioration something that makes the
cured product less harsh is respiration
that we mentioned earlier respirations
the process in which organisms convert
biochemical energy from stored food like
the sugars and starches from
photosynthesis into adenosine
triphosphate or ATP for ripening during
respiration plants take oxygen from the
air and give off carbon dioxide moisture
and heat the opposite of photosynthesis
and respiration continues until the
stored starch and sugar reserves are
depleted temperature dictates the speed
of respiration and is the most important
factor in influencing post-harvest life
and quality of a given product the
oxygen in the surrounding environment is
above most importance because it's the
primary gas to use during respiration
the lowering oxygen in the air allows
you to lower the respiration rate but if
there's not enough oxygen the product
goes into anaerobic fermentation and
will produce alcohols that
impart unwanted flavors
enzymes also play a role in respiration
and there are four enzyme groups
facilitating the curing process
proteases amylases lip Hayes's and
cellulases and they all break down
different stuff these enzymes use stored
plant energy to break down unwanted
plant materials like proteins nucleic
acids starches fats phosphate esters and
other macro molecular substances during
the cheering process I temperature
drives enzymatic reactions and affords
protections against microbial growth but
high temperatures will also negatively
affect secondary metabolites
temperatures that are too high or too
low will denature enzymatic activity and
that cannot be restarted these enzymes
need plant material heat proper pH and
moisture to activate and they need time
to work but their process creates longer
chain molecules that have unique flavor
and amplified effects in the case of
water in the case of curing waters both
a preservative an assault it plays a
critical role as a catalyst enzymes and
is a vehicle for removing unwanted
products from the bud hydrolysis is a
chemical reaction in which the
interaction of a compound with water
results in the decomposition of that
compound this process breaks down
chemical polymers into simpler units and
an example of that is turning starches
into sugars hydrolysis is one of the
most important processes that improve
the quality of cannabis as it cures as
water migrates out of the plant
it will remove byproducts from the
breakdown caused by enzymatic activity
and further the development of secondary
metabolites if water moves too quickly
there will not be enough time to
effectively compete complete the
processes if the process is too slow
you risk mold and other biological
contamination
water activity drives microbial activity
and that's why we need to remove it for
long-term storage
but in controlling water migration
through the plant we allow it to
modernize development stimulate
processes and produce a cleaner smoke
thinking about post-harvest diseases
curing and stored products are subject
to a variety of rots and decay caused by
fungi and bacteria unknown fungi that
can develop an occuring phase or
botrytis and Kazarian and some of the
bacteria sued ammonia and astralis these
diseases can cause color change
degradation and will certainly result in
a failed microbial test it's important
to note that many infections of diseases
start before harvest and when these
products are transferred to storage
infections continue to develop so proper
environmental controls product handling
and SOPs are required to prevent post
harvest diseases the caring space should
have appropriate biological filtration
in place to prevent contamination and
the growth of yeast bacteria and molds
sanitation biological filtration are
also important to handlers to protect
products from post harvest diseases
people carry pests we have about 10,000
microbes on each hand and we lose 40,000
skin cells every minute these are things
to consider in order to protect the
final product
what makes cannabis great turns out time
is a factor in chemo type expression the
process of polymerization is magical
studies show us that when cannabis is
cured over time we do not see an
increase in the quantity of terpenes we
see a measurable difference in terpene
profile terpenes marry commingle and
continue to develop and homogenize the
polymerization process takes sort of
fantastic individual terpenes and
harmonizes them in a way specific to the
genetics and ball it's like going from
mono to stereo and flavor and effects so
we know that during the curing phase
secondary metabolites reconnect to
create new compounds not present at
harvest this is when the product becomes
unique and stands out in the market I
think this is also a very important
aspect of medical viability as well when
my mom was sick with cancer we tried
every strain we could find and the
results were inconsistent
I think the curing was inconsistent to
when cured correctly the terpene
cannabinoid expression has fully
developed and is more capable than the
individual metabolites cured cannabis is
better medicine curing creates a better
recreational product - but better yet
polymerization allows for the true team
of our expression of strains if we
really want to know the medical
viability of each genetic we need to
make sure that we cure it appropriately
in order to capture the symphony of
polymerized secondary metabolites and
not just a few standout notes so how do
we consistently achieve great results
understanding the factors we just talked
about there are a variety of coaches
that we have seen have success in the
market first is the legacy birth this
classic process has been refined for
generations it has a rich history of
success
the core concept here is to harvest the
plant remove the fan leaves hang it
upside down blast it with air until it's
crispy to the touch
then bucket put it in an airtight
container burp it and monitor it many
iterations of this method exist everyone
has a different opinion on how long and
how often to birth and even how long did
you err is it 7 days 14 days 30 days 6
months depends on who you ask what we do
know is that this system works but we
don't fully understand why even at the
highest level of academia they're
studying this legacy method to better
understand the science behind the
results understanding what happens to
these buds scientifically while they're
in this airtight environment should
prove to be a very strong breakthrough
in curing cannabis science another
method we've explored is freeze drawing
and I'll admit at first I thought it was
a gimmick but then I experienced the
nose and bag appeal of products that had
been freeze-dried uname important to
note that this level of freeze-dried
carrying is not something you do with a
harvest right survival freeze dryer it's
a precision machine built and operated
by professionals oversight and
understanding is needed but the core
concept here is that we vacuum purge the
water from the product remove the water
from the chamber then freeze dry the
product freeze dry is one of the best
ways to halt the degradation process to
protect THC in the secondary metabolites
however this process does require
delicate hands to not damage the product
and a fundamental understanding of
timelines to make sure that appropriate
enzymatic activities can occur we are
all excited to follow the evolution of
this technology and see where it leads
us speaking of technology I'll let our
CTO take it from here and talk about
how we've been refining the process of
drawing and curing in the same room rob
thicke thanks Jesse
you got everyone over I'd inspire we
delved into providing these environments
control systems for drying and curing we
went to the best we went to the worst
and we look at all the different parts
of between and we came to the
realization that the most specialized
and effective combined drying and curing
chambers on the market have the
following features they can accurately
control temperature and humidity in a
wide range and they can have a
substantially high airflow rate relative
even to the cultivation rooms we were
designing at around 20 to 30
interchanges per hour but we were still
being asked to design a large-scale
drying room in one part of the facility
in a curing room in the other and this
naturally led us to wonder what's the
point of drying in one room and then
curing in another specialized device
being a jar a Tupperware container or a
card bare cardboard barrel why can't we
try and cure cannabis in the same space
now this might end up being one of those
game-changer ideas that flies in the
face of conventional wisdom jesse was
just describing that conventional
technique earlier the drying step and
the curing step it happened in two
different rooms well this is a
tried-and-true approach it brings with
it this extra incurred cost of labor
equipment and real estate and also you
have a risk of damaging the product in
the transfer from one spot to the other
you know why take up two different areas
in a facility anyways for drying and
then curing if instead it could be done
quickly and in the same space why not
use that freed up floor area for like
bigger and better things I don't know we
don't drilling more plants so if you
want to design a dry cure room and
handle this in one fell swoop let's talk
about some of the ideas that might serve
you well the first place to start is
with confidence that you've got
consistent airflow around the product in
the room you're trying to cure we
consider this to be a task for the CFD
modeling software we employ and it's a
good way for us to provide a strong
validation to our curing room physical
layout suggestions you're also going to
want to have a strategy for moisture
removal over time you want to
understand whether it's going to be a
tenday linear drying rate with the same
amount of moisture remove each and every
day or some other strategy but this is
going to form the basis for your
equipment selections now if you want to
take it to the next level you'll want to
start talking about what those actual
set points in the room are going to be
you'll probably want to target a
specific temperature for product quality
maintenance and a humidity level that
allows you to realize the strategy you
came up with on the previous slide to
maintain the balance of that highest
level of terpene retention our
reasonable curing and polymerization
rate and a satisfactory level of
enzymatic activity then that temperature
is probably gonna be around 65 degrees
Fahrenheit and humidity anywhere from 50
to 65% now the most advanced way to
approach this task is to automate the
whole thing it is possible the field
feedback moisture removal from the
product back into your humidity control
scheme so we've seen a number of systems
do this but the most accurate way seems
to be tracking the weight of the product
through time in the curing room and the
best data we have tells us that the rate
of moisture removal changes over time at
a given temperature and humidity
setpoint in the space but if instead of
fixing your temperature and humidity
let's say we just fixed the temperature
we could manipulate the space humidity
to change the vapor pressure on the
moisture content of the plants and this
directly controls the rate of drying now
again
manipulating the room vapor levels
controls the moisture removal and gives
you the ability to slow down or increase
moisture loss over time allowing some
polymerization and curing to happen at
the same time as the drying step this is
the best way to achieve a hands-off
approach to the curing process and also
deliver consistency through benchmarking
from batch to batch we don't expect
curing strategies to be fixed over time
and neither should you even the
differences in bud structure of
different crop genetics will be
influential in determining a signature
curing methodology that you can attach
to your product flexibility in the
conditions you can maintain might be
even more important in this regard so
how did you get into the actual InDesign
keep the following ideas in mind first
if you're going to turn your room into a
big cheering jar you really need to
think about sealing your room
tight construction and filled concrete
floors are some of those considerations
this is going to prevent gases from
getting into and out of the room we love
your control to that end you'll probably
want to break the seal every once in a
while you should consider a mechanism to
ventilate or burp the room just like you
wouldn't a jar to do this effectively
you'll need a way to bring atmospheric
air into this space to delete the
build-up of gases and be sure you've got
at least Merv 15 filters on this
mechanism on the room exhaust be a good
neighbor and consider an odor
remediation systems that you're not
exhausting air that other people in the
neighborhood might find offensive when
you release it into the atmosphere
lastly consider a sensor array for
determining when and how often you'd
like to ventilate or burp the room
sensing systems for ethylene are readily
available as well as for co2 as we heard
from Jessi these gases provide real
indications of the stage of curing
you've achieved monitoring them will
help you hone your caring strategy and
in the future I think we'll see
electronic monitoring of other specific
gases I mean she's got a system flexible
enough to incorporate what might be
coming by way of example we're finding
out that the pathogens we're trying to
avoid in the rooms actually generate
gases that usually can't be detected by
humans with a background of all the
other smells that are in there currently
claro ana soles and styles are compounds
of interest and we're as curious as you
are to see what ours and others research
leads us to in the study of the gas
sensing arena hey Jeff you there
absolutely Rob great job I was buddy
back to you to wrap up this puppy you
know and that sort of brings us to the
end of our presentation I wanted to take
a moment to say that I really think
we're all in this together
sharing knowledge and going down the
path of education is only going to
improve the curing process but even when
we have enough data to talk objectively
there's going to be an artistic touch
that sets many people apart
a signature that's a byproduct of
experience and fuel and we just hope
that this webinar gives you some
information need to refine your
signature and paint your masterpiece so
thanks again for joining us today please
give us a few minutes to organize the
questions from the audience and for me
to get a few sips of tea and then we'll
jump into the Q&amp;A here the first
question is can you achieve
decarboxylation through curing and it
may it may be worthwhile to quickly
explain what the decarboxylation means
sure
so decarboxylation is essentially the
process that cannabis goes through to
become psychoactive traditionally we
associate that with heat a certain heat
requirement that changes the polymers
that allows them to be more psychoactive
so that product thing can be used
directly to manufacture edibles or even
consume directly to still get the
effects whereas fresh bud that's not be
carboxylated won't get you that
psychoactive effects I think an
interesting note here is something we're
still discovering Allison justice and
outcode did a study on curing hemp and
cannabis and what they found was that in
over the process of a 30-day cure right
around day 30 they actually achieved
decarboxylation which is a dramatic
breakthrough because that's not
something that's been proven to be
achieved through the curing process in
the past I wonder what the elements
involved are you know it's important to
understand the parameters and the
conditions the heat that was in fact in
impacting that that shared isolated
space but also the pressures and the
gases there are a lot of things going on
in that airtight space that could
actually contribute to decarboxylation
I think pH is another one too but anyway
there's a handful of things in there
that could they could affect
decarboxylation actually make it happen
and now it's been proven on paper so I
think it's something we need to explore
more but it's an interesting note that
we've actually seen through a study
it can be done I love it
to terpene rich psychoactive raw
cannabis some new to chew on I could be
pretty cool all right
no pun it one application for ya another
question coming in here at what point is
it no longer considered drawing securing
sure for me you know drawing is a
fundamental aspect of the curing process
but when you harvest the product you
immediately make a decision on whether
or not you're going to dry it or cure it
what I mean by that is that drying is a
route where you just try and add heat to
remove moisture and that's only one
small component of the curing process
that must account for all the other
things that are happening so you can try
without curing but you cannot cure
without drawing if that makes sense
that's sort of my perspective on it I
know we have some differential opinions
there but my feeling is that appropriate
curing will involve drawing where as you
can dry any way shape or form and the
curing process starts immediately upon
harvest it's the decisions you make from
that point moving forward that allow for
this game progression and polymerization
to have so you know the conversation is
just in hi I have on this or long and I
usually go right into the night I'm
convinced that you know the drying jet
through Jesse's persuasion I'm convinced
that the drying and curing can happen in
one short period of time traditionally
we see all sorts of things being asked
of us design a drying room here we're
gonna leave it in there for 10 days and
then we're going to design a curing room
over here put the things into jars or
whatever containers and move it into a
curing room in its own conditions and
let it cure in that in that area that's
usually also a seven to ten day process
and then it goes into bags and we see
the continuation of caring when we've
got map systems involved in the storage
of the product over time like I said
Jesse's convinced Utley we can do
otherwise and we've started to see the
data come back that yes you can do
drying and curing and polymerization
control caring control this can all be
done in one area but in the room that
you're doing it in you have to be able
to control different levels of gases
whether it's the water content of the
air whether it's the content of ethylene
in the air whether it's the content of
co2 in the air you have to be able to
independently control some of those
there they both know becomes a challenge
especially at scale in a large room
we're looking at those designs right now
we're doing our own tests and I can't
wait for part two of this webinar we can
come out and kind of reveal some of the
data that we've got oh when do you know
cheering is finished this another great
question
yeah I mean I think there's a subjective
aspect of interpreting that product if
you like to sort of listen to that new
book by max Montrose and his ethos on
how you determine whether or not
cannabis is good or bad or the level of
it I think there's some interesting
touch points in there that really give
us an idea on how we judge cannabis but
let's be honest there's two factors
right there's the test results and then
there's the customer experience and sell
through numbers and both of those things
sort of need to line up and and justify
that higher price point that's how we
tie it back to oh yeah we're going to
get those numbers and we're going to
achieve cleaner smoke and we're going to
get better self your numbers and better
brand recognition through caring it's
there's no better answer Jesse like just
like there's no better way to do it I
mean we measure all sorts of things in
terms of product quality and the KPI is
our bike you know grams per square foot
or whatever but the fact is it comes
down to bag appeal and it comes down to
does it move through the stores you know
if it's going towards the smoking
process people have got to see it smoke
it want it it's almost as much brand and
marketing as it is the actual physical
curing of it right so yeah great point
Robin something I want to add to that
too is that
there there's an ideal time or product
that we want to get but it's important
to understand the market pressures maybe
this doesn't quite apply to the six
plant grower or the craft consumer
that's growing cannabis for themselves
but a lot of times I think Rob you can
back me up here when we have
conversations at scale on hearing
there's a time line that doesn't
necessarily correlate to the curing
process that needs to be met and that's
a time line to get products into a space
out of a space and onto the shelf and I
think the more that we master that
process at a high commercial level the
more we'll see high quality products
come out of those commercial facilities
on a consistent basis what's happening
now I think just an opinion here is that
there's a race to market there's a need
of product in the market and that sort
of demands that these products get
pushed to market more quickly it's about
getting them out of the room in seven
days burping them in three bagging them
and moving them rather than
fundamentally understanding how we're
going to get 2% more THC 1% more terpene
and more flavonoid expression so for me
there's a pressure that goes on there
too that needs to be considered because
it's a real market pressure so we need
to work within these certain frameworks
so a lot of times when is it ready is a
matter of when can I get my money and
that limits some of the data that we've
been able to collect as we pursue more
can of Sewer products we see that yeah
that curing process takes a little bit
longer the product has better shelf life
and gets more money at the end that's a
long-winded and maybe didn't perfectly
answer the question but there's a little
bit of insight there I think well I
think we can also use this topic to
address Alexander's question which is
having separate rooms for dry cure has
been used to support perpetual grows can
you address this well the reason that a
separate room for drying and curing have
been used for perpetual grows is because
I've got two weeks in between harvests
and I have you know a drying room in a
curing room and if I do anything just
throw off the balance of my harvest I've
got to be able to move product through
my facility I think where we're going
with this is to
the state-of-the-art why aren't we
drying and curing in seven days you know
Jesse just mentioned seven-day DRI
three-day here a three-day bag that kind
of thing we're trying to compress the
drying and curing process by
manipulating variables and minimize the
infrastructure and facility you need to
take care of this process that's going
to be the next step and this is where
we're trying to push this if we're just
gonna be talking about having a separate
room for drying in a separate room for
curing sure you can go down any any path
you want to achieve the net effect but
at the end of the day you're you will be
better served if you can if you can hone
these homies processes and really
optimize the system that you're working
with
yeah great thanks very much and that I
would encourage everybody that's more
interested in some of the financial
impacts that this can have go to go to
the Revenue calculator and play with
some of those variables and see what how
much how much revenue or drop in
operating costs you might be able to
achieve by like getting more dollars per
pound on better cured cannabis lower
lordalu or lowering your operating cost
and on top of that like if you have any
more questions about curing and you want
to take a deeper dive you know reach out
to rob and I you know maybe we won't
talk to you until 2:00 in the morning
like we talk to each other but we'll
definitely get back to you and we love
to hear questions and contributions from
the community so thanks for the other
questions come in you have recommended
temperature and humidity conditions for
storing cannabis
it's been driving here yeah we've been
asked that question quite a bit so after
after it's been dried and cured you know
I think you mentioned Jessie mapped and
that's it's a really good way to
maintain the quality and the
environmental control of a product in
one specific aspect which is moisture
control in the container which is
storing it I think those things there
are secondary gasses that are also being
controlled and their levels being
controlled that you know I don't know
enough about map systems but they seem
to do a very good job and I mean Jesse
you tell me is that the typical way to
do things on the market today then times
on nitrogen flush and and what that's
all about
yeah I mean that that brings up all
other ball of wax but I think for the
most part I mean we know the the
cardinal factors that influence the plan
and cause degradation and once that
process the enzymatic process is halted
and we've removed enough moisture it's
really sort of about light and
temperature so have putting it into a
container where light doesn't penetrate
and temperature doesn't have a direct
impact will be beneficial and I think
we've seen a lot of people look to
commercial agriculture and commercial
packaging for solutions here which is
why we tend to have a lot of
conversations about nitrogen purging
essentially bringing in into gas into a
controlled space like a 55-gallon drum
which will essentially displace the
oxygen so that oxidation process won't
continue the idea is that now that will
hold in that state for a long period of
time and it can be shipped overseas or
wherever it needs to go or just held on
site to appropriate processing time the
issues we see with that are that we're
not exactly sure if there's a
degradation associated with that
nitrogen gas but what we do know is it's
been in these holding cells these
55-gallon drums let's call them for
conversation usually they're done in
metal drums for good long-term holding
for safety those drums are lined and as
those drums are impacted by atmospheric
conditions and temperature the terpenes
sweat and get absorbed by the liner
now in a long-term holding environment
you have to smoke the drums to get high
that tends to not have a lot of market
their viability so that that's one of
the situations we've seen come with long
term holding and nitrogen purging in
large spaces especially metal drums that
are line but really it's about you know
halting that oxidation process and if
you can stop photo oxidation and auto
oxidation by preventing light
penetration that's a huge first step
secondarily if we can continue to
control the temperature we'll have much
less volatile and and evaporation of
those secondary metabolites I think
there's a correlation here see our
corollary between weed and wine right if
you want to hold on to wine for a long
period of time you put it in an opaque
bottle you use a core oven to seal the
thing with nitrogen on top so that after
you've opened it you purge that oxygen
out you print prevent oxygenation and
you store the thing in a cool place I
think the same thing applies to weed
here if you're trying to maintain those
those same flavor profiles in weed
that's good point let's see let's move
on to a question about the mechanical
side of things how do you determine the
mechanical needs for a drying room
there's been several questions similar
to this yeah there's a good one too
because I see Nadia and Nadia's asked a
question about you know moisture removal
in the first 24 or 48 hours that kind of
thing Tim to Andy I want to start off by
saying that every every traditional
drying we room we go into they the
impression is they want the people who
are doing the drawing will want to
remove the most amount of moisture in
the first 24 or 48 hours we're gonna
remove 40 to 50 percent of moisture in
the first 48 hours I think there's
there's two things here I think people
are seeing that their rooms are under
designed and as such they can't maintain
a temperature and humidity anyways they
set the set points on the thermostat and
the humidistat but they end up losing
control because they don't have enough
moisture removal capacity which
means that if they don't have
independent temperature and humidity
control the humidity levels go way out
of whack and then the temperature
control goes with it it's one thing to
say you want to remove most of the
moisture in the first 24 or 48 hours I
don't think that's a necessary step IV
you can control temperature and humidity
you can do a very linear moisture
removal over time and that's going to
lead to a consistent moisture profile
inside and through the bud so that's
what we're trying to go for here we're
trying to avoid pockets of wet product
inside the bud that can lead to the
pathogen expression and when the
pathogen build up that we're trying to
avoid in the first place to maintain
product quality so you know how do we
how do we size these systems
you guys go back to what does the grower
really want to do or what does the
harvester processor really want to do
with the product are they going to if
they had their way could they control
the product quality over time by doing a
very linear moisture removal the same
amount of water take just taken out of
the plant every single day in the
seven-day 10-day three-day drying period
well I kind of accenting it comes with
control it comes with sizing correctly
we do have our own product input sheets
that we can talk you know we can have
you fill out and then talk about the
process after that it's you know it's a
matter of understanding best influence
of temperature and humidity on product
weight over time just you have any
comments about that linear linear drying
gras yeah I think it's sort of it sort
of speaks to a couple of different
processes that cost a lot of energy to
restart once they or re-energize once
they slow down what I mean by that is
that when you have you know a big spike
in moisture removal it's usually
associated with a spike in elevated
temperature which can have the ability
to text effects on those secondary
metabolites but you would it I what I
think it really comes down to is
precision control and putting this wet
weight in there and knowing how much
you're going to remove over the course
of time allows you to sort of game plan
for how long it's going to take with the
appropriate temperature and humidity set
points the spikes in temperature and
humidity either too high or too low you
know do things to enzymatic processes so
if you speed up the enzymatic process
early on and then you denature the
process later you're not going to have
completion of enzymatic processes so
that linear line that Rob talks about is
really sort of the concept of curing we
have water pressure that pushes the oils
to the outside we have the enzymatic
process which is fundamentally driven by
water and temperature and if we have
spikes we can have enzymes just sort of
you know go crazy and then die off
we need them to all sort of work
together with enough time in the
appropriate environment to break down
the things they need to break down we've
seen this technique applied with a
little bit higher temperatures to remove
a lot of moisture and inevitably the
smoke is a little bit more harsh and
tends to test a little bit lower on the
THC and terpene scale relative to the
biomass that's there there's still stuff
remaining in the bud that compromises
that test result so although it's it's a
wonderful conversation especially
talking about retarding microbe growth
and getting down to that 20% but if we
do it in a linear fashion it doesn't
allow moisture to be rican sumed by the
by the cannabis then we know that we are
moving to a finish line and not moving
in a circle
if that makes sense yeah well to your
point about curing being an art as well
as a science I have a feeling you
probably have some specific methods in
your sleeve to bring bring a fantastic
finished product to market that involve
different
princess once along the way but you know
that's loaded Brian you've been a part
of these conversations where I've been
screaming and yelling about five
different ways that I think are great to
do it and win a cannabis cup and and
then you know we talked about whether or
not those are possible and the real
science involved so yeah absolutely
we're still in the mode of discovery the
proof is in the pudding really good weed
is really good weed it's undeniable
I think interpreting is a big factor
here and really determining what good
weed is but the market will tell you
price point
use use sell through numbers and brand
recognition are a big factor because
they're tied directly back to the
product you produce well word has it
you've won a cannabis cup but in your
day maybe back in my day I may have won
many others with genetics but I bred
that I didn't actually compete with too
so it's a fun game to be a part of all
right very cool got another question
here about turkeys what percent terpenes
would you call high chirping content man
it's interesting you know because we see
a lot of different test results but you
know I think I saw some granddaddy
purple test it like 4% one time which is
sort of a real high mind-blowing number
and somewhere around 2% as far as a mass
mass collection of terpenes usually is
pretty good but again I think that the
quantity of terpenes although very
important and measurable the symphonie
that's created through polymerization
has been shown to just be more medically
effective or more psycho actively viable
for recreational products the quantity
of terpenes is important but more
important is the quality of each turkey
as I talked about the trichrome heads
they need to remain intact because they
have the secretory cells and the
secretory vesicles that contain
cannabinoids and terpenoids a lot of
ways to get it done and I think there
we're just sort of trying to figure it
out that's a good point I think when
you're when you're testing terpenes you
get just a overall an overall percentage
but you don't get you may not always get
to full the full profile or spectrums
those quantity and yeah but also quality
yeah man maybe we should think about
having a conversation about why we
should talk about spectrum and
cannabinoid profile in the same vein
that we talked about 40 percent THC test
results and four percent 13 results you
know what about that could cost me what
if I'm Way more high off above the test
at 18% than 28% it's happened I'd been
there was about the bud variability or
was it the polymerization process that
made me so much happier at 18% a lot of
considerations there and subjective as
well implications for for therapeutic
uses and medicinal uses as well
absolutely
all right and with shift gears back to
the mechanical side you have recommended
specific air flow velocities for Karen
no I don't the idea of a sort
lots of velocity ton low velocity so
we've seen some data for different herbs
that dry out and meaning cannabis we've
seen to see the numbers that if you're
maintaining consistent temperatures and
humidity it's the condition of the air
that matters more than the velocity of
the air so that end it's important that
you get the conditioned air to this to
the product that you're trying to cure
and dry but it's the quality and
quantity rather of humidity in the air
the temperature of the air that's going
to affect the drawing out process so
just make sure you have air flow the it
doesn't matter if you go faster so this
with the data showed us if you have way
too much air that's not a bad thing if
you have way too little that's a very
bad thing just get enough air to the
product so that you can think
homogenized the atmosphere
inside the room in not developed pockets
of moisture retention inside the bud I
think you know something that we're
still exploring here too and I think Rob
and I have seen a little bit of
differential data here's it you're
really not going to blow the trichomes
off the plant with air velocity it's
just something I want to bring up here
that you don't worry about applying so
much air that you think the trichomes
are gonna volatize or blow away that
that mechanical processes and what's
causing the evaporation of trichrome so
just wanted to put that out there yes if
anyone knows sure they know it's just a
blast it with air that's money okay
great
some questions coming in about different
different molecules in the air maybe we
can combine a couple here but questions
from NOAA is there any benefit to
drawing your journey in a more inert
environment to limit exposure to o2 like
an argon or co2 atmosphere with this
inhibit enzymatic activity and and maybe
we can also address the concept of
ethylene yeah I think great question
great question Noah and I think that you
know one of the reasons we talk so much
about math is that we know the
importance of these environmental
conditions and that they need to be
controlled and I think you nailed that
you alluded to it right the lack of
oxygen in the space or not enough oxygen
in the space is going to slow down
respiration prevent enzymatic activity
and could lead to anaerobic fermentation
so it's important to control that
environment but it's also important to
know what's in the air because there's
an amount of oxygen that's probably
accept acceptable that doesn't have a
huge negative impact that still
facilitates the process might even be
necessary for the process right I do
believe it is necessary although there's
oxygen within the plant and the cell
tissues I think that oxygen in the
environment is also of critical
importance and studies show that I'm
scared to get too far down the road of
ethylene because it's such a fun topic
for me to think
my experience in growing cannabis you
know is more than 15 years now and when
I first started growing after I
graduated from Cal I found that the
knowledge was legacy authors and tomato
studies so white papers on tomatoes and
books by guys like Ed Rosenthal and you
know forefathers of the industry and
that information you know it was in its
infancy we've come a long way since then
and I laugh because I rarely think about
tomatoes anymore when I cultivate
cannabis but when this ethylene
conversation comes up I can't help
myself you know in commercial tomato
production we know that ethylene is a
popular solution to packaging and
creating deliverables you know ethylene
is a hormone and they usually deliver it
as an external gas if you don't know you
know
tomatoes are picked green and then
basically gasped before sale in order to
change the color change the texture and
change the flavor further development of
this product and give it more market
share and value so my question always
sort of comes down to well in tomato
production it's a hundred to 150 ppm of
ethylene over the course of a 24 to 48
hour period with high humidity levels
85% or so and that triggers that
enzymatic reaction chemical reaction
within the tomato to make it a better
product so as I go further down this
path
I'm intent on studying the effects of
ethylene the build-up of ethylene in the
space specifically in airtight
environments under pressure I think it
can have a dramatic influence I want to
say that we're still exploring it
although it is a very popular approach
in commercial agriculture so there's a
lot of quote unquote tomato data to look
at we just don't have anything on
cannabis yet but also on a side note you
know we've talked to facilities and this
is third-party data that we've collected
just from conversations but have have
expressed concern for
whereas alene leaks in their facilities
or greenhouses because they've had
situations where they've tested high
levels of ethylene higher than normal
and their entire harvest you know will
be two weeks early with cloudy - amber
trichomes
two weeks before they extended and the
in such a growth right
lack of biomass lack of development
nightmare and harvesting because now
you're pulling down every single Bay
rather than a week by week staggered
approach so we know ethylene has an
impact on cannabis we're still trying to
figure out how it impacts the curing
process we know it's a byproduct but we
don't know the effects of the PPM's and
pressures associated with that so we're
still sort of exploring that if that
makes little sense it's really not even
a comment here about greenhouse tomatoes
being picked vine-ripened of course
because everything's better the
greenhouse and vine-ripened Tomatoes are
better house is opinion in a in as a guy
who has tomatoes in his backyard I will
preach let the tomato ripen on the vine
it has more access to sugars and
products to develop it's going to be
better what I'm bringing up here is just
simply the market pressures of producing
Tomatoes at scale which are now starting
to impact cannabis production as well
and I think it's important to look at
some of those you sure let's have the
craft grower that you know cures for 60
days and gets a better product without
any ethylene and complete control I
think that would be a superior product
but market factors might not allow that
to happen so we might need to look for
appropriate organic natural elements to
help us influence that product and make
it a better product for final final use
that's that's sort of I had totally
understand what Nadia saying she's
absolutely right
I just saying that there's there's a
differential application here that might
be applied to someone in a certain level
of scale with a certain style of
cultivation and distribution hopefully
that helps answer the question
a couple more on the mechanical side and
your opinion our steam humidifier
humidifiers a requirement for a dry room
and then are you recommending hepa
filtration on supply side to protect
plants our steam humidifiers that do you
say yeah steam humidifier is a
requirement for a dry room yeah I would
say absolutely not unless you're doing
this in a desert and you've ended up
over drying your product and need to get
moisture back in but even then you can
be able to just still don't do it right
I would definitely not use a steam
humidifier you might as well use a you
know adiabatic cooler inside your space
to do that
famous get the same effect and then yeah
I don't know you know if you're trying
to rehydrate your product you might run
into a challenge if you have the right
mechanical equipment you don't have to
worry about going below the dew point in
the room and then over drawing your
product because you've got the right
systems in place to make it all work and
then in the data there are gonna be
systems that are fighting each other you
should have enough water in the product
itself and not have to take so much of
it out you have to put some back in
which just conflates the whole project
the whole process and in terms of HEPA
filtration I'm gonna so the hepa
filtration is necessarily a great idea I
mean HEPA filters are so good they're
gonna take out some of those VOCs out of
the air as well as the particular you're
trying to avoid but the pathogens were
worried about are generally captured
with a really good myrrh 13 filter that
hasn't been cut become gummed up and you
know started letting more particles
through because it's blown out because
the filter hasn't been changed so just
using really good Murph 13 filter and
avoid the extra energy penalty and first
cost and ongoing cost of replacing those
HEPA filters just someone owners yeah
make sense
what kind of diffusers would you
recommend for a combination giant your
room any any thoughts there yeah I'd say
that any diffusers that get air moving
through the room will work again we
don't
you know we can make recommendations on
that but the other day we'd like to
model every room that we're in because I
know I can make a recommendation but if
I can't actually see it happen you know
with a smoke test or with a CFD model
I don't like trust it seeing is
believing for me so we've just seen a
lot of a lot of limbs get designed with
the best of intentions and did not work
out so well and we like to we like to
think about that before we start making
recommendations one of things I've seen
that you know I thought was a great idea
counter-intuitively ended up not being a
great idea was those linear type
diffusers on one wall supplying air and
then a returned grill basically making
up the other wall you have this like
very linear airflow through the room
well that's sounding a great idea
because you'd have good laminar flow
through the entire space the question
becomes where do you put the temperature
and humidity sensor for that space as
you go through the room that air quality
will change as it either picks up or in
other ways changes the air quality
changes as it goes past the product so
it's a very tough thing to for me to
recommend using one of those type
systems I prefer a room that mix as well
I want a room that's mixing the air
constantly so I have a homogeneous
atmosphere around all of the product
that's inside that room as opposed to
doing that linear airflow across it
where I only know based on my sensors
and humidities my temperature humidity
sensors I only know the temperature and
humidity and can control the one spot in
the room essentially so mixing is better
lots of sensors in a mixed well mixed
environment will give you a pretty good
idea if you've got the mixing you need
and I'll help you achieve that
homogeneous environment how's that
answer the question that's great I think
I think you took that one over over and
above thank you what is the ideal
moisture content and water activity for
a final product
to each their own well I'm not let's go
so you want yeah but I mean be if the
idea is though and I think there's been
proven in a couple of studies is that
you know we have to reduce that water
activity and we have to get the moisture
content of the bud below 20 percent
otherwise there'll be enough energy and
activity to stimulate microbial growth
and pathogens and bud rot and all that
stuff that's going on so there are some
thresholds that we need to abide by but
you know I think this is a great point
right I had mentioned that the
difference between you know 5% water
weights worth millions but also that
water weight might lead to a product
that's not as well received in the
marketplace that additional water weight
is going to have lower test results for
THC and terpenes so these are all
factors of considerations that need to
be taken into account although you might
be able to capture more money weight by
selling that water people are not going
to appreciate it as much as a smoke that
burns cleaner burns easier and doesn't
have those those remnants in there I
think that this is a big portion where
you get to sort of define your signature
it's about time line it's about
balancing of terpene loss and enzymatic
activity you know it's sort of about how
much water content you want to leave in
that product if you're at 20 percent the
likelihood of winning a cannabis cup is
low the product won't smoke well in a
joint or the traditional testing testing
methodologies and when vaporized there
are other flavors that you might pick up
from that water vapor whereas a lower
product around 10 percent
you know moisture in the in the cannabis
bud is much more likely to be received
as a premium product so again it's a
signature balancing act and and market
pressure aspect where you have to
understand you know how much it's worth
to get better test results and better
product relative to product weight
biomass
another one related to humidity relative
humidity what what effect is raising the
relative humidity temperature remains
constant on trichomes and turkeys in the
cure to prevent over drying so yeah go
for a rub go for it all right I think we
get two different maybe different
pinions here the vapor pressure of a
particular gas is independent of other
gases so if you're worried about
moisture content inside your plant you
can decrease the vapor pressure by
increasing the humidity in the room so
if all you're doing is hoping to get a
moisture content reading that is
consistent at the end of the drying and
you don't over dry you need to raise the
relative humidity inside your space to
keep the moisture in the plant and keep
the pressure off the liquid water in the
product from evaporating into the air
this is something that I need to see
testing on and this is part of what
we're doing here at inspire I need to
see that if I increase the terpene the
terpenes in the air that it also applies
the same vapor pressure back to the
terpenes that are on the plant that
we're trying not to volatize so
volatilize so if you think a question is
strictly on what is the effect on
terpenes and THC inside the plant I
don't have a very good answer if the
question is what is the effect on
moisture content of the product the huge
huge effect increase the relative
humidity to decrease the vapor pressure
on the water keep the water in the plant
do not put yourself in a position where
it says high humidity and completely
unchecked that you have this pathogen
build-up that you can't control so
balancing anybody goes like I totally
agree with you Rob and I just sort of
want to add a you know historical side
note that I think a lot of people that
pure and the small batch jar philosophy
you know we all prized that jar because
we know something magical happens in
there
one conversation is about the relative
moisture in that space right the
humidity in that space rising up through
respiration evapotranspiration in that
product which actually might have an
influence the only reason I sort of
bring that up is that I know that high
humidities certain gases are gonna
change and have different atmospheric
you know they're gonna impact the but
differently and that also high humidity
is going to a you know dramatically
change the you know effects of ethylene
or the effects of oxygen so there's a
lot of variables there that really need
to be controlled and that's what I was
glad you nailed on this it's about
precision control and understanding
rather than you know just as simple hey
this is this is the number and this is
how you get there you know it's sort of
about understanding all those influences
and impacts that go into that process
and and monitoring and measuring them
throughout the entire journey
great thoughts on HDL HDL s ceiling fans
high volume low speed ceiling fans in
the drive cure space sure what does the
model tell you right if you can if you
can put into uh if you can put it into a
room and show that look I've got good
air velocity and good air mixing around
the product great there's a question in
here that I saw about you know how do
you get air mixing when you have all
these tight baker's trays and you know
hanging racks and all that other stuff
that's what I'd be worried about if I've
got air just coming from one direction
and I'm counting on a somewhat linear
laminar air flow off of this off of this
thing pushing down constantly on the
product is there gonna make it into each
and every tray that I'm drying product
on I don't know the answer that so I
need to see it born out show me a CFD
model show me something smoke test in a
room that tells me it works and if
that's the case get after it I think
there might be better ways to handle
that though I think
hi I think those fans are interesting
but there are a huge surface to clean if
you're not going to use some sort of
aerosolized cleaning solution or system
in between your drying and curing stages
so that's a factory keep in mind yeah I
got it thanks s we have some some
questions coming in about freeze drying
and the cryo cryogenic tearing you know
just to maybe you can just address a
little bit more your thoughts on on free
drying cannabis versus versus a longer
cure sure no I think that you know it's
a technology that you know not in its
infancy but it's it's still in its early
application stages for cannabis and you
know I'm lucky enough to know the guys
over there at crack here and they've
been a great resource for me and just
sort of understanding you know what
they're doing and how they're doing it
and and the you know the obstacles and
pinch points and how they're getting
better I think for the most part you
know I really like the idea of
processing and curing as quickly as
possible knowing that the monoterpenes
are going to disappear within you know
hours and that the other terpenes and
secondary metabolites will you know
basically degrade on a day-by-day basis
so for me I'm excited about a process
that can get us to the finish line
quicker while still producing a premium
product and I'll be honest you know like
the products I've seen from
freeze-drying have incredible bag appeal
and some of the best nose that I've ever
experienced my question is is that the
quality of smoke doesn't lie just in
those two things it lies in the
cleanliness of the burn it lies in the
test results and relies in the usability
and that's where we're still trying to
refine the freeze drying process when it
comes to vacuum purging water in that
environment we're just not sure if it's
a 12-hour period or
forty-eight hour period I'm sure if you
give the guys at cryo here a call
they'll actually talk to you about the
options and past that they've gone down
with exploration they have some
incredible scientists on staff doing
discovery and research and refinement
but that's the idea is that we don't
exactly know how long we're going to
vacuum purge the product that's
important because once we freeze dry we
denature everything we stop the
degradation we stop the enzymatic
processes things it's a hard handbrake
so we need to make sure we're at a point
in that vacuum purging process where the
enzymes have broken down the other
unwanted stuff and the hydrolysis has
occurred to remove those products from
the bud that allow us to freeze-dried at
the right moment that's one of the real
artistic aspects of freeze drying is
that making sure that the products going
to be clean after you freeze dried
because there's no going back
re-energized me enzymes and restarting
that process it's great in that sense
and it's terrifying in that sense I
think there's there's applications for
sure for this product as the technology
grows but it will take a mastery of
understanding what's going on in that
vacuum purging process the effects of
pressures you know and and basically
really close concise monitoring this
one's related to the chemistry in the
air
are there any technologies to monitor
the chemistry continuously during the
curing process none that I know of I
think there's some work being done on
the visual photographic evidence based
curing I think that when do we get
further down the line with the testing
will realize that we can use certain
gases as a certain gases as a corollary
to the curing process so for example
what we monitor our co2 in a room that's
for general commercial occupancy we
don't actually care about the co2 level
we're using it as a surrogate
to tell us how many people are inside
the space I think there's gonna be some
gas we can measure as a surrogate that
tells us he goes this far along in the
curing process so I think that's
something to keep in mind otherwise I
don't really know of those you know two
different methods that I just mentioned
a way to do that in Fitzhugh you know as
its as it's happening
Jesse Jeff any ideas here I was I was
gonna sort of take it a different vein
and just you know there's there's some
great companies out there filter comes
to mind and and my buddy Jason over
there is always feeding me really good
information you know I always talks
about how we're moving forward and how
we you know collect information in these
grow spaces and curing spaces and we've
had some great conversations about how
they're moving forward basically sampled
the air and the space for microbial
contaminants I mean it takes a
collection a petri dish and sending it
off to lab and some interpretation but I
think that's an important thing to
consider - Rob you touched on basically
having a mechanical nose in this space -
you know tell us elucidate some of the
pathogens as they come about I think
this could also be a tool that could be
incorporated even into the shared spaces
of the hallways space is thinking about
the pressures in the curing room and
what might be sucked into them and he's
sort of tracking it back to where those
pathogens might be born or starting from
in the first place and also just having
something a system like that and in the
space where you can sample and send it
off and get real about lab results it's
not exactly the answer to the question
that came up here but I think it's an
interesting point we've seen some great
companies explore that filter like I
said sort of comes to mind but there's a
handful of others out there that I've
talked with as well pursuing some
similar approaches I think we'll take
the opportunity to to wrap it up here as
mentioned there's opportunity to reach
out for additional questions and
specific follow-ups I think we got - the
vast majority of those question topics
really want to appreciate and thank
everybody on the line for joining us and
just a quick plug for our next monthly
webinar that's planned for a month from
now Thursday
July 2nd same time stay in place we've
been talking quite a bit about these 10
parameters these 10 cardinal parameters
and you can review our first webinar
that's available online if you if you've
missed that one but it's sort of this
concept of ok great let's do it in the
best possible way scientifically and
making sure that our plants are really
going to thrive and you know on and on
and on and on but whoa wait a second
what does that now do to our overall
cost of this facility both capex and
OPEX which is such a significant factor
and that needs to be considered in this
so really excited to to sort of do a
deeper dive in our next one to really
start to be able to balance cost-benefit
and that relationship together it's to
make sure that these decisions that are
being made really are are the best
possible decisions for your business and
your business model and your
profitability so with that really want
to think think the guys Jesse and Rob
particularly for spending the time on
this and doing this deep dive that's
been great and we are excited to hear
from from the community with more and
with that have a great day and I'll talk
to you guys soon Thanks