a lot of my passion is in farming and
teeming with microbes and you know and
just the love that cannabis gives you
back when you give it love is just so
empowering you know and you see it come
out and but but it's fascinating with
your dry and caring cos you put such a
long period of time and energy and
effort and love and intention into
growing a plant it's so fascinating how
in the last week of harvest and like
drying carrying you can take your like a
plus plus and turn it into C and it
smell like hey you know and it's
fascinating how perishable of a of a
plant cannabis is really when it comes
down to it is you know so much and how
you set up the drying and curing you
know it almost you know put you I mean
cuz if you if you bag plant you know if
it's crispy and dry on the outside and
yet there it's tons of moist in the
middle and you bag everything up too
soon and then like you just let it sit
for too long and all of a sudden the
moisture just bombs and kills and it
smells like hay from then on you can't
really do much to get it back well you
can do certain things and you know
really moisturize it but it's just it's
amazing how how how big of a hit you
take you've got multi-phase very this is
hilarious because it's like you've got
multiples and you're playing around with
the moisture content it's like you know
you have from from whole plant to hangar
to buck down you have paper gift plastic
you know it's like you know eventually
someday we'll have glass and curing you
know
I don't know anybody that's doing all
jar Curie yeah but but I do know that
you know it's like when I'm taking yeah
but I'm taking my eight plus plus right
and I'm hanging it just being present in
the dry room right daily just going in
the the cannabis that I leave for a week
and come back you know it cause it's
like it's inconvenient for me to get to
that space you don't like I'll have
someone else when I go and check that
cannabis turns out to be a much less of
a quality the Canada secured on site
well I'm able to check daily and I'm
able to adjust you know fan speed or you
know run the D hum for the first day and
then you know and then and then take the
D hub out was thinking such an involved
Moses you can't just it's not you mean
you can't just like throw it on where I
was booking you know and then and then
you know and then six days later seven
days later depending on you know if I'm
in all wood or if there's some plastic
involvement if we you know whatever it
is with the ventilation systems like
it's like you know it's just call it six
days and buck it all down in the paper
right and then go off into the attic and
then and then you know have it all
curing of matter but my daughter's room
during harvest season smells like
forgiven
no smells like that other than my
outdoor he doesn't think is it's all
about or in paper bags in the Attic you
know and it's like it's right next to
their room so it's like but then I take
you know so I can take an entire harvest
and put it in you know and then lay it
out on all the floors and it cure and
then I take it out of there dump it back
in and plastic you know ding and then
give me then get it you know
then get it trimmed then you know they
gets trimmed from there
but sometimes the trim goes back in the
paper you're not saying before then it
goes into turkeys and sealed up and and
how is it being trimmed so many people
will just let it be
just fuckin yes it you know or put it
through trim machines like I like those
Catholics or my friends you know me and
oh dude outside looking at that every
day you see in the development watching
the hair - like all the watching the
trichome development watching it already
express itself to its folks
I don't take pictures of developing
tribe trichomes and show them up because
I want you to knock them off with a pair
of Fiskars you know it's like you know
being present watching them and you know
what gives me so many ways - which is a
repetition repetition one of my friends
one of the most meticulous kind of dry
here guys I've ever met dude from Oregon
mr. named John Green Bodhi this dude you
know intentional world of cultures you
know very on the organic - vibe
anyway he he's got one of the best cure
jobs that I've ever seen and then he's
like he gets so pissed at trimmers and
people if they do it improperly you know
because it you know the whole thing to
work all that you know and and you know
one time you know I was helping him move
some observe way back in the day and
took his fire pound of his and you know
like so many farmers do I took the
turkey bag you know what it was you know
like cuz you know and he chopped me so
hard and from that moment I learned and
I chopped everybody from now on that now
that one that because it's like sake
dude each time that you're opening a bag
to like take a look at and smell and
then you just you're just ripping you
Olin you're just ripping all the buds
off or the whole the trikes off buds you
know that are like to become Kinston to
smashed against each other just so you
could take a look at it and it's just
amazing how how quick that degrades a
pound and how quick the bag appeal after
six people doing that you know could
ever two changes you know and it's like
you know respect to the trike beard you
know it's like dude no harm technique to
cuz we're always hanging around the
quarters it'll be something somebody
throws us like ten bags of G we want to
pick the one that we like and then we're
done with it we like to just suck it all
out spin it twist it you hand it back
you're done and it looks like here look
there's no oxygen in there so that
you're it's going to store better no
actually that you know butchering or
yeah bludgeoning bludgeoning the truck
oh yeah
the best person if anybody wants to like
get schooled on your keyring invite
Frenchie into your into your room right
it's like I he does her either split up
all of our hashing you know he's there
he's there for foreign development
flower development all the way till he
picks his date based on what he sees but
with week six and then
they'll come out for two weeks you know
on a date where he feels like if we jerk
properly and he'll run our stuff that's
not it's not done well just because he
was do you know you just want the
relationship was to do it but I could
tell he'd rather be doing something else
it's like when he finds something that
he really really likes super odd and
he's he's not afraid to tell you you're
curing like shit so tell me some of what
he's saying or some of the stuff he's
educated you on in terms of like as a
hash maker like what he's looking at as
these plants drying here I mean you know
it's it's like he's a fine china dealers
right so it's like he's less involved in
the specifics around ventilation
humidity control things of that nature
like I mean ideally I think we would all
be in stone floor wood wall buildings or
even cob building I think ideally in his
world we would all be bundling
everything and then just like setting it
like away from everything with like very
minimal airflow and then going back and
beating it on Civ uncivilized you know
like and and it's beating the living
shit out of it and scoop sweeping and
scooping and if I see if that's that's
where you see him get passionate right
he's I mean yes he respects flower but
he doesn't he know he wants to Trek he
respects my he's like oh that's really
pretty but he is a he's gonna what he
wants to be the one that brutalizes it's
attractive yeah he wants to be the one
that does it he wants as many of them as
possible in one area to go through that
process so it's it's when he's walking
through the rooms walk through
everything he's like don't touch that
don't walk there
you know turn that fan around you know
don't you like like like these are
things he's saying you know basically
you want it to develop just like that
nobody touch don't throw it into totes
you know he calls trimmer stupid you
know you're like all the time us stupid
you know like you know he gets really
frustrated we lifted the trim bins and
he sees all the amazing things it's a
waiter wrong yeah yeah and you know in
so many ways to it's funny how like you
know the art of the you know hashish in
you know kind of like French cheese but
but the heart of the farmer you know
it's just that all the intuitive things
that we've come upon you know figuring
out almost intuitively from this
relationship of the plan and the plan on
was communicating with us teaching us
these things because I find it really
fast is now science is around you know
testing and we're able to help
substantiate or qualify these certain
aspects you know it's it's an almost
just like that much more proving like
why people figured it out all along long
ago in this certain way you know and and
you know it's it's it's it's a trip
because they cannabis with terpenes you
know there's you know we tested after
tennis for about 34 different terpenes
but but what we see of you know of all
those terpenes we only really ever see
between five and nine of them ever show
up in any real amount and and of the
nine there's only really like three or
four that ever show up as the dominant
or codominant terpene and then some of
the other ones will be there in very
small secondary tertiary amounts but
what we're talking about like is like
and there's and there's two different
types Turkish right there's the
monoterpenes
and sesqui terpenes right and so the
difference really is the monoterpenes
boil off at much lower temperatures as
opposed sesqui terpenes which boil off
the higher temperatures and so so with
the monoterpenes
those are the ones that are there in the
most amounts in any really given any
given strain so you know so you talking
about limonene you're talking about
pining you're talking about Turpin
Helene so so so Turpin names the turfing
high in like Jack and trainwreck and
sage Durbin Zeta you know a lot of those
kind of like quotes sativa type strain
you know and that's predominantly
turpentine and then there's little other
terpenes but predominator friendly and
then and so then you have you have mere
seen also as a monoterpene and you have
little rule which is lavender as
atropine but but so all those terpenes
which are the ones that ever show up is
the primary secondary Turkey you know
they are the ones that go away and
volatilize that the quickest whenever
you know you're introducing them to
prolong like improper heating kind of
what have you you know it's like it's
drying in a barn you know that super hot
and unable to keep controlled
temperature in humidity you can
immediately drop some rich turbines and
you're sesqui terpenes like vinegar
awfully and inhuman lean will then kind
of concentrate all the other ones are
boiling off so you can almost alter the
turbo file of the archetype of the
strain you know through kind of improper
drying curing because then all of a
sudden like say the you know if it's if
it's like you know you know yeah like
Dutch treat or something which is like
you know Turpin lean and a little like
beta-carotene all of a sudden it could
become Turpin lean and like almost equal
amount of beta-carotene you know and and
so so just in the process of drying and
carrying you know you can vary
significantly alter the expression of
what the plants supposed to be just from
you know
[Music]