powers destined powers is known as
future 4200 sweet future 4200 calm and
on Instagram he's one of the biggest
proponents of open sourcing he's created
a huge forum and well he's actually a
gang leader it's called the good life
gang and it's just a way to open up
different networking opportunities they
put on different networking events and
different different cities we've done
over here inhalation extraction mostly
extraction but some cultivation as well
and they certainly move like towards
other other parts of the head again like
hemp is becoming a big focus on that
stuff as well but it started from this
dude going around and like paying
consultants to teach teach him something
and getting the SOP for that specific
thing and then and then he just loaded
up his website is a treasure trove of
kind of the history of how people have
been extracting and it was and now all
these other people just upload their as
like you know he was doing he was doing
his own extraction Hughes you know it
was just that he he's a great market
kind of guy like well he worked he
worked for he worked at skunk farms for
a little while like so there there was a
connection there of this mentality from
like very wolf of opens you know this
dedication to open source and then like
Dustin came out of that school of
thought is for a little bit of influence
yeah and he he's actually completely
changed the like he the website that he
produced was something that now it is
the resource for all all the cannabis
extractors all the big names and now
lots of large-scale CBD companies
and you know big shiny china
manufacturers of equipment are all just
getting in there and I mean there's
advertisement going on personally but
it's not an advertised website he's not
taking money off of it it's just this
just treasure trove of people just
talking about ideas unedited unedited
and like sure he catches plenty of flack
for the things that he puts out and he
tries to promote businesses as he knows
that they're legitimate and if things
don't work out he has to take the brunt
of those things and by putting himself
out there it's just it's been a noble
thing and how he how he has given this
information to so many people and I'm
like yes take a beatin from time to time
give you something that you came across
on that site the past month that you
forwarded to him we were maybe Delta ten
yeah yeah Delta ten stuff Delta time THC
there's now a huge thread regarding that
and Delta live when we had a fun little
fort aid a little for a layman's
background so depending it specifically
they're all everybody's different and
I'll all have their own special ways of
effective but depending on where or how
the different pieces of the molecule are
laid out you you know the difference
between THC delta 9 and THC a is THC a
has a carbolic acid molecule in its tail
and no boxer group carboxyl group and in
another thing there's Delta eight THC
which has gotten really popular with the
water clear trend and people would you
know they would throw a bunch of carbon
and some acids and stuff into their
boiling flask and then they'd start
distilling it and it's coming out
beautiful water
here they sent test results early to
send testing labs and then it's yeah
like very low percentage of Delta 9 THC
eventually we started they got standards
for Delta 88 see then started
quantifying that there's more THC in
this that there is but then there's
still a little missing piece that like
you'd see you know 60 to 70 80 percent
cannabinoids and this water clear stuff
that you know is all cannabinoids and
there's plenty of isomers and stereo
isomers of THC and these are things that
happen through different reaction their
reactions that happen through heating
and the presence of acids and bases and
given the different different
environmental things or what was sprayed
on those those that that can actually be
a big indicator in what's happening into
the reactions as well so so go about all
that distillation method we're like you
put stuff in a pot it boils at different
temperatures and all that well throw
catalyst in that pot that you don't know
is there like you know people spray it
put sulfur on their plants or people you
know certain things get sprayed on
plants and when you concentrate that
thing in a hot flask under vacuum where
fires and fire attack yeah there's a
whole bunch of ways you could do that
but to go back to Delta 10 Delta 10 is
simply an unknown type of THC that until
recently was it is yes in different
income in different ways they affect all
three of those can affect a single
person completely