and so whoa this one's a little louder
so in terms of retrofitting a greenhouse
you know there's a lot of greenhouses in
the Central Coast right now that are
being retrofitted that were used for say
fresh-cut flowers roses and orchids and
and other sorts of flowers and you know
maybe most people don't know this but
you know since most flowers are not
being eaten and are not edible they just
have to look really pretty and so they
dumped a shitload excuse me kids of
pesticides on these flowers they will
fumigate the ground and the air and that
space is probably pretty polluted
speaking of remediation you know they're
rickety greenhouses they're wood framed
they're torn plastic and you know like
you think you're getting a good vibe I
get it you know by buying that
greenhouse but you have to completely
replace all the wood with steel or
aluminum you have to replace the cover
with something else I hope maybe now
you're gonna add pad and fan cooling
because you can't just you know open up
the windows to let you know the cool
coastal air come in when you have it for
these flowers that you don't really care
if pests come in or what the environment
is because well you're gonna fumigate it
so it doesn't really matter so much and
so you know having to deal with a an
existing greenhouse structure in some
ways can be more painful than an indoor
structure where at least you have bones
that are gonna stay put that may be you
know it like you'll fix up I mean in
terms of indoor facilities you know the
roof the structure itself is horrible to
deal with because a lot of it can't hold
the load of the equipment that you want
to install you have neighbors both for
greenhouses and for indoor that are
gonna complain about odor that are
forcing less efficient greenhouse
designs because we're trying to
keep all that odor from leaving the
facility and then if you let it leave
the facility now what are you spraying
into the air using to mitigate those
odors right also not a good solution so
being able to find a green a property
where the greenhouse is maybe more rural
and you're not gonna get all those
complaints and you can do some install
more efficient equipment would be ideal
we don't always have that option though
right the ideal isn't always there is
still sticking on the design topic what
are a couple things that are commonly
overlooked on just general designs of
greenhouse of space in general what are
a few things that are overlooked is is a
post-production pre-production the
happiness and health of the employees
what are some things that you've kind of
noticed that people kind of go in
forgetting about so I guess you know
kind of coming from the last question in
terms of retrofit versus fresh build you
know every time if you can do it once
and right that's the way to do it on the
retrofit side of things I I think it's a
lot of it comes down to what I would
consider to be workflow you know and
that includes materials flow you know
harvesting flow all of that you know
I've worked in far too many facilities
I'll give one of my favorite examples a
couple hundred light indoor facility in
Denver it was back in the day Cummins
engine test plant and so you know they
had it was clean there was no major
issue they had huge bay roll-up doors
you know obviously they were bringing in
heavy you know diesel engines and stuff
to test at a mile high and so it got
converted into a cultivation facility
and in their enthusiasm they walled off
all the roll-up doors for security
measures and so the biggest entrance
into the building was a man door and if
they wanted to bring in things like
tanks they know it's gets totally
laughable if they wanted to bring in
things like big tanks which you might
want in a you know a couple hundred
light indoor possibly you'd have to cut
a hole through the roof and crane it in
which you know given the crazy HVAC and
lighting and everything was in
entirely functional forum so you know
it's good to plan for for the purpose
and you know certainly workflow I think
is like the biggest thing you know soil
in soil out material and material out
Jurgen omics all of that is pretty darn
key yeah I think workflow is one of the
things that people constantly leave out
in the efficiency model that is probably
one of the most efficient models that
they need to be thinking of is how do
your employees get from point A to point
B as well as the product so I'm just
gonna say real quickly is move the
plants to the people as opposed to the
people to the plants the amount of labor
efficiency and just risk of cross
contamination by doing it that way huge
savings huge opportunities there and you
know when we're just talking
horticulture in general you know like
some of you may have seen you know these
lettuce greenhouses where you know they
they transplant the seeds at one end of
a deep bed water culture and then and
then they incrementally move those
plants down the row and then 30 days
later they're harvesting from the other
end
people never moved those plants never
had to harvest them by hand they
literally just have a machine that just
scoops it up takes it over to the
packaging room and then people handle it
I mean then um you know we're so
concerned about energy efficiency in the
cost of energy but what is always the
number one cost of any business labor so
anything you can do to reduce labor
increase labor efficiency which is move
plants to the people as much as possible
so I I was only going to say one thing
I'm now gonna say - so you are asking
sort of what are some of the primary
things that people fail to consider and
I agree with both of the things and then
the other thing that I'm gonna say
people fail to consider on the regular
which is
kind of shocking is where their most
fundamental components are gonna come
from where is your electricity coming
from where's your water coming from what
people genuinely don't ask those
questions when looking at properties all
the time
you don't just flip a switch and it's
all done that's that's not actually
where electricity comes from it's not
magic it has to get to you from
somewhere and understanding where it's
coming from
and how it's going to get there kind of
important when it is one of the highest
cost factors and one of the most
critical components of your facility
secondarily I will say that we very much
confuse
energy efficiency with efficiency and
sustainability those are two totally
different things and super important
when we are speaking on an efficiency
panel to recognize that the we are not
only considering how to be energy
efficient we are considering how to be
efficient in the entire scope and
function of our business and that's not
only going to capitalize on your
electricity so the people become really
important the workflow becomes really
important all of those things are part
of efficiency all of those things are
critical parts of sustainability and
will ultimately have massive impacts on
the cost of doing business I want to
kind of jump in there and follow up and
you know coming from from you know
Nevada County and being you know having
my roots in organic cultivation and
things like that you know there's been
this ongoing debate that I'm sure
everyone's been somewhat preview to
write which is organic versus synthetic
what's better what's worse what's more
efficient what's not and and you know
the the opinion that I've come to is
essentially that you know you can do
organic cultivation very well you know
you can have an efficient business model
built from you know an organic
cultivation model you can also do
organic cultivation very poorly you can
do organic cultivation in a very
resource
in efficient manner you know so to me
it's no longer you know is it organic is
it synthetic you know there's there's a
triple bottom line of course but in
terms of just resource efficiency you
know one doesn't inherently mean
resource efficient or low carbon
footprint at this point you know so that
that to me is you know I'm sort of
surprised that that's the situation in a
certain way but but that's the reality
of it you know you really need to be
aware of your supply chain where are you
if you're in the middle of nowhere it's
gonna cost you more you may be less
resource efficient bringing in bulk
organic media you know and and the only
thing I thought of too was you know I've
been working on this project in Ohio you
know and it's it's a big project they're
you know they're a very limited number
of licenses and I talked to the lead
cultivator a few weeks ago and we're
starting to talk down you know way
further planning stages beyond build-out
and I said to him so will you send me
the water data and he was like yeah yeah
I'm pretty sure we have it somewhere and
I'm like yeah can you like find that and
you know I can't believe you're millions
into a project and you don't know you
have excellent supply you know water
quality and you again you might want to
take that into consideration in the
pre-planning stages so you know what
your capital requirements are gonna be
for the equipment to remediate your site
and get it to you know the spec that you
desire I mean thank you for saying water
quality and water source that is should
be number one when selecting a property
because that is the life of your plant
and yeah and it's going to affect your
filtration needs or do you need reverse
osmosis it kills me to see all these
facilities installing reverse osmosis
that has perfect water quality right or
that has really crappy water quality and
isn't filtering it or doing any sort of
remediation I mean I don't not even sure
which one is worse you know we recently
worked on a project in Oklahoma we're
designing a high-pressure fog system and
you know one of the first questions is
what's the water quality because how
much filtration do we need to put on
on the water that's gonna go through
these teeny tiny teeny tiny nozzles and
the growers like oh we have that a few
days later well we can't find it so
we're getting it tested again and it's
just like you wanted an answer for this
you know fog system two weeks ago and
now we're waiting two weeks for your
water quality sample so water water
water
it all starts there it's pretty
important thing again you know yeah yeah
right exactly yeah and that's the that's
the truth I like how you touched on the
the topic of organic and it you know it
could be a good thing or it can be a
non-sustainable thing just depending on
the the inputs
another thing that's you know comes to
mind too when the efficiency of the
design is the operating procedures
literally every single function in the
farm even going to get the mail should
have an operating procedure you know and
they're adaptable they're you know
that's an evolution depending on how the
business grows and evolves but
everything should come with a procedure
you know and that procedure should
always be scrutinized and and how can it
be more efficient and how could it
benefit the program more and that's
something that a lot of people overlook
is that yeah I got my procedure it's in
here I pour a little visit for a little
of that and we're all good you know oh
no I had that eight percent you know
couldn't you know strain you know what
do I do
and so yeah having an operating
procedure and a standard procedure for
everything that you do is very very
important so I want to just have a
moment to touch on that because actually
somebody on the legal panel was talking
about how sort of freaked out frustrated
bent out of shape everybody gets with
the regulation the regulation the
regulation and it sucks and we're coming
from no regulation and really any
regulation feels excessive and
frustrating and expensive but at the end
of the day it's those regulations those
procedures that ultimately create the
sustainable functioning economy of an
industry of scale they are I'm not even
going to call them necessary evils they
are just flat-out necessary
it's how we figure out how to do this
well it's how we figure out how to do it
in a way that supports everybody
actually being able to stay open and
actually being able to make money off of
the work that they do
you