yeah I mean you know touching on
operating procedures it's a it's an
important part of the new paradigm for
cannabis cultivation undoubtedly you
know I would say mmm the majority of
cultivators that are here probably have
a methodology that they are at least
content with you know so perhaps the
challenge becomes how do you standardize
your methodology so that other people
can do it are you going to be there
seven days a week are you gonna be
hustling are you going to be building
your brand you're gonna be networking
you know are you gonna be the guy
running the hose like you used to when
you had ninety nine probably not you
know so the reality of you know
efficiency in terms of is what I'm doing
replicable how do I convey it how do I
assess whether it's being done in an
efficient manner
you know one of the examples I like to
use is you know let's say people are
irrigating a crop right by hand in the
in a warehouse setting let's just say
and you say well it takes them four to
six hours to do it and it's like well
why is it for six hours is it because
the volume that they're putting down is
different or is it because some people
tangle the hose more than others or you
know and and how do you get any grip on
what the reality of your cost of
production there is if you're not
tracking that how do you decipher
actually 20% of my nutrient cost last
year was because my guys screwed up the
res mix and they had to dump it because
I had a standard operating procedure you
know that even so that they knew to do
that or you know what I mean and so
there a lot of it is is really
developing that system unruhe you know
on rolling out those SOPs and and
monitoring them and like you said you're
constantly re-evaluating looking at them
how can we do this better how can we do
this more efficiently and it's not the
same as you know one person or you know
a small group of people doing it by
themselves
you know as you're scaling those
processes have to be replicable it you
know at scale and so it definitely
changes the dynamic not just how can I
do it better how can I do it efficiently
but how can I do it consistently which
is per
one of the most critical endgame
components without a consistent product
you can't have a consistent following
you just can't you can't build brand
loyalty you can't build consistent
expectations within the marketplace if
you can't have consistent output and a
lot of ways that sort of circles us back
around to you know facility design right
and what are the seasonal limitations or
you know what are the limitations of
what you're working with and and how
does that impact you know the model and
and the end product and data collection
I mean that's a big setting I've come
back full circle you know I mean yeah if
your hand watering okay so are they all
doing it the same you know is it like
you said volume of water so are they
standing there counting for 10 seconds
oh oh my god I have you know I have a
phosphorus toxicity and now like there's
water everywhere right and I mean and
speaking of that you know I hear a lot
of people say well we want to keep hand
watering when they've gone from you know
like 50 plants to 50,000 plants and the
argument I always get every single time
is that well it gets us looking at the
plants it gets us in the room so that we
can look at the plants and my thought is
if you just built into that walking walk
through the room for an hour as opposed
to standing there for six hours and like
going like this right then you can
actually focus on the plant as opposed
to happenstance catching a problem
because you happen to be standing there
watering the plant what if you actually
scouted on purpose your crop I was gonna
saying if you're looking if you're
paying so much attention to the plant
then you're not paying attention to your
watering that you're doing you know
sorry yes the key is to set yourself up
for success right that's kind of the
hope you know we only have a few minutes
left so do we are there any questions
out there for these amazingly smart
panelists I hear you're thinking about
them right now they're serious questions
how can you efficiently design a site
plan for a county that is not knotted
not legal yet well the thing that all
right I'll start the thing that comes to
mind is probably do as much of that
pre-planning as you can yourself so
you're not incurring additional costs
beyond that I would look to you know
what the standard you know probably
first CD if you see DFA is presently and
try and you know and and all the other
agencies involved and try and orient
your plan to that you know there are a
lot of good resources out there in terms
of you know how do you draw a site plan
you know you know it's basic stuff like
that so depending on the intricacies of
your particular project or parcel or
whatever you know you if you have all
the sort of the background information
then I would say go ahead and and be
creative design your your dream and you
know wait and see and be patient and
don't spend a lot of money in the
meanwhile I I would agree with all of
those things and add that ultimately
designing a site plan specifically for
cannabis isn't necessarily wildly
different than designing a site plan for
other agricultural purposes there are
some unique capacities but the
components like all the pieces that are
gonna go into it can be much the same as
as they are for anything else and so you
can start not worrying about the very
specific components that are going to
come in once it becomes legal and start
dealing with kind of the big block
considerations with your power with your
water because those it doesn't matter
legal or not legal there will be little
things that come up like can I use a
residential well versus a commercial
well etc etc and what you might have to
do to deal with the water but you can
start that
process and quite frankly not a lot of
it may be impacted
once those changes happen and once those
changes come down and in all honesty by
the time you're done with your planning
you may already be legal with how long
it actually takes to get that planning
in process and underway and I guess you
know waterboard compliance if that's not
a target and not checked off on your
list that's a good place to start
California cool so thank you guys that
was the efficiency model feel free to
come up and ask our amazing panelists
questions all day they love talking
about this stuff they do it in their
dreams whether they like it or not
promise
so yeah big big thanks to the Columbia
School House for allowing us all to be
here and for flowering for putting this
amazing event onto the community
we love you guys thank you and and if
anybody is local and has a garden and
would like a basil plant we have a bunch
of starter basil plants at our booth the
dr. greenhouse booth towards the front
entrance we grew them in our little
vertical farm that we have in our office
we just Harvard that harvested them four
days ago they're already in these little
compostable pots so you can just stick
them in the ground next to your tomato
crop it's a great companion plant so
feel free to pick one up first and for
serve or organic
you