yeah so I guess the key is to pay
attention right you get that a percent
terpene strain and you don't know why
it's a bummer
[Laughter]
cool so on data collection to be able to
understand what our purpose is you know
a lot of people come in to and say I
just want to grow a ton of weed
well I mean you know okay well I want to
I want to grow this type and I want to
grow this well you got to kind of
understand what your focus is you know
and focus is a hard thing for some of us
exactly
so really really one of the one of the
highest benchmarks to really aim for is
the pre-planning right because this is
the phase that really tells us what our
business model is and what we're trying
to build for the market that we're
trying to produce for the the plants
that we're trying to grow and cultivate
for that production method and how we're
actually even going to do it down to the
what is my facility going to look like
Who am I going to hire for it and so
pre-planning is one of those steps in
the process that kind of gets overlooked
when creating the business model it's
it's easy to it easy to get 40 million
and throw it into a huge project but
without knowing and understanding what
you're actually trying to achieve it's a
lot of waste of money and so let's start
over here with Anya what kind of things
in the pre-planning realm that you see
are kind of an often mistake and things
that people can do to kind of help
mitigate that that risk at the beginning
oh I feel like that's a minefield of a
question right there I think from an
example standpoint one of the biggest
mistakes that people make is expecting
that they can have a budget without a
plan so you say you can throw 40 million
dollars into a huge project and if you
have no plan you can be forty million
dollars in and not two-thirds of the way
through the project so not understanding
that there actually has to be a plan to
determine a process and a budget is I
think mistake number one
the number of people that come to
that say we have a building we want to
build out X Y Z they've got a drawing on
a napkin how much is it gonna cost me
it's gonna cost you anywhere from two
hundred thousand dollars to ten million
dollars so like if that's the starting
point and the expectation is that you're
gonna get anywhere within a reasonable
range to be able to make a plan you're
already in the weeds and I swear I
didn't mean that as a joke the planning
has to happen on the project and the
development before you even get to how
much is this gonna cost me and if you
don't do it in that order
you will ultimately wind up not seeing a
return and you will ultimately wind up
failing before you even start so there
are many other things that I could speak
to about that but I'm gonna stay with
that one yeah so I could speak on this
for a minute as well you know for from
for me in sort of environmental control
HVAC world what we see is the biggest I
don't know lack of understanding is how
much it's gonna cost to control the
environment in your greenhouse or your
warehouse and you know I think that you
know speaking of squirrels is that we
get so growers get so focused on certain
technologies it could be lighting or it
could be a Hydra pannu hydroponic system
or a new automation system and they
forget about the other pieces and how
all those pieces will integrate together
and people come up with very unrealistic
budgets especially for environmental
control and you know we had a project
once where they were gonna spend a
hundred thousand dollars on the latest
LED technology twenty-five thousand
dollars on sensors are gonna put sensors
everywhere and five thousand dollars on
an HVAC system and I'm just like what
are you gonna control with all your
sensor
you know when it comes to greenhouses
versus warehouses even is where is the
best location where are you located you
know if if you know where you're gonna
be located does it make more sense to
have an open greenhouse it could be a
high tunnel right cold flame cold frame
greenhouse because you have good breezes
and you have a pretty mild climate and
you just want some protection and some
light depth but if you're in a harsher
climate you know do you need a closed
greenhouse and if you do that's you know
150 dollars a square foot type of
greenhouse this is not a cold frame $5 a
square foot greenhouse and don't split
the difference either because it's
pretty expensive so for me its budget is
you know growers under having a
realistic budget about what their
facility or their greenhouse is going to
to look like in the end so you know kind
of going back to the question of you
know initial planning stages and things
like that
you know obviously there are a lot of
ways to skin a cat is one of the sayings
that I like to use and so you know
understanding one what your model is is
probably helpful you know and given that
you know the cannabis industry and and
regulations and you know things are
moving quite rapidly you know my
suggestion would be that whatever you
plan on plan on it being lean and plan
on it being nimble you know if you go in
big and heavy and hard and front-load at
all and you're like we're just gonna
crush it we're gonna see such crazy
returns and you miss out on some of the
pieces that you know pre-planning like
well we didn't invest into an on-site
extraction we didn't put that in our
model because we're we're gonna grow all
a great flower you know not recognizing
that like a much better model would be
incorporating that potentially waste
stream into the overall profitability of
the business and so you know that's
that's just sort of a tid but I'm sure
all of us could go on you know the
mistakes that have been made and the
money wasted but you know pre plan
where's the electricity coming from
right yeah it can be pretty dynamic and
as we see it's rapidly evolving I came
from the organ market and I'm sure we've
all heard about kind of the challenges
in the evolution that that market has
taken and if anything that showed us all
that we have to just be ready and
available to adapt to the circumstances
but there is there is a certain level of
pre thought and understanding now that
we know these certain markets are this
way you wouldn't move into Oklahoma and
expect it to just be the most amazing
thing it's going to be a challenge so
knowing what your local legislature has
to offer and the potential changes that
might come is really important to bring
into that pre-planning phase I also just
capitalized on on what you said being
nimble and being ready to change I think
is huge and recognizing to the what Nadi
you and I were speaking about earlier
that none of these changes are changing
a wall color so when the company that
you based your design off of starts
having all sorts of manufacturing
problems with your fixtures and you
decide to go with a different fixture
you're starting all the way back from
the beginning everything changes every
single aspect of your facility changes
by one tiny little seemingly
insignificant change of a piece of
equipment and recognizing that yes
you're gonna have to be prepared to do
that because technology is changing
every other day new stuff is coming out
companies are coming up companies are
falling down people are failing we are
learning constantly and very often we
suggest to people that they phase a
project instead of going all in all out
right from the beginning yeah absolutely
and another one of those aspects of that
is actually the design of the facility
itself so you understand your business
model somewhat you understand the road
path on where you're going you've
started to bring in the team that can
design this system for you
now you understand how am I gonna lay
this out whether it be a greenhouse
whether it be an indoor facility how am
I gonna lay this out what does the law
in my state require what am I allowed to
do what are my limitations there's a lot
of retrofit designs there's a lot of new
construction designs so maybe let's kind
of go into some of the differences in in
in the actual implementation of the
design for retrofit compared to a brand
new build and some of the challenges
that have you've seen comparatively in
in in a nutshell well I could say I've
had the misfortune perhaps of dealing
with a lot more retrofits and pre-built
facilities than you know the ideal fresh
build that being said you know I think
it's yeah right it's pretty important
too you know once you're have some some
clear understanding of what you're
working with it's pretty important to
understand the limitations of that
system you know again back to kind of
what the model is and and what what
you're striving to produce you know if
you have hoop houses at 4,000 square
feet certainly don't have a model where
you think you're going to produce year
round right you know if you have a
greenhouse in the desert you know
understand that you're going to use a
lot of water for pad cooling you know
and you're going to use a significant
amount of power to run those fans all
the time and so you know it's really in
the minutia that that the efficiency is
found and you know until you continue to
you know amass more data and understand
what those data points can be you know
you're you're only making as much
progress as as what you can sort of
analyze and capture in that way and on
that I just want to add - we don't want
to leave out the you know the the
outdoor scaping is well - because
there's a lot of situations where you
come into a previously used farm or a
previously used just a spot of land and
you have to make something of it - so
let's not let's not forget about the
rich as far as the land goes so I'm
actually that's actually what I was
going to speak to not just land
buildings as well if we're talking
retrofit of a space not not just
necessarily retrofit of an existing farm
what was that space used for before and
we are seeing it and it comes back to
planning in terms of understanding where
is it actually most efficient for you to
land right for a long time everybody
wanted to go out agriculturally because
that was going to be the cheapest
because land was inexpensive property
was inexpensive you had a lot of space
you had a lot of options well as it
turns out there is not an extensive
electrical grid out in agricultural
territory because we didn't farm this
way we had not massive electrical usage
on farms and so what people learned
after the fact I may say is that as it
turned out it was going to cost them
four hundred thousand dollars to bring
enough electricity to their facility so
ok now everybody wants to go in an urban
environment but buildings and rent are
really expensive so we're gonna find a
previously used car lot and we are going
to dump a bunch of green houses on that
car lot Wow what's the remediation
question there what are the other
facilities around you doing in a highly
urban industrial environment and how
does that impact the product that you're
producing coming out of that environment
so what mitigations do you need to put
in place in order to make that retrofit
safe and effective for the business that
you are now going to be operating in
there
you