so welcome to the heart of cannabis 2019
hopefully the first of many this is the
efficiency panel and we have a awesome
group up here from all walks of life in
the cannabis realm to my left we have
drupal bonnie he's a commercial grower
consultant all-around amazing helper guy
I'll let him speak a little bit more on
what he does and second uh to my left
dr. Nadia Saba
she's with dr. greenhouse if you want to
talk greenhouses this is the person to
talk to so you don't setup for failure
to her left is Anya Gordon she's from
Gro tech Builders they're the ones to
talk to when you're just thinking about
what you're gonna do so she's the one
that's going to help you not fail in the
process so I will give it up to them and
they can give a little bit more
introduction on themselves
you guys can hear me all right hey good
afternoon everyone my name is Giovanni
thanks for the intro I'm the founder and
CEO presently a commercial cultivator
Inc it's pretty special for me to sit
here honestly on stage as I used to live
up here on the ridge you guys can't hear
me at all is that better
alright anyways you know I as I was
saying I used to live up here on the
ridge so it's pretty special for me to
sit up here on stage and talk to you
guys sort of you know my background is
in cultivation and before that in
geology and environmental science and so
you know from the from the background of
a cultivator the cost of production
became pretty important and you know
going forward as the industry has
evolved you know cost of production is
now much broader and much more involved
than you know maybe in in the old model
so where the company really started as
both nutrient supply chains or a
solution to that growth store model
we've sort of progressed into offering
efficiency services and consulting and
project management and owner for owners
rep stuff for new builds and I guess
that's my interest so I'll pass the mic
down can you guys hear me alright so I
am Nadia Saba I'm the president and
owner of dr. greenhouse we are an
agricultural and mechanical engineering
firm so we design environmental control
and HVAC systems for greenhouses and
indoor farms my PhD is in agricultural
engineering
I studied evaporative cooling
ventilation water use efficiency for
commercial tomato production houses for
my PhD and after that I went on and to
learn how to be a mechanical engineer so
then I design HVAC systems for
commercial high-rise residential
buildings and the such in about
two-and-a-half years ago I was able to
bring my two passions together
agriculture and mechanical engineering
to form dr. greenhouse so we've been in
business for about
two and a half years and we help growers
all over the country and and in a few
different countries
we've just finished store just started
our 60th project in the last two and a
half years and a lot more growers are
looking into greenhouses as a
cost-effective and efficient way of
cultivating their cannabis crop and so
we do a lot of studies energy modeling
studies looking at the benefits of using
shade systems of using different types
of covering systems looking how it
interplays with the crop that you're
growing the lighting system the
irrigation system and so we're really
trying to help growers learn how to
maybe come out of their indoor facility
and go into a greenhouse and what works
there or people who are coming from say
tomatoes and cucumbers trying to grow
cannabis then in a greenhouse and what
the nuances are there so not really a
microphone person but uh my name is anya
gordon i am the co-owner of gro tech
builders and we are exactly what we
sound like we are builders primarily
actually what we spend most of our time
doing now is project development so
early-stage project development working
with various municipalities utilities
and city county state code and processes
to navigate a project from start to
finish and make sure that all the t's
get crossed and the I's get dotted and
working on the planning stages from the
very beginning to make sure that the
process can be as efficient and
functional as possible yep yep it's all
too often when the eyes get crossed and
the t's get dotted these days so
essentially this panel is pretty much
what you need to get going with an
efficient project and something that's
going to actually succeed and be a long
term solution so one thing that we've
been talking about is the knowledge that
we've had within the cannabis community
where that's come from an agriculture in
another crop science has had the ability
to to you know look within itself look
within studies from university to find
out what their crops are doing how to
cultivate the crops what proper nutrient
ratios what environment they like and
really dive into the breeding to
specifically cultivate and breed crops
for certain purposes and now we're
finally getting to the point we're
actually starting to understand what's
going on with this specific plant which
is really cool and all the breeding that
we've been doing over the years and all
the cultivation without really
understanding why and how we're actually
able to bring that out into the
forefront and one of my really favorite
areas is data collection I'm a data geek
I really love information on every
single aspect of cultivation whether
it's something to do with the substrate
the biology the environment or the
genetic itself I'm a plant nerd I'm a
data geek so data collection is a big
one for me
and we're starting to see that a lot
more and more with a lot more automated
systems a lot more sensing equipment so
let's kind of talk about data collection
what kind of points of data are
extremely important for a cultivator to
not only start out understanding but to
develop throughout their process to help
them succeed we can just kind of go all
right well I mean I think you know
there's obviously a few facets in the
current commercial cannabis paradigm in
terms of you know the various data sets
that we might be looking at you know on
the cultivation side solely I would say
you know obviously you know you
mentioned quite a few of them I think
really what I'd like to point out in a
certain way is you know if you're doing
experiments right if you're in a
greenhouse environment if you're in an
indoor environment how rep you know what
is the replicability of that experiment
you know and as you're going forward and
sort of perhaps on the fly even you know
encountering new dynamics where you say
oh man I need to monitor you know that
particular aspect that perhaps I wasn't
keying in on in a different environment
because the dynamic is somewhat distinct
you know so on the cultivation side
it really depends on the model you know
and for me that a big piece of it is if
you're not collecting data even if you
don't know where you're going you know
and trying to get as much as you can
it's tough to hone in on that model you
know when you're ready to otherwise
you're sort of flying by night and so
data is is a big piece of what we do and
a lot of what we're missing
in this industry as Casey mentioned you
know with other horticultural crops
there's a lot of university research
historical research that's been done
over 50 years or more depending on what
you're growing that we have been able to
develop growth models on production
models on understand how much light the
crop needs what the nutrient mixes
should be to get the best qualities and
the best highest yields but with
cannabis you know we don't have that
same level of data right now
universities aren't doing that research
because they feel like their hands are
tied behind their back because it's not
federally legal and so we rely on you
growers to help us fill in those gaps
but you guys also come from a history of
not wanting to keep records for good
reason right and so a lot of it has been
anecdotal which has been a great place
to start but now we really need to rely
on you to collect that data what you
know if you're in a greenhouse having a
weather station and knowing the dynamics
of temperature and humidity and rain and
wind and how that might affect then
should you open up event to naturally
ventilate do you shut it down to use
fans and maybe an evaporative cooling
system can you use shade well if you
shade will it reduce the yield of your
crop or if you're not pumping the
greenhouse with carbon dioxide anyway
maybe you can shade and you know or
maybe you don't shade because or maybe
you do shade because you're not gonna
get the full benefit of all that
sunlight if you're not also pumping the
greenhouse with co2 but we don't have
that data we don't know how much light
these plants need we know they need a
lot of plant a lot of light but where's
the threshold we know they they
use a lot of co2 but where's the
threshold both high and low and really
we need to tie it to production data
into quality data right and and we
really need that information from all of
you rather than it being anecdotal is if
we have some record-keeping if we can
even standardize what variables what
parameters were monitoring and then what
the outcomes are so that we can make
direct connections rather than oh this
will happen to be a sunny dry year and I
got a really good crop so I'm gonna hope
for another sunny dry year next year
when actually it had to do with I don't
know the strain you were growing that
year right so data is key to the success
and moving forward in this industry and
being as efficient as possible I'm
actually also gonna I mean maybe talk
even from a server 10,000 foot level
about data because in Casey you know
this because I've spoken with you at a
number of events that for me then from
our lens as a as a builder and as
somebody who helps to develop these
projects data is the key it's the
primary component that ultimately drives
the industry towards success or failure
it's the threshold of what are the
minimum baseline requirements that I
need to meet in order to be up and
running in a functional way that in the
long run sets me up to actually be able
to produce my product efficiently both
from an energy standpoint from an
environmental standpoint and from an
economic standpoint so a lot of what I
find happening now is there's this rush
to entry rush to entry rush to entry and
then it's kind of you're in a chicken
and an egg situation a little bit right
we don't have the data because of where
the industry has come from and because
of sort of all of the various reasons
that there was never a reason to collect
the data and there were never any
supporting entities doing that well the
ultimate cause of that is that we don't
really know how much is reasonable for
it to cost
to build a facility and we don't really
know how long it's going to take for
that to pay back dividends in the long
run and we don't really know whether or
not we can maintain an economically
successful production cycle without
those data points because not only can
we not sort of compare with ourselves
from year to year but we can't compare
with anybody else
which ultimately means there's no
successful healthy equitable competition
so from a 10,000 square foot view it's
not even just the purpose of being able
to cultivate effectively it's being able
to operate as a business and as an
industry effectively over the long term
just to Anya's point to the first
candidates project endure a project that
I worked on about four four or five
years ago we told the grower look there
here's these two or three different you
know HVAC system options you could use
this one's really efficient and it has
an 18-month return or an 18-month
payback like it from coming from
commercial buildings anything that's
less than a 10-year payback is a score
right and and the grower literally said
unless it has a six-month payback I
don't want to hear about it and that's
because you know the risks were real of
being shut down now you know fast
forward four or five years later now
efficiency is starting to become part of
this conversation and so you know it's
just we have to get over that artifact
of where the industry has come from and
where it is now and where it can go and
we can be a real leader in agriculture
itself to be very efficient we have that
opportunity
you