all right Thank You Gretchen I'm Adrian
Adrian Giovinco CEO and co-founder of
inspired inspiration solutions thank you
for the opportunity to share some
information with you guys today let's
jump in on the next slide we learned
earlier from Corinne that light plus co2
plus water equals the sugar and oxygen
that we're looking for the plants need
to make sugar because this is plant food
and if you can't do this effectively
plants suffer and your outcomes will
suffer in the facility so when the
people who work with plants tell us that
there are nine cardinal parameters we
must remember that co2 and light are
only two of the nine important things
for plant growth and vitality as
providers of HVAC systems we designed
equipment knowing that we had direct
control over four of the nine parameters
the ones we highlighted in the circle on
the left side of the slide but
indirectly we affect the four parameters
in the root zone and even more
importantly if you want to take
advantage of the investment that you've
made in your lights and the full
spectrum of photons they provide you
ideally want to have the healthiest
plants to do so now all of this comes
down to the environment we take it so
seriously because we recognize that
environmental control is cultural
control and in the backbone of an IPM or
integrated pest management plan is
environmental control you know our team
has a mantra and that is you must
control the culture or the culture will
control you and managing your
environment correctly will prevent a
whole host of more costly interventions
and we just heard a little bit from
Chris about the importance of
biosecurity mindset we can talk about
that a little bit more and dig deeper
into it but something that's that's so
so important in this case you can truly
say that an ounce of prevention is worth
a pound of cure or in this case cured
bud let's move to the next slide and
discuss the importance of temperature it
is significant because the actual plant
cells will thrive in a narrow band of
temperature and outside that they'll
assimilate less and less of that
Rush's co2 that they need to drive the
sugar making process but keep in mind
that leaf temperature and room
temperature are sometimes two very
different things so how to growers
balance the room environment to control
the leaf temperature let's move to the
next slide and take a look
so most sophisticated growers will use a
VPD chart which is the chart on the Left
let's start with some definitions a
plant will move water through the root
system up the stem into the leaves and
out of tiny pores on the leaves the
pores are called stomata this process is
called transpiration and is driven by
the fact that just inside of the leaves
on the other side of the stomata our
saturated wet pockets of air the high
humidity inside the plant creates a
pressure with the external environment
which is at a lower humidity and this
pressure is called the vapor pressure
differential or vapor pressure
difference or vapor pressure deficit or
differential all abbreviated as VPD in
this case difference differential
deficit mean the same thing when you
hear that we can take a leaf at a
specific temperature and set of
temperature and humidity conditions and
generate the VPD metric most typically
calculated in Pascal's to measure that
pressure and now sophisticated grower
uses this this particular chart to
maintain try to maintain a temperature
and humidity most conducive to the stage
of life that the plan is in as a
mechanical engineer we use a similar
tool called the psychrometric chart
which is this chart on the right to
design an environment that delivers the
VPD to the grower that that is we
deliver an environment that allows the
plants to have a VPD that is suitable
for it's appropriate stage of growth and
in doing so delivers maximum vitality
and yield now take note that the axes on
both charts have temperature and
relative humidity which allow for these
charts to be used together in
conjunction now moving from the
theoretical this chart can often be Mis
applied by people who don't understand
that the VPD chart is not a static
diagram
in fact it starts by knowing that the
temperature of the leaf relative to the
room around it and this is most directly
impacted by the type of lighting that
serves the plant let's move to the next
slide and look at this in practice this
VPD chart is drawn on the condition
whereby the room temperature and the
leaf temperature are the same this is
usually indicative of a room at night
where there are no lights shining on the
plants let's move to the next slide and
this is a VPD chart showing optimal
conditions for a plant when it is
exposed to LED lights take note that in
this case the leaf temperature is cooler
than the room temperature or in practice
with the HVAC D systems the room
temperature is held on the warmer side
let's move to the next slide
and look at a VPD chart showing optimal
conditions for a plant when it is
exposed to HID lights here the leaf
temperature is warmer than the room
temperature or in practice with the HVAC
D system the room temperature is held on
the cooler side now can you see the
difference on how the chart is redrawn
each time we've gone through that
exercise between those three different
charts the really the real point to
drive home here hang on one sec the real
point to drive home here is that VPD is
a moving target in any room and it
really requires a deeper understanding
than what a downloaded VPD chart off the
internet and taking that and treating it
like gospel what would allow you to do
now thankfully growers are coming around
to understanding this and can use or
horticultural specific environmental
control systems to bring dynamic VPD to
their rooms let's move to the next slide
and talk about the significance of data
metrics and KPIs it's so important to be
able to take advantage of data and learn
from data but if you don't have a funnel
and a means of taking that data turning
it into metrics and ultimately KPIs for
your business to be to be benchmarked on
and be able to take actionable
Corrections or you know direction from
that
data you know what was then that purpose
of gathering that data right so
benchmarking is a key function in in
figuring out where you start from and
where you're at and then you can use
different types of these metrics and
KPIs whether it's grams per watt dollars
per gram operating cost per pound
condensate capture over total water
things like this from a high level
cultivator perspective and business
owner perspective and the lighting side
we can talk about micro moles per Joule
for us on the HVAC D side we talk about
pounds per hour of moisture removal per
kW of electricity that it cost to remove
that that moisture and it's such a more
impactful metric than tons of cooling
type metric let's move on to the next
slide and talk about some HVAC design
considerations you know this is a as
Chris from live well documented it's
come up a number of times through the
through the panel today this is a
moisture removal challenge not an air
conditioning challenge and knowing
knowing that and knowing that it is
really based upon understanding your
actual daily watering rates is such a
key component and we'll talk a little
bit about sizing in a second room
conditions are key to that because
different as we just talked about
different types of lighting systems
require different room conditions and
then those as such then those those room
conditions have a either in at positive
or negative affect D rating or
increasing the capacity of any given
HVAC system based upon what those room
conditions are and the amount of
moisture that you that you wish to
remove air flow considerations have just
been touched on significantly in the
last couple especially with Chris who
league which is which is Graham just
consistent clean trying to remove
microclimates airflow over is really one
of those things that can can
significantly positively impact your
facility with with not a whole lot else
to it if you're having big challenges
and I'm really glad that he talked about
biosecurity that's
you know of course all of these topics
are things we could have much deeper
dives on so just to quickly flash up for
you a what we use as a basis of figuring
out the pounds per hour of moisture
removal to size HVAC equipment so pounds
per hour it is truly the daily watering
rate times the percentage of moisture
removed during the day divided by the
number of photo period on hours and then
converting from gallons to pounds four
of water and this is just a graph
that'll give you an example of a
particular particular room we go to the
next slide this is really important you
know what we're advocates for growers to
know and understand this equation and be
able to be an active participant in the
design of their systems but with any
ruler equation really comes nuances and
exceptions to the rules and an
understanding that there's different
rooms different you know bedrooms versus
flower rooms versus mother rooms also
different proportion who will have
different proportions as well as
different crops will have different
proportions is very very important to
understand that let's recap on the next
in the last slide and give you a few
nuggets to take away to the Q&amp;A section
cultural control is the foundation of
success we really are big believers in
that and the environmental control via
the HVAC D system D for dehumidification
is key to any IPM strategy the third
bullet here of different HVAC D systems
system types we could go into another
multi minute our conversation about all
the different types of systems it's
mostly important to understand that
there's many different types of HVAC
systems out there and then it's really
important to be able to evaluate the
limitations and risk of different types
of systems be able to look at different
types of energy savings features work
that in conjunction with your utility
early and often as mentioned earlier and
then be able to balance that with capex
op X and cash flow in your speed to
market plan I'll just leave you with you
know we advocate for choosing your
partners with care and we always want to
say to treat those plants with respect
and have fun thank you