hey there bam just wanted to say man
thank you so much for doing that show
last night i learned so much from you
guys uh i got rated in april
and i've been trying to kind of like
talk about what's going on and
you know i was blasted all over
instagram the local newspaper facebook
and everybody thought it was just me and
then
everybody started getting raided and now
shit's kind of popping off they're
raiding this morning
and i've been trying to speak out kind
of like watch what i'm saying though and
i'm trying to work it behind the scenes
and all that shit but like
watching you guys last night gave me so
much faith and hope i learned so much
like i've been in this for
in the industry for 10 years myself uh
but you know this is my first time
getting rated like this
and i just i find solidarity in the fact
that this is not just happening just in
this county has happened
everywhere and if we all come together
we can figure this out but if they keep
us isolated they're just going to keep
fucking everybody for a long time so i'm
just
thank you and i really hope to work with
you guys and other industry leaders man
i fucking love everybody