[Music]
so what is losing losing men started
as a plant that translates so if I'm a
slow death it just leads to death what
kind of joy can there be so how about we
don't lead to that how do we start I
would say there's one more step we got
to teach people the difference between a
dirt which is dead
you can play and die on my plan there
too yeah it's great to get dirty but
it's not growing yeah let's go get dirty
but then come back and go sir
and to do that what do you I'm gonna
make it even more simple what crap
well 95% of them all pretty much like
the same thing yep so now up to a
one-to-one meeting and that's that's
called counting and most people don't
realize that scientific speech is like 2
to 1 it's just like your THC CBD ratios
1 to 2 ratio that's it well how do we
find that out and there's an expectation
that we have to go buy something to do
that yourself for free if you have time
if you have the price of a microscope
you know about $300 for that microscope
you learn how to use it and you can do
all of your own testing at that point
well why would I want to do all my own
testings why would I want to pay someone
a lot of money to take my soil sample to
tell me if it's healthy or not because
you learn a lot faster exactly what you
need to do is that keep things done
faster you don't wellfest
and it takes you 20 minutes what it
takes you 20 minutes to look through a
microscope mm-hmm why are you doing so
slowly I can literally look hey there's
some fungi right well you still know
that a representative number
but the cannabis community the normal
person who's not a true soil nurse they
literally just want to know if there's
this right stuff in it how can we help
the plant be more of what it wants to be
do we do anything or do we just work
with the microbes that do all the work
it's our job to put those microorganisms
back into that soil because it's us that
have destroyed that soil and turned it
into dirt and we got to reverse the
process we've got to turn that dirt back
in the soil and so if we want to do it
at human speed and you know we're very
impatient we've got to have everything's
got to get fixed yesterday and if we
want to do it that speed we're gonna
have to take it into responsibilities
right right we've got to be the ones who
come back and heal it within the time
span that we require mother nature will
get it back don't worry don't fuss but
she could take ten thousand years to get
it down no I don't either I would like
to stay alive I'd like my children to
stay alive I would like to just still be
around next year and sometimes I worry
so we've gotta put that yeah we've got
to put that biology back into the soil
and the sooner the better because then
we can start taking that elevated carbon
in the atmosphere and putting it back
into the soil from whence it came so
let's just start what can I do tomorrow
to make the changes that we have to make
me start making some mom posts for you
guys he yeah well I'd like to start with
the compost so just allowing organic
materials to break down in a beneficial
way yeah we we want to make certain that
it's selecting for the right
microorganisms in there they have to be
aerobic those are the good guys we don't
want to be growing diseases or problem
organisms we don't want to be putting
anything toxic so it's gotta stay
aerobic but quick question about that
because most people have a perspective
of
who wins right who the fight that battle
between good versus bad bugs and why
does an aerobic environment when out
over the negative microbes for our
benefit and our plants benefit mm-hmm
well plants are obligate aerobes they
have to maintain aerobic conditions
around that root system around any part
of the plant in order for that plant to
be able to perform its function of
reproducing making fruit yeah cuz what
do we actually eat mmm
all of that good reproductive tissue the
plants are making so we've got to make
certain that it stays aerobic and that
means having organisms that will build
structure in your soil and that's a
major component of what microorganisms
do aerobic microorganisms do for you
anaerobic microorganisms don't build
structure because they don't want to
build airways and passageways to allow
oxygen to move into their habitat
because they thrive well back from our
point of view yeah bad from the point of
view of producing food so we've got to
make certain that we maintain that
habitat around the root systems of the
plant and they both got part of the
plant so that that plant will thrive
we've got to convert the nutrients which
are in our soils already there 55 pounds
worth of gypsum or lime or inorganic
nitrogen fertilizers or phosphate
fertilizers or sulfur fertilizers we
don't know if I haven't put the bag of
that product on the soil how did it get
there how did it get there all these new
trees the 42 necessary like supporting
yep or more than that actually now that
we newly start getting into it now
always always good to be more I always
love it when you go back in time and you
look at back in the 1950s there were
only three major nutrients that if you
put in
Aion you were gonna be just fine that's
all you had to worry about and then it
got to be a couple more and then a next
thing you knew I was eight essential
nutrients and then it was 12 and it was
18 and then it was 24 and then it was
30-something and you know now if you
talk to certain plant people they're
gonna be saying it's 42 I like that I
like a number 42 because it's the answer
to the universe what's your what do you
think the best kind of clay to grow
cannabis to use to feed the microbes
best microbial food for cannabis and can
you talk about montmorillonite clay or
like the best kind of clay for I don't
think there's really a best kind you
just have to recognize what kind of clay
you've got what's your sand with your
silt what's your clay remember clay is a
mineral differentiation just like sand
and silt okay so clay does not grow
anything so yeah not really you just
have to understand why is that clay red
and it's telling you about past history
the reason why clay is red as it went
anaerobic at one time and under
anaerobic conditions your iron is going
to be converted into a highly reduced
form when oxygen comes back into that
system then as that highly reduced iron
is oxidized it turns into a completely
not a plant usable form of iron so of
course and we think that this is
horrible clay this is really bad get
some iron like I'm referring to
montmorillonite clay specifically that
has if you look at the MSDS breakdown it
has every trace mineral on it like gold
cadmium lead arsenic and everything that
can think
and you know but we don't even know
everything basically but I mean it's
it's I see the difference in my plants
when I use it and it's it's I think it's
really good stuff because you can eat a
tooth livestock feed and I don't know
I'm really curious about using my
mineral clay and really when you look at
any soil which you know the mineral
component in any soil is gonna be the
sand to seal the Clay's only three it's
all size fractions and that's all we're
really talking about when we're dealing
with the difference between clay and
silt what's helping your plants grow
really do man they how do the microbes
break down clay I love this answer
they have enzymes that they make and
they pull out of the crystalline
structure of that clay the nutrients and
it's my six-year-old in a way that would
make him so the bacteria and fungi at
the direction of the plant are gonna do
exactly yeah they're told what to do and
golly they go do it because the plant is
giving them cakes and cookies in order
to do the work that the plant requires
because the plant can't move yeah and
it's kind of just like your mom you know
luring you to clean your bedroom she
offers you cakes and cookies and then
you go ahead and do that work because it
makes the name the clone originator I'm
trying not to give the name away for all
these indoor grows we call them mothers
so literally the mothers are
communicating into the soil ecosystem
what they need yep and when they don't
need it yep they don't eat it so you
don't have to add whatever mineral the
store says you have to add yeah because
you don't need to you know mom is
already taking care of herself so you
know let her right now we gotta stop
interfering and pretending like we
no better right yeah so we we go in
there and we interfere with all this
stuff and all it does is destroy the
biology that would have done the work
for us if we had just let things go the
way they're supposed to not amazing it's
because we don't understand what we're
doing
why did the Green Revolution happen it
wasn't really because we needed to be
put in those nutrients into the soil
it's because we had piles and piles of
leftover munitions from war from World
War one and then World War two even
worse because we bombed Hiroshima knows
a lot about the byproducts of war mm-hmm
and we're still picking up the pieces -
yeah but instead of picking up the
pieces and ending up with a bunch of
poisons and nitrates you you said
ammonium nitrate and nobody even
flinched but that's the same stuff
that'll blow up a building right well
you have to have the proper combination
of nitrate and ammonium but I can have a
truck full of soil I love it mass
prosperity
I love selfish farmer questions because
farmers share can you can you talk about
the the dance between the the two most
common polymers in nature the cellulose
and the chitin how can we intentionally
produce large amounts of chitin ace to
use as a pest deterrent and activate the
pest deterrent abilities of plants the
best way you know do I need to add all
that to my soil it's growing there all
by itself so why would I get anything to
it except for the required organics and
microbes that access everything and when
you think about the plant is going to be
putting out cakes and cookies to get
those bacteria or fungi to do the
decomposition of the exoskeletons of the
dead insect
structural materials cellulose in the
plant material that's why most people
think they need to add it because we're
talking about full-blown full beautiful
organic true holistic growing mm-hmm
okay
a lot of people need to add things
because they're growing in a pot in a
basement at which point of course
there's nothing for the one worm or
whatever to eat because it's not a
complete ecosystem you're lacking a
whole bunch of the microorganisms to
help that earthworm stay alive and like
you explained earlier when you send your
soil in to be tested gosh this is the
misnomer right yeah and they come back
and say look at all this horrible stuff
or they say you don't have an adequate
amount of the soluble inorganic
nutrients hmm so you're gonna have to
put more in there translates into plant
accessible mm-hmm plants have access to
it
it's microorganisms are gonna do the
conversion of that material from plant
not available into plant available on
whose terms on the plants terms the
plant is getting what it wants already
there we go your plant tells the soil
food web what it needs and statement all
we as human beings have to do is make
certain the full diversity of all the
organisms are present in there the
bacteria the fungi the protozoa the
nematodes microbiomes earthworms spiders
voters voles choose insects don't have
dead insects you don't have chitin so
the insects everything now this is the
fear well then how the hell are my
plants gonna grow if all these other
things are in my garden and I'd like you
to explain cuz I'm a California
grower mm-hmm and I grow plants mm-hmm I
didn't with all my background I didn't
know the simple truth of the reason
ground squirrels and Gophers will not
eat your plants right how many of us
wrap our root balls in wire because
we're trying to protect them we're doing
our best to protect them we don't
understand but all that those Gophers
the voles the shoes the things that eat
your root systems they're there because
mother nature told them to go there and
make certain that they build structure
in the soil pathways for the bacteria in
the fungi protozoa nematodes to get into
that soil so they're breaking up those
the Gophers are breaking up the
compaction well until you fix your soil
and still until you get rid of that
compaction layer and that's what these
guys are situation you and so action
layer is the kicker yeah it's a ground
squirrels hole or the mole hole or
gopher vote depends cannot support
itself open mm-hmm it collapses right
that tells the animal which is part of
the soil food web you don't want to live
here you've got a job move along so they
will literally turn around and not go
into your garden because it's a truly
healthy ecosystem yep I'm not kidding
dude did I tell you look at it knows
what she's doing and it's just as human
beings that keeps screwing up because we
paid no attention to the information
that Mother Nature is bright and
sticking right in front of my face we
don't pay attention to it and we think
we know better
poor little mother nature she needs our
help and so we're gonna as we sing in a
redwood grove yeah that no one planted
these trees have been growing here just
fine all by themselves no inorganic
fertilizers no no
nothing where's the 55 pound bag of
gypsum yep and these guys are putting on
putting more carbon into their bodies
every year then any crop that you want
to be growing wait a very night after
talking about global warming climate
change these are called carbon sinks
yeah yeah these trees put on more carbon
every year that global warming have
cleaner air blah blah blah all the
things people whined about we should
just let things grow mm-hmm stop tearing
them down stop no harvesting them and
turning them into especially mature
ecosystem yeah because they may take
10,000 years to truly develop yep it
takes a special place yeah because if
you tear down these trees and you till
the soil and you wipe out all the
biology it's gonna be a thousand years
ten thousand years for you even to get
to the point where these trees could
possibly grow again so they've got to
have all of this development of the soil
to even be able to germinate and get
established here so so when do you start
growing when do I start growing my
answer is when do I stop yeah why would
I have my garden growing mmm-hmm there's
currently no cannabis planted in it but
there's everything else I'm building
soil every second that we're sitting
here I usually so this is a fun one
how much compost tea I make a
five-gallon bucket of fungal rich and
bacterial dense every week even in the
off season and I brew it outside so that
the microbes that are grown are the
microbes that are thriving at that
temperature range because that's what
I'm gonna put on my plants because
they're at that temperature range it's
not that hard right it's not that
difficult it's that's outside that's ten
gallons
of love a week you should have a pretty
good food webbing oh it's so beautiful I
have I have dicots
that haven't even popped split with 9 in
route 9 its roots alright very good
because the food web is feeding because
it hasn't really started even
photosynthesize yet so who's feeding
that plant because it's too young to
even make cakes and cookies really I
mean it is a little bit but yeah the
food web is literally saying oh we know
what to do with you come here you're
gonna need some of this right and
because that little plants should be
already tuned into the below ground
Network those Michael Raizel fungi are
already colonizing those roots and so
we're talking about three to six months
yep
so it when you have a good functioning
food web in that soil the root systems
of that baby plants are going to be
colonizing immediately with an hour so
not three to six months literally
instantaneous but we just don't see the
effects from maybe hours yep so sounds
good to me
we want a really healthy plant right
from the very beginning so you never
realized that it would have otherwise
been stunted and limited and unhappy and
no fertility and sick and diseased
because it's been started out right yeah
from the very beginning and you know how
much I spend on my compost tea couple
dollars I bought a twelve dollar
I got a twelve dollar bubbler and I've
been using that for a long time yep and
it runs two hoses that's where one for
each bucket yep so it's you know the
electricity things so a little bit
electricity a little bit for the to
start the materials that you put in
collecting yeah and it's your time yeah
and that's all it is so how much is my
time worth
I don't know $25 an hour here's a
question all right how much how much
does someone go and spend at the store
or you can just hang out with your
plants for an hour max and it's doing
good things for you to hang out with
your plants so I'd rather be outside
putzing around in my garden then do and
then go into the store and buying toxic
chemicals and then having to figure out
how I'm gonna spread them and do you
ever walk through a hardware store
anywhere like that and just walking near
that aisle makes your skin like you feel
the toxins in the air
yep right yeah like you're like that's
not healthy yeah come here children
you're like what are they being exposed
to in my garden nothing yeah except
goodness yeah good breathable air
where's that come from let's start out
from that
where's good breathable healthy air come
from diagnosed well from anything that
photosynthesizes because they're taking
that carbon dioxide and pulling the
carbon off and blowing off that oxygen
there's where a good breathable air
comes from so instead of standing in
front of like a air purifier in my
office I should maybe just have a plan
on my toes yeah you should have a couple
plants yeah so you know if you just have
a couple of plants in your office that
you're taking care of and they're
healthy and they're happy they're gonna
provide you all the oxygen you need for
the whole entire year and are you
talking about just breathable air or
maybe a little soul air too
well because those plants are pretty
good comfort you know they brighten your
day they will eventually flower and well
that's positivity flowers are
you
[Music]