[Music]
have made further forces Michael our
message would be our message will be to
endure
kofi from Java if you don't have the
exact world that define that exactly
profile that pain that you that you want
of seiga or why not eat cheese or
anything that the birth test that is
degree stative you need a vocabulary to
think to to to distinguish and with
cannabis even more so because there is
so much inner city into it like grapes
you know there's how many different
kinds of those are you to know there is
thousands and thousands and thousands of
of you of cannabis creative that what
complicated little bit the basic to our
story it's simple we don't even have to
prove that we have a cannabis day while
it's over now it's when you you are
devious the diversity of cannabis to the
firstly to zero to two - what horizontal
tell it bring it to to another limit to
another dimension you did with cannabis
anyway so it's no bigger than any single
already it's gonna be imitation per se
it's just much bigger territory to
create a lot of different happen for
file you know what I mean so it's like
yes we should small stick to the basic
it's like the deposition the lesion it's
something it's dedicated to create
quality only that's is the one name of
the game is that so we should stick to
all the song down that create quality
stuffing I never really thought about it
but the my copy in your soul I guess
that would be the number one stage you
I mean knowing your swords a plan to
take from your from your soul and what
define that specific characteristic of
the place where he goes the taste of
that specific place that's the value of
the small of small farming and terror
definitely is the precise mix of the
nutrients that are being taken up by the
plant and how the planet is dispersing
that in its body and that's what gives
that unique flavor different cultivate
yeah but not chase the cannabis for a
vision it's like the way of a beach
because in function of T WA the lawns
the crime and the couch Eva and and the
summer the community that creates that
quality but you have also the terroir a
testings that they were and in that case
it has always been a big debate because
it's never been proven that the grape
actually capture the characteristic of
the place now is the study on my home
they theorize that it's actually the
microbial life that change from that
specific piece of lung to that also side
of the of the track and this is what
brings us different characteristic to
the to the one it's not a plant it's a
life in the circle that do everything so
I like schedules there's communities in
the soil right and how are the
communities in the soil translating into
communities above-ground cannabis
because it uses step and to all every
single both ground then the specificity
of the of the climate as sex life is
going to bring certain aspect of a
profile that you're not going to get on
the other side of the valley or
or in any other is the unusual places in
a in a world so it's like you have that
as much as you get the tape and from
also all that mutual that the plant
absorbs ooh step ends and the plot mix
them
depending on that above-ground necessity
basically so I want to see if this
metaphor holds up all of these little
puzzle pieces is like a pixelated
picture that by themselves they're part
of it but only all working together do
you see what's really going on yeah I
think that's a good metaphor and it's
certainly in the world of science being
very reductionistic they want to take
each little pixel and study that very
very finely and they get lost in that
reductionism they forget that they've
got to put all the pieces in the puzzle
back together to see that overall
pattern and then you realize that this
is just one tiny little pixel and like
any four four people you know how is it
how's the the clay the communities in
the soil gonna affect the communities
and as people
well that's nutrients know about getting
in food who's helped of the most which
communities around the world not just
here in America when you take into
account the soil food web it's well you
know when what can we influence which
group of people communities which
cultures are most receptive to learning
just how to do it the natural way yeah
where did yeah it's the poorest
countries in the world or where the
biggest effect can can occur most
rapidly right because you've got to send
somebody there to get them to understand
the the simple measures whereas in
industrialized nations we've got to have
big equipment we've got you know a
thousand acre farms or ten thousand
hectare farms or something like that and
and that's hard to change is not good
for the planet they just don't get it
like you can you can do big space
but you have to cut down that big space
into chunk and especially in nature
chunks that poor not producers and
project because our sake life the world
life web of the planet is made of
diversity and we fucking scale of
diversity is like it's like you want to
create GMO tomato to make to me to
resist our heat place the tomato was
bloody born in the desert okay so we
don't have another planet some genetics
that could do exactly and better
whatever you want to do is like it's
crazy so it's like it's that fear of
diversity and wanting to corner that
specific aspect of whatever because we
fancy it better the reason why we do GMO
and in the conventional world is because
we want everything to become right now
on exactly the same day is that the most
important thing about your food is that
it became there was all pickable at the
same time on the same day it's the wrong
thing to be emphasizing I mean they
don't really a future you need to create
plants that can work that can go on
poison if you want to grow a plant or
you have to clean the soil to be able to
go and then Ziploc there is only two
choices on and I mean I don't know it
sounds very simple when you say there's
only two choices
yeah working 100% with a healthy
ecosystem which takes care of the plant
for you or growing it and poison I mean
that's where we stole them is that where
you still do industrial version
you have to grow it in poison to control
every single little process yeah to
death and the fact is if we get the
proper biology in the soil we can
achieve the same end which is to get
everything becoming ripe on the same day
and harvest it just the way that
chemical companies wanna be able to
manage all of their their growth we can
do the same thing but you have to
understand all the bits and pieces and I
have a picture puzzle yeah executors
yeah it's Fabio casting falsehood
because we have we have a connection
with our family of therma of small my
mom she never bought in our life
anything but at the farmer down the
street every usual day of your life and
my go home as the same Zeus famine
during World War two not only they were
going food for France but they were
risking their life to bring that in
inner city they have a lot of power the
farmer they are protected like national
treasure there is nothing that come in a
country that can compete with the
quality and the price that are old by
the French government and the farmer is
a because if they go on or if they go
and on strike there is nothing that move
in France ever until you give it to them
so it's like that that pause that
relation with people you don't have it
here there is like there is respect for
farming there is a better understanding
that your kawatte is actually growing in
soil literally this like most people
have no relation with that part of of
the food chain because here it's not
food it's business you know and I mean
it's like food it's not something super
importing food in in Europe sharing
water or on the Mediterranean Sea
it's a give the Gators hospitality just
that you can give it's like food is
everything and now we just see it as a
necessity is a reason there is nothing
behind but its business when a commodity
exactly the word I was I am much more
than that it's like all MCS is dependent
you are what you eat and we are eating
poison and they want to make it worse by
creating GMO monster when you can just
clean the place and it's like you say
it's not that difficult to clean the
place you just need to dedicate as there
is so much organic matter that we can
take care of we we I mean it's like we
are responsible because there is there
is a huge responsibility behind being in
a cannabis and you see where you are
supposed to save the planet and then you
go in Colorados extract only CBD from
from plant and this was I'm stuck in a
let it rot in you don't even do paper
with it like seriously CBD is a
by-product is the icing on the cake that
prout has been bleeded for tens of
thousands of years to make fiber and
seeds and that you just go away okay
it's like there is the money people they
don't see what you can do with with an
fiber it's like it's not only you can
change the face of the planet but the
guy who is gonna put out biodegradable
plastic bag on the table it is going to
eat it seriously you want a jackpot you
want money
Doozers bag Doozers hotel-dieu or
everything that we is made of paid whole
like it would give us some bricks that
are that are fireproof we really need it
in California there is like so much to
do with it and at the same time you
clean the ground and is like it's a it's
a you teammate power that give us the
ability to go into the 21st century and
finally new source of
of energy that that doesn't compromise
life on those many traditional cultures
that I've experienced around the world
the farmer is at the same cultural level
in the community as the best hunter or
the best fisherman because it's really
about meeting the community's needs and
the farmer is the one when the animals
aren't there plants are really hard to
run away from we have managed to
denigrate the role of the farmer most
don't farmers is being stupid and not
really knowing but part of it is that
instead of them managing their own land
and them managing the plant and getting
the best they just call up fertilizer
agents and that fertilizer person tells
them what to do you need to go out and
put out three tons of line and half a
ton of gypsum on your land and then a
week later what am I supposed to do from
the farmer well you're supposed to go
out and you put on ammonium nitrate or
you put out urea the next week it's
something else something else and that
farmer has released the responsibility
they are just slaves if you will they're
their serfs to the chemical companies
you're being told what to do basically
yeah they're not thinking they're not
participating in this they're just the
worker and we've farmers that actually
understand and know what they're doing
and small farms are much better for
having people really know what's going
on in their soil what's going on with
their plans you have a thousand hectares
you a thousand acres how can you keep
track of everything so I really like the
European model much better where the
farms are small when you look where when
I look at the space you are here it's
really hard to sink small farm yeah I
mean you don't
but at the same point why they don't
understand is monoculture is like when I
learned that you have to move your be
from A to Z to a grantor C order or
elder country to be able to have put in
is yes I mean if you're if you're a
farmer and you don't have this you don't
have Polly nation is like a man is like
and you're not slipping out of your
shoes no seeds no so it's a greedy
reaching a point of no heat down here
like that's that's Kelly ceilings and as
the world poor economic power that stone
behind Kennedy's as to be used to to
challenge that so it's like for us it's
not like I mean I'm cool I don't want to
make money I'm just dude literally a
giveaway and stuff yeah it's nice take
care of people but fucking make money
because if we have money it's a tool
that you have a money you can do stuff
okay the moment you have the bigger
stuff you can do
well he's so much stuff to do that it
would be cool that people with the
certain level of consciousness and the
blade to make it happen
and take care of the community yeah
because it's you know 2d to define the
terroir there is six science one is the
science of soil which is to science at
the same time everything else it's all
the community it's more it's beyond an
actual farmer it's more than the
community of the observation and so I
couldn't meet that change that specific
place and stuff so I just heard him say
that there's the soil community and then
there's the rest of the community
because it's all community and now what
we're doing is even bridging the gap
between the soil community and the rest
of the community you know I think it's
so it's business community so
is that an odd yes
but it's obscene that or ancestor of
ancestor knew that I mean it's like Oh
grandparents a the knew how to keep the
sole factor doing not that much and
producing a lot so it like it's now we
have the science to show what our Valley
tradition are basically and this is
important because it you need this to
validate anything in in the 21st century
basically otherwise it's just like
bullshit of old people crazy P all that
type of stuff now and you can put the
number and show that we shed you're
doing this you do you produce such a
such a such a ripple in in the life web
and that's why you shouldn't do it when
it's only vocal Oh hard knowledge that
is passed down it's something that you
have to be into it to believe now you
can you can tell everybody here that has
been better using bullshit pushed by
your by companies look it's simple
you're making a mistake because this is
this and this and it's not refuted or
dislike you fast fact such a beauty of
it is like now tradition of the weight
that science bring with it for me ash
and everything that is happening it's
the same I need that science to be able
to prove explain what I experience with
the plant and everything on my life
nobody sings of my home and the life web
of the sort when everything is coming
from that simple three words or less and
so I came up with something that I
referred to as symbiosis to synapse so I
think that's a very good way of relating
that you know because your brain
and then the symbiosis so I think that's
really a good expression I could be
wrong but I like to keep things very
simple for people's every word is rule
to a good visual yes right moseys that
if you could simplify it even more that
you would say kind of embodies I work at
fairly small scales and then build the
layers up and look at each layer you
know we often talk about breadth of
knowledge well we need depth of
knowledge as well kind of like our roots
yeah hmm it's somewhat similar so here's
the question how roots will the roots
grow how deep will the roots go it
depends standard ecological answer it
depends on the conditions most plants
can be put in their root systems down 15
20 25 100 you know you get two feet feet
feet yeah why is my plant growing in the
pot this small SMO Tina but that's a
good question yeah there is no thougts
there's no smart foot it's a nice it's a
nice bone name but she knows the main
the woods destroys a bottom and go
straight down is empty to clue that you
don't you see then confine the soil when
we don't have plant material on the
surface of the soil then rain frame will
hit that surface and cause compaction at
some depth which means your roots going
down can't get through that they're
gonna go
ways and they're gonna fight with their
neighbor you know fight with things
around none of your plants are gonna be
healthy so instead of them thriving as a
community this is a metaphor - they're
fighting for survival mm-hmm yeah it's
warfare and then I think I'd fight
nature really selects more towards
symbiosis working together socially with
plants in the soil they should have
Michael right so fungi that they're
sharing and therefore every plant in
this whole thousand acres should be
connected equally as healthy because
they're connected below ground this is
really one plant the aspen tree is a
literal example that a lot of people
know because when an aspen tree turns a
whole hillside will turn because it's
really one tree with lots of branches
that come up as a ground runners right
where in our situation we know that it's
not just one tree it's one community and
we want the whole thing to be healthy
everything connected below ground
because then everything's healthy if any
one of those plants are is healthy then
yeah that Chinese there is any one that
cannot fit the other violent when you
think of it it's yeah the potato heating
issues every theory until there is the
goodness that the plant is is taking
from it I didn't I hope you really like
the plant is the farmer you know the
plant is putting out the exudates to
grow this system to protect itself to
both above ground as
below ground the the plant is in control
of all of this and since World War one
human beings have started to forget
about that not pay attention to it the
plant is stupid we have to supply it
with all of its nutrients it can't fend
for itself you have to put all of this
effort into growing a plant or as if you
would just stop and let the right
biology come back the plants perfectly
capable of growing itself of getting the
nutrients that it requires and
protecting itself without us adding
truckloads of amendment that it doesn't
mean we're killing ourselves as the
winner you to know that your Warren PK
that you're the one induced fee of
feeding penalties raised on the sea I
demand that you find aunt you burn the
plant so you figure it out away the
world a limitation of the living
organism burning that living organ is
and checking what is left from it it's
like how would you figure out the
alimentation of a human being by burning
a and getting the data from the ashes it
doesn't make sense in the first place is
that it's scary and everybody follow it
and the people bullshit you with a veil
of no jikan opposed to me that is really
scary and like nobody asked question
it's all good chemistry where you have a
huge number of emergent properties that
you cannot predict just on the basis of
the chemistry in your body the mineral
elements you can't you can't predict
human behavior from that point of view
so why do we keep trying to do that and
it's all it's used as an excuse to sell
people something they don't mean they
put themselves into that
trap they get too needy touch them
because they have no choice but an
addictive relationship you know they
have to go back just like that one time
and they're dead they're not there to do
the job that the plants expecting them
to do so now the plants not getting the
nutrition it's not getting what it needs
so he thinks that we have to come along
and we have to provide it if you kill
the organisms then you're gonna have to
do their job and we are doing the job
that these microorganisms should be
doing and they love to do it yeah yeah
like human beings living in houses and
stuff yeah human beings over there we
want to grow we want to have families
well sort of the organisms in the soil
that's just their house yeah why do we
keep destroying that one they're only
trying to do what they're supposed to do
because somebody wants to sell you
something they're not mine you don't
yeah doctor is there any evidence in
using crystals or rocks with plant or
living organisms in earth to you know we
don't have and that's the problem
yes there sometimes seems to be a
benefit the frequency oh the time yeah
cuz we're we don't have machines we
don't have a way to assess it and if you
can't measure something feeling for a
while and I wasn't sure if you know if
there was any kind of say yes yeah
scientists point to work on how we
measure this yes how do you measure moon
for tidal forces different kinds of
energies coming through the atmosphere
area yes resonant frequency and exactly
yeah so that's that's fine thank you
yes sorry no I
this is how I answered that question to
my kid not that's the city I don't know
and then I say let's go find out and
sometimes it's a Google search
sometimes it's us going out to the
garden because he's like what happens if
you do this my garden is a place where
he can experiment growing life and
sometimes it means he kills my plans but
my plants once they die stop growing
they go they don't get ripped out they
go back into the soil like I don't even
pull roots the root is the pathway
exactly so you don't take that plant and
throw it on the waste pile and take it
off to the landfill oh yeah
why would you do that and yet we've
we've taught the current generations
that that's what you do here in the
United States it's what you don't leave
the you don't leave something you can be
busted for a reality to the culture so
why are you growing in pots so that one
rabbit
seeing where the plum goes because it's
prohibition you don't live shit in your
garden you burn it you saw it in a place
nobody see it it's like there's a lot of
stuff that people do is because of
prohibition and they don't really know
better leave that material I'm a soil
surface that it grows pathogens it grows
[Music]
that's how it started yeah
so should we be taking the organic
material that grew right up out of the
ground that we're standing from and then
use that to go back into the ground yeah
it has to do that that's what should be
happening but who's making money yeah
that's how you have to go that's what
it's like when you create start out of
quality you can define as well not only
the microbial life that is going to be
moved actually to do such-and-such a
plant in such a such a place but you can
control every aspect of it so that
people like given me as a ice maker okay
I gonna make I gotta spin them in water
but then I should put them back to the
plan that gave me it and it's like there
is every plant on the planet is going
from the preceding generation I mean
that's what they do so not having that
it's something we are missing or so in
that it like I was telling them last
night there is if the plant has an
epigenetic memory how come we always
have all the problem that there is here
that I have never seen in producing
country like the plant should be after a
few generations have no problem
whatsoever
it like at best the best genetic here in
this paradigm of conventional
agriculture they are killing all of
those things that would be allowing that
plant to develop the resistant
populations a bacteria fungi protozoa
nematodes in this weakness we need to
create strength don't these weeks there
is something going wrong me elastic
that's weak it's a lack of the proper
biology in the soil the plant feeds
those organisms in the soil using
exudates using sugars and
proteins and carbohydrates being
released from that root system and that
plant is expecting to have those
organisms around that root system in
that soil because it's been there for
the last four billion years so the
plants and we've destroyed in modern
agriculture we've destroyed that biology
for the I was telling them it because
maybe who is this
they don't winter lucid in account so
that there is something missing in that
world seasonal life of the plant and
maybe not I think the seed in the ground
in a winter maybe you don't have that
memory changing the DNA and giving the
data to the next generation but I never
thought about the soul at that level
either having the seed in the ground
hopefully we've got other scenes you
know there are to the place you know
what I mean because we the keep it they
protect it in a winter they just put it
in the fridge often - before germinating
it there is something that is not
happening in the life of that seed that
normally happen - to see that face
evolution and diversity you know I mean
maybe this is why exactly doesn't get
stronger and stronger generation after
generation
these are questions that are honest
questions we don't know the answer yet I
think we have observations where I'm I
would probably say I don't think that
that scene being in the soil through
that winter time period is all that
important in the soil over winter may
not be important may not be that
important me movies that's something
like the springtime we see all those
populations of beneficial organisms
develop around the root system and move
up on to the above-ground part of the
plant we grow plants that have no
diseases no pests no lack of fertility
and so that leads me to suspect we don't
have to have that seed in the ground
there isn't really anything that really
requires that to happen because we're
not having plants that are weak and
unhealthy from it was like for the plant
to really become part of the terroir to
become heirloom I think that is that
something that they miss and to breed to
breed with the plum that strive after
going after a winter under out condition
that slowly slowly you created genetics
that become an heirloom literally that
is its local and now might that might be
more the defensive system as much as I
thought well the flavonoids you develop
the developing some chemistry in that
plant that is very dependent on making
certain you have exactly the right sets
of microorganisms to end up with that
flavor that in
my and really it might be that you have
to save the seed from those plants and
plant those seeds in the springtime
again
organisms in the soil as well as those
results but I never won by difficulty
Oliver yeah no no never
it's like I'm it's super fascinating
bring it bring another dimension to your
ability to fine-tune and makes the best
of of what the longest to offer you I
mean we should and we should clean what
we cannot do the best out of it as fast
as we can and that's right and we know
that we need to make compost in the
location that you're going to use that
compost because it's the indigenous
species the bacteria fungi protozoa numb
toes micro arthropods that we want to
have growing and becoming a high number
large biomass so that selects for plants
that can grow in a healthy fashion in
this community we don't want to be
taking compost from Alaska and bringing
it to Southern California because the
organisms from Alaska don't survive in
that desert kind of system or vice versa
the desert organisms can survive reason
up here I'm having a hard time surviving
and I'm from central California we're up
in Alaska Jeff would be happy we'd be
free frozen nobody's a kid like that
world operation division in France it's
over is about that concerted holes that
local web life that is used that makes
the quality of the project that go here
why would you bring from the outside and
change the recipe when the recipe is
like wow you know what I mean while you
have when you have unique
and quality that recipes that the Lord
is giving you you just want to protect
it and nourish it basically so if the
plan is the farmer and it's the one
telling the whole ecosystem below the
surface what's going on and what it
needs what's our job our job is to grow
eggs yeah harvest of it yeah and then
make certain that those organisms that
are supposed to be in that soil are are
promoted that they're you make sure that
they're gonna still be there for the
next crop that the plant is the only
thing that promise won't each to work
adios that's it
the name of the game is the production
the best condition the IPOs the plant is
gonna is going to be maximum nutrition
in it maximum quality that's the purpose
of that plant and we're just helping
ourselves to that bounty so I like that
we reserve some of those seats so we
plant them again we don't have to worry
about rotation if we don't kill off the
biology in the soil you're not gonna
have disease you're not gonna have pests
you're not gonna have a lack of
fertility you have more than enough
nutrients in your soil especially with
organic matter
yeah all of it world class mine right
you're killing things when you're
putting in those buckets of other stuff
let's be natural I mean there is no
mostly you organic and you don't touch
any chemical and neutral and pesticide
or you're not
must be doesn't
it's not about organic because salts
organic and if I put salt all over the
base of my plant it's organic but is it
gonna grow yeah I needed to help that
plant grow in a healthy fashion well I'm
not a very good Stewart if I'm killing
the farmer mm-hmm how do we get started
down that path like you know using being
dependent on petrochemicals started with
the mechanical tractor where that when
we went from us having to hold the plow
on the ground and push it and we have to
expend all of our energy making sure
that horse or mule or whatever pulling
that plow as we go from one human being
can only manage a small acreage you know
probably no more than 20 or 40 acres
something like that you can engineer for
a much larger parcel parcel if you're
not telling it there's no need to tell
well the dependence on petrochemicals
like we're we right that's it's a
vicious cycle which it really is so you
know we have to we have to do something
to put seed into the ground and that
usually means you and a plow and a horse
and you've got to apply that muscle and
you can't manage that much land all by
yourself well if you have kids and you
can have you know okay so there's the
grow a family yeah and as when the
mechanical tractor was invented in
Australia
thank you Australians for messing us up
and also you could jump on a tractor and
you could kill a hundred acres and of
course as soon as you start doing that
you put your seed in what comes up
because you've tilled the soil you've
brought that seed bank of wheats to the
surface of the soil so what do you do to
prevent those weeds from growing you go
out and you till again and you slice and
dice
crushin destroy the biology that your
plant needs in order to be able to
out-compete those weeds or you since but
pesticides and herbicides on plants we
came back from world war one or world
war two is when it really starts getting
massive alien and what do you do with
all of the munitions that were not gonna
have to use because we dropped the
atomic bomb on Hiroshima and Nagasaki
and we ended the war two years early and
that means we had literally pile of
munitions that weren't gonna get used
and somebody noticed that if you threw
those munitions on an agricultural field
the plants started growing better
because we had already destroyed the
biology in the soil now when those
plants get those soluble inorganic
nutrients they grow there whereas if you
had the biology in the soil and you
through those spent those munitions out
there's absolutely no effect yeah
so it's that destruction of the biology
in the soil because of the mechanical
tractor and then the imposition of the
wars having just at the right time so
that now we went down this pathway of
the Green Revolution and in order to
reverse that we've gotta start putting
this biology back into the soil so when
you put those inorganic fertilizers on
nothing happens it's a waste of your
time and you're gonna stop that's right
gonna stop using those pesticides
because you don't have the problem with
those those pests and that's diseases
like cancer or is that that burned also
in your butt because every scene is
smaller in your heart it didn't have
that much of an impact in Europe it's
all small farm so yeah you're going to
use a tractor on your bigger piece but
not everybody or they were sharing it
they were much less damaged what is the
word that means you have much less
damage and and it was also the time
where they were pushing poison on us
because nobody knew better
I make your life easier just about there
Europeans resisted more dis didn't see
the point and purpose in it can we
answer that question
looks president um the question about
where do we all start to a long time I
think it was actually when Europeans
came to the United States and we looked
at the Native Americans and shot that
weird that they were doing it wrong and
that they weren't making money off of it
and we can make it better I mean they
were looking to nature for all their
answers they are working with ecology
and fire and I mean they were really
putting it back in watching the earth
and how it worked
biomimicry in the end they all we can do
it better we're going to cut down all
these trees we're gonna mix up the dirt
and that's where sorry is making money
um when you look at the Europeans when
they first arrived in the United States
they went into the typical
slash-and-burn approach where you were
hungry you would cut down all of the
forests you till this land you would get
the crop for five to ten maybe even 15
years at which point everything's a
disease that's unhappy you can't make a
yield so you go to the next plot and you
take down the trees you kill it you
repeat that whole cycle if you go to the
journals of Thomas Jefferson at
Monticello
in Virginia you see that's exactly what
he was doing was he do a Greek ulcer
here and then have to move there and
then had to move again and then he had
to move again and then he had to move
again and then he had to come back to
that first original plot and he could
not grow the crops that he used to be
able to grow when he did slash and burn
and so he started working with compost
he started trying to put whatever it was
he didn't really understand what it was
but he was trying to put it back into
the soil not being very effective no but
it's civilization and nomadic life it
clash but listening to Valen most of the
bigger civilization that were that lived
on a planet where died because the Dixie
kills the soul and they could not
nourish themselves so it's we started
that from the beginning of civilization
the beginning of Agriculture we have not
been doing very good civilization a
civilization Oh magic people who use the
plant kingdom
but didn't control it it's vastly
different but at the same times humanity
when they come in that continent they
destroyed every animal prehistoric
animal that was really big in the matter
of a thousand year unless so it's like
don't sing that the Indian and all what
a good thing in in America did not have
a huge impact on the on the continent
like all that the people living in the
Peru that world Mississippi civilization
they starve themselves to death
literally because they killed the soul
and now that I'm thinking I'm starting
to sing backward to a bunch of like I
know really well my store on the
Mediterranean Sea and you know a lot of
it it's like they don't talk much about
it but it slowly slowly the territory
getting a lead so they have to to move
on and then they go they they go into
other people territory and Europe wasn't
that deep they've been walking each
other since since civilization was born
I wanna say the reality that this is the
biggest treat for me I hope you
understand
so I'm dr. Elaine in ham my company
soil food web incorporated and so a food
web school and I spend my life going
around talking to people about all of
these concepts promoting getting away
from the toxic chemicals growing plants
in the most natural of ways all using
all plants are plants using life in the
soil those organisms who vent were the
first ones on this planet and started
everything rolling so let's go back and
replenish that biology that's supposed
to be in the soil to help your plants
grow better mei-li see from the farmers
that receive from the living so I'm at
the end of the of the shine and the more
I know about what give me quality is a
better I can I can pass it down to other
bazooka and my name is Ryan nos from
Central Coast let it grow where that's
what all I want to do is grow thank you
so much I also want to say thank you so
much to future cannabis project and
signs of the times signs for the times
and the one log dispensary we're so
grateful for this venue which is
probably the most unique we are
literally inside of a home made from one
redwood tree its hollowed out and its
oh how cool is that thank you so very
much
[Music]