so I have this Sheldon black downstem
piece that has all these little holes in
it so if you listen to the sounds see
how loud it is and the water kind of
sprays up into my mouth but then when
you put this thing on suddenly
yeah it's much more gentle so anyway we
have some raised cannabis some ice cream
cake that John and Larry gave me up and
humble a few weeks ago anyway so we got
some raised cannabis and I'm gonna bring
back do you remember the ember from
around 2012 I think it came out we're
actually talking about bringing this
back to the market but with some
upgraded functionalities so first thing
is it only has one temperature which is
really fucking hot let's wait for it to
heat up more in soon yeah I can feel so
anyway instead of using a lighter
normal people keep taking all my
lighters but anyway instead of a lighter
with I'm sure Bix uses the finest butane
yeah so you can see that heating out so
all right so let's try this thing with
nice that works and then just gonna try
it with some let's do some hash we have
some Cali hash here together oh yeah
that thing only lasts 90 seconds okay so
it's probably way too high for this and
I think that's one of the
anyway
of course we got the glove in there the
cool thing is that you don't even really
have to clean this the stuff wipes or it
comes right off but anyway so this has a
ceramic tip currently only has one
temperature so what I'd like to hear is
some ideas for various temperature
settings that you'd like to see if
you're dabbing with it or your personal
preferences and then other features and
functionality what I think as a an
ergonomic replacement for a lighter oh
and so it has this little protective top
so now it's yeah so even if it's hot you
can put I think this has aluminum in it
so it's not gonna burn anything and this
thing also turns off after 90 seconds so
if you get super high and pass it on the
couches it's not gonna be on for as you
knock it over with your feet anyway
that's the ember and then we have the
Sheldon black holes in the bottom of the
stem actually you know let's see how
fast you want to take another hit and
you're like oh my god
let's light you back up
and here it goes you're the jeopardy
music so anyway I hit the Kali hash and
I hit the flower
[Music]
yeah so I have two of these so I'm gonna
play around with them and but yeah
looking for feedback on what you would
like in a little ceramic tip besides
super long battery life nice ergonomic
design and variable temperature settings
so anyway I know gotta go pick up my
daughter at preschool so