this episode of the curious about
cannabis podcast is brought to you by
you our dedicated listeners and
supporters
thanks to your continued listening
sharing and donations
we've been able to continue the show
free from third party advertisers and
sponsors
so thank you and if you'd like to learn
about other ways you can support the
show
visit patreon.com curious about cannabis
my name is vincenzo di marzo i'm a
research director at the
national research council and currently
i'm actually
a canada excellence research chair in
quebec city
in canada i've been working on the
endocannabinoid system since
basically its discovery at the
at the beginning of the 1990s and
i've been working on the biochemistry
chemistry pharmacology
development of new tools uh analytical
tools pharmacological tools to
investigate this system and uh more
recently i've become
interested in investigating the
expansion of the endocannabinoid system
into a larger
larger uh chemical uh signaling system
uh which we we define as the
endocannabinoid dome
and the relationship between the
and the gum microbiome which is what i
do in
quebec city at university lava
[Music]
you're listening to the curious about
cannabis podcast
hey everybody this is jason wilson with
the curious about cannabis podcast
thanks so much for tuning in once again
and so today i am beyond delighted to
connect with somebody i've been wanting
to talk to for
many years since i started studying
cannabis and cannabinoid science i'm
with
dr vincenzo dimarzo who if you haven't
heard of him
by the time you finish listening to most
of my podcast episodes you will
definitely have heard of him
thanks so much dr dimarzo for being
willing to come on the podcast today and
talk to me about cannabinoid science
my pleasure thank you for inviting me
yes absolutely so
one of my first questions um in
the beginning of your book the
endocannabinoid dome in your dedications
uh one thing that you admit is you have
an obsession
about endocannabinoids and cannabinoids
so i guess my first question to you is
why are you so obsessed with
cannabinoids well
i would say more than cannabinoids i'm
obsessed with the the endogenous
counterparts of the cannabinoids which
uh
which are the endocannabinoids and uh
and uh
in fact um since the beginning when we
started investigating this uh this
chemical
signaling system we were intrigued and
fascinated by
its involvement in basically all uh
physiological uh aspects of of mammalian
life and then
we also understood that in fact this is
a system
uh so deeply involved in physiology that
becomes also deeply involved in
pathology
and and it seemed to be quite
complicated to study but then it became
even more complicated
uh when we we could see that this system
was not
as simple as we thought at the beginning
but it was easily to be expanded into a
much bigger uh signaling systems which
probably we will end up discovering
controls uh uh all aspects of human
physiology
and pathology and um
the other reason why i became so
interested in this system is because
there is a lot of
space for for uh chemistry i'm a chemist
to start with
and and there is a lot of chemical
variability and biodiversity in chemical
diversity in
not only the cannabis plant but also in
the in the endogenous
signals that we discovered uh starting
from studies on on thc
so the more we started it and the more
complicated it looked so it
i really like complicated things uh i
like things that can explain
in in a mechanistic way uh things from
you know the the functioning of a single
cell
to up to the behavior of a complex
organism like
like uh laboratory animals and humans so
um i still think that there is we've
probably done less than 10
or 15 percent uh and and one lifetime
will not be enough to
to to study though yeah
absolutely well and that just gives uh
plenty of work to the future generations
something that's been on my mind a lot
um
that i was i was emailing um raphael
michelle just a couple of days ago and
asking him about
um i don't know what he hopes that
people take away from the work
that you know uh himself and and you
and you know other people like roger
perchway and others you know who were
really
kind of at the beginning of a lot of the
stuff um where it hopes to go and we
were talking a little bit about
the future generations of cannabinoid
scientists that are you know coming on
the
on on board with new opportunities to
study
uh cannabinoids that um you know is much
more difficult
back in through the 60s the 90s or so
when we're really
getting a lot of this grounding
established it's a really
exciting time to see what the future the
subsequent lifetimes
um unveil that we won't be around to to
see and
i would i was very lucky to start to
start uh
in this field when the pioneers of this
field like
rafi meshulam and roger perth and allen
all it was
were really still very very active in
this field
uh they're still active of course but
and obviously those were the times when
they were making also
themselves the major discoveries uh in
this field and it
this also explains my excitement of
being there
and i've been very lucky because i i
when i think about
my involvement in this field i thought i
was in in the right place at the right
time
so i very much a lot of of what we did
in in my group to the the work of rafi
and roger and ali knowledge
and how uh so talking about
your start in doing some of this
research um
how did you start to get clued into i
mean
you know obviously you were involved in
um
foundational research that characterized
the concept of the entourage effect
and as well as your paper in 1998 that
sort of
described for the first time what the
endocannabinoid system does
and that sort of thing but when did you
start to
um when did the idea
of the endocannabinoid system start to
expand for you um
when did you start to think about um
it seems like there was a perceptual
shift in how we saw
fatty acids and all these other
components of the body
once you know we started studying these
cannabinoid receptors and
how the vanilloid receptors are part you
know all these things so when did that
start to really expand for you where you
realize this is something way bigger
than just cb1 cb2 anandamide 2ag all of
that
well yeah that's that's a difficult
question but obviously
the realization of the importance of the
endocannabinoid system came
i would say between uh in my case at
least
1995 and and 2000 because this at those
times those times we actually developed
uh analytical methods to measure the
endocannabinoids and undermited 2hg
in biological fluids and and tissues
and we were very very lucky to
collaborate with tens i would say even
probably hundreds
of of uh of scientists all over the
world
who would provide us with samples from
uh from patients with various disorders
or from
uh from animal models of disorders so we
basically
started analyzing tissues and and blood
uh like like meds uh all over the world
and uh and
we we realized that this system was
very easily perturbed by several
different
uh not only pathological conditions but
also
um changes in in the in the equilibrium
in the physiological equilibrium even
physiological changes
would change the the endocardia system
so
i and others came to the conviction that
this this system is
is a pro-miostatic system uh present in
all cells and tissues
and especially if you if you expand this
system beyond
cb1 and cb2 you will find
endocannabinoids like anandamide and 2hg
in all tissues
in all tissues from from not only from
mammals but also from higher vertebrates
and in some cases also from the
vertebrate so
you we we noticed that we started
working also in
in some very uh primitive forms of life
like a hydro
or some molluscs or or echinoderms and
and we could see that the
endocannabinoids were there even though
the cannabinoid receptors
as we know as we knew them cb1 and cb2
were not there so
we wondered why why do we make these
molecules and
and we also realized that the the
amounts of these molecules
were subject to be altered by by the
diet
and and by the intake of some
particular fatty acids in the diet so we
we we wondered
how how come that there is such an
important system and
this system can be changed by something
as simple as as
eating uh one oil rather than other
than another so you know we were really
intrigued and we we thought that this
maybe was really the response of the
organism
if not the only one but one of the the
most important responses of the organist
to
all forms of uh um
going far from the from the equilibrium
from the homeostasis
and and this system would be activated
to to bring back homeostasis in
in cells and also at the organismal
levels and then
uh we realized that several forms of
stressful conditions
would would also alter this system in a
way that this system
could change the output of other
chemical signals
so in those years we came to the to the
hypothesis it was still a hypothesis
that
has been since then
i would say largely
proven that this system is a system made
of local
chemical signals because you know the
endocannabinoids cannot really
travel from one organ to the other so
they act where they are produced
um produced and and and triggered by
by stressful even kind of benign forms
of stress you know
subtle perturbation of of the of the the
of the status of the cell um but also
environmental stress
uh like physical exercise
diet changes in the in the light the
dark cycles
um in order to re
retune the output of other chemical
system
signals but in turn since this this
system was present in
in different part of the the organism
the system was also
itself being uh controlled by by many
other chemical signals so
it's like uh we we made a comparison you
know it's it's like an orchestra
it's like the director of the orchestra
which is also directed by the
the musicians of the orchestra so it's
it's it was quite an intriguing
hypothesis that we're still
investigating and of course now with the
discovery of the endocannabinoid
this is this is becoming more difficult
to to prove
yes yeah absolutely and for those
listening
that um maybe don't have such a
techno technical background on
cannabinoid science how would you
describe
the concept of the endocannabinoid dome
to somebody
okay so basically you know with the word
dom now
we make new words containing the the
the prefix the suffix ohm to identify a
very large system
um so we have the genome we have the
metabolome we have the proteome
and so on and so forth so the endo the
endocannabinoid
um came in a way from
you mentioned before the the the study
that
rafi meshulam in which we're
collaborating collaborated on the
entourage effect so basically what rafi
perceived is that
and what we were measuring in fact uh
when we were measuring endocannabinoids
is that this these two molecules and
undermined to a g
were accompanied by uh by a plethora of
other
uh compounds and these compounds these
metabolites were chemically
and biochemically similar meaning that
the you know anandamide and 2g belongs
to belong to two different families
of metabolites and these are the an
asylum anonymites and the and
the monocyte glycerols some of which
were already
known in fact even one or two decades or
even
longer than that before the
endocannabinoids were discovered so
but nobody knew really how these
molecules were acting so
rafi in a very imaginative way that this
is really
uh is his main feature is creativity in
my imagination
uh thought well this these are
accompanying uh
molecules that are there to protect to
to make
make the two big actors look even more
important than they are so it's an
entourage
or you know when politicians go around
and they
take with them a lot of a lot of
accompanying people
and that that's certainly part of the of
the picture but that
then we started realizing that these
compounds in fact do have
molecules uh do have targets of their
own so
the endocannabinoid if you wish is is a
kind of evolution
of the of the entourage effect um
molecules like the enocytomines or the
monoxide glycerol started being
investigated
receptors were being found and and this
created
of course exciting but also
complications
uh because you know the the
pharmacologists
and the drug developers where the
therapeutic drug developers where we're
thinking okay we can
we can uh manipulate the levels of the
since they are so
strongly involved in pathology we can
manipulate the levels of the
endocannabinoids
of anandamide and 2hg in order to
make more of these compounds where
they're needed or to reduce the amount
their amounts where they are produced in
an excessive
manner so you can do that by
manipulating the
the degradation of the biosynthesis of
endocannabinoids but then
when it was found that and we found we
and many others that
anandamide has the same biochemical
pathways
as other enacelateral minds which have
different receptors from the cannabinoid
receptors
this created a strong complication we
cannot really manipulate the levels of
an undermine in this way
without manipulating the levels of the
other previously
known as entourage compounds but having
an identity and and in the mechanism of
action of of
independent from the endocannabinoids of
their own so
the endocannabinoid dome is basically
the
uh the the bigger system including not
only an undermine and 2g
their main receptors which are cb1 cb2
but also
some of the other receptors for
anandamide and 2g because these are two
very promiscuous molecules unlike thc
this is one major difference from
between between the endocannabinoids and
the plant and cannabinoids
uh or at least between between the
endocannabinoids and thc
um and then uh it was found that
in fact even the biosynthesis and
degradation of of these two compounds
could not be only
uh mediated by one or two enzymes there
was a redundancy of biosynthetic and
degrading enzymes
and and sometimes the ingredient enzymes
were not degrading enzymes because they
were
simply converting anandamide and 2g into
molecules which had different receptors
and this is
you know this is this may seem strange
but not to people like
like me who have investigated the
bioactive lipids
all their life you know all bio
are transformed into something different
and
come from something different with the
different biological activities so
uh and then there is the congeners of
anandamide and to agita
what we called previously the entourage
compounds which
have their own receptors even though
they share with the endocannabinoids
the same biosynthetical pathways and
then
finally there were other molecules which
have a
different biochemical
pathways as the endocannabinoids but are
nevertheless
they're not congeners they're not like
cousins
they're not like brothers and sisters
but they're cousins so you have
other anastile uh amides
uh and in fact um
when we collaborated with the
uh with the with the with the other
groups we we found that in fact
um in particular with the group of
michael walker
the late michael worker we we found that
many
uh many compounds many amino acids could
make amides with fatty acids and this
could create
an almost an incredible number of new
combinations between
the 10 or 15 fatty acids and 20 amino
acids so just
just imagine all the permutations and
and so these compounds actually exist as
as the group of other brands show
us as also uh recently uh
investigated and and so it's really
we're talking now
about a a huge number of chemical
mediators so the endocannabinoids their
con
their congeners their analogues
which may or may have not different
similar
biochemical pathways normally have
different receptors
we we talking about the several other
targets that anandamide and 2hg have
beyond cb1 and cp2 we're talking about
other enzymes
so we're talking about something
something about more than 250 chemical
mediators more than 50 enzymes and
and receptors and some of these
receptors were actually
known previously like the the trip
channels or the
or the p-bars and and and the
interesting thing is that you know of
course with
when the endocannabinoid system became
so big
then the next question was okay thc
is the only out of 100 and more
plant cannabinoid that interacts with
the endocannabinoid system what about
maybe maybe if we don't look only at the
endocannabinoid system but we look at
the expanded endocrine
system at this endocannabinoid maybe the
other cannabinoids will interact
with the endocannabinoid dome even
though they don't interact with the the
endocrine system this is true
uh to a large extent uh for
for things like cannabidiol or
cannabinoid
the other minor
not so minor anymore uh cannabinoids
uh and and in fact in the case of
cannabidiol
even the endocannabinoid is not
sufficient to to explain its
pharmacology because it
it has been suggested to interact also
with the
with receptors and proteins outside the
endocannabinoid
not just outside the endocrine system
but even outside the endocannabinoid
so i think the endocannabinoid is a
complex complex con
concept which however has the merit of
explaining
the mechanism of action of a much higher
number of cannabis of plant cannabinoids
than the endocannabinoid system
yeah yeah absolutely and it's it's
definitely a very tangled web
that you can't uh so many things are
interconnected that it is
tricky to manipulate one piece i saw
um wasn't there research i can't
remember what year it was now there's
research i think in france
where they tried to do i think it was a
fah in their inhibitory
study and ran into some problems there
um
unexpected consequences and things yeah
even though in that particular case
the problem was not uh due to the fact
that
by inhibiting the degradation of an
undermine they were also inhibiting
degradation of other fatty acid amides
um
they basically were hitting with this
with this
new chemical they were eating a
completely different set of proteins
and enzymes that that
for which there is less redundancy in
the brain so when you get rid of that
enzyme you have serious problems
yeah fortunately when you inhibit far
you you have much less
side effects because as i mentioned for
the degradation of the endocannabinoids
there are many enzymes so
this this is a system so strongly
uh and deeply involved in
in mammalian and animal physiology that
it's it's not enough to to kick out one
of the enzymes of the receptors to see
major
major problems right yeah yeah and
and one and one thing that's come up in
several discussions i've had
um both with raphael michilim
and another colleague of yours ethan
russo yeah um was
how do we i guess taking this to a
practical level
uh because what physicians are
interested in is okay this is all
interesting we see it's connected to
um all these aspects of physiology but
how do we measure it
when these compounds are so um kind of a
femoral they
they get built when they're needed and
then they get broken down quickly and
i know that in the past there have been
like spinal taps and stuff like that to
try to see
what endocannabinoids are circulating at
the moment
um but can you speak at all to the
um the challenges to trying to
characterize the endocannabinoid system
or the endocannabinoid dome
in a human being yeah it's it's it's uh
you're perfectly right it's it's very
complicated
it's a system that undergoes uh the
levels of these mediators
uh undergo changes uh by the hour
um as i said you know they're affected
by whether or not you
you eat foods or what kind of food you
eat
um like like with all the
other homes uh the the
real picture of the of the system uh
can only be taken at a certain
time frame thanks to the
very sophisticated new machines that
have been really uh have characterized
the
the more recent years of of scientific
development
as you know the the means by which we we
can look into the cell into the
biological fluids have become very
sophisticated
and very sensitive and very specific so
we can now measure the levels of
of anandamide and we can distinguish
anandamite which is a very
uh minor uh compound in fact
uh rafi meshulam always jokes about that
that you know he could only discover an
undermine because
he was probably using a big brain that
had been
laying in the slaughterhouse for hours
and and this this was later shown to be
a process that
increases the levels of
dishes so at that time when he
discovered an andamite there were no
uh mass spectrometers
sensitive enough to measure uh
picomolar or femtomolar amounts
of these compounds now we do and we can
distinguish anandamide from
from its brother which has 20 carbon
atoms but
only three double bonds instead of four
and
uh and maybe that difference is enough
for that compound to hit another
receptor rather than just cb1 and cb2
so clearly um we we have the
these days the the possibility of
measuring with high sensitivity
specificity
high rapidity as well
these compounds in all in all tissues we
can
we can measure the expression of the
enzymes that make these compounds
with even at the single cell level
we we can measure the proteins that are
made by
uh by this uh but by the arena
the rnas uh through the rnas of the
various proteins and enzymes and
receptors so
we can have a real uh
real time almost real-time picture
what's happening in a given tissue
or a given biological fluid in a given
animal with a
with a with that which is undergoing a
physiological or pathological
condition so and then of course all
these data these days
these are also the days of of big data
of
artificial intelligence so all this data
can be put together there is the new
approaches of the systems biology
so all the networks can can be made
sense of
and there is a lot of space for
mathematics not just for analytical
uh chemistry and molecular biology so we
can have a picture
and at the same time we have very
sophisticated ways
to modify uh if not one single
mediator of the endocannabinoid because
that would be very difficult to do
but at least one single receptor in a
single cell
for for those endocannabinoid mediators
and by modifying that and then you know
controlling you know like in an on and
off
situation we can then understand what
the endocannabinoid
mediators in the endocannabinoid system
is doing this has been done to a large
extent in the brain because that's where
all the research
started but it's now being done also in
peripheral organs
and this is where we really appreciate
the importance of the
of the endocannabinoid dome and the
endocannabinoid system they're not brain
uh systems they're really pleiotropic
they're doing a lot of things in a lot
of places
and it's yeah it's difficult to
understand because of course
you have lots of molecules being
produced and degraded at the same time
but we must
uh imagine that if these molecules are
doing something important and we have
evidence that they are
they must have a way of coordinating
themselves and being coordinated by
by other mediators by other systems
physiologically
and pathologically yeah and
and since um all of this activity is so
localized
if let's say five ten years down the
road
if some of these analytical technologies
become more accessible to
hospitals and things you know worldwide
would someone essentially have to have a
biopsy on a particular
set of tissues or you know particular
organ that sort of thing
in order to get some sense of what's
going on
um with endocannabinoids or receptors
and that sort of thing
um since they're not being circulated is
that really the only way to
to kind of do that yeah this is yeah
unfortunately this is why we still need
the animal studies
um we we've been uh this is one of the
reasons why i've been
working on on less invasive uh
and more ethically valid
uh systems like you know invertebrates
or zebrafish
um but at the end of the day
you you cannot do without the animal
studies also because there is
genetic manipulations that you can do
only
in animals fortunately and at least for
now
and and obviously it's mark we've done
lots of studies with biopsies
the blood when we when we look at the
blood of course we have we get very
interesting information from from the
plant
the plasma from the csf now also from
the saliva saliva from the feces
but uh but obviously we don't really
know where
where what we measure comes from and
uh and and this is therefore we can make
correlations we can
we can make hypothesis but we cannot
really have a mechanistic link
between what we see and the pathology or
the physiological situation
biopsies offer uh
a better way but then you have to be
very of course you cannot always take
biopsies from from humans
certainly not from the prey and and and
i've been trying to convince students to
do that but i haven't managed
yeah i mean geez
but you have to be careful even with
biopsies because you know they need to
be
taken in the right way kept and stored
in the right way
so there are less invasive ways there is
imaging
techniques that are emerging like pet
techniques due to image receptors
enzymes
now you see that for the endocannabinoid
system
and that's that that's really raising
the possibility of
of doing uh studies in vivo in real time
also in human beings and human
volunteers so
i i i see honestly no limit if not the
technological limits of the time
which are probably going to be surpassed
tomorrow or the day after tomorrow
uh yeah the only the only thing we need
is the realization that this is an
important
topic to to analyze because when you
have
hundreds of mediators coming more or
less from the same pathway or
having to do with the same pathway which
originates from the endocannabinoid
system but simply because that was the
one we discovered first uh but eating
different uh completely different uh
targets
and then you you when you realize that
this is important then you you will find
a way of
of addressing the experimental problems
and challenges
so just it's just a matter of having the
right questions and
you can get uh you can get answers at
least partial answers
as we said at the beginning you know a
lifetime would probably not be
sufficient to understand all these
what all these mediators are doing and
how and how do they
interact with each other yeah and one of
the
most important things in the scientific
process is finding better questions to
ask
than you necessarily started out with
and always
always having the right hypothesis
because i'm very much
even though you know with the omics you
you
you go fishing a little bit
i'm still a believer in the hypothesis
driven research so
it's nice to have an hypothesis and then
of course if you're lucky
you can get you can get an answer to
your hypothesis
and even if if the answer is negative
the secret is not getting too attached
to your hypothesis
exactly exactly yeah yeah being more
interested and just trying to understand
yeah what's happening hypothesis to to
to start with yeah to have a focus yeah
absolutely
um one thing i wanted to make sure to
talk to you about because i know it's a
focus on a lot of your research right
now which is
the connection between the
endocannabinoid dome and
the gut microbiome um and this is once
again
something that when i spoke with ethan
he kind of teased a little bit
um of some of the work that's going on
now but
can you speak a little bit to um
i mean obviously research these days is
showing how the gut microbiome the
all the gut flora affects so many
different things and
how the immune system and psychology and
all these other things are
interconnected
with it but um what is your uh
research focusing on and what are what
are you currently
um learning about those connections
between the endocannabinoid dome and the
gut microbiome
yeah yeah the yeah this is as
as i said at the beginning i like
difficult things and
it was given a big one i was given the
opportunity
uh four years ago to start on on a new
uh project and i must say i was
immediately attracted
because you know the grand microbiome uh
i i saw it a little bit like the
endocannabinoid i don't because it's
it's it's not really an external part to
our body
it's something that has been selected
through generations
passed on uh genetically but not only
genetically from from mothers to to to
children and uh uh it's there for if
to to to play an important faction has
been concerned
it's not been fought by the immune
system so it's clearly something that
that we need and
all animals that have microbiomes
microbiota
need them so it's a ideally it's a it's
a wonderful symbiotic symbiotic
uh relationship um with the with the
with another organ there is several more
cells microbial cells in our body than
our own
uh eukaryotic cells so
so clearly this offers the opportunity
if you think of it of and expanding a
lot the potentiality of our own body
there's there is thousands of genes more
than the ones we have
lots of more proteins and small
molecules and obviously what the gut
microbiota
does to to help us first only does it to
help itself
but obviously in the process they they
produce molecules that can be
useful to our own functions uh by
reinforcing
our own molecules our own signals but
also by creating
uh something that we don't have um
but you know the the experience of the
endocannabinoid dom told me that you
know
you never enough the chemical signals to
to deal with the complexity of life
and experience especially when it comes
to
dealing with the the environment and the
environmental challenges you know
uh having a few thousands genes more
actually quite quite more than a few
thousands more
definitely helped helped us and many
other animals to survive
and to better respond to the to the
environment to the changing environment
um our our own bodies itself
a an environment for for these these
microbes
uh who live in in completely different
conditions like you know
for us would be living in the north pole
or or in the on the equator
so it's it's really fascinating and it's
uh and then you know you start thinking
oh
seeing all these papers on the ground
microbiota and the grand microbiome
again
here the difference between the word has
to do with the fact that the microbiota
are the microbes
the microbiome is the microbes it's
their genes it's their proteins it's the
small molecules
and so on and so forth it's a bit like
the endocannabinoid so
beyond the the
the the names what i saw and what
everybody can see is that
the microbiome uh is involved
is potentially involved not just in
controlling
the function of our gut helping us with
metabolizing things
but also in behavior in the immune
system
and in most of our functions a little
bit like the endocannabinoid system and
the endocannabinoid
if you think of it but it was really
patrice kanye in the uh
in a nice paper that was published i
think uh
before 2010 um we put the two things
together the endocannabinoid system the
gun microbiome
but this can is a scientist a brilliant
scientist
in belgium and he showed that some of
the effects of
of intestinal dysbiosis the perturbation
of the gum microbiome because like all
things
also like the endocannabinoid system
also the gut microbiome is perturbed
and the perturbation uh known as
dysbiosis
produces some of its effect its negative
effects on metabolism
through the endocannabinoid system
through the cp1 receptor so he was
really a pioneer in this
in this uh in this in this field and
at that time i i looked at the paper it
was very interesting very nice paper it
published a few more but then i was
given the opportunity to to work on a
more or less similar
uh subject and i honestly didn't uh want
to lose the opportunity also because it
came with
with very nice funding and uh which
which
we don't always uh have in italy we
almost never have in italy and
uh and so i i took this opportunity
but it's very complicated because you
know i i'm not my
microbiologist and and the microbiota
is very complicated although it's not
there by chance
there are rules but every person has a
as a different microbiota and
but again you know every person has a
different profile of endocannabinoid
mediators so
again maybe you know there are things
that these two systems
do together in collaboration or one
through the other and uh and there there
were many many evidences
that that there could there would be a
triangle between the
the endocannabinoid dome the gun
microbiome and
mammalian physiology and pathology
so initially we we're still focusing on
the metabolic
on obesity and metabolic disorders
uh which are obviously the first place
to look
uh for when you're talking about the gum
microbiome but also when you're talking
about the endocardium system and
what we're doing now is trying to prove
that these two systems communicate
and again and again there are there are
things there are easy
relatively easy things that we could do
for example uh
use animals which don't have
a gut mic which we don't have a
microbiota at all
so they were raised in steroid
conditions
and so we went and looked at their
endocannabinoid system their
endocannabinoid and it's completely
different
and this could be due to too many i mean
that doesn't really create a cause
effect
relationship but then when we reign
stated
the gut microbiome in these gem free
animals into
these gentry mice it took it took only
one week
to see almost at least in the gap almost
exactly the same situation as
uh conventionally raised in mind so that
was really the evidence we were looking
that was the first experiment we did
that was really the
the span we did to say okay we we stop
here or we go
we work harder and we're moving forward
you need to go further okay
and then you know there are other things
you can do like knocking down
enzymes of the endocannabinoid system
specifically in in different parts of
the body
or in the gut and see if the
endocannabinoid system is modified and
again
we find changes sorry if the
gum microbiome is modified and we found
changes
but uh it's a complicated field because
like with the endocannabinoid
almost everything can change the gut
microbiome yeah yeah
and and there's still no
exact definition what is a healthy or a
pathological
uh gut microbe exactly like the
endocannabinoid system
so and possibly also many other
endogenous systems that we have so
um there are many experiments we're
doing we we find very interesting
correlations
in human styles following interventions
between changes in the endocannabinoid
and changes in the in the gut microbiome
we find that if we modify the gun
microbiome with probiotics or prebiotics
or antibiotics we we see strong changes
in the endocannabinoid system
uh we're now investigating whether the
changes we see in the endocannabinoid
system when we
modify the gun microbiome are partly
responsible
for the effects of the modification of
the gun microbiome
and the other way around we try to if if
when we change the
the endocannabinoid dominant in a
specific manner
the changes we see in the gun microbiome
participate
in in in the effects of the
the changes of the endocannabinoid so we
can do that using exactly the same tools
we were mentioning before
plus more omics
technologies like metagenomics to
investigate the
composition of the of the gun microbiome
and the proteomics to investigate their
proteome so
and eventually we will have to ask to
mathematicians to
to to to look for algorithms that that
explain that these correlations we find
but there are mechanistic ways to look
at the the relationship between these
two worlds
it's it's yeah it's really fascinating
uh
and the the crosstalk is super
interesting um
you know that it's it's not a one-way
street that endocannabinoid doesn't just
affect the microbiome or vice versa that
it's
back and forth and i would imagine too
you know going back to something you
mentioned very early on about the diet
and you know that we have certain um
requirements to have precursors for
different things that our body needs to
either construct the enzymes necessary
to build up and break down
um endocannabinoids or receptors or
whatever so i imagine
in just a simple manner the microbiome
would be involved
in influencing um
how some of those precursor those
building blocks that we get from our
foods
are actually made available to the body
to even use for some of those
biosynthetic pathways
absolutely absolutely the the you know
there is
such a large biodiversity in the in the
in the gun microbiome that
obviously you can imagine these bags to
do
a lot of things a lot of things yeah
they they
they uh they were discovered because you
know we could
we could see how some of these
microorganisms helped us
processing stuff that we're not able to
process
uh what came out after that was that in
the process of processing this
for example complex uh fibers
uh which we cannot process because we
don't have the enzyme to make
them this this uh these microorganisms
this bacteria make
molecules like the short chain fatty
acids that are strongly active
both on the gut but also on the on the
uh on the brain because they can travel
uh in the bloodstream in which enrich
the brain or act on the
on the peripheral nervous system and and
influence the behavior as well so
clearly there are many many
possibility that uh the microbiome can
modify
the endocannabinoid dome that they the
microorganisms make
enzymes that are similar uh to the
enzymes that degrade the
endocannabinoids
in fact some of some of the commensal
bacteria
they also make endocannabinoid-like
mediators so they make compounds
mediators that are very similar to the
the the sisters and cousins of the of
anandamide and to a g
so and they were shown to act on the
same receptors
so the chemical differences between the
these molecules when they're made by the
microbes
are not such to impede them from to
to prevent them from interacting with
the same receptors so
there is there is really a lot of
possibilities for for crosstalk
um and of course as you mentioned
the even though we're perfectly capable
of processing most
most fatty acids there are fatty acids
that we cannot make
like the the pollen saturated omega-3
and omega-6 fatty acids
so for that we rely on the diet and and
these
fatty acids uh can change the function
of the of the microbiome so the the
omega-3 fatty acids found in fish oil
for example uh we know we knew already
that when you supplement them in the
diet they can change the endocannabinoid
dome
now we know that they can also change
the ground microbiome and some of the
changes
we see in one or the other are probably
due to the fact that they're changing
the other rather than than the former so
the latter rather than the form so
it's it's really uh it's really
interesting
we have um what is really difficult here
is to
to find models to study this uh this
interaction because we cannot really do
it
in an in vivo setting so we we're
developing in vitro
systems uh for example the organoids
where we can
uh keep pieces of gut alive for several
months
we're now trying to find a way of
inoculating them
uh with with gut bacteria without
killing them
because all normally organoids are grown
in antibiotics so
uh so we need it's really challenging
yes it's a big challenge
but you know we can we can at least we
can do this in an indirect way so we can
take the media of the bacteria and see
the effects that they have on the on the
organoids
but we can also do experiments
on the on the microbiome outside
the the organism using the so-called
simulator of the human intestinal
microbiome ecosystem or shine
so we have a shine in in quebec where we
we
basically in state
a real human microbiome so there is
several flasks each of them mimicking
the conditions you find in the stomach
in the duodenum in the helium
in the in the column so we we and if you
put the fecal sample of
of human being in in this system
after a couple of weeks the bags will
start populating the different parts of
the of the shine
in a way similar to what they do in a
human uh
gastrointestinal system and at that
point when we have this shine
we can give it foods we can give it uh
fish oil for example we can give it
polyphenols we can give it
many many dietary stuff and see what
happens independently of the host
and then we can find a way of
introducing the host cells in this shine
and this is more complicated but people
are working on this
there are very strong groups in in the
netherlands were working in
in simulating uh the the microbiome in
uh and the host interactions on a chip
for example or in very small systems
so once again technology is just waiting
for us
uh to ask the right uh the right
questions
absolutely yeah that is that is so
fascinating to learn about how that
research is done that's
been something i've wondered for a while
exactly how you
start to piece all that out because it
is so complicated and it sounds like
you and i both share uh an interest in
complex systems that's something that um
yeah i definitely like as well i like
puzzles and
so all of this is uh yeah very very
fascinating and i want to be sensitive
to your time i know we're
we're creeping over um over the hour
here i've got one last question
one thing that i think people
misunderstand
about the entourage effect is that in
the research that was originally
published
that you were an author on that first
described this effect as you were
looking at
2ag and you noticed that there were
these
other compounds that
didn't seem to have much activity of
their own on these receptors but when
they were present with 2ag
you got unique effects is it fair to say
that the concept of the entourage effect
has been a little manipulated
in popular culture to sort of take on a
meaning that is different than what was
originally intended
yeah absolutely i i agree and and both
rafi and i wondered
sometimes whether or not the the
entourage idea had not been kind of uh
mis misinterpreted or misunderstood in
in many cases because you know it has
been applied to
to cannabis and to the pharmacology of
cannabis which is a
which is something that for a
pharmacologist has really no meaning
uh because you cannot speak about the
pharmacology of a plant you can speak of
the pharmacology of the
of the components of the chemical
components of the plant and even that is
is quite difficult to to do
so uh clearly the entourage effect as we
conceived it was was
was born to to explain why
an undermined and to a g2 a gene
particular
was accompanied by in tissues in in
blood in
wherever we analyze it by congeners by
by
other monocyclists which at that time
were thought to have no receptors so
they were orphan of receptors okay so
we wonder why would the cell make uh 2g
together with these compounds or
anandamide together with the its
congeners if these congenitals have no
uh no biological action that would be a
waste
of a of a biochemical machinery
and then you know and he said okay maybe
they're they're
doing something to the main actor of of
the scene
and i thought that that something could
be to their degradation because
uh as as i mentioned both the anastasia
and the monocyte glycerols can
be degraded by the same the same
enzymatic pathways as an undermined and
to a g
so clearly they can compete for their
degradation by this enzyme
and through these means they can enhance
their they can prolong
their lifespan and then then then
enhance their activity and this is what
we found that this is what we
demonstrated
in that paper but then uh we
you know the concept went on forward and
since for for some of these compounds it
was really difficult at the beginning to
find a receptor we
we we carried out other different kind
of of uh
experiment for example whether these
compounds could act as allosteric
modulators of the receptors and in fact
we found that
one of them palmitoylethanolamide later
on
we showed would enhance the activity of
anandamide
at 3d1 channels so these were really the
early times of endocannabinoid research
and then
many groups including the group of
danielle piomenli
and and others showed that in fact these
congeners were not inactive
they had their own receptors and these
receptors in some cases did
uh things uh quite different from uh
from the cb1 and cb2 in some cases
things
even opposite so the entourage effect
was kind of uh
crushed by by this idea because if if
28g
acts on cb1 and by acting on cb1
stimulates food intake stimulates fat
accumulation and its congenital act on
another receptor known as gpr119 which
is
which is doing exactly the opposite
there is no no more entourage effect
at the organismal level so
that was really something to be
interpreted for the
particular historical situation and
i think it's still valid in some cells
for example when
because in all cells these compounds are
produced together with their and
congenitals and not necessarily the
receptors of these
congenitals are there so when they're
not there maybe and when cb1 and cb2
receptors that may be they're actually
acting as entourage compounds the
situation in the plant where it has been
proposed that some terpenoids
could enhance the activity of of thc or
cbd
or that other phytocannabinoids could
enhance the
is completely different and and and
i don't know if there is an entourage
effect in cannabis
i don't know whether it explains
anything if there is one
but but clearly it's different from from
what we did what we
uh conceived uh in the 1990s with
with rafi yeah absolutely and i think
that's a really big thing
that a lot of people listening to this
are unaware of uh mostly because i mean
a lot
of casual you know lay people that are
interested in cannabis a lot of them
aren't
going to the original research papers
and and reading the technical details on
how these things came about
so i think i think that's very important
to point out because a lot of times what
i teach is that
we now know enough to realize how much
we don't know
and you know and and we and we have
learned a lot
um but a lot of times in the industry
a lot of claims are made that we know a
lot more i think the emperor
effect as it has been used today is
something different
uh it's it's basically stating
another potential truth is that the the
the the effect of the
of the the the sums of the effect
okay the effect of the single components
together
is stronger than the sums of the effects
taken along
right uh this is this is
this could be true but it's not the
entourage effect that uh
that rafi and i thought about okay the
entire effect
something that comes together with the
with the main actor and is
protecting it uh from being uh
it's a real entourage effect if you
think of it from being degraded
from it's it's enhancing its activity
it's visibility
uh and uh and the entourage the the
synergistic effect that you find in some
plant preparations it's probably i'm not
saying it's not true
but it's different from what we what we
we found and it's probably due to
different components acting on different
receptors in a synergistic manner
rather than in an additive or a
counteractive
manner yeah yeah absolutely the way i
always describe the entourage effects
i'm always kind of
a hyper analytical person anyway but i
always say that
the entourage effect was initially
conceived to describe an effect
that that has components that generally
you couldn't identify their effects
yeah by themselves and then in together
they had unique effects which is
slightly different than this sort of
herbalism synergy kind of
exactly kind of concept yeah that's
that's really great to clarify
well before um any more hurricanes come
your way
and uh and knock us out here i hope it's
in you for today
i know yeah yeah um off
off uh recording we were talking about
how the
storms everywhere just getting so bad
and we've been struggling to finish the
interview because of uh thunderstorms
coming through but you can put things
together right
oh yeah i'll edit it together no one
will know the difference but um
uh dr dimarza thanks so much for being
willing to spend i know i
i took up you know about 30 minutes more
of your time though
it was not our fault yeah
i really really appreciate it and you
know i'm going to be following your work
as
as things continue for you thank you
very much
it was nice speaking to you very very
nice questions yes thank you thank you
yeah i'm glad our paths could cross
and do you mind if in the future i reach
out to you again sometime maybe next
year or so
no problem no problem excellent i hope
to
be able to tell you something
interesting regarding the interaction
with the
microbiome absolutely if something comes
up that gets you excited feel free to
email me because i get you know
i'm excited about all the stuff too so
thanks so much for sharing
uh your insights with our listeners take
it easy and have a great rest of your
day and
and week thank you very much on youtube
if you want to learn more about cannabis
check out the curious about cannabis
book on amazon.com and other major
online book retailers
[Music]
to support the show and get access to an
exclusive members only podcast feed
access to private events merchandise
discounts and more
visit www.patreon
curious about canvas
you