[Music]
so as I was putting together this
presentation I realized that I have a
lot to say I always have a lot to say
I'm very grateful to the panel before me
because I I just assumed that more
people would be talking about plants and
their responses to their environment and
there actually hasn't been that much
discussion so Corinne thank you for
introducing the concept of DLI which I
have here I have some slides here about
plant responses but I just planned on
skipping through them pretty quickly but
I might actually need to talk about them
a little bit so everybody understands
why it's so important what we're trying
to control and why it is so energy
intensive okay so why the heck are we
growing indoors in the first place right
it's all of these reasons right
ultimately we can grow anywhere we want
any time regardless of climate change
regardless of season we can grow in
Vermont and we can grow in San Diego and
we can grow on Mars for that matter
right so so that's a big piece of why is
so energy intensive because we are
literally controlling the weather we're
controlling all of the inputs that we
need to grow plants because we don't
necessarily have all of these resources
available to us wherever we are whether
that's good soil good air good co2
levels for that matter good sunlight
consistent sunlight and so by growing
indoors we can be very predictable we
can be very consistent we can have very
safe food and you know and it can be
available all the time so controlled
environment agriculture is just like
what it sounds like we are controlling
the environment like I mentioned earlier
when I introduce the panel my aha moment
was working on a mushroom farm who
couldn't you know where the farmer
couldn't control his greenhouse humidity
to grow mushrooms and I was like this is
what I want to do help them control
their environment and we are controlling
all of these variables right irrigation
and nutrients lighting climate air
quality ultimately for quality control I
want to remind everyone that farming
whether it's indoors or outdoors or a
mix of the two is a business right the
productivity the the product that
farmers are growing they are selling to
us the consumer right to you the
consumer and so they have a very vested
interest in reducing their cost of
production so that they can have better
margins so that their bottom line is
greater right so they have to think
about their customers their markets
their distribution are they local are
they growing lettuce or tomatoes or
cannabis or berries right and what is
the market for those things right so
ultimately greater productivity should
result in greater profitability but that
depends on how many resources they're
using and what the cost of those
resources are so as markets change as we
have more market pressure in terms of
resource utilization if they can lower
those while they're also increasing
productivity that's a very profitable
business so common ground right so I
broke it into sort of three categories
the grower slash farmer the consumer
which is pretty much everyone whether
you are a grower a non grower a
government a utility a regulator a
teacher an engineer you're a consumer
and you care about
although those things right so what I
mean
we want better yields we want an
available product higher quality it
tastes good I'm not gonna get sick
because I smoked it or ate it you know
government of course is concerned about
consumer safety right we want growers
want fewer consumables because that's
less things they have to buy okay and
consumers don't want chemicals and the
government doesn't want pollution or
chemicals if they can avoid it right
we're interested in labor markets and
jobs we want a good market price the
grower does in fact if they can have a
more consistent and predictable product
they can potentially drive the price
themselves and have a better shelf
placement okay wellö operating costs low
prices low resource use Same Same Same
and whether we call it optimization or
we call it efficiency that's about doing
more with less we are all in this
together so I'm gonna talk about a few
plant responses again I was planning to
go through this really quickly but just
look at this slide okay light has a huge
impact on the plant right on the way it
looks on the way it produces on whether
it's fruiting flowering or vegetative on
I don't even know temperature so model
opening nutrient and water delivery I
mean the list goes on and on and on
white is there's a reason why we have a
lot of focus on light plants need light
period we would not have life on earth
without the Sun okay so nobody has shown
this graph either okay this is a general
rule of thumb in horticulture and
agriculture 1% more light is equal to 1%
more biomass or yield okay in general
okay we have learned that not all light
is created equal
but this is a general rule
DLI
thank you again Corinne so this is an
image of what DLI looks like which is
how many photons within the par range
hit a given area a given surface area
whether that's the plant leaf or whether
that's the wall over there okay air
temperature air temperature affects
photosynthesis and it also affects plant
transpiration
okay plant transpiration in general has
a linear correlation with air
temperature and as you can see here for
tomatoes that it increases pretty
quickly with temperature but then there
is a limit at which now we're gonna get
a degradation in photosynthesis vapor
pressure deficit a term that is very
near and dear to my heart as a
mechanical engineer who's trying to
control both temperature and humidity
vapor pressure deficit affects quality
it affects yield and it affects water
use a slide I don't have on here
actually shows that you can you can
train your plant from a very young age
to be drought tolerant by giving it less
water when it's young and it's
automatically going to change the way it
grows to use less water when it's old we
can literally manipulate VPD to create a
drought tolerant crop and use less water
very exciting okay
let's talk about co2 for a second okay
carbon dioxide the thing that kills me
the most about cannabis growers and just
when they pumped 1,500 parts per million
of co2 and then hit the break with
temperature Oh
seventy you know 70 degrees in 1500
parts per million okay we saw a chart
earlier right from Eric oh that yes you
could have a lower temperature lower
light level and increase of co2 and it
will act like you have a hat it's all
more light okay but we can optimize all
of these variables all these parameters
together to really maximize productivity
okay and here's something that's
important is that every plant has a
different optimization curve I'm showing
sunflower we haven't we talked about
sunflowers right but cannabis tomato
lettuce chrysanthemum whatever it is all
of these plants have different
optimization points for these three
variables combined together so we saw a
graphic yesterday that looked a lot
different than this graphic in this
graphic HVAC is using the majority of
the energy and if you think about it
HVAC is not just air conditioning it's
not just dehumidification it's also
moving the air around it's potentially
using co2 burners or some other source
energy source of co2 okay it might even
be the air filtration that's affecting
fan power and the use of energy from a
fan so I'm going to talk about these
potential opportunities to save energy
other has I don't know probably five
subcategories within itself I actually
wasn't going to talk about greenhouse
glazing except that it keeps coming up
everybody wants to know my opinion about
greenhouse glazing so I had to I had to
bite and I want to talk about it a
little bit okay and I could probably
give a 45 minute talk on greenhouse
glazing alone I'm not gonna bore you
with that I'm gonna try and hit some of
the highlights okay first off I just
want to say this is the appropriate time
to use supplemental lighting in a
greenhouse do you guys see it's overcast
and cloudy not good light intensity
right we're not gonna hit the DLI that
we want for this crop this maybe not so
appropriate I walked into this
greenhouse in Colorado and it was
beautifully sunny outside and the lights
are on for two reasons one because they
had horrible control and didn't realize
that the lights were on I'm like that
was the first thing I noticed right okay
so talking about having qualified
growers okay one story but also this is
a triple pane glazed glass greenhouse
look at all the structure you need to
support the weight of all that glass we
just eliminated all the light so now
what are we doing for energy efficiency
using light every plant just like it has
an optimization of co2 and light and
temperature and water and nutrients has
an optimization point for how much light
it requires lettuce very low light
requirement on a daily basis strawberry
a little higher because it is a
flowering fruiting plant Cannabis really
high bruce bugs beat Bruce Bugbee has
given presentations where he shows that
they have maxed out over 50 DLI and as
long as the co2 and temperature is
optimized for that higher light
intensity it keeps eating it up we have
not found the upper limit for cannabis
that doesn't mean we should grow at the
upper limit but it's pretty high even
compared to Tomatoes so greenhouse
glazing why do we want to regulate
energy efficiency or energy efficient
greenhouse glazings and what does that
mean for most people coming from
commercial buildings who are regulating
windows it's about you value and our
value it's also about emissivity a
little bit but you value right so you
can see black
it's not looking so good right double
polyethylene does great okay
there's even an a sa b e what do you
call it greenhouse that is a historic
historical landmark because they
discovered at Rutgers the double
polyethylene greenhouse okay but right
with decreasing U value we also get
decreasing white maybe that's okay maybe
not I also want to point out infrared
and UV infrared is basically responsible
for the greenhouse effect in a
greenhouse glass is opaque to infrared
long wave radiation so when the sunlight
comes in and it bounces around it loses
energy turns into infrared light hits
the inside of the glazing and bounces
right back in great for winter cold
climates glass okay double polyethylene
and plastic maybe not so good at doing
that which is great if you're in Arizona
we don't want to try all that long wave
radiation we want it to escape but what
about UV right mark talked a little bit
I think you did did you about stretching
the par right but also stretching the
wavelength at which plants like to grow
and not just for photosynthetic reasons
but for quality reasons right for
pigmentation Jen from Gotham Green says
that she doesn't get red leaf lettuce
until she opens up the windows in her
polycarbonate covered greenhouse because
now we're actually letting some UV into
the greenhouse which is what causes that
red pigmentation so let's talk about you
value wow that's a pretty big difference
right 36 percent energy savings on
cooling okay that's looking pretty good
oh my god the Sun just exploded any
savings that we thought we gained from a
you value on the envelope eleven twelve
thousand percent difference okay
yes I think you values are great if
you're in a cold cloudy climate Kay
there's there's gains to be had by
saving heat but if we're doing this in a
warm sunny climate please but maybe
there's another option what if we add
shading to block out the sunlight when
we want to we did this study this was a
project in white what we demonstrated is
look at the load reduction K this is
just a glass house okay there's your
glass house envelope matter infiltration
mat son oh my god it's like a hundred
percent okay okay so now let's put
double poly on it instead we two percent
reduction but look at this we added a
thirty five percent shade and look at
how much we gained in cooling
requirements for this project that we
did in Texas we're actually going to
air-conditioned the greenhouse I am
going to talk about that later and we're
looking for ways to minimize the size of
the air-conditioner while they're
growing lettuce low DLI plant oh my god
we can like seriously do some fun
shading control so what you're actually
looking at is we say hey when the
outside solar radiation is between two
hundred and fifty watts and five hundred
and seventy watts per square meter we're
going to pull one forty five percent
shade curtain okay and this is the
result right here okay so this is
outside solar radiation or par and then
this is the incoming solar radiation
then we say oh now the outside is five
70 watts per square meter let's pull a
second shade and really block out the
light this is the result that we got we
are able okay so this is the DL I okay
our target is right in here for this
lettuce crop okay from January through
December and by having that ultimate
shade control okay that's this yellow
bar we are able to hit our DL I every
single month of the year and we're not
shading a crop in the winter when we
want to take advantage of sunlight okay
that is my piece on glazing and shading
okay so I mean I was really gonna talk
for about lighting for like a
millisecond so there's like two slides
up here I figured everyone would talk
about lighting but I'm gonna make one
case which is photo period control
this is vegetative crops only okay so if
we use a lower light intensity fixture
for a longer period of time we can
reduce the size of our lamps the energy
power requirements of our lamps and also
potentially the HVAC loads from that
light but but we still as long as we
still have well watered crops if we make
adjustments to the temperature and even
the co2 so that the plants continue to
transpire at about the same rate we
still have to dehumanize and
dehumidification is stupidly energy
intensive so we might be able to gain
thirty five percent energy savings on
lighting but maybe only 10% on HVAC I
mean it's something okay all right so
speaking of dehumidification anyone own
a cat I try to cover all the pets in the
in this okay so this is a desiccant
wheel solid desiccant wheel and any of
you who own cats kitty litter is what
heavy
right so imagine how heavy this wheel is
it's heavy okay all right
anyway so with dehumidification and
humidity control in general what are we
trying to do we are trying to control
evapo transpiration and
evapotranspiration is very important to
the plant for a few reasons okay one
number one water and nutrient delivery
if we don't have good water and nutrient
delivery we get leaf tip burn blossom
end rot and a whole bunch of other
issues okay it also is responsible for
holding the plant up right and the
cellular structure of that plant when
you don't water your plant the plant
wilts because the cells are dehydrated
okay one of the most important things
also is it cools itself by transpiration
we are evaporating water which is an
evaporative Li cooling process and so
plants regulate their temperature
through transpiration and photosynthesis
is miniscule okay so I actually realized
I didn't talk about moisture removal
efficiency but I am talking about
moisture removal capacity for a second
kay and they're closely related but
moisture removal capacity depends on the
equipment but it also really depends on
the room conditions every single
dehumidifier is rated at these
conditions 80 degrees and 60 percent
relative humidity for all the growers in
the room any of you growing at that
condition exactly I don't care what
you're growing there's no one growing at
this condition so what are the
ramifications okay you're a grower and
you're like I need to dehumanize I I'm
in a Google right dehumidification unit
so you google it and you say oh okay so
my let's just say you know what your
evapotranspiration rate is and what how
much dehumidification you need and you
say oh I need about to remove about 20
pounds per hour of water I need to
dehumanize but wait
in vertical farm and you're trying to
grow at 70 degrees and say 60% relative
humidity
its moisture removal capacities now 7
you need three not to owe you you're
operating a drying room your it like 60
degrees and 50 percent relative humidity
3 pounds per hour right you don't need
three you need six did I do that math
right three times six eight yeah I did
it right this is one of the reasons why
growers are having a hard time with
dehumidification it's not necessarily
because they don't know that they have
to dehumanize it's because they don't
understand that the cut sheets that
they're looking at are not giving them
the full picture and manufacturers are
not giving away this data readily or at
least to the public okay for a really
good reason I'll give them I mean it's
an okay reason they are actually doing
their own tests in facilities where
they're controlling temperature and
humidity but the problem is is that
there is no standard for rating
dehumidification equipment at any
conditions other than 80 degrees and 60%
so Keith I'm pretty sure that you guys
are involved in trying to come up with a
different rating system a lot of the
dehumidifier dehumidifier equipment
manufacturers are working on this right
now so they can be of better service to
all of us so dehumidification there's no
way around it is just intense okay in
order to remove moisture we have to drop
the temperature to below the dew point
to way below the dew point the dew point
for those of you who don't know is the
temperature at which do forms okay so
typically to actually remove enough do
from the air we have to drop the
temperature to less than 50 degrees we
have our project right now where we
a chilled water cold water system at 36
degrees because there's so much moisture
being pumped into the room that we have
to drop the temperature that low to
remove moisture well I'm not delivering
36 degree air to my plants I'm gonna
freeze them so what do I do i reheat so
i just used all this energy to remove
moisture and I'm gonna use all this
energy to control the temperature
well what about desiccant well desiccant
has the opposite problem now we heat the
desiccant to recharge it right so it
sucks out the moisture and then it's
holding on to the moisture and to dry it
out we heat it well now I don't want to
deliver 120 degree air to my room right
so what do I do
I cool it okay so where is the potential
to save with dehumidification first of
all heat recovery there are some
manufacturers who are doing a really
good job at doing hot gas reheat
runaround loops any way that we can
recover the energy that we're removing
from the moisture and from cooling and
putting it back in to the air without
using practically any extra energy at
all economizers well okay no I'm not
economizers give me a second on that
heat exchangers okay so we can have an
air-to-air heat exchanger where we can
recirculate back through like this piece
of technology over here so we removed
heat and moisture and then we're gonna
return through this return loop back
across that heat exchanger and pick up
that heat that we sucked out with
dehumidification in this case we're
using outside air indirectly through an
energy wheel so we're using the outside
air to pre cool and pre dehumidifier
before it goes across a cooling coil
let's talk about
fans okay dogs dog people okay a little
less shy than the cat people go figure
okay why do we have fans okay there's a
lot of reasons we have fans we have fans
to distribute that cooling and that
heating from our various equipment to
get it into the room okay and remove
that hot wet air and send it back to the
air conditioner okay but also we have
air movement across the plants
themselves in the space themselves right
for to break up the boundary layers this
little pocket of air that forms around
the leaf remove moisture remove heat
from the plants or from the lamps take
away the waste product called oxygen
right and deliver even co2 to the plant
air movement is very important this is
so this is the only time I directly pick
on title 24 so one of the sub measures
is fan efficiency okay which actually I
mean I'm not paying on I think I mean I
think this is still a good plan right so
they say that the circulation fan should
have a minimum efficiency K of some
watts per square feet or CFM I don't
know how they figured out the potential
savings I'd actually like to know the
answer to that Kyle perhaps just so that
I can in the next slide I could do the
same analysis or I'll just give it to
you and you can do the analysis okay but
the incremental cost is fifty to five
hundred dollars let's talk about a
bigger issue air filtration do we have
any air filtration people in the room no
really do we perfect snake oil salesmen
mmm-hmm no it's fine I'm talking to the
national air filtration Association in
Phoenix next month and I'm gonna be
having a get real conversation with them
about this those of you who have been
duped into installing HEPA filters I'm
really sorry because you're using an
unnecessary amount of energy to clean
air that or to remove constituents that
aren't really harmful to your plants or
at least that you don't really care that
much about what do you care about mold
powdery mildew botrytis well guess what
your regular old run-of-the-mill merv 11
filter can do that work I still
recommend more of 13 but okay can do it
you do not need a HEPA filter to remove
viruses and viroids okay there was a
paper that was written a few years ago
that looked at the energy savings
potential of different air filtration
media based on fan power it also looked
at the cost of replacements and how much
more costly and labor-intensive it is
even is to have a more high efficiency
filter that you don't necessarily need
so ultimately if you can reduce the
pressure drop across this filter by
having a larger screen basically you are
going to gain a lot and fan efficiency
so I did a little back of the envelope
calculation for a project that we did
okay and we had in this indoor facility
K requires 630 ton air conditioning
units if we use a HEPA filter it will be
equivalent in fan power to 250,000
kilowatt hours Merv 1395 that's some
real fan savings
and guess what the incremental cost
maybe actually there's a savings okay so
now on to my other opportunities all
right let's talk about equipment sizing
and VPD control BP again really near and
dear to my heart this next section is
especially for my growers in the room
VPD by the way for those of you who
don't know and are not familiar with my
favorite tool in the toolbox this is a
psychrometric chart and VPD is the
difference between the saturation vapor
pressure at the plant leaf at the
stomata versus the vapor pressure at the
room temperature and humidity the longer
this line the bigger the VPD the drier
it is okay so you have a room okay and
you have a good engineer who has figured
out that this is your sensible and
latent load sensible load is managing
temperature latent load is managing
humidity so your contractor or engineer
doesn't really know what they're doing
they're not familiar with indoor plant
environments and they're like you know
what I don't really trust myself I don't
really know what's going on so I'm just
gonna double the size of the equipment
right and just cross my fingers that
we're gonna get there well and so they
picked this unit and this is the airflow
is 4,000 CFM to meet there's 4.7 latent
tons but look at how much sensible we
have we almost have three times the
amount of sensible load which means
we're gonna really over cool and really
have to reheat okay this is so common in
the industry to oversized equipment
because hey you don't know what's going
on or be because you don't have good
conditions to start with okay so I mean
these are some of the options I put up
you can upsize the equipment you can add
stand-alone dehumidifiers between old
water growers or band-aiding right you
can reduce the temperature of the coil
so from 42 degrees down to that 36
degrees okay squeeze more moisture out
you can increase the thickness of the
coils but that's gonna increase fan
energy what else can we do let's change
the conditions in general when we have a
higher VPD as I talked about before we
have higher transpiration rates your
plants use more water which means we
also have to remove warm moisture from
the air if you have a lower VPD it's
more humid your plants don't use as much
water and there's less moisture to
remove plus okay so this is the chart
that we have on our website for cannabis
we have it also for strawberries lettuce
tomatoes okay if you guys are interested
in calculating your VPD so this was your
original condition 75 degrees and 50
percent relative humidity okay
and I've been able to convince you or
you've convinced yourself that we could
do 75 and 675 degrees in 65 percent
relative humidity and rather than having
a VPD of 1.5 I'm gonna have a VPD of one
which is much more standard for most
horticultural crops we are closer to the
saturation curve with our new system
which makes it easier for our equipment
to D humidify there's also going to be
less moisture in the room because the
VPD is lower so what is the result
oh my god now we have a 12 ton unit we
are right size we're right there for the
sensible and latent loads and look at
the fan though 2500 CFM
we saved saved saved and your plants
I bet are also going to be happier
happy plants happy HVAC what about an
economizer
okay again another 45 minute lecture I'm
gonna talk about it for like 30 seconds
okay because this is whoa this is a lot
of data okay a lot to get through we
looked at I think 10 different locations
I'm only gonna present three here very
quickly just to show you what the
opportunity is
okay so here's climate zones that ASHRAE
has defined okay there's hot humid hot
dry cold humid cold dry temperate and
everything in between very hot very
humid did you know ASHRAE created a new
climate zone 0-4 very hot very humid
well okay sorry and it's probably gonna
get worse okay so dry and cool okay so
this is Denver okay so I'm in Denver
this is where your temperature and
humidity set points are to hit a one
kilopascal
okay so this is a tomato or cannabis
this is your lettuce okay and this is
strawberry maybe they like the
temperatures kind of low and dry during
the daytime so as you can see the dew
point okay so this is the hourly bendata
this is how we read the dew point as
this horizontal line look at how many
hours are below the dew point the reason
this is important is because even if
it's cool but there's moisture in in the
air what are we gonna do we're gonna
cool yes but we're also going to
humidify a space that we want to
dehumanize so if all of these hours are
below that dew point temperature that
means we get to dehumidifier and that's
the energy intensive process okay what
about Orlando whoo it is tough in Miami
and Florida and Hawaii and Abu Dhabi
right to dehumidifier use the outside
air to conditioned our space why because
look at how high this dew point is
we should not be using economizers maybe
some mixed air but really if we were
gonna mandate economizers I would say
don't do it to poor Florida so can we
use the outside air to D humidify so
just quickly looking at lettuce versus
tomato in Denver the answer is a
resounding yes it's nice and dry but in
Orlando probably not okay
I'm so glad that Katelyn talked about
odor control yesterday I feel like I'm
the only person that ever talks about
this so a little story a couple years
ago I got a phone call from a grower a
potential grower new grower in Boulder
and he calls me up and he says hey Nadia
I'm building a new 30,000 square foot
greenhouse in Boulder and the greenhouse
costs half a million dollars but I'm
being told the air conditioner is gonna
cost two and a half million dollars does
that make sense to you
so pull out my calculator and I just
real rough back-of-the-envelope thousand
watts per square meter right a 30,000
square feet oh my god yeah 800 tons of
cooling right multiply that bake just
three thousand dollars for ton and yeah
two three million dollars this sounds
right to me
why did you do that
odor control the city of ball and one
from the city of Boulder do you really
want to talk to you about this I want to
know what's happened since our
conversation a couple years ago County
so Boulder has a very strict odor
control ordinance these growers were
smart enough to know that a greenhouse
in Colorado is an awesome idea we have
plenty of sunlight it's dry it's cool
they should be using conventional
greenhouse technology but they got a
complaint from a neighbor down the road
who happens to be an organic farmer
putting shit on his field that they were
concerned about odor so Boulder told
them you have to seal it up sealing the
greenhouse for odor control created an
energy monster why we're air
conditioning the Sun this is nuts
and there's so many people out there who
are looking at true-blue sealed
greenhouse not semi-closed greenhouses
but sealed greenhouses to prevent odor
from leaking out and air conditioning it
like it's a well insulated warehouse
building so when people say do
greenhouses use less energy than a
warehouse I mean I'd like to think so
but not if you're gonna do this right
you might as well just go into a
warehouse maybe add some solar tubes or
find a way to introduce outside light I
don't know but it's not black and white
and just for a moment because Caitlin
did talk about measuring VOCs this was a
study done out of Iowa State a few years
ago looking at harvested flower and we
have known for a long time that there's
about 20-25 VOCs right Mersin limonene
pining blah blah Blee okay that produce
odor what they I determined is that
there's actually 220 VOCs and what was
shocking is that the VOCs that were the
most offensive to our nose that we were
most sensitive to they could barely
detect with mass spectrometry we are so
tuned in to the smell of cannabis that
they're brilliant has to be any there
and we find it right it finds us so how
do we control something that we
can't even measure what do we do right
we had all these act you know that all
these carbon filters with recirculating
fans which there is literally no logic
whatsoever to how many you have how many
you install you talk to a different
manufacturer or a different person with
the same manufacturing they're all gonna
give you a different recommendation so
here's this greenhouse 450,000 cubic
feet okay in Boulder because I'm
guessing that they're not just air
conditioning they really want to make
sure that they don't get a complaint
from their neighbors so they're also
doing activated carbon filters and look
at how much energy they're using
everything we just saved by switching
from HEPA to Merv we just lost through
odor control and then I have to show
this video because one of my favorite
videos odor-neutralizer I'm asking
people in the room okay they say that
the the essential oils are non-toxic
they will cure the MSDS reports with you
but I always say this is also 24/7 I
know I mean there is too much of a good
thing right I just keep thinking about
all these oils getting sprayed into the
environment a slipping hazard walking by
all getting flushed down into our
waterways like and by the way privately
neighbors will tell me that they
probably think maybe the smell of
cannabis would have been less disgusting
than the smell of Febreze being sprayed
over their neighborhood all the time
they won't say that to the County Board
of Supervisors but they'll say it to me
in a phone call okay
monitoring and control it's just real
quickly there is a problem in this
industry with good control systems we
have horticultural control systems that
can't communicate with commercial HVAC
systems we have commercial control
systems that are like irrigation what's
that right I love this picture this
and a facility in Michigan and we
literally were looking at six different
sensors in the same exact spot giving
different readings okay what are we
controlling which one's right we need
more research right engineers and
manufacturers let's face it
regulators utilities a lot of people
don't understand plants they don't
understand the occupant of the room it's
not a person it's a green thing and it's
not an alien I guess it feels alien
growers don't understand energy balance
they don't understand psychometrics VPD
HVAC HVAC operation is very complex and
plants are living dynamic organisms that
don't have feet in hands and can't walk
over to a thermostat and change the
temperature we have to be able to
respond and predict to what the plants
need when they need it right and we need
better help defining the metrics into
finding baselines and benchmarks and
there are a lot of different metrics
that I hear getting thrown around I
actually realized yesterday I didn't
include a big one which is like watts
per gram right or energy input / output
but I mean it's pound per light dead do
we have to keep using this one is it
going away no okay I see some giggles
some smiles but remember again this is a
business and we have to be focused on
profitability and the cost of the
resources and the cost of production who
talked about footprint yesterday I was
so excited you talked about it
kale ah okay anyway
floor area of this greenhouse is 9,000
square feet we go vertical and now we
have a canopy area of 35,000 square feet
when we ask for an energy use intensity
and we have a limit are we talking about
canopy area are we talking about floor
area are we talking about illuminated
area are we because guess what you can
stick the light
right over the plant and that's your
illuminated area awesome
my HVAC system is conditioning the
entire volume of the room Oh
so you look at this floorplan you're
like oh that's easy and then you realize
oh crap these things are stacked 30 feet
up in the air and they're just packed
with biomass again is this our footage
or square footage
our footprint or is this our footprint
so research that's going on active
groups we've met all of these have been
mentioned today actually which is so
awesome I'm so glad that there's so much
awareness in this room about the
research going on about people who are
trying to define these metrics these
benchmarks these baselines and trying to
help growers optimize what they're doing
scri
is the Optima a group that is led by a
bunch of academic researchers and
they're going into vertical farms
specifically define the optimization
points for light co2 temperature water
air flow and then of course thank you
Derek for all your guys's work ASHRAE is
trying to fund a bunch of research and
then we have this standard that we're
developing so ultimately energy
efficiency comes down to optimization
for the growers and it all comes down to
being able to control our inputs and our
outputs all of these things are about
control one way or the other control
control control control I don't know
there's ten controls out there what can
we all agree on it's complex right it
depends grateful again for all the
speakers who have come up here and said
it depends on the crop it depends on the
location location meaning of the climate
the market all sorts of things right the
facility we can't increase the bottom
line we need more research and
ultimately I
do believe that it's possible to
optimize and be more efficient while
also increasing profitability for the
people growing our crops
the end
[Applause]
sorry I went over I knew I would but I
feel like I went through it pretty
quickly
you are amazing how about one more round
of applause for Nadia what what an asset
not only not only does she have the best
information she also can deliver it in
an insightful way and help the process
at the right time and get us all on the
same page thank you thank you Derek
thank you for putting this together in
the hospital