[Music]
I'm Gary corlett with Southern
California Edison
I'm Brian Anderson with Anderson Porter
design one architecture firm based in
Cambridge Mass and now newly here in in
Fullerton California yeah the
interesting thing here is what is is
that you know we're here at this event
talking about cannabis growing and
talking about indoor indoor agriculture
and how growers interface use utilities
how architects and facility design
interfaces with the utility early right
that's one of the things that we really
encourage is that cultivators get in
touch with us early on in the process
get us involved it's there's a couple of
things that about the electrical system
a lot of lot of things so let's start
with the the devant issues yeah all
right we we operate on a ten year
planning skill plan so we we plan out
our grid enhancements ten years in
advance because it takes us that long it
takes if we want to relocate a
distribution line it takes a year to two
years to do that if we want to upgrade a
substation it could take us three to
five years to do that or if we build a
new substation it could take five to
seven years and what kind of what kind
of crimp in your system does it count as
a one cannabis facility what crimp in
your system does 12 or what is a hundred
thousand square feet of canopy or two
and a thousands maybe canopy effect your
ten-year planning cycle so let's take
the first off it depends on where
they're at so you know in California a
megawatt of power will power about 750
homes yeah
a small facility a cannabis facility is
you know easily 1 to 3 megawatts
it's it's in an area of 10 to 20,000
square feet so now we're putting you
know 750 to 2,500 homes in the
equivalent of 20,000 square feet
our grids typically aren't built out to
provide that type of power in that in
that density and there's no coordination
between farmers or is there coordination
between farmers and planting boards and
the utility as a bike great because as
an industry were pushed right there's
stigma
we're pushed into areas that that's what
zoned for us we can't go anywhere else
right and but is that coordinated with
you does that help you what does that
hinder you it in some cases it can
hinder us just in the in being able to
to meet the demand
you know we've got cannabis in
particular has gone into low population
areas where they're well they're more
just underserved areas underserved
communities and so there aren't a lot of
industrial businesses in those areas
your mower zone for residential or you
know small industrial and then when you
bring in a cannabis facility now you're
talking about major loads that the
infrastructure does be a minute
structure wasn't prepared for it and had
we known you know 10 years ago that it
was coming we could have planned for it
but so when's the right time when's the
right time for the you know for the
farmer for the cannabis you know indoor
grower for the outdoor grew it not the
outdoor but let's say mixed light grower
to alert you like when's the right time
in their planning process they start
talking to you is it you directly or is
there is there a team that is this yeah
so they need to contact their local
planner yeah so we have planners in each
of our districts and they take care of
you to the individual cities and
counties yeah
and they can look at the grid in that
particular area and then decide what
needs to be done to provide them with
the capacity they may tell them that we
can't get you a capacity for you know it
could be two or three years right
but you know always we will get your
capacity but it may not be on the time
frame that you're looking for so that's
the first step and you should do that as
early in the process as possible as soon
as you start thinking that that you're
going to be meeting that that load then
you need to go to the planner and talk
to them about what you have do you need
to have a full one-line diagram produced
by it by an electrical engineer in order
to begin the process what can you just
start talking in generalities well you
can talk in generalities but you won't
get into the system until you have one
line drawing okay and there's there's
fees associated with with doing that
well yeah that means so you know as an
architect one line drawing is comes out
of you know three to two months of
planning work before before the engineer
is prepared has enough basis of design
notice how many plants are gonna go in
those how many lights going those how
much water is being used right in order
from electrical perspective to to say
plunk load light load HVAC load here's
what I need for amperage right so we've
got we you know that the arktech grow
team in the farmer have two months of
work to do before we can give you what
you need to drop the power well it's
it's it's at that point that your
service order to service it to get into
our system where we start and really
planning it yeah and agreeing out how to
do it now it'll be two years from that
point till we could get a drop possibly
so I mean we do things as quickly as
possible two things happen first off
when they get in in line we we operate
on a first-come first-serve basis first
one at 9:00 this first one gets out
and there's no jumping in the line so
you know basically that's one of the
reasons you want to get into the queue
as soon as possible because you know
they have to work through the queue to
get to your project before they can
design it and install it right and so so
one of the things are you know affecting
power delivery beyond the timing of it
what are the other
so is it location yeah it's location so
you know think about our our grid in
terms of ductwork or an irrigation
system so you start out with a larger
line at the very beginning because you
got a lot a lot of flow and then as you
get further out on that steps down to
keep the pressure up our electrical grid
is exactly the same way so the further
out away from our our power sources we
get the smaller the line sizes are and
that means that there's less capacity
out there right so it's important to
know where you are on our grid and how
capacity limited the grid is at that
point so just quickly can you talk I
want to get specific with some
geographic markets like you deal with
Carpinteria there's lots of cannabis
cultivation there Valley downtown Los
Angeles kind of what's what some stuff
you're seeing in each of those yeah so
we write cannabis cultivation market yes
so just a clarification
Edison doesn't cover the LA proper
that's handled by LADWP and so i don't
know what their issues are in there but
but in in in Carpinteria Carpinteria and
santa bárbara areas are actually
impacted areas for us it has to do with
they basically have one main
transmission line into that area
and and it's already is is impacted so
growers wanting to add capacity add to
that impact in we look at other
facilities like Desert Hot Springs we
have in Desert Hot Springs there's a lot
of transmission that comes through there
but we didn't necessarily have the
distribution capacity to do that because
that area was initially it was going to
be five acre home Lots right and and now
we're putting 10,000 and 20,000 square
foot cannabis facilities on there each
of them you know in a 1 to 3 or 4
megawatt requirement so that taxes us as
well because we weren't the the grid at
that area wasn't designed for the load
that's out there now so to take Desert
Hot Springs as a specific example what
are you projecting let's say three years
from now the demand from the cannabis
community and Desert Hot Springs
I yeah your plan yeah that's big yeah we
we don't have the numbers off the top of
my head that's in the pipe here that is
what your team is working on this figure
yeah what tries it's gonna grow help
make it's gonna grow we've put this much
does the facility design affect power
consumption are there right in it just
in terms of an indoor crow versus a
mixed light grower do you do you take
that into account when you project out
we tried to yeah so we're seeing in
indoor crows that we're averaging about
35 watts per square foot that's that's
that is that's that's down when we first
started a couple of years ago where
we're looking at 51 watts per square
foot so we're getting more efficient as
we go along
do you let's try me II was driving this
is that just data it's just data now
that we're getting better data on it we
did when we first started looking at it
we really didn't have a lot of data and
and now as we've gotten more data we're
getting better numbers we're getting
better at estimating what the loads are
going to be that's an indoor throw yeah
the greenhouse grows I don't have the
specific number but it's probably in the
range of 15 to 20 watts per square foot
so it's it does matter can you know a
lot and then the addition is the
greenhouses typically are conditioned
with water walls and basically swamp
coolers and indoor grows are typically
done with B X units package units and so
a lot less efficient and then the
evaporative cooling is there any is
there any call in so you represent do
represent gas as well as electric we're
not just just less electric so yeah then
to speculate differences in guess so we
see nationally you know a lot of
difference between gas prices and
electric prices will drive choice of
cooling systems let's talk about indoor
I'm speaking silly but indoor grows or
closed environment greenhouses that
aren't open air so closed air
greenhouses or or full indoor
environments make decisions on using
shale are you know chilled water and
show systems versus DX and electrical
systems based on based on energy price
yeah so is there any way to I mean I'm
speculating here I guess you're reaching
for something but say this is there any
these gas availability similar to
electrical availability in in new
markets yeah specific markets and if
they are would there be any relief for
for the electrical demand if people were
considering something other than a DX
system because yeah so
there the gas has the same problems that
we do in terms of their pipelines they
have a major in Desert Hot Springs in
particularly they have a major pipeline
that runs through that valley but they
don't have major gas lines coming off of
it that they don't have it yeah so their
gas system distribution system is
similar to ours and in that taking
plants it's you know plant and they're
planning yeah that the 10-year plan is
is because none of our equipment is off
the shelf it's all custom-built right
and so that's a two to three year
process of getting that and then the
everything that we do when it's major
construction like that has to be
approved by the Public Utilities
Commission so bureaucracy yeah and and
so it just takes time for that to happen
that could be a two to three year
process itself so given that it would
still make sense right because it's
gonna take these it's gonna take this
amount of time just to get electric it's
gonna take this amount of time to get
gas right and I'm looking at ways to
decrease load so if load and load
distributions is affecting all of us
from homeowners to indoor AG growers
what is there is a future zero what is
the position here in Southern California
on on dividing your operation into both
gas and electric so California has a
goal to be decarbonized
by 2045 which means that essentially gas
will not for the most part not be
available for for most things okay so
this is this is interesting right
because around the country this is a
conversation that's starting which is
we understand from a carbon perspective
that if we have renewable electrical
sources that is our goal we would want
to do all-electric homes right
all-electric cannabis grows all-electric
indoor AG if we can get our get looking
at our electricity from a renewable
source but what happens when our
electrical generation is from 30%
efficient gas-fired plants or from maybe
even lower efficiency Coldfire
coal-fired plants so aiming for the same
goals aiming for carbon neutrality
aiming for efficiency there are really
efficient on-site gas systems that are
up around 80% efficient today right I'm
not saying no system that we install is
gonna last forever right my boiler in my
house is I'm is maybe gonna last you
know 10 years if I'm lucky right I know
I'm gonna replace this system so let me
say who is there an opportunity to was
installed today a gas-fired system
because it's 80% efficient knowing that
in 30 years to meet the 2045 goal well
that's not for the prettiest ways 25
years I'm definitely gonna replace that
system right there's there's no question
and I'm not saying that there aren't
opportunities to do those types of
things that the challenges is harder
because of the policy that says we're
driving towards total electrification
the the goal is for California's by 2050
or there abouts to be what are those
powers general what are the Janet where
is it where we are we buying power from
from Utah and it's cold fire don't we
blow it's that's in in California terms
it's it's all renewable where's the
percentage of renewable today can you do
you know that for our great it's about
30 little over 30 percent 30 percent
renewable right now much higher than
other places the country right and our
goal as a company is to be 70 percent by
for 2045
so what are some things then let's take
that let's take energy efficiency and
carbon neutrality how does that flow
from a criminal from your perspective
from all of our goals what are some
efficiency things that you'd like to see
in terms of in terms of indoor plant
growth like what is it is it L is it LED
lighting is that is that a big game
chance so I was talking about right yeah
I was talking about cooling loads right
well right only ones if we're growing
with HPS we know we have a lot of
cooling right and if we stick with a DX
system or some sort of direct exchange
what about lighting is there ways in
which we can reduce power in these
facilities right by changing out
lighting yeah so LED lighting is has
made a tremendous growth in in the
industry in terms of the the type of
lighting that's being produced today
right and and so we can see tremendous
drops in load thirty to thirty to forty
percent in just your lighting load and
then the air conditioning load drops on
Ross as well and and so we're seeing
savings of roughly forty to fifty
percent total savings of the lighting
and interactive effects on the
air-conditioning system yes oh and we
know that there's we know that that's
that adoption rate is slow right because
because nationally and globally it's
been this industry has been indoor
indoor cannabis grow has been dominated
by high pressure sodium right well the
whole agricultural industry has been
dominated by high pressure sodium and so
it's you know when you talk about
controlled environment agriculture
covering the gamut of crops it's it's
the same issue the same issue yeah
so what what is so is there is there a
is there a line that you know Southern
California Edison has for the for the
inner grow for the inner grow industry
relative to their position is it just is
it a is it a general push to support the
state's policy or is there any specific
things that you would tell growers or
that you do tell growers yeah well are
pushing in with growers is to try and
drive them towards led yeah lighting and
more efficient air-conditioning systems
so we would love to see them get into a
chilled water system but the the the
biggest problem with most cultivators is
initial cost and the lack of lack of
available capital and so that's one of
the factors that we try to offset within
Central District Fire chiller like to
fire chilled water like yeah electric
shield chilled water right with LED
light right but uptake on that idea has
gonna take a long time for people to
really understand well what does that
mean to me as a grower right what does
that mean to my operation if I'm working
with you know a set of Goodman five tons
right now and and some quest D Huez and
you know a set of kavita's what is my
grow environment gonna be like how's it
gonna perform
so they've got issues right they've got
KPIs they've got responsibilities to
stakeholders they've got quotas to me
right exactly
so there's education education testing
there's there's there's yeah so we just
data we need and so that's one of the
things that we're doing is we're
supporting engineering studies and
providing LED lights where we can
operate to grow rooms side by side with
different technologies and gather that
data and and show that you know we
understand the the key components are
quality and yield and so what we're
looking for is to be able to show that
with with the right lights you can get
the right you can get the increase in
yield or the
equivalent yield and and the equivalent
were there any are there any TV spots
that we're gonna spec to see on cable
networks for the way we the way you know
the way we were the way we were educated
about you know compact fluorescents in
the home are we gonna see you know TV
spots - aimed at the grow at the grow
community - sort of you know how is the
outreach which what shapes the outreach
takers yeah so right now the outreach is
is the the organization part of the
organization that I'm in is a customer
outreach organization and we go out and
talk with the the growers and there are
groups and talk to them about what the
opportunities are and what the studies
are showing and work with them and try
and convince them to to make the
investment in LEDs and and we support
that again with incentives so that we
can help offset some of that that cost
to the incremental cost I have a
question so specific I guess - like
Desert Hot Springs in in that area I
know that people have spent a lot of
money investment in enlarged buildings
and large operations out there and
they're under pressure now so when you
go and you talk to them do you do they
give you sob stories do they come you
know they are they under like economic
pressure and and that that might
mitigate their ability to put some of
these reforms into place and do they
talk to you about that yes so in the
cannabis industry in particular we know
that there under cost pressures we saw
basically we looked at at the other
markets Colorado Washington Oregon we
saw what happened there where there was
the the prices started to drop down
because it became a lot more supply
and so we recognize that the the
financial implications of that we don't
get a lot of those sob stories so much
but because the growers just aren't
sharing those but we know that that's
happening and we know that the the lack
of access to capital is a big issue
aren't real estate prices also falling
out there do you know I don't know but I
believe that is true yeah yeah which
which might also mitigate their
willingness to you know make capital
improvements on on you know operations
that they don't even know they're gonna
be able to hold on to I mean it's just a
tough situation I would think so due
diligence I mean I would put that I
would put a lot of the four new
operations let's say not for existing
operation but for new operations those
are the elements that need to be
evaluated early when in the planning
process when looking at availability
power when looking at real estate price
when looking at Finance and capital you
want to balance what you what we tell
our investors were capable of producing
so that it's a realistic number and that
it takes into account real estate price
upgrade price power availability time to
market labor costs I think what if so
I'm seeing that is if the picture can be
so with that that what did you call it
the the sob story or the heartbreak
story right now when those come out it's
usually result of there's a mismatch
between what the investor wants back at
the end of the month and what and the
rock and the hard place that that that
that the growers is cultivators is
pushed into and they might have had
expectations for the market that didn't
didn't pan out yeah or that or the
municipality may have changed their mind
lo and behold a municipality could
change their mind and you now wait a
year in extra year so yeah plan plan
plan I mean so one of the things that we
always tell them when we're when we go
out and talk to our customers is you
know
the the opportunities that we're
identifying for them to become more
energy-efficient is an opportunity we're
trying to help them stay in business so
we're trying to help them lower their
energy costs which are there the major
non-personnel costs of the facility and
lower that operating cost down so that
they can stay in business and and make a
profit absolutely and it occurs to me
that these conversations should probably
be taking place before a shovel or pick
ever hits the ground absolutely exactly
yeah it's like exactly we can work
together holy cow
who thought we could work together right
let's the exact about this in the
planning phase so that we don't get
between the rock and the hard place so
that these eventualities have been put
into place that part of the due
diligence the investors understands that
look there's two years to get power what
are we gonna do in those two years do we
just move elsewhere or do we take that
time to actually build a plan so that
when we're ready we're up and running in
a way that's sustainable yeah and the
other side of that is if we start this
conversation upfront we can help decide
where you locate because we can tell you
if there's capacity available on the
grid for where you're at and and if
you're if there's capacity then it's a
lot easier to get you the the power that
you need and that's a mind that's a
mindset shift are you gonna say where
are you seeing a lot of new facilities
popping up like are you seeing trends
well there's still a lot of growth going
on out in in Desert Hot Springs but
those are facilities that essentially
been in in the process for mostly two to
three years but they're still expanding
theirs
well they're they're going in the way
that they were they're coming online
yeah
and they're still probably a year or so
out from actually being it what's the
pipeline looking like right there are
there new are there new a new
applications coming into that pipeline
there are new applications coming in but
more of them are coming in I think in
the urban areas which is what we're
trying to do we're trying to one
specifically
with German Aryans well the largest
urban area right now is is Long Beach
okay
for us in terms of energy applications
of applications coming in or in terms of
businesses that are already there the
the next coming up one is probably in
the the lancaster palmdale area we have
a lot going on in Atlanta right now and
those are some of them are new and some
of them are have been in the pipeline
for a while so you know we've been
working pretty hard pretty diligently to
to get power to the the Business Park
that is out in Atlanta to satisfy them
so there's you know nationally there's
really three three huge issues that face
any indoor growing farmer it's available
capital its state licensing and its
municipal entitlements so your local
Planning Board but what we're adding
here is this third right if there's a
two-year wait time to get power to your
facility we're adding a fourth major
earn 'el just starting a business or to
continue in two years come from is that
is that an accurate wait time two years
it's project specific but we were
talking about this a little bit earlier
the the utility plans the changes to the
grid on a 10-year cycle it takes it
because depending on what it is if it's
a relocation of a distribution line then
the the it only takes us a year maybe
two years to relocate a distribution
line to get power if it's putting in a
new distribution line it's two to three
years if it's upgrading a substation to
get more capacity there it could be
three to five but if it's a new
transmission line that that's required
then it could be seven to ten years you
know I have a question when the state
propagated its rules and created its
strategy for the state its patchwork
strategy of rolling out and everything
did it come and consult with you was how
these businesses how these areas and
obviously they way they did it it was
inevitable that certain parts of the
state would have more businesses than
others and probably be overloaded was so
was the energy component on their agenda
well no the state didn't consider that
at all and and because the state wasn't
telling people where to go right they're
not telling people to go to any more
reason so when we when proposition 64
passed it basically said it's legal in
the state of California and then the
state said they left it up to the
individual municipalities and counties
to decide whether or not they wanted to
allow it or not okay and so what so
what's what's what's basically happened
is the the disadvantaged communities
that don't have a lot of resources a lot
of capital coming in they're more open
to having new industries come in and so
they're the ones that initially passed
and the ordinances and said yeah you can
come in and grow here he's not
coordinated that's that's when they
didn't coordinate because and and we've
since worked on that with our local
public affairs people to go out and talk
with these communities say look before
you start accepting applications and
setting up business parks you come talk
to us and let's talk about what the
capacity is there before you you start
taking applications so when we talk
about the
communities that are hardest hit for us
in terms of capacity you know we've got
Adelanto in California City and Desert
Hot Springs or the Coachella Valley that
was all done before they made those
decisions before they came and talked to
us and so we've got a real problem in
trying to meet that demand we're doing
our best to do that and it works through
the process but again some of it you
know is going to be 7 to 10 years if we
have to put a new transmission line in
and and so what we've done since then is
is you know this all caught us a little
bit off guard we had you know in our
planning cycle we had no clue that this
was coming and so we didn't plan for it
now we're out talking to communities and
the different organizations and saying
hey look if you're going to come let's
talk first and you know let's work
together to provide still think the
state has a had a responsibility to
communicate what these smaller
municipalities we're going to face in
terms of being able to provide the
energy and the power to these businesses
knowing the timeline that you guys are
under you know right I don't think I
just don't think anybody ever thought
about it they didn't really think well
that's interesting in a state where are
there like 13 different sequa areas in
this a so you know the flip side is
they're very environmentally conscious
but energy is I mean tied inexorably to
right environment yes so it doesn't
really add up
we've been here for three days we're
kind of like some energy and power
related sites that you get out so that
would be greater like like what's what's
like wonder take away energy related
conversations you've had this past two
days or yeah you know it was this last
session here I was listening to and what
really witch's farms of the future there
was two sessions farms in the future one
farm with future two and and both were
populated by both urban and and and you
know Kentucky in various locations
nationally folks focused on the leafy
green and small and small vegetable
markets and and I noticed one distinct
difference was the language that they
used right talking about these as farms
talking about the the their grow
environment as a bot as a as a as a
biosphere talking about their their
total growth area in terms of acreage
these are all terms that can be
understood by a farmer right meaning
specifically his son grown suppose we
son grown work we understand labor we
understand we understand acreage we
understand biodome biosphere and I was I
was struck by how that leafy green
industry is is speaks with ease about
the same we're using the same language
around their indoor grows fully indoor
grows but in the cannabis industry we
still call it the cannabis industry we
don't call it necessarily farming we
talk about in terms of square feet and
canopy we talk about you know watts per
square foot and we seem to be it sounds
like if we started to share language
that with with farming and with big AG
that there might be some more
cross-pollination I think that was a
real takeaway that I heard that we could
we might have even I mean it's rapidly
changing right now this cannabis
industry changes fast but the idea that
we could even adopt more innovations
more quickly if we shared more
information with the at with the with
the AG community right right
the one thing that struck me is is that
you know the the the AG community that's
out there today is they're very
knowledgeable about what their
requirements are and how they get from
here to there with the new technologies
and they understand that much more so
than the cannabis industries and and so
I think a lot of a lot of it goes to
education and educating the cannabis
industry and bringing them trying to
draw them into that agricultural
community and and give them that
knowledge base that they're lacking
right now many of them don't know what
their requirements are another takeaway
was so RI is one of the co-sponsors here
and I sat on their panel yesterday not
sat on their panel the way that they did
a breakout session and they really
brought together HVAC issues lighting
issues utility issues and policy issues
and looking at that and saying look all
of all you all got to talk to each other
all y'all got to talk to within your
within your discipline within the
lighting discipline but then let's get
the lighting folks to talk to the policy
folks let's get the utility to talk to
the growers I think those are really
powerful conversations what were
somebody two takeaways for you and then
yeah I again it goes back to the
educational process you know I think
getting getting the growers more
involved in in that whole process
because we talk a lot with the the
lighting manufacturers and HVAC
manufacturers and you know so we have
that relationship going and I think it's
drawing in the the growers into that
conversation that's really important do
you think growers at every scale I mean
there were some large-scale growers here
I don't know if there were too many
small or you know I didn't see anything
yeah it's I mean it's really important
because the growers that I've run into
the ones that are growing on a smaller
scale
they they're growing by rote yeah you
know it's it's not necessarily that they
know all the science behind it but
they've learned the technique and that's
one of the reasons that they are
reluctant to change technologies is
because if you change the technology you
change something something in the
formula you need to be able to tell them
teach them what the the what other
components have to now change to to make
the same yield and same quality and
because they most of them don't know
that great and they don't have the
knowledge to do what is figuring out all
right so there's the tech part of it
then there's what about finance what
about the financial side of that so
rebates are a big great yeah and
understanding right so there's the
technology piece there's the there's the
adaptation of an existing grow that's
going to take some time we talked about
that right but what about the carrot the
stick thing right they are there are
their real financial incentives that
need to be communicated to growers at
certain scales like I one takeaway for
me was a growers at a large scale do
don't always have excuse me
growers and a large scale often have
more patient investors growers at
smaller scales often have impatient
investors and so that's that's another
rock in a hard place like how do you
satisfy the the investor who wants his
return tomorrow with the time it takes
to wait for power adaptors grow between
an HPS light and an LED light understand
those differences and now bring in the
technologies that allow him to benefit
and allow that plant to work right I
mean that's one of the differences that
that we heard over the last couple of
days the larger growers a lot larger
agricultural companies are looking at
paybacks in the five to seven years
period the in the smaller grower and the
cannabis industry is looking at a
two-year payback
you know because their business plan is
get in get out in five years and and be
done and either be it acquired or or
some other sell the business but
shouldn't that shorter payback allow
better a technology adaptation shouldn't
that quicker payback allow if the
resources are they should look at didn't
say what I'm gonna pay that back in two
years why wouldn't I adopt that new
technology like yeah so it takes a
different investor we're looking for
here - no but it doesn't that's that's
one of the things one of the the issues
that we run into is that you know the
the paybacks on these new technologies
are typically under three to five year
range and so my challenge and in terms
of incentivizing is to try and and
incentivize them enough that it gets
that payback down to two years or or
less and and that's not always possible
it's always based on the the amount of
savings that they can generate and the
smaller let me see the larger the
cultivation facility the easier it is to
to get enough savings that'll bring
those costs down so we have a lot of
smaller growers who aren't large enough
to have the generate the electrical
savings that would then be incentivized
to bring that cost down what's your
definition of a small grower when you
say small grower what's nice farming or
we are we are you have in your mind I
would say anything that's under ten
thousand square feet you got you know
ten thousand gross square feet canopy
yeah well if talking canopy it's
probably five or six thousand square
feet can it okay okay gross facility
sizes 10 K yeah 20 K and you cannot be
in that sort of six to eight K yeah okay
yep operation but that's still in the
scheme of things right here to lettuce
you know you're not a KERS we're talking
right first forty four thousand square
feet in an acre that would be a lot of
canopy yeah so you know it's and and
that's pretty much of the the average
size of
growing in our territory in particular
is about 10,000 square feet extend north
into Northern California where their
terrain is so different from obviously
the desert and maybe even down here we
don't go into Northern California so
much but it's yeah we we cover so on the
on the coast we cover up to about Santa
Barbara Goleta area in the Central
Valley we cover up to the most northern
place is count called wood lake which is
just north of to Larry's your so you're
not really on a massive scale dealing
with altitude with with with farms that
are remote or you know high up or in you
know difficult environments or on or
that yeah well yeah I mean we have
there's we have farms in Tehachapi for
example which is a on higher elevation
gets snow so I guess my question is do
those present special challenges
energy-wise or for what you're doing so
in terms of having capacity out in those
areas they're they're typically it turns
out that where they're at there is is
capacity we have up on the on the east
side of this year as we go up as high as
Bridgeport we have some facilities in
Mammoth the mammoth area and there's
some Indian tribe tribal areas out there
that we we service those are pretty much
there they're smaller grows so that they
don't have the capacity issues so yeah
most yeah but do they still need to
become more efficient well I believe
absolutely if they want to stay in
business they're gonna have to become
more efficient
you know the the price of cannabis is
going to go down we know that
historically that's happened through all
the news to the north are experiencing
it right now right now exactly yeah and
so if they're gonna stay in in business
they want to stay profitable they're
gonna have to cut their operating costs
and and so what about this discussion
then about way to cut operating costs is
make a business decisions what what
you're growing and why what is your
customer actually consuming right and
what is going to distil it and what is
what is prized flower and saying can we
grow in our in where we are let's say
you're at elevation in this town you
mentioned and you're growing in a hoop
house or you're growing in a warehouse
and a pre engineer metal building is
there anything you could do outdoors to
increase your capacity as opposed to
building more indoor facility and is
that is that part of the planning
process of the cannabis company or is
this is the municipality in California
limiting are they legislating against
outdoor grows are there where's that it
in the urban areas in particular the the
state regulations pretty much limit and
what you can yeah it's in there so
there's an area where we could use
better legislation right if this if the
if the legislature wants to hit carbon
neutrality then don't force everything
indoors that's just the two don't work
because we're gonna consume a lot of
cannabis are those zoning issues or
agricultural land outside in an urban
area what are the challenge was zoning
but it also has to do with just the way
the regulations were written you know
the regulations were written such that
the facility has to be secure so nobody
can just break in and you get some of
the product they had has to be invisible
to the outside world it has to be there
has to be owner control so that each
state each state is legislating that
differently and so one of the big newest
examples here is Illinois it is great
come right coming online and we're just
reading that law but in their
legislation they are forbidding outdoor
growing
and for a new state coming online the
size of Illinois with the population
Illinois and with the growing season
what can we grow outdoors in Illinois a
lot of soybean lot of corn there's no
there's no prohibition about growing
outdoors right so why why limit the crop
and why is the reason for that do you
know I'm sure it's I'm sure it's stigma
it's also older stigma security who's
out of sight keep it up yeah well we
just went through that here in
California because the government moved
hemp from the controlled substance list
and so we have this year we had a lot of
hemp grown outdoors and the the
requirements for growing hemp are much
less onerous than than cannabis and so
in Ventura County where I am based we
had about three thousand acres of hemp
grown a lot of it was grown in the urban
areas and after the first crop all of
those communities have now since that
we're having a moratorium on cannon hemp
because it's got the same scent as
cannabis and nobody wants it it's it's
the odor issue colleague was talking
about maybe just you know creating a
forum creating creating more
opportunities to bring you know I like
this concept of utility meat grower
grower meat utility that's a really neat
that's a productive one of the points I
took away from the future of the farm
was so there's these vertical farms from
back east and there they were talking
about how they want to compete with
California agriculture right and I'm
like okay that sounds great but someone
mentioned the other day with respect to
cannabis Thailand producing at one penny
a gram so really you know and I know
people are already thinking globally
especially larger operations but you
know how do you compete with that
now we don't know what they're you know
processes they have in how
how clean that crop is and how they're
making it but one cent a gram so I mean
it's one thing with your leafy
vegetables in your Tomatoes but if
you're talking cannabis do you also want
to think globally as well yeah you do
and so one of the issues around that is
is understanding the product and if we
have decriminalization if we can de
schedule cannabis from Schedule one at
the Controlled Substances Act out of
five now the FDA can come in and may and
and and may and manage what is the
product and to whom is it being sold as
being prescribed by a doctor if it is it
must be you know C GMP certified or G
ACP certified on the growth side and
cGMP on the manufacturing side that's a
whole new set of regulations that we
need to be that we need to prepare for
right so we need to understand what are
we growing for and we're an industry
that's we just talked about the
municipalities and how difficult they
are the state and how difficult that is
now we're going to add federal
regulation to that mix and we need to be
prepared for that we need to understand
that our facilities are regulated at
those three levels yeah that's true yeah
I mean for the last three years they've
been warning okay that the FDA is coming
yeah you know yeah it's coming and with
it and that will touch every aspect of
cannabis every no no overall they'd be
different verticals you either be a
medicinal verb that's right hemp
verticals right and don't use vertical
we're projecting that that would be
controlled by the TTB the taxation and
trade Bureau because it is not going to
be a product that is prescribed by a
doctor you're gonna have to have you
know you can just have to follow and if
it's gonna but if you're gonna sell in
you know marijuana infused products then
that is consumed orally that's taken
internally that you have to do that in
food safe situations right so it's very
similar to it's the food and drug
industry and I think that's we've talked
my language earlier changing language
about what what industry were in we're
in the food and drug industry right we
are drug which is a drug manufacturing
industry we need to produce drugs that
are consistent every time it is
consistent so that when the customer
comes and buys it it is exactly the same
you know I've interviewed large written
articles about large cannabis companies
where the owners came out of the food
industry yeah in a big way they were
they were established in the food
industry and these are established
cannabis companies from Colorado a
couple of them and it was very
interesting to interview these these
CEOs these executives because their
outlook about everything was so
different they they had so little
patience for the cannabis regulators
because so many of these issues they
said we've already solved them you know
a day really in the food industry okay
you know as foodies they were foodies
you know and you know so but they would
you know they would work very closely
you know and these are people who like
eight ten years ago were set set up
their kitchens in in Colorado and then
the regulator's would come in no nothing
they wouldn't know what was the right
standards or what to do for setting up
so they were teaching them so that
relationship with those local regulators
is a decade old yes yeah and that has to
count for something it does when the FDA
comes in because one because and this
this is another thought I had if this
because someone I talked about how they
were developing regulations at a local
or state level and my what I was
wondering was okay well when the federal
come when in that research when the
federal government comes in will they
use that data will they use that
research so that we don't have to go
back and start at square one
right they really should I mean there is
actually a lot of data this is one of
those data intense industries there is I
I've been covering it now since 2015 and
there's more data in this industry than
practice and it's extremely
technologically advanced industry except
that so much of that data is in silos
yeah yeah not share so GM so GMP
certification and communicating that to
governed officials is about
record-keeping
the fundamental idea of cGMP is
record-keeping it's being able to report
on the spot when somebody shows up a
knocks on the door and said we're here
to inspect you and you've got the
records you so that so data is gonna
read data data drives everything in our
world having it readily accessible it
you know it can't just be written in
pencil on a spiral bound notebook with
dog ears it's got to be you know
electronic recorded pull up at an
instant and ready to ready to transmit
to the to whoever shows up that kind of
data means you know this is a really
great point I've been to a whole number
of grows from Washington State through
this one and you go and they're all
different some of them are run even if
they're large operations are pretty much
run on notebooks everything's written by
the door written down is manual others
are all electronic and digitized can you
speak to that a little bit the variety
of operations and technology and
sophistication that you've seen yeah
well I've seen that the gamut in our
territory I I've seen some that were
literally run off a notebook and others
are what I consider you know top of the
line we have there's a grow that I know
that is operated by a person who came
out of the the pharmaceutical industry
and so everything is done
Six Sigma you know and its controls on
everything how do we not leave people
behind right how do we how do we bring
everybody up because we're because
there's incredibly sophisticated grows
that operate off a notebook but what
we're saying here is what are the tools
to to to run to the tide rising all
boats
you know we don't want to lose our
traditional growers our small craft
growers because they have knowledge and
genetics that are invaluable we want we
don't want them to go away
right now so are they're teaming and I
don't know they're teaming are there so
with it one thing we suffer from as an
industry is lack of shared information
right so peer-reviewed journals would be
a great thing so if we could get data
written out peer reviewed and
distributed would be awesome right
because nope
because one of the lament he talked
about the things that about the
takeaways from this conference that
maybe weren't so good we don't have
enough growers here and because growers
don't have time in their day to is why
we're doing this you know while we're
doing this videocast so that we can
reach people where they're at and if
you've got time to listen to a podcast
merge the title is with you know YouTube
channel maybe you could you know can
learn something and I think that's where
it falls on folks
you know professionals in the industry
that how do we share that how do we how
do we get that information out there to
share it so that would rise all boats I
think yeah this is like this type of
conference is almost like a dull
conference it's like oh uh you know this
car you know at this this is such an
important topic and yet it's been
disregarded in a sense maybe taken for
granted is that the attitude is energy
taken for granted I think it is in a lot
of cases you people are used to going to
the light switch and and turning it on
and and it's there you know and at home
you never have to worry about capacity
right rapid growth right we talked about
how quit you know if the investor wants
the you know it does not have the
patience for due diligence then nobody's
got the time to come and talk to
Southern California Edison right now
right and if you don't take the time to
do that then you don't understand that
you're you could risk an enormous
investment if you didn't because you get
shut down or right so that that patience
aspect hasn't been established yet right
it's now now now now now so we need to
slow down a little bit go slow to go
fast if you heard that go slow to go
fast planning is not gonna slow you down
planning is gonna speed you up so if you
do diligence is planning right meeting
with the officials is planning and
that's one of the things when I go out
and I do outreach with grower
organizations that's one of the things
that I try to to espouse to them is is
that we need to have this this ongoing
conversation so that when you're
planning to do something let us know so
we can help you achieve that
so so now you've been to this particular
conference which is really focused what
did anything happen here and and you
know there's all these industries here
and the industry is kind of focused here
so is
anything you're taking away or that you
heard where you went um like inside Oh
No oh we got to work on that this
situation is like worse than I thought
like have you learned or heard anything
yeah we're yeah yeah okay yeah and it's
it's kind of why I'm talking to you
Gary's because you know I'm new to the
California market not new to cannabis is
new to California market and
specifically oh this is worse than I
thought y'all been at this fort for
20-something years and yet the what's
bad what's worse than you thought
the hodgepodge of municipal messed up
nests here that is way worse than I
thought
and from a so when I think about how do
I add value to the conversation how does
an architect come in and improve the
situation beyond subject matter
expertise I need to know I need to know
the utilities because I need to figure
out how to how do you match how do you
met how do you knit this patchwork of
completely disparate laws back together
so we can talk about what what we can
talk about things like best practices in
the industry we can talk about things
like the traffic cones which are the
sort of standards within with within
which we operate you can do different
techniques within those but these are
the standards like energy consumption
water consumption building thermal
envelope you know but now you add this
difficulty of the patchwork of municipal
different in laws and that's this
enormous that's a really big
complication yeah that's worse than I
thought you know we probably used to the
patchwork I mean I'm here in California
the whole time and so we've had to deal
with this from you know see from and
it's been a mess from the very beginning
I'm wondering if the state regrets
rolling it out that way and giving every
municipality the choice because it's
created havoc within this state yes yeah
I have no no idea whether they do or not
I know that they've they're going
through some changes in the way that
they're doing it yeah
you know one of the biggest issues was
the the the hope that you know by
legalizing it that we would eventually
work out the illicit market and one of
the big issues that we we have is the
taxation and you know by the time all is
said and done the the product is taxed
you know basically 54:39 percent the
other day at a shop which is you know
for for someone who has their patient
card and all that that's that's
unacceptable but I told the regulator's
that I mean other than the politicians
and you know um one of the cannabis
Control Commission officers from
Massachusetts is here for this
conference
Doyle yeah and one of the things that
the state of mass does just as an
example is publishes a map of the state
and all 360 plus or minus municipalities
and you can read right from that website
which municipality has voted for it
which percentage of the vote who voted
in that town so we had two votes like as
you as you did too right we had a we had
a we had a medical vote in 2012
Massachusetts did they had they had a
adult use of vote in 2018 and you can
read on the website who voted what was
the percentage of vote is there a
moratorium today when is that moratorium
sundowning so as it so as an industry
the industry can look at that map and
say well let's let's go to a town that
is that is open so that that increases
planning so there's a world of the state
plays did in that enables development
and that's a critical understanding is
that the state can enable develop the
state can help by just publishing data
you know which sounds great that really
sounds great I hope the Massachusetts
now that I'm thinking about it also said
oh we also need to make sure that if
there's a gold rush or a green rush into
one particular town or sector that they
have the energy that you know to meet
that and and and every state has to be
the same they have to have a long
timeline to make you know big changes so
there that's the same example it's like
that does sound great but you and then
we realize that everything is connected
you know and and
can't move forward with large projects
without empowering them and the very
thought of putting a project into place
and having to wait two years for your
power is mind-boggling unless you
already have a two-year rollout you know
and then it's all you're gonna work for
you yeah well and that goes back to it
takes us a while to get the power why
you need to get involved early and have
us involved early into the planning
process the earlier we can get into it
then we have a parallel path going well
that's an interesting thing writing we
talked about the earlier if you know
you've got a two-year wait for your
power this is you now haven't you ever
give a mandate to go slow to go fast you
simply can't go any faster than that so
the question now is what are you gonna
do how do you take advantage of those
two years what do you do do you have a
roadmap can we provide a roadmap for
what needs to be set in place so when
that two-year time is up you're ready to
go theoretically that might be the best
thing that ever happened to you in a way
yeah because because because capital
capital can't push you any faster
then then then the utility is able to
provide that drug so that now I'm
thinking so Desert Hot Springs which you
spoke a lot about and I've been out
there I was out there for when can
Desson launched their first two
buildings you know several years ago and
the city was there and they had a little
boy scout true I mean they really they
really played this up and I have to say
it was a small ceremony but it was
moving the mayor spoke and what this
dirt what it meant to this dirt poor
town it was moving to me I was genuinely
moved because it was so real and so
sincere a very poor City you know half
an hour north of Palm Springs you know
you know and so all of that sounds so
great but you know due diligence you
know all this things so I guess my
question is so that was several years
ago now these large places are coming
online so once they come online then
their power deeds don't they escalate
and like America well well they do but
they don't come online all at once and
that's that's another part of the
planning process
so typically these these facilities are
coming on
in phases and so if we know that in the
year you can plan we can plan for that
too
and that's another reason why it's
important for us to be involved in the
upfront so but specifically with the
desert hot springs do you feel like
right now that you know how the rollouts
going to come and so you feel like
you're in good shape to be able to meet
the needs I think we are I don't know
the exact timeline on all of that but we
have a pretty good handle on what's
going in and in that Coachella Valley
and what the requirements are and and
we're building to do that raises a
question is there any follow-on benefit
that you from a utility perspective see
from a large consumer customer coming in
like a cannabis entity is there any
follow-on benefit by providing that
power for that for this industry
are there other it does that create
opportunity for other businesses to move
into into Desert Hot Springs that
weren't there before yeah support those
industries it's possible seen it I
haven't seen it I know but it's possible
because I'm just thinking if if if the
economic drivers for for the cannabis
industry for the food and drug industry
are allowing entities out there to wait
those two years there must be entities
who don't have that time to wait and so
wouldn't be wouldn't be lining up to
come in to Desert Hot Springs so that
mayor that passionate occupy yeah he
must be thinking of well this could
actually spur further development no
doubt that's what that is what they're
thinking that yeah yeah they see a
future finally we see a few just more
marijuana or drug drug manufacturers but
the follow-on industries the other jobs
if you create 200 jobs those people need
a place to live those people need a
place to shop they need a place to get
their car fixed right those are all
follow ons that that are that are
invisible but that absolutely did
they're real I have a question for you
just occurred Amman is probably specific
to a state like California which has
this you know obviously the traditional
cannabis market for four decades so and
it's still out there it's still robust
larger than the legal one they consume
power to but there are probably people
that you have
the difficulty of not impossibility
having conversations with they don't
want to talk to you they want to still
stay underneath so how do you account
for that well we don't is the bottom
line
the we look one of the the challenges
that I had when we're looking at state
licenses for for cannabis gross
they the the cannabis growers have one
name for the state and when they get
power from us it's a different name and
so trying to correlate the two together
the entity LLC I see what are they
actually registered as who have they how
do they apply and what is the legal name
of the entity is it attached the
property or they a tenant right and and
so those that are in the illicit market
as long as they're not stealing power
from us we don't know what they're doing
and we don't care what they're doing so
as long as they're paying for their
power it's and so they're there are
entities within our territory that I
know or I'm sure are cultivating but we
don't know that they're there and
they're they're paying their bills on
time and so and law enforcement still
doing their thermal scanning from the
skies over the state I mean I think you
know looking yeah for entered hot spots
right but but we're not involved with
that no you're not don't they let you
know no we only react to that if we get
subpoenaed to us you know we don't we
don't coordinate with the the
authorities you know we're not part of
the the policing organization the only
time that we get involved is if we
discover that there's power being stolen
and and then we get in you're required
then obviously to do something but in
terms of identifying where grow houses
are or anything like that that's we
don't have any any role in that at all
it occurs to me that the the energy
needs of the larger
this community in California were
probably baked in a long time ago you
know I mean they've been at it for so
long so you know we haven't gone we
haven't had a blackout for that right
yeah yeah you know we have although I
don't have any statistics to go with it
I'm sure that we've had transformer
issues and in certain areas that may
have been caused by grows but we don't
have anything specific to to relate to
that