[Music]
we're sitting in your 5000 square foot
grow in Pacoima California in the black
haze room you have a unique way of doing
your indoor grill explain that to us
yeah I don't know if it's so much unique
as much as it's just an old way of
growing it's a way that used to be
referred to as Dutch trays if I'm
correct on it it was really more popular
kind of in the 90s and the primitive use
of it was with kind of rain gutters and
water was fed to the plant and it would
recirculate into a reservoir and it's
just the way that we've grown for 13
years I really like the way the herb
comes out on it we get a good smell
every grower thinks they have great herb
but our I think the consensus a lot of
patience it does very well at shops so
basically what the system is that we
have our six inch PVC pipes with five
inch net pots we drill holes into the
net pots and the roots it's suspended in
the pipe the water circulates over the
top it's called NFT or a nutrient film
technique and it washes over the roots
and recirculates under the reservoir is
it energy or resource efficient it's
very efficient for water because the
water circulates this room has 210
gallons of water in it and it gets
changed once a week you don't use soil
what are you used in place of soil we
use rock wall with hydro time we could
just use straight rock wall like a lot
of people do but what I found is a hydro
ton repels algae better a lot of the
grow dam cubes or the rock wall algae
just seems to have an easy time there
and if you go with a lot of girls you'll
notice well everybody uses a lot of
floor flex now so it blocks light out
but before those days those are the caps
then it's a brand name for the caps that
people put on top
the large rock wall cubes which is the
common way people do hydroponic these
days aha
now do you use any nutrients or
fertilizers or any chemicals at all oh
yes we use we use ten different
nutrients from four different companies
in our formula that we mix we just use a
lot of the classic companies general
hydroponics bow Tanic air super thrive a
couple things from the company Canadian
Express we also use a product from Mills
so we're really hitting a lot of
companies across what we do is just
follow the things at work and we pieced
it together now talk a little bit about
your your harvesting your cultivation
practice how many strains you have
running at any point in time and how
many harvests you do we just run more
strains than we do now and a lot of that
is because testing has gotten very
expensive so it doesn't make much sense
to run three or four varieties in a room
because the testing really starts to eat
into your profit margin and since we are
a boutique Kraft scale grow operation
we're a specialty size which is up to
5,000 square feet of canopy our real
canopy size is about 20 to 5 so if you
start eating up a lot of that in testing
it basically kills our profitability and
so we've had to scale down to just one
or two varieties per room so that we're
doing a maximum of two tests for the
flower although then we did the pre
rolls which is a couple more tests as
well before we get to the pre rolls
which is a new product you're putting on
the market you raise sort of the issue
of margins so how tight are the margins
in a in this market place and in a grow
of this size I've marked our tight for
everybody I think a lot of cultivation
if you're profitable I think that's a
feat in itself right now because I do I
personally believe that a lot of large
operations and small operations are not
profitable people are searching for the
right niche for themselves and until
that happens
it's it's just a nature of the beats
there's also a huge investment bubble in
here so there's a lot of people that
don't subscribe to regular market
fundamentals such as profitability
they're more interested in market share
than profitability and so it's kind of
created a bit of a distortion on the
production side that you just have to
deal with you know if a fund comes in
and and they're putting down 20 million
on a grow and they can afford to lose
money month after month while they
establish their market share it's just a
reality you have to compete against for
us as a small craft girl or we've been
doing this for a long time we have to
make money to survive and so finding
that niche in that place that we can
achieve profitability is basically if we
do we survive if we don't we don't
survive so in other words in addition to
the the testing costs for additional
strains if a strains out on the market
and it isn't moving that's not really
working for you it's fair to say if you
can't sell your weed at the price you
need to sell it for you're gonna be in
trouble when you go into a shop and
you're distributed by refinery distro is
that correct yeah refinery does my
distribution I've known I've gone way
back obviously I've been in the industry
since oh five and back in the days where
we used to do a lot of civil
disobedience and protests and we used to
lay down and block DEA cars when they
would raid shops the Bush years were
exciting and a lot of people I know I've
known from back in those days when it
was very antagonistic between the
federal government and even the local
government and the cannabis industry and
so refiner does my distribution I've
known them over there for over a decade
as with most of the shops I deal with it
I've always dealt with her the people
who are here prio seven so most of my
personal relationships go way back
wasn't the cultivations alliance in that
fold into a group or did it stay yeah
it's it's basically folded into the
Southern California coalition right the
cultivators alliance still exists as an
entity but for the most part we eat that
was a kind of a conduit and along with
some other groups such as the California
Minority Alliance and glocca and the
delivery alliances well now we kind of
rolled into a larger group to try
encompass as much of the industry as we
could gotcha but from the very beginning
you've been there you've been out there
representing Los Angeles cultivators for
years and years talk about that journey
what why did you step up because you're
pretty visible
you've been out there you've been a
leader in that role how did that happen
that happened because when I first
started here in 2005 I had the great
fortune of going to work for Don Duncan
who is one of the founders of Americans
for safe access and has really been the
leader in pushing positive legislation
for cannabis in the state and all of
those what I had mentioned before about
protests and civil disobedience that was
all tactics that had to be used in those
days to get the shops to be allowed and
so going from that and having gone as my
mentor I saw how he organized the shops
back in those days to push back and to
get the licensing so when I first got my
warehouse up here I looked at this and
thought well there's no permit process
for me yet and I can't really rely on
somebody else to come do it for me I saw
how it happened with the shops and so I
just decided it was time to try to find
like-minded cultivation people that had
their own and wanted to come and push
for a regulated industry and we
organized found those like-minded people
and we formed the group how have the
politics of the city changed how
different are they now the politics is
one issue and then the economics is the
other issue well let me put it to you
this way of the leg of the of the of the
LA growers that you've known over the
years how many of them are not going for
licenses you know the two pressures I
think that every growers had to the last
three years is one meeting the
regulatory challenges and process and
the other one is the economics and as
cultivation of cannabis has gotten more
prevalent and up north has dealt with
this as well prices have collapsed
prices are about you know a third to
half of what they were 10 years ago in a
lot of cases
less than a third and I think people who
weren't efficient struggled to get
through that even before the permitting
had started which presents a whole
nother set of challenges coming through
and I think at the end of the day people
who are growing or looking at it as how
am i supporting my livelihood and a lot
of them just look at the path towards
regulation and said this isn't it I mean
if I'm just gonna be honest about why I
I would say 90% of the growers I know
haven't went for license and to be fair
a lot of those 90 percent they they hung
it up a year and a half ago anyways I
would you know I think the number of
growers I know who are still growing and
are gung-ho black market I don't even
know if I know anymore most of them just
they they've kind of washed out and have
moved on to other things a lot of them
interesting they're consultants for a
lot of the big companies that come in
now right and you know and I think those
who have been pretty successful at
growing and who have been able to
differentiate and as I said before find
their niche are continuing to do it and
with us we're lucky in that we kind of
have found our niche which you've
discovered yourself and shops I guess
the question for me is at the end of the
day will the Los Angeles cultivator
community be a fraction of what it
previously was is like is it'll just be
much smaller but more dedicated and I
mean is that what we're looking at or
will new people come in and try and you
know take up the slack there's plenty of
plenty of new people are already here
and cultivate oh yeah and it's a
different it's a different type of
person than the the grower before and
everybody has a different idea of where
their places and how they're going to
get there I think with a lot of people
have looked at it as everybody wants to
scale and how do you scale correctly I
think is the one that I'm not sure
anybody's really nailed yet a lot of
times people scale up and the quality
suffers and so just working out those
issues is a thing and I think a lot of
cannabis out there at least the feedback
I hear
a lot of the quality out there isn't as
good I I've heard people talk about a
race to the bottom on it and it very
well could be but I also know that those
who can produce a quality that will
differentiate itself will differentiate
itself right for for our selves you know
for our company here legacy strains
we're not carried in very many shops
because we don't produce that much but
the nine shops that we are carried in
they buy up all of our inventory and if
I had more inventory we could open more
shops so um are you are you breaking
even are you profitable can you sustain
yourself your business model currently
yes we are okay right now I don't know
if in the future we can which is a whole
nother dilemma is the real estate prices
or the rental prices for cannabis
facilities if you go back five eight
nine years ago industrial was renting
for seventy five cents a square foot
eighty cents a square foot sometimes
even sixty five cents a square foot now
if you're doing cannabis you're lucky if
you're under a buck fifty a lot of
brand-new of turnkey places they come at
you with three bucks a square foot I
just don't think that that is realistic
long term because I think prices will
continue to face a downward pressure as
scaling does ramp up and people do start
to become successful at scaling really
well quality wise are you pricing a
product yeah the prod the wholesale
pound price well I think continue to
fall a little bit so what do you think
will happen with with craft or artisan
boutique products such as yours do you
think prices will be maintained do you
see the marketplace what do you see out
there in the marketplace because this is
something I ask all the time like the
consumer is the consumer just want the
cheapest or as or do you think there's
connoisseurs out there who will pay for
quality and continue to this this comes
from my night I was a budtender for nine
years while i moonlighted learning
cultivation
and the one thing a lot of people I
think forget and especially I think a
lot of the outside people outside the
cannabis industry getting into it is
they look at this large untapped
consumer base but the reality of it is
and has always been is that 20% of
cannabis users consume 80% of the
cannabis and you can try to target
people that are in that other 80% that
consumes 20% and there's untapped market
how big that is is anybody's guess but I
do think they the core constituency
still is that 20% of cannabis users and
they generally care about really good
quality cannabis or else they want the
cheapest cannabis and those are kind of
the two everywhere in the middle is kind
of a no-man's land so for myself as long
as the consumer will pay is willing to
pay $50 maybe up to 55 dollars for an
eighth of some of the nicest herb they
can see in the Shelf I will be ok if the
day comes with a consumer will no longer
pay $50 for the nicest herb in the shelf
then what I am doing
needs to change because that you know it
if the ceiling becomes $35 then this
business model is unsustainable
but but if it stays at 50 and a lot of
people they they come in and they want
the nicest jar there and the bud tenders
pick ours out and say this is it it's
and the price point is around there I'll
be ok I know that small price points
make a huge difference in markets in
these markets well you know the
retailer's $5 price point is less than a
$5 change on the wholesale side as well
speaking of of of your product in
particular it could go for 40 right but
also 50 like a mile and a half from
Greg's place it's selling for 50 and 8
at actually if buds and roses so you
know and actually that's not that far
away so you know there are some
differences we're basically in the four
year the 50 well I think I think to be
fair you have to look at the
the demographics in the area that Aaron
is with buds and roses in the area
Greg's at with refinery and they're just
they're dealing with different client
tells all together Aaron is kind of in
the creme de la creme of the studio city
you know getting close to Sherman Oaks
young Ventura I would imagine
Aaron I would imagine buds and roses is
probably paying more per square foot of
their shop that Greg is playing over
over on Oxnard and Custer
all right so my concerns number one
personally is taxes are definitely tough
it would be a lot easier I think a lot
of us initially to have the taxes start
to go down the regulations are really
crazy to deal with as a small cultivator
I have had to pay my entire savings life
savings into hiring consultants and
attorneys try to get me through this
application process and just for being a
small kind of self-funded person it's
pretty brutal again we the other side of
it is as far as what would I like to see
the larger industry there's a lot of
people such as myself who have been
around a long time and have been part of
cannabis kind of as a culture in this
state and I think as the commodification
of it starts to happen some of those
cultural aspects are going to be lost
which is really more of a nostalgic
thing but still I think it would be a
shame as a lot of the small independent
growers are just unable to to do the
heavy lifting of the regulatory process
or even just being able to hire the
professionals that will help them
through it and just that you need to
hire so many professionals to get
through the application process is
another thing that's going to be very
hard to stop new people from entering
the one concern going forward is with
too much regulations is going to stop
small new entrepreneurs from coming in
and trying to do something new and
different and potentially better that
will benefit the entire industry and the
more hurdles you put in place up front
the harder it is for that person to be
able to take a chance and see if they're
gonna hack it now where are you in your
application process right now or in your
licensing we are about to submit our
permanent state application we have our
temporary from the city we have our
temporary from the state and and
actually right after this interview we
will be putting the final touches on our
state application and getting that off
and compliance wise how you how you feel
about things I have my appointment on
coming up to go down to City Hall and
give the city my my first tax payment
since I've been off
here so what about like Bill did like
the bill planning department all that
kind of stuff the city agencies I've
worked with through the DCR have been
great I absolutely could not complain
they've been very helpful they've been
very supportive
I think the DCR is really really doing
the best job they can with the resources
they have and I am very very happy with
the effort they've been putting forward
nothing's been perfect and smooth but I
nunn of nunn of the fault I would put in
the DCR I really think they've been
doing a phenomenal job with what they've
had to do and have been very supportive
of of trying to really make this
industry happen you have to be really
pleased that your legacy strains product
is moving off the shelves the way it is
I call around and you know people are
waiting especially the black caves you
know to get it in so plants please grow
quickly okay because these need on the
market so is your is like let's come
back to just briefly about about scaling
because we want to see an industry with
with with product that is that as that
has the attention has been brought to it
that you have you know you're a
dedicated grower and have been for many
years and it would be a shame if you had
to go off and do something else you know
or work for some big company so how do
you scale like what is your plan what is
that biggest challenge finding another
space it's the cost in real estate or
will you will have to pick up and move
to a cheaper part of the state if push
comes to shove
yeah if push comes to shove I will
definitely have to I want to stay in LA
the big problem is just more the real
estate speculation and I think that I I
could expand tomorrow if I could find a
40,000 square foot building that the
landlord would be giving me a buck 50 or
less in rent if that happened I could be
there I could have the funding for it we
could make it happen but I mean my I
have a couple broker
looking at it and I hear things like you
know talk to a building owner in a
compliant area this particular was in El
Monte which has is permitting very
supportive city but the zoning they only
have 15 to 20 locations that are
suitable for cannabis under their zoning
you know and one of the owners who had
where it's actually open said until it's
three bucks a square foot don't call me
back so that's pretty much the issue
everywhere same thing was looking at
desert properties and it's three dollars
a square foot and it's just I mean that
I would scale up and have a worse
overhead than I have my five thousand
square foot that would be less
profitable than my smaller facility like
that so at some point for example one in
the desert I heard have been on the
market for almost two years now and at
some point these owners are gonna
realize that the money in the cannabis
industry is like it is for everything
else you know in some ways we have
smaller margins than other manufacturing
sectors and until that realization comes
and those buildings were sat there for
long enough and nobody's paying the
three dollars a square foot they're
gonna you know then then the then the
rent will eventually come down when they
figure they're sick of paying property
taxes on a vacant building and
eventually it'll come down to the where
people like myself will want to occupy
it and we see opportunity but are there
owners out there who are open to other
arrangements like yeah yeah yeah I'll
rent it to you for a two bucks a square
foot and you give me 15% of your equity
yeah there's there's that too but you
know it's I think a lot of small smaller
people and even larger people have to be
careful that they're not just making
money for a landlord and that's it I
think profitability is going to become
an issue here probably in the next year
or two I think you're gonna see an
emphasis in the industry on
profitability like real profitability
and not not just you know being funny
with your books and I think it's going
to matter and when that does matter it's
it's gonna happen it's gonna have to
happen do you think that that when that
happens it might there might be an
advantage
smaller operators who've managed to stay
independent and efficient and quality if
that you know it that that dynamic might
be more prevalent in the lords
publicly-traded or the large companies
that are acquiring now where they have
to continue to grow their business
models they're not growing they're
failing yes so each one of those brands
that they've acquired will need to
perform yeah well I mean that's the
thing I think I think the emphasis a lot
in the industry from you know particular
people outside and I don't mean to beat
up on them we you know it's it's nothing
nothing against it but it seems like
people see value in acquiring brands
more than they see the value of the
brand performances themselves and so
when when it comes down to the you know
it's I have 20 companies well I have 30
companies well I have 40 companies well
what are those companies doing and I
think that's the question
nobody's really stopped to look at yet
because they're just more concerned
about acquiring more and more companies
and you think the day of reckoning is
maybe a couple of years away all right
sooner well that's it who really knows
when that day of reckoning is I all I'd
I am I feel like the day of reckoning
will happen but I mean what do I know it
may never happen it may speculation may
just continue and and people might just
continue to invest money in it and you
know last question for you your
pre-rolls they're coming on the market
talk about them when are they when are
they when can we see them on the market
and what are they
we're they're gonna be strain-specific
the first one rolling out is the black
haze and we are hoping to have them on
the shelves right around 4:20 maybe a
little earlier great and that their
packs of seven packs of seven half gram
joints they taste just like the strain
they're supposed to great wonderful so
what are your so you're moving into
pre-rolls do you have high hopes for the
pre-roll market for pre-roll sales I do
the pre-roll markets pretty competitive
and I know that quality is an issue in
the pre-roll market and so
I really just hope we take our same
attention to detail that we've taken
with our packaged flour and that the pre
rolls will speak for themselves as it is
for legacy we do zero marketing like all
our marketing has been word of mouth and
so that we're gonna try to grow the pre
rolls the same way the people who
already get legacy are probably gonna be
the first ones to buy them and if they
like them they're gonna tell their
friends how great they are and their
friends are gonna check them out and
they're gonna become repeat customers as
well you know that begs the question you
know I mean legacy up in the Bay Area
expanding your footprint I know you
can't do it now but I'll thank you sure
would like to I would like to when the
day comes where I can find a reasonable
rate on a forty thousand square foot
warehouse and that gets cranking I
should probably have the bandwidth to
start releasing I have shops in the bay
that wanna carry us already and I you
know just unable to make it happen right
now because I'm too busy filling the
orders my existing shops