where we are tuned into a morning
breakfast briefing the title of this
conversation but we will cover a variety
of topics is essential and on the brink
of collapse a weighty start to your day
take it away mr. Tom Hines so I guess
the genesis for this discussion was
anecdotal discussions that we've all
been having with business owners people
in the industry and also a series of
three very recent articles one in the
Sacramento Bee one in MJ beers and then
a Forbes article basically same thing
that California cannabis even though
it's deemed essential is in crisis and I
think what we want to do is kind of dig
down into that kind of talk about why
it's happening what's the result of the
pandemic what issues were percolating
already and we're aggregating by the
current situation and what people are
doing about it
so I don't I think maybe the best thing
to do to start is to have everyone one
at a time kind of talk about within this
the perspective of this subject what
they're doing right now in the industry
and they can sort of weigh in if they
want with their general perspective
right now and we'd also like to get from
people you know because everyone here is
is is deeply involved in policy in in in
the in the the overview and the nuances
of the industry to talk about about
what's really going on from your
perspective so give us an overview in an
under view and I think that would be
very helpful for whoever's listening who
do we want to start with who's who
why don't we
lower-left with Jackie and then will at
least on my screen and kind of just
introduce yourself for us Jackie tell us
what you're doing and you were one of
the people quoted in one of these
articles so give us your perspective
sure thanks Tom
my name is Jackie McGowan and I have a
consulting company called Green Street
consulting and a Facebook group called
California City and County regulation
launch where I set up 540 google email
alerts to every city and county in the
state four and a half years ago to
capture all of the movement at the local
level and I've been banning those Google
email alerts for the past four and a
half years and reading every article
that's come out in every jurisdiction in
the state and so the actual quote that I
gave to the Sacramento Bee who I view as
a very biased publication which is
unfortunate considering that it the the
state capitals newspaper but the editors
of the SAC be the editorial board came
out in opposition of Proposition 64 and
if you look back at the last year to two
years worth of articles in the SAC beat
they loved to harp on any negative
stories they do not like to tell
anything positive about cannabis and my
actual quote was that the industry was
on the verge of collapse prior to the
corona virus pandemic and that part got
edited out and and I had a few words
with the with the journalist you know
that that it wasn't acceptable that
they're not telling the entire story I
think that the media did the industry in
extreme disservice by you know
publishing article after article talking
about how there was significant increase
in sales and everybody was stocking up
because that just made everyone view or
continue to view the industry as a cash
cow which it is not you know
and it's not because there's so many
different people and agencies with their
hands out and it all does add up so I I
think that the industry was in some deep
trouble prior to this and given that
they've had to especially if you come at
it from a retail perspective retail has
had to come up with an entirely new
business model and the reason that I
believe that the industry is on the
brink of failing is because that
business model
it worked for existing retail when
people were visiting retail stores you
know there's a there's one store in in
San Jose that prior to the pandemic was
seeing 1,500 people a day and I don't
know how you replicate servicing 1500
people a day and be profitable if you
have to do curbside delivery and a
curbside pickup and and shifting to a
delivery model I don't think that the
the numbers pan out to pay expensive
leases for real estate as well as
running a delivery business you know it
would make a lot more sense if they were
in industrial areas and that would bring
the cost of leasing down but that's not
something that you can just change in
the midst of a pandemic and so I think
that distributors have become sort of
the the credit master in in this game
and a lot of retailers have pushed off
their their credit on to the
distributors and when they blow out a
distributor they just switch to another
one and so we're seeing those accounts
receivables get larger and larger with
with many distributors if it doesn't
blow them out
so a distributor didn't get a license to
then become the financier of the the
cannabis industry and that's what's
happened and so I don't know I hope that
there's some other brains on this panel
today that can come up with some
out-of-the-box solutions because we are
we're in some serious terrible territory
well that's my perspective
Chenin and you wanna well weigh in I'm
Cheyenne Manhattan
I am co-founder and CEO of insular
screens and high-tech district we've
been in the industry in California for
about 10 years coming out of the prop
215 market we were one of the earlier
adopters of getting our prospects before
license so it's kind of a running joke
in our organization of uh Shannon she's
the first one to ever do it you know
we've we've spent a lot of time helping
regulators figure out how to implement
some of their rules at the local and at
the state level and yeah it's been a
battle we started this as cultivators
and tincture makers and I never imagined
we'd be in the distribution business but
we were having such a hard time finding
a distributor that could represent us
and meet the needs of our clients most
of our products are non psychoactive so
I thought that was a tough sell in the
early days that we were selling weed
that didn't get you high so we started
our own sales team and in the last few
months with COBIT and just some of the
extinction going on in the distribution
space we've taken on a lot more at the
last mile fulfillment and we're actually
onboarding other small brands right now
that are getting pushed out by the
distributors and really just trying to
build that portfolio of boutique
heritage products and keep the people
that built this industry viable 3 that's
next transition
Amandla good morning had unmute myself
so that's good to see everyone I hope
everyone's doing well this morning so
I'm Amanda Ryman and I'm currently the
vice president of community development
at Flo kana
we are also distribution i've resonate a
lot with what jackie was saying so we
are based up here in Mendocino County
and we work with a network of
independently owned small farms their
son groans so that's kind of our our
brand is Sun grown product and we
distribute around the state and I think
you know in addition to what's already
been said as Jackie was saying you know
this isn't like Co vid caused these
issues and prior to this pandemic
happening there were some policy issues
that we were working very hard on that
we felt were necessary in order to move
the industry forward one of them being
tax reform one of them being market
expansion and the fact that cannabis is
banned in most of the state of
California even though they
overwhelmingly voted for legalization
and then banking at the federal level
and I think it's interesting that after
kovat happened these issues did not go
away in fact they became even more
necessary and I think Kovan actually
started to give us some talking points
around these issues that we hadn't had
before and you know it's interesting
I've been working in cannabis for over
20 years as an activist first and then
moving you know more into the industry
but you know as activists we were never
in a landscape that was friendly you
know and we were never in a landscape
that wasn't in crisis mode
we had dispensaries getting raided every
day we had patients going to jail
we had people you know losing their
freedom so the idea of having to operate
in a crisis scenario honestly feels a
little bit more comfortable to me than
operating in a business-as-usual
scenario and so I think you know we as
activists and as those who really had to
push this movement forward we
an opportunity to think about what used
to work and what we used to do before we
just tried to go about it as business as
usual and how do we change hearts and
minds and how do we ignite passion and
how do we help everyone understand the
hypocrisy between being essential and
being illegal and this is giving us
opportunities we haven't had and
actually quite some time so I'm
interested to take advantage of them and
also kind of use this as a pivot point
to see where we want to go moving
forward and I've got more thoughts on
that in terms of how the state of
California is handling cannabis how the
federal government is handling cannabis
and what we can do as business as an
activist to try to impact change even in
a time of kovat you know I kind of think
of this as like getting the carpet out
and like shaking it out real good you
know for society and when that happens
you have an opportunity to slough off a
lot of the crap that's been hanging on
for a long time and to breathe some
fresh air into that and I think that
that's an amazing opportunity so I look
forward to having this conversation with
this miss Burt today
Thanks wow it's like a panel of a real
activist so Adam weigh-in hey thank you
for having me
so Adam Spiker I'm the executive
director Southern California Coalition
which has been in existence for about
five years now four and a half
predominantly initially to you know try
and you know fix LA's situation shall we
call it previously and currently I also
run a lobbying firm that has been in
existence in the state for three
generations definitely concur with some
of the things that I'm hearing from you
know the rest of your you know your
panelists I would say it's a shame that
it isn't hyperbole how you titled your
you know your conversation today
it's just flat-out not hyperbole that
that the industry is you know failing
and I would almost argue that the legal
industry just about has failed I mean
we're two and a half years in just about
we still have 70 to 80 percent of the
industry ally
and there's absolutely I would challenge
anyone to give me an example of another
regulated industry anywhere in the state
or country that has that type of
environment they're dealing with where
they're getting taxed and you know and
you're dealing with the over-regulation
and the costs associated and meanwhile
seventy to eighty percent of their
competition is still in existence
dominating their market so what we try
to do is you know we try to think
outside the box
continuously understanding politicians
whether local state federal you know
there's certainly tactics involved in in
how to you know create consensus and a
lot of times it means getting creative
and that's kind of been our you know our
mo from day one and it still is you know
as you know some of the the focal points
about I I don't have an answer for for
more licenses because the state really
can't they can't force that issue you
know because of our to two-tiered
structure you know on taxation you know
I'll just kind of start off a
conversation and Greg and others can can
chime in you know our challenge on
taxation has been for three years since
this Sieben became a concept of 64 the
the folks that were trying to do it
right and do it legally we're facing an
unfair competition and each year the
industry would get behind you know
typically you know Assemblymember Bonta
or others proposing ways to try and make
them more competitive and it just hasn't
even begun to got traction you know in
the legislature and unfortunately a lot
of the reasoning behind that is branding
it's been deemed corporate tax relief
it's you know the example I would give
is it's basically try it's basically
having you know med men harvest key
relief and acreage you know telling the
state we need help
meanwhile the state was seeing them
you'll be evaluated over a billion
dollars and so it was a universal no and
so one of our big pushes is to change
the narrative right
to this being a social responsibility of
the state you know we're all working
hard in our different local communities
to you know try and try and correct some
of the wrongs over the last 60 years as
it relates to the war on drugs you know
social equity programs and you know our
argument and our challenge to the state
is that it's a social responsibility to
them to make this industry more
competitive you know at least for those
programs let alone the general legal
industry or else they're set up to fail
and so that's where we're trying to
change the narrative and and also trying
to build more consensus within the
industry because a lot of times it it
gets really fractured and you know
different groups and different segments
go at you know policy at you know
advocacy you know in their own way and
sometimes it it does more harm than good
when you're not singing the same song
and so that that's kind of our argument
so we've you know we spent a lot of time
because we had our hands full just
dealing with LA we still do but we felt
it important to kind of try and you know
take a you know you know a second line
of of battle with with the state of
California as it relates to just the
competitive landscape for the legal
operators and the social equity
applicants and operators that are going
to enter this market that you know
unless something change the statistics
are not going to lie they're going to
fail at an alarming rate and it won't be
their fault great you want to sort of
pick up this why not I mean you know
what everybody's saying is correct and
you know you don't have to look into the
future to see that most of the
businesses that are coming in half are
gonna fail all you have to do is look at
LA cities oh I mean I just don't jump
right into I'm for those that don't know
me I'm Greg CEO refinery Inc we're
licensed in both
phase 1 phase 2 and phase 3 in LA and
been involved local la boy born and
raised been involved in the cannabis
politics since the beginning from glocca
nam andhe also on the board of the SE
c-- since the beginning and that's just
a quick brief one I'm also a Marine
combat veteran and so to get into that
right you don't have to look but la
phase two social equity a licensees to
see that it's failing you had 800
something different people awarded
licenses to life half and those are
already abandoned cancelled gone they
didn't have the funds they didn't have
the means they're gone
those were 400 licenses that were issued
by local and state that are now dead so
it's kind of gonna be hard in my opinion
to convince the state to give more when
they gave more and then they just went
to nothing so the focus should be I
believe more than giving more licenses
to help people succeed and not lose
those licenses because that is what's
happening and in my opinion I mean the
taxes are high everything is high you're
gonna keep the taxes high then you need
to subsidize cannabis and what I mean by
that is subsidize the price difference
between legal and illegal cannabis so
that we can be competitive against the
illegal market and part of the reason
why and it's not a excuse because it and
people need to pay their bills right
just like anything else and this is a
touching because I think I heard briefly
what Jaclyn was saying about retailers
bouncing from distro to distro and
basically bouncing on their bills right
and so peep these retailers are used to
this different
situation where they just get a item and
they double the price or they put a 80
percent markup on it and they think oh
I'm gonna make all my costs and then
here we are two years later and a lot of
the retailers like I'm gonna go bankrupt
so not only do they not have enough
money to pay their taxes which are
overpriced and then on top of that when
they're paying their taxes the state has
this ridiculous tax where you get hit
with 50% if you're even late on your
excise tax I've never heard of any
industry that gets 50% penalty you know
you have a hundred thousand dollar bill
Nelson it's a hundred fifty you couldn't
pay the hundred how are you gonna pay
the 150 you know so it's it's all
connected it's not just one issue one
problem it's a bunch of issues it's a
bunch of problems that have to all get
solved pretty much at the same time or
else it's not gonna work a great can you
talk for a second about you it told me
that the taxes are so fucked up that
you're disincentivized from selling your
own homegrown product in retail you're
incentivized to sell it bulk yeah so the
tax liability on distribution is a lot
less right and my situation is maybe a
little different because we're a micro
business right and so I have to remit my
excise tax at the end not at the
beginning so what happens is I don't end
up paying an excise tax on 80% markup
because I've done the math and eighty
percent markup means bankruptcy so you
know I have payroll taxes I have all
these other taxes that we haven't even
got into as a normal retail would and
and so god I just went off track and
anyone else can weigh in if you have
something to say about this but you were
talking about the bulk as opposed yeah
so for me it you just I pay less on
taxes and end up profiting more money
when I just sell my cultivation in bulk
instead of spending the time the package
it lab test it put it through the retail
and then pay full excise tax at the
point of sale which sometimes I'm doing
it 225 percent markup you know so the
whole system is very it's wrong because
you have some people paying less taxes
than others and then there are people
that are working the system you know
saying oh yeah I'm gonna remit my own
taxes and then they never remit any
excise taxes because they're doing
distro to distro and the state hasn't
and the city have not caught up to Ted
yet and so there's people out there that
are avoiding taxes you know on the
excise side and claiming that they paid
when they didn't pay and eventually
that's going to come back onto the
distributor as well you know and then
there will be a dispute of who paid who
didn't pay so there is there's even more
problems coming down the line and those
that's gonna be huge is that one you're
talking about millions and millions of
dollars I mean just in excise tax alone
we pay over two and a half million a
year
I mean excise and sales tax not not just
exercise to the state so you know your
that's a lot of money that people are
you know basically frauding this data I
think we're in the tax war story section
part of our discussion anyone else want
to weigh in on this a Tom this is Adam
this is a definitely a pet peeve of mine
and I think it's a pet peeve of the you
know the legal industries in general I
think maybe for your viewers or
listeners
maybe an analogy might be appropriate
and while I totally appreciate it and
can understand the legal cannabis
industry doesn't like you no comparisons
to legal alcohol what I do think is an
interesting you know perception of what
happened you know post prohibition of
alcohol in 1932 we lifted prohibition
and you know because of supply and
demand alcohol was this robust industry
all underground unregulated unprotected
so we lift prohibition in 1932 and the
first federal tax in 1933 on alcohol was
2% because they were trying to
transition that robust legal industry
into regulated means and it worked
obviously it took some time and they
staggered the tax rate I think they went
from 2 to 6 to 13 to probably 3,000
right now who the hell knows but the
point is it doesn't matter what the tax
rate now is on legal alcohol they
eradicated the illicit competition they
staged up the taxation and made sure
that they were capturing this new legal
market of legal alcohol again you know
through you know regulated means and
channels we've not done that in cannabis
you know and in California and a lot of
you know I know Jackie is bringing up
your reporters out there that are trying
to capture the story in the essence of
what's going on there's no other example
that exists in the world like California
where we had a twenty plus year history
under compassionate use to create
collective models and medical
protections for patients and consumers
and and coops that turned into a
multi-billion dollar industry and so in
California like it's basically the
analogy I like to use is that you know
Colorado Yosh you know Illinois some of
these other states or canada and in a
large sense they got to you they got to
play with a blank chessboard and figure
out what to do with legal cannabis and
they still had their challenges
california we
prop 64 you know predating that the MC
RSA and then mal curse' eventually and
we started with a chessboard where
pieces were all over the goddamn place
and no one can figure out what to do and
our argument was always in Gregg was was
part of this from the beginning you just
need to incentivize the illicit folks to
come out of that of that gray area and
into legal in whatever way possible we
proposed registries you know checks and
balances within those registries but
just get people to come out of the
shadows and start being on the right
side of legal and we've never done that
and now we're two and a half years in
we've created this price point
disparagement that's so severe that and
Greg can speak to some sure others they
all had friends that were playing in
that gray market you know in the
collective model and a lot of their
friends said good luck to you but I'm
not going there because what's in it for
me you know I'm gonna lose money I don't
think I'm ever gonna get caught doing
what I'm doing which is now completely
illegal they just take their chances and
a part of this discussion definitely has
to be enforcement and in particular
deterrence for you know for illicit
activity right now we have none most of
most of any sort of felony charges or
prosecution were taken away under Prop
64 and I think at that time you know
certainly you're giving sympathy to the
war on drugs you can understand the
logic but now post Prop 64 and licensing
for the legal industry we're making
clear distinction between legal and
illegal yet we have no deterrence for
the illicit operator to think twice
about starting a legal cannabis business
and basically it's become a it's a line
item in their budget you know in LA
we're playing whack-a-mole every day and
to bring up la not you know obviously
you know you have a broader audience in
that but la sets the tone for the whole
state's market because of how big it is
and in LA
and others like him can't compete
because you know while the city's trying
their best to enforce and shut down a
lot of illegal stores and they just they
just finalized a padlocking order in the
city to be able to close down illegal
stores they still find a way to open
back up sometimes they'll open back up
in the same strip mall you know in a
newt and a new address but 40 feet away
and you've got to start the whole
process over again and I and I think
it's just got to be critical to the
discussion that there's no deterrence
for illegal operators they're not afraid
to keep doing what they're doing because
the client tells their and the it's a
risk/reward thing the risk is very
minimal for them and that's a problem
when I just weigh in what's the best way
to write this imbalance is it is it
enforcement which is the stick or
carrots
what reducing taxes incentivizing
patients and consumers to come back to
the legal market what what and how do we
get there what's happening in Sacramento
are they just simply not listening
so anyway yeah so I mean honestly I
don't I don't think enforcement ever
really is gonna work we have way too
many hidden places in Los Angeles and
way too many people for them to find
everyone and beyond the whack-a-mole I
had an illegal retailer maybe a thousand
feet from me it took gangs of narcotics
seven times raiding him and then finally
the last time the idiot decided to run
up the street with a bag full of cash so
they got him on some other charges not
even cannabis and then that's what
finally closed him but yeah and I have
friends you know I've a lot of friends
that are still in the illegal market
because there's no more gray area now
and they have no intention of coming in
and
call me the idiot for paying all this
money in taxes and while I'm suffering I
think they're right you know I mean I
probably invested in real estate hey Tom
I would just say this that definitely
turned over the others I don't think
there's a silver bullet in my opinion
just fixing taxes especially
understanding the landscape of how
difficult is been to get any sort of tax
relief the last couple of years of the
state is gonna change the problem I do
certainly sympathize with Greg and
understand where he's talking about from
an actual enforcement standpoint you
know illegal operators have been pretty
damn good at hiding for 20-plus years if
not more and and they have a lot of
confidence that they won't get caught
I do think more deterrence is key I mean
going after the land landlords that
safe-harbor these folks you know doing
things like that and having more
administrative enforcement rather than
boots on the ground enforcement you know
is a help you know like the you know
Reggie jones-sawyer and assembly member
brew Bo both have bills in the
legislature that may not go anywhere
this year because of Copan 19and and
Reggie's bill is to go after landlords
to the tune of $50,000 a day if they're
having an illegal cannabis operator in
one of their premises Rubio's bill is to
go after the operator to the tune of
$30,000 a day and Greg was there you
know from the beginning in LA we tried
to fight for as much enforcement under
Prop M as possible and we settled on
trying to do $20,000 a day fines
attached to the landlord and the
operator if they were caught thinking it
was more of an administrative action and
that we can send letters in the city
attorney can start you know enforcing
and adjudicating and then we come to
find out they can't enforce it you know
they don't think the city attorney
doesn't think
can win those those battles in court to
charge people 20,000 a day and you know
we're sitting there looking back at it
you know now saying well why the fuck
did you write it into the ordinance you
know and into the initiative if you
didn't think you can add force it but I
do think enforcement's key I do think
more licensing is key and I agree with
Greg you know there's you know there's a
lot of licenses out there I think
there's an overabundance of cultivation
licenses but when it comes to a safe
access standpoint you can get into
pockets of the state or you might have
to go 75 miles just to get to a licensed
retailer and so it does matter in that
regard because the illicit market will
follow where the clientele is gonna be
so I'll just leave it at that jet just
quickly I'm a big fan of concrete
examples
so Greg touched on kind of the craziness
that is taxes from the retailer
perspective Shannon you wear two hats
distributor and brand I'm sure flow kana
has a distribution license too and is
also a brand so can you guys just talk
about some of the crazy stuff of how
you're taxed from a brand and
distributor perspective and then Jackie
you're in Sacramento so can you talk
about that the tax conversations you're
having with the Laurie Ajax's Nicole
Elliot's Fiona Maas of the world and
kind of what they're where their heads
are at
that's actually not my lane I spent time
at K Street or K Street had dedicated
lobbyists working on those issues and
I'm no longer with K Street but I did
want to touch on enforcement and then
I'll let Shannon and a man to talk about
the taxes at those levels that they're
experiencing I can't stand when we have
any conversation about enforcement where
operators are asking for increased you
know law enforcement presence because
that didn't work for for 20 years under
prop 215 when
commercial activity was illegal and it
was a felony and so now it's a
misdemeanor and we're still expecting
we're expecting a letter offense to work
to prohibit on the illegal market from
existing in flourishing and I think
that's the wrong approach I know that in
the prop 215 days that dispensaries were
paying sales tax and I don't believe
that that ever stopped and so if the the
old BOE which is now the CDT FA is
knocking on illegal dispensaries doors
and demanding tax payment is that not
the definition of taxation without
representation and if they're painting
those taxes still currently and they're
illegal why can't we tax them more and
even the playing field it is the only
way that the legal market will ever
thrive is if we can bring these two into
alignment you know and and then let the
consumer decide you know I love to I'm
in Florida right now and I love getting
into a new area you know typically I do
this in California but I'm in Florida so
I did it here and I went to a city
council meeting two days ago where a ban
was on the agenda and I just wanted to
see like you know another state how they
were having this conversation but on I
have been asking about the illicit
market to anybody that will talk to me
here and and whether or not they
purchase in the illicit market and if
they purchase in the legal market as
well and you know the illicit market
here is is even bigger than than I had
ever dreamed because you know I talked
to one girl and she loves the
dispensaries here but even without taxes
those dispensaries are charging fifty
five dollars an eighth and the girl that
that I had asked about her purchases in
the illegal market
she said she gets hers directly from a
licensed operator out of Washington
state mails it directly to her and she
can get an ounce for $200 and so if our
legal market has their their paws all up
in the illicit market and is now going
direct to consumer across the country
like we're in trouble and so we need to
be thinking along those lines what is
the illness at market doing how are
consumers purchasing their their product
what are they getting what are they
getting it for and how can we compete
and that's that's the conversation that
has to be had that is the only way
they'll eat the legal market across the
country is ever going to thrive is if
we're actually having the honest
conversation about what a consumer is
getting for their dollar we've never had
that conversation and it boggles my mind
how we never took a consumer into the
picture Greg and I just wanna touch on
what Jackie said some things I agree
some things I don't so but as far as for
the taxes majority supermajority I'm not
gonna say all because there might
despise some people that are paying but
I could say 99% of retailers illegal
retailers here are paying zero tax sale
tax zero and I believe that the CDT FA
should go after them for tax evasion
just like any other business and just
like they did to Al Capone you cannot
you have no defense against tax evasion
and if you're not paying the state in
our government taxes and I hope you rot
in jail
that's my feelings because I pay lots of
taxes and if that's how you want to be
whether legal or illegal you you should
go to jail not for cannabis because I I
have my home you know I got charged with
triple felony in 2007 for just 55 grams
of cannabis so I really don't like
seeing anybody going to jail just
because of cannabis but if you're not
paying your taxes and you're doing other
things wrong then yeah you should and
that's an easy
ace and I don't know why they haven't
done more of that because there is no
defense for that and then as far as
legal people going direct to market in
another state I would not believe the
consumer and what she's saying because
there's so many fraudulent products out
there where they're making counterfeits
of other people and I could be an
illegal person and Washington is very an
Oregon they are probably well Washington
Oregon California we are the worst we
send so much stuff out of state it's
ridiculous and and you know anyone could
say oh yeah it's a legal product I
ordered some you know I could order brat
little I don't know about now doing Co
bid but you know I could have ordered
brassknuckles packaging in parts and
filled it up and said yeah it's brass
knuckles and send it across the country
you know a lot of brands are having
serious issues with that and getting and
that sent to the point of where you said
Jackie what is the consumer getting for
their dollar well in the illegal market
they're getting illegal products that
are not lab tested and could be severely
bad for their health especially during
the time of Ovid where we know that
people with breathing problems can are
more susceptible and can die and
pesticides you know I don't know people
don't realize pesticide is a nerve agent
and it actually lowers your white blood
cell count which makes it you know hello
you're gonna die even easier now so that
that's a very important point but that
gets into the educating and I believe we
need the state and not states all the
states that are legal to do a education
program to educate to do more to educate
the consumers like look you might be
saving a couple of bucks getting you
from the street but is your life worth
it is it worth it to risk your health
and well-being just to save a few bucks
you know and and it has to but that's
where that difference has to come in
right if it's a fifty dollar difference
where you're paying double the price the
consumer is gonna definitely risk it but
if we could get that
to be very close to where it's only a
few dollar difference then then they
probably wouldn't risk yeah well a lot
of consumers they don't even know
they're going into illegal shops I mean
we talked about it in the industry and
we can all list illegal the you know
unregulated shops around us but your
average consumer all they know is they
drove by a building with a green cross
in the window and they went and got a
great deal on product you know the BCC
sent out those QR codes for people to
scan I don't know anyone that's ever
walked in and looked for the QR code to
verify that they're an illegal shot you
know so we've got to get that
conversation outside of the industry in
to the average consumer so that they
have to know that they have the choice
of purchasing regulated or unregulated
but you know the bottom line is we've
got to simplify the amount of compliance
in this industry and we've got to
simplify taxes as a distributor I'm
playing taxman for retailers and
cultivators I'm not responsible for
taxes but I'm responsible for collecting
taxes and then remitting and that's just
that's absurd there's no other industry
where someone's paying taxes on behalf
of someone else's business I just wanted
to say something important before I
forget because and I and if you're the
only distributors notice they tax us on
the excise tax they count the excise tax
that we're collecting from the retailer
you know uh they tax that tax so it's
really not in the benefit of the
distributor to collect and remit because
we're getting on a attacks that we're
not even making money off of we're doing
a service right it's insane
yeah and then he only just the
compliance side of it as the other
reason the regulated markets really
struggling if you think about the old
days you were a cultivator you have a
few plants and you
back yard or in your basement you trim
them at your kitchen table you put them
in a backpack and you went to the
retailer you know you were it was one
set of hands touching it throughout the
process on one piece of property now
we've got you know all of the
regulations for setting up a farm
getting permitted staying compliant with
Canada you know with cultivation you've
got to have a band you've got to have
someone that knows metric on the
cultivation side someone that knows
metric on the distribution side we're
inventory the stuff twice a month so you
know we're paying that overhead then
we've got to have somebody that note you
know metric and pulling it out putting
it on another band trying to schedule to
get into retailers and with copepod
coming on retailers have limited hours
now so you know we were doing deliveries
five days a week
now most shops are taking deliveries
Tuesday Wednesday Thursday and so we're
having to put more vehicles more people
on the road to get there between ten and
four three days a week where previously
it was you know eight to six five days a
week there's there's a lot of things in
the supply chain that were already on
the brink that are getting constricted
even further and we're gonna see a next
round of extinction I think happen in
the next couple of months and you wanna
weigh in I'm sure I'm I can't really
speak to the specifics of Taxation on
distribution because that's not my role
at the company I'm in Community
Development so I do a lot of policy work
and that policy is my background and not
business so I will talk more about
policy so we did have the LA o report
that came out last year which is the
legislative analyst office that
basically looks at how the system is
working and then makes recommendations
about how they feel we can change the
regulations in order to bring what we're
seeing more in line with what the goals
of legalization were and one of the big
goals of legalization was to eliminate
the unregulated marketplace so the LA o
looks and sees how long are we doing
that we're
doing terrible at that as has already
been discussed by other panelists one
out of every four dollars spent on
cannabis is being spent in the regulated
market three out of every four dollars
spent on cannabis in California is being
spent on the unregulated market so
obviously there's a huge disconnect as
was mentioned part of this issue is that
we had a very robust gray market for 20
years to the point where in many ways it
mimicked what the regulated market ended
up looking like so unlike other states
even states that had medical prior to
Biegel ization which they all did they
didn't have these gray market scenarios
even Colorado had a very regulated
medical cannabis program when they
legalized so they already had a
licensing structure in place they were
licensing the entire supply chain folks
may forget prior to legalization the
only people of the state that had a
license to do anything were a handful of
dispensaries and even they risked
federal interference and we're skating
shut down so it was really not a stable
environment for anyone you know now
we're trying to bring some stability
into it and I think with that we're
constricting it so what the LA OS office
recommended was that we eliminate the
cultivation tax so that's something that
absolutely impacts the folks that we
work with no other crop has a separate
tax associated with just the fact that
you're growing the crop so that's a huge
issue the second issue is the way that
tax is collected so the cultivation tax
as was mentioned is collected by the
distributor but we have to collect that
before we have any idea how that product
is gonna perform in the marketplace so
individuals are paying cultivation tax
based on weight prior to the product
actually getting into the marketplace to
where we know whether that's gonna sell
well whether it's not gonna sell well
and that is completely unpredictable
right now as to you know what's gonna go
on dispensary shelves what's gonna sell
what's not gonna sell so it makes it
really difficult especially for smaller
cultivators to be able to have any kind
of assurance of their economics and how
things are gonna work and how much they
need to grow in order to pay the tax in
order to sell this much it just doesn't
make sense so I think eliminating the
cultivation tax is a really good first
step and then the second issue is about
the excise tax
so excise tax is sin tax
it's attacks that we put on products
that we think are gonna cause some kind
of public health or safety harm to the
community and we feel that that tax
money is there in order to make up for
that so for example tobacco tax alcohol
tax the idea is that if you drink for 50
years and end up in the hospital with
cirrhosis of the liver and the society
has to pay for those medical bills that
that's supported by the excise tax that
people pay on alcohol so of course when
we were legalizing cannabis there was a
lot of comparisons being made to alcohol
and unlike alcohol prohibition when it
ended it hadn't been that long since
we'd had legal alcohol so people getting
back into legal alcohol after alcohol
prohibition wasn't as jarring with
cannabis we've had you know decades and
decades and decades of prohibition so
when we came and said all right now it's
time to legalize folks were like well
you got to have a syntax because
legalization is gonna cause all of this
harm health harm and safety harm and bus
drivers are gonna be smoking weed and
your pilot's gonna be smoking weed and
your teenagers gonna be smoking weed and
we need a hefty excise tax to make sure
that society doesn't end up footing the
bill for all of these harms of course
those of us who study cannabis knew that
was all bullshit and we knew there
weren't gonna be these harms that we see
with other substances but that was the
thinking of folks who were making the
rules I mean they felt cannabis needed
an excise tax so last thing I'll say so
here we are with this excise tax the
excise tax is being levied on the
consumer the consumer that is currently
spending three out of four dollars in
the unregulated marketplace now the
theory is that if you reduce taxes you
make less revenue and that has been one
of the reasons that the state has been
very reticent to touch the excise tax
especially right now given that we've
pushed back tax filing in California
till July so they're like we don't even
know how much money we're gonna have how
are we gonna cut excise tax so we don't
even know how much money we're gonna
have but see here's the rub and this is
because we have this unregulated
marketplace cutting excise tax may
reduce temporarily and in a very
specific way the amount of tax that
dispensaries were met because of that
sighs amount however what it also does
is have people buy more product because
it's cheaper and they're paying less for
it people are going into regulated
stores instead of unregulated stores
because the price differential is more
similar so in the end you actually end
up making more money if you just reduce
that tax and bring more people into the
regulated marketplace so I think from a
taxation perspective what we're really
advocating for is the elimination of the
cultivation tax and a hefty reduction of
the excise tax at least for the next few
years and then the other whole side of
this is the fact that consumers don't
have a lot of money right now and so
that's pushing them even more into the
unregulated market which is even bigger
reason for us to reduce the excise tax
because on top of all the other public
safety issues we had a volley and I know
that like that's all old news and people
are like oh Holly what's that but that's
the vaping illness right and so we know
that a lot of those situations are tied
to people buying unregulated products so
now that we have this lung illness of
COBIT going through the country are we
really gonna keep prices so high in the
regulated marketplace of an essential
business that we're pushing people to
buy unregulated vape carts which is just
gonna increase the likelihood of lung
disease you know and people listen to
this or like that makes no sense
and this is what the impact of
propaganda is this is the impact of 50
years of trying to convince people that
cannabis is evil that people that use
cannabis are evil because this is what
it does it makes people completely
reject logic it makes them not think
about business models it makes them
react to how they feel so one of the
things we should be doing as an industry
really is going back to our activism
days when we were really really good at
changing hearts and minds and we were
really really good at making people feel
a certain way about our mission and I
feel like we've gotten away from that a
little bit because we're trying to go
about it legitimately and we're trying
to lobby our legislators and we're
trying to form these relationships but
we're not going into city council
meetings anymore we're not going and
talking about the fact that it's 75
miles to a license
sensory and how is grandma gonna get her
meds like you don't talk about that
anymore and I feel like it's done us a
disservice in moving things forward as
an industry so just quickly
Nicole Elliott just joined the
conversation a coal we will gently ease
you in so just listen for a minute and
then you can get up to speed
Amanda I love everything you were just
talking about in 2015 at the state of
marijuana
we had pony Olivera an economist speak
and he was talking all about you know
price like when you have a comparable
product which is the traditional market
product you can only tax people so much
before you know it's basic economics and
I thought from my perspective you know
common sense would prevail when you have
a competing product and obviously it
didn't so I'm gonna send everybody that
link because I think it's like you know
everything he was talking about in 2015
of what not to do has since happened and
you know he could do a mic drop with the
cultivation tax which I think every
grower would agree with you which eight
just out of curiosity like which
agencies or who in the government do you
approach to say hey this is crazy like
which eight like is it Richard parrot
the CDFA is it Newsom's office as a who
do you talk to and start that kind of
press well I think a lot of it is
thinking about where your options lie at
any given moment so if there's a vehicle
that is in the legislature to do some of
these things it's really about
supporting that vehicle this past year
we had a B 1948 that was introduced by
Assemblymember Bonta that would have
eliminated the cultivation tax and
reduced the excise tax that made it to
the finance and tax committee
unfortunately it's not going to make it
out of that committee this session
primarily just because of what's
happening with Kovac however the button
Nicole can definitely speak more to this
but you know we're gonna have the
governor's trailer bill on and budget
which are going to be coming out here
a little bit later in the summer and so
there's a lot of opportunity to think
about what we need to do for this
industry to help us get through these
next few years and I think that there
are some some sweeping steps that we're
gonna need to take to make sure that
this industry stays afloat and this
isn't just for the sake of us you know I
think that you're right but the industry
sometimes sounds like we're like big
tobacco coming and asking for corporate
tax breaks and I understand that which
is why I'm like let's start getting the
public back involved and get them to
start talking about this as well but I
think for the state of California I
can't imagine not a I can't imagine a
world where having a struggling cannabis
industry is helpful to the economic
recovery of the state of California post
kovat I cannot imagine a scenario where
we are not looking to the cannabis
industry to be robust and to be and
fulfill its promise and fulfill what it
can be when the state so badly needs new
jobs when the state so badly needs
opportunities for people who have been
displaced from other industries you know
it really is a time for us to come
together and kind of get over the fact
that it's cannabis and start talking
about it as an economic driver which is
honestly what it's always been
even when it was illegal and you know we
can talk about the illegal economy and
how much that has supported California
over the years because it absolutely has
and now we have the opportunity to bring
that industry above board and to allow
it to really shine I mean to really come
into its own and we just need folks to
get out of our way what the analogy I
like to use is that you know if cannabis
is a lifeboat and we're telling the
state of California look we can bring
some folks into this lifeboat you don't
have to shoulder this alone but this
lifeboat is full of holes and it's not
seaworthy and we can barely use it to
sustain ourselves help us patch this
boat and we will bring people into it
and so that is what I'm really looking
for is a way for the cannabis industry
to be what it needs to be for the state
of
California so they call let me cue you
up a thriving industry generates lots of
jobs and taxes currently the cannabis
industry is has a whole bunch of
diseases and is very sick so can you
talk about kind of what the governor's
office is thinking as it looks at this
sick patient and how to get it healthy
and contributing economically and
financially to these state the great
state of California apologies I'm sort
of in and out of this conversation
because I'm working on a couple of other
thing have this hold on my calendar but
I believe the question was really about
mechanisms for health is that what you
was that what you asked health of the
industry yeah I mean basically every
operator there is not a single licensed
operator who would disagree with you
statement you know they're over it's
they're basically trying to be
businesses with two hands tied behind
their backs as compared to any other
industry California cannabis is not a
poster child for success so from the
governor's perspective do you do you see
that and where's your where's the
governor's offices head at in terms of
hat how do we fix this problem because
so I think it goes without saying that
the governor recognizes the challenges
of the industry that's something that he
talked a lot about last year we
collectively talked a lot about just I
think that you know to sort of gut check
this conversation of course nobody saw a
pandemic hit this state of California
the nation the world the in the way that
you know we are now experiencing that
and so that sort of turned many things
not sort of it has turned many things
upside down
and you've seen this state really expend
an exceptional amount of resources in
trying to preserve people's lives and in
that in that effort obviously there was
a you know there was a lot of thought
given to what businesses would remain
open and what businesses wouldn't in the
governor as you guys clearly know is
essential in that effort when we talk
about what lies ahead and what can be
done for the industry I want to make
sure that we're doing it in the context
of the here and now and that is a
challenge economic time for everyone in
the state including businesses that were
not deemed essential and so we as a
state are gonna have a challenging
economic forecast and we need to keep
that in mind
when we talk about what resources the
state can expend so I think you know it
is important to contemplate changes that
can be made absent those resources so
thinking about those administrative
changes that can be made I mean perhaps
even statutory changes knowing what
we're up against in the legislature as
far as the legislature having bandwidth
to take up anything non-coated related
at this time so that's a long-winded way
of saying you know we're sort of seeing
where where everything the dust settles
and trying to figure out how to best
proceed knowing that our objective has
been and will continue to be to ease the
burdens on the industry whether that be
regulatory administrative or financial
where possible but that has to be
couched in the context of these times
Nicole this is a this is Adam Spiker how
you doing good how are you Adam lovely
doing lovely just enjoying life here in
Southern California I totally appreciate
everything you're saying and it
as you know you and I've talked before I
think the legal industry has complete
sympathy and respect for what the
priorities have to be for the
administration given koban 19 and and
what we're dealing with you know what I
would say to you is in you know we've
talked about it you know privately but
what we're trying to do is just present
you know a fix or two for the industry
that is now two and a half years in and
and just frankly getting its ass kicked
by the illicit market and I know you
mentioned obviously the budget and and
other you know other panelists talked
about it and you know more candidly
before you joined but obviously the
budgets in is in peril no one knows what
that budgets gonna look like and no one
knows when the you know we don't know if
the Trump administration is gonna gonna
help relieve the state of California
it's local governments all that aside I
do think that there is an argument to
make that the legal industry has now two
and a half years in not had a chance to
compete and we also believe in you know
the Elio report got brought up earlier
I think there's faults in that report I
wish there was time to refute them we've
tried to refute it I don't think they
show their work very well for others
outside of it to be able to take that
work and try to refute it especially as
it relates to the illicit market and
trying to offset tax reductions not
simplification or restructuring but
offset tax relief by capturing more of
the illicit market into the regulating
realm I I would assume you agree with
that I know it's a challenge in this
environment but I'd be remiss if I
didn't bring it up is just something
that you know if we were gonna pick one
or two things that are a priority for an
industry where all these industries and
all these residents and constituents are
coming to the governor's office in the
administration saying we need help if we
could focus on one or two things for the
kegel cannabis it would have to start
there and I think the stories on our
side
I don't mean as far as responding to
that I think what I'm hearing you say is
as an industry of the industry where to
have to pick one or two things to focus
on this year enforcement should be top
of that is that accurate
I think it's taxes I think it's the car
let me let me broaden that and certainly
allow others to chime in it's at the end
point it becomes the price point for the
illegal the illegal market versus the
legal market so right now it's about
double and Greg can chime in and others
you know that are operators you know if
we restructure taxes or simplify them
but the end result is that a consumer
especially in a world where unemployment
I think in the states about four million
and you know nationally thirty million
they're gonna be more price conscious if
at the end of the day legal cannabis you
know is double the price just to make
ends meet of the illicit they don't have
a chance so I think it's I think it's
the economic argument but I want to make
clear to you that we're sympathetic of
understanding that the governor's got a
lot on his plate and certainly the
administration and the legislature has a
lot on their plate we also believe that
we there's 80% of the of the demand for
cannabis in the state there to be
captured by the state and local
governments and regulated means we just
needed to be more competitive in order
to start capturing more of it and you
know just to reiterate everything that
Adam said it's absolutely true I mean we
are I just had another illegal store
open up a thousand feet from me and so
enforcement it enforcement is never
truly gonna work and you're never gonna
really get rid of all the illegals
especially in a big city where
everything's so congested and law
enforcement already has their hands full
with because gangs and narcotics are the
ones that
doing the investigations and raids and
like we had discussed earlier now
they're doing investigations and trying
to do raids on people that is it's not
even a felony now selling illegal
cannabis so I believe the only way is
going to be through reducing the taxes
so that we can be competitive with the
illicit market and that way the consumer
and it doesn't have to be lower than the
illicit market or even equal if it's
just to the point where it's only a
couple of dollars or a few dollars more
expensive we can start also education
program where it starts educating the
consumer that hey yeah maybe the illicit
market is only a couple dollars more now
since we lower the taxes but is your
health worth of paying a couple of
dollars less to buy illegal products
that are not lab tested so it's two
things right you've got you got to lower
the taxes and you have to do an
education program like we see all those
commercials on TV for the vaping and
tobacco hey don't buy illegal cannabis
by legal cannabis because it's not gonna
kill you
and it's not going to have pesticides in
it that's all
I want to add one dynamic in here if I
could as a consumer and a patient who
increasingly sees the industry from that
perspective almost actually now
universally I I wonder how the powers
that be are they cognizant of the you
know the amount of anger there is at
being charged user e tax rates as a
consumer a lot of these taxes rolled
downhill right on to us and I'm you know
I'd be interested to get a perspective
from retailers they're people who are
public facing what they're hearing what
they've dealt with because it's
unacceptable I have I've had no qualms
over the years of telling legislators my
since I'm just one person so I you know
III be interested in you know people's
thoughts on that dynamic because I think
it's real Tom you're absolutely correct
you know the retailer's being in the you
know the tip of the spear if you want to
call it you know we get we get bashed
for everything you know the the
consumers love two batches that like the
taxes are our fault somehow so it is
actually it's absolutely correct they
are upset and they have no problem
letting us retailers know that they're
upset and usually my answer is please
call your legislator and let them know
because it's out of our control but they
are absolutely furious and you know
we've been told well this is why I'm
never gonna stop at the illegal play a
legal place I'm gonna go up the street
to the illegal place and they literally
tell me where they're going because they
think nothing's gonna happen that person
and it's all a joke enforcement is a
joke and our taxes and our high prices
are a joke and you probably have more
like sixty seventy percent of the market
buying from illegal market not from the
legal market item I want to add
something that's not kind of a little
a bit of a different take on you know
other wastes from the consumers
perspective because Tom I really agree
with you in Nepal hi is Amanda Ryman
from uh so kana so you know I when I
first started doing research on medical
cannabis dispensaries it was 2005 and I
did a study on how dispensaries were
operating as community health service
providers and that was really because as
folks who have been doing this for a
while know you know in San Francisco
coming out of the AIDS crisis was really
when you saw these dispensaries start to
proliferate and you saw people providing
community services in addition to
cannabis in these dispensaries and so it
wasn't just about buying weed right it
was about taking yoga and working in the
garden and having access to Internet and
having access to pure support and
counseling Americans for safe access
used to come in and do pure counseling
you know we had lawyers that would come
in and give free legal advice and so I
think all this is to say that you know
kind of like taking a full-spectrum
plant and then distilling it into THC
we've taken this beautiful cultural
experience of interacting with cannabis
and distilled it to Walgreens and I
think that that has really disadvantaged
the consumer not just because of the
taxes but because of the education and
knowledge and community that they used
to get from that experience so all this
is to say is that we need alternative
models of retail we need to start
opening up the idea of what it means to
get cannabis and start offering other
pathways to that besides just
dispensaries so you know we need farmers
markets we need direct to consumer sales
from the farmer we need more
opportunities for subscription boxes and
mail order you know we need more
opportunities for people to grow and
process their own cannabis at their own
homes so we need to look at where
they're not allowed to do that and why
because that's definitely the most
economical way to consume cannabis is to
grow it yourself so I think that you
know we get focused a lot on what the
current model is and how we tweak those
taxes
those models but I also think we need to
be really thinking outside the box which
is a term that I think is way overused
but thinking back to those days of the
community model of cannabis retail and
you know we sound like we saw a huge
amount of social problems as a result of
the fact that it was super easy for
people to go into dispensaries and get
cannabis you know we aren't we weren't
trying to solve for a public health
crisis around cannabis access we never
have and we won't unless we keep pushing
people into unregulated marketplaces and
then we will absolutely have a public
health crisis around cannabis booky
Valley which we had before kovat so you
know it's just such a vulnerable time
for medical cannabis patients many of
them are immunocompromised anyway so the
the idea that they don't have the access
that they need that they have to go
through this one very specific model of
retail that may not speak to their needs
I think is also a big threat to the
industry because I you know those
individuals are gonna still need their
cannabis and they're gonna get it from
the place that they feel is safest and
is most economical to their needs
they're not naive these aren't new
consumers and so we really have to meet
them where they're at I just want to say
Amanda that I appreciate those comments
I appreciate sort of I really appreciate
the approach that you're coming at it
you even though you hate the term
thinking outside the box I think that's
really what's necessary right now we all
really need to get creative and how we
approach addressing things like
financial burdens and enforcement
because you're absolutely right
you know tweaking the existing model is
one way of getting at it but it's not
the only way and we should really be
maximizing you know which avenues were
pursuing so thank you
[Music]
you know I just want to comment that I
think the I have a lot of respect for
the argument the health argument by
legal buy healthier but I think it may
not have as much traction as it would
otherwise precisely because so many of
us do come out of the gray or
traditional market and have years of
experience there we were we all come out
of it we've all work work were our
children of the of the traditional
market and we weren't you know really
suffering horrible health consequences
as a result plus it's you know people
there might indeed be more receptive to
individual needs you might know more
what you're getting then a CPG packaged
in a retail store where you're donating
exactly sure despite the fact that it
has its CEO a and I just think that
those are subtle dynamics that are very
real with people and that cannabis is a
very personal personalized
individualized experience for so many
people and they don't necessarily have
that that that fear of traversing the
traditional market and I'm back I don't
think that dynamic is necessarily true
for new people coming in but who don't
know but I think that might be one of
the you know one of the problems with
that with that as argument well I think
we also have to remember that just like
every substance the majority of the
substance is consumed by a small
percentage of the consumer so you know
when we talk about the people that are
buying the most cannabis that are really
making up the most of the marketplace
it's a very small percentage of people
and so if that's if those are the people
that we need to get into the regulated
marketplace it's not the purse
and that's buying cannabis once a year
or you know for a special occasion
because they are gonna go to the
regulated marketplace it's the person
that is using cannabis regularly for
medicinal purposes that's you know
purchasing a larger amount that's the
person we need to bring in and that's
also the person that's most likely going
to go into the unregulated marketplace
both because of economics and because of
comfort with that marketplace knew their
growers and we're working with them and
you know we had 20 years of that and we
had 20 years of access to safe products
I've got a file folder in my home office
with lab reports from 2012 because we
were testing before we delivered
anything to a dispensary you know so
there were those mechanisms in place for
the dispensaries who were enforcing that
and were only selling lab tested
products and they thrived and they did
well under prop 215 well because the
consumers drove that I mean and that's
something that you know consume a
cannabis consumers you know as were
saying their relationship with the plant
is so personal and so intense that they
really do think a lot about what they
want to put in their bodies and they
were demanding that dispensaries give
them more information and you know I
started working at Berkeley patients
group in 2010 and worked there till 2012
and we started to sell product that was
tested because patients were coming in
and saying I need to know what's in this
and you know I saw in the evolution from
like 2005 to 2012 edibles go from like
just cellophane wrapped brownies with no
label like a bake sale to people
actually trying to tell you how much THC
was in it and this was because the state
was making us do that there were no
rules around it it was because consumers
were saying this is something that I
need to make sure that I'm dosing myself
accurately and so I really believe that
if we opened up more farm direct sales
where farmers could sell directly to
consumers we would capture a lot of
those regular consumers those that are
that are consuming most of the cannabis
because we're giving them a way to
connect personally with the product
again in the farmer and that's
definitely something we lost you know
with although the packaging which I get
I totally understand why we have it but
you know walking into a dispensary and
smelling like everything that they had
behind the case and being able to choose
you know being able to have that more of
that relationship with the farmer I
think that's what that specific
population of heavier consumers is
looking for they're not looking for like
super low dose really pretty packaging
CBD treats you know they want to tow and
talk to the guy that grew their cannabis
for like 40 minutes about genetics and
there there isn't that outlet for those
folks anymore like you know the area 101
you know old school Emerald cup types
advantage mm-hmm yeah as you were
talking I was actually writing down
farmers markets and they talked about it
I mean I think for every farmer who
grows quality product and as a smart
intelligent person that would be a
lifeline lifeline survival because
they're small they don't need to clear a
lot of product in December at a like
Emerald you know the NorCal farmers who
would come down to the Emerald Exchange
in December with their recent harvest
proudly sharing it with the SoCal market
and educating them on sun-grown cannabis
they don't need to sell a lot to clear
out their inventory and be able to move
on to thinking about the next season and
right now they're at the mercy of the
distribution networks and the retailers
convincing consumers in LA that this
tiny brand is worth your time this is
also a great and I just want to touch on
something because one thing that was
mentioned also is the experience right
and that is something that the
dispensaries were robbed of is that
experience and being able to provide
that experience where you show the
product
you smell it you actually get to see it
being laid out in front of you you know
that holistic approach that we had
coming out of the medical we have lost
that and that has also affected us
against the illicit market because they
still are doing it that way if they do
it but with us it's now it's no longer
personable that that engagement that
relationship with the consumer you know
it's become more cold you know and we do
different things to try to change that
but it becomes it becomes very difficult
because you know everything's
prepackaged and the consumer even though
in their mind yeah I see your little
sample I'm staring at it but I still
really don't know until I get home when
I open that package what I'm really
getting and so that in a way has also
affected the legal retailers because
that experience that we had broad kind
of like a farmers market where you go
you look at the fruits and vegetables
everything it's gone you know and and we
still have a whole bunch of vendors that
would show up on our appreciation days
once a month and they would all have
their products and they would all set up
different tables like our own little
mini farmers market and that experience
is gone as well
yeah and now when they show up well now
they don't show up because it ovid
nobody's going but when they used to it
became oh here's a hat or a t-shirt you
know and I could talk to you about the
product but I have nothing to show you
you know and so it it really changed the
whole dynamic of what we had gotten used
to for over two decades you know and and
I think that is a very very good point
so just quickly cuz nicole has to jump
off for a meeting
Nicola thank you for being such a good
sport she had no idea that I was gonna
send her a link to join this call joined
it
so let's encourage her to do it again
Nicole I sent you that link to the 2015
Economist talking about price elasticity
and
economics you know I hope this state
views cannabis like Walmart and Costco
view profits which is if there is a lot
if we do low margins which for the state
would be low taxes and high-volume we
will make more money than high margin
and low volume and all these small
operators going extinct and not being
able to hire people and job losses and
things like that
so anyway that's my two cents on how I
would hope the state approaches taxes
thank you thank you guys for having me I
appreciate it thanks thank you guys all
right
Tom our most I actually have a question
for I have a question do the people here
think that generally speaking the state
needs more legal shops I think in
certain areas they do yeah I think they
do I mean they're just because there's
so many areas that have banned I mean
it's not necessarily like are we adding
more in some places it's like are we
adding any and you know I think that the
state really should take this up and you
know this was something that we had
cloak on ahead put into our
recommendations for legislation but we
know that you know with because of the
budget and cost but this idea of market
expansion and the state really getting
involved in helping localities pass
commercial cultivation ordinances and
cannabis ordinances when maybe before
they've been reticent because they
thought it was gonna be too hard or they
didn't have but they didn't know what to
do and you know so I think that if the
state can really start encouraging
localities to pass ordinances and maybe
major owner ate a model ordinance or be
willing to give them some support then
we'll start to see some of these
cannabis deserts change and I think now
it's time to strike while the iron is
hot because these localities are going
to be looking for job creation they're
gonna be looking for sources of revenue
post kovat you know we hear countries
all over the world now talking about
legalizing cannabis as economic recovery
functions so I do think it's time and
could start with localities and I always
like to pick on Marin let's start with
Marin that voted overwhelmingly for Prop
64 but has banned commercial cannabis
activity and you know there's so much
NIMBYism let's start there and let's
really put pressure on them to open it
up so quick quick adding to this dist
sixty-four need to be a man you to do
this did it not codify the patchwork
nature in this state mmm so how do we
get how do we get it definitely includes
local control and in order to change
that that's all about the League of
Cities so the League of Cities you know
local control has been there sticking
point for Oh 20 years League of Cities
long-term Friends of the cannabis
industry yes long term cannabis industry
you know so local control was in the
medical legislation that was passed in
2015 and it was actually stricter than
it was in prop 64 we actually wanted to
get rid of local control and prop 64 the
compromise was to make it a little bit
less onerous than it was in the medical
regs but to still keep it in there we
have met with the League of Cities we've
taken their temperature on this they
have had some leadership change it has
been good leadership change but that's
really who we have to have come to the
table to really do anything to eliminate
local control so absent of that I think
we need to make it as easy as possible
like turnkey local regulation so that
localities can just turn it on or
localities can pass an ordinance that
says if a business applies for a state
license and meets all those requirements
we will give them local authorization
like we don't have to pass a local
ordinance but if someone's ready to go
and they meet all the requirements we
will grant them authorization which is
what the state's looking for in order to
grant their licensure so I think that
there's some ways that we can wiggle
around it but until we really engage
these localities adding another 500
dispensaries in San Francisco or another
thousand dispensaries in LA is gonna
help some things but it's not gonna help
a person that's in a cannabis desert
unless we have mail order then that
would help them
so who was we yeah go ahead more retail
I think we're at something like eleven
hundred and fifty when you count
storefront retail delivery and micro
business with retail or somewhere around
there
for forty million people in a you know
incredibly big vast state so you know
that what we need to figure out how to
incentivize locale local municipalities
and you know in the beginning it was
well you're not gonna get any
enforcement dollars unless you regulate
retail and cultivation and that doesn't
seem to have worked so maybe we have to
you know up to that amount that that
jurisdictions are getting and then shine
a big spotlight on it and say look who's
getting the tax dollars over here but
you know Los Angeles is very interesting
and it's the consumer cannabis consumer
capital of the world I believe there's
more consumers per capita than in any
other jurisdiction and if we could get
LA you know to at least be moving in a
positive direction it could turn the
entire industry so I know that you know
there's been a lot of drama over the
first 100 equity permits that have been
issued and a compromise to the 700 that
are you know and technically all 800 are
sitting on the sidelines waiting for the
city to figure out what they're gonna do
but the the compromise right now that is
being discussed in in articles and in in
the community is that the 700 that did
not receive that first permit would
qualify immediately for either
manufacturing distribution or delivery
now if we were to turn on 700 delivery
licenses you know this year that that's
a game-changer and that could be the
number one way to try and compete with
the illicit market it could be the one
thing that could change the fact that
that la needs enforcement it could be
that we instead of enforcing you know
offer a way to compete and if that was
if that was coupled with some sort of
equity easement of local taxes then that
could possibly spur you know other
jurisdictions to kind of follow suit
maybe making delivery and
over-the-counter permit like like
someone else just said before me making
sure that that that delivery license is
compatible with with all the state
requirements and then just giving them
an over-the-counter permit locally you
know that that could change everything
and since we are an essential business
you know I'm really hoping that we see
some big win for for the cannabis
industry that that comes out of this
crisis I'm gonna tu oh so just quickly I
mean when Jackie mentions delivery it's
almost as if we're aspiring to act like
every other type of product like we all
order stuff from Amazon I think Co bid
is kind of putting delivering the
spotlight in a positive way so Greg can
you talk about your are you doing any
delivery or do you have aspirations or
what's your delivery route is your going
forward we are and we actually started
pretty much with our delivery so like I
had said earlier like I'm licensed and
phase one since the beginning our stores
been around since five micro-business I
have three phase two licenses
cultivation manufacturing distribution
and we got one of the 100 phase 3 social
equity licenses as well so I mean
ability I do not believe that having 700
delivery licenses come online will help
anything at all l I'm doing delivery the
max I get is 20 to 30 I don't even know
how the next 100 social equity licenses
which the audit was complete
and found that it's good to go so we are
gonna be moving forward with the issuing
licenses for the 100 we did get that
email so that's a done deal there is no
more argument there and so but the thing
is is I feel the hundred social equity
licenses that are coming online they're
gonna fail first of all they don't have
the contacts well unless they're
partnered with somebody like myself
who's experienced in hella who has the
contacts and connections a lot of
manufacturers and distributors and Flo
Connor couldn't attest to this they
don't have too much product left for new
retailers I go on the website of Flo
kana and it's almost always sold out of
a lot of stuff and that they're not the
only ones there's a lot of distributors
that are already at their max capacity
with the retailers that they already
work with so a lot of these new
businesses coming online who have zero
reputation zero contacts with or n
relationships with vendors good luck
getting anything on consignment and that
goes to the point that Jackie had made
in the very beginning where eight
people's AR books are out of control
because people aren't paying so they're
already too paranoid to do anymore
consignment because they've already had
that taste and it doesn't taste it right
and and and so you're gonna have a lot
of businesses coming online and Bailey
and my thing has always been is I don't
want to set up anybody for failure I
want to set them up for success and if
it takes a little longer to do that then
let it take a little longer let's do it
right but to rush into and jump into and
just do licensing and then and then what
what did we miss all what did we really
achieve other than having these people
who are just thrown into a situation
they don't know anything about metric I
pay my metric compliance officer 6,000 a
month
how are these social equity people gonna
afford that good luck and then metric
the amount of times it goes offline and
then you can't even get product onto the
floor because you have to wait
hours and hours until it comes back
online you know if there is so many
intricacies and nuances that really have
to be you have to create a social equity
education and mentorship program for
success or else you could get hand-up
thousands of licenses and they're all
gonna fail
okay we expand about a metric a little
bit here others my fear is that metric
is an auditing the tsunami waiting to
happen for a lot of people can people
just kind of weigh in on their
perspectives and their experiences with
metric I could wait to somebody I mean
the mining stop my experience has been
insane be as a retailer we deal with a
lot more like on the distribution side
it's easy we only have a handful of line
items but on the retail side we have
over two thousand line items and then we
get one order in from a one distributor
and you have 60 different COAS you have
to enter all of those in and it's it's
it's really a mess like before we would
get a product in medical days you get
the product and you pay for it you get
the bag you can just throw the bag on
the shelf and start selling it now we're
like oh we hope to be able to get it on
the shelf on the same day and we hope
that metric is online you know so it's a
huge problem and it's a huge bottleneck
for the entire industry you know as a
distributor trying to get samples out to
retailers we've got you know 25 30 SKUs
that means someone has to go and
individually tag single items 25 30 per
retailer we want to send a package out
to yeah and what's the benefit are we
keeping children safer by having 30
metric tags go out on samples you know
there's got to be a wet better way to
handle some of that it should not take
my fulfillment manager two hours to put
together a sample
then have to put it in a ban and you
know it cost us three four five hundred
dollars to get samples out to a retailer
now speaking to Shannon's point about
the samples yeah we were experiencing
the same thing so we worked to get a
bill introduced trade samples bill that
would allow distributors to give samples
to retailers without having to go
through all of that craziness and and
designate certain product as sample not
for resale and so that is again you know
one of those things where it was like oh
this seems like an easy fix no one's
really gonna have a problem with this
and then it gets stuck right now it's
stuck because of Kovan for some
immediate relief and the supply chain
that you know if it buys us five ten
hours 20 hours a week and labor costs
like that's the difference between some
people surviving absolutely and I think
that you know and you know Nicole's not
on anymore but I think part of the
frustration I think that the end that I
feel coming from the industry is that
the super controversial things like
eliminating taxes and the super not
controversial things like allowing
distributors to designate samples seem
to have the same hold up like they do
it's not like I don't have confidence
that giving them something that's
completely budget neutral totally in the
context of covent everything they say
they want that anything's gonna happen
because I feel like we're putting forth
all kinds of ideas and all kinds of
suggestions and regulatory fixes from
the very very big and profound to the
very very small and everything is
getting stopped and so that makes it
really difficult and to be honest
sometimes the industry is its own worst
enemy and you know we have to understand
what incrementalism is and that not
everything is going to be a vehicle for
everyone so if we submit something
allowing distributors to give samples to
retailers you know there may be parts of
the supply chain that are
included in that but this is a
low-hanging fruit like let's get this
show that it's benefiting us and then we
can go back and say look it benefited
the distributor so much let's have it
benefit the cultivators let's have it
benefit the manufacturers but the
problem is is that folks are so afraid
of what's happening which I totally
understand that they don't want to get
left behind and so they feel this need
to be included and involved in every
step of the way when sometimes that's
what's holding us back because we and
then appear to legislators to not know
what we want that they're not gonna be
able to make us happy that whatever they
do is gonna be the wrong thing and
that's not the kind of situation you
want to put legislators in you want them
to think that they're gonna sign this
and everyone's in a clap for them and
give them a pat on the back and I just
don't think the industry's given them
one of those situations except taxes you
know eliminating the cultivation tax
would be the easiest thing in the world
for them to do and not get the pushback
and let it be a sign of good faith that
they really do want this industry to
succeed yeah and you know one thing
about the cultivation tax that I when we
were speaking about that that I don't
think was mentioned earlier is you know
they they tax US per clone you know for
every clone we make we get taxed and I
don't know any and you know they keep
talking about how we're like agriculture
you know but I don't I don't go to a
nursery and I don't see the nursery guy
making clones of his succulents getting
charged her succulent attacks you know
can you imagine if you did that all hell
would break loose what do you mean I
gotta pay every time I make a clone off
of my plants or you know it's ridiculous
it's that that it's the most asinine
thing I've ever heard that we have to be
every time I make a clone off of my own
plant I have to pay a tax
it's insane well part of that issue is
because cannabis in California is
considered an agricultural product and
not agriculture so even when that clone
is can stack load is considered a
product and products are taxed like wine
is an agricultural product and it's
taxed though grapes are a taxed
but the product is and so the problem is
that we don't have a designation for
cannabis and it's raw plant for him to
just be agriculture and if we did it was
just agriculture then we wouldn't be
applying the taxes to it now of course
well one of the rubs right is that one
of the things we're finding that's a big
pain in the ass about the industry is
the multiple agencies that are involved
in the duplication of things that you
have to do for your you know compliance
for this agency in this agency so one of
the recommendations that was made that
the governor's office is considering is
consolidation and bringing all of the
cannabis activities under the Bureau of
cannabis control now this is a
double-edged sword because on the one
hand yeah it'd be great to just have one
agency's rule that you had to follow
instead of sometimes conflicting rules
coming from two agencies but on the
other hand it takes cannabis out of CDFA
so there's a concern that that is gonna
separate cannabis from agriculture even
further if the plant is no longer
regulated by the department of food and
a good soul
industry we really have to think about
what we want cannabis to look like ten
years from now and work towards that so
if we want it to be an agricultural crop
with farmers markets and interstate
commerce and being treated like the wine
industry of California we should set our
sights on that and I really do think
that's a good model even though I don't
like to compare cannabis to alcohol as
an industry the California wine industry
really does make a lot of sense in terms
of the Appalachians and the branding and
the tourism and everything that comes
along with that for them to aspire to
have their California cannabis be right
alongside with that California wine and
we had during non kovat times we have
thousands of buses a day going from cal
francisco to wine country and the state
makes a ton of money on that the the
industries make a ton of money on that
so why shouldn't we have thousands of
buses leaving San Francisco every day to
come to the Emerald triangle you know
again I go back to those missed
opportunities you know because we still
think we're don't want to encourage
cannabis use and that's really getting
in the way
letting this industry flourish in the
way that it should and you know I just
want to get to that point because you
said the taking of the buses to wine
country which is something else that as
cultivators and even manufacturers we're
not allowed to do we can't do cannabis
the cannabis tourism we can't have
someone come and give them a tour the
facility and then later on go and
purchase products from the retailer that
it we're not allowed to do that even
though my other property that's how we
set it up with the grow the
manufacturing distro and the retail all
there on the same property they're not
going to allow us to do that and that's
a big hit like you said because that's a
lot of money in the cat into tourism
I have a question um do you guys think
that the that the it California says the
California industry is on the same page
about what it wants to look like in ten
years now yeah I just want to add on
that you know I it's the industry is in
a patchwork too and I have a note here
perception of of wealth and I think that
depending on who you're talking to their
perception of the industry is is is
unique to them I I've done this a lot
talk to people down in LA retailers
where's all the money and they go the
growers up nor if you talk to growers up
north where's all the money and they
point fingers down to retailers and
they're like two separate entities also
there is myriad number of trade groups
throughout the state I've never seen in
industry with so many trade groups that
pop up out of necessity in geographic
areas representing a swath of different
businesses rather than setting up trade
groups that represent you know specific
areas of business which might make more
sense
I'm not criticizing it I'm just it just
seems to be really piecemeal and arrests
p for disparate voices and so then who
is the state listening to and you know
how how do we how do we get on the same
page
well I think the reason that the
organizational situation is what it is
is just because of the growth so you
know when before we were in industry it
was like the consumers and then the
people that were providing to the
consumers and those were two groups and
they were represented by like normal and
Americans for safe access on the
consumer side and then on the people
serving the consumer side you had you
know like Marijuana Policy Project and
drug policy Alliance because they
weren't businesses yet so the people
representing the the industry were
really representing the criminal justice
piece of that and the policy piece of
that we're much bigger now and so you
know the example that I'll give it I'm
curious to hear what Jackie has to say
about this because I know that she does
a lot of work with organizations and
things a lot about realization of
politics well a few years ago I was
invited to speak at the alcohol
distributors conference and they have a
huge conference just for alcohol
distributors and they have another huge
conference just for alcohol retailers
and they have another huge conference
just for the alcohol producers and they
don't necessarily agree with each other
but what the retailers want isn't
necessarily what the distributor's want
isn't necessarily what the manufacturers
want but they don't all get together in
one room and try to figure out a path
but they all agree on and said they meet
in their factions
and they decide what's best for their
faction and then they sudden it is to
talk about what that means as an
industry and I feel like we're in that
awkward teenage phase between these two
worlds where we need to grow out of the
idea that we can have one umbrella
organization that represents accurately
every sector of the cannabis industry
and we need to start thinking more about
representation by sector which I think
you are seeing we have the California
distributors Association we have
regional cultivation associations you
know and I think that that's really
where we're headed because it's just
getting too big for us to come together
and think that one Association is going
to be able to accurately and fully
represent the needs of out of all the
members across sectors I can agree with
that that it's probably gonna end up
being
a few different ones but definitely not
like 30 or 40 like we have now and that
each section the distributors
manufacturers cultivators retailers
eventually probably hopefully gets into
only four and that will be a lot easier
for you know when each perspectives
board goes to meet with the other
executive board you'll be uh less
because I mean I I've been a part of so
many trade organizations and helped
found so many California Growers
Association Greater Los Angeles
collectives Association which been
around for ever was like the first
cannabis trade organization I'm on
Southern California coalition
cultivators Alliance when we had started
that in the beginning and it's just you
know he gets he gets a little tiring you
know when you just all of these
different organizations and then you
help put them together some succeed some
fail some stick around some don't and so
for me just to see and just to have some
kind of unity on that forefront would be
amazing and to have that message that
all of us even though we're separate
were together when it comes to certain
messaging would resonate a lot further
what our elected officials and in all
reality if they if they knew or even
thought that we were all together like
we all because whenever it's a crisis we
all come together really quick you know
you know we could hit the crisis mode we
all come together we all form together
we get things done and resolved and then
they see though everybody's off to the
winds again which is what has happened
almost every time and so I would love to
see that not happen where we come
together during crisis and we stay
together and continue to progress
towards what we want was you know ten
years from now whatever it may be but it
does get exhausting when you have so
many different organizations and then
you it's like you're just playing
conference call after conference fall
when we could all just get on one call
and and get to the meat and potatoes if
you want to say of the subject and
actually get some real resolution and I
mean we la we're notorious for it down
here it's like every year there's a new
organization if not every three months
you know and it's because it we know we
are very diverse and the diversity adds
to that as well because every seems like
different also ethnic backgrounds have
their own organizations as well but
honestly trying to get it down to kind
of you know minimize that I think what
further are us in getting our message to
what we want to our officials to really
push forward our agenda which at the end
of the day we all want the same thing I
truly believe that we all really want
the same thing which is just to be
treated like normal businesses and not
like third-class third-rate citizens
which I'm kind of sick of you know I
mean in 2008 I got a DA letter saying
I'm gonna go to federal prison and I got
arrested in 2007 for 55 grams and they
try to give me three to five years for
less than two ounces and it's just I'm
just so tired of being treated okay
third class and all the amount of taxes
we give and it can you imagine if we
were in essentially businesses where
would that leave us we would all be
bankrupt because we don't get a bailout
so the whole thing and the whole
thinking has to change because we are
citizens we are taxed members we are
fathers we are mothers we are we are
your average working-class the last of
the middle class because this is where
we transitioned into because there was
no other jobs left you know and you know
we are normal regular people and we
should be treated as such you know and
that's that's that's my thing and and
the sooner I think
can all we're not all gonna come
together
it's gonna be so but as long as we can
all come together in our own perspective
feels and then communicate with each
other I believe and that's where the
Southern California Coalition is trying
to make that happen we are trying to
talk to different organizations about
whether it's on paper or just by word
coming together you know it's that
appearance and that sends the message to
the officials that hey we're coming
together and and we're gonna get this
together and you need to start paying
even more attention to what we're saying
because we're tired yeah it is
exhausting and it doesn't feel good and
then you look at the liquor store down
the street who's paying only $1600 a
year for his city tax and I'm paying of
over a half a million and I'm getting
treated worse it makes like zero cents
and and you know I could get into so
many things you know I served in the
Marine Corps for seven and a half years
I got shot stabbed blown up and now I'm
getting treated like a third class
citizen when there is someone who
migrated here three years ago who has a
liquor store and is getting treated
better than I am
when I sacrificed almost my life for my
country so it doesn't make sense you
know it doesn't make sense it and we
need to get our officials to to start
having more common sense and and looking
at us and preceding us in a much
different way than what has been in the
past Tom thank you for pressing that
question by articulating that there's 30
or 40 groups at a necessity like that's
that to me is really important there are
30 to 40 groups out of necessity out of
whatever their issue is that they've
come together for whether it be
manufacturing or retail or cultivation
or patient access whatever it is you
know um and I think that you know in my
eye
I think it's been like five years that
I've been in this industry now and I
can't tell you how many people how many
regulators the legislators and
politicians have asked me this question
do you have an NRA of cannabis and every
time I'm like no we don't have an NRA of
cannabis no we don't have a Consumer
Association no we don't have anybody you
know working at the federal level
representing consumers but I'm anybody
at state level representing consumers we
have niche little organizations
representing factions of consumers
normal you know probably being the one
most recognized Americans for safe
access being the most recognized for
patients and their access we've never
had a consumer association someone as
powerful at an organization as powerful
as that the NRA and that might be what
we need um we I think that that if if
all of our operators throughout the
entire supply chain were to forget about
their operator hat for a second and
remember that most of them are consumers
I would say you know a very high
majority of them are consumers and what
is it like to be a consumer in this
marketplace and for me I'm constantly
frustrated as a consumer on a daily
basis of you know when I find a product
in California that I like I can I
struggle to find it in multiple retail
establishments I struggle to find it at
the same price point in multiple retail
establishments I'm usually not able to
find it in Northern California and in
Southern California and I think that
that is the type of problem that's going
to get worse as the industry does evolve
and if we evolved without any policy
reform we're gonna see more of a
segregated market because the only
operators that really are able to
weather this storm are the vertically
integrated ones and the more vertically
integrated you become the less likely
you are to sell other people's products
right because you're not incentive
- you're you're trying to survive and I
get it I understand why the market looks
this way but for me every time I find a
product that I like I struggle to get
more of it and so I really think that
maybe we could all come together and
it's been really playing in the back of
my line during this entire Kobe crisis
do we need an NRA of cannabis do we need
you know a consumer association I know I
would pay a hundred bucks a year to
belong to an association that told me
who my cannabis friendly politicians
were to vote for if someone did that
work for me that would be worth a
hundred bucks a year for me you know
somebody that was an organization that
was working on rectifying the fact that
I have a problem that I can't find my
favorite edible in more than you know
three areas of the state that to me is
an issue and I don't think that we've
ever come at this from a consumer lens
and taken the consumers perspective you
know into consideration and you know if
there were if there were an in our NRA
of cannabis they'd be at the Capitol
right now saying this is ridiculous we
can't pay forty five percent more for
the same product we bought two and a
half years ago with our bongs and
instead of guns but I know I don't want
to take up too much more time on this I
know that our panel is supposed to be
done right now but there are a few more
hot topics that Peter wanted to talk
about so I think we should probably do a
check in with everyone to see if
everyone can stick around and what Peter
is thinking about how much longer he
wants to take I could stick around I
just have to take care of one thing but
you did make a great point and I think
there has to be a consumer organization
because every time we've done anything
on initiatives or referendums or
anything we've done
and speaking of Americans for saying
we've always thought about for the
patient's for the consumer this is
what's always our message and that's
what I've heard rest us so far because
those elected officials they care more
about the consumer then what they think
is the wealthy cannabis business one
even though they need to just look at
our books and
realize we're not wealthy and if they
don't care because they for us they
think oh they're just complaining cuz
they're not making enough money but when
the consumer says something it drives
that message a lot further and coming
from us well that's the reason why we
did this this banking campaign and
that's consumer facing so you know we I
totally agree and I think that's one of
the things that's really been missing
post legalization is bringing the
consumers into the discussion prior to
legalization consumers were like our
biggest asset I mean they were making a
stink they didn't want to go to jail
they wanted access to product they
wanted access to things that were tested
I mean they really had a lot to say and
then I think after legalization
unfortunately there was this idea of
like okay the businesses have it now you
guys are good and we kind of lost some
of that from the consumer so you know
one of the big issues I think we need to
fix is banking the fact that cannabis
businesses don't have access to banking
I mean obviously that's a big issue for
us as businesses but for the consumer
what it means is you have to pay cash
you have to pay cash at the dispensary
dispensary workers have to handle cash
and given the current environment that
we're in we were like hey this is
something that consumers I myself as a
consumer but worries me I don't want to
have to use cash every time I go to a
dispensary and my brother manages
dispensaries and I don't want him to
have to handle cash every day and then
go home to his one and a half year old
daughter so we thought this is something
that consumers to get behind so we
started this dirty money campaign aimed
at getting the safe banking act included
in the next federal Kogan relief
stimulus package and so we did a
public-facing campaign aimed at
consumers to write the representatives
to basically say I don't like the idea
that I have to handle cash when I go and
purchase my cannabis and you know so I
think that we're gonna see how this goes
we've had the campaign up for two days
we've had 180 letters generated to
representatives in California we're
gonna keep going with this
and I think that this is an opportunity
for businesses also to help engage their
consumers and to recognize that you know
consumers do care about
it's happening and it's not just about
how expensive it is and it's not just
about products it's how we feel we're
being treated as adults that are seeking
out a service that is legal to us to
seek out and and so I think that in the
future there is definitely a role for
consumers to play you know I I really
would hope or wish that normal would
take a more nra approach and be more
aggressive I don't think they were
aggressive enough and I think that
that's really what we need you know we
need folks that are gonna be super
aggressive at the federal level on
behalf of consumers because there's
millions of cannabis consumers I would
you know hazard a guess that there's
more cannabis consumers and there are
gun users so you know we definitely have
a leverage they're often they enjoy or
they overlap too often my belief is that
cannabis consumers are potentially the
most powerful constituency in this
industry they just somehow need to be
mobilized the lesson I'm taking away is
that this is almost a call to action I
may devote the rest of my life to
building that organization since it
really is near and dear to me and has
been for a long time because as a
consumer I feel invisible and unhurt I
just want to say and you know this you
know that when when it push comes to
shove right and things happen the
dispensary operators they start sending
emails and texts to their to their
consumers and we rounded them up and
next thing you know we have hundreds of
people at City Hall so it's not like it
can't be done we could do it but the
thing the part that I always have a
problem is it's not that we can do it we
never keep it going once we get what we
want
everybody goes off to the wind and and
that's the most important thing is once
we do the call to action and everybody
we gotta keep it going
we can't just oh we got what we want
okay I'll see you guys next time there
is a problem
that doesn't work well I'm sure there's
strategies for mobilizing people and
maintaining their interest over time
that people have developed in the people
who are you know you have done that
there's techniques to doing that I don't
think it's easy but it's doable and
there's people who are really good at
having clear strategies short term
medium term and long term keeping that
information in front of people and
trying to keep them mobilized I think
it's super hard but it's it's necessary
otherwise you're a you're a victim you
know you're just at the mercy and who
wants to be at the mercy of anybody
including the state which from my
perspective is kind of acting like a
drug dealer in not the best sense of the
term yeah one of the things we were
trying to do with 420 being all month
and April was we were designing some
postcards we wanted to put at the point
of sale for every retailer we worked
with that they could melt a Sacramento
that you know itemize some of these
things because you're right the
consumers have to start making their
voices heard the industries talked to or
blue in the face and we're just not
doing interaction you know obviously the
Kovach kind of threw a wrench and not
when we tell our consumers weren't able
to walk into shops and everybody's got
masks on so we're working on a different
plan but you know what happens if a
couple million green postcards show up
in Sacramento saying taxes are too high
you know I don't have access to medicine
I have to drive three hours to get
epilepsy medicine for my child like
that's how we get things to change
absolutely that's a big issue for us is
how patient you know what happens to
comments almost like we need to organize
a call patience and access to medicine
and and and and we're actually doing
that we're organizing it in the
background we are doing that so just
quickly let's get to the speed round on
some fun topics in no particular order
but we got high times getting into
retail
we got weed maps subpoenas not gun round
and one of my favorites take them one at
a time topics med men which most people
here know for a long time I've been
calling the Enron of cannabis Adam
Biermann the Martin shkreli the pharma
bro he's the canna bro so why don't we
start with High Times thinks that the
the retail game is where it's at and
they're making big pivot so who wants to
start with that one yeah I could start I
told Tom I was like everybody wants to
do retail until they get into retail it
sounds fun it looks you know glamorous
but it's you know I think High Times is
in for a rude awakening when they
realize that the amount of money they're
there is it retail is horrible if you
know unless you're gonna try to cut
corners and try to have a certain things
here and there which I'm not gonna lie a
third of retailers are doing that you
know they're not doing things that
exactly the way that they have been
supposed to so you know it and which
shocked me because there's been a few
quite a few retailers that have already
been busted by the BCC legal ones doing
things that they're not supposed to I
mean I know of one that got caught with
a hundred pounds of illicit cannabis
selling it out of the jar from
underneath the register underneath the
counter and they have their license and
nothing's nothing's done so
you know that's another disheartening
fact you know off subject but yeah I
think High Times is in for a rude
awakening when they realize that the
retail business is not all that was
meant to be and that they're not going
to be able to get the evaluation that
they want from retail to sell it or what
they eventually plan on doing well wait
a second let's back up a second where
they just slap where they just let go or
there was a slap on the wrist because
that's dumb
that's not enforcement no it's not
enforcement at all and you know the BCC
has always said oh we only enforced and
the DCR we only owned of course against
legal operators because that's that's
that's what we can do that's what we're
allowed to do we're not allowed to
enforce against illegal but they're not
enforcing against legal ones either that
are breaking the laws so and when you do
that now you're creating a completely
miscued market because now you have
legal operators that are doing illegal
stuff to cut corners isn't Creek isn't
cushy punch back to business as usual
because she punches back the business
hey you know I mean they got caught with
a completely illegal facility running to
location and again I know are you guys
selling cookie punch in your shop I am
NOT but I am friends with the owner and
I met him up with him the other day and
I asked him he said oh yeah we're gonna
be back online so I don't think they
actually have products back out there
yet but you know it all it is is the
brand gets caught they find another
licensee they make a licensing agreement
for the name and next thing you know
that brand is back online with a new
license so you know and again I I love
the guy very nice guy family guy but you
know when when people are doing things
like this and he's not the worst you
know the other retailers selling you
know literally they confiscated a
hundred pounds from his facility and I
know of another incident where the idiot
manager started running down the back
alley with like 20 pounds and the bcc
agents tackled him okay I
and they're still operating it makes no
sense and I'm over here worried about
taxes and this and that I'm getting you
know if I'm late I'll get a threat
letter that I'm gonna lose my license
but then the person who completely does
something illegal and gets caught
red-handed nothing so it just it's a lot
of things just don't make sense to me
you know and and if you're not going to
enforce in areas where you have complete
control to enforce let alone the ones
that you don't well again you know
you're setting us up for failure and
you're rewarding the people that are
doing illegal stuff to continue doing
illegal stuff yeah okay so back to the
question at hand about high times I
don't know if anyone else is as bored as
I am but I actually pulled up the SEC
filing on to look at what assets were
included in that purchase so you've got
to kind of unwind it free harvest before
harvest entered the California picture
it was have a heart out of Seattle that
was you know getting some of the retail
permits in not so coveted jurisdictions
let's say so harvest purchased have a
hearts dispensaries and then they were
also in the process of getting some of
their own licenses so I unpacked just
what it is that High Times allegedly
purchased and I'm saying allegedly
because you still need a stock to go
public and on all of these different
jurisdictions to sign off on this before
this deal could ever go through so
minimum I would say you're looking at a
year before you know any dots would be
the t's would be crossed and and eyes
would be dotted before this would be
completed so we've got a harvest in Palm
Springs and if you're familiar with Palm
Springs Market Palm Springs is one of
two jurisdictions in the entire state
that have an open process
for retail the other being lompoc so if
if you're interested in getting a retail
permit those are the two jurisdictions
that if you can find property that
qualify you can get you pretty much can
get a retail permit there so you've got
a very overcrowded market in Palm
Springs that's one of them you got
another one in harvest of venice which
if my memory serves me correctly I
believe Venice is only a medical market
which is a really tough way to compete
these days we've got harvest of Merced
you've got harvest of Riverside and I
don't think that one is opened yet
you've got harvest of Han and ferd which
isn't open yet you've got harvest of
blithe which is definitely not open yet
and then you've got to very expensive
dispensary permits in San Francisco
you've got another one in San Bernardino
which I don't believe is open and two in
Oakland one in Kalinga and the final one
being in Santa Cruz and Santa Cruz only
allows you to sell off 20% of the
business so what they sold was their
twenty percent stake in or no actually
it's only ten percent so you've got a
lot of less you know desirable areas to
operate you know I know that the Kalinga
store is if it's still open is doing
about $1,000 a day so um the these are
the types of assets I want everyone to
be aware of that harvest unload
potentially unloaded on to high times
high time still has to go public and
still has to you know take possession of
these and in the midst of a pandemic
when everybody is shifting from retail
to kurd side or delivery you know those
business models absolutely do not make
sense in either Oakland or San Francisco
and
maybe they could make sense if you're
going to turn all of those assets into
trying to become a statewide delivery
brand is the only thing that I could
think that they would attempt to do but
that would all depend on how expensive
those San Francisco and Oakland
properties really are and how much those
are bleeding them dry until they
actually are up and running and up and
running in a post pandemic world where
we're not wearing masks and were you
know congregating again and so this to
me should be viewed as a Hail Mary by
both harvest who's looking to unload
their less desirable assets and a Hail
Mary by high times hoping that this will
help them go public and that's all this
is and nothing more and just quickly a
show of hands the panelists who here is
getting in on the high times reggae
offering getting in while the goings hot
but you know something funny about high
times in that whole situation first of
all it's just hoping screams Hard Rock
Cafe to me and like this idea of just
these super like commercial just wonky
look in places that have like cheech's
pipe in a glass display or something but
funny High Times story so you know flow
kana we launched this dirty money
campaign on a Monday and we did an
Instagram post it was basically like
encouraging people to contact the
representative and you know we don't
want to have to handle cash great
actually posted it some dude from High
Times who works there commented and was
like all his comment says was your
lobbying wrong or that's not how you do
it or something like that and I was like
okay so we responded and we were like
you know what do you mean we think this
is an issue people would care about so
she says you just purchased 13
dispensaries and this is about not
having to handle cash in a dispensary
and they responded that of course they
care and that they invented grassroots
lobbying so in case folks didn't know
that out there hi time invented
grassroots lobbying which actually isn't
even a thing
but they
and so you know they obviously really
know what they're doing and they've got
a great team I did just read that stormy
Simon is no longer the CEO step down she
lasted four months yeah yeah now I I had
conversations with stormy where I told
her to get out I said you do because you
know where it started was when I got the
emails and you know the one from today
is coming you know who sent it high
times investor who sent it Adam Levin
and then there was one that had Stormy's
name on it and I immediately emailed her
and said don't let them put your name I
was like and then I was like don't you
do not a couple years from now want to
be associated with duping little old
ladies who invested in high times you do
not want your name associated with that
and then we had a long phone call and
I've you know I've been trading emails
I'm gonna try to get her on to do a
webcast but just and being clear for
anybody who's watching coz I'm gonna cut
the high time segment so people don't
have to wait till the end the people who
currently run high times are a bunch of
finance douchebags who have nothing to
do with the grass roots history of high
times from the sick from the 70s and 80s
and any master you know any good grower
does not read high times today
okay so just everybody who is thinking
of investing in high times or who thinks
oh my god that'd be amazing to go to a
high times dispensary so we have a
couple brands on here Amanda is Flo kana
going to rush to supply product to High
Times retail Shannon is Fiddler's
Green's is that going to be the first
phone call you make when they take over
those retail operations and shame on you
we'll see I blame high times in a lot of
ways for bringing this weird idea of
what quality is to the marketplace and
that's really been hard for sun-grown
because when I was growing up in Chicago
and looking at High Times Magazine they
had be centerfolds of buds that are
supposed to be like the highest-quality
buds like these were the buds and they
were all indoor and they were all grown
like this far from the light and none of
them really looked I was would come
compare it to like the Playboy
centerfold
we're like you grow up thinking that
that's what like the ideal woman looks
like and then you get out in the world
and you realize that was all bullshit I
kind of feel like that's what high times
did they set it up for people consumers
to think that quality meant orange hairs
and tight nugs and that's not true so
then I make corn hub of cannabis no no I
kept Kevin I have a video clip of that
I'll play in the end the on-demand
version Kevin Jerry said it best which
was the article on the left side of the
page which is that hydro bud its sole
purpose was to sell the product on the
right side of the page which was an HP s
light or whatever it was what you have
is you have information that's used as
basically marketing it's kind of like
reading old high times because I've read
the shit in years it's like reading high
times and every article was basically to
sell the material on the next page so
they're not giving you any information
they're giving you a marketing pitch
wrapped around some photos yeah
absolutely and and but unfortunately the
impact that it had on the consumer
marketplace was that all these years
later in doors being sold for $65 an
eighth and Sun grown is lucky to get 40
and I do think that's high times played
a huge role in that like I don't think
they'll ever take responsibility for it
but I think they played a huge role in
really leading the consumer or on us
astray when it comes to knowing what a
quality cannabis product is yeah it's a
double-edged sword right because for I
grew up in Texas and a lot of my first
exposure to cannabis was you know High
Times magazines that we were able to
look out and see so it brought it to
people who weren't
Northern California weren't part of the
community but like Amanda said it was
also miss branding and misrepresenting
it was you know selling McDonald's
hamburgers like it was filet mignon and
so we've got to undo that at this point
I like that innovation be rushing to do
business with high tines
retail shops that's not really in line
with our brands and our mission got it
okay have we beaten high times
sufficient will okay
do we want to do weed maps for me I'm
cognizant that it's 10 20 so why don't
we do a quick wrap and you won't have
any thoughts on weed maps and said Gemma
come say hi to everyone quick quick
quick quick
oh my gosh look at you I left her and
we're getting a tour of Greg's place too
III left her unsupervised with a bag of
tortilla chips nothing like getting a
delivery from a CEO I see you're
actually going Greg on this subject
you'll ask you a really quick question
in terms of staffing and everything have
you had to go down how has all of this
impacted your what you know your
staffing well I mean it's impacted
stuffing in multiple ways from staffers
that I lose staff yeah so I mean a
staffing I've lost a lot of staff you
know Garrett on let's quickly go to
let's talk
we'd maps and then we'll come back to
Greg
okay so go for it so anyone want to talk
anybody been following the weed map
stuff
yeah the subpoena I mean who doesn't
love to read a good subpoena is the best
one ever you know obviously there's
going to be more news to come and it's
just very ironic that it's the Chinese
you're the rat people I mean like Ardley
all the articles that have been written
about it suggests you know the federal
government's sure did cast a very wide
net and it's not clear who they're after
but more definitely will be revealed
anyone else have any I mean they think
they're going after the legal market now
they're going to take down law-abiding
shops during a pandemic that are one of
the few businesses paying tax oh thank
you
well my hope is that they're gonna be
the little discerning and they're gonna
look deeper into the folks that are in
question and and there's definitely some
people that have sense or you know at
the time we're in process of getting
their licensure and maybe have been you
know trying to move in that direction
and other folks that have been flaunting
you know the fact that they are on meat
maps and not having licenses and so my
hope is that it's not a
one-size-fits-all scenario and that they
prioritize who they think are the bigger
the more egregious actors I guess it's
hard to know what's really behind this
if it's a bill bars agenda or something
else going on I don't know if anyone has
any insights into into that so just
quickly Greg how many deliveries are you
about to go out with how many of them
got it how many of you doing a dang well
like 30 something or so so so bad and
are you the main delivery driver do you
have this gets back to your staffing so
I'm the main delivery driver that's
that's what's happened and yeah I've
lost like between people getting sick
people being afraid to work and just and
also what's happening is and this is
something that I'm sure a lot of people
are there's like a competition amongst
the businesses for good employees
because people are just dropping off and
to find a good employee
I had another company another retailer
outbid me for my own employee literally
they stole my employee for me so I've
lost the employees like that as well and
I pay really good but I don't sugarcoat
it I don't lie to employees I don't tell
them something that's not gonna happen
you know I tell them book you you not a
manager you'd still need to get this
training you don't even know how to do
math
how can you even yeah can you you don't
know QuickBooks you don't know metric
you don't know this you don't know that
and then there's other employers that
are just just feeding these employees
with a lot of stuff in their head and
making promises that they are never
gonna fulfill just so they could get the
employee there as a budtender for the
meantime and some of those how do I know
I know the owners I'm friends with all
of them so I know their personalities I
know their characters though we know
each other
and so it's really tough finding good
employees in this pandemic it has made
everything worse you know I mean we get
flooded like on indeed I'll get three
thousand emails of people applying for a
job and we specifically put must have
experienced and over 2,000 of them will
be will be bartenders or something like
that and you know we do want to hire and
we want to give them a chance because
people need jobs but then they come in
here and it's it's very hard because
even bartenders they have different
habits and different things that you
can't do in cannabis in cannabis as a
retail if you're selling a product and
it's because the state one the state
says check it in the front the city says
check it at the register you know and so
you have to have an ID checker in the
front and in the back and a lot of times
with bartenders if you don't look if you
look over 21 they don't even card you at
all so those are two big differences
because that could cost the business a
big violation if you don't scan the
person's ID so you know it's just a good
employee has become a very big commodity
at least out here in Los Angeles in
cannabis very very difficult to find and
a lot I'm not the only owner business
owner unless you're one of the bigger
companies who's funded and and got a
billion dollar evaluation a small
business
are having to either play delivery boy
but tender doing whatever you have to do
to make sure your small business
survives well what are we seeing in
terms of layoffs in the industry so a
lot of the layoffs are coming in
Manufacturing is what I'm seeing not too
much in cultivation and not too much in
retail because retail were hurting for
employees but manufacturing I've even
seen a few companies already go bankrupt
example open and district edibles
they're gone they're never gonna be
around again you know that that those
two brands are gone they are gone gone
and they were great brands my customers
loved it because the price point was
good and and so you've already seen the
first of a few businesses because of
this coronavirus already suffer and you
know because the whole pandemic just it
just multiplied everything that we're
feeling already you know when you
compile everything that's going on it
makes it very very difficult very very
difficult so why don't why don't we wrap
on that and we can we can always get
back to med men and future episodes but
everyone did with with calling it a day
at a weave for two and a half hours
strong we saw like 30-something people
tuned in online so I'd like to thank
those people for for the creature double
feature it's a safety right it's PPE and
a bomb you didn't have to refrain from
hitting that
thank you I appreciate it
hey guys safe delivery
no thank you drive safe