I want to introduce someone who really
doesn't need a lot of introduction in
this crowd. Um, but I'll just do that
for a moment anyway. Um he is called by
the Rolling Stones the real drugs are
the point man for drug policy reform in
this country and increasingly
nationally. Formerly a professor at
Princeton 25 years ago he started to
really get involved in drug policy and
over 20 years ago he started what is now
the Drug Policy Alliance.
and and he's been here since the
beginning. You know, I'm new to some of
you. I've been with DPA for five years,
but Ethan goes all the way back to Prop
215 and before, and he's been here and
kept a large presence in California for
over 20 years.
And I'm so honored and touched to
introduce my boss, my director, really a
drug policy reform warrior, Ethan
Natleman.
Okay. Thank you very much, Lynn. That
was wonderful. and Liz's been doing an
amazing job as heading up DPA's effort
in uh in California on this, not just on
marijuana, but other things as well. So,
before I get going, and I should say I
if somebody here wants to give me a
fivem minute warning because there's no
clocks and I don't have a watch, so it
could be like running into the debates
before I finish here. But let me ask
you, how many of you have heard of Prop
19? Raise your hand. How many you don't
know what Prop 19 is? Raise your hand.
Okay, you see all that about 25% of
hands. How many of you know what Prop
215 is? Raise your hand. How many of you
don't know what Prop 215 is? Raise your
hands. Okay, just so you know, 215 was
the medical marijuana initiative in 1996
in California. And I apologize uh
because I realize in talking with you
here, you ain't a movement audience.
Most of you are people in the
money-making side of this, right? And
so, you know, part of why I'm up here is
that I want to be able to talk to you
not as just maybe fellow
stoners and not just talk to you as
people looking to make money in this new
and emerging and booming green rush of a
legal market.
But I'm hoping that I can be talking to
you so that when I say to you fellow
drug policy
reformers, you think that's me. That's
you. Okay? And let me say why this is
important. The reason
why the reason
why these opportunities exist today, the
reason why you're here, the reason why
there's a legal marijuana industry for
medical and hopefully for non-medical
beginning after election day, the reason
why this is happening around the
country, that none of this
transformation was driven by people who
wanted to make money in this industry
trying to change the law so they can
make money legally, right? None of it
was driven that way. Okay, understand.
And also, by the way, this didn't emerge
also because of some new uh invention,
some new tech thing that just popped up
and all of a sudden we got this thing.
It's not like that, right? This
movement, your opportunities exist here
today. The reason you are here today is
because a small number of people like
me, like Rob Campy, Marijuana Policy
Project, like our friends at Normal,
like Graham Boyd, and a few
others, and the people we work
with went out there beginning over 20
years ago to raise money from rich guys
who had no financial interest in this
area. We're not making money in it
illegally. had no hopes to make money
illegally, but who became engaged in
trying to end marijuana prohibition
because of the feeling that marijuana
prohibition was a monumental disaster
for this country and for this world. And
that arresting, right, you know,
arresting 700,000 people a year, right,
putting tens of millions of dollars into
the hands of gangsters on this side of
the border and across and
internationally, right? that that that
that doing things like ripping people's
property because of acid forfeite laws
and taking their property away because
they found a little weed or some money
they thought was for weed that that
dragging women through the through the
child custody courts because they tested
positive for we when they gave birth or
when they had a little baby with no no
indication of harm to a child right that
drug testing people in American society
and saying you can't hold a job simply
because you like to smoke weed not on
the job but the night before the weekend
before that all of this was a disaster
right and that it should not be allowed
to continue. And more than that, more
than that, it wasn't just about
marijuana for most of the people I'm
talking about, right? You know, if you
the guys, you look at the guys who put
the money up early on. I mean, George
Soros, and who's still putting it up,
you know, Peter Lewis, John Sperling,
somebody said George Zimmer, George
Zimmer is a men's warehouse guy. John
Sperling's University of Phoenix. Peter
Lewis, progressive insurance. George
Soros, famous philanthropist and
financial investor, and a range of
others. None of them were getting into
it just so that they could get high.
Some of them like to get high. someone
didn't give a damn about it. It was the
notion that not just the war on
marijuana and marijuana users was
problematic, but that the entire drug
war was fundamentally wrong. Right. And
right and and what it meant was that
even though we understood and most of us
understood that the answers with cocaine
and hero methamphetamine and
psychedelics, etc., etc., was not
necessarily going to be the same as
marijuana, we weren't going to be
looking to make an alcohol-like model
for these drugs. I mean some people feel
that way and all of us think that maybe
that's the way it should be on some days
but by and large that was not the idea
but it was the idea that this
prohibitionist war on drugs right was
not just about marijuana but everything
else just the wrong thing for this
country in the world that taking America
from 50,000 people behind bars in 1989
drug charge to half a million as of a
few years ago that putting more people
in the United States behind bars on a
drug charge than all of Western Europe
put behind bars for everything and they
have 100 million more people than we do.
They're driving America's incarceration
rate up to the highest in the world,
more than the Russians, more than the
Chinese, more than anybody, the highest
incarceration rate in the history of
democratic societies. America today with
barely 4% of the world's population but
over 20% of the world's incarcerated
population and that increase driven
overwhelmingly in the 80s and 90s and
early 2000s by the war on drugs that
that had to end. So why is marijuana so
pivotal in all this? There's a few
reasons, right? The first reason, the
first
reason is that the area where we could
accomplish the greatest reform was on
marijuana, right? We could take
marijuana unlike the other drugs where
we have to talk about decriminalizing,
rolling back mandatory minimum
sentences, having a less harsh drug war,
a kinder a kindergler drug war, learning
from the Europeans, etc. But with
marijuana, we could actually take this
thing out of the prohibition system,
right? And it's why in 1996 when we did
the first Prop 2 Prop 215, the medical
marijuana initiative, the other
initiative we did was a treatment
instead of incarceration initiative for
people struggling with drug addiction.
Right? Those were issues where we saw
that a majority of Americans who had
been, you know, seized by the drug war
of the late 80s and all the hysteria
could say, "Wait a second. We can see
it's gone too far when it comes to
throwing people in jail who seriously
have a drug addiction and aren't hurting
other people. And we can see it's gone
too far when we're telling sick people
that if they want to use this medicine,
they're a criminal. Right? That's where
this stuff came from. So please
understand that you know that as we're
moving and as we're making moving this
market in this incredibly awkward way
and difficult challenging way from an
illegal market to a legal market
understand the origins of where your
opportunities emerge from. Understand
that you can all make money in this
stuff without having had to invest a
penny in changing the laws to get where
we are today. Understand also that we're
standing on the shoulders of pioneers
who led this stuff before. I remember
back 20 years ago when this local
activist on HIV and marijuana, Dennis
Peron in San Francisco, you know, and
basically if Dennis had not gotten that
thing going, drafting 215, for all I
know, on the back of a napkin, I would
not have come in then and raised the
money from the big guys and get this
thing and ch make California the first
state in America to legalize medical
marijuana, right? going back six years
ago to Richard Lee. I mean, Richard
Lee's hutzbah with getting out there and
saying, "I'm going to try to legalize
marijuana in 2010 and I and Rob Campy
and other leaders were saying this is
too soon, Richard. It's not a
presidential election year. Hold off."
But when Richard said, "I want to do it.
I want to do it now. It's the right
thing to do." We said, "We'll help you
on that." And I'll typically when you
run a ballot initiative and you lose,
you lose. But with respect to Prop 19
six years ago, that initiative lost by
seven points, right? But in fact, it
transformed the national dialogue. It
was the first time, right? I mean,
literally in six months, we went from
having people from journalists and
others saying, "Ah, legalized marijuana
never happened." to people going, "How
come you didn't win?" Somehow a
consciousness shifted at that moment.
And so, Richard Lee will always deserve
his historical credit for having been a
catalyst, even with his loss, and
opening this thing up. Right now, the
other piece of
this is about as we move forward, one of
my fears as we try to end the broader
drug
war is not to leave the rest of this
drug policy more reform movement behind,
right? I mean, most people, you know,
with marijuana, part of the reason we
focus on medical back in 20 years ago
was because the majority said it was
time to end. Part of the reason was
because the large majority of illicit
drug use in America use nothing but
marijuana, right? I mean, there are a
range of reasons for this, right? Half
the drug arrests in America are on
marijuana, although not half the people
incarcerated on drug law violations.
When you look at people going behind
bars, right, and and spending years
behind bars for low-level cocaine and
heroin meth
offenses, that it's not right either. No
matter how much you hate those drugs,
that's not right. And my fear now is
that as we move forward with legalizing
marijuana, let's not leave behind our
commitment to rolling back this broader
drug war, right? You know, I mean, Drug
Policy Alliance already positioned where
we're beginning to say our 20-year
commitment to marijuana legalization.
We've been in a pivotal leadership role
throughout with the the first seven
medical marijuana initiatives and many
of the state legislative efforts. And
we've had a hand in all four of the
legalization efforts that have been
succeeding United States and in
Washington DC and in Uruguay. But we
know is that as this thing picks a
momentum of its own, our mission is
going to be to some extent to try to end
the broader drug war. And for example,
most importantly to advance the notion
which is already common place in Europe
and other parts of the world that nobody
but nobody should lose their freedom or
go to jail simply for possessing any
substance for their own use. Right? I
mean, whether you're a recreational user
of coke or an addicted user of heroin,
whatever it might be, we don't know how
we're going to make it available legally
or whether it's going to be maintenance
programs like you got in Europe. But
what it does mean is the notion that
nobody but nobody should be losing their
freedom or going to jail simply for that
little bit they got in their pocket or
they're using whether recreational or
addicted user. That's a core principle
because it taps in to what is our
underlying most core principle which is
that we
ultimately must have sovereignty over
our own minds and bodies. That core
principle is
absolutely vital no matter what. The
same way as the first amendment just
doesn't just protect good speech or
gentle speech. It protects ugly speech
and despicable speech and we have to
hold on to that. Now we begin to get in
an era where elements of political
correctness and protecting everybody. So
we have to sacrifice the first
amendment. But you don't sacrifice the
first amendment because when you start
to sacrifice the most offensive forms of
speech for all sorts of
rationalizations, then you begin to
sacrifice other types of speech. And the
same, hey, I'm a good old marijuana and
psychedelics guy. You know, I love my
weed. Psychedelics been good to me. you
know, my profound spiritual experiences,
you know, you know, never much care for
cocaine. I got to admit to me it was
like, you know, having too much coffee
and post-nasal drip. I mean, you know,
but I understand some of my friends
became poets when they did cocaine. But
the fact of the matter is that core
principle of sovereignty of our own
minds and bodies has to hold not just
for the drugs that we love, but the
drugs that we hate and the people who
consume them. And there's
another there's another piece to this
was when you look at the origins of drug
prohibition in this country. When you
look at who's been disproportionately
decimated by this drug war, arrested,
targeted, punished, incarcerated, it is
overwhelmingly people of color, black
people and brown people. Goes back to
the first, you know, even Asian people,
right? The first, you know, anti-opium
laws were about Chinese minorities
coming to California, Nevada, 1870s and
80s. The the first anti- cocaine laws
were about blacks storing cocaine in the
south in the early 20th century. The
first anti-marijuana laws were about
Mexican-Americans, Mexican migrants in
the teens and the 20s in the west and
the southwest, right? You look at the
origins of these laws are steeped in
racism and racial prejudice and racial
stigmatization. But then when you look
at who's getting you look in California
where for many years not one white
person was prosecuted on a crack offense
even though white people were lots of
white people were doing crack right but
just where they were looking in my state
of New York where we had these notorious
Rockefeller drug laws and and you had
95% of the people behind bars for
selling or possessing cocaine and heroin
were black or brown. But that was not
true of 90% of the people possessing or
using that drug. Right? You know, with
marijuana that almost any place in
America that if you were to randomly
stop 100 black kids, 100 brown kids, 100
white kids and look in their pockets,
roughly the same percent would have a
little weed in their pocket. But in
every city in
America, the black kid is two to 10
times more likely to get busted than the
white kid. The brown kid is probably,
you know, two to five times more likely
to get busted than the white kid. And
that on some level, I mean, how can it
be that you're black, white, brown,
you're doing the same thing, but that
person is the one who's going to get
shafted, right? And he's going to get
shafted here because he lives in a in a
black neighborhood where you got tons
more cops there. Or alternatively, he's
walking through a white neighborhood and
people, what are you doing here? Right?
I mean, you're damned if you do, damned
if you don't on this sort of stuff,
right? So understanding as I'm talking
to this mostly beautiful white audience
here, but let's understand and there
have been millions and millions of white
people but then slammed and killed and
hurt and damaged by this horrible drug
war as well. But understand that the
disproportionate impact on this makes
this a particularly venal public policy.
And when you have a book out there by
Michelle called the new Jim Crow,
understanding that the war on drugs is
the new Jim Crow from slavery to Jim
Crow to the modern-day war on drugs. you
are all part of this thing. Now, that
brings me here to California right now.
I live in New York, by the way. I'm not
a California. I'm very proud of my
California team for all the work they're
doing this, you know, but this
initiative and I have to say I'm very
thankful to one of my new favorite
billionaires, Sean Parker, because I
mean that guy, you know, I don't, to my
knowledge, he has not invested or
planning to invest in this industry.
When I've sat down and been talking with
him about this, I've known him for about
eight, nine years now. when we talk
about this stuff, it's about good
governance. It's about smart public
policy. It's about moving America and
the world in the right direction. Right?
That his commitment to doing this and
the partnership that we've had with him
has been absolutely pivotal to making
the possibility that California is going
to legalize marijuana 6 weeks in a day
from today very very real.
Right? I mean, I'll tell you, I I am I'm
nervous cuz it's part of my job to be
nervous. I'm not a naturally nervous
person, but I mean the fact is when
those polls came out a couple days ago,
first the PPIC poll and then the field
poll with different methodologies, but
each one of them showing 60% support for
legalizing marijuana for for for Prop
64. I haven't had the experience of
having numbers that good just six weeks
to go. Now, my job is not to get
overconfident. It's tell you not to be
overconfident as well, right? And quite
frankly, any one of you can even give
five bucks to help this thing over the
top. I mean, I'm pouring millions of
dollars into this thing. I'm raising it
all over the place. I'm depriving my the
rest of my organization of other
resources to do this sort of stuff. So
whether you want to go to the website
CRMR and do it, whether you want to go
to our back table drug policy and make a
tax law, do something. Do something.
Just a little something, right? Just
have a little skin in the game. You
know, have that feeling that when that
thing wins on election day, you can say,
"I gave just a little bit to make this
happen." Just do it because it's the
right thing to do. Just a little bit.
Little bit. Little bit. Not going to
cost you a lot, but you're going to feel
good that you did it. You, believe me,
you're going to feel good that you did
it. But I'll tell you what else. The
rest of the initiatives, I think some of
you know the lay of the land right now.
You know, we got initiatives up in
Arizona and Nevada and Maine and
Massachusetts. DPA, drug policy alliance
work with marijuana policy project and
local activists to draft these things
around the country. MPP with local
activists been taking the lead on the
fundraising these other states the
polling in the polling in almost all
these states most of the polls most of
the time show more people in favor than
against that's no guarantee of victory
especially six weeks out especially when
there are rumors of Sheldon Adlesen or
Aden pouring millions of dollars into
the campaign against Nevada. We're not
sure if that's true yet, but we think it
is. And he just bought the local paper,
which went from being pro- legalization
to anti, right? And he put a million
dollars in against the medical
mariju. And then you got some opioid
manufacturer trying to get into some
part of the cannabis pharmaceutical
stuff, pouring money, a half million
dollars into Arizona. And you got some
crazy woman in Virginia who thinks all
marijuana users are terrorists, pouring
over a million dollars into California.
So, it's not as if this is just going to
be a walk in the park, right? We got to
win. Well, we have to win California.
This is the no lose, right? We have to
win it. I mean, imagine how terrible it
would be if we lost it. We have to win
it, right? But I mean, the rest of these
things, we got to win a few of these
other ones as well. And then there's
medical. Florida's looking good, but
there's real money on the other side.
You know, Missouri broke my heart
because if we got that, just a little
screw up on the signature collection. We
were about to make it and the numbers
were great and that's not going to be on
the ballot. I'm sad to say.
Arkansas, this is the new world. two
initiatives, both trying to make on the
ballot, one trying to sue the other to
get them out of there. And the one that
I don't like is the one I mean, it'll
it'll be a that step forward, but you
know, it's basic guys just trying to
make a lot of money for themselves and
not caring about the broader policy
stuff and just an ugly game. It's part
of what we're getting into. We almost
had that happen in Maine as well, but
we're able to get both sides to get
together and just do one initiative. you
know, North Dakota popped up going to
have medical marijuana, but you know,
they should have called us first because
they drafted this initiative and I hope
it wins, but it wasn't as good as it
could be. You know, in Montana, they're
trying to fix something in the past.
This is going to be the year of
marijuana come election day. Five
legalization initiatives, three or four
medical. I don't think we can win all of
them. I hope we can. I'm reassured by
the fact that in all four states that
won, Alaska, Washington, Colorado, and
uh Oregon, in every one of them, the
final tally, 55% in favor in three of
those states, in Alaska, a little less,
was higher than we expected in the late
polls. So, I'm hoping that there's that
thing lurking out there that's going to
be good, right? But here's why I feel
special about California. I mean, it's
not just that you guys were first with
215. And I feel bad you didn't go first
with legalization, you know, but you got
your moment now. And the fact of the
matter is the market here is more than
double the size of all the four other
states that have already legalized,
right? And the fact of the matter is
that all eyes are on California. And it
may be a very blue state, but all eyes
are still on California. But there's
some other things going on with this
initiative. Apart from the
fact that it is the most thoughtfully
designed
initiative ever to happen in the
marijuana field apart from the fact that
one of my key cal colleagues Tamar Todd
who's been the lead drafter of many
marijuana initiives around the country
did inter you know basically interviewed
hundreds of stakeholders from humble to
LA to industry to government to what
have you and got it in apart from the
fact that even many of the people who
were competing with Prop 64 to get their
own initiative are now joining hands on
64 and saying we got to win this and I'm
very grateful for the folks who are
willing to do that after the it was like
it's almost like being in a primary
battle where all a sudden you come out
of the primaries everybody's got to get
behind the 101 but that's really
beginning to happen now but there's some
other stuff going on in this initiative
that's really important the fact that
it's the first statewide initiative on
marijuana to be endorsed by the
statewide medical association California
medical association unprecedented the
fact that it's got the endorsements of
major environmental groups right I mean
absolutely do one of them just came out
a couple days ago. Also unprecedented in
that way, right? The support we're
getting from unions and others,
absolutely pivotal, from civil rights
groups, absolutely pivotal. But you know
what else is
special? This is not just about
legalizing weed. It's also about
sentencing reform and about social
justice and about human rights. You
know, this initiative basically says
that if you've ever been convicted of a
drug felony, that cannot be the sole
basis of excluding you from getting a
legal license in the new legal market.
And that is pivotally important given
the grossly disproportionate way that
people of color have been landed up with
criminal convictions for doing the same
thing that white people have been doing
for a long, long time. This is the first
initiative that basically
says, I think it's the first one, if
you've ever been convicted of any
marijuana offense that would no longer
be an offense under Prop
64, you can apply even if you're still
behind bars to have that fund that
offense expuned or removed from your
record.
This initiative, I believe, is the first
one that says if you're under the age of
18 and you get picked up with weed, you
may get an infraction and have to do a
little community service or something,
but when you turn the age of 18, that
offense you got before you're 18 is
automatically wiped off your
record. Hundreds of thousands of people
in California have been hurt by these
laws and have these things hanging
around the records. This initiative is
the first one that
says up to $50 million after a few years
is going to go specifically to help
those communities that have been harmed
by the drug war,
right? You know, and 60% of the money is
going to go to help kids and not
bullshit stuff, but stuff that we wrote
in there to make it real. And 20% of
that stuff is going to go for
environmental and not just cleaning up
the mess that some growers have made
over the years, but even trying to
invest in smart environmental stuff,
envir parks, maintenance, that sort of
stuff. And 20% is going to go for local
law enforcement, but only in those
communities, right, that actually are
allowing the retail sale, right, and
production of cannabis. Okay?
So, but the other reason I care about
this
thing, it's not just that when this
passes in California election day that
it's going to reverberate throughout the
country. It's going to reverberate
globally, right? I got I got
tell about a year and a half ago I was
on a plane going from San Francisco to
Mexico
City and I looked to my right about an
hour before and there's sitting Jerry
Brown and his wife and last time I knew
Jerry Brown when he was the mayor of
Oakland and and we had a really vicious
fight on television right before ballot
edition of 2008 I hadn't seen him since
then went over said hello he remembered
the vicious fight but we put that behind
us. Um, you want to see that, go on
YouTube and type in the words either
rude debate or really rude debate. What
pops up is me and Jerry being unfriendly
with one another. Um, but I said, you
know, what are you going to are you
going to see President Ponto down there?
He said, yeah. So, what are you going to
say if he asks you about legalizing
marijuana in California? I don't know.
Huh. Said, well, you know, what should I
say? I said, well, you know, look, the
fact is we're going to get on the ballot
and it's probably going to win, right?
Well, you go, you know, marijuana is
gonna be the damn nation of civilization
and society and d, you know, look at
him. Are you crazy? You know, half
people know Jerry Brown said he used to
smoke, other half don't. I don't know
what the truth is. Yeah, she said she
could find. We have confirmation right
here that he used to smoke. So, who the
hell knows what? Maybe had a bad trip
sometime. But any the fact of the matter
is he did go. He did meet with President
Ponto. President Po did ask him what he
thought and Jerry Brown said, "I think
it's going to be I think it's going to
win." And said nothing bad, right? And
we're hoping he continues to say nothing
bad, right? I mean, the fact it's going
to be a billion dollars in tax revenue
and this guy's legacy is solving your
state's budget crisis, you know, has got
to look promising. And the fact that
there's been some law enforcement buying
and other stuff like that got to be
promising. But the fact is, you got out
of Mexico and I asked my Mexican friends
and allies and government people, what's
it going to take to change the the drug
war in Mexico and the whole thing?
100,000 dead in the drug wars in Mexico
last last 10 years, last five years. And
they say when California legalizes
marijuana and I'll say what about
Washington, Colorado. They say that
helped. What about Oregon Alaska? That
helped. But California, if you do Texas,
too, that'd be big. But California,
right? It is going to reverberate in
Mexico, in Central America, the
Caribbean, and in Latin America. We've
been working with our Latin American
allies to try to roll back the drug war
there, and they keep banging their
heads. in this peace agreement that's
going to happen in Colombia between the
FARC, the leftwing gorillas who have
been involved in drug dealing and the
government looks very promising. But I
mean, quite frankly, even in Latin
America now, they want to know what's
going on with marijuana in the US.
Medical marijuana from Brazil to
Colombia to Mexico to Costa Rica to
Chile is the issue that's moving. and
they're seeing how the medical marijuana
issue back in the late 90s, late 2000s
helped to transform the dialogue in our
country and to change the face of
marijuana and educate people who were
closed on marijuana. And they see that's
the way things are moving as well.
Right? People in Jamaica where they're
trying to inch their way towards
legalization, but they're still scared
of what the US government will do to
them in one way or another. California
goes, it gets very hard for anybody to
start rolling this stuff back at this
point. It's still not going to be 100%
in the bag, right? bigger events have
been turned around in the past, but it's
going to be huge. It means that when we
go to the United Nations and are talking
about, are we going to keep cannabis in
these international conventions that we
have that much more traction, right? It
means that when Canada hopefully moves
forward to legalize marijuana next year
and God bless Justin Trudeau, we need
leadership like that. You know, I got to
tell you, you look around the world now,
you look at that bastard Putin, the
biggest mafiosi in the world. You look
at Chinese leadership, she is just
becoming a dictator. You look at Erdigan
in Turkey. You look at what's going on
in Hungary and in Poland. You look at
the mess in Brazil and practical civil
disorder in Venezuela. I mean, you look
at this ugliness going on. And I got to
say, I look around and say, who's good
out there? Justin Trudeau is at the top
of my list.
I kind of like the Pope, too, even
though he's kind of closed on this
issue.
And truth be told, I mean, we slammed
President Obama in his first term. And
his people would say, if we get a second
term, we'll be there. And I got to hand
it to him. Do not take for granted the
extent to which the White House and the
Justice Department have allowed this
stuff to proceed. That was not
inevitable. and the fact that they still
have a DEA saying bullshit all the time
and a national center of drug abuse
doing bullshit all the time and that
Obama's kind of letting that whole
conflict play out. But the fact of the
matter is what's opening up here
notwithstanding with the letter of
federal law is a credit to this
administration, right? You know, now I'm
not supposed Let me take off my How much
time do I have left by the way?
A few few more minutes. Okay, I I won't
go through this long here. Go for it.
So, let me just take off my Drug Policy
Alliance hat here and my drug, you know,
and just speak personally for a second
about the spectacle that's going to
happen tonight and over the next six
weeks. Um, from a drug policy
perspective, there is no question but
that Hillary is better
than the other guy.
And I mean it did not reassure me that
Governor Christie, who's been mixed on
these issues, right? We've we have an
office in New Jersey. He's been mixed on
this stuff. You never know. Like last
week, week ago, okay, medical mar PTSD,
but meanwhile he's in the primary
saying, "Smoke your weed now because I
become president. I'm going to bust you
all right." I mean, so he's unbr but the
thought of him as a potential attorney
general candidate or something. Not
promising. Sheldon add screwed Trump.
You're only going to give him five
million, 100 million. he's pouring into
the Republicans, right? But the fact
that AD was the first major Republican
donor say, "I'll back that guy." And AD,
meanwhile, is pouring the only guy
pouring seven figures money against
marijuana reform. Right? Not promising.
And that his VP is Mike Pence from
Indiana, who has been the far evil side
on the drug war. I mean, finally as
governor, he finally agreed to allow a
little needle exchange where a whole ton
of people, basically white people,
started getting HIV and stuff like that.
And so, he really had to do something.
But he's been a nightmare as well. So I
don't know that Trump, you know, he's a
New Yorker. He doesn't give a damn. He
could say, in fact, I think he did 20
years ago said, "Let's legalize all
drugs." And then he'll say something
else. You know, whatever comes out of
his mouth, you can't count on anything.
He could flip-flop any which way. But
the people around him and the people
he'll appoint, not good. Hillary, she
doesn't have this in her, you know? I
mean, Obama was more cool with it, but
Hillary is going to Democratic
fundraisers and saying, "I promise you I
will be at least as good as Obama was on
this." And that's important. That's
important, right? She's willing to sign
on to stuff about ending the drug war in
a big way. She gets the problems of mass
incarceration. She gets some of this
stuff. She's paying attention. So from
that and look, Gary Johnson,
libertarian, listen, Gary, we opened
office in New Mexico back in January
2000 when Gary was governor of New
Mexico and he and I became fairly close,
right? He was a libertarian Republican
governor wanted to move drug policy
reform in the right direction, right?
And and and and and basically the
Democratic legislature hated him because
he was vetoing all the spending bills.
And we opened up to work in a bipartisan
way with both of them. Gary Gary Johnson
signed a whole host of things from
giving back former felons the right to
vote to all forms of diversion programs
to getting behind our medical marijuana
bill which only passed some years later.
I think it may well
be Gary Johnson increased state spending
on drug treatment by 50%. That
libertarian cost cutting governor did
and I think we brought out the best in
Gary. He did the right stuff there. He
did the right stuff. But the fact of the
matter is there's an election happening.
If you live in a nonswing state, you're
in California, you're in New York,
you're in Mississippi, you're in
whatever it is, vote for Gary, vote for
Jill Stein, vote for whoever you want to
do, but if you live in a swing
state, there's a real choice. now a real
choice whether it's about drug policy
and don't let get me going on my
personal views about the future of the
country in this world and you know so
I'll leave that as back to my DrakePa
hat so going
forward my
hope is that this industry as it grows
as it becomes more dynamic
can become a model of illegal industry.
Now, mind you, there's tactical reasons
for it to do that because this thing is
not in the bag as yet. And if this thing
goes south, if all of a sudden there's a
whole lot of bad product on the market,
if all of a sudden we have major
increases in adolescent marijuana use
and things like that, we got a problem
on our hands, right? If all of a sudden
there's all tons of tons of marijuana
being produced legally but shipped out
of state across state lines to states
that that we got a problem on our hand,
right? We know that the Obama
administration gave the states that
legalized a qualified green light to
proceed, but there's a whole bunch of
conditions, right? We know that they
said, "Hey, listen. In the 1970 federal
sub control subs act says it's in the
interest of drug policy behind but
advancing public health and public
safety. Marijuana legalization to keep
moving forward safely has to continue to
be about advancing public health and
public safety. That's how we succeed.
But I think because of the origins of
where this all came from, remember this
is basically never happened before.
There has never been a social justice
movement in American
history that resulted in the emergence
of a legal industry worth tens of
billions of dollars a year. I mean, if
you look at the other social justice
movements that we sometimes model
ourselves on or whose shoulders, you
know, we we step on as we move forward,
you know, gay rights, civil rights,
women's rights, all of those movements
as they preceded in America had
significant economic consequences, but
no one of them created a brand new
industry worth tens of billions of
dollars. The closest analogy
historically is the repeal of alcohol
prohibition, but even there that was
essentially just relegalizing a market
that had been legal just 15 years
before. We are doing something
unprecedented and truly new. It is truly
special. The benefit that will happen
almost automatically is that people
getting busted, especially black and
brown people getting busted for drugs,
that that opportunity is just no longer
be there for them to get busted. It
means that as we move forward to
legalize marijuana in the states where a
majority support that, we cannot forget
about what's happening in the south and
other parts of this country where you
still have people serving many years
behind bars for a second or third
marijuana possession offense. We cannot
forget about the half the states where
marijuana is not even legal for medical
purposes as yet. We cannot forget about
the millions of Americans continuing to
be victimized in the workplace or the
course in all sorts of ways and
disproportionately victimized if you are
poor, if you are young, or if you are of
color. We cannot forget about that as
you're making the money, man. Remember
that piece and fight for that.
So, I want to make this pitch to you.
Think
about as you move
forward, making a
promise to
do just one good
thing, just one good thing to make
legalization of marijuana a better thing
for society in the world. And by what I
mean by one good thing, I mean something
that does not help directly or even
indirectly, maybe indirectly indirectly,
but does not help your bottom line.
It means the notion of tithing one, two,
five, 10% of your sales or your profits
to helping advance this cause further.
It means making a commitment to
diversity in this industry. It means
making a commitment to setting up some
little mentoring program so that people
who might not otherwise have a chance to
get into this industry can get into it.
It means taking real pride in the
quality of your product and in the way
you try to make sure that the ro that
people young people are not getting
involved in this stuff and that you are
really being careful and responsible
about this stuff. There's make that
commitment to yourself. You can tell me
later if you want to do whatever, but
just make the commitment to do one good
thing. Just one good thing. Okay?
Because I I'm in California. I don't
know how many of you know what what the
word mench means. You know, mench is a
Yiddish word. It basic Yiddish word
refers to a man or human being. And what
it really refers to is a human being who
uses their head and their heart, you
know, in the right ways in life, right?
to treat their fellow human beings
decently and etc. Right? And I remember
people ask in TV program say what's your
vision of a drug policy legalization?
It's not just all drug legalization. I
think we need to think about it
arguments for it but no it's more subtle
than that. Well, are you talking about
just a kinder gentler drug war? No, no,
no. Kind of. What I'm talking about is
the menshite approach to drug policy.
I'm talking about a way of dealing with
drugs and drug users and drug markets
that's about doing the right thing,
making this thing fair. I would love to
see that, you know, I'm kind of a small,
beautiful guy. I would just assume not
see big alcohol, tobacco,
pharmaceutical, or consumer goods
companies take over this whole thing,
right? I'd like to see, you know, the
the micro brewery market or the vineyard
market be a dominant modality here. I'd
like to see us get to the day when maybe
we could have farmers markets in some
parts of this country with some quality
controls, but like to see I'd like to
see that. I'd like to see this industry
be reasonably taxed in a productive way
so that basically the illicit side is
essentially fading away, right? I'd like
to see us work side by side while the
pharmaceutical companies are producing
their isolated, you know, products from
the cannabis plant in ways that are
going to help people, right? I'd like to
see us do all these things in the right
way. I think we can do it. We can do it.
So, come election day, you know what to
do. But don't just vote for Prop 64.
Look at the rest of the ballot. There's
another initiative that Jerry Brown's
actually behind. Never thought I'd be
getting behind Jerry Brownish, but Prop
57, which is about parole reform and
juvenile justice reform, putting fewer
people behind bars. When you pull the
lever for 64, pull the lever for 57 as
well. Right. When we get into
implementation, be at the table. Do so.
I understand you got to protect your
interest, but do it in the right way. So
just to
conclude, we are now beginning the
second generation of the global drug
policy reform movement. We've gone from
215 and 96 legalizing medical marijuana
to over half the states legalizing
marijuana to California about to
legalize marijuana 6 weeks from now and
create a whole new model for how to do
this thing. Right. Right. We that we are
turning the country and we're beginning
to back away from mass incarceration.
But if we've hit the tipping point on
marijuana legalization, we barely hit a
turning point when it comes to ending
mass incarceration in this country. You
know, actually, it's nice. I somebody
say where we are in mass incarceration,
we've hit a turning point, but it's like
turning around an ocean liner. I've
never actually said that on an ocean
liner, but it means that even when you
point that in a new direction, it takes
time to turn. And it means when we're do
talking with people who use drugs, no
matter what that drug is, no matter how
much you hate that drug or had a bad
trip with that drug, we're not going to
demonize people simply because they use
that drug. And if they use that drug and
don't hurt anybody else, it's none of
the government's business or even their
employer's business so long as they're
doing their
job. And if they're struggling, if
they're struggling with addiction, it
means don't just whack them over the
head and lock them up. Don't throw them
into some drug court which is going to
keep trying to chip them up and put them
in there for longer if they can't be
clean
clean. It means let's do this the right
way. So listen everybody, best of luck
on election day. Make it happen. Make it
happen. Make lots of money. Do the right
thing. Thank you so much.